Hello, good morning everyone. I am
alive. Am I? Hi. So, let me show you my
screen. We are going to code wam
language today. Geometry.
So, you see this is what we going to
code. This is called costics. This is
light rays reflected off of a circle
reflection and refraction. So when you
draw this kind of thing and they the
envelope of the lines forms a shape and
that is called costic. Well the the
whole study of this kind of thing is
called costics. Okay. So you can see
several other examples. The most famous
is parabola.
Okay. And then I just have a bunch of
other you know arbitrary
kind of interesting arbitrary images of
the light ray reflection to arbitrary
curves and see what they what we get. So
there are many curves that are uh that
turns out to have relationships
being a costic of another famous curve.
For example, cooid of diaos
uh this curve. So this curve is let's go
back is the uh if you put a light source
on the focus of this cesoid curve. Now
where's the focus? I forgot where is the
focus but anyway then then the result is
a cardioid is this one which is rolling
a circle around another okay so anyway
that's the things we're going to code
actually we're going to code wam
language so let's begin
so wam language such that it will wait
did we begin it yes
so
it will be able to draw any parametric
equation any the costic the lines of any
um so let's see so you see the costic so
if you have a circle and you you have a
light source on the rim of the circle
then it will the light source reflects
off the circle and creates this
ass shaped curve That curve is called
cardioid.
This one which is which which is defined
by rolling a circle around another
circle. You see is that fascinating?
You see magically you see you create a
curve by rolling a rolling a circle
around another like a a coin you know if
you take out two quarters.
Uh so this curve is called cardioid.
Cardioid means heart shaped. Okay. But
also but then if you have a circle and
you have a light source on the rim of
the circle and you shine a light ray
they will reflect off the circle and
form
so-called envelope and form the cardioid
too and you can see that often in a cup
in a coffee cup. So this is amazing
mathematical properties and there's tons
of it. There's lots of more okay lots of
more. So we did we we did a lot of
coding of curves in the past few weeks.
Uh watch my YouTube will see a lot of
them. But today we're going to so today
we're going to just code this one. Okay.
So go back. Uh we were talking about
costics. All these images needs to be
updated because they were created 30
years ago
uh in 1994 beginning 1993
1993.
Okay. So yeah, so we're going to So and
today specifically we're going to start
with this one. We So this one right now
is this here is a code. It's done by one
of my packages. Okay, paste paste the
code and magnify magnify.
Okay, fantastic. And control shift N to
type set it. You can see you got a
fraction. And shift enter to run it. So
fantastic. And beautiful. Is that
beautiful? So this is this is light rays
from above reflecting off of a circle
and it forms that shape and I believe
that shape is neoid.
Does it say
uh oh ne uh yeah right neoid is the is
the catacostic of a circle with parallel
rays. What does catacostic mean?
Catagosic means the the curve that's
formed
by reflection. Okay. So when you so you
see this light ray coming from above you
have all these reflections then they
form a curve. The envelope of these rays
forms a curve by reflection. Okay. Now
this the other part here is refraction.
Okay. But we are talking about
reflection. So the curve formed by the
envelope of reflection rays is called is
called catacostic.
Meanwhile, if it's refraction, then it's
called diiacostic. Okay, did I explain
uh catacostic and diostic? Okay, so you
see this reflection
catacostic this refraction. Yeah, you
see that's diiacostic. You see, you see
they also kind of created over there.
But the the you see the images here is
too small, hard to see. That's why we
are writing the code today to update it.
But anyway, so I already have the code
of course you can get it by plank curve
plot. Search the web sorry on GitHub
you'll find it. Okay. But what we're
going to do today is to write this code
independently.
So you don't need the package. So along
the way you'll take an hour. I'm going
to go uh going to show you guys how do
you draw these things. So okay. So hello
uh JJ. So if you are here say hi. Love
to see your comments. Uh if you are not
here play at 1.5 speed or faster
cuz I'm just going to go slowly. Have
fun. You know this coffee coffee honey
coffee fantastic wait can we see the can
we see the costics let's see this is
very interesting
So we we got a we got the light. You see
it shines. So can we see the coffee cup?
Can we get some kind of like costic
going on? No. That's like a moon. So you
need to be like above,
right? Do do we see it? No.
Okay. Not really.
Okay. You need to be I think the light
needs to be much stronger. Okay.
So,
yeah, either light the the light needs
to be much stronger or
or the uh you need like clear I think
clear cups will show better. Okay. So,
where's the photo? So let's see the
photo.
Uh not here. So let's go to cardioid.
Okay. Let's show the photo.
Go to cardioid.
That's rolling a circle of another
and or reflection of light rays off a
circle. So there. Okay. So yeah, you can
Okay. So you need more. So I need to
drink more.
Um, so the liquid needs to be
low in a cup in order to see this
cardioid light effect.
So, I'm going to massively drinking it.
We actually see it a little bit. Okay.
Now, can you see
Can you see like the uh
cardioid effect?
Yeah, you can see a little bit.
Okay, the light needs to be stronger.
But anyway,
stop.
Okay. So, let me be right back in 10
seconds. Okay.
you know, so it's getting hot
Okay, let me tell you guys what do you
need to do in order to draw this like
what is the mathematics involved?
Okay, what is this? Uh, stop that.
Stop that. Okay. So what is the math
involved?
So you go to
uh yeah what what so we so what you have
to do basically not difficult. All you
want to do is you want to find the
tangent. Okay. So first of all you have
a curve you need the equation for the
curve. Of course for the circle it's
cosine sign. uh you can just plot x
squar or whatever you know first of all
you need a curve then you need a bunch
points on the curve where you want to be
able to find the you know the light ray
will hit that point okay so that's a
bunch of parameters
um then so so so for each of these
parameter for each of these point on the
curve you want to find the tangent
Okay, at that point now tangent. How do
you get the tangent? Very easy. It's
just the derivative of the x formula and
the y formula. Just a derivative. Okay.
So you get a tangent line. Then then
what you want to do is is you want to
reflect. You see when you when you have
a light source shooting down, you want
to reflect off the tangent line. So it
will go into that direction. Okay. So of
course the light ray you need to draw
the light ray from a given source. So in
our case it's from x = to zero and y is
5,000. It's like way above. So you from
that point you draw a line. You draw a
line to the point on the curve. Then you
find the tangent but don't draw the
tangent. Okay? Then you you find the
reflection. So you so given a line and
given another line tangent line you you
are you can uh find the reflection or
the refraction. Okay, which is basically
just rotating the line
um
90°.
Wait not wait not 90° it's it's
involving like swapping the coordinate
and negative one of then something like
that I'll show you okay I I don't
remember off hand
uh so it's mathematics so you you you
you just find the uh the reflection or
refraction and just draw that line and
that's it and you do this for a bunch of
points okay so we got lots of examples
we have already showed okay so let's
code let's code it Okay.
From Wisconsin. Hello from Wisconsin.
Wisconsin is a cheese the cheese
town. Cheese state. Am I right? Cuz I
had a I had a uh boss kind of from
Wisconsin back in 1990s. Back in 1991
actually. Like 1991 when I was like 20
years old. She's from Wisconsin and
she's got Wisconsin accent, you know. I
can still remember. Make a copy. Make a
copy. Can you make a copy of this paper?
Not copy, but make a copy.
Is that is that right? Is that Wisconsin
accent?
Uh so anyway so yeah there was fun times
you know when I was 20 30 years ago
close to 40 years ago anyway so um yeah
so we want to start start to code okay
go to nefroid we want to start to code
let's get onto this code
uh okay so let's get on to this code
okay so
yeah so now Remember we need the
tangent. Okay. Now once we got the
tangent everything is easier. We just
you know so first of all so how do you
get a how do you uh get a code for
tangent? Well let's just copy
make a copy make a copy of copy our code
from few days ago. [laughter]
So let's go to evolute. We just we just
created this code. Um, wait, not what?
Uh, not evolute. Let's go to envelope.
We we wrote this like two weeks ago or
three weeks ago. Here's a code for uh
that. And but we created a independent
page for tangent. This is shiny page for
tangent. Let's copy that. In fact,
uh tangent and normal. We also need the
normal because when you start to talk
about reflection refraction we're going
to do a lot that you see vector this is
about vector geometry vectors so copy
the code okay so uh what are we doing
here so let's go to
uh well let me just show you okay so
copy the code paste the code here shift
enter so you got bunch of tangent lines
and normal lines normal lines are
defined to be the lines perpendicular to
the tangent and passing the tangent
point. Okay,
so we got the code. So, uh
never worried. Okay, so we wanted to uh
redo which one? This one. Semi-ircle.
Okay. Cateostic of a circle or cardiod.
Hot hot hot. I've been told accent uh
what
so uh
uh not that that's again that that's
interesting by itself because the net co
curve is
okay I'm I'm going to I should stop
talking about it because if I start to
talk about it it's going to be nonstop
anyway is a curve
you can defined by there are many ways
to define it but One of the most popular
way
of defining the curve is a a a circle
rolling on another circle but the circle
outside of a circle. A a circle rolls on
another circle on the outside of the
circle but the rolling circle is half
times smaller. The radius is half times
smaller. So you get that. Okay. So
that's how you got this like double S
like double S shape. Okay. that you know
that is something else anyway. So you
know the double ass shaped curve.
Ah I need to update this page.
Anyway so that's neoid right and
there are so many other properties. One
another way to define it is you shine
your light ray parallel lights onto a
circle. Then the
envelope of the reflections forms the
cardio. So the so that you see that that
is exactly called uh nephoid. Okay. This
is called nephoid.
Okay. So you know there's lots of
properties. Okay.
But yeah so uh we so what are we doing?
So but we were talking well what what
about that one? Well that's that that is
another property.
Another way to define it is you um so we
did this yesterday. Fantastic and
beautiful. Yes, we we coded this
yesterday and here's a code. Uh but but
we want but you know so this I did
offline last week some something like
that. So this is nephoid is the envelope
of a set of circles
with centers on a base circle B and
tangent to a fixed chord that bicts B.
So in other words, you start with a
circle. Imagine here. Okay. So you you
start with a circle and you cut in half.
You draw a line passing the middle of
the circle. Okay? Then you draw a bunch
of other circles centered on the rim of
the circle B. Okay, fixed circle B
centered on the rim of the circle. But
however each of the circle you draw
should touch the bis sector of B then
you form this kind of thing. So the
theorem is saying that this is you see
the envelope you know the the the
formation the envelope of this bunch of
circles is
a neoid is is just like rolling a circle
is is a neoid okay magical magical
properties
so that's why you study the visual
dictionary of special plane curves the
project I created 30 years ago when I
was young uh which got me a job at Wuam
Research.
That's true. This I did this that got me
a job wam research and it turned out
that's basically the most I've done for
mathematics.
Kind of sad. Yeah. See, really kind of
sad.
Anyway,
so anyway, let's let's go back to code.
Okay, so we wanted to uh we so again
what what is it we want to do? Yeah,
this one. So let's let's focus on that
one. Okay, don't get distracted. So
let's
copy. So, let's go to um
is it does that make sense guys? Say
something you guys watching. Uh does
that make sense? Reminds me of some Xc
screen saver.
Uh who makes make mark making um making
hearts? I'm only on here. Uh I don't
know who who who else say hi. Okay. So
what is this? So constic uh so this is
the yeah this is a curve we want to do
and uh let's create wolf language code.
Okay now let's start to show you. Okay a
circle first of all a circle is go sign
sign. Okay so um
let me just show you guys. Okay, a
circle is um x cosine s
cosine and sine. Okay, now range list.
So cosine sign. So let's see. So
typically
cosine sign is starts from right I
believe. So let's say
uh okay so range list is going to be a
range let's say from zero uh to
i
and pi divided by six the seven okay
let's say seven points okay this just
means
just this is just like python range okay
let's run it you see that symbolic
result now if you want numerical result
just give a number one of the number
approximate then it returns numerical
result. You see
fantastic supreme wam language by the
way you can download it free just search
for uh my my website for example this is
website this is my talk show January
30th
uh
okay that's you know interesting topic
but anyway so go to today's talk show
download Rufam language okay just search
the web kali.info
info wuam download wam engine you can
find on www.wfam.com/developer
wufam.com/developer
turn on JavaScript
and you can download Wufam engine which
is you know this wam language
that's about about 4 gigabytes okay you
need to give your email and stuff so
it's like for student I mean for
personal use so read their license okay
you know you have to read their license
agreement and whatever so you can
download it and Then just read my
articles. You also want to download. So
once you download the wam engine, you
have the woofam
the wufam script which you run in
terminal like that. You see you you run
in powershell or in bash in terminal
like that. But you if you want a
graphical user interface then you have
to download uh you know just like read
my page download the wam research for
Jupiter movement language for Jupiter
wam
research created it now there's
alternative you know so there is
actually someone else wrote a open
source alternative to the to the jupiter
it allows you to run wam language
on a website of course with a with an
engine you have to download
but you know read my website you'll find
it you know uh again so my website wufam
language tutorial you'll find it okay
also I have not been able I have not
been able to update my website in the
past month for technical reasons but
that should be fixed in few days
I saw the tangent line.
Yes. Uh yes. Okay. So, let's go back.
So, yeah. So, let's start to code again.
So, code. Okay. On on Twitter, you know,
because I haven't been updating my
website for technical reasons, but I
have posted wam language code to
Twitter. So
for those of you can't wait to grab you
know the wam language code for example
this one we coded yesterday and the
updated code is here you don't need to
download my package
you know otherwise you can get the
package but if you just want to run it
you know so there's a code and and sever
several others you know several others
I've done in the past um
anyway anyway on Twitter. So you just
have to remember today's date then
search for it anyway. So
so we uh okay we going to never finish
at this rate. So let's start to code.
Okay
[sighs and gasps]
range list is just a list of numbers.
Okay. And let's just say and
okay so that's makes it numerical. Okay.
Then uh Okay. So
tangent line length we don't care about
that really.
Uh okay. So for now leave it. Okay. Now
here is the tangent vector you. Yeah. So
here is a derivative. So you see fcurve
is defines a function. It returns a list
of two
values. Okay. So essentially it's a two
functions two functions okay in a list.
Now fcurve
prime that is a derivative that's a wam
language syntax. So this f tangent
vector is is is
a fun is a derivative function. Okay.
Then what we want to say is just to show
okay show the curve. So here we plot the
curve from 0 to 2 pi. No, let's plot it
from zero to pi. Just half of it. Okay.
In fact, we can just copy it. And let me
just show you so that people so that you
see something interesting. Okay. Paste
the code. Shift enter. So you see you
you see you begin to see have a circle
and uh all these you know tangents and
normals. Okay. So go back to the code
now. Plot range. Uh let's let's um plot
range. We don't want like that. You see
this plot range is off.
This you know this looks like the
Japanese wartime flags. So plot range is
negative one since it's like this is
like a circlegative one.
Then just times um
times 1.3.
Okay.
Select all. Paste and shift enter.
Fantastic. Fantastic.
Now there's something you see. We can
increase the range. Increase let's say
uh pi pi over let's say 20. Okay. Then
we got something else wrong. So you see
the normals is going all all around.
the normals are not following the
tangent for some reason.
Uh so you see so this is normal line
length uh
okay so let let me let me work on that.
So,
so tangent line length normal line
length. Okay. So, this is the derivative
show this is the curve. This this line
plots the the the
curve itself which is a semiircle. Okay.
Now, now the tangent line is the um
[sighs]
Okay. So we got um
from language is kind of nested. So it's
all nested thing kind of hard to read.
So we uh so
x point is a point by evalu evaluating
the fcurve at parameter t.
Then this line normalize f tangent
vector. You see that's a derivative. So
you evaluate the derivative at t. That
gives you the tangent vector. Then you
normalize which is a function which make
it a unit vector. So it's a vector
length one. Okay. So that's we name it
unit vector. Okay. Now let's highlight
that. Okay. Unit vector. Then what we do
is we um let's see unit vector times
tangent line length that because we
wanted to draw you know the tangent line
at certain length otherwise it's too
short you know so
uh so do we need that not really so um
we you know so this is tangent vector
this is normal vector so what is going
on here. So, actually, let me do this.
You see this formatting make it more
intuitive. Okay, that's what we want.
Okay, so yeah. So, that's kind of more
let's make it.
So, this is actually one line, one
thing. Okay. So this is the tangent
line.
Tangent vector. This is actually tangent
line. This is normal vector. Okay,
that's not a lines. That's a vector.
Then the line, the tangent line is this
point minus tangent vector and point
plus tangent vector. So that gives you
the beginning point and end point of the
tangent line [snorts] and color it red.
Okay. So if you don't want tangent
comment out that
and we can plot it. You see select all
paste shift enter. You see we remove the
tangent line
now. So we can see why we we get oh so
the normal you see we got this part
because they the normal lines are alone.
It's not because they are from the
curve. You see that's why so we our code
is good.
Okay, our code is good. Now you see
because we want it not to you know we
want to draw the light rays. So we need
light rays. So we need actually need to
draw
light
source.
Okay. So light source needs to be um you
know you have to specify a light source
for now. Let's say 9 and uh uh 20
something like that. Okay, just a point.
And then you need to draw a line from
the light source to to the curve to a
point on the curve that represent the
light ray. Right? So So that's what
we're going to do. Okay? So you got the
light source there and you need to
remember that is tangent. So copy that.
So you want to draw a line from light
source there to to the point on the
curve there. And this line let's color
it c because cen is usually like a
light. Okay. And this tangent line we
don't need. Okay. Copy. Now
select all paste.
Now control shift N to make a type set.
So we see this fraction is a little type
set. You see some of the brackets gots
larger. You see
when you when you type set you see
n means n means give numerical result.
So range 0 to pi pi over 7 that means
divided pi by 7 subdivisions. So give
give us eight numbers. Then n means make
them numerical not symbolic. You can it
can be symbolic but slow things down. So
it doesn't so it should
it doesn't matter but if you have lots
of numbers it's much faster when you
have numerical
evaluation. Okay. So you see, so here's
a code. So let's shift enter. So
fantastic. Can you see the light ray?
Okay. From the top. Now let's make the
circle from the bottom because that
makes more because
it's more intuitive for us to think of
the light coming from top.
For this for this illustration, you
know, we can make the light source come
from any direction, but it's more
intuitive. They are from top. And since
we want to illustrate the property of
the um
God,
where are we? Oh god,
we want to Oh god, we you know, we got
so many other things, beautiful things.
Okay, we wanted to illustrate. Where are
we?
Okay, we need to go to the ne uh the
nephoid page. We want to illustrate this
reflection of light rays. Therefore,
let's make the circle go from here to
here. Okay. So, let's change the range
uh range from
pi to
2 pi. Fantastic. Okay.
Uh and let's make it let's say 12 a bit.
Let's say a bit more. Okay. And uh so
copy all. So let's do it again. Select
all. Paste. Shift. Enter.
Fantastic. Okay. The the this is still
wrong. Okay. Yeah. Well, that's because
here
uh yeah, but you want to go from pi to
um
I to 2 pi. Okay, copy.
Select all paste. Shift enter.
Fantastic. Now better. Now you see this
normal lines. That's no good. You don't
need these normal lines. Okay. So remove
the normal lines. Okay. So remove the
normals. Okay.
Copy all back. Select all. Paste. Shift.
Enter. Fantastic. Now now we just need
to draw the reflection. You see? So so
the question the in order to do that you
need to answer this math question.
The math question is given
a vector how do you find its reflection?
Okay.
Uh so hi JJ I saw the tangent line AI
sent me here because Emacs. Oh
fantastic.
We got a EMAC fan. Of course I'm a EMAC
master.
Do you know about my Emac tutorial?
like have you heard of me before JJ
because I'm well known for that and I in
fact most of my past videos
hundreds of them 500 like by by now I
have 700 videos but I would say
500 of them is all about Emacs
so today's can we go to today's talk
show uh let's put this back okay syntax
X go ahead show in browser. So we are
working on this page and go down go down
go down go down go down go down go down.
So we will we are working on this
graphics and this is the current code
not done yet. Okay now this this is the
Alish code for but you require my
package you have to go get it on GitHub
plane curve plot. Okay but now let's go
back to talk show. So show today's talk
show. So you see today's episode 777
not 666
the number of the beast of the
Christians thing
but 777
uh so I've done that many videos but in
the past like most of it more than half
is about Emacs.
So, so are you still here? Like can you
like right I mean uh like did you hear
about me before or was it first time you
saw my name?
Okay. Cheers. So, let me continue. How
many people are watching now? Like not
many. Uh three. Okay. Something like
three.
Okay. Five. Okay. So anyway, so is it
does does this make sense? Right. So far
so good. Cheers.
You see now let let us take a moment to
observe the beauty of code. Fantastic. I
mean imagine mathematics. You see
mathematics.
Okay. Shift controlN.
You see, we got mathematics, fractions,
notation, you know, this human knowledge
of 20,000 or 4,000 years.
Exactly. That's what they are. you know
calculus derivatives you know Newton
Newton Lebnes
Aranes
you know Newton and Lebanese they kind
of invented calculus in 1800 or was 1700
or was it yeah I think 1700 but then
calculus has its origins from like 2,000
years ago Archimedes and others
and uh you know So the knowledge of
humanity you know part of it is here it
condensed into this code and computer
and not not to mention the science of
computation the binary digits you know
huge number theory it's all here you see
you are looking at the knowledge of hum
human uh knowledge fruit and the of
course
computational geometry how do you
implement this you know all this uh
linear algebra and all that fantastic
and beautiful I have to watch I asked
about the idea of modifying stuff
I have to watch
I ask about the idea of modifying stuff
I don't know what you're saying how old
are how old are you are you like pretty
young like I don't know what you're
saying
I have to watch you have to watch What
what my videos and you say you say I
asked about the idea of modifying stuff
modifying what stuff
about using Emacs
to modify code or what is what like what
what
okay so let's go back um
so yeah so so how do you reflect the
curve well actually I don't remember
because [laughter]
But I have the code. Let's just look at
the code. Okay. You know, so this we we
we right now we face the question
given a vector, how do you find and give
gi given a vector
let's say the vector heads um like how
do you want to phrase it? I mean the
basic question is given a vector and
given a line
in the plane find out their intersection
point of course then well given two
lines okay find find the intersection
point and find find the other line line
that's a reflection and also the
refraction let's just simplify just say
reflection how do you do it okay now in
order to answer to answer that question
first of all you need to be precise
price for example we can start to draw
uh well so what I'm doing here is kind
of like kind of education okay kind of
like uh let me let me let me let me
start a drawing program first so I'm
kind of trying to do uh education tell
you guys for for those young students uh
about how to think about mathematics
okay so uh where where do snipping tool.
Okay. Yeah. So I I just want to open
this.
I just want to be able to draw.
Okay. Ignore whatever is. So anyway, so
given Yeah. G given given a line you. So
let's say
let's say um you see let's say this
second line. Okay. Let's say this one.
This what
let's say this this line. Okay. So you
are hitting here. So there is a kind of
there is a tangent line.
You see that is a tangent line.
Okay. So this
AB so let's say this ABC. Okay. the the
ray B. Okay. So, it hits there. And how
does it reflect? Well, the way you find
that out is you you draw a line
perpendicular to this tangent. So,
that's a normal. Okay. So, this is a
normal.
This is called normal line. Okay. Then
you just you just by symmetry
you can see the reflection line is this
one.
Okay. Reflection. F L E C T I O N. Okay.
This is the reflection. You see by
symmetry because you just find find the
angle. So you find the angle between the
line the this ray and the tangent then
you just reflect it over this axis
and you get that. Okay.
So that's kind of the math background.
So in order to answer this question you
can work it out by you know slowly by
spec by trying to find how do you
specify this vector first in the first
place. So you can imagine it's the like
move the whole graphics through the
origin like you can imagine if it's just
a vector like over here
you know so so basically this point is
the origin so it makes everything easier
so because
then you can find out reflection because
to move things away from the origin all
you have to do is just add a point you
see vector addition or vector abra uh
subtraction right So anyway, so this is
how you can work it out. You see this
method thinking clearly, you can not
just work it out. You can like always
remember it's not like, oh, I need to
look up the book about formula,
memorize it. No, you you you think
logically, okay? So you can you can
always derive the formula yourself. I
can do it now, you know, but it'll take
me like 30 minutes, you know, I did this
long ago. So, but the point is I can I
can derive it. That's the key when you
do mathematics. You don't want to like
memorize oh you know me and you know you
memorize derivatives or or integrals you
know by this method that's not good. You
want to know how it works. Okay. Once
you know how it works,
then you can derive it on the fly. So
you don't have to like memorize it. So
it works in every every mathematics like
advanced
uh
you know complex analysis, graph theory
and so on. Okay. we forgot to uh
make we forgot to save a stupid uh
Microsoft.
Anyway,
so we going to code. So let's look at
the code. So get directory search for
curve. So you can see my packages.
Search for this here. That is a package.
And we are looking for costics there
there.
That's you see we got a code here. So uh
costic line length that's that's one of
the uh option specify the length. So
actually we need that you see. So let's
copy that. Let's go to
uh we need that neoid.
So is this what we're doing? Yes. So you
need to say here.
Okay. So actually we
yeah costic line length. Okay. So you
need to say that somewhere
we need we need that eventually. Uh then
we also let's go back here. So search
for costic
that we uh costic origin already have
that.
Okay. Style we don't care. So let's but
we want the code like how do you compute
the costic there here okay here is the
function so let me explain to you guys
there that's what we want okay go back
to the code uh go back to the code we
will explain this code
okay now okay so this this is one thing
let's put it back but let me explain the
mode.
Okay. Now put it out. So So here is the
code that that is the heart of drawing
all these costic
ray reflections you see used in many
packages. Let me show you one of them.
Beautiful. It's most amazing. So let me
show you an example.
go here. So you need to go to deltoid.
Deltoid is is the curve formed by
rolling a circle inside a larger one
with a rolling circle onethird the
radius of the larger one. Okay. Then you
create this deltoid curve. It can also
be created if the rolling circle's
radius is 23
of the large one. They create exactly
the same curve. Fascinating. Deltoid.
Okay. Now deltoid. Now let me show you
another one called asteroid is created
if you have a circle 1/4 the larger one.
You roll a circle inside the larger one.
But this rolling circle is 1/4 the
radius of the larger one. You get
asteroid
curve with four cusps. CS cusp means
these sharp points. Okay. Now, so you
got asteroid, you got deltoid. Very
similar. Okay. But now there's a
relationship between these two. Okay.
And that re relationship is
optical property costics. Okay. So now
let me explain fascinating this one the
most amazing
theory.
Well one of there are so many amazing uh
relations and properties about these
curves. You see, so given
given an asteroid, you know, you roll a
circle inside another four times
smaller, you create this, you know,
given an asteroid and you shine a light
from outside the curb. So from far away,
you know, you let's say you you you
shine parallel rays, okay?
Oh, okay. So wait, given given a
deltoid, look at the center. Okay. So,
let me show you. Look at this one. Okay.
Given a delta, can we enlarge this? We
need to recreate that. Open image a new
tab. Uh
yeah.
So, given a deltoid, look at the thing
in the middle. Okay. Then
then if you have bunch of light rays,
parallel light rays
shines onto the deltoid from outside and
the reflections and refractions will
form the asteroid. You see does not
matter which direction the light ray
come from. You see the light ray can be
anywhere.
Their reflection on the deltoid is
asteroid.
Do you guys see? Do you guys find this
like amazing?
So, this is super amazing. Okay.
Anyone here say hi. Okay. So, um
so I sent here because I have to watch
your videos. I don't think I should be
modifying this. Oh, okay.
Um yeah, super cool.
Uh yeah. Yeah. So you mentioned screen
saver. Yes, screen saver. There's a lot
of screen savers uh based on these
curve ideas.
Um you know so anyway so
and we have so this is uh ge algebra
illustration actually. Let me show you
that. Okay so this is very interesting.
So you can see this dynamically.
So you see in the middle you see this
blue it's it's a deltoid. Okay. Now
now there's a light source. You see I'm
dragging the I think the the point I'm
dragging is a light source. Yeah. You
see outside of the deltoid. Okay. Then
you can and then you look carefully on
the reflection. You see the reflection
is this
asteroid. Okay.
Okay. So, one part is reflection, the
other part is refraction. That's right.
I think um
yeah. So, the reflection and refraction
on the deltoid creates the asteroid.
Okay, can you guys see? Let me do this
slowly. Okay, this is just amazing.
That's one of the most amazing thing,
you know, is quite amazing. Now, how do
you prove this? Actually, I don't know a
proof. I I I um I asked a mathematician
one time, but he didn't
he didn't know neither. that um
so I anyway I did this like 30 years
ago. I should ask I should actually try
to find a proof and see how to prove it.
It's not
is it easy? I'm not sure it's easy. It
involves I think um the the concept of
envelope anyway which is I think
involves differential equations.
>> [snorts]
>> I'm not sure how to how to prove. Okay.
So actually let's try AI. So this is a
very difficult question.
Uh
show proof that
uh costics of
parallel rays on deltoid is an asteroid.
Let's see AI can answer that. This is
like very difficult. I mean this is not
I don't think it's a common question.
Show proof that costics a parallel rays
on deltoid is an asteroid. Let's see
what guac will say. So this is
digression.
Uh
yeah so let's let's see you see how
powerful are you AI? Can you can you
prove this?
I would be very interested because I
never seen proof myself.
Okay. Deltoid uses equations like um
okay thinking about users request
thinking standard deltoid
assuming rays parallel to x-axis. Okay.
Features three cusps and concave inward
curves. That's right. Recalling evolute
relation where deltoid evolute ties to
asteroid costic. What does it h
now searching the web you see you see
that American mathematical society that
website contains my page
uh
well due to this mathematician John um
bay you see this blogams.org or John B
about
seven years ago
like posted my my my my page about this
deltoid and asteroid so
to the American Mathematical Society
anyway so oh it's still thinking
okay you see this is uh not an easy
question I've never seen a proof
And I don't know how difficult does it
involve.
So, okay.
Fascinating.
Hi, Coffee. Hello. Been a while since
I've joined in a stream. Hello, coffee.
For the past month, I've been coding a
lot wam language. Uh,
Tabania, fascinating. AI usually answers
me before I ask yes. [laughter]
Okay. So AI is actually still thinking,
you know, so I don't think it'll come up
come up with a with a correct answer
because it's like trying to do it stuff.
I don't think it's going to
come out a correct answer. But the
answer, whatever answer it gave is
probably helpful to find the proof.
You see, it's still going.
You see, that's that's that is why when
I why I learned about these um many
properties of plane curves, I started to
write programs, you know, when I was 20
years old so that we can visually prove
it. I mean visual proof doesn't count
but at least we can like visually see
that is kind you know that's kind of
true
you know this amazing property like you
can visually see it's true now you know
before computers
mathematicians do geometry it's very
like strictly logic there's no like for
a period of time you know they don't do
illustrations at all because they they
try to stick with pure logical analysis.
Right? So when you say when you given
given this theorem you know asteroid is
the costic of deltoid with parallel rays
in any direction like people you know
when you read that like you don't know
what's going like it's very dry
but in in your head then you might
imagine like this picture but it's like
very fuzzy like it's hard to imagine
right like asteroid is the costic of
deltoid with parallel rays in any
direction but no But with computer
technology, you know, you can see it.
And of course, the interactive
technology, you can actually see close,
you know, in detail,
but still you need a proof.
You see AI is still going. Fascinating.
Fascinating. I've never seen a proof,
you know. So,
you know, like um
like I I want to show you this uh
deltoid and asteroid. Okay. I want to
show the
American you see American mathematical
society that's a professional
organization for mathematicians.
So if we go there, this is 2013
about 10 years ago.
You see this is by professor John B.
He taught me
a lot mathematics.
We we don't know each other but we know
kind of online, you know. So online he
wrote a lot about mathematics. So I
learned quite a few math from him. he's
he's a um you know one one of the top
mathematicians.
Uh so anyway so he wrote this um and you
know he borrowed from my website. So I'm
very uh thankful for you know for
for having my website shown on the
professional mathematicians blog.
So anyway, but then I asked, you know, I
asked him that, you know, do you know a
proof by the way? And he says no. So,
so I wanted to see a proof. Okay. So,
but I just I have not seen.
Um I don't know how to do it though. So,
you see AI guac is still like thinking.
I've never seen guac took so long. this
by now it's like two three minutes
interesting
AI is much interesting they do courses
on it in college nowadays really yeah
there's so much you know we don't know
what's going to happen anyway so let's
go back to the code okay so how long
have I been talking
already 70 minutes okay So anyway, this
this is the code that does the uh
reflection and refraction draws. Okay.
Um so how can I like what do I want to
do? Can I
so first of all let me do a quick demo
using this code. Okay. To show that what
it does. Okay. Let me just quickly so
let me read let me show. Okay. So for uh
this part let's go to talk show. Okay.
So wait,
let's go to today's talk show.
Okay, then uh go to go down
new section.
That's the question we asked AI
and I wanted to show
[snorts] this um
yeah this this
AMS
uh American Mathematical Society
link.
Okay. And we wanted to Yeah. I want to
demonstrate this this code how it works.
Okay, so this this this code costic
lines takes a bunch of points. Let me uh
let me change that, rename it. Okay, so
okay, it takes a bunch of points and
tangent vector points and ray origin and
the line length. Okay, that's line
length.
Uh let's just say length. Okay,
wait.
It should do. Okay. Anyway, so that's
the argument. It returns a list of
lines. They represent rays from ray
origin shooting towards the points on
the parameter curve and reflected. Okay,
each line length is x length including
the reflected portion. Okay, so how do
you do this? How do you uh what's the
example of using this code? Let's do it.
Okay. So, let's uh yeah, so let's call
that function. And the function takes
this bunch of things. Okay. Uh points
let's say cosine s
uh cosine
sinx.
Okay. Then you want to map them
uh
uh x x from zero to let's say from pi to
let's say from 3 to six. Okay, it's 3 to
six in increment of 0.2. Okay, now
that's the point. Okay. Now you want the
tangent vector. Well, tangent vector
that that's a list of tangent. So how do
you what what is the derivative of
cosine and s? I believe derative of
cosine is negative sign. Derative of s
is negative cosine. Is that right? Uh I
forgot. So but let's try to find out.
Um
yeah. So that um and the derivative.
Okay, let's see what we get.
Fantastic. I was correct. 30 years
[laughter]
of of derivative. I never thought of I
was correct on that. So that's a
derivative. So what you want is this
function.
Okay. So okay then well let's just copy
it. You just say table
that from
uh 0 3 to six in increment of that.
Okay.
Okay. So you don't you need that delete
that. So that's that that that is the
tangent vectors. Okay. Those are tangent
vector points. Then ray origin. Let's
say uh what was the origin we were
using? Uh I forgot but um
Oh yeah. So 9 and 20. Okay. So ray
origin 9 and 20. Okay. And length let's
say 99. Okay.
So that is the actually so that is the
input to that to this. Okay. So I
actually copy it.
Uh it returns a bunch of lines. So you
need to output to graphics.
Okay.
Okay. So cut that
that.
Okay. Copy all. And I think that's it.
So paste the code here.
Shift enter.
Wrong. We got something wrong. Okay.
Well, we can fix it.
Let's see what is the
coordinate something re Oh.
Oh, we need some other code.
What?
Oh, yeah. We need another code. We
didn't copy that thing. Okay. Reflect
director.
uh reflect direction vector. Okay, we
need to that get that that is simple.
Okay. So,
uh go to get there there
search for that that that that
there okay so actually we need this
function
that's why you know all these
dependencies we don't want
that's why I'm removing all these
dependencies so so this is actually so
this is how do you get the reflection
and refraction. Okay, involve start
product. Uh pretty simple actually when
you actually once
uh think about it. Okay, pretty simple.
So anyway, copy that. So go back to the
code.
So you just go there and uh
Okay. So now
copy all
paste it. Shift enter.
Fantastic. Now you got something wrong.
Why is it um Okay. You don't want the
line length. Let's say line line length
29.
Okay. So you see fantastic and
beautiful. You see now you see it
actually works. So you just need
uh range plot range. Okay.
Fantastic. And beautiful plot range. You
need -1 to one.
Okay. That's x and y and multiply by 20.
Okay. That's how we do. And uh copy all
and let's just open a new one. Paste
shift enter. Fantastic. Okay. So
you don't want 20 plot range. 20 plot
range. Uh let's just say two shift
enter. Fantastic. And beautiful. Can you
see?
So this is like how the code works, you
know.
Okay. So,
well, um I think that's it for today.
You know, I should actually explain
exactly how this reflection works.
Uh but
you know, let's magnify. But you know
then we need to
what I need to do is actually so you
know I should explain how this work. So
reflector director takes two arguments
ray ray vector and the war vector. Okay
returns a unit vector that is the ray
vector reflected off a war vector. Okay
the ray and war vectors do not have to
be unit vectors. And if the wall is the
zero vector then zero vector is
returned. Okay, that is a function.
Now what does it actually do? Well, if
it's
when the wall vector is zero, then just
return zero. Zero vector is um you know
it's like divide by zero. You don't want
that. So otherwise here's a formula. So
you just
So you just negative ray vector plus 2 *
okay that's a dot product times what you
know I don't I don't remember the
details but
but
okay here here's what we can do okay so
let me show you so you can actually find
the formula So let's say a b because wam
language does symbolic computation
x y. Okay. So let's see
given a given a ray vector ab
symbolic and given a ray a wall vector
xy what is the reflection? Do it that is
the answer. Okay. So
yeah so you know so actually just just
the normalized part because the other
part is testing if XY is zero vector you
know so let's just do this part what
does it okay so that
in terms of
A and B that's that that's the formula
fantastic
Let let me demonstrate the wufam
automatic formatting again. You see
automatic formatting on the fly of
programming code. Not just simple
programming code but mathematically type
set code. You see they can format it on
the fly unlike the Python idiots, the
JavaScript idiots, the C++, you know,
the industrial coding idiots.
Okay, let me demonstrate that again. In
notebook, wam notebook, you can format
this on the fly. You see as you like as
you type. Okay, and not just simple code
like this, you know, for example, can we
can we Yeah. You know, not just like
simple
code, which it does format on the fly.
You see or this indentation,
there's no tab there. It's like just
rendered on the fly. You see
indentation, you see they they they
do it in a intelligent way. You see
indentation and the line wrap you see
and
it can do that for code and you can
actually you know double click it. It
will expand selection according to the
syntactical unit of the programming
language wam language. You see you see
double click on that. Double click.
Double click it. You see it selects this
entire list. If you click you know you
do again it select entire if statement
you see. Then if you expand they in
select entire map thread you see. Or if
you start from that map thread you click
twice it select the entire map thread
semantic unit syntactical unit. You see
so this wolf notebook the front front
end it understands the woofam language
syntax
you see so for example let's select any
you know for example here double click
double click again you see it it
automatically you know goes to the plus
normalize you see you see you see it's
select the normalize and whatever part
together because now this sum this sum
That plus that is one unit. You see? Now
if you click again, it's it's going to
select this line unit. You see? Let me
let me show. Okay. Double click. Triple
click. You see? Let me do it again.
Click. Click. Click. Click. Click.
Click. Uh. Okay. Click. Click. Click.
Click. Click. Click. You see? Let me try
again. Okay. Click. Click. Click. Click.
Click. Click. Click. Click. Click.
Click. Click. Click. Click. Click. You
see?
it expand the selection
by the syntactical unit and semantic
unit. They actually are in sync. Why are
they in sync? That is because of the wra
language. Every syntactical unit
correspond a to a semantic unit just
like lisp.
Okay, that's not the case for C or C++
or Java or JavaScript. These idiots or
Python syntax, you know, like in those
languages there is no systematic
correspondence between syntax and
semantics of the programming language.
But in lisp language it does because in
lisp everything the parenthesis
it serves as the
the unifying force between the syntax
and semantics. So it corresponds well
you know every syntactical unit is also
a semantic unit of the programming
language. Okay. Now in Wufam language
that's also the case because Wuam
language actually I've explained before
it's actually based on nested syntax.
Okay. So anyway all these you see you
see all these plus sign or equal sign or
double equal or the nest you know the
curly bracket those are just syntactical
shortcuts. Okay. All the greater than uh
let's magnify let's see the full glory.
You see the greater than equal sign you
know you there or the pi sign or the or
the amperand
or those are just syntactical shortcuts
they correspond actually they have a
full bracket form anyway I'm digressing
all over so
right now I'm just mention on the side
the the this great concept of
of the editor understand the the you
know There's several things I mentioned
the the the
the feature of ex expanding selection
based on syntactical unit that's one
great idea great feature okay and the
concept of a programming language where
the semantic unit and syntactic unit
corresponds
which applies in the Lisp language and
wufam because wufam is actually you can
think of it as a lisp okay because it's
has all the properties of lisp meaning
symbolic symbolic everything is symbols
uh predominantly functional programming
and purely nested syntax which I can
show you but not here this is a shortcut
purely so symbolic predominantly
functional programming purely nested
syntax X list macros in the case of wolf
language it's actually more fullfeatured
called term rewriting system so it
satisfies everything about you know list
language the special properties and
every symbol in list for example they
have you have several slots like value
slot you have properties and stuff you
know so same thing with wuam language
okay so wuam language is very much like
a list
So, so I mentioned several things the
the feature of the editor
expanding selection by syntactical unit
that's one thing the the concept of
programming language of semantic unit
and syntact syntactical unit in in in
coherent incoherence is another concept
okay then [snorts] I also mentioned the
automatic on the-fly formatting of wam
language You see
that's another feature. Okay. So we
don't we don't see this in like the
industrial idiots with their Python or
Goland C++ or even Rust like nowhere in
in their you know in industrial Google
oh Jesus Google AI you know they they
don't have this like their brain is dead
this you know the JavaSc what's what's
so typescript you know type
s open
not typescript well types script too but
VS code okay like you don't see this in
VS code no way to be found the idea is
foreign like they don't they don't
understand the thing they never thought
of this industrial coders
okay let me let me mention again I
mentioned this many times this
industrial coding idiots
in their life they've never seen a
scientific programming language.
[laughter]
Well, today they started to see some of
them because due to AI because in you
know in able to code AI there's a lot of
science involved starting like 10 years
ago you start to have data science you
know statisticians and and you know and
you know they you started to have quite
a lot math especially AI you know linear
algebra you know you need to understand
math but but not the [laughter] not the
t Still most other programmers like the
the the operating system fanatics like
they talk about Linux kernel Linux this
or the web dev like most of them they
never seen they don't know what the
is s cosine okay that's a situation
okay we digressed um but okay so but
anyway that's it uh for that
talk
uh so how long So, are you guys like
enjoying the show? Am I like,
you know, sometimes I I'm I'm pretty
sure I get some haters.
[laughter]
Um, Python lost its charm for me. So,
tough to get run dependently. Rust will
collapse like Pascal. I think, you know,
I kind of I don't know much about Rust.
What I know is that there's a lot of
fat.
Uh but also Rust is like has a lot of
like um functional programming ideas.
It's partly based on Okamo you know the
meta language.
So um so my feelings about Rust is mixed
but I don't think it'll collapse like
Hascal because Hascal is like too pure.
Ascal is from academia
although since 10 years ago you know
Facebook or some other you know we there
are some commercial organizations use
Hascal but not much then so the there
was like huge movement but it never
stayed Hascal in the in the coding
industry because Hascal is like you know
they they they want pure functional
programming. Meanwhile, Okamo
uh F you know the meta language lineage
is very practical.
So I have this pad to my seat or camel
you know. So
so um F is actually used in industry and
or camel in financial industry
and uh and rust is kind of the new
thing. So lots of functional programming
ideas it's based on Okamo. So
what I I don't like is the fat. You
know, there's a lot of fat. But however,
I think it's actually here to stay
because on the other hand, what we don't
want is the C and C++ Okay.
Doesn't matter how much I dislike rust
because there's fats, you know, there's
a lot of young people fats, but but
there's nothing compared to the
perpetual the the the the steel forceful
forceful C and C++ plus you
know, they should die. You know, we we
we need in other words, what I'm saying
not not the people, okay? What I'm
saying is that the industry we need to
get rid of C and C++ and they practice
their ideas like almost everything about
C and C++.
That's what I'm saying. So, so, so for
me, Rust is,
you know,
I don't know much about it, but at least
I I think it's it's better than C++ for
sure. Okay. C++ should die.
Golang is not the best. In fact, so I
guess you are new. Golang is uh I
believe Golan is one of the best
language. Okay.
Uh like why? What do you mean why? Okay.
So I think that's it for today. I
already talked for uh 90 minutes. Is
that right? Yeah. 90 minutes.
Would you characterize the syntax of
woof language as more like lisp or
prologue? It's lisp.
Okay. So, I talked about this many
times. In fact, is in the past 30
minutes. Um, so there's a lot videos
I've done talking about wam language
compared to lisp.
So, let me Okay, let me show you a few
and that's it for today. Okay. So, um,
wuam this. Just search that and see what
you find. Wuam language tutorial. No wam
language versus the syntax. Okay, that's
one of my article.
Okay, and uh you should read that
article. So this is language language
versus lease article 2013. Okay. Uh
no, this is not the article you should
read. The 2013 is kind of old uh early.
Okay, but you can read it, you know, but
I have much better articles since so you
should read actually all these. Okay, if
you guys are interested in what I just
talked about in the past 30 minutes
about this uh language issues, you
should read all like all of these. Okay,
many of these
fundamental problems of lisp syntax
irregularity lisp infix syntax survey
nested syntax xml versus lisp actually
that's not a very good article that's
kind of half asked I need to uh write
more about that uh concept and
confusions confusions of this prefix
infix postfix and list okay let me let
me open a few of the articles that I
recommend you guys should read if you
are interested of what I talked about in
the past 30 minutes about these syntax
and issues. Okay, so let me open them
and so so people don't waste time. Okay.
So, uh
yeah, that
um
Okay. And also I haven't answered your
question yet. The the difference of lisp
and wuam language. Wuam language is not
based on prologue at all. It's lisp and
apl. And I have an article on that.
Okay. Actually, just search for wuam
language lisp and APL and maybe put my
name. you'll find my article
because I show the historical uh
documents and why you know it's like
like that. Okay.
So, but meanwhile and also I've done
videos so I haven't so so you know so go
back here. So you you click on the
videos. Uh so let's say go to videos cuz
I w this go to video section. Okay. So I
can tell you uh episode seven. Uh so
I've done you know I I've done hundreds
of videos
about five like I would say five or more
full one hour talking about the list and
wam language relations. Okay
but it's hard to search like this. Uh
yeah. So it's not you know it's it's
hard to search like that. So you need to
Okay. So let me let me show you what
guys to do. Okay.
Emacs go to my Emacs section Emacs
tutorial. Okay. and go to Emacs blog
and there is
uh a saw talk show video live stream
talk show 2024
June 11th episode 558 which is best list
commonly scheme emac closure wam
language okay that's one of them you
could watch but um
Yeah, that that's one of them. Watch
that. Okay.
But um so this article is also good
fundamental problems of this syntax
irregularity. Uh
yes
then.
Okay. So, so that one
and this one is also very good list
infix syntax survey because lots of list
coders they don't want I mean they they
are trying to create a nested
syntax okay so there's lots of effort
throughout the years by top lisp experts
okay these are top lispers they created
them they want them including the
creator of lisp John McCarthy
they didn't want the purely nested you
know thing they want something else okay
so that that's article one of them and
this one also important concept and
confusions of prefix infix postfix and
this notations okay
important article so read that one too
and Uh uh I'm not sure about this one
but uh but I have better ones to show
you. So okay. So let me just show you.
Okay then. So you go to um go to kasa
wu. Yeah let's search. Let's not use
because when I search people can see
they can replicate. Okay
wam language. Okay. You just go to my
wam language website. Okay, there. Then
once you are here, you go down.
There's a section uh wam language
history. Okay, so you want to read uh
wam language design this APL history.
Okay, read that one and this one. So let
me show you. So this one, wam language
design, this APL history. So you know it
I show you historical documents. Why
Wuram language is a combination of lisp
and APL and Stefan Wuram's own idea
about
a term rewriting system. Okay, that's
the essence of Wuam language. It's a
pure essence
lisp from the lisp heritage like the
syntax is like everything lisp and from
the APR heritage where basically it just
means everything is a array it's a array
language like what that mean basically
is that every function when it applies
to an argument that is a nested list or
matrix it automatically apply to each
element. Okay, that's the kind of APL.
Okay, it's called array languages. Okay,
now you combine these two ideas
everything this
but instead of using the parn you use
the symbol and square bracket. Okay,
then comma instead of space. Okay, so
combine these two idea then combine the
idea of a term rewriting system. You c
you can kind of think of it as like list
macros. Okay. But but but complete
in computer science it's called term
rewriting system
to do mathematics that is wam language.
It was called Mathematica for the first
20 30 years. Okay. It was named the
language is now given a name wufam
language since about 201 uh5 or so.
Okay. So it was called Mathematica.
Okay. That's an idea of that's the
essence of wam language. Now so now let
me show you um so this is like my wam
language code from 1990s
19 you know 30 years ago.
Okay. And so now I so let me show you
the um uh go back. So this article okay
so wufam language versus lisp.
So in this page I give you a comparison
of everything that exist in lisp such as
common lisp scheme emac lisp and the
corresponding thing in wam language.
Okay, side by side
this you know this is like 10 pages.
Okay, so first of all you got symbols,
identifiers are symbols check.
Everything is an expression check. An
expression is either a atomic expression
such as number, string, symbol or a
list. Check.
Purely nested syntax check.
predominantly functional programming
check lisp and woof both they are like
that you you can have variables you can
change variable values but predominantly
it's functional programming okay
[snorts] read the macros meta expression
in this check in wuan language that's
called syntactical shortcuts
okay that's why you are seeing you know
like if you came from lisp you are
wondering no this doesn't look like lisp
you got equal sign you got square, you
know, curly braces, you got comma, you
got double equal sign, you got pound
sign. You know, you might think, oh,
that doesn't look like this. No, you are
wrong because in this you also got this
uh Marco characters such as the pound
sign stand for function and and several
others such as um comma, you know. So
anyway, so in so these are called um in
Wuam language they are called uh syntax
shortcuts. Okay, actually they don't
call it that. They just call it the
normal standard form. Okay, like like
most people
would be freaked out if you if you uh
call them like lambda or like computer
science jarens. Wu doesn't like that.
Okay, in Wan language it's just normal.
Okay, I mean they don't have like oh
this is called by the way sex that is
called meta expression you know or this
is called lambda language does not use
uh you know the in end or whatever the
obstruse
uh jarens okay they use whatever
terminology that's most easy to
understand so for example they don't
call their function lambda they just
it's just fun function okay not lambda
They don't call it sex you know symbolic
expression. No it's just full form.
Okay. So on the left side the these are
called full form. On the right hand side
they don't have a name. It's just
syntax. Okay. They don't have special
name. Okay. But they are equivalent
because every time the wam compiler or
interpreter runs code first first thing
it does is convert the right hand side
to this you know this short syntax to
the fully nested form. So in wufam
language in fact everything is is this
fully nested like most people don't know
you anyway so I was talking about so if
you go back so
check so then list macros so list got
macros wuam's got the full feature
pattern matching so in other words in
wuan language in fact the entire program
is computes by pattern matching okay all
the all these you see are in fact
actually um
well not here but most like half of the
code in Wuam language is pattern
matching in other words think of this
where most of your code is is written in
in this macro style okay that's that is
wam language
full pattern matching not just like this
maros like idiots this list this are
really like idiot idiots.
I really despise the common especially
the common lispers. They are like idiots
and but but the reason they are you see
they are not the original Lispers like
the John McCarthy which I respect but
today's Lisper the the common lisp
phonetics they are like idiots okay they
don't know about functional programming
they think oh you need object you know
like lisp object system oh that's so so
so good you the common
lispers Okay, they they don't know what
the you know they they up every
good idea of John McCarthy, the creator
of Lisp.
Okay, that's what I'm saying.
Okay, so so you got this uh so you got
to read that. So read uh watch that and
so I was did I finish that? I think
that's it. Okay. So this article every
comparison about lisp and wuang language
is here and
uh then then I show you actual every
every detail like the syntax on the left
hand side on the left you see this
nested par on the right you see the
bracket you know the nested bracket
comments then expression grouping in
this you have prog n in wam language
it's called Compound expression more
logical name. Okay, not prog like what
the is prog end compound expression
logical name that applies to every wam
language name or the short syntax is
just semicolon.
You see this semicolon here? You see you
see that semicolon that's actually short
syntax for compound expression. You see,
you know, this is like advanced, you
know, you wouldn't know until you dive
deep into wam language. You see that
semi semicolon that actually is
equivalent. You can rewrite this
by changing that you know this line into
into the compound expression. Okay? And
then square bracket then then then this
line. Okay? then you don't need a
semicolon at the end.
So, so, so for example, this this this
part and then this part they are like
part of the compound expression. So,
they so instead of semicolon you use a
comma to separate that that and that.
Okay. So, that's you know
um do I make sense? Like
okay. So let me show you again this for
those you haven't seen it. We we did
this today. Fantastic re refraction
reflection of light rays and this on the
fly code formatting. Okay,
not just
programming code but
type set mathematics and on the-fly
formatting of type set mathematics.
Okay, these technologies began in Wuam
language in 1996.
Wuam language Mathematica version 3.
Okay. And to this day in the industrial
coders the C C++
idiots and tech latte these idiots they
don't have this okay like they actually
never seen it in their life.
The Python idiots. Okay. So anyway, and
the the common dispers
because I've been trying to tell the
common lipers this about 30 years ago.
Every time I do, they will attack me.
They will say, "No, you are just a
troll. You don't know nothing." You see,
I I started my life coding wolf and
language. Then I got very interested.
Why am I in into this? because you know
I'm into computer AI you know that's you
know so they are all related in fact it
so happens that wuam is actually part of
lisp so I started to learn lisp and I
got you know questions about why why is
lisp you know why do you have cons why
you know how come you are not consistent
how come you you know uh so I talked to
the dispers then you you know well part
of it is because I don't I'm not a um
like nice and polite like social kind of
person. So they they they they call me a
troll. They don't but but part of it is
that they just don't know. They don't
know. They don't understand. They they
are the they are like the industrial
coders the C and C++. They don't know
the the essence the the why why is John
McCarthy list the creator list created
uh uh evolution like they don't know you
know these people.
So they anyway so that's I think okay
that's it.
coffee says, "I still got Wuam 9 on my
old computer." Wow. Amazing. Wuam 9.
Now, what that what year is that? That
is that um
Wu 9. Is that 2008 or something?
I know plenty of common packers who
don't like claws. That's okay. That's
good to know. I I despise that
common dis object system clause because
like every time you talk like every time
you talk to the common dispers
2012 okay like every time you talk to
the common dispers like a lot of them we
all mention this command this object
system idiots that them you
know lisp is not supposed to be object
oriented but this commonist fanatics
like they they don't know they think
object It's good good thing. them.
So I I I so I you know I very despise
you know I I don't get alone with a lot
of these
you know the lipers.
I can understand part of it is just
because my personality okay but part of
it you know they are like idiots.
Okay. Okay. Bye guys. That's it. Um,
also, did you see Orin SA's work on on a
rape polymorphism?
Uh, no. I know. I know that guy. What?
You know what's up. Did he do like he's
um, you know, he created um
Skim Shell, you know, or Lyn
Shivas, he created Skim Shell. Uh but I
don't I don't hear any news from him
like in the past 10 or 20 years. Is he
still teaching at you know it must be
very old by now.
Uh thank you for the stream. Thank you
guys. Bye guys.
Bye guys.