good evening my name is Safi this is our
talk show you are listening to and
today's date is September 14th 2019
Saturday Saturday is the day where
everyone have fun okay welcome to
Startalk show and what is today's topic
we don't know I don't know and you don't
know and nobody is here yet okay and if
nobody is here then then we are going
just going to talk about random okay
there's one guy watching say hi please
type something and pick a topic now if
not no one's here I'm just going to talk
about random things
there's keyboards they actually there
are some things I want to say
oh good morning Quinn deck how are you
green deck hi to russia from USA
actually green deck I was thinking you
know I should take a break I need to I
want to go have a cigarette you know and
come back in five minutes
and so in wait for people to tell me but
now you are here and now we have another
person do I have the luxury of going so
green deck you know green deck tell us
how did you learn English I mean you are
in Russia right and and how are you
roughly good morning Derek okay so now
we have people coming okay I should be
back okay I I be back in in in form in
four minutes okay should I
yeah okay I'll be back in four minutes
but you guys pick a topic for today
you know let's stop you know let's talk
about something you know pick a topic
and let's talk about that okay great
fantastic and greentech I wanted I
wanted to know you like what you are
twenty studies and or 40s you know and
and how did you learn English did you
ever travel outside of Russia you know
that I like to know you know if you
don't mind that is okay so I will be
back in four minutes I be back I'll be
back in for me
CSS SVG or math would be fun okay that
would be the topic today okay see you
guys in four minutes okay in four
minutes maybe I should play some music
sadly music now this let's play Bach's
well-tempered clavier the greatest fugue
on earth okay music symbols for Champloo
no Persian blue is not what we want
Chopin versus least that's a sa that's a
satire now let's go to piano and that's
got well-tempered clavier number four
okay this is a greatest career
and let's play actually let's play
number well-tempered clavier book one
filk number eight this one okay and
let's play by this guy
cool down okay in its fear
you
I am back what you have heard the first
part is pre lived well tempered clavier
pre Lee Prelude number 8 and this part
the second part this is the fugue number
8 and this puke is one of the greatest
piece of music in it who acts your brain
it gets you beautiful music yes that's
that's those are very well known pieces
you know most famous fugue of Bach so
let me be the comments and maybe then
and then we talk about CSS SVG or math
or math now we have not talked about CSS
before I suppose because that's neo CSS
technology it's technology that the
hacker types they sneer you know they
don't think of it too much and usually
it's by designers you know designers
typically female you know women they
yeah typically they you know they do CSS
and CSS like HTML it's very simple it's
very simple to do simple things but then
it gets extremely complex more complex
in HTML it gets really really extremely
complex when you want to actually do a
website like like you go to website
today for example YouTube or even my
webs my website my website is you see I
I am what you might say a minimalist ok
so I don't I don't put a huge amount of
tag HTML tags or CSS you know look you
can look at my CSS file this is the file
and this is this file is 800,000 kilo
but you know 8.5 Quique 8.5 k so eight
thousand nine nine thousand characters
by today's standard this is very small
CSS file now you can see the file let me
show you
you know pitch down pitch down pitch
down you know this is my CSS file pitch
down you know seven pages 509 lines but
if you go to youtube for example and if
you look at their CSS or in any website
Stack Overflow Wikipedia Twitter
Facebook medium any website they have
like I would say let's see
so my CSS file is only Nike okay they
are CSS file is like 30 K at least
30,000 characters at least minimum and
extremely complex
pretty much unreadable CSS I mean even
me having just you know 500 lines of CSS
that's already fairly complex I mean
because you know anyway that's CSS CSS
if you guys don't know comments okay
guys comment if you guys don't know CSS
is this technology let's go through my
CSS website okay I have a website a
tutorial of CSS I name it visual CSS
meaning that many of the CSS effect you
can actually see for example you have
CSS animation yes you can do animation
with CSS and you have this transition
you see if I move my mouse over it it
because it's a kind of do an animation
so so let's click on that and if I move
my mouse over here you see that's how it
works
I mean that's that's affect CSS
animation and you can animate you know
quite a lot of things
for example yes it is kind of neat you
know it's kind of neat
but in practice this is rarely useful I
mean so CSS stands for cascading style
sheet and the primary purpose is just
for styles like visual styles the trace
placement position the font you know
things like that so I have it I have
this CSS tutorial and if you have never
studied CSS this is a good beginners
starting point okay I show you all the
most fundamental or the basics of CSS
like I said CSS is very simple for
example you begin you begin at okay
begin not there begins so at the bottom
there is a panel index of articles you
begin with the CSS basics this page so
that I tell you what it is about how to
use it you know the very basic the first
lesson you can understand it in few
minutes then you progress to you know
other things you know like color like
radio gradient this fantastic video
gradient let me go to the chrome ok just
such folk sorry CSS I have Firefox off
over here so I mean the JavaScript is
off on my Firefox that's why you don't
see actions but let's go through sauce
visual CSS sorry you have fancies things
fancy things such such as this radial
gradient now I this is actually actually
a JavaScript application that generates
the CSS code you see here that's a CSS
code corresponding to this you can you
can use random random random and you
know three colors
or seven colours to colors and you can
change color let's say let's change
color to red bright red okay so I want
that's big bright red you know and it's
interactive so you can actually you see
you can actually it changes right away
in real time and you can see the CSS
code they also change in real time you
see so let's go to yellow let's go to
red you know so it's nice so this this
one is about CSS Radio gradient meaning
that you can color something in like
this you know like a radio smooth change
of colors or these are examples for
example if you want this here is a code
here's a CSS code so that's one of them
you know then you have linear gradient
linear gradient let's say rainbow random
linear gradient is common very common
for example if you are using Windows
Vista or Windows you know Windows 10 or
something you typically the windows top
border will look like that and in fact
let's do a window border okay so let's
see so if you want if you want to
emulate the windows you know windows
windows back in 2010 something like that
in Windows Vista you can say let's say
two colors and the first color will be
blue okay and then the second color will
be red okay that's kind of the window
Vista is that right is it red or black
or white something I forgot any one
member say it okay and also you can
change the direction like random
direction you see
anyway so that oh these these are my CSS
tutorials and you can do animation you
can you know lots of things
so maybe yeah we talked about that a
little bit so who asked that who asked
that let's see Derek
good morning Derek so direct yachty so
Derek if you have specific questions
like you know I don't know if you know
CSS before or you never learned it if
you never learned it then maybe we can
start from the beginning I talked about
it basic tutorial if you know about it
already then if you have specific
questions then you know just post you
know like I don't know where to go so
let's see the comments meow cat
good morning male cat I was here since
one hour before he started guess it's
not showing views properly viewers
properly oh okay
and again male cat you know contact me
through email you know it's it's tough
it's talk on video milk milk add is a
friend so so green deck says I'm in my
twenties did not travel a lot learned
English since early childhood but most
of my skills I think I got from the
internet oh the great internet but I
don't think that my English is any close
to being good okay so I'm guessing you
read English well but you don't speak it
so well that's typically the case for
Chinese or for that's typically the case
for nerds for programmers you know you
can you can read and learn things you
know you read and learn another language
but you don't speak well because
speaking and listening is entire
different skill than reading and writing
so Sam Tong says Hika
hi Sam Sima says howdy howdy
Seema's way way are you from CMAs and
male cat where are you now
okay green DX is green decks says it's
it's if it's important in Russia
everybody in school learn English or
German French okay but that's not very
successful for example in school I
learned French for eight and I know only
a couple of words okay
Derek says for you in for your
information I'm watching you from Roku
TV
okay what is Roku TV and at luck and had
to login for my phone to comment I may
or may not go grab the MacBook but it's
cool to watch television
yeah you sit in your couch you know you
know what you should get this okay today
o Simas is from New York right and meal
card is still in Romania male cat is in
Romania now male cat is originally from
Canada right I don't I don't think you
might you know nobody know who you are
you are me okay you know cat is
originally from Canada and you're still
in Romania Wow
so what we're gonna do that's right yeah
that's right so what we so you know
Casali keyboard there is this thing okay
let's see let's go to Saudi keyboard and
let's go to PC keyboards and let's look
at let's look at this one okay wait who
is it yeah okay so let's go through
miscellaneous
and and
[Music]
they Derek so Derek you need to buy
these on the couch
you need to buy these on the couch
keyboard and mouse now this is of course
of gamers interest you know game lovers
thing yeah well I guess if you see in a
couch often then that guess and you need
to play first-person shooters
I don't think you're due well he hope
you dead doing that well for adventure
games yeah but on the other hand if you
doing adventure games then you don't
need a mouse you can use the controller
anyway you know so people sell these
things Roku TV so so what is what could
he be so should we actually should we
start to talk about CSS so simisage I've
done CSS before it's okay for colors in
layout the rest of CSS I don't think I
ever get used okay let me mention
something about CSS okay you know in CSS
okay what's what's real good TV I guess
it's just a TV Dhin now is roku a brand
name or what let's see what could
streaming players and Smart TV oh it's I
guess it's just a brand name right yeah
is it's just you know like a lot TVs you
buy today they have they are called
Smart TVs meaning that they connect to
the internet so they are you know you
can you excuse me
you can watch Netflix and Amazon video
stuff from your TV now me as a loner as
a single you know single old man I don't
have a TV and well actually I don't have
a TV since year 2000 and also I have not
watched TV for 20 years you know
eliminate those
thought-control totally cut off that cut
cut off the cable you know they don't
even they don't influence me now this is
part of the reason I'm a little bit
strange because for average people let's
say America you know because I'm
American I live in America so average
people for example in America they they
watch TV every day you know most people
well and well TV kind of gradually
declined but instead of you have phones
you know every teenager every every you
know boy girls is watching the phone all
the time
that's a TV replacement and today the
Internet has kind of become TV like
YouTube you know they are they are
becoming just like TV before so anyway
so I haven't watched TV since year 2000
and you know and typical typically
everyone America for example you well I
guess you know most people watch TV oh
you watch your phone all the time and if
you don't watch TV if you are someone
who don't do that then you're thought
your opinions on everything is gonna be
slightly different from the mainstream
because that's because that's that's
what TV does I mean that yeah that's
well because you know everyone is you
know they're what they see everyday what
they hear does not matter what they
actually think but the fact that they
are seeing all these kind of things you
know every day it it gets into your
brain you know that is why when you grew
up in different places you have
different view of the world if you are
if you grew up in Russia in China in
Middle East you know in America in Japan
you have your perception of things are
different so if you don't watch TV well
actually don't watch TV is a good thing
okay
but it's a for most people it's hard to
do because because everyone else is
watching it your brother your sister
your mom your
that is watching it every day TVs at
your home you grew up you wake up the
TV's on you know you even you don't try
to watch it but it song it's faying and
occasion and then your friends your
roommates you know they all want TV they
watch it and sometimes they talk about
it even you don't want to but you cannot
help
I mean wait this is suppose your friend
you know say oh oh look at this you have
to look you know because otherwise you
are rude so that's hard to cut off yeah
so that's about TV so anyway so let's we
digressed and let's go back to the
comments and see what we have and we've
have been talking for 30 minutes already
well okay so this is our talk show
today's talk talk and talk so a
beautiful music male cat so generate so
appropriate so male cat so Russia so I
saw you learn English by yourself
or I guess by yourself green deck okay
that's because yours is handwritten
whereas there is made automatically by
unhinging
[Music]
and Roku TV I guess Seema says I've done
CSS before it's okay okay okay yeah so
let me talk let me tell you this about
CSS now you see CSS it's designed for
basically for appearances for changing
for example all these CSS effects now
when you did when you use CSS you can
almost categorize CSS into two parts one
is all this very easy to understand
visual effects such as color opacity you
know like transparent color so you can
you can specify opacity and this here is
an example we have a background image
let's see let's magnify okay that
doesn't work well so anyway you see this
screen they are at different levels of
opacity meaning transparency okay and
the syntax is this you know the syntax
is this so and in practice in real life
I mean the actual code looks like this
for example this one says any paragraph
tag you know HTML paragraph P tag with
the class X then you want to color it by
this color RGB you know value for red
green blue then the last argument is
opacity so one is opaque you know if you
say one it's totally not transparent so
if you say zero it becomes it becomes
completely transparent so anyway this is
one one of the CSS thing opacity so I
was saying CSS you can divide them into
two categories one category is what you
would call visual effects such as color
opacity you know linear gradient radial
gradient parks shadow here here is
example of box-shadow you can generate
it randomly you can use inset random
color random color you can increase the
offset let's say you know you know you
can do things like that and change
change the direction
oh let's let's see offset let's say that
okay
then you can change the direction you
know so so all these all these are very
easy to understand
they are just visual effects including
animation
well the syntax for animation is a bit
more complex but anyway what I'm talking
about is they are all visual back
box-shadow
you know box shadow so you see this is
actually not image this is text for
example you can copy it copy go to Emacs
new buffer paste okay and in large you
know this these are actually Unicode
Unicode characters for example this
character let's call described cha okay
then this character the name is
mathematical Franco small a okay
and the code point is is over here it's
1 2 0 0 9 4 ok so anyway this I that's
that's unicode character but anyway this
is not image it's just text for example
let's see if we can change
do we have a text box I should have a
text box anyway so you see you can
change the blood let's see make it big
you know sharp hand blood okay so all
these are visual effects now
that's one part of CSS now there's
another part of CSS is wait a second
oh so we show of also the other part
about visual effect is like underlying
over line you know underlying over line
strikethrough
these are also visual effect very easy I
mean the concept is very easy to get and
you also have board you know for example
both text then you have letter spacing
for example you can do that and you know
so so all these are visual effects we
the concept is very simple now that's
one category of CSS now the other
category is layout so what do you mean
for example for example if you look at
this page you see I have a panel on the
Left I have kind of a main column in the
center then I have the right column
that's for ads and also I have a top top
row that's ads okay so that's one of the
layout and also I have you know these
boxes and then I have boxes here so
that's that's about layout now if we go
back to YouTube you can see YouTube you
know this page has its own layout layout
for example he has this box at top then
this box then this you know so layout is
actually the most critical and practical
for webpages not so much for visual
effect you know all this color
you know you rarely see people do all
these colors you know that yeah color is
still important for basic use but you
know you rarely see it's so oh these
they they look fancy and they stand out
they are dramatic but they are not they
are not actually in real life they are
not that useful compared to the layout
now this section are tutorials about how
to use CSS for layout and they are
actually the most important should we
should we go to another website to check
the layout for example this tuk-tuk go
such you know it also have a layout for
example the top is a white row then then
then you have a column that's not so
wide and also remember this layout
changes for example on this page I can
for example let me show you this weight
let me show you my CSS page first
so my CSS page if you change the window
size now watch watch the change of the
layout as I adjust the window size okay
here we go
this is small smaller smaller smaller
smaller you see they auto adjust name
whoops you see the right column is good
let's go back right column now the right
column is good
okay now let's keep shrinking keep
shrinking keep shrinking woo the left
column is good you see this is what they
call with responsive design of course
you use CSS to do this and this and this
the
is all about layout so why do you need
that for example when you are on a forum
let me show you okay
you know when you are watching this page
on the phone you you know then you want
a different layout that that is mostly
why on the other hand some people you
know cameras they have you know war
sized TV screen Oh like if you are
watching on TV then you may want a
different layout so that's so that's all
about layout let me show you the phone
hold on a second let me show you a what
is this okay hold on second so let's
press that yeah so now we are seeing we
are looking at this page on the phone
okay this is actually bad because you
see this empty column on the right
that's not what you want you want so
this is actually bad I you know I
probably should go fix it let's try
iPhone 6 iPhone 7 okay now it's good
okay so for iPhone you know it's very
tedious you see you can see your example
now for iPhones iPhone 6 7 8 works
I know it works wait hold on a second
let's go back well anyway you get idea
so you want to change the layout because
you know different screen sizes so back
to what I was saying back to what I was
saying so CSS you can kind of categorize
CSS into two parts one is all visual
like these state they look great they
look fancy and they are pretty easy to
understand you know you can see what
they are about on the other hand the
layout that's actually more more
important and and also
they are extremely difficult to
understand why that's just because the
design of CSS they are rather fairly
involved to actually understand then
well you know have you guys seeing a
comic on the web you know kind of viral
comics let me show you okay let's show
you okay let's see where are they oh-oh
that's Google showing my other web pages
okay so what is this ad okay let me show
you this comic okay but before we do
that let me read the comments now remind
me to show that comic and keep the
comments going okay so good morning web
that we have tag web dog we have dog
so gradient green that beautiful music
that's because you know kind of the
entire painting maokai says I've seen
entire paintings emulated with gradients
yes I have seen that too you know there
are some people who went crazy with CSS
for example have used use you see Mona
Lisa right the classic painting Mona
Mona Lisa now typically you do that well
we stick with a pen or image right it's
an image but people have tried to use
CSS to emulate that so it's extremely
calm complicated it's like you know
programming language see up first
occasion competition you know you create
this in unreadable code and minimal like
golf you know minimal you know just few
lines and it does something incredible
and it's impossible to read you know up
first occasion so people have created
Mona Lisa painting or some other
paintings with CSS itself nothing else
you know so that's that's you know
that's kind of a major hack incredible I
don't like those things at all
so actually let me just go to the page
that shows the okay let's go to excel
code homepage and let's go to
programming blog okay then let's go to
on the left side there is a design web
design over here okay now you guys seen
this this this comics this being viral
for a few times I think this picture is
at least 10 years old now it's a joke
you know do you do you get it you see
because CSS a CSS is awesome but you
know the awesome went outside of the box
why because this is a common happening
when you try to do CSS you know when you
try to create your own blog or website
this happens a lot because you know that
like that's why I said you know CSS the
layout part is rather hard to understand
it's it's rather pretty hard to
understand you have to you have to study
it you know really focused and study it
for you know sometimes days that
depending on which part you know dude
there are so many CSS what you call tags
or whatever they call it
you know properties so anyway that's why
you have this this gun viral you know
it's all over the place because people
can feel it this happens often like you
know you like you say okay picks up the
width is 300 pixels but then the text
went outside where does that happen then
you have to do some other techniques you
know you have to go to stack overflow
how do you fix that you know in this
case it's called shrink box you want a
shrink box typically typically you can
fix this by using a table like this rate
table okay so that's all about for
example I explained the display property
here typically when you say
display table then then they'll fix that
problem but however this tray table has
other problems
the other problem scraps quarter so
that's that's about CSS this happens
often so CSS when it comes to layout
it's fairly complicated fairly
complicated so anyway a ver tutorial so
you can you know read them we could go
over it let's see what let's see the
comments okay so I never used Vista okay
you know Cass says it's increasingly
common to generate your CSS not to write
it manually yeah you know people do that
there are so many CSS libraries now
there is one that's the most popular
does anyone remember the name type it
web dawg you you probably know what
what's the what's the most popular CSS
framework I forgot the name you know I
don't use them because I know CSS inside
out I
I watched CSS grew up from nothingness
you know CSS began this the idea in
specific specification began around 1998
something like that but it was never
used in you know it didn't become
popular until let's say five years three
years later bootstrap yes thank you
Chinese Stefan Chinese Stefan good
morning web dog says post CSS oh I
haven't heard that one but anyway boots
bootstrap is the most popular CSS
framework you know I I meant to look
into it but I never did you know I I
watched CSS go up and the first five
years of CSS I don't pay it I didn't pay
attention because I think that that's
crap that's for designers that's not for
real programmers you know I am a real
programmer
I don't do CSS okay but until I think
until 2005 let's see which one let's
let's look at one of my earliest article
on CSS then I'll know what's the date I
started - anyway it's around 2005 or
2006 I started to learn CSS because by
that time it's inevitable I mean if you
want to create a website page you have
to know CSS and today you have to know
well you cannot do JavaScript or
anything you cannot create web page
without knowing CSS and in fact you have
to know CSS as well like you have to be
a master of it to create for example
this website even you know I have all
this to create for example just just
this page very simple you have to know
CSS you know you have to know how to
create that and you in fact you have to
learn you have to read a page that tells
you how to create three column layout or
you know and also CSS over the past ten
years they have grown grown and grow and
grow now it's like JavaScript now like
every year they have new things every
year they have new things like you
cannot keep up you know just like
JavaScript you cannot you cannot keep up
anymore because they you know that they
come up with new new things every year
and you know then you have to check
which browser implements that so you
know it's like the thinking is that it's
going to go forever you know it's gonna
be more and most of CSS so today you
cannot you know write the web page
without knowing CSS at all so CSS if you
do web coding in front and you have to
know CS as well and most people for most
people today well they just use
bootstrap right the bootstrap is a CSS
framework just like in JavaScript you
have react yes you have angular you have
you know a bunch of others and many of
today's fun end programmers they don't
really understand JavaScript and Dom but
rather they just they just know react
changes you know
rely on the frameworks so in the same
way you know you don't really have to
know master CSS you could just rely on
bootstrap and they are quite a few you
know they like all these frameworks they
are cutthroat they are competing with
each other you know each each one you
want to say oh use me use me use me
having the most popular you know things
like that you know oh and the other one
a newcomer says no use me
don't use that because I'm new and I'm
the the most modern I'm the most minimal
you know that's so you know they are
competing all the time
CSS frameworks JavaScript frameworks you
know they and they they they tend also
to come and go like this you know every
three years something will be very most
popular after three or four five years
they becomes less popular some other
becomes more popular so for me partly
because I'm getting old so I don't use
those I don't use any of these
frameworks I kind of despise them okay
you know the bootstrapping what not crap
you know I code I code HTML manually by
hand and I code my CSS manually by hand
you know so this is for example this is
my website on top here is the CSS and
you open it you see the CSS code I know
every every character what they mean you
know I know them well and yeah so that's
that's me you know but if you are
younger generation you probably you know
using the frameworks is inevitable if
you work in a company ok because it's
kind of and it's almost actually
necessary as well I mean for me I'm just
a single person I'm doing my own website
so I don't have to I don't work with I
don't have to work with people right but
in a company you have a team of 10 you
have team of 1000 you have several
departments
it's kind of necessary to use a
framework so you have JavaScript
framework you know bootstrap you know
it's kind of necessary on the other hand
if you you know but but still you should
if you really want to know what you are
doing if you aspire to be a great
programmer if you envision one day you
are going to create your own framework
then you'll absolutely need to know CSS
well inside out you know they're like
you can you can begin starting by by
reading my tutorial and similarly for
JavaScript my JavaScript in depth and
and my Dom my Dom tutorial you know
these are all necessary or or do not
require any framework you know other
application I wrote do not use any
framework it's just good old JavaScript
done in a functional programming style
elegant code minimal and the fast faster
than all the other website faster than
you know whenever the moment you use a
frame framework CSS or JavaScript the
moment you use it your code is going to
be five times slow doesn't matter what
you do because that's because that's
framework that's the job of remote
because they generalize they make things
easy but then they have to they have to
compute you know all the different cases
you know that you know you have
trade-off so if you know the stuff if
you know any technology well you tend to
not want to use any frameworks because
you know the stuff you can code it
yourself and you have more flexibility
you have more power you have more
control you have more elegant code and
so on ok so that's about that's kind of
meta comment about CSS so what what were
you talking about so we talked about
that we talked about that we talked
about let's go back to CSS and see what
else and park and
YouTube okay let's go get back to
reading comments
okay so more comments and design so you
know cats so someo castes handlebars ejs
yes yes handlebars is what handlebars is
a CSS library right framework or was a
JavaScript I forgot reading CSS is slow
and dangerous
not really not if you know what you're
doing
let your templating engine read it and
fix the templating engine and then when
there is a problem you know fix it no
well you know that's no that's not what
I would would do you know yeah you could
use those frameworks they allow you to
modify it you know modify the templates
and so on but it's more work and it's
not less it's less flexible anyway yeah
so what that's using framework right if
you want to use framework and in fact
it's inevitable in your company use it
but on the on the other hand you know I
don't use them I'm saying that you do
also you'd it's important that you also
master CSS and the ability to create CSS
is a is a great asset it's a great power
that because you know those who wrote
you know because if you don't know CSS
you cannot write those frameworks you
know what wait what do you think they do
you know they you know the job when they
write a framework they don't use another
framework because you know it's like
recursion infinite recursion to Abi's
they have to know the stuff the real
vanilla CSS you have they have you have
to be a master of CSS then you create
bootstrap you have to be a master of
JavaScript and Dom then you could create
a reactor yes or angular things like
that so you know that's that's my
preference to noticed of the raw stuff
well and design is the most use now oh
and design and because it's a
react component components okay now it
seems you wrote you own CSS because you
wanted to practice CSS and as I say some
exercise no that's not true if you were
writing for a kind you would have
generated today no that's not true okay
so let me check the previous comments I
missed so it's importing in Russia and
so I've been seeing this before it's
okay for color saying they are so CMOS
any particular questions you have about
CSS or comments or interesting things
like that we can talk about so in your
case I guess you just need more practice
you know you just need more practice you
know CSS is kind of boring actually I
mean like yeah I did I mean there's not
not much to it
I mean for example for layout for
example that for example this thing
position the position property statics
related fixed absolute this is fairly
complex to understand so I could do a
tutorial on this I could you know to so
you understand exactly how they walk but
today is kind of too late because we're
already talking for one one hour it
would be nice if we begin maybe next
time
if you are interested you know you know
say this then we talk about that but in
general CSS is kind of boring you know
like you know you just like like border
for example this is most simple example
you have all these you know you can have
all these folders so the years are code
that's all you say you know border:solid
two pixels read okay that's the most
simple border you know that that is
almost that's all that there's not much
to you know expand
so CSS yeah so CSS to master CSS
actually require you doing it everyday
you know for example you try to design
different layout for a website you know
you like because once you do then you
are running into this then you then
you'll get these then you will say oh my
god how'd you know this is very
interesting because this this this
happens all the time like every time let
me tell you my experience okay every
time I try to modify some CSS on my
website
this happens every half a year you know
because something is not right I need to
for example you know this I need to move
to the left or something I do this every
half a year every time I think oh this
is gonna just be 10 minutes it turns out
several hours really because I thought
you know I I'm just gonna you know
change this you know how it looks you
know it's gonna be ten minutes I just
adjust some size then this happened you
know then you try to find out what does
that happen then you try to you know you
just do experiment you know like you
started to you know Oh marching is wrong
you know you change the marching oh the
you know which is wrong you change the
width it doesn't walk like you do this
then after three hours after one hour
still doesn't work then you then you
realize oh I need let's go to stack
overflow then you go to stack overflow
you read it then you try it you know
four hours this happens every time every
time I try to do CSS that's how that's
how convoluted CSS is when you get into
the details like I mentioned before you
know the visual parts like oh this color
border that's easy
okay that's easy but the layout part
kiasu the layout part this happens it
kills you and and this is why does this
happen this is because CSS the way it's
designed of
rafi is really just it's not so good
okay plus it's over like not we have
like 20 years of CSS almost 25 years of
CSS they are not in many ways just just
like a programming language you know
they have watts you know they have bad
design like in like 20 years ago in in
year 2000 people cannot possibly imagine
what we are doing with Internet they
could not possibly imagine they did not
see the phone coming
I mean well in some sense they did but
they don't did they didn't see what we
are doing today so 20 years ago back in
year 2000 you know they are thinking oh
CSS is just going to be for you know
header you know chapter header the in
section header you know how you know
like very primitive is entirely
different from they they have never seen
today's concept of single page
application that's the thing they didn't
envision it you know back then to 20
years ago they are thinking the way they
are envisioning CSS is that you know
it's it's for a book you know chapters
sections paragraph how you want to move
the paragraph you know the width and so
on that that's what they are thinking
they did not imagine for example let's
go to youtube youtube you know let's go
to typical youtube they didn't in not
imagine this this thing coming up you
know this well my youtube you know and
then you see use this you have this menu
this interactive menu then you have you
know they did not imagine this or if you
go to amazon you know that's out of the
imagination so CSS was not designed like
that for the for this this before it was
you know the the core is entirely
different but that's life you know
that's life so you know
then we have named around 2010 we have
some kind of way other ways then today
we have today's situation you know where
AI is doing things we have Google become
Evo and we have phone we have all the
other things so anyway so all this
remember all these are done with CSS
this this interactive menu for example
with CSS I think it's it's CSS by itself
now now we carefully look at when how
the menu pops up now I move the mouse
there this animation
watch you see there is actually an
animation so the whole thing is CSS at
BAM pretty sure there is no JavaScript
involved how do you do that back to the
CSS fundamentals here animation so I
show you the fundamentals how you do the
animation so so actually that is not
about animation that that interactive
menu that is about using transition you
see this transition okay so you see
that's how it's done
so you you learn about so you learn
about this transition from this page
then you learn about and also look at
this button this 3 pass that becomes
popular about about 10 years ago using 3
bars to stand for menu that is actually
also pure CSS you know you use CSS to
create those shapes 3 bars and it's
rather very complex so for example if
you go through my back to my page I have
a page that explains that I think I
removed a link it's kind of a hack okay
it's you know CSS people do all kind of
things
CSS you know anyway I used to have a
link but I removed a link that is you
you can use CSS to create all kind of
shapes for example for example this
thing this thing this thing or the three
bars or the YouTube logo you could use
CSS to create that so it becomes rather
very fairly complex and in industry
people abuse it all the time because
using an image is usually more expensive
because you have to yeah usually so
people started to use CSS to generate to
create actually create these shapes and
they are websites that dedicated to that
for example just search for CSS widgets
or CSS shapes you will see that you know
you'll find people have created
libraries and in fact yeah a lot you
know you see gets very complex if you go
into detail CSS anyway so I'm saying I
was saying you know all these
interactive things all these are CSS
including I'm free I think okay
including all these icons they are all
CSS so to do this is very involved okay
it's very complex you know on you know
CSS seems simple but to do those things
actually is a hack it's it is a hack
what you would probably you would call
it a hack technically and fairly complex
so back to the comments and and also
today they are tremendous websites
that's about CSS how to like very
specialized like how to create icons you
know it's very complex and also of
course hacker news oh those fonts are
icons sometimes SVG okay yeah you are
right you know like it also like I
mentioned it depends on you like
for example this today for the past
three years
everything is Newton by CSS then the
next five years they changed because
then people find oh that way is better
oh-o-oh CSS now is you know some feature
in CSS is now supported in browsers so
this kind of things change all the time
you know they've been they've been
changing in the past 10-15 years so
similar says CSS only graphics the three
bars were removed now it's just SVG
images okay yeah they'd yeah I know I
you know because I've studied this in
detail like every every few years I did
I look I exam how other pages are doing
things you know every every about this
happens every three or four years for
example you can see that in this page
now this page is a collection of
articles on web design so I dive into
first of all I dive into what what is
the latest style like how people do
layout these days you know this changes
over the past 20 years you know in year
2000 that's one style year 2005 then
taps becomes popular you know remember
tabs amazon tabs ebay tabs apple tabs
you know let's go to apple.com tabs
become popular is that's also you CSS
okay okay now this style now the style
is like that you don't actually have
like tabs but you have this kind of
thing okay
you go to ebay it's a bit different you
go to Amazon it's a bit different okay
but basically every five years they
change you know it's the industry why
they kind of follow southern designs
they change let's go back to my web
design page so on one hand I look at you
know what they I look at the appearance
what have you know what they do what's
the current fashion and and also for
example
what's the expected window size it
changes over the past 20 years like
today for example what do you mean for
example let's look at Apple website now
let's try to shrink the window okay you
shrink shrink shrink shrink oh ok so
Apple no wait it changed okay
so Apple you see Apple the apples
philosophy apple design apples thinking
is that when you have your window is at
this many pixels they decided to change
change the layout
okay now you okay everyone is using
three baths Apple is using two bars ever
is typically the trend setter okay now
Apple is like two bars for the menu you
go to Amazon it's different okay so they
Amazon hey ma gon you know some of them
use flow design like like fluid and why
are others they have more fixed layout
let's try Amazon okay so here's Amazon
okay so tab apparently is out of fashion
you see you don't you no longer see kind
of you know like the browser tabs so you
don't see that but anyway let's shrink
Amazon page let's see what happens
Shing yeah you see you see you see the
text you see the chart the card okay now
when you shrink it becomes hidden you
see now this is a different design
philosophy from Apple this is kind of
more code fixed layout okay so it expect
we when Amazon detect that you are on a
desktop and also using javascript
he knows what your screen size okay so
Amazon's philosophy is that okay now he
knows you are from a desktop he knows
your window size he knows your screen
size
and he decided he decided there should
be a minimal window size when you go
below that you know things just cut off
you know so he expect that everyone on
this table should you know it would be
so this is the minimum width so to speak
but however if you shrink a lot more
let's see what happens okay yeah they
are absolutely they are they are based
on my absolute design you know ABS
what's the proper term is absolute
layout you know they don't they don't
you know which is very different from
Apple they want you to they expect you
to always have this minimal size so you
know so that's about several different
design philosophies all these are done
with CSS okay for example all these are
CSS Apple Amazon and you can look at
their CSS file if you look at their CSS
file basically it's incomprehensible
should we show it or not actually we've
been talking for how long we've been
talking for one hour let's so maybe
let's talk for 10 more minutes okay okay
show it okay so we've been talking for
10 minutes and I haven't answered some
of the questions yet I think and there
are some questions
okay yeah so okay let's show that but
let me hold on a second I want to
explain my page so this page is about
so I serve a web design not just that
okay so first of all I look at the
design also I look at what phones what
font they use for example this page is
my survey of what is the expected
minimal window of size now this one is
written in 2012
okay 2012 Facebook expect you to have
1014 pixels Apple 1014 same for Google
microsoft.com
X you know expect you have 1,000 pixels
yahoo also one thousand 614 amazon 1033
okay and twitter 900 minimum Gmail 994
minimum okay so you know this is my
survey you know I go check their website
and so on and this one is back in 2012
so let's look at the fixed there's
another design issue we talked about
let's say tab okay
survey of tab style 2006 now this alko
you can see all the different websites
tab you know tab came around around
I think 2002 tabs you know desired tabs
because back then its new you know like
as I said CSS evolve evolves over the
past 20 years so every few years you
have a new feature or or you don't have
a new feature but people discovered you
know oh you can do tabs you know people
hack CSS and they discovered you know
they those are called CSS gurus or web
design you know there are many websites
like
you know people discovered oh you can
you know do this or that or sprites or
taps oh so tap came about around 2002 I
think or 2003 maybe then in 2006 I
surveyed you know that that's a date
yeah 2006 that's when I started to study
CSS seriously you know like study every
every part of it
so in 2006 you have these tabs so you
have Amazon looks like that eBay looks
like that
Yahoo looks like that now yahoo is dead
now yeah
companies come and go and Apple looks
like that you have tabs and I have of
course I teach you how to create apps
using CSS this is my page is on my index
CSS index page so anyway let's go back
to the CS then I also looked at
yeah fix layup yeah you know remember we
were talking about absolute layout yeah
the wood is actually fixed a fixed
layout fixed layout versus float the
layout so I was talking about that this
is written back in 2010 well anyway some
of the many interesting issues for
example found serif or sans serif so I
did this one a survey in 2016 I look at
the top you know the most popular
websites I look at whether they are
using serif font or sans-serif so I have
written a report so serif body texts
include websites that use serif for body
for text body includes Wall Street
Journal New York Times Washington Post
LA Times Time mag Scientific American
typically journals and while most of the
websites use sans-serif for body
ok now title font you know title font
like that title is that's a different
story when you design when you do
typography typically the title and body
texts are separate
you know you consider with respect to
fonts so title found you know depending
on our website so there are differences
also I study how they use the font like
what technology like do they use Google
font or do they use what's called CSS
found you know I look into you know you
you you you watch you you watch the
source code you study them so apparently
you know back in 2016 for example New
York Times they are famous for you know
this kind of font Franco so back in 2016
you can see so my question is is do they
design their own or do they use Google
font or do they use image for font or do
they use SVG like so how do they do it
so Wall Street Journal use SVG as well
as New York Times Washington Post Los
Angeles Times us us today
okay us today is not using SVG and
Wikipedia Wikipedia is using PNG okay
the image so anyway so that's how you
know I looked into what they how they
implement you know the technology how
they implement their things so that's
that's all these web design articles are
about there are so many different issues
one of the thing I hate the most is gray
on white gray on white this this became
popular like fifteen years ago or ten
years ago gray on why it becomes a
fashion it becomes part of the boost
bootstrap and all the framework facts
you know that's that what happened
that's what happens gray on white you
know why do people do that because they
look cool you know all these designer
gurus and then programmer idiots they
think this looks cool this looks
beautiful you know going on white it
became popular like ten years ago and
they are these gurus including this
solar right solarized okay very popular
these gurus they are you know doing
talks at Google conference or whatever
they tell you oh we you need to do gray
on why because because look at nature do
you ever do you actually ever see you
know black and white very sharp black on
white no never
if you look at nature you know it's all
in between colors they are gonna tell
you stuff they tell you they want to
tell you what to do but they are like
the most of the earth thing you know I
don't like the designers I don't like
the web designers of guru they are their
thing is usually crap
they are typically designer you know
design gurus okay they have a name like
expert you know but they create crap
don't do grant wait okay look at this
unreadable thing it it depends on your
what device you are using the contrast
you know the your device how old is your
monitor things like that it depends on
lots of things you know if you do it
reasonably yeah it works okay it you
know it's it's good going on right you
know but but what ends up is that on the
whole you know all the words website
typical answer we said you all this
happens unreadable like you cannot read
it it's too bland you know it it's too
bland
that's what actually happens in real
world the audio these you know
frameworks yeah this is part of you know
part of the reason we have this all over
the place like all plugs is because
these frameworks you know these
frameworks they centralized they
centralize everything you know bootstrap
you know the react.js all these
templates yeah also all this like every
website looks the same now if you don't
know like back around 2006 okay oh it's
2005 I was looking for a job you know I
was looking to join to join a startup
company okay so you have lots you know
startup companies usually they have a
website right and often they are written
in Ruby on Rails often so you look at
that you go to their website like every
one of them looks the same they look
exactly the same exactly the same layout
you know actually I should I should go
find a find that one of those site and
so I can show you they look exactly the
same
first of all they are all pretty okay
not like my website you know which you
know you don't see website like mine you
know like oh this is not you know rather
what do you see is you know pretty like
my cat like Apple you know pretty but
anyway you go to all these startup
websites you know they are all trying to
change the world you know over here
where I live you know Silicon Valley you
go today website everyone looks exactly
the same
well first of all they are all pretty so
then that you know they have then you
have you know when you go to a website
you have you know animation some kind of
animation then you scroll down like
Apple kind of like Apple ok and then you
scroll down yeah you see these do you
see all that I don't want to click ok
hold on a second and it's slow ok then
you go down then you see other
animations ok then they then they have
like three or four dots that that lets
you swipe swipe you know switch to the
next okay have you guys seen that you
must have right you know like it
everyone looks the same why do they look
the same because they are all using the
same framework same templates you know
it's framework do you have several
templates for you to choose and you know
they are just brainless you know they
are they have people they don't they
don't know CSS well they you know they
don't know CSS they know the frameworks
they don't then they know how to use
frameworks but that's it they don't know
how to actually how to use CSS they know
they don't know JavaScript but they know
react.js you know they know query jQuery
okay that's what they do they don't
actually understand JavaScript or Tom
but they they use the actuators in
jQuery okay
so every page looks the same you know
everywhere every website you know that's
it's that's kind of funny you don't
realize until you look at all the you
know you look at all the startup
websites you know you know so that's
that's kind of interesting I guess so I
think maybe that's it for today's so if
you have any questions interesting
comments posted right now okay we shut
down maybe in twenty in two minutes okay
okay guys post post post comments and
say goodbye now it's a good time hold on
let me did I
miss anything I want to talk about I
think that's about it yeah so check out
my CSS to tobio okay now let me post it
and also my JavaScript tutorial my dumb
tutorial they are all good they are good
stuff
I spent well by now I must have spent
you know years 10 years writing name so
let me post a link here
that's CSS okay and let's see what else
and here is about web design so let's
first add link to
and let's read the comments and that
would be it for today green deck says
have you seen articles about RMS on base
yes actually I posted that today it's
well let's talk about it some other day
tomorrow or something yeah yeah maybe
that's a that's kind of a controversial
topic because it's about social justice
stuff Oh
Channing hey Channing haven't seen you
before
welcome to Startalk show ha ha so on the
couch yes on on the couch yes I have
YouTube app on roku I don't have cable
ok meerkats YouTube is ho-ho YouTube
YouTube is for homies for noemi's I
prefer something something with my
morning breakfast ok top fan here Derek
okay literally watch YouTube and Netflix
on my TV or streaming thank you guys for
watching thank you guys for coming by
check out my tutorial share it ok share
the link tell your friends let me talk
about simulation Oh simulation argument
that's too late for today sorry
we're dog tomorrow come by early come by
early and say that then we can talk
about that suppose yeah so that's a
that's about the simulation philosophy
argument most people know about that in
the Matrix movie back in 2000 or was in
1999 the first Matrix movie or red pill
versus blue pill but that philosophy
issue is pretty old I think at least
back to the cards in 1500s about whether
in
whether you are in a dream like how do
you know you are actually in a dream
country you know you are just a dream of
some devil yeah that's that's so angel
I'm not sure that's a first anyway
that's a classic topic of philosophy and
the subject matter is about mind versus
body yeah you can look up on Wikipedia
mind versus body that's part of that
subject matter simulated reality and
today of course today we have AI
technology we have brain and computer
interface although we don't have it yet
but it's on the horizon where we can
just plug we can just plug it in like a
USB ok I need to connect I need to get a
USB T ok the next version now we have
USB you have USB different plugs now
today Apple introduced us PC which is
the latest fashion we need to have us PC
which is faster faster in everything
better better and faster and you don't
have to worry about which side is up and
tomorrow we are going to have you SPD
such that we can plug in I can just plug
in into my brain I can download itself
and then I can close my eyes and I have
I have I have you know I'll be rich yeah
so that's part of the simulation
argument so the question is would you
would you want to do that would you
so would you do you want the repeal
where you get harsh harsh reality and
you have to struggle to make a living or
you rather prefer the blue pill which is
like you just plug in and you live in a
fantasy you have a great life you have a
great wife or girlfriend or husband or
whatever your partner okay today is you
have to say partner you can
say husband and wife that's that's
that's you're gonna be beaten okay so
you can I have a great partner you're
gonna have rich life you're gonna enjoy
stick oh my god stick you know great
stick beef and that's Rubio you know but
but somehow you got a sense that that's
not real so which one do you prefer you
know you can actually do that you know
you just go to a hospital you ask the
daughter you ask you ask a doctor to cut
off your cut off your frontal lobe or
something they are being then you will
be happy you will be smiling all the
time it's like it's like it's like this
okay I got this from a friend
wait let me show my okay so he's like
this name is perfect
I don't know if you can see the smoke if
this is th P dat HP from I've from a
friend and this is the main ingredients
of cannabis and but it's not really for
me I don't even I don't you know it
doesn't it it's it's it's not really
good for me because I don't feel hey you
know it makes you dumb that's what it
does
it makes you done and relax and you know
you just um you cannot you can no longer
think anymore like I cannot do math okay
I cannot think about math anymore I
cannot think about philosophy anymore
like Boop Rufio video what are the
consequences what's the argument yeah
you know you cannot it stops you from
thinking and if you take too much of it
then you're just gonna smile all the
time he's just gonna smile and and that
makes me nervous that makes me very
uncomfortable really actually that makes
me okay so maybe we already actually
it's a week by chance we actually talked
about that topic about you know about
simulation maybe you have some another
thing I mean maybe your question is more
specific or actually I should ask you
what do you think about it anyway that's
it for today
so thank you guys for watching I hope
you guys have a great weekend now this
is great this is a weekend bye guys
peace out
Oh rambha