Good morning, everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Saw Talk Show.
Today's 2020 August night August 29th.
10:00 10:20 in morning San Francisco
time.
So, we had some technical problems with
YouTube streaming because I was
streaming
two streams and you know, because the
streaming keys they got confused.
Because recently Google made a change.
So, anyway, so I hope you guys are
seeing me here.
And we going to start over. So, so we
are going to do it here.
So, are you guys here? Can you guys type
something? Let me know I'm alive.
Alive and well.
So, my audio seems to be doing okay and
my video is doing okay. So, today we are
going to do Emacs Lisp live coding and
here are the topics we going to do.
Okay, fantastic. Finally, it's done. So,
good morning, guys.
Bot Informatic, Renato Renato and
Juhani and George. George and FMS
Informatic. Good.
So, if you have Emacs questions, just
type it in the chat, okay? I'll I'll get
back to it and and I'll I'll try to be
condensed today so we
going to go through what we going to do.
So, we we going to we we going to do a
live coding of Emacs Lisp plus I'm going
to explain what to do.
So, I have a command called
site HTML escape chart to entity. For
example, if you copied something from
the web, you know, you copied a giant
huge chunk of text. Let's say that,
okay? And you you want you know, you
want to put in your blog. So, you open
you know, you you go to your blog page
and you paste it.
But, however, some of the characters
such as uh that, that,
and the ampersand, you need to escape.
You need to say, for example, you need
to change them to less than uh less less
than sign. You need to change them to
that.
And and uh greater than and the for the
ampersand, you need to write it like
that. Otherwise, they won't show.
Because, for example, let's say three uh
greater than one. Uh three greater than
two.
And let's say and AT&T. Okay,
copy that. Close close that. Don't save.
Now, I'm back on my talk show page. Show
in browser. Let's say I paste it here.
Make a paragraph.
You see?
Now, show in browser.
Oh, actually, that shows. But, um
But,
if you have something like that,
something
You see? Something to AT&T. Then, it
does not show. It becomes two and AT&T.
It's incorrect.
So, when you copy paste some a huge
chunk of text, it's tedious to uh
manually change those entities. So, I
have a command that does that. For
example, I press the key
to call the command and it becomes that.
Now, if I go to the browser,
showing browser, you can see this is
correct. So, this is this command is
fantastic.
And this command is called
uh this command is called that. C HTML
escape char to entity.
Which you can also see here.
But, however, there's a
I'm going to modify the command so that
whenever it makes a change, it will
highlight those changes red. So if I
have a giant buffer, let's say I copied
I copied some meaningless, you know,
messages from the web and I put on my
blog.
I call this command, it'll show all the
places that's changed. That's what we
are going to do today.
So let's go to the source code for this
command. So what you do is you
you call the function describe
function
and
type the command name, enter, then Emacs
will show the documentation for this
command. And you just press the tab key,
go to the
file source file where that command is
defined and we are here. We are at the
source code.
So now we are at the source code. I I
want to make a copy,
open a new buffer,
make it larger,
paste it here, okay, smaller. So here is
the code and let's save this as a new
file, okay.
xx_
file the command name and date.el.
So I start my file with xx, that's my
convention for temp file.
So far so good. Type your questions any
questions
Emacs related, you know,
in the chat box. We I'll get to it.
So So we are going to modify this
command
so that we will add highlights.
Okay?
Um
Okay, this is going to be a big task
because I need to explain the code. So
far so good? So far so good, everyone?
You don't need to escape those symbols,
but it's good practice to do so. Well,
yeah, that's true, but you actually do.
Uh you you you do need to change them if
you are uh working with XML or XHTML.
Now, in HTML 5,
you know, HTML 5 is the new version
started 10 years ago. They relaxed the
rule uh such that
So, when do you need to escape them?
Okay, uh
so, when do we need to escape those?
Basically, the characters you you need
to escape are less than equals to sign,
greater than equals to sign, and
ampersand. And when
in XML in XML, you always have to escape
them, always, okay? That's XML or XHTML.
But, in HTML
or HTML 5, you don't have to anymore.
Uh
the case the cases you don't have to is
when
for example, let's say three equal uh
three is less than five.
And
five is less uh five is greater than
two, let's say.
Cases like this, you don't have to
escape them. When when they have space
around those characters, then you don't
need to escape them.
This is valid HTML.
Okay, you can go there's a HTML
validator you can go and check it there.
Right? So, um
Is this a custom CMS or do you use
something like a static site? No, I'm
using plain So, what you are seeing is
uh just plain HTML. There's it's not a
it's not a content management system or
anything like that. It's just
a manually written HTML file.
Uh that's uh basically that's how I work
uh with my website. So, anyway, let's go
back to the command. Let's Let's make it
Let's try to modify this command, okay?
So, here is the command where is Here's
the command.
So, I'm thinking what to do now because
this command
um
this command essentially is doing some
find and replace. It's pretty simple.
You want to find the ampersand character
and replace it by that.
And the less than equal sign replace by
that and greater than equal sign replace
that by that.
And you want to do that for the whole
buffer um
So, what I'm thinking what do we
How do we
Should I explain the whole thing like
What do I do next?
Um
We can actually we we can just
uh write this from scratch. Perhaps
that's easier if I if we just write this
from scratch.
Um hold on a second. So, let me think
think a little bit about this.
It's probably easier
if we write from scratch and explain it.
Shall we do from Shall we do that from
scratch?
Okay, so let's write this command from
scratch. Uh should we do that? Yeah,
let's let's let's write from scratch,
okay?
Okay, let's let's try to do this fast,
okay? Any Emacs questions, just type in
the comment chat, okay? I'll get to it.
Okay, let's define a function. Define a
function let's magnify. Let's magnify,
okay? Define a function.
Yeah.
Okay, define your function and our
function will be name of that and the
documentation string
the doc string here will be something
like that. Replace HTML characters to
entity, okay?
That that that
trim the message to buffer occurrences
if any with position.
Okay, so what So, first of all, we
decide, you know, we are writing a spec
basically when we are writing an inline
doc, that's my habit.
Me So, this is a designing stage of the
command. What exactly do I want the
command to do? So, I want it to once
then the find and replace, you want to
print the message to the message buffer.
And you also
want to
and highlight
highlight changed
parts
in buffer, okay? That's what I want to
do.
And also this command
you know, replace HTML characters to
HTML entities on current current line. I
don't want it current line. I want to
current text block.
Okay?
Then
if universal argument is called first,
then then the replacement direction is
reversed, okay? Let's do that.
Uh this part we don't want. We don't
care.
This part we don't care, okay? So,
for the date. So, that's the that's the
um
That's our documentation.
And let's begin to do it.
Okay.
So, first of all, the first thing we
need to do is to
to find the position we actually want.
Uh let's open a new buffer. Let's go to
the talk show today's talk show. We want
to find a position the region
beginning position and end position
where we want to do the work. So, how do
we do that? So, first of all, we can say
uh region beginning. So, position one,
okay? Position one, position two
set position one equals to region
beginning.
Set position two equals to region end.
So, that's uh beginning and end
positions.
Now,
we got a position. Now, we want to do
find and replace of within that region.
So, what we do is
um
find and replace in that region. So,
first of all, we narrow to region.
Narrow to region. Now, if you guys don't
know
narrow to region, it's a command. It's
very useful command. For example, you if
you have a big file, you can select a
region, then you call the command narrow
to region. Then Emacs will pretend that
whatever before or whatever after
doesn't exist. So, your whole file
becomes, you know, that region you are
interested.
I mean, even if you go to the top of the
buffer or bottom of a buffer, it's still
within that region. Emacs is
you know, Emacs pretends the whole file
is just that region.
So, that's narrow to region. You can
meta X and call that. Uh quite useful. I
use it, you know,
uh several times a week.
Now, once you want to get out of the
narrow-to-region, you call the command
widen, okay? So, you can see uh wait
uh what?
You can see I call the command here. Uh
wait.
Widen, okay? Meta-X widen. That's that
exits the narrow-to-region. So,
narrow-to-region is very useful. So,
anyway, I select So, so I want to call
narrow-to-region in Emacs Lisp here.
Narrow-to-region region one uh position
one position two
so that
you know, we focus on this region.
So, that uh
find and replace does not
does not spill out to uh outside.
But But once you call narrow-to-region,
you also have to say uh save
restriction, okay?
Save restriction.
So, what that does is
you know, whatever
your code is done, when your command is
done, Emacs will revert to whatever the
region user have.
Okay?
So, that's that's that. And now, we
narrow-to-region and now we go to the
beginning of buffer, okay? Go to
char
buffer minimum
uh point minimum.
Point minimum uh
this basically this
moves closer to the beginning of the
buffer, okay?
Now, our cursor is at beginning of
buffer, we want to find do find and
replace.
Uh so
uh we So, so let's do find and replace.
So, what we do is search forward
search forward for the greater than
equals to sign.
Bound, neo, no error.
True.
And count, nothing. Okay? So, search
forward. When it's found,
replace match.
Am I making sense? Is it so good?
Get on the dark web. California
Republic, question. I saw you are having
a couple of keyboards around. Which one
do you use the most? I got myself
Kinesis Advantage 2 a couple of months
ago.
Well, yeah, that's Kinesis Advantage 2.
That's what I use the most.
You know, almost every one of my live
stream I talked about that that
You know, if you go to my website,
Kinesis Kinesis Advantage 2, just search
for that. You will also see a video
review of that. So, anyway, replace
match.
So, go to forward. Replace match, we
want to replace. I'm going to start to
do this quick. Too much explanations.
Uh because we have a lot to do. So,
replace match, we want to replace by
uh
Uh we want to replace by uh this is
greater
uh
greater than sign, okay? And optional
optional, we don't care.
So, that's what we want to do. So, this
part and also
Now, we just change for the less than
sign. Less than sign. And another one
for the ampersand sign.
Okay?
So, that's it. However,
So, you let's So, we go to we narrow to
region then we go to the beginning of
buffer then we do we we search for
greater than equals to sign greater than
sign then replace it. So but however
this only replace one occurrence. You
see that's the thing but but but what we
want to do is replace replace all
occurrences.
So what we do is we add a while
statement.
Okay we just do a while statement.
So while
search
if it's found
replace okay.
That's what you do. So this okay so
similarly we need to add a while for the
rest of the code the rest of the
thing here.
And one more for
Okay.
Does that make sense?
Now we have one two three that's what
yeah that's what we want one two three.
So this we all make find replace
basically that's that's it for the
command but actually we have a lot to
do. So eval the buffer
shrink a bit
let's see let's look at the whole code.
Actually let's go let's remove those
comments so it's more compact.
Okay that's our whole code.
And eval the buffer and let's go back to
our HTML page and let's select this
region
and call the command okay. So what's the
command name?
The command name is
xah html-escape-char-to-entity.
Do it. It looks like it's working.
Showing browser.
Uh no, wait.
What's going on?
Oh, I see what's going on.
You see, so here comes a very tricky
part. This is related to uh find and
replace algorithm. Very tricky.
Do you guys know what's going on? This
because when I was doing this kind of
command like 10 years ago,
uh I got into this problem.
So, basically, what's happening is that
you see So, you have
So, first of all, our our program tries
to replace the less than equals to sign.
Okay, so let's look at our code.
So, our code goes through the beginning
of buffer, then tries to replace greater
than equals to sign.
Then, we
you know, for the whole buffer. Then, we
do the less than equals to less than
sign for the for whole thing. Uh then,
the ampersand.
So,
So, for example, it will change this to
that.
Uh wait. Hold on.
It will change this part to first of
all,
this will be greater than equal this
will become that.
Then, it will do this part. Then, it
becomes
um
Uh wait. What's the character?
Less than equal. Then, uh wait. L
less than less than. Okay, so it will do
that less than sign. Then, it will do
the ampersand. So, it's going to move to
the beginning of buffer, I mean
beginning of the region, then it will
replace all
ampersand characters. That one
and that one and that one by the
ampersand. So so it's going to become
like that.
You see?
You know, so we can try it. So we if we
call it, you see, it becomes like that.
And that's no good because it it it's
doing extra replacements.
That's a problem.
So what is the solution to this? Uh So
the solution is actually
you have to do the replacement twice.
The first time the first round is that
you you replace what you want to find by
some
random number. Okay, so you replace
parts of a text to some random number.
Then you replace those random number to
to to the destination characters you
want to the final uh
replace string.
So so that's a bit tricky. So let's do
it again, okay?
So for example, so in order to do that
I uh see.
Uh
we have to think uh hold on a second. So
Nah, all we have to do is just do the
replace the ampersand first.
Yeah, once yeah, replace the ampersand
first, okay? Eval buffer, go back to our
page.
Undo.
Now select it. Do it.
Do it. That's correct. Yes, that's
correct. Go to browser,
show in browser.
We have it here. That's correct.
Let's try on this part, okay? So, you
have to select it. Go ahead.
Do it.
Wait, undo.
Copy it.
Wait, copy it, paste it here, and do
that. Do that.
So, why is the less Why is the greater
than sign not replaced?
Let's go back to our code.
Oh, yeah, because we we we misplaced the
go to the chart to the beginning of the
buffer, okay? Eval it again. Eval the
buffer.
Go back to our buffer. Undo.
Let's
Let's do it.
Fantastic, it's working.
Oops. Uh
Where is it? Yeah.
Show in browser.
Yeah, so it's working. So far, so good.
Let's see. Uh so far, so good.
We have quite a lot quite a quite a lot
things to do. So, okay, so now now I've
been talking for 20 minutes 25 minutes.
Let's Let's keep keep going, okay?
So, now So, let's let's improve our
code. There are quite a few things to
improve because right now we have to
select region first. It's kind of
annoying.
Uh it would be nice we don't have to,
you know, user doesn't have to select
because when you call the command, we
automatically work on the paragraph.
So, that's what we want to do. So, all
we have to do is we want to modify this
part, okay?
Let's going to Let's modif- modify the
position, the region position.
Um
So, what we say if
if
use region P, okay?
So, what that means if there is already
a region, I mean if user selected a
region
I mean if user selected region
that means, you know, they have this
specific region in mind. They want this
command to work on, then work on the
region. But, if there is no region just
work on the
um just work on the the line the cursor
is at, okay? So, if there is a region,
then we do this, okay? Now, this two
code can be combined into one.
Like that, okay?
There. So, if there is a region, set
position to region beginning and region
end. Otherwise
otherwise, we say
position one will be become uh line
beginning position, okay? Position two
will be line end position. Okay, that's
that's it.
Okay, we can we can actually
clean up the code. We don't need that
part, okay? Like that. Select eval the
buffer, go back to the code.
Uh
go back to the code and let's let's undo
this undo this undo and undo.
Let's get back our code, okay? So, we
have these two examples.
Okay, so let's put the cursor here
call the command
do it.
Fantastic.
Now, this is when we don't have a region
selected. But, however, user, you know,
I'm a user. I I select these two lines,
call the command,
then now it works on the region.
Fantastic.
Go back to the code. Now, we have
something more to improve because right
now it automatically automatically works
on the current line. But, usually that's
not what
There's an improvement. A better way is
to work on the current paragraph, like,
you know, paragraph as defined by
separated by empty lines.
Okay, so let's uh improve improve on
that.
So, if there's a region, work on the
region. If there's no region, we want to
work on the current paragraph.
Okay. Now, there is no building way to
do that.
I don't like this code, okay. Set.
So, set position once.
Okay, so how do you code this? So, if
there's a region, do that. If there's no
region,
what we want to do is set position one,
P1 and P2 to the beginning and end of a
paragraph.
So,
so what we do is we
search backward
for
double lines and
bound nil, no error,
true,
no error, um
no error, true.
Okay.
Um
Okay, we search backward. Now, if I call
something I didn't explain, you know,
you just look look up the doc
documentation, describe function, okay?
You just call describe function and you
can read the detail about, you know,
what parameters I'm using. I'm not going
to explain it. So, anyway, so so we
search backward for two
uh empty lines. Then we
We move character to the right two times
to go to back to the beginning of the
paragraph, okay? Then Then we set
position one
point, okay? That's how you set the, uh,
position.
Okay, prettify the code. Then
now we
search for word
two empty lines, optional bound, nil, no
error, true. Okay, then we
backward char
two
move backward two positions
so that the cursor will,
uh, end at the end of the paragraph
before the new lines, okay? Then set
point
position two
point,
okay?
Prettify the code. Prettify. Prettify.
Prettify.
That's it. So So
So what So what happens here? So this
This code, if this is region, then
you know, P1 and P2 is a region
beginning and end. Otherwise, you move
around the cursor to find the beginning
and end of the paragraph.
Okay?
Eval the buffer. Go back to the HTML
code. Let's So now we going to call the
code. When we call the code, it should
work It should work on both of these
lines. So we call the code. Do it.
Fantastic. Successful.
Now, let's go back to the code. There's,
uh, more things we need to do. Uh,
remember we want We want all the changed
places highlighted. For example, for
example, I can select
uh, these three parts, okay?
Uh, let's do it again, okay? I select
these three parts and call the command.
Do it. You know, there's lots of
changes. I want the command to highlight
all the
uh, places that it changed, okay? Undo,
go back to the code. So, let's let's do
that.
You want to highlight the changed code,
okay? So, what you do is, first of all,
you do the ampersand.
So, you change the ampersand here.
Uh,
replace match.
And how do you how do you make it red?
So, to make it red, we talked about a
few days ago. You If you watch my
live stream cuz our live stream
cuz our talk show
the past five or six episodes, they are
all about Emacs Lisp coding. So, in
fact, we covered this before.
Uh, and right now, let's go to my Emacs
Lisp tutorial, okay? So,
Okay, go to my You can search it. Search
for Emacs Lisp, you'll find it.
And you go to
you go to write a major mode.
Then you go down.
Then you go to overlay overlay
highlighting. So, this is how you
This is how you make it
how you color text. So, this is the code
we want.
So, now back to our code.
Back to our code, the command we want to
call is
this command, overlay put.
It will take three arguments. One of the
argument we will need positions,
beginning and end positions.
So, we need to find the beginning and
end positions of our uh the replacement
we just did.
So, how do you do that? Replace match.
You see, once it once it replaced this
ampersand character here to this
ampersand AMP semicolon.
Now, we want to know the beginning
position and end position of this word
ampersand
AMP semicolon.
How?
Okay, I don't know how offhand, but we
can
um
Of course, we can find out.
Uh I
So, once we do the replace match,
the cursor will be the cursor position
will be at
the end of the replaced text, I'm pretty
sure.
So,
so the end position we want will be
point.
Okay, point returns returns the current
position of the cursor.
And the beginning position is simply the
point minus uh wait.
I got typo. So, the beginning position
will just be
the point
uh wait.
The point uh
the point the current position minus
minus how many characters are there?
1 2 3 4 5, five characters. Uh by the
way, you can you can count characters in
Emacs Lisp by calling the command count
words, okay? So, you can see in the min
in the mini buffer it says five five
characters.
So, here you say five. So, that's you
know, the current position minus five.
So, that's the beginning.
Okay? Then
then you want to say
I don't want to say bold. Can we say
red? I'm not sure. Uh
Let's just try that, okay? Let's just
try that.
Eval buffer. Go back to HTML. Select
this
We don't have to select this. Just put
the cursor here. Call it.
Do it.
Oh, wait. Call the command
html-escape-char-to-entity.
Do it.
No, the highlight is not successful.
Undo, okay?
So, it's not successful because this uh
red is not supported.
Let's try bold.
Bold will work, I'm pretty sure. Call it
again. Do it. No, it doesn't work.
I don't know why. Okay, so um
Let's do this. What is it? Eval buffer,
okay? Did we eval buffer eval buffer?
Let's do it again. Call it.
Uh it's not bold.
Uh it didn't work. Why?
So far, so good?
What is your primary programming
language?
Uh well, I've been programming Java I've
been programming Emac Lisp, Mathematica
Mathematica since 1992, then Perl in
starting in 1998,
then
Python starting in 2004 or 2005,
then JavaScript starting in 2009,
and Clojure and uh and Golang.
Oh, okay. So, that's a good uh Iris says
you don't have ampersand in the code.
Oh, that you are right.
I've been I've I Thank you for that
Thank you so much. I love feedbacks.
Being an idiot. So, okay, let's try it
here. Do it. Yay!
Fantastic.
Now, they are bold. Okay, so let's go
back to the code. Let's try if it red
works. Eval the buffer, go back to that.
Now, we uh wait.
We close the buffer, reopen it so that
all the highlights are removed. You
know, the easiest way to remove
highlight is just close it and reopen
it. So, now we do it again.
Okay, that So, the red doesn't work. So,
back to the here So, the red doesn't
work.
So,
what do what to do if you wanted red?
Okay, it's easy. You go to here. I don't
remember, but you can go to the text
properties here.
I did a talk show on text properties two
two five days ago or so.
So, anyway, the the code you want is
here. Okay, copy it.
Um
Let's
paste it here. The code we want is
actually
this part. Okay, foreground red. Okay,
copy that.
Uh paste it here. and also
let's use font lock face instead of
face, okay?
Okay, so now it's actually, um,
Uh, let let's make it let's put it here,
so
So, prettify the code. So, this part we
will make it red, okay?
Eval the buffer, go back to the code,
let's call it do it. Fantastic, love it.
Undo.
Let's select the whole bunch of things,
do it.
Call it.
And, uh, remove the selection. Okay,
that's fantastic. You see, there's no
ampersand in in here, that's why you
don't see nothing.
So, let's do let's, um, undo, close,
open again, magnify, magnify, go back to
our code. So, we want to do the same
thing over
for the greater than greater
than sign
over here, except that this time
there are only four characters, not
five, okay?
Copy that code, we also want to do it
for the less than equals less than sign.
Okay, prettify the code.
Prettify,
uh, prettify the code, let's see.
Okay, let's
let's prettify the code, let's shrink
them
shrink them.
Eval buffer, that should work.
Eval buffer,
now go back to the to to the HTML here.
Let's talk call it do it. Fantastic.
Now, you see, this is very useful
because because when you when you have
huge chunk of text, you call it. Now,
you see, now all the changed places are
highlighted. So, this is
This is
fantastic.
So, we've done
what we set out to do today.
So, now we can chat something random.
So, Jack Davison, why do you use Mac?
Well, that topic we talked about several
times, like at least twice
on my live stream.
I'm using a Mac right now because I'm I
got a Mac free, okay, in 2000 uh
2017.
Um you know, basically, what you want to
ask your question is which one to which
one should you use, Mac or Linux or
Windows? There is a Xah Lee talk show on
that topic. We talked We talked 30
minutes about that.
Uh just search, you know, just go to
You- YouTube, search for it, you'll find
it. So, anyway, this code is works. Now,
let's see there's any Are there any uh
final touch-up we need to do?
So, yeah, this this This is actually
production code. Uh I'm glad I I I
rewrote it from scratch.
Let's see if there's anything. Oh,
there's more things we more features we
need to add.
So, you see, sometimes we change the
entities to the to the ampersand, but
sometimes we want to change it back.
You know, it's not easy to change it
back, you see.
Uh you know, once you don't have undo
Well, if you have undo, that's great,
but once you made a change
and save the file, close it,
reopen the file,
so now you have that. Now, how do you
change it back? It's not easy. So,
so you have to, you know, you have to
write a command. So,
so we can we can make our command to do
to do that.
Okay, yeah, let's do that. We can make
our command to
you know, to reverse the direction.
So far so good.
I would never recommend Windows to
anyone. Oh, yeah. Hmm.
Thomas Herman says, "You might be in the
wrong branch. Try to put the overlay
into the next if."
Uh yeah, maybe yeah, we probably fix
that error.
Uh
Okay, anything else?
Yeah, so Iris, that's a great uh
suggestion. So, let's use universal
argument.
Okay, so let me let me tell you you
know,
those of you don't know what that is.
So, in in Emacs in Emacs there is this
thing called universal arguments. That
is, you know, in Emacs we have
functions, you know, we have many
commands that's are useful. So, but
sometimes you want a kind of a variation
of a command. For example, in dired in
in
for example, I go to the directory
uh I go to the directory and I want to
So, here's my directory and I want to
hide hide hide the um
hide those those permissions. So, here's
my directory.
So, let's say I want to copy uh let's
let's shrink. Let's say I want to copy
the file name of of this file name.
And uh I can, you know, in dired you can
press W. That will copy the file name.
So, split buffer, new buffer, paste it,
you see.
Now, I got the file name.
But, what if you want the full path? You
can do that, too.
So, you So, you what you do is you press
control U
then
whatever key for that command.
Okay, not
not control U. Okay, so let me do it
again. So,
you press W to You press W to get the
file name.
Okay, so but what is the command
corresponding to the shortcut? You can
find out by you call describe key
then W, then it'll show you here.
So, the command you are actually
calling, wait, uh wrong. So, let's do it
again, okay? Let's do it again.
Control HK for describe key, then type
the key W.
Then
you have it.
Here. So, it says W runs the command
dired-copy-file-name-as-kill.
And, you know, here's the documentation.
So, it tells you
copy name copy name of marked marked
files into the kill ring and blah blah
blah.
So, you see, now it says with a zero
prefix argument, use the absolute file
name of each marked file.
You see? So, now So, what that means So,
what does it What does it mean zero
prefix arg arg? That means
you want to call the universal command.
So, let me just show you, okay?
So, I want I want to copy the full path
of these
uh of some marked files. So, let's say
one more, okay?
So, I press
I press
control U
then zero
then W.
That's it.
And then now I split the buffer new
buffer paste it
magnify. You can see there are two
There are two uh full file paths. You
see?
One one and two.
So So that prefix argument thing, that's
that control U is called universal
argument.
So what's the purpose of that? The
purpose is to allow commands to have
to have variation of behaviors.
Basically, you are giving a different
parameter parameters to the command
interactively.
Okay?
So that's a explanation of the universal
argument. And in fact, close this we are
we are going to code it.
So we are going to say in our
documentation, we are going to say
uh
Yeah, we we already said it here. If
universal argument is called first, the
replacement direction is reversed.
That's right.
So how do we code it? Well,
uh we can code it here or we can look at
our tutorial. So let's see um
Uh we we have a lot to code actually. So
what Any comments? Questions?
You should factor out the repetition.
Well,
uh
So uh if universal argument is called
Okay, I don't remember what's the How do
you do that? But let's, you know, go to
my Emacs Lisp tutorial.
That's what I do. I write a tutorial for
myself. Go to the Emacs Lisp section,
introduction to Emacs Lisp.
Then there is a section on
get universal argument. So, this page
tells you all about it.
You can read it later, but now
but what I want to do
I just want to uh
That's what I want. Here.
current-prefix-arg
So, this variable, current-prefix-arg,
contains the value
of that control-U or whatever user
pressed.
So, this this is the argument argument.
So, we want to say if
current-prefix-arg
Uh if
So, what is the what's the value? So,
current-prefix-arg
It's a bit complicated. Okay, so I'm not
going to explain, but you can read it on
my page.
Uh what I want to say if
Okay, so if current-prefix-arg, so if
control-U is pressed then
reverse direction. So, we need another
parameter,
reverse direction, okay?
So, if current-prefix-arg
So, set reverse direction to nil by
default.
When current-prefix-arg is true
then
set reverse direction to true, okay?
So
So right. So okay. So but how do you get
the reverse direction? First of all, we
need to actually there's a lot to do.
We need to
Okay, so so there's actually a lot to
code and a lot to explain.
How do we code this? Because you see
we also have the highlighting going on.
You know, the easiest way is just copy
this entire code and repeat it.
That's that would be the easiest way.
Let's do that first, okay? Let's do
that.
Okay, so let's let's just do that. Okay.
So if reverse direction is true
then do something here. Otherwise
do this, okay?
But if it's true
we do this, okay? Yeah, yeah. This is
this is
this is the tried and true method, you
know, this is the simplest swim method,
but it works.
This is the most plain
no fancy stuff method.
So if reverse direction is true, we want
you know, we just want a different we we
just do like that, okay? Uh
Let me just simply quickly code it here.
Wait.
What did I do?
Then here is one.
Then
that
This is
greater than or this is less than
one. That's it. That's it. That's our
code.
Uh that will work. Okay, I'm pretty sure
that will work. Let's not just Let's
compact our code again. Now it's getting
big. We cannot see the whole thing in
one screen.
Now it's one screen.
Eval the buffer. Are we sure? I'm pretty
sure it will work. But let's
double-check before, you know, otherwise
we'll run into some errors.
Uh reverse direction. So
So if current prefix arc, then reverse
direction is true. Okay.
Okay, wait. Hold on a second. Close,
save, reopen,
magnify. You need it You need it to be a
bit bigger.
Magnify a little bit.
So reverse direction
By convention
a variable name that ends in  p
means it returns true or false usually.
That's the convention of Lisp.
Okay, so if reverb if reverse direction
is true, then you do this. Otherwise,
yeah, that that should be that should
work. Run it Run Eval buffer.
Okay, now let's call it. Let's try it.
Call it.
Do it.
Uh yeah, that's that's correct. We
forgot to press the control U. Okay.
Undo.
You know, there there are some other
issues we want to
uh if we prefer
Okay, let me let me let me let me answer
the question, okay? Before we answer,
let me let's try the code, okay? Close
the buffer, reopen it,
magnify, magnify, okay? We're going to
try on this uh section of code.
Remember, we want to change it back to
the
to the characters.
So, press control U first, then meta X,
then HTML escape char to entity. Do it.
Fantastic.
Our code is working.
Now, you know, now we know it's working.
Now we can we can try to
elegantify the code, you know, to make
it less repetitive, you know, the those
kind of thing. You know, those kind of
thing are kind of the
the hacker types. They are they are
endeavored to do, but they are usually
not practical.
Well,
it's good to have, you know, it's good
to I mean, this this code right now is
kind of too much
too much repetition. Uh
anyway, our code works.
So, what's the next thing we we want to
do? Well, let let's let me answer the
questions first, okay?
Yeah, so that's that's a good
suggestion, you know, the the
the to reduce our code, what we have to
do is we want to extract
the find and replace pairs, you know,
that we have a bunch of pairs of
characters, find string and replace
string. We have several pairs of them.
We want to make them into a list.
So that if the direction is changed, we
simply change we swap the you know the
pairs of list. Yeah, but that that's a
bit
you know that will take 5 minutes or 10
minutes of coding to do.
But let me answer the next question.
What is the hell What the hell is nil?
Okay, nil
nil in Emac Lisp just means essentially
it means false.
Okay, so there are two meanings of nil.
Nil in
Emac Lisp just means it's an empty list.
Empty list and nil they are equivalent.
They are completely equivalent
in Emac Lisp.
And but in Emac Lisp nil also means
false, okay? When you when you are in a
eval situation. Yeah, it's kind of like
null in other programming languages.
Okay, let's let's do this one last
thing.
Wait, how how long have I been talking?
I've been thinking maybe this is getting
boring. 57 minutes.
Uh
Let's let's let's
let's let's
let's do this, okay? Let's let's let's
simplify the code code, okay?
First of all, let's make a the copy of
the whole buffer.
Okay, copy the whole buffer and go back
to the HTML and let's paste the code
here.
Let's let's
Yeah, let's paste the code here.
Okay?
And show in browser
and you can see the code here
and let's prettify it. Syntax color it.
And now refresh browser.
That's our current code.
Uh
Okay, now let's go back go back.
Okay, let's go to the code. Okay, let's
make the pretty I mean let's make the
elegant version. Let's let's improve
this.
Okay, so we want to
we want to create a variable
called char
find replace map. Okay.
So here is our variable find replace
map.
That's
you know, that's uh
And I'm going to show you what that is.
Okay.
Set Q element. Okay, and we want I'm
going to use a vector. Okay.
vector
vector is going to let me show you.
You know, there's this Emacs bug. You
see how that column
the line of number, you know, the
the line number display they kind of
like moving around. I'm not sure why
that happens, but it does.
So anyway, so I want to make a list of
pairs. So this this is going to be
like that. Okay. Let me show you. Okay.
And
uh
this will make the code much more easier
to understand kind of.
Okay, so now less than equals to sign
now greater than equals to sign.
Okay.
Pretty fine. Okay, that's what we want
basically. Pretty fine again. Yeah.
So we this this is our this is find
replace pairs.
Okay.
Then
let's go mount let's go to our code.
So, this then if region that part
selects a region
okay, so let's add okay, actually let's
add the
breaks so it's easier to see. So, if
reverse direction is true,
then do something, okay? We don't we do
something.
Okay?
Uh
otherwise, we do this thing here.
So,
so we going to replace this code. So,
what we going to do? So,
okay, let me show you.
So,
while
okay, so we going to so that's our old
code. I'm going to
I'm going to duplicate the code here so
you can see what we are doing.
So, while um
actually, it's more than that.
Now, we need to go through our vector.
We need to loop through our vector.
Okay, so let let's scratch the whole
thing. Let's we need to redo the whole
thing.
Scratch.
Scratch. Scratch. Scratch.
We
Yeah, let me just let me scratch the
whole thing. Let me show you what what
to do, okay?
Okay, we
we start um
from scratch. So, here we say save
restriction, okay?
Then
now to region, okay? Then P1 P1 P2,
okay?
Then we start our code here. If reverse
direction is
is true
If it's true, we do something here.
Otherwise, we do something here, okay?
Okay, now first of all, we want to do uh
first of all, we want Okay, what we want
to do
We want to uh loop through
We want to loop through this find
replace map, okay?
So, how do you uh loop through? Uh what
you do is
uh
map
map C, okay?
map C
Okay, first argument is a function, the
second argument is a sequence. Now, the
sequence is going to be find replace
map, okay? Now, the first argument is
going to be a function.
So, let's do a function lambda l a m b d
a, okay? lambda x body
Now, let's prettify the code. We need
it. So, lambda So, what the function
What does the What will our function do?
The function lambda
will take no argument
and the body of the lambda will be
while search forward just like before.
Uh you know, we are
Okay, while search forward. We can We
can write this very fast, okay? Okay,
I'm I'm just going to write write uh
fast without much talking, okay?
The set point mean end point max
according to the lengths of the item of
the list. Yeah, that's right.
I'm just going to code fast because too
much talking. So, you just just um
Uh
anything I call
Wait.
Okay, so anyway, I'm I'm just going to
code code it.
Lambda actually the lambda needs one
argument. The argument is the um
the pair. Okay, so let's say X pair.
Okay, so while
search forward
array
X pair
wait array
Yeah.
What?
Wait.
Okay, index zero. So this is going to be
the find string.
So search forward for that find string
found nil no error true.
Okay.
So search forward for that if it's found
then just say replace match. Okay.
Replace match by
replace match by the second
argument. Okay, that that's it. We don't
need the rest of the thing.
Okay, so that's our function.
A very simple. We shorten the code a
lot.
Okay, so that
Then now now the highlighting part. Now
we need to highlight it. Remember?
Now the highlight part will be let's
copy it here.
Okay.
While
search is the
highlighting part, okay?
Now, we want to highlight
end what position. So, end position will
be point. The beginning position will be
the length of the character exactly. So,
the length of character it will be
Uh we need to uh
we need to
lengths of these, okay?
Uh so, length
that, okay? That should work.
Okay, so that that should work.
Actually, that that will work.
So, you see if reverse direction is
true, then do something here we haven't
coded yet. Otherwise,
uh do this part. Now, we don't need that
uh program thing. So, let's remove that
program thing.
Okay?
Now, our code will work if the direction
is not changed. Let's just re- eval the
buffer. Let's just test it, okay?
Let's move. Let's Let's call it.
Call it.
No, it didn't work. Uh
what's the problem?
Close.
Wait.
I don't know what's going on.
Um
It's huge chunk of code.
Cuz I teach HTML escape char to entity.
Do it.
Nothing happened.
Selected code it again. Nothing
happened. So, we have some problems in
our code. So, let's double-check.
So, we got the find replace map correct,
I hope.
Yes, that is correct.
But, nothing happened. Okay. Uh save
restriction.
Anything Anything, guys?
Try it first, yeah.
So, Kapisan team says, "Hey, why you use
array of arrays, array of list?"
Uh I don't like list, okay? So, there is
a
In my opinion, there's a uh huge mis
concep- conception in the list
community. You know, in this it's a
tradition to always use list.
But, uh
but often times it's not efficient,
okay?
Basically, if you do not need to change
the length of the list,
don't use a list. Uh that's kind of a
simple rule. In our case, it doesn't
matter. In In our case, a list is
probably faster.
But, I you know, I'm a maverick. That is
why I use array.
Basically, that's that is true. If you
are not changing the
length of the list, then just use an
array. That's that's a good uh rule of
thumb.
That's what I do anyway. It doesn't
matter here. We We could use a list. In
fact, if we use a list, it's more uh
more conventional.
So, anyway, we have a bug here, okay? We
need to find out what's going on.
Lambda, so
while search forward array,
the first part
Okay, now if it's found, then you
replace match, right?
Okay.
Uh
Yeah, you do that, then you overlay.
So, what is wrong in our problem?
What is wrong in our
um
code?
I I don't know.
I'm I'm kind of getting tired.
Uh
I don't know, but let's do let's do a
let, okay?
Let's do a let to simplify this.
Let, we have two
uh
Okay, we we give it two
temp variables, find string and replace
string.
Okay, so that will make the code
kind of simpler to read.
Instead of this array thing, okay? So,
let's
Right?
Yeah.
Okay, that's a code. Now, let's
prettify. Okay, prettify. That's that's
uh
So, we got find string and replace
string.
Do some print debugging, maybe? Yeah, we
should do, but I was hoping we could
I was hoping I can find out what's the
problem. I'm pretty sure I can.
You know, we probably missed something
simple. Let's let's look at the whole
thing again.
So, set Q, this map, find replace map,
we can actually um
This is a vector, right? Yeah, that's a
vector. No doubt about it. So, we can
clean up the code
by just putting it here, okay?
And uh let's shrink it. Let's make it
Okay.
So, find replace map, okay? Uh and uh
Find replace map, that's right.
So, when current prefix arc, okay, this
part we don't care yet. So, reverse
direction is nil. Search for it.
It occurs three times, that's right.
Okay.
Then
Do we have our region correct? Use
region.
Region is correct, no doubt.
Okay.
Do we have some kind of mismatched
bracket?
No, it seems right.
Okay. Then we save restriction.
Then we narrow to region. That's right.
If reverse direction, then do something.
If reverse direction is true, then do
that.
Else is false, then we do this. That's
right.
So
So we are map
We are mapping to
So we map the first argument is the
lambda.
The second argument is the
is this um map.
Okay, I don't know what's going on. So
let's print let's print let's do the
uh messages. Let's print
Let's print the find string.
Okay, so every time it goes through the
it you know go through the find replace
map, you'll print the
Okay, split the buffer, go to the
message buffer. So at bottom is the
message buffer. We will see if we when
we call the command, we will see it
prints out things. So let's call the
command. Call it.
Do it.
Okay, symbols value of a variable is
void x pair.
Uh
okay, so I probably have some
misspellings here.
Yeah, we have a misspelling.
Where This pair? Wait.
X pair should be part of lambda.
Oh, yeah. So,
yeah.
That's right. So, this let is incorrect.
Okay. So,
let's do this.
The let should be inside map. Okay.
Well, inside inside the find inside the
inside the lambda.
Okay. So, it's like that.
Like that.
So, now we have the let part
inside the lambda. Okay.
Give up a buffer.
Let's do it again. Call the command.
Do it.
Okay. So, you can see it prints that
it prints ampersand and uh
less than sign and greater than sign.
So, the
the find string is correct.
Let Let's
So, why why is it not working?
Search for word find string.
Oh, we forgot to go to the beginning of
buffer. That's
idiotic.
That's why. We forgot to go to the
beginning of buffer.
Right.
So, go to char point mean.
Point mean, okay?
Eval buffer, go back to the HTML.
And let's try it. Do it. It worked.
No, there's no destruction in Emacs
Lisp.
Okay, so close the buffer.
Reopen it again.
Magnify.
Magnify. Let's work on this part, okay?
This part is
call the command.
Do it.
The highlighting is incorrect.
Can you see that?
Because it highlighted the five and two
for some reason.
So, in Emacs Lisp, you can call uh
unhighlight.
No, there's no unhighlight region.
Unhighlight region. Uh okay.
Just close it.
Close it.
Reopen it.
And magnify.
So, anyway, the highlight is incorrect.
So, let's find out what's going on. So,
go to the beginning of position
of buffer.
Yeah, there's remove overlay.
Remove overlay, but um
I I don't I don't think Well,
yeah, but
I don't think there's a
a command for user to do that. You can
do it in Emacs Lisp anyway, but that's
getting advanced. You You know, I'm
trying to A lot of people don't know
what we are doing, but
we are getting too complex.
And just move backward, forward, what do
you mean?
Anyway, so we we we we got to finish
this. So, what's going on? So, right now
we have a problem that is our
highlighting is in the wrong position.
Uh highlighting is in the wrong
position. Oh, yeah, that's because
caps-a-tine delete overlay. That Yeah,
that may work.
Uh let's finish this. Uh uh highlighting
is in the incorrect position. How
So, we need to debug it. The You know,
the code, you see,
let me just explain what's going on.
Okay, so right now the code is like
that. It's you know, it's much shorter
than we have before. But however,
the problem is
the problem with now is that before our
code is very simple and very easy to
debug.
You know, as as a human you know,
animal, you look at this for example,
this code, you can see the repetition.
You can you can easily understand what
it's doing.
But now,
with our code is highly condensed.
There's you know, there's a loop
and
um
and it's hard to debug because right now
it's it's not more difficult to debug.
Because before
if we have a problem, we know exactly
where to
uh you know, check for the wrong code.
Okay, so
So let's try to debug again. So make
overlay.
You know, basically what we need to do
what I need to do is to think.
That means you know, I just stay quiet
and do nothing.
So make So make overlay.
And actually I'm getting tired. So make
overlay
um
So what what what? So what do you think
is wrong? Any any any of you guys? And
you will see the difference with move
forward.
Compare your initial code. Okay, so
I will say is compare your initial code
and you will see the difference
with move forward.
What What do you mean?
Did we Okay, let's check our old code.
Did we miss anything here?
Let's try it again. Eval the buffer.
Let's go here, select it. Call it. Let's
just say wait. Let's just say
uh
Let's just say that, okay? One single
one sing single change it should be. So,
call it
side channel escape char.
So, that works. But, however, it uh
highlighted the whole thing.
Let's do it again.
Okay?
Okay, so it highlighted to the end of
the point, okay?
So, apparently
something else. So, we're going to try
on this
this paragraph and it seems it will
highlight
It seems it will highlight everything.
Let's try it.
No. Okay, so you can see it highlighted
to the end. It
It highlights
Basically, what's happening is that our
code logic is wrong somewhere.
Uh
Somewhere here.
Okay, I know what's wrong.
This overlay this make overlay needs to
be inside the while loop, you know, a
simple silly problem.
Yeah.
So, the overlay needs to be inside the
while loop.
You know, I I I guess we we could call
this a disadvantage of this syntax.
Okay, evalbuffer.
Now, back to our code. Back to our here
and test it.
Yeah, it works.
So, we got, you know, the nesting wrong.
That's That's right. Now, let's finish
it, okay?
So, now if direction is true, we need to
reverse the pairs, okay?
So, what we can do is, okay, so let me
just finish the code, okay? Let's Let me
just do it quickly.
Uh
Okay.
Okay, wait. So, wait.
So, let's do this way, okay?
So, here's our code. Here's our map.
And we're going to
change the map here, okay? So, delete
that. So, if
reverse direction is true,
if it's false, then use this map. If
it's true,
we want to reverse the map, okay? So,
we're going to have a little code that
reverse the map here.
So, what we do is we can say it's uh not
hot.
map
um map car
Okay.
map car a sequence and uh then a lambda
X, okay?
Then
um
Uh wait. Hold on a second, okay?
Here's what we what we do.
There.
Okay, so
if reverse direction is true,
we remove reverse the map.
Uh I think that code is correct.
Double check. That's what I'm doing.
Double check.
Oh, yeah. So, we got the zero one, so we
zero one must be reversed. We are
reversing the elements.
I think that's it. Eval the buffer.
Let's test it, okay?
Oh, okay. So, um
So, we press control U for the universal
argument. Control U, then meta X, then
call out command. Fantastic.
Successful.
So, that's it for today.
Uh yeah, we we could use map C reverse.
Uh that we could use that, too. But, I
was trying to
I didn't use, you know, the reverse
function because
uh I'm pretty sure this is faster. And
also, reverse
the reverse function may not work on
vector. It It may actually actually uh
let's see. Okay, reverse describe
describe function. Okay, yeah. So, it
Oh, yeah. So, it reverses uh uh it
reverse it can work on a vector. But,
also, what's more important is that it's
in C code. So, that means it's faster.
So, that it it will be faster than my
code.
You know, so so when you code uh Emacs
this, sometimes it's important I mean,
it's good good to know whether the code
is in C or in this. So, if it's in C,
that usually means if you code this
function, it will be faster than
whatever you write.
But, if it's in this,
then it may not be. Whatever you write
is maybe faster.
So, in in our case,
uh we could call reverse. But, the
problem is reverse returns a
Okay, it returns a vector. So, the if
the input is a vector, it returns a
vector. So, we could use that. Okay.
Uh reverse X. Okay.
So,
So, you see,
reverse X instead of instead of our code
here.
Okay, let's try to see if it works.
Uh
eval buffer,
do it here,
call the command, do it, works.
Control U, call the command, do it,
works.
Fantastic.
Then we don't need that anymore. Clean
up the code. Clean up, clean up. Yeah.
So here's the code. Um
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching.
If you like my tutorial, you we've been
doing this for long today. Uh for 70
minutes, 80 minutes.
For 90 minutes.
Uh so that's it.
Yeah, so if you like my tutorial, go to
Xah Lee Emacs tutorial and buy it, okay?
You don't even need the lambda.
Uh so what are you saying? So Oh yeah,
so you are right.
So uh more
more code clean up. You don't even need
the lambda.
So we re- replace the whole by just the,
you know, the
um apostrophe reverse.
Let's try it, okay? Eval the buffer.
Go back to the HTML.
Call it, do it.
Right, it works. Control U, call it, do
it, it works.
Fantastic. Thank you guys so much.
Hi Diamond. Uh that's it for today.
Uh we are done. We already talked for 90
minutes.
Bye, guys.
Mhm.