good morning welcome to another episode
of exan talk show today we're going to
code wolam language I'm going to
introduce you wam language Association
list or simply called
Association and which means python
dictionary Java or JavaScript map object
or in Ruby and pearl it's called
hashtable so wam language
Association okay let's begin begin if
you have questions ask me okay if you
are watching offline skip around P play
at 1.5 speed okay uh go to the website
search foram Language tutorial atar
doino you'll see it uh so in recent in
the past
month I've been working on this a whole
lot so a huge amount amount of update
wolam language s programming blog okay
so you can see wolam language uh
Association so the entire Association
section has been updated so let me start
to show you some demo okay wam Language
tutorial close that uh talk show
okay
uh W Language tutorial put the link
there and go to it open it and go down
then you'll see Association now
Association remember it's like a hash
table or dictionary or map uh different
languages have different names for it
now in wam language it's called simply
Association okay now in iMac LP you also
have similar called Association list but
in wfam language it's simply called
Association even though it's actually
like emac lisps Association list or
common lisps Association list okay so
but anyway it's a hashtable or
dictionary uh it's ordered okay so in
wam language is ordered so let me start
to show example so here is my article uh
you can see Association introduction of
the association data structure uh and uh
then you can see a lot of Articles so
you you got Association how to create it
in different ways systematically or
generate Association or get value check
a key exist check value exist and so on
so it's a list of pairs okay usually
called key value
pairs okay
now go here copy the link go back here
and paste the link there and let me
begin to show you okay so
Association
uh okay so associ iation by the way so
pop it up uh
Association so you can see this is a
syntax so you have Association then you
say a uh what a arrow one comma B Arrow
two so that means the key are A and B
and values is one and two
evaluated so you can see this is a
result I mean this is just like literal
expression for the key value pair okay
so you can uh you can put the result
here uh so what what is this why it
doesn't print that because this is
actually the alternative syntax this is
this is the short Syntax for example I
can say now let's change it to string a
string a and string B and some value
okay so some value you know you can you
can do it like that so evaluate the
current
line you see it print out like that you
know so so this is uh this is just a
short short syntax this and
uh this and that is actually exactly the
same because in W language when you
write this and you run it the compiler
will actually first turn it into this
syntax so they they are like 100% they
are just syntax equivalent okay
syntactically
equivalent so this is Association this
is a literal expression and uh so now
let me introduce you so what I'm doing
so in wam language let's start it okay
now wam language is free you can
download it I highly recommend it
because it's a magnitude higher level
it's a highest level programming
language than all existing python Ruby
Pearl PHP Java goand rust closure common
disp emac disp hascal F Shar or camo
then all of
them obviously C and C++ they are kind
of low level and rust you know low level
the so-called system languages you can
eliminate them because they are low
level you know so so python for examp
python is the most popular so python is
fairly high level one line of python
equals to 10 lines of C or 50 lines of C
right now one line of wam language is
equals to 10 lines of python or a
thousand lines of python literally why
because wam language you know by default
it has
7,000 functions building okay so you can
download it um let me just quickly intro
okay you can download it just search for
go to search for Wam Language tutorial
then you can see download download wam
engine and you can read about the
differences wam language Mathematica wam
engine from script what are the
differences are they just synonyms you
know you can uh read about it you can
download free or you can buy the uh
Raspberry Pi it's it it is bundled with
a W language okay so download it then
you can um for example I bought what
they sent me a copy okay I'm sponsored
by wolam research I've been coding wolam
language since
1994 and I worked for them for a
while so 1994 okay so I've been coding
it kind of on and off for you know like
three 30 years um okay so w from
language you got um so for example let
me show you Association let's paste it
there shift enter there it is this is
how it looks in not wam notebook this is
what you get when you pay to get to buy
the Mathematica or
language now if you want to download it
for free you um you run wolam script
okay so let me show you
start uh wol
FR uh we don't want wol desktop w w this
is what you get if you download for free
okay so run it so you can see it's a
command line user interface and you can
copy that paste it here uh control
V enter you see so it's the same thing
now I'm running it so for example in
here let's remove that
evaluated uh
problem Oh I got the problem it says
problem because I cannot run multiple
copies at the same time so I need to
exit
here okay now back to
emac run
this you see same result now I'm running
so this emac there's a sar wolam mod
package you can download for free that
runs the wolam language code in emac it
ca the wolam script okay so let me show
you how to get that so for example I
uh tab R to eval the current region tab
to jump to the source code so here's a
code that let me run wolam language in
emac so go to the top you can see this
is a package this is wan mod okay go to
the top and there's a URL showing
browser search foruan mod you'll find it
it's on GitHub okay so GitHub just
download it am I doing good audio check
video check say hi guys so let me check
audio video yeah I'm good and
Alive um okay so wolam language assoc
Association fantastic now let me show
you start to show you the the power of
the wolam association remember I said
it's the most high level bi magnitude
than python so today you can check what
I'm about to show you the wolam language
Association like hash table or hash
table or dictionary features compare you
can compare to python Java JavaScript or
Ruby or whatever language you know you
can see you can immediately see how the
higher level and Rich features in wam
language then than the version of
dictionary in
Python okay and today it's going to be
short I plan to be just 20 20 minutes or
okay so let me start to show you so wam
language wam Language by default you
have seven th000 um 7,000 building
functions okay so let me show
you uh question mark question mark names
to see the documentation of the function
so list of the names of the symbols okay
so let's
try names and uh and uh you need um yeah
and okay let's
magnify so names uh then quote then
let's say
string then that will return a list of
all functions with the
name String in it okay so now let's try
that
again uh contrl L to show the last so
this time we list all functions so this
is going to be a list of 7,000 of it
okay shift
enter so you know you got a bunch of
symbols then you see 7,000 W you can see
the score bar you know so it's going to
be endless okay 7,000 building so when
for example if you want to Traverse the
directory or if you want to use regular
expression or if you want to open a file
close a file or you if you want to do
networking uh or if you want to grab a
URL HTTP or web related functions you
don't have to load a library like in
Python if you want to use regular
expression you have to import V
something if you want to Traverse
directory you have to import system you
know input system file something so in
WF language you don't have to do that
every 7,000 functions building okay it's
not in
libraries then you do have libraries so
that's even more okay so let me show you
so let's see uh let me show you okay
contrl
L then we slash slash then we say length
so length they'll tell tell you how many
items in it slash slash is a postfix
notation so you don't have to like
bracket and you know you don't have
nesting so shift enter so
7,540 symbols spilling okay now minus
some of these you know any symbol
starting with a uh a dollar sign that
means that that means it's a global
variable it's a building variable uh
usually related to configuration Okay so
you are you got lots of them um you know
but all together you got about close to
7,000 functions okay so all these are
functions uh you know all these are
functions so let's look at
Association now I'm going to read the
comment in a bit okay so Association
here is a literal syntax then uh I want
to show you some of it because you know
I just give you an idea and that's it
for today okay uh let me read a comment
I don't know hi I don't know I haven't
seen you for a
while that's an interesting question
let's digress just a little bit okay
have you heard of Janet uh it's like
closure but without JavaScript you know
without the Java virtual machine baggage
so let's look up
quickly uh I I oh yeah I seen it you
know with that girl picture um
so I haven't so I I've heard of it like
a year ago also someone showed me Janet
is a functional and imperative
programming language it runs on Windows
Linux Mac OS BSD and should run on other
systems with some porting the entire
language is less than one megabyte oh
okay good and bad you know whenever they
say that usually for industrial
languages that means good because people
means you know people like things to be
small so you can for example embedded in
some portable device or phone uh and uh
you know it's small but that also means
right away it's not going to be powerful
like wolam language or common disp so
lots of things you have to do you have
to either import a library the building
or from somewhere so anyway you can also
add Janet scripting to an application by
embedding a single C source file okay
yeah okay J you
know you know lots of new languages
today but uh one of the problem with um
new language okay I'm starting to
digress but let's so so one of the
problem with the lots of new languages
is that you want a language that's going
to be
persistent massive number of users so
that is accept acceptable in indust
industrial use for example it will be
possibly chosen by Google Facebook
Microsoft or any other big
corporations okay you don't want a
language that's one man's show so right
now this Genet language looks like a
onean show I don't know for sure but you
know it looks like it because there's
lots of it like that onean show so what
happens with onean show well maybe you
got a million users million is actually
small okay like fans like me you know we
interested in you know different
languages but it's going to be a toy
forever for the next 10 years for the
next 20 years for the next 30 Years and
and then it dies something like that
okay so there's a lot of these little
language name is another example name
there's quite a few today okay so
but I mean nothing wrong with it but
it's uh it's somewhat hard to become a
widely accepted industrial programming
language that's what you want to be okay
otherwise it's like this like 10,000
academic languages 10,000 like almost
literally I mean well practically there
are few hundred okay academic languages
they do things you never heard of you
know but
um so so yeah yeah so I mean with
respect to
practicality or with respect to your
personal career choices you want to pick
a language that is possibly all part of
the industrial languages okay widely
used for example wam language it is not
exactly industrial like you don't see
Google Facebook or uh Microsoft or
Amazon
use it but actually wfam language is
special because all the physics
mathematicians the people who design
rocket engines who design car engines
they are all using Mathematica okay I
mean so this is like outside of the
typical programming
Arena those people are Engineers
physicist uh you know mathematicians
Engineers they deal with equations
differential equations they they need to
solve heat equations engine you know
heating you know those sort of problems
okay so this is kind of actually
different from typical programming like
web or Linux kernel
crap predominated by the bit diders like
the C and C++ and rust
idiots okay back to the association then
we're going to you know few minutes
let's wrap up okay so wam language
Association you can um
uh so there are many uh different ways
to create soci Association let me just
give you a just a few examples okay so
so this example is about creating a
Association from a list so let's say you
have a list of keys uh so list one two
three a list of keys you want to turn it
into Association a list of pairs and
these are keys so so so you can you can
do that by just uh using this
Association map
okay
uh okay so here is you your list okay
takes two arguments the first argument
is going to be a function uh and the
function will be let's say identity
let's say x return X so the key and
value will be the same okay so so now if
I run this eval
region you can see there is a result so
let me paste the result
under there it is you
see uh let's say you know so let me show
another example so you want to so these
are Keys let's they they are um let's
Okay so value let's say plus one uh
let's say squared okay if about the line
there you go key 1 is one key2 is four
key3 has a value of nine okay so that
that's one way to create Association of
course you can do this in Python um so
assoc so next Association thread this is
to allow you to have a list of keys a
list of values you want to some kind of
merge them so they become key value
pairs okay so example um
example uh what is this
Association thread okay so again two
arguments the first argument is a list
of keys okay let's say a
b c okay those are let's let's make it
string so the keys by the way in wfam
language key and value they can be any
type so the key can be a string or it
can can be just a symbol okay like a or
a A or whatever it you know like symbol
because like lisp you know it's a symbol
or it can be a string okay so let's use
a
string the value is let's say one two
three okay so if you run
that then you get that okay so this ABC
are keys wolm does you know when woof
language prints a string those a BC are
strings they the wolf language doesn't
print the the the quotes so it's kind of
easier to read okay so here is the
example so let's skip to next so that's
two ways to generate Association okay
there's lots of other ways so you can
get value obviously there are several
ways to do it look up let's try Okay so
let's try
it uh so let's say that is a Association
many ways okay one way uh let's say XX
equals to so here's Association then you
just XX you want to get the value of a
okay so actually you need to
uh
okay uh eval
region there uh What uh the expression
cannot be used as part of of
specification why is
that uh part spect the expression cannot
be use okay so
yeah okay so there's a little issue okay
so let me explain so if your keys are
strings okay if your keys are strings
then this works
fine okay you see one let's try B okay
you see the value is two because the key
for the key B has a value of two now
however now if your keys are not strings
but symbols like that for example let's
use AABB okay to make it more uh not
ambiguous okay so the keys are now
symbols in fact keys can be arbitrary
expression you know this can be key too
you know so it can be actually
arbitrary uh okay so actually it's not
it's let's save it
to okay so let's go back here uh let's
just say key BB okay so you got AA and
BB as key now then you want to extract
the
key BB okay now when you do that this
you need to say instead of that you need
to um say you need to say this
okay
uh you need to actually say key because
that prevents ambiguity
because because
um because this you see this BB could be
a
list so when you don't say if you don't
specify the key you don't say it's a key
then it's just become a list then then
this syntax becomes extract a list of
keys so that's why so this is the
actually the normal way to do it okay so
let me show let's run
it okay two you see now but if you if
you do it this way it'll give you a
warning okay let's try it
you see
warning you know the expression BB
cannot be used part of a specification
why because it is not a string so if you
have something like like a arbitrary
expression or key you need to say you
know put a key in front Okay so that's
that's this is one way one of the way to
get the value from a key out of
Association one way okay so another way
is this look up more this is more uh
explicit you know and I prefer that way
okay uh this way we just introduce is
more common like when you are in Python
Ruby Goan you know typically you are
familiar with this form you know because
that's a form how you extract array
elements but it's actually not good okay
relate relative to the functional
approach the functional approach is
lookup okay so look up you want to look
up so let's uh let's define the
association there then you want to look
up uh look up the association XX and
what key you want to look up B okay so
let's
run two there it is correct yes okay so
look up is the is it's a good way to
extract
elements okay so there are several ways
you know so this is another way
uh oh you don't need you don't actually
need the double quote I mean
it's uh yeah I forgot let's try
it yeah you don't need you don't you
know that's my mistake
so so if you um let's let let me see if
you do you still get that error if
you run
it yeah so you you don't actually get an
error even though it's a symbol but
anyway what we talked about about
this key thing is still valid this is
valid when this BB is a arbitrary
expression for example let me show you
okay so this so remember any key can be
any arbitrary expression so now let's
make it very arbitrary
X squar
plus
plus how do I type plus it's one okay
y squar ided
z okay so now you got a key so let's
let's make it easier to read here so you
got two keys okay one is just AA symbol
the other thing is this like expression
okay so can you evaluate it yes run
it uh let's make it print okay run
it there it is there's your Association
okay
now okay so now if you have this
Association then if you want to extract
the key now now it becomes a issue let
me show you okay
so right you want to
extract from xx and this key you're
going to have a problem so let's run
it oh that still works okay that still
works
um well I can I can show example it's
going to be a problem so let's do it
again let's say this time is one two
okay
um so the key is this expression of one
two okay run it that's your works I
guess yeah that's your works yeah but
the anyway so there's a there would be a
case
when when this just won't work okay so I
have do I have a example
here yeah the the here it is the example
okay
so yeah this works okay so let's
say let's say you have a key
actually of one and a key of two okay so
here is your Association and you want
to extract the key of one two so let's
give it some different value okay
okay key 1 is 88 key2 is 42 then this
key list of one two is uh uh
what is two okay so now we extract this
key let's see what
happens uh two okay that also works yeah
okay
anyway yeah let's not let's not you know
dig dig a whole uh that you know just
understand that this this ambiguity
happens okay you know I'm not going to
spend time to actually find a example um
so anyway there is Association then then
you can check the key exist you can then
you can check key Exist by pattern now
this is new you don't see it in python
or any other languages not in Python
Java
JavaScript uh not even in hcal or camel
F or Lis or closure why because in wam
language remember the key can be any
arbitrary expression it can be like one
1,000 lines you know a mathematical
equation or differential equation or
whatever actually we can show a example
okay so let me show a
example so so let's just say a single
key okay so this key will be um let me
show you this okay so
um so we got that and we raise to the
third power
okay okay that expression raised to the
thir
power is that okay but but now you want
to expand it
okay ex expand
that you got that okay and you can put
that you can put that in the in let's
see let's put that in
the association okay so
this this is the expression okay so I
mean the key okay let's see it actually
expand the key or
not no actually keep it symbolic it
doesn't expand but if you uh say this I
think it still doesn't Okay so let's
try
uh I need I need a auto format I don't
have it let's run it
oh it does okay so so you see now you
got a Association of one single
item and uh you know so the key is this
line the value is simply
to you see so so the point here is that
the key can be opportuity complex so
when you have this
situation you know then you have a
associate where you have let's say 1,000
items and each one each of the key is is
a math expression like that okay now you
want to find all
keys where it contains z in it okay uh
you see you want to find all any of the
key that contains z in it that's when
you want to use the check key Exist by
pattern actually uh actually this just
check key exist but actually what you
want the way we are talking about it is
to get all keys or all values that uh by
a pattern okay which you go
here Association delete items by filter
okay so you can you can you can delete
or filter you know delete take take the
things you want or remove the things you
don't want either way to speak it so
filter by key via list of keys that's
one way to do it or filter by key via a
function so if this function returns
true that means keep it if it returns
false that means ignore it okay via a
function or you can filter by values via
a function okay okay so here you filter
by key you can also F filter by value
via function or okay where's a pattern
uh we want to filter uh Key by a pattern
okay uh
wait there delete item by key okay key
okay this is delete by literal key
Association variable delete by key okay
so where is that um
filter filter by list of keys I want to
filter by key and by a pattern pattern
matching of the keys okay filter by key
list of keys filter by key via the
function filter by value via function
wait there's a filter
by
um key VR a pattern now where is that
okay so anyway we are about to end
that's that's the my introduction to wam
language Association but let me just
find the things we
want uh oh
here to list of rules to all keys to all
values uh get all values get values by I
get values by Ma pattern matching on
values okay
um wait I want I want to filter a
Association by a pattern matching on the
keys so I want to check each key if it
contains a pattern now where is that
did I did I miss a link
here get items delete items by key okay
so this is by literal key
match
uh now because Association is ordered
therefore you can also also delete by
index range or extract by index range
okay now but I want
filter right so is it in the
map oh God I'm stumped on this
thing I want to filter by value why is
that you got Association which is a list
of key value pairs now the keys can be
each key can be arbitrary symbolic
expression like complicated math formula
okay so of this
Association I want
to basically delete any key value pair
such that the key does not contain X I
mean the key does not contain Z
okay so so I want to do some kind of
filtering okay so some kind of filtering
function uh so it should be here and uh
this filter needs to be by
a oh okay so I think well you can do it
by this by by a function and the
function is simply uh match Q which
means it match a pattern
okay okay I think that's it for today
okay then you know
so uh so let through our
question you know you know we can do it
this way okay so let me show you uh
filter by key so copy that
so so now so this is Association okay
let's put it like
that XX equals to this
Association and then you say key select
okay now it needs a function so here's a
function so it selects the even numbers
keys right okay but now like like we
said before we don't want you know a we
want a pattern so so you're going to
need so here's how to do it okay so you
write a function because it requires a
function key select then you want to say
match Q
okay so when this return true that means
it's valid so so let's say one of the
key is uh x x
squared then Z third part uh then 3 Z
okay let's just say
that so we got this Association okay now
we want to filter by if it contains Z or
not not okay so match what is the Syntax
for match uh
check expression and form Okay so ex so
again two
arguments expression is the X and form
is simply Z so this will return just
this this it will return Association
containing just that entry okay let's
try
it
empty
uh oh because this mat means whole match
okay
so it it needs to match the entire
expression not just
um uh not just that so you need some
kind so again you need a pattern
matching that matches a Sub sub part we
can easily do that but then we need to
look into a little bit so let's look
into okay so let's go to pattern
matching uh symbolic pattern imine
Okay click on
that and
uh and uh we want to
say if it contains okay pattern matching
functions okay not not this okay so this
is patter match Ming syntax go to the
introduction to pattern matching then go
to the pattern matching syntax creating
rules to match to transform expression
function transform expression by pattern
uh other functions using patterns there
let's see so replace replace or set set
delay cases position member
Q that's right okay so
any member of a least matches a pattern
no okay let's look at match Q
okay yeah so match Q checks only match
the entire expression so you need to
just um
oh God we get into a pattern matching
problem but let's finish this and that's
it for
today okay
so so we want to match a pattern now the
problem is let me explain we have a
pattern like that or any arbitrary big
expression uh we have a expression like
that we want to have a function that to
check if it contains Z anywhere
okay um how do you do that
so so you can use match
Q okay so this is a sep separate problem
uh let's let me just try it
there okay so you can use match Q now
does match Q has a
option uh no it must match the entire
thing uh but what is
the what is the
way to just
to just
um so far so
good oh this key oh
oh I didn't know that uh common L yeah
so it's very interesting because you
know wam language is like it's just a
lisp okay because in every
aspect for example even I mean compared
to emac LP which I know very well I know
wfam language very well for you know 30
years I know com uh I know emac this for
16 years been coding it every day so
it's like every aspect in emac this
there's a corresponding part in wam
language just like every I mean even the
association we are doing today you know
like in Elis there's Association list
which is you know even the name is like
similar um but this you know this emac
list Association list is is not really
good okay but I mean it's it's like a
hybrid between list and hash table then
emac disp has actual hash
table but in wam language it's just
simply Association so it's like
Association list which is ordered can
can act as a list you can you know you
you can just treat it like a list any
function that works on list will uh
simply work on the values okay and but
you can also but it also functions as a
so-called hashtable implementation or
map where you can have millions of items
and it's very efficient okay um so but
not so with the emac lp Association
because that every time you want to
search a key you actually have to search
item by item so that's emac disp so you
mentioned about a key in
disp uh I'm not too
familiar oh that that's not like this
quote that um well in some way they are
similar but
anyway uh so what I want to say what I
want so we have a issue yeah so we want
to have
arbitrary okay so the question is when
you have an arbitrary expression such as
that uh or you know
plus uh
any just really arbitrary expression you
know
z y squar okay like this is one
expression you simply want to be to have
a function to be able to tell you
whether Z is in
it uh does member Q
work okay let's try that by the pattern
Z okay run
it
Force why is it false I kind of know why
is it false
because because there's actually no item
that that that is the
um that is just a z because this
actually becomes time three and Z okay
and uh okay it actually gets a bit
complicated I can explain but it takes
more time you know so you see this level
spec that's what you need okay so uh let
me show you okay so this is false and
but now if you say level
spec uh level spec from one
to
Infinity okay run
it true you see that's what we need okay
so go back here so actually you just
need uh you need a function actually
member Q okay so actually you need this
okay so copy
that you need
that and so you need let me show you
okay so key select from the association
X how do you select you select by a
function this function
okay by this function the argument is X
and what does it do well it checks if
it's a member Q so member QX if it
contains Z but you need to check it from
from the tree depth level one to
Infinity meaning that you check not just
the leaves but also the intermediate Nos
and you know gets a bit complicated it's
because you dealing with
because we are dealing with keys that
are arbitrary expressions meaning that
each key is arbitrarily nested
tree and you are we are trying to
pattern match the tree so that is why
you get a bit complicated involving this
you know so but anyway this will work
okay let me show you so delete that
delete that remove remove okay so here's
a thing
okay we got a Association where the keys
are arbitrary complicated Expressions we
want to extract the association only
keys that contains the symbol Z okay
that's how you do it you say key select
uh takes a one two arguments the
association and a function so here is
our
function the function takes X argument
then check member Q of X check for Z and
with this levels uh Tre depth levels
okay run
it you see that fantastic and beautiful
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching finally you know um thank you
and we
done did you enjoy it did you guys learn
something okay if you like it pay me uh
this is important okay uh despite me
repeating so check out my Wan tutorial
go to just search for wolam language you
can download it free search for wolam
language
okay and then and go
up then you see all my kind of all other
programing language tutorials go to S .
info homepage code and uh all the way
bottom you'll see PayPal
patreon Amazon gift card okay so pay me
thank you guys and good
afternoon
bye so put this back color it showing
browser that's what we talked about
fantastic close it member queue
documentation close it Janet language
interesting but this this you see this
is this programming language I can tell
right away it's a onean show okay why
because first of all because first of
all it's got this icon you know a woman
icon yeah it's pretty nice it looks
She's you know
fairly
goodlooking but if you want a
professional programming language widely
adopted that is a no no okay that's a no
go that's BEC I how do I know because I
I know you know diverse kind of things
okay so this is related to logo
design one of the rule of logo design is
you don't want complicated pictures you
want simple Simplicity okay you want
something on icon that people can
recognize so that's one violation of
logo design this women yeah beautiful
too complex a logo is not just like a
painting or artwork okay so that's first
violation second violation you don't use
a generic women to represent your
language like a logo okay logo needs
needs to be
symbolic and symbolic to your whatever
your company whatever your company is
doing so McDonald's for example it's got
a m m reminds you of McDonald's sh
Corporation it's got a shell seashell oh
shell
reminder tackle Bell it's got a bell
bell oh reminder tackle Bell there's
there's a bell what is this jet language
well a a girl a woman named Janet like
what what what the is this so
that's a second violation of logo design
okay I mean it's no big deal right but
it just tells me that this language is
like one guy's one man show you know
he's just a nerd somewhere uh he doesn't
know he doesn't really know about the
principles of logo design or you know he
doesn't have money to hire a logo
designer well today logo design is
pretty easy you can ask ask AI Bots to
create a logo for you but he doesn't
know apparently he doesn't know the
principles of logo design so if you are
a corporation you know you are not you
know you look at this are you going to
like put this women picture in your
corporations you know like tools you
no so that that's something you know uh
and uh lots of other issues with this
one man
show kind of language
okay uh Calvin
Rose created it okay anyway interesting
though okay bye guys bye