good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2020 august
what day is today august 30 sunday
nine o'clock in the morning san
francisco time and today we are going to
do emacs and emac list
live coding uh plus tutorial
so first of all the background image the
background image is this
keyboard configuration the i created
x no code keyboard that's the name so
the idea of this keyboard you know i was
thinking i mean this is a physical
keyboard design
uh but i don't think i'm i will be able
to actually make it
you know you can do it as a do it
yourself but anyway it's an idea
it's an idea of a physical keyboard
design
and this keyboard the the primary
feature of this keyboard this design is
that
it minimizes it
it change it it is trying to get rid of
key chords such as ctrl c alt
tab things like that so read of
key chords read of the shift key as much
as possible
so you can see this keyboard the
in the middle you have a number pad and
uh
but you don't have the number row on top
you so you
so it reduces the use use of the shift
key
and because it's uh the number pad is in
the middle so you have
you have a separation of the hands so
there is no
so you don't need to um make them
uh like a v shape for ergonomic purposes
because now your hand is like on the
side it's uh
far apart wide enough and you have
tons of thumb keys thumb keys
uh and and i was thinking you know you
know
to in order to revolutionize
revolutionize
um the keyboard uh
market you have to make something cheap
so i
envision that this will be made very
cheap like
thirty dollars okay twenty dollars
thirty dollars
uh mass produced and uh
you know you could be rubber dome you
know just the cheap keyboard rubber
don't
and mass produce it
though of course but that may not be
likely unless if you are a
big corporation like microsoft or
logitech
anyway one you know and then of course
if we can have mechanical
keys then that would be much better
but that would add much to the cost
of creating this keyboard but anyway
there are two extra features
uh unusual feature features on this
keyboard you have two mouse wheels on
the right
so those are those are wheels just like
a mouse wheel
high quality wheel so one of the wheel
is intended to be
page up and page down while the other
wheel is
it can be volume sound volume up down or
it could be switching tabs or it could
be other things
uh it should be programmable so anyway
that's the background
image today and that is the x no code
keyboard
okay now let's begin to do emacs shall
we
so naivel neighbor are you here so
neighbor has a question
but you know if you are here type the
question
okay i'm gonna answer that emacs
uh good morning bots and uh sergio
thank you for uh checking out my uh
websites
so let's start to do emacs we have tons
of things to do
so i'm gonna show you what am i going to
do today
uh
so neibo if you are here ask your
questions okay any one of you
go go go ask your questions okay
uh and we are going to start to code
emac this
now now let's let me do one more check
to see if i am
doing well audio and video
okay we are going to code let me show
you what we are going to go
we are going to call this command okay
html named entity to char
um so okay so let's copy
this so in htmls you know you have a lot
entities okay
for example these are entities uh let's
see
for example all these bunch are entities
what do i mean uh you'll see what i mean
if i call the command okay
um
it
you see there it is that you see the
entities becomes
becomes characters let's magnify again
let's undo so actually let's just focus
on the first one okay
so you see
so this is before and now we call the
command this is
after call it
you see the html entities becomes
characters
what entity means is that in html if you
want to type some
some of the unicode characters such as
this uh
pound sign the british pound sign you
could
type that and when it shows in browser
it will become
it'll show as a pound sign but however
but however if you declare in html
with utf-8 let me show you okay
so you declare in html you say
charts.utf8 then
you don't need the entities you see the
entities are ugly that's the thing you
see they are ugly they are hard to type
you know you rather you know as time
goes on you want
the characters themselves you know the
technology the
that's what unicode is for so anyway so
i have a command so
so i have a command that converts all
the entities to characters
why do you need that because sometimes
you go uh grab
a webpage
sometimes you go to a website you grab a
novel okay
let's see if i can find some examples we
have a lot to do okay
um
well anyway sometimes you go you suppose
you want to put some
uh novel some classic novel let's say
uh a towel of two cities a tower of two
cities
to your website you grab it from one one
you know
one of the open source website and then
you have
you are not realize that they contain
lots of entities you know the
whoever created those html contains lots
of entities and you don't want that
i mean you want to make it more elegant
so you want to use the characters
that's that's when this command is
useful okay
let's try it again so here it is let's
do it
you see so that is the command
now there are something i want to uh
modify
okay right now the command only works on
the current line for example now i have
two lines here
now i put a cursor on the first line i
call it
i call it uh shortcut is uh that that
okay you see it only it assumes you want
to work on the current line
but but how i undo however what i want
is i want to
work on the current paragraph uh text
block
okay so let's go in uh we are going to
modify the command
so go to the source code describe key
press the key then it shows the
the documentation of the command
uh runs the command cause html name
entity to char
and tab to the link open it here we see
the source code okay here's the source
code
it's copy it and by the way go to the
top of the page this is
html mod okay you can download
on my git just search for the name
so create a new buffer paste it here and
save it
okay we want to say we we are going to
edit
modify this command so save it let's say
xx
that then today's state dot el
okay we saved it to the file we want to
modify
so instead of instead of assuming work
on the current line we want to work on
the current
paragraph text block so we go to the top
modify the inline documentation
replace html named entity to unicode
character
in current text
block or selection okay
for example the copy ampersand copy
semicolon symbol becomes a copyright
symbol
okay so
right so let's do it
so we have to do actually this is pretty
easy all we have to do
is change this part so this part says if
it's region uh let's see can you guys
see so
so if this region if you if you have any
comments questions just type it i'll
read it pretty soon so we all we have to
to do is change this part
so this part says if there's a region if
user selected region
then you just say beginning
region beginning and region end that's
the starting position and
end position of the place you are
interested
otherwise if there's no region you say
line beginning position and line
end position now
notice okay let me explain what's this
part interactive
for uh notice this function takes two
arguments beginning and end
okay it takes two positions uh in the
buffer two arguments
now normally in a programming language
you know you you have a function with
two arguments so you can call the
function and give two arguments
but in emacs lisp you see when you call
a function
when you call a command interactively
the question there's a question how do
you
actually give that command uh
arguments so emacs provides
a way to do that in fact there are many
ways but one of the basic way is
you you say interactive
okay then you then you um
you have this interactive clause
return a list okay so right now here we
are returning a list of two elements
and whatever that returns will become
will become the arguments to the
function
so that is what this interactive is for
so when you
for example when if i do meta x and i
call this command
i press enter you see there's no
arguments
but however because emac this sees this
line it will
then it will run this line interactive
and you it will find out
you know what arguments actually uh
to use so this part is actually
supplying the
beginning and end arguments so let's
modify it
so if there's a region region beginning
and region end that's correct but
otherwise
if there's no region here's what we want
to do
save excursion okay
uh if you don't know what say what save
excursion is look up
on my website okay save discussion
um
search backward okay search backward
backward two two empty lines
okay bound neo no
error true count okay
search backward and search forward
okay and then set
uh wait since
point okay return point returns the
current point
then
then do the pretty much the do the same
thing okay
then we search forward to the end of
paragraph search for
two new lines then we search backwards
so the cursor is back at the end of a
paragraph
then returns a point so here is the
beginning of paragraph position
and here is end of paragraph position so
we want both of them to be
inside the list okay so
that's that and then we don't need
this list here so let's
so that's our code okay
let's run it run the code back
to the back to our
html and
let's try it so we put the kuza on the
first line
and it should work on both of both lines
okay let's call it
okay uh wrong arguments wrong number of
arguments lambda beginning end
okay the wrong number of arguments
if least otherwise
oh yeah okay i know what is going on so
okay here is what we need
here is what we need so save excursion
if there's no region
we do this we run this block of code
and this code is going to return a list
the first
element of a list is you know this
this uh lines of code
at the end it returns a point and second
element of this
of the list is this line of code okay
run the code eval buffer
back to html it's called the code
command
fantastic it works okay that so that's
one
modification successful now there are
quite a lot more things to do
uh but now let's read
the comments see what you guys say
opinion on doom e-max
i never tried it okay i never tried
doing emacs
uh if you have any specific questions
you can ask me uh
s synthesia kings
synthesia king uh
you know if you ask me what my opinion
on doing emacs or space mac
my answer is just use stuff like keys
okay that's my recommend recommendation
because i created
soft light keys i use it and if you use
soft light keys
just use plain glue emax you don't need
helm
you don't need iv you don't need any you
know i recommend my recommendation don't
install any of those packages just soft
like keys
that's what i'm using right now it's the
most simple
efficient uh way of course that's my
buyer's
opinion so so once you have
uh plain glue emacs and stuff like keys
then
if you need you know just use it use it
for a month then
you might need you know maybe you need
something you can ask me on discord
remember to donate okay don't just keep
me asking questions
you can ask me on discord and then you
know
then you might install some other
programs gradually
so love your site button menu says love
your site have you
seen the uh
title new tactile variant no i haven't
seen that keyboard
i would also be interested in any idea
and opinion you have on how title doctor
could be improved
okay yeah i don't uh i don't know what
it's like
we we might talk about that later but
today we're going to focus on emacs
emacs list
so we i'm going to continue this uh
doing these uh
codies so we have done one of the things
we wanted to do
uh let's go to talk show let's see
what's the next thing
i want to do
okay go to class talk show today
then go to notes so this is
the notes to do
so modify excite html named entity to
char
so it works on text block instead of
lines
also make it highlight okay so yeah so
there's another thing we need to do we
want to make it highlight
okay we we want to make
highlight the changes
around a second
okay so so yeah here's our
our code now one more thing we want to
do we want to highlight the changes what
does that mean okay hold on a second
uh let's copy that copy that copy that
okay
we so we so we call the command it makes
the changes but
i want all the changed places
highlighted okay
so now let's go back to the code uh and
let's uh see if we can do it uh we can
fix it
let's see
yeah it's easy to do okay so let me show
you actually we
so yesterday in the past five videos
because our live
talk show we have let's go to my emacs
blog
in the past five videos it's all about
emacs this coding so if you are an emac
list you are learning emac this
you can you can watch the past five
videos also
they are all uh fairly condensed so
right now we want to highlight text
so we did this yesterday actually
yesterday and before
so we go to emac this how to write the
major mod
then then we want
um
let's see text properties yeah let's go
to text properties
okay so this is actually the code we
want
uh copy it copy it
so back close that so we're gonna modify
the code here
so the relative the relevant code is
actually just
this one okay um
it's pretty fun yet so put text
properties beginning end so the
beginning and end position will be
the end position will be point okay
the begin position will be
point minus
length of the last
match okay
so put text properties and give two
positions the first position is
is the the current cruiser position
minus the length of last replacement
um text
okay so we we we don't need this fixed
case in literal actually
and the second position is just point
then we add the property front lock face
then we say red okay so that's how you
add color so eval buffer
go back to html let's do it let's
make let's let's call the command oops
arcs out of range okay
uh arcs out of range what
oh yeah this part
this line needs to be inside the while
loop
okay eva buffer let's try it again
do it wait there's no color
do it no color okay now why no color i
think is because
this part let's say
let's just try that okay why how do i
know uh well that's technical details
you just have to have experience let's
do it
still no color okay so
okay this is annoying so we have to use
overlay instead
instead of instead of using text
properties we use
overlay
so let me show you how that how is that
so here's one line that's our o line
here is our new line
so this so we're gonna do this new way
the new way is going to be this is the
beginning position
and end position is just point
then uh front lock face
okay then uh
foreground red okay
this this line okay that's what we want
so common are that predefined
evil buffer go back to here
do it fantastic you see it works now
select the whole buffer wait hold on a
second
cut the whole thing close it let's make
a text block um
okay let's do this showing browser
uh well so anyway anyway so
so here is the okay
select the whole thing call it uh wait
uh make it html make it html mod
okay now magnify select the whole thing
do it fantastic you see all the all the
changed places are red
so that is done so that ends another
upgrade uh so so far successful so good
so
here's our code but that but there's
more there's more
uh change we can do so let's see what
what comments and questions
naibo sniper are you still here
so we've been talking for 25 minutes
that was pretty good today
uh so let me read the comments then then
we go to the next
thing we want to do
can you so search your says can you
share
keyboards for sale of the type keyboard
that you
recommend can you share keyboards
for sale links of the type i recommend
yeah
how can i set up the keyboard of my
macbook pro
i just set this huh
what do you want to do sergio uh
okay i want i want to talk about emac
this not keyboard today
i mean i talked about keyboard all the
time so anyway so let's go to
you just search for xrd keyboard so you
will arrive at my keyboard block
keyword blog you go to the ergo
keyboards
then there is a link best ergonomic
are pick in fact i just updated this
page yesterday
so here is our five keyboards that i
recommend you can pick any one of these
so you have microsoft ergonomic keyboard
this is the cheapest uh grade for emacs
you know intro keyboard 80 70 or
something it's
this is fantastic okay they know
you you want to spend 150 for kansas
freestyle
uh very good or miss uh mr
barocco okay this is also fantastic
oh this one is a bit more expensive 250
something like that okay it's it's
pretty good but if you have money
uh then expo
is also fantastic this you know i have
i have all these except you know i don't
have some of them but you know i have
this one this one is just fantastic
oh this one this is my current you know
i showed
almost every video i showed my keyboard
so i'm not going to do it again
uh so anyway that's the keyword i
recommend off the bat
okay i'm going to go back to emac this
so what is your question how can i set
up the keyboard of my macbook pro
either set this with what do you want to
do what like what
are you want to do
so so let's go back to the entities
okay yeah that's mistake okay so anyways
entities so now let me explain to you
what is entities uh
there are more things to do okay and
html enters
entities so you go to xsa html website
you search that xrd html tutorial you
you'll find my html tutorial and there
is a page
explaining about allowed characters
how do you do them you know what is
utf-8
uh encoding things like that uh
then uh character set and encoding
why is it not character setting encoding
and then
then you have the entity list okay
so in apparently
about about seven years ago five years
ago
the html5 maybe 10 years ago
the html5 people they added huge amount
of
entities so before they are about like
or 200 entities but but since html5
uh five years ago or so they added
a huge number like you know like a
thousand
entities you can see here
[Music]
now this is really uh idiotic you know
all these are unicode uh you see you
have
arrow down arrow a double let double of
arrow double up down arrow
double vertical bar and things like that
so instead of
having a character itself you can use
these ascii
um entities you know is that's not good
because
entities are very complex you know you
make your
technology you make your html5
html file unreadable
so anyway so you see there's pages there
are thousands of them
the html5 added them
[Music]
you see you can see it's endless before
before html5
uh you you you only have this many
okay let me show you
[Music]
uh where is it where is our code
yeah you see here is our code now before
html5
that's all you have you you have like a
hundred or two
let's let's show it let's copy let's see
how many okay
so here we have replace map
copy it a new buffer paste it
and uh let's make it
that's so you are looking at my workflow
okay so then then what we do is
we
we want to know how many are there
[Music]
replace
replace all so there are 248
so there there were there are 248 of
them
so anyway close that so what what i was
thinking of doing
is to update this command
because html named entity to char
so that they will contain
you know the new thousands of entities
you know because that is
that should be you know you should do
that because that's what this command
you know is supposed to be but i'm i'm
i'm
having doubts about that because
but because you don't really you
shouldn't use these
entities you know these people you know
i don't
i don't think this is a good design
so let's talk about design you know so
we are talking about you see
so this is html we are talking about
html
design of the html markup language
you know the specification so imagine if
you are
the designer of this html language
markup language
should you should you add you know
thousands of these entity entities
in my opinion no because you know as
technology advances you know first of
all why do we have entities in the first
place why do we have entities
in the first place why do we have this
you know you know for example if you
want
for example if you want the
the copyright symbol you can just you
know
you can just type it for example let me
show you how i type it
uh copy i press a key then you got that
or if you say if you want pound sign
pound
you see that's how i type it and uh um
the command i'm calling is this one
math input change to symbol
uh and in fact i have a package i can
show you so
let me show you the package okay
describe key uh space
space t calls our math input change to
symbol
and it is in this package some math
input okay so you open it
you can see
here is the source code go to the top
you can see this package is on melpa
okay and there's also a
home page so you go to the home page
showing browser
so this is a package i wrote that allows
you to type
thousands of unicode symbols
go go use it
okay let's go back to my talk show close
close that
and do let's go to my back to my talk
show
keyboard vlog
talk show okay let's
paste it here link talk show today's
topic
uh and entities okay let's not forget
about
entities so we were talking about
entities
so so paste it here showing browser
so that's today's topic and another
thing we talked about
is let's go to emacs blog you can see
this html replace
entities so here is a page
copy the file path copy the file path
close it close it
go back to my talk show page paste it
here
linkify showing browser there
there are the things we talked about and
now we need to reorder them
go back to emacs so first of all remove
those
uh extra url things let's
reorder them
okay show in browser so that's the
things we talked about
actually that the last one item should
be
at the bottom that's the
proper order
so as a design you see you are designing
a new html language
should you have the new entities i don't
think so because
as you know so before
so
you see why do we have entities because
let me show you okay let me tell you why
because
back in the days in the 1990s
unicode we don't have unicode yet well
unicode consortium
it began around 1990 around that time
but it was nobody knows it very few
people know it
new unicode didn't become popular until
let's say until 2000
to or something after 2000 year 2000s
so back then you only have ascii so
there's a problem in html so these are
the problem okay so let me show you
uh okay yeah
yeah i want to type right arrow okay
so that's you know
entity is just like the escape sequence
you know the backslash
escape in a string in in languages like
c
java pearl python you want to
because you need you need some
characters
you don't want special interpretation
things like that
that is why so if you want to have a
ampersand
in html i mean if you want to have a
less than sign or greater than sign html
you have to escape it
you have to you know for example you
have to type less than sign
using that entity instead why because
otherwise
otherwise the less than equal less than
sign
is used as a um
you know it's used as a markup
so to avoid confusion you have to have
entities you have some kind of escape
mechanism
so that's so these are the primary
entities these three these
three are the important the kind of
necessary html entities
okay then
then the people decided you know the
the html the web you know the html
people
decided we need some other characters
such as uh such as acute e
for example you know for european
languages
uh cedella a e
a with a ring on top you know acute a
things like that
why do you need that because you know
those characters are often used
in europe it's frequently needed
and meanwhile there's no way to do it
because unicode
was not popular it's not around yet
e so you have to use some other european
encodings
which is uh kind of
not popular neither because
back then remember back then in the
1990s
internet was not that popular yet
internet just began so if you are
american you know
but occasionally you know you want to
write a character with the european
language characters
entities are very useful so you can just
you know you just you can just type
this you know erq to have a
you know acute e so that's why
these entities are added also back then
in the 1990s you know internet before
you know internet back then was used
mostly
in academia used by mostly scientists
scientists mathematicians you know they
exchange information so so besides these
european characters you also have greek
characters
because greek characters are often used
in science sciences you know
in math mostly these are just for math
okay
math is the mother of everything
so you see so you then you have all
these math
symbols you know left arrow for example
these
uh these you know fantastic
uh characters imaginary part real part
of complex number
then you have the trademark sign then
you have a left symbol a left symbol
stand for
you know that the origin of this symbol
is is
from uh
uh is from um
the jewish language what what's what
what is what's the name of that language
uh hebrew hebrew
but anyway in math this means a left
a left symbol it means the
i think it means countable infinity you
know in fact we can look up
there it is
magnify magnify yeah in mathematics
particularly particularly in set theory
the left numbers are a sequence of
numbers used to represent the
cardinality or size of a infinite set
that can be well ordered exactly so a
left not
a left a left zero a left knot
is the smallest infinite cardinal number
which is con
you know known as countable infinity
i'm pretty sure you know don't quote me
on that cut on the number
uh
i'm pretty sure it's countable infinity
so anyway
that's uh that's uh advanced math
okay so so back to entities you see
so you you know you have some
entities for math symbols
so that's the origin of entities so in
summary in in
the beginning you just have you know
three entities to escape the special
characters
then back then because it's very
extremely convenient to
have some characters for you european
languages or math
symbols so you know then that's why you
have this
about 250 entities
okay so this is 1990s
now so but after 20 years after
around 2010 you know by 2010
unicode is very popular it's you know
almost every you know the entire web
technology is based on utf-8 unicode
unicode is well known you know because
internet
internet began the communication between
different countries
so now it's um it's normal
for you know people talking you know
european countries or japanese or
chinese talking to each other
so and we use unicode because unicode
have you know
hundreds thousands of characters
but so do you need so why do you need
entities
for you know you can use unicode
directly you don't need
you don't need entities for you know all
these thousands of characters
so i think so in my opinion as a
designer
if you are going to design html language
you shouldn't add them
because by now the technology for
unicode is
very mature you know you know remember
back then when you
use ascii you you have transmission
problems because if you any character
that's
that's more than eight bits you may have
transmission
problems because all those uh internet
protocols are based on
a byte
but now we we no longer have that
problem
so i don't see i don't see i don't think
it's a good design for the html people
to add all these entities
okay so anyway any anything else
so neighbor says swabs was dying was
eating
dinner so naivo if you have the question
ask it again i'll answer it okay
then maybe that's it for today how long
have we been talking
because you know i want people to ask
questions when we are live
so peop you know so people can see it so
sergio says
what i can do is insert characters like
uh
that that but i cannot find where is the
key
in a keyboard in mac os sorry if i
cannot explain
i don't understand what you mean so i
just i don't understand what you mean
insert characters but i cannot find
where is the
keys in the keyboard
in mac os what do you mean where is the
key saying on a keyboard
in mac os keyboard is a physical
keyboard
so you can see usually there's labels on
it so you you know
and so how what how is you know what do
you mean keyword macro is
yeah i don't understand your question
sergio
okay so neighbor asks the question can
you explain the general idea behind
socket things okay let's talk about that
okay so back to
uh first of all let's finish this back
to an entity
so what we're gonna do so anyway we
yeah so if we are going to add all these
entities
you know basically we just create uh you
know more lists
here you know more elements here then
you
will work so it's not that interesting
so let's skip that so if i decided i
want
actually to do it i'll i'll do it
offline
so let's talk about thing at point
naibo's question
so in emacs you have let's open a new
buffer okay
so in emacs wait before we do that
let me finish this so we we have
completed
editing this code okay so let's
delete the file then
put it back in my html mod so
where is it let's find the code okay so
what yeah the easiest way
is actually describe key then press the
key
then jump to it yeah what
okay i uh yeah
back to html mods so here it is
so paste it paste it okay
then select the old code
and uh
we don't need it okay so we have a new
code
so here is our new code
save it go to the top of the file
and update the version number okay
let's say three okay
okay back to the html and save it go to
e-shell git status
git add
git commit
okay git commit commit we say
better improved improved
improved site html named entity to char
okay committed then git push
so now you will see that on my github
xlr html mod
okay close that so that's done that's
done for that
close that close that now we can talk
about a new thing so let's talk about
thing at point
let me create a new buffer so create a
new buffer
magnify so defend
yeah let's talk about thing at point
okay go to my emacs tutorial
and we'll be done in in five or ten
minutes
including answering neighbor's question
uh go to my tutorial so you go to emac
list
introduction to emac beast then
you go down a little bit then you'll see
a section
that's get buffer string here
you see get buffer string and and this
section
tells you how do you get
you know grab the text under cruiser you
know you have a cruiser position
somewhere in the buffer
so let's say you want the current world
or you want the
url under cruiser or you may want
something else
under cruiser that's how you do it so
for example
so for example you can do buffer
substring no properties
then give two positions that will return
the string
of the text between those two positions
that's
you know that's this function that's how
you get the string uh
alternatively if you want you know if
if user has a text selection then you
can say
uh region beginning and region n
you know both substring no properties
then to
to to return the string of that region
then sometimes you want the current word
you know the word under cursor then you
just
use the command current word okay but
sometimes
you want the okay current line
and or sometimes you want a file name
okay let's do it okay so let let's let's
write a command let's uh
let's explain this interactively
what's going on here um
what is this let's go to talk show
what is this emacs vlog close
okay so back our code so let's say uh
define function let's say get
something okay let's say dark string
return the url
under cruiser okay so
so what you do is you
uh you say buffer substring no
properties okay
then start and it start position and
end position so you can say
thing at point okay that's how you do it
see thing at point then you just say url
okay
that okay predefine the code that's how
you do it and you don't need
that anymore
okay you don't need you don't even need
both a substring no properties you just
need thing at point so run that okay
that eval buffer
okay then that's a command name
uh let's say okay i
i need a url okay so let's let's
find the url then
so we have a url here so i put a cursor
somewhere
somewhere here
you know this is one paragraph so i put
kuza somewhere in your url
i call the command meta x get
thing get something you know our command
do it it returns okay it returns but you
don't know because it doesn't
do anything so actually so you just want
to
message okay print it
okay evaluate it evaluate
it and try it again call the command get
something
now you can see in the message you know
you it prints out the url so that's how
you do it
and uh then in a similar way you can
also
make this current word okay so if you
change it to word
okay evaluate the code
and
[Music]
here work okay so but
for example let's call it here okay so
you can see it's
it shows water there okay but anyway
thing at point there are
there's another let me let me get to the
question okay there is another use of
thing at point
what you want is
[Laughter]
what you want is um you know sometimes
you want
you know you you want to grab the string
you know it returns a string but
some other times you want you want the
beginning
and end position of the thing
so in that case so there are two two
uh major functions from the package
thing at point one of them is just sting
at point
uh let me let me write this thing at
point
uh okay so this is one of the way to use
it so
all these you know you see all these
arguments those are all the possible
arguments so you can have variety of
things
symbol means symbol just means the word
you know
a programming languages keyword under
kuza
so what does you know what's the
difference between symbol and
word well the difference is mostly like
um
you know like whether whether whether
hyphen or
or low line counts or not
okay something like
this okay for example if you have a word
like that
depending on you know if so what do you
mean by a word
by a word does it does it mean just that
or does it
mean that or does it mean the whole
thing including underscore
so that's the major difference between
word and symbol
and in e-max you know these two things
is dependent on the major mod depending
on the character table
anyway most often they
often what they how they differ is just
whether they include underscore i've
hyphen
that that's usually the case so anyway
besides symbol and word you can also
have a list
okay for example let's do a list example
that would be interesting okay
uh let's do the sixth example okay
so so yeah sixth so let's put it here
instead
okay so that's our new function okay
evaluate it and now put cursor somewhere
here
show the message buffer so so you'll see
the result here
so we put the cursor somewhere under
here okay let's say
let's say put it here then call the
function
meta x get something
uh it returns message okay you see
it returns message but what if
we put it the cursor under here let's
see what it does
get something uh it just returns
sixth okay what if we put the cursor
under the beginning of
a parent let's call it there it is
that's you see then it returns the
sex symbolic symbolic expression that's
this syntax you see so anyway that's
so thin at point so you you have all
these uh different
arguments depending on what you want to
get
okay now the other another use of thing
at point is
let's say what okay
[Music]
the name is called bounce of thing
at point okay
so instead of just returning the string
it will return the beginning and end
position of that thing
okay so the thing could be you know file
name word
white space or line things like that it
returns the
two positions
so anyway so thing at point you see with
all these possibilities there
is you know they don't have something i
want
which is a paragraph so
for example typically when you call
command such as
replace entities command typically you
want to do
the change on a whole paragraph because
a paragraph is a fundamental unit
in writing you know also in code
for for example this is one paragraph
usually if i want to call some some
command that capitalize something you
know usually it's uh
between empty lines you know one
paragraph
that's a unit convenient unit so i don't
you know i don't want to require a user
to select it first
so user can just call it and you'll work
on the paragraph
so i often need a you know a
i need something that read you know that
works on paragraph
but thing at point doesn't support that
therefore i have a package i wrote
that's called
sarget thing i think
okay let's see let's call the command
let's see if we can find it
describe function get
thing at point yeah there it is there it
is the function
[Music]
okay so here is the documentation for my
function
start getting is a list closure in
socket thing.el so that's the
that's the package it's on mailpad okay
so this is how you use it
so you open let's go to the source code
so here's the source code
[Music]
uh it's on lpa so you can use it so let
me just show you how to use it
okay so for example i remember i want a
paragraph
so let's use it okay uh so let's use it
so what how do we use it let's see let
me show you okay require
socket thing that's right
[Music]
then let's get something
then uh then let's get something and
what's the command
uh because i'll get thingy at point okay
cause i'll get bounce of thing at
or region yeah okay so here is what um
what we want to do let's call the
command
let's describe function to see the doc
same with uh
okay okay here's the documentation okay
target spawns of thing
let me show you how this works uh so
what do i want block okay
the unit is going to be a block
[Music]
okay like that
okay so let's position one position two
and bounce bounce is a boundary okay
so set
bounce equals to
that so so what this means
i want the boundary beginning and end
position of
the of a text block okay you'll get it
so but however if user has already
made a selection then return the
boundary of that selection
so this will save lots of code
so once you get the boundary then you
let's say then you
delete region okay delete region
um p1 uh
position one position two
set p1 car
okay and set
p2 cutter bounce
okay then we don't need this we don't
need that we don't need that we don't
need that
okay so that's our code
[Music]
so here's our code basically what it
will do is
delete the current paragraph okay so
let's evaluate it
now let's put cusa somewhere here
you know somewhere inside this uh
paragraph
then just call it code it'll just remove
the whole paragraph
but however if if i have made some
selection let's say i made this
selection
and i call it it'll just delete that
code you see
so that is what sarge thing is for does
that make sense
neighbor okay that's
i think that's it thank you guys for
watching
one hour and five minutes if you like my
stuff
go buy my tutorial okay so just search
for
emacs tutorial
thank you bye guys
and uh now let's just let me do some
clean up
and uh copy it
delete the file fantastic i love you
see ya brother uh go to the talk show
paste the page code there show in
browser
today's result and back to
emacs syntax color
show in browser maximize fantastic so we
talked about
today no code keyboard fantastic
then siteml named
entity to make it highlight we did that
fantastic
then
[Music]
then we have the source code on my
website actually so you can grab it
but however i haven't updated the code
here yet
so i'm going to do that then we talked
about
entities and
then we talked about the design the
design of a
markup language whether should we have
this unicode character
entities then we talked about
xr math input mod then we talked about
get thing okay now if you search for
socket thing you know
there's actually a web page uh you know
home page for it so here's the my
package is
home page socket thing okay copy it
shrink the browser back to emacs and
back to my talk show pc here
linkify show in browser
there it is thank you guys bye
you