hello guys good morning welcome to
another episode of s talk show we going
to code wolam
language uh if you are here say hi hello
toga toga I remember I think I remember
you toga toga where you from and uh
we're going to call wam language plain
curves geometry okay you're going to
learn some mathematics
and wolam language coding okay I'm just
going to go slow easy if you are here
say hi love to see your comments if you
are not here play at 1.5 speed and jump
around that's critical because I ramble
over if you don't jump around or uh you
know you jump around or when you are
driving you can like listen to
my
Rambo in sequence
okay so we're going to do W uh coding so
uh I want to get a drink first so let me
show
you my
equipment
glass
Coke hello theago now report where you
guys from I don't remember everything
okay so you got to report
so that is
Coke and we going to have
tequila repos
something from a recommendation of a
friend
today is Friday on Friday I practice
hunger diet that means suffer from
hunger and
uh the goal of hunger diet is live
forever it's better diet than dinosaur
diet or whatever American diet
Obsession Che
damek is from
France Thiago is from
Brazil sou Polo
Brazil That's a place where you got the
giant Jesus sculpture right I
think or maybe that's the other
city I never been to Brazil but all I
know is Brazilian girl girls they are
hot they got big
ass toga my favorite base Chinese come
back soon don't want to wait in silence
I'm here okay let's begin uh coding okay
so if you are not familiar with wolam
language uh let's go let's go Brando
uh let's put this
here and uh here we go slowly at leisure
okay uh life is good uh no need to
rush okay today's talk show so you can
see all the
topics uh you know if you watched me I
have over 100 wolam language videos and
tutorials so search for Wam Language
tutorial you'll find it and you can
download uh not going to repeat all that
so and uh we're going to do plan curves
so I've done like 100 videos on these
things so just check out so today we're
going to do uh not certain okay so you
got um we're going to do one of these
though so last time we did
Parabola few days ago uh we did
tremendous you know Parabola properties
we did this one tangent properties
of Parabola so I'm not going to repeat
it and this we need to
redo okay let's just start to
um so open the parabola file so I'm in
emac of course using Sly Keys the most
advanced key binding system on Earth
this is class sly key source code 4,000
lines of code and go to the top and you
go to this URL this is Sly Keys
introduction the most advanced efficient
key binding system on Earth more
efficient than Vim okay uh less
keystroke than Vim so there's a
introduction video and uh it's a key
binding system for the text editor emac
the most powerful text editor for
programmers so this would be of interest
to programmers okay uh yeah so but today
we're going to do this wolam language so
go to the top. MB so open the wolam
language notebook this is this is
notebook Parabola open it this is a
source code of the notebook now open
wolam
language now notebook differs from the
com command line unit [ __ ] okay the
command line all also known as
repo uh the obsession of industrial
coders you know so what is
repo press a key go to pow shell there
is your pow shell okay so in emx press a
key that calls the
command open in terminal search for that
you'll find the source code you so you
can
open the terminal of the current
directory so do it again see works on
the Mac or W or Linux or Windows okay so
you can see I'm in this directory now
let's magnify control scroll
up uh okay so duh so magnify again duh
you see this is repo this is shell this
is Bash you know this is uh repo stand
for I have article on
that go to kali. info search r p it's a
Ed concept especially from the python
Zumer
idiots okay let's see repo
versus there it is command line
interface repo versus notebook interface
so in this article I detail I tell you
why
which one is superior of course that's a
notebook interface so what is the
difference let me we digressed already
so let me explain this in a command line
interface or also known as a shell
basically you have you type one command
after another uh you know in sequence
then if you want to go to if you want to
call previous command you can press up
Arrow or uh control uh are to search
back then you might add it you know for
example let let me show you let's see
Kasa too doc theme okay you can find the
source code for that as well so you see
it's doc theme and in emac press the key
doc theme doc theme the
supremacy of my system okay I don't want
do theme so turn turn it back okay now
the pink window becomes white uh leave
it white okay so there's article on that
dark theme and there are actually 10
articles on Dark theme so is Dark theme
good for you you see when you Dark theme
is one of those subject matter where
it's dramatic everyone will love to talk
about it what what's your opinion what's
your favorite them you
know but if you talk about mathematics
no two people watching
okay Dark theme we talked about before
but here this is article that tells you
everything you need to know about Dark
theme and in summary is Dark theme good
no Dark theme destroy your eyes don't
use it okay if you want to know the
details read the article so press a key
to power
shell press a key to tle do them do it
so now it's white white means theme
fantastic okay so here is article on
Dark theme should you use dark theme is
it good what does science say science
you know you have to listen to science
and then um then there's article CSS
stock theme that is about how do you
actually make your website doc theme so
there's a lot of details it's not just
you know you can actually just put this
code in and your system will become dark
theme depending on if your operating
system is dark then your your website is
dark if your operating system is light
your website is right okay so just this
code but that's not all because if you
just do it then a lot of your website
will become [ __ ] you know for example
these images SVG images and and some
other details for example your keyboard
diagram will become blacked out so
there's you know
details uh then there is also okay lots
of details then JavaScript so you can
click a button to turn it dark theme or
light theme so this is how to do it and
uh then there is why windows you know
Windows is one of the most idiotic
operating
system nothing you can do about it they
are idiotic not because the programmers
at at Microsoft are idiots that's not
the reason they have a lot money they
can in fact they have created great
operating systems but the problem is
they saturated the market so they don't
change and besides they are affiliated
with deep state state so Microsoft you
know they are the way they are they
don't have to change because it doesn't
do them any good it sucks but you still
goingon to use
it why because on the other side you
have the Linux idiots like most of you
guys the Linux idiot they they think
their operating system is so good but
actually nobody can actually use
it without being a nerd you know a
computer nerd for like 10
years nothing works in
Linux okay we digressed so much but
about this stock theme so Windows stock
theme got lots of problems and so this
article details the problem then you got
Powershell this is the code where you
can toggle dog theme okay do it
dog dog
you know here is Twitter now Twitter is
another got another idiotic thing going
on you see Twitter inter
interface they allow you to have dark
theme
but I I I'm not going to go into my
settings but you can choose between dark
or white okay but however it doesn't
automatically adjust according to your
operating system so my operating system
right now it's dark but tror doesn't go
dark you know so it really sucks you
know because at night when you you know
after Sunset your system goes dark set
by the operating system but tror is like
shiny Shar your eyes so Twitter you know
so you got lots of problems with dark
theme okay so I don't recommend
it uh okay close that yeah that's that's
not what I
want okay do theme and then here is emac
this is everything you need to know
about themes color themes in emac okay
so for example I can um
load theme okay so what theme you want
Tango okay let's see Tango Tango looks
like
that but anyway but I have my own so
let's just do it okay so I don't want
Dark theme
uh what yeah okay yeah anyway so that's
about Dark theme now let's go back to
what we need to do okay wam language now
I don't I don't like this okay I don't
like these them so let's do it
again okay so starting a new emac
instance uh and
uh okay and close that showing browser
back to emac close showing browser back
close close close close close close
close okay create that so now you
got and back to where I
was now you need to adjust the
window so wam language coding okay let's
go back to wam language
coding so good so far so good let's go
back to mathematics the all important
not the theme color theme drama okay so
you see
fantastic uh typ
set stuff okay so let me think about
what we want to do okay so Parabola you
got this light source do we have it at
no okay so we need to
update uh update this image
respond on
Brazil hey Sam
Hammer how do you code in inferior
language without going
nuts very easy don't code in inferior
languages and if you are forced to quit
quit your job
okay let's just do this
one
um like so we are doing the light Ray
property of Parabola okay so we got yeah
so let's do
that so this is the
code uh let's go to talk show today's
talk show this one opening browser back
to emac and uh start a code block wolam
language paste the code and pop it out
okay so here is a wolam language code
okay let's clarify it a little bit uh we
got
[Music]
rotate okay so you
see you see this Parabola
um the formula for Parabola is this one
okay let's copy that here there
okay so here we need plan Cur generator
we need um we need the formula for
Parabola okay so where is
the yeah the formula is very
simple the formula is just that okay
copy that go to wam paste it here paste
shift enter so you can can see that's
the parametric formula equation for
Parabola okay so now
press now let's magnify so you can see
better okay so now press shift control n
to make it type set now you see now it's
more better uh what we want to do is so
we got a formula okay so we got a
formula the formula is that okay
so we got the formula and so this
formula will replace this this part okay
so it's just
that okay and
uh
wait okay
then what we are doing here is
um you see it's it's got this rotation
going on can you see
that so you want to rotate this formula
by
um by Pi / 2 pi/ 2 is 90° okay so
actually let's not use that so now this
rotate formula I created I mean I wrote
it 30 years ago so you don't want it
so rotate 90° that's just swapping so
let's do this manually
okay so you don't so
rotate remove the
rotate and
simply swap X and Y that should do it
and then this + one one is to move it
um uh should we do that okay it doesn't
matter okay
so so yeah we don't want this rotate
remove
it okay
then the parameters from negative 3 to 4
and 04 okay so let's let's do this again
okay
parametric okay parametric
plot of this formula
uh3
to4 okay uh and uh what are these
options PL range
or okay and aspect ratio automatic okay
there copy that remove the semicolon
because why let me let me explain this
one because it's interesting okay go
here click
click what paste
evaluate uh oh yeah we got extra comma
remove that shift enter you see it's
empty because of the
semicolon this is an interesting point
because the semicolon in wam language if
you have a semicolon at the end that
suppresses the
output okay this is very interesting but
uh we're going to digress uh um okay let
me quickly explain it okay so in emac LP
so for example in emac this uh we can do
you you you in emac this you got this
program and thing that groups a bunch
bunch of thing for example
messages High okay then um
wait let's say
hello
world okay let's remove that so you see
this
PRN the only thing it does is group this
whatever is inside of it as a one single
syntactic unit okay so we can run the
code uh run the code and go to the
message buffer you can see hello word
okay and this P GN Returns the last
expression which is this one okay so why
do you want to group so this is similar
to in C programming languages or
JavaScript it's similar to the curly
braces okay or in UK they call it curly
brackets in United States we just call
it braces in United Kingdom they say cra
brackets the United Kingdom way is
actually more logical because you have
round
brackets square brackets then CI bra
brackets now in United States we say
parenthesis
bracket
braces okay that's interesting so anyway
so in C in C programming language you
have this
braces you know that's that's that makes
your code a syntactic block okay so in
emac lisp in lisp in general you have
this
PN that serves a similar purpose kind of
similar syntactically
okay so in wolam language wolam language
is actually a lisp you have exactly the
same thing so what is the wolam language
version of PN okay hold on a second let
me explain a little bit more why do you
need this
PN in this it's actually it's critical
just like in C this C brais is critical
when you have if statement okay so let
me show you so let's go to JavaScript
mod uh console log 3
okay so run it this is Javascript okay
file file not save first save first okay
uh okay so hold on a second so let me go
back let's create okay I'm
uh JavaScript and let's create a new
block of
code uh what were we doing uh emac this
okay
okay okay so cut that close paste okay
now color it showing browser so you got
wolam language code you got JavaScript
code JS you got emac L code so let me
explain this C basis
thing so in JavaScript or C
C uh syntax derived languages
what's the what is the significance of
the curly braces let me
explain what is
the
significance of curly
Braes in C like
syntax lens okay that is a question let
me show you so the craes function as a
group grouping of statements so for
example right now we are in JavaScript
so you have if statement if three is
true then let's say console
log is true okay so you see there's a
cly
basis and we can add another
statement and you can say and I love you
okay so remove that so if we run
this run it if three is true or not it
is true is true and I love you okay now
if you want a else
else again cly braces then you
say I hate you okay now press a key to
pedify the
format I'm using Kar JavaScript mod
okay so you can see uh
wait JavaScript mod okay here's a source
code the source code is uh
1,500 lines
okay if you like it you pay me to get it
okay if you like myff pay me JavaScript
mod you
got El Moda JavaScript Moda HTML mod and
CSS mod and Goan mod and K diet mod got
a lot goodies and Kasa WFA mod kasaa mod
is free you go to the GitHub and you can
download it
instantaneously okay but the other ones
are not free they used to be free but
the open source
[ __ ] they pay nothing and they just
ask you questions every day like uh or
argue with you uh this should be that
way you know you got a bug you know you
know they argue with you uh this should
be coded this way and you know blah blah
blah that's the phenomenon of the open
source
scums so now you have to pay I'm not a
tech support anymore you know like I
spend one hour every day literally every
day or two hours for like over for more
than 10
years so they are not free but they are
still open source okay so JavaScript mod
and uh you can see and a whole bunch of
my EXA mods okay
okay I digress so much so let's copy
that hold on a second so let's put the
links to talk
show uh go to talk show so you are also
looking at my workflow okay so there is
there is Javascript mod
copy or one single key press there s
packages okay close and we back here
okay so back
here okay showing browser yeah close set
Clos that okay we back here so we what
we just did is that we pred defy the
code you see we can make it one single
line now run the code is it true I love
you now if you change the three to false
run the
code I hate you okay now press one key
the code has been pred
defied so that command is part of
JavaScript mod that command is KJS
format buffer okay you need the Deno
installed anyway so you see they also
remove the curly brackets you see they
remove it uh let's add it
back let's add it back because they
remove it because in JavaScript if you
only have one statement then you don't
need the curly brackets cly braces you
see um so that is the purpose of curly
braces they group they syntactically
group a collection of statements in
JavaScript
okay so
okay so run the code again yeah
okay so now press the key to pedify it
okay so that is the significance of
curly braces in C like syntax languages
okay now now uh remove that put it back
color showing browser go down there it
is now
so
similarly you have emac disp so go to
disp so pop it up so similarly why do
you need this PN to group a bunch of
this Expressions why do you need it well
you need it when you have if
statements
if
true then
program
print okay love you
okay
now if false
print H yeah H okay now press the key to
color it to uh format it now we
can run it okay so comment that out run
it so run oh yeah you forgot to um wait
show in browser there it is I mean show
the message wither okay there it is I
love you okay so let's um so actually
you see okay now it looks
better so you need to group so for
example when you have another
statement hello
world Okay C format it pretty format it
run
it uh show message buffer so you can see
Hello what I love you so you need to
group these two print State print
Expressions together that's why you have
P GN the purpose is similar to the C
language cly
brais because if you don't you know if
you don't have that then it becomes if
true print this otherwise print that you
see that's the issue
okay so undo so
um okay now put it back syntax color
showing browser refresh there is a list
version now let's tell let me tell you
about the wolam language version because
wolam language
is basically a lisp okay now if you go
to my wam Language tutorial you'll see
uh essay about that okay thisp versus
wolam language so here this
article uh they
enumerate
or suchar
similarities so you can go down you can
see the syntax one is a Lis way one is a
wam language way commment and uh every
other function for example if expression
grouping in wam language is com is
called compound expression or semicolon
which I'm going to explain right now
okay then you have arithmetics then you
have bulling equality test you know and
Ne or not true false equal greater than
you know this like almost everything in
thisp there is
almost you know the the is almost the
same analogous one in wolam language
because they because wolam language is
um because lisp is a parent of wolam
language
okay
so okay let's go to my talk show put the
link here and let's uh let's start to
explain okay
so so let's go to the wolfen language
okay
so let's do a new
one pop it out so compound expression so
let's do the same thing if uh if
true okay
then
print I love
you else
print I hate you okay fantastic run
it there there it is I love you okay now
what if you want if you have
two statement there two EXP
well you need like the EAC L you need PL
in but in wam language they they named
it well so you don't have like prog in
what the [ __ ] is plog in you have
compound expression so let me show
you there it is so you put this inside
compound expression one two you know or
more
arguments hi I love you
okay so let's I don't have a pretty
format in emac for Wam language so I
have to like you have to manually do the
inent you know but
anyway um but if you copy this for
example you copy the whole thing copy it
go to the wolam language
paste it oh you got a mistake hold on a
second we need to correct the
um uh yeah you don't you cannot have
that because this you see
so copy that c paste make it one line
copy it and uh
paste you
see shift enter you see hi I love you
now copy the previous input you can make
it
[Music]
um shift control
n h it doesn't do any I
mean that's the thing I'm going to
explain okay so you see you got this
compound expression okay uh let's remove
that you got this compound
expression that's how you group things
together because in wam language
everything
is like regular syntax nested okay but
this compound expression is too long too
too much to type so wam language has the
idea of
meta expression which which means for
every nested expression like lisp you
know in this this this nested expression
is called are called
sex okay this stand for symbolic
expression s
XP but this also have the idea called
meta expression originally in
1960 by McCarthy the guy who invented
this you know so he he wrote about meta
expression we should have that but lisp
never implemented it that's the end of
the story so so Le people to this day
they stick with the extremely nested
parenthesis
expression they they never have you you
know you cannot write 1+ two you know in
this is
very annoying if you want to
say you know it's very you know when you
want to do a lot of arithmetics
arithmetics um then it becomes very
cumbersome because you got this nested
for example you got this nested uh you
know
or you know it's impossible to
read so that's a problem but in wam
language you have uh so hold on a second
let me
uh let me okay
so so one let's say let's change this to
4 5
six evaluate that that's 22 okay now if
you have infix notation then that's
going to be 1 +
uh 2 * 3
then
four then 5 + 6 okay five plus six so
this way uh so
this much easier to understand so let's
try that in actually let's try that in
Python
okay uh so wait cut C let's um we
digressed
but uh okay so that's another topic
let's go
here IM my this paste okay then create
python okay uh let's not python let's do
JavaScript okay so this belongs to
JavaScript so
this 22
okay put it back now
JavaScript console log that run it oh I
got a error so oh yeah so you need
to there it is 22 okay
[Music]
so run it uh
right
uh right
uh there it is 22 okay so that's
JavaScript now color demo uh actually we
never made mistakes so
actually color demo showing
browser so here
is the list version of arithmetics and
here is the JavaScript version of
arithmetics so the infix notation is
much easier to read okay now we
digressed now let's go back to the
compound expression so wolam language
has
this this syntax shortcut so meaning
that compound Expression A
B can be written simply
as a semicolon B okay
so this is equiv equivalent to that so
that makes this much simpler so instead
of that then you just have um
that okay yeah so this is the same as
that so you see the compound expression
is simply a semicolon in
between okay so we can run this for
example let's run
it uh what yeah so run
it there it is hi I love you okay okay
that's about this compound expression
this is a syntactical issue so we
explained the cly brais the cly brais of
the C syntax in
JavaScript to group uh group a bunch of
statements together then you have the
list version which is p o g n a group a
bunch of expressions together then you
have the wam language version which is
compound expression also group things
together okay let's put it
back now let's uh let's put
the let's put the JavaScript version
first okay because because JavaScript is
easier to understand because most people
industrial coders that's what they know
they don't know about lisp or the wolam
language so you got JavaScript first
then you got
uh this version
there okay then wam language version now
color it all showing
browser there uh there it is
Javascript thisp W okay that's a
digression that's a giant digression
about this syntactical
issues uh this is important when you
design a
language so you know I give
uh you know a dive down on the on all
the details so we I need a
drink am I doing
good so there's a question about have I
ever done hascar before no but I'm doing
the proof systems I'm doing the link
programming language and F shop okay uh
I don't like hascal much because
hascal since about 2010 hascal is field
became a
fad you know then you got a bunch of
young people zumas they babbling about
you know they
driil you know because tascal is uh pure
functional language so it's so cool so
they drible they don't know
nothing they drible like category Theory
monad but they don't know
nothing so I don't really like hascal so
let's have a little bit more
drink uh so it's already 1
hour and
uh I'm doing good thank you hello tyer
so let's have this we got to get this
drink
right just a little bit
okay how is the SW board going
made and I haven't done anything with
it uh yeah but but I will okay so let's
go back so who are
you Nostalgia
nostal here yeah I will I will do
it another question do you ever try VSS
Code PO co-pilot
no I don't use I don't like you know I
don't use any of the AI copilot [ __ ]
okay but they are useful but if I want
to use them I go to uh I go to
gr so for example I can then G is very
good uh and it's also available on the
website so you just go to G just search
for G AI chatbot
chatbot you you'll find it I think it's
free
okay so sometimes especially when I'm
learning a new language like right now
now I'm learning link and I'm also
learning f shop so I use qu to ask
questions or show code it's very useful
uh
but but I don't like the the common
idiots you know like when you code you
don't know what's going
on you know if you are learning a new
language that's a good thing
but but um but if you are doing a
profession if you are a professional
coder you have to and then you rely
copilot or whatever [ __ ] that's that
that means you don't know what you're
doing that's that's no good you you you
use AI to help you understand the
language you know you have to understand
reasonably okay not necessarily master
master is always good but today you got
so many things you got you know five 10
languages usually three languages you
have to know for a job um
ideally you should Master every one of
them but life is lots of things you know
you work and there's also mathematics
like mathematics is like infinite depth
you can spend all your life on math and
you cannot learn much so you can't you
know just Master everything so but you
have to know it reasonably well for the
programming language you are doing your
job
with but today you know with the zumas
there's a lot them of them like they
don't know even the basics like they
don't know the basics they just let's
try you know the the chat gbt co-pilot
oh this is a code let's try it and fix
it you know but they don't know
actually have little idea exactly you
know they don't really understand the
code you know they just
like especially especially especially
the
Zoomers Okay so we uh digress let's go
back to uh actually plot this thing okay
so actually you see the semicolon remove
it now do it you see now we got the
curve okay fantastic beautiful okay
showing browser let's get this quickly
done and that will be it today I mean
let's finish this curve okay so you got
the formula correct let's
see uh so it's more moving upward why
should you move no uh let's not move
okay
then
then3 23 okay PL range all okay remove
that okay so that is a code make it one
line
copy
paste okay that's beautiful
now now you want to um
what you want to do now you want to draw
yeah okay so you want to draw the
reflection the reflection of the light
rays okay let me show you how to do
that
um okay so we
need okay so we need uh one of my
package let's go to Parabola Let's uh
yeah copy that
so so we basically need that okay so
let's paste it
here and
uh okay the curve
is the curve is that okay uh
let's three two
okay okay so let's go here okay
so
okay
uh here okay
so plle plot plot this
formula -3 to3 in increment of
04 then costic length five costic
origin uh that's
two one not sure about that uh the the
focus should be one Zer okay so let's
let's try that for now okay put down
force x ratio remove that okay let's try
that okay so you
need you need
this thing okay copy
that paste draw it
beautiful can you see
that
beautiful now let's remove the
complexity let's not plus one + one that
that move the whole curve to uh one to
the right one to the up upward so the
COS orine will be one zero okay
one zero
Okay so so PL this curve with this
range and the rest are options okay this
is W language copy
that do it beautiful wouldn't you say so
we successfully done it you see very
interesting because now you can change
the focus the costic or engine
cic cic means the reflection of light
rays
so when you have a
curve that's formed by the set of
lines that's called costic okay costic
so anyway basically just think of it as
reflection of light race okay so if you
change this to let's say um
0.3 or you know 0.9 and
0.3 shift enter you see you started to
get different
things so let's make the ray longer
costic length
50 you see okay 50 is too much let's say
uh
10 you see this is a design of the you
know kind of headlamp and
stuff but this is what we want okay
let's copy that um
you see there's an animation let's do
that animation okay actually we need to
do that
animation uh let's try that again
okay there it is and uh so now we don't
need this Del delete
delete okay delete delete delete this is
the code now we want to do an animation
so what you do is you want to animate
this plot so you just do a lot of
it
uh table okay so table of two arguments
the first one is expression the second
one is a parameter so you want parameter
X goes
from uh let's see where do you want the
okay goes
from let's say
five to
0 uh
1 five okay in increment of
0.1 okay now what is the expression the
expression is just this okay so now this
expression there
okay now in this expression you want to
yeah so this costic origine is X you
know then X goes from 0.5 to 1.5 in
increment of 0.1 okay so if you you do
that okay so if you do that select all
paste shift
enter you see you got a bunch of
fantastic so now you want to
um uh let me let me change something
okay PL plot range plot range should be
0 to
5 and3 to3 okay so plot
range 0 to
5 and the y axis
is negative 323 okay so copy that that
way we fix the frame so the graph
doesn't Jump Around okay so now we all
we have to do is just say animate
okay so it's a command animate list
animate s all paste run it
fantastic can you see
that okay let's increase the number of
light rays
okay so let's
stop we want to increase the uh so0 2
increment of point2 instead of point4
fantastic now let's go back and
force beautiful this is what we
want okay the the light Ray length
should increase let's say on N do
it fantastic now it's
better okay and
then then increase
2. s okay let's do it
again uh let's increase it to two
cheers okay is it good yes I think it's
good beautiful
stop now copy the code this is the code
we
want paste
it okay then cut that so now what we do
is
we we want to uh create a movie so
export uh
parabola.
MP4 okay so we want to export to that
file of this
expression okay copy that
paste do
it oh wait we don't want this animate
okay let's do it
again no more
drink am I doing good is it
interesting so how many
people
seven back to Wolf
language uh what's going on okay
excellent I think we are doing excellent
today wait for this to finish Can we
cancel it
uh
renaming remaining time 20 23
seconds
okay
fantastic okay that's it for today so
you know basically we we'll finish up in
three more minutes okay
so that's done I don't want that okay I
won't remove that
okay we can go to
documents and we can look at the file
okay so there is the
movie not bad but I don't want this you
know this control widgets you see let's
try it again yeah yeah let's do it okay
so we I don't want the control widget so
do it
again oh God this okay fantastic so open
this
again beautiful that's what we want okay
so copy
close put it back showing
browser uh actually paste it here make
it a link and uh
also move
it what
permission denied oh God we need to
close this you see Windows got a problem
if you have a file open then you cannot
move the file you cannot rename it you
need to close it first okay so
now re move it to the current directory
showing browser there it
is oh this is so quick you should I
should have increased
the you know I I I should increase the
the
focus yeah so this should be actually
three let you
know okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching how is it do you like
it fantastic you can see how
the optical properties of parabola
okay uh if you like my stuff go to cali.
infoinfo all the way down the bottom pay
me 99 bucks okay Amazon PayPal that's it
for
today Freddy hi
Freddy you are an e celebrity am I I
don't think so well a small time
celebrity unlike most of the others like
one million followers this this grifters
[ __ ] uh you know recently I've been hit
with the with the my ladies group you
know that's that's another fascinating
thing let me show you you see my
ladies uh you guys know about my ladies
that's the basically the crypto
graph I mean the uh cryptocurrency
bit
money
uh bit money frying group okay so let me
show you uh you got you know actually
there's a
lot you see this my ladies you you see
kind of let me show you okay
so yeah let me let me show you my
website
okay so my lady is this kind you you
know it's kind of Myster mysterious you
might read my article but my lady me or
me lady my lady Remia crypto
nft that's a big scamming stuff okay so
you will see lots of these profile
pictures that looks like that um so what
are they you know I explain they are
basically crypto currency of the zumers
they are frying the money you know so
you can make you oh I want to be rich I
want to be rich
instantaneously that's what these people
are trying to do
so so you see these kind of figures you
know this this kind of
um profile photos is this kind of a I
think there's a thousand or 7 10,000
variety
something anyway so that's what this my
lady is okay it's not it's not if you
are following me I got you know I got
the my lady Army oh wait this is this
one is interesting you know this little
reason schema That's a classic book like
20 years old or 30 years old uh what is
he saying by coincidence the first pick
on Google image is him doing the bo face
yeah that's a this guy let me tell you
about the story this guy I think is the
author of a lan programming language
proof
system tutorial writer so he wrot he
wrote a
book
um so he wrote the book
functional programming in link okay and
I criticize it so his name is David th
Christian Christianson David th
Christianson okay so this book
functional programming in Lim it's one
of the worst [ __ ] you know this guy is a
idiot he doesn't know how to
write but I've you know but according to
you know the introduction I've I I
understand that he wrot this season the
the the reason schema okay so I believe
that's what he's
saying yeah here is I criticize this
this is the worst book you know
functional programming link extreme
idiotic offensive offensive to my eyes I
can tell you because I'm kind of expert
on
documentation and the logicality and and
technical writing
okay so this guy I read you know I'm
trying to learn Lan so I read his book I
started to it's like completely idiotic
like
brainless and but I know according to
the introduction he wrote the book The
Season schema okay now let me tell you
about that book that book is like 20 or
30 years old that was one of the famous
book among the schemers I try to read
one of those it's it's got like it's
like a series of books there are three
or four of them I tried to read it in
like
199 uh
7 I didn't quite like it I don't like I
don't quite get it I don't think it's a
good book okay the thing about technical
writing and and uh books of programming
languages is that there's a lot of style
issue so
sometimes it depends on your um the way
you view things so for some people you
you probably prefer this style because
you kind of you know understand it but
for other people you don't think it you
don't view things that way then it's not
good then it becomes incomprehensive
anyway my my
um my comment is that you know I I think
this guy is is a idiot
okay okay so back to my lady my lady is
this um this this this nft thing okay
I'm I'm too out for it so uh it's not my
thing and this my lady photos they are
extremely ugly let me tell you what it
is okay this my lady you know they they
got a philosophy behind it this this is
kind of a movement but very Niche very
very Niche so it's not a not a big
movement okay it's a very very Niche
it's only among the zumas who are doing
cryptocurrency and who are trying to
make a lot money you know that those
kind of people and and some of them are
kind of shady
okay so and uh there is a lot politics
behind it okay there's a
lot serious politics behind it so what
they are doing you know they have a
philosophy like they say oh this is the
way to express yourself and to like
freedom of the world and like a new era
this is a post post post modernism
something like that okay and this is
based on Japanese Aesthetics you know
Japanese Beauty standard you know on and
on but what really it is in my opinion I
can tell you what it is it is
a a semi scam okay and part of it is to
justify [ __ ]
post you guys know what is a [ __ ] post
[ __ ] post is when you go online like
foran a lot of you probably familiar you
go online you you you see a bunch of
like uh [ __ ] [ __ ] you know like no
like brainless troll attack slur you
know just like [ __ ] posting like
meaningless like like you just post
whatever [ __ ] you don't care about
nothing you don't care about other
people you you want to laugh at other
people The Misfortune of other people
like the trans the cows the low low cows
like you know like and the politics the
bidden you know all the wars the Gaza
the war and the blood the
misery the black people the the doing
the violence you know like beating
people you know you you it's it's fun
it's
funny you know you just go online and
[ __ ] post that's [ __ ]
posting uh it was made Popular by forun
starting around
okay so but in summary what this my lady
is is a just
justification a validation of [ __ ]
posting [ __ ] posting okay it gives it
gives it a valid background so that
according to the my lady if you are my
lady is like yeah go ahead go ahead do
[ __ ] posting because because we are in a
new era everyone needs to express
themselves you know it's it's a New
Freedom that's what these my ladies are
so for example let me show
you uh for example let me show you my my
ladies okay so for example you go to
Twitter you see like 1,000s 1,000 1
million not that many because my lady is
actually just like a niche very Niche
group
um one two three one two three one two 3
one two 3 one two 3 one two 3 one two 3
one two 3 one two 3 one two three there
is okay one two three one two
three uh one
two this is by the way this post is by
ell
musk ell musk the boss of my lady it's
so funny so this post is by Elam musk
back in 20
23 um you know so it's it's kind of
funny
okay so and this one is a beautiful my
lady this is not actually but you
know um but let me show you the the the
thing I want to show you
okay so you got the my lady thing here
so I I asked the question what is the my
lady thing because I started to see it
uh in this article
okay yeah so in this article what what
what is this you know I I don't even
know the name so I'm asking people what
you know I started to see this kind of
pH what what is this kind of profile
picture I'm starting to see you know I
want to know tell me the meaning the
Orin okay so then I got 1,000 replies
six
68,000 views
normally my my post is only 300 views so
this one 68,000 views and all the
replies is all the replies is like let
me show you okay you see the my lady
Army like my lady my lady my lady my
lady my lady you see the my lady
Army fascinating uh thing internet
phenomenon uh and this you know this
very creepy things very creepy you see
so I started looking to you know so some
some of them help me you know they tell
me what it is you know they they help
they kind of try to explain to me you
see so I did research I spent like three
days looking into
it fascinating okay I think that's it
you know and the creator of my lady he
he actually retweeted my stuff so that's
why I get so many views several other
people my lady and some of them are emac
users apparently some of them are my
fans so they retreated and then the the
boss the creator of my
lady uh retreated me that's why I get so
many so so that post is here okay that
post is uh so thank you guys thank you
guys the my lady
again
um you see by the way this pretty girl
this thought is one of the my lady okay
this
is this is one of my my lady in real
life
uh so then I I I found that Elam musk
posted
it and this guy is the creator of of my
lady okay this guy you see I got this my
lady Army so the creator of this guy is
this known as charlet fan okay so I
believe he's uh as you know he's as
Asian uh Korean or South aan I forgot
but
anyway so this this this guy shot
charlet Fang supposedly he's a guy uh
you know he's a creator of my lady and
uh you know so you can go read his blog
gold
goldenlight miror
doxyz uh it's not my thing okay thank
you guys
but I'm not sure this is a good thing
this is this is this is the
justification
uh for [ __ ] posting okay and
for for making money okay something like
that I'll just say that okay bye
guys don't forget to donate me okay I'm
not into crypto just go to PayPal s.
info PayPal me $100 okay thank you em