foreign
talk show today's topic is random
so we are just going to talk random if
you have questions comments Post in the
chat you direct what I'm going to say
okay that's for today sound talk show if
you don't know
this is Star Talk Show we talk random
mostly about programming languages live
coding wufam language Golan JavaScript
python uh you know programming language
is design things like that and keyboards
okay and today's topic is random and
maybe one in 20 times I comment on
politics sometimes okay so welcome all
Welcome To The Feast okay so we are
going to do random so nobody is watching
no questions so in that case I'm just
going to random uh I'm just going to do
what I need to do so today's I'm using
glove 80 keyboard gravity keyboard and I
got my new keys which is fantastic okay
so you know today you're gonna see
you gonna see me type uh this keyboard
all day and night
fantastic I got my
chalk
Kyle
you know this company name the the chaos
which is very annoying name Kyle chalk
switch and this is pro red for red
switch at 35 grams okay activation Force
so it's fantastic okay
Club 80 now I'm this is gonna be my main
uh and uh and and you are also looking
at
ultimate hacking keyboard on the side I
use it for uh Marco it's my macro keypad
okay uh automatic hacking keyboard it's
fantastic
and I'm going to review Automotive
hacking keyboard version 2 and uh
possibly Kinesis 360 as well
so grab 80 is great okay so
um yeah so let me just talk random then
since nobody is here so showing browser
showing show my uh the instruction page
Let's uh first stop keyboard so I'm
giving I'm going to give you my updates
and what's happening in my life you know
what I have been doing in past two weeks
so keyboard first stop then we're gonna
talk some about something about emacs
okay and programming stuff programming
blog okay what what is functional
programming so if you want a topic
answer just say it now okay
so keyboard okay so uh you know as usual
I do lots of update I work on my website
all day and night every day so you know
so there is this Shinobi keyboard uh so
hold on a second it's check oh okay so
you are not seeing it let me show my
swing then okay
so the first stop is keyboards Shinobi
keyboard This is a keyboard made by a
company in Taiwan the company is called
tech text keyboard okay and apparently
the creator of Ruby he just
posted on Twitter this is his main
keyboard now okay so this keyboard is
inspired by inspired by the ThinkPad
keyboard the very classic loved by a lot
of people I never used it myself but it
you know Think Pad keyboard is one of
the best quality keyboard
for on uh the PC you know for the
personal computer Microsoft Windows
think pack okay Shinobi this model is
called Shinobi and the company is Tech
and now it's used by Ruby Creator maths
and you can you know here's a company
website you can go and buy and the lots
of let me tell you something so you know
lots of updates on my keyboard blog
there are over a thousand articles now
okay so let me so first of all let me
tell you about my glove 80. so let's do
some typing that hello we have people
here let's do some
let's let's do some hold on a second
let's magnify so I'm using emacs as you
can see and on the pink window is all my
command course and keystroke you'll see
you know popping up in a pink window you
can you can see and undo you can see
undo and on the left side is the
keystroke I'm using a vorac layout vorac
layout is what I'm going to talk about I
mean one of the things we can talk about
again ask me questions okay ask ask ask
thank you you mux twenty dollars
fantastic so questions anything comments
question anything programming whatever
you think my talk show so ask now okay
so what I'm using a via keyboard so you
can see
living window that's a keystroke and I'm
using some fly Keys okay let's see let's
show The Source Code tab you see now I'm
on a glove 80 I'm flying I'm flying it's
it's a fantastic the most wondrous
keyboard okay
soft like keys so so soft like is is a
Emax key binding system it's a keyboard
shortcut system for emacs okay if you
use that you will never almost never
you'll never use you you never need to
press the meta key and
95 of the control key you don't need to
press anymore so everything is just
single keystrokes so you can see
you know for for example I close this
close this so
let's do some typing now and I'm typing
in HTML and I can to mark up like this
okay boom boom you see now you got a
paragraph showing browser you know
everything is single keystrokes no
control meta [ __ ] that [ __ ] up your
fingers okay so here we have the result
you can see and if I want to select the
block you know press two keys and expand
above you see that's a selection by
semantic Unix syntactical Unix you know
you know you instead of the manually
select so you can see all the commands I
call is on the pink window and you'll
see you'll see no control key except
here you see this this command size HTML
open browser it says Ctrl R but actually
that's a key macro you see let me show
you so I want to show this page in
browser I press this key on Ultimate
hacking keyboard
and there you go now back to emacs now
you can see
easy that's C control r c r I don't
actually type print control but it's the
key marker that's why you see the
control so my point here is that when
you use software Keys you almost never
need to uh you know press Ctrl key or
meta key okay
so let's see what's the question
umux hello how do you learn
how new topics quickly I don't learn new
topics quickly maybe when I was younger
20 something maybe but I'm now 50
something I don't you know that's the
impression you get maybe because I know
a lot you know I I have 6 000 articles
on my website uh well that's because 20
years for 20 years basically I mean
that's my job almost you know so
so I don't really learn new topics
quickly and memorize and apply them to
life such as math and programming where
the concepts are rather abstract Okay so
so the question is how do I learn
quickly so first of all I don't I'm
actually I'm kind of a slow learner I
would say comparatively you know so
comparatively I'm a slow learner and but
a methodology
methodological and logical and usually
in depth so I step by step step
logically you know on things that
interest me I will know all about it you
know but but slowly but because I want
to read everything I want I want you
know every book you a typically I read
Wikipedia encyclopedias you know yeah I
have a talk show dedicated to
encyclopedia like at least two of them
so I've been reading encyclopedia since
I was 20 okay almost every day even
today I mean since since like 15 years
ago 10 years ago it's Wikipedia every
day so I have for example
Wikipedia I have I have I have like 10
000 links to Wikipedia you know but I
started to remove them all about two
years ago so you can see so okay so
let's you know let me show you something
uh
answer that question and and
by the way I will talk about lots of
random stuff okay so you go to sorry
info so this is my website
check it out uh there are there are uh
7548 pages on sally.info uh today it's
probably 708
7800 you know more than seven thousand
and that's saudi.info and I also have
sunny.org so press run key to open a new
tab
study.org
dot
org.org go
so here's my when you know increase the
fund again just press you know the power
of keyboard macro so I recommend you buy
a keypad okay so let's see
sorry.org now there is how many articles
on saudi.org about three thousand okay
so in total I have like about eight
thousand
articles okay on programming or
mathematics on uh uh on art on English
writing on vocabulary or Linguistics I
mean so typically my interest I'm a nerd
I'm a big nerd okay that means I'm
a social not too much of a social person
and not very good at it so I'm a Nut so
my interests are mostly academic
subjects programming math you know
Linguistics philosophy as well so that's
my interest so for example recently chat
sheep chat GPT artificial intelligence
I'm having great fun with it you know
tremendous
you know asking him about a bunch of
questions testing the abilities you know
testing is that's that's another topic
incredible so
I'm a nerd academic type of person so
let's go back to Sally info okay Sally
dot info and we wanted to show Wikipedia
so I digressed
so so I have let's see I have about 13
articles on Wikipedia so on Wikipedia's
misinformation written in 2005
2005. my friends
Wikipedia began in 2002 also 2003 you
know in the beginning it's just 10
articles mostly by nerds nothing else
and they flame they hate deep Microsoft
hatred and giant propaganda on open
source you know that's how Wikipedia
began 2002 it began by this
Jimmy where where who sells pornography
Jimmy you know Jimmy
Wales you know he sells pornography
websites poem
then he he you know you know he started
to do Wikipedia so
lots of articles on Wikipedia Wikipedia
morons 2005. so I've been contributing
to Wikipedia since about 2005. you know
and I stopped you know because you go
there you basically just nerds teenagers
college students argue with them day and
night and censorship you know American
view that's a Americans point of view
anything else you get censored and today
is worse today is now controlled by
politicians and giant corporations oil
weapon bosses in USA you know all sort
of things today
so Wikipedia is fairly corrupt but but
but on the academic subjects on any
subject that's not in the current news
and that's not sensitive or politic
political or taboo for example on
physics or mathematics on programming
Wikipedia is the best resource okay best
of all resources on Earth Wikipedia is
the best on those things
you know that's not being uh corrupted
you know but if you look up politics you
know beaten or Whatever USA controversy
guns abortion gays you know rights
rights human rights rights I have a
right I have a right to do my talk show
anything you like that it's it's it's
fake news it's just uh fake news okay so
you so you know there are many people
who are
um
you know people don't know but anyway
if you really want to know stuff you
know on Wikipedia what you can rely on
is usually
um
technical topics that's not
controversial that's not um
controversial or political or in current
event news those are pretty good okay
Wikipedia so so I have a several
articles on Wikipedia and here Sergey
bring the creator of Google you know in
2008 they you know he discussed China
Wikipedia and search engines and you
know what YouTube censored the video now
this video is from Sergey Brin you know
he's he's giving a talk at UC Berkeley
2005.
that's when Google became popular very
popular you know uh and now it's
censored you know they you know they
YouTube you know it's become you uh it's
a tremendous story okay uh Google become
very corrupt okay so let's go back to
what I was going to say okay so
Wikipedia so I was saying yeah so I'm an
academic type of guy so I study a lot
and uh I read Wikipedia is one of the
central resource I read you know even
before Wikipedia before you know in the
1990s I go to the library reading uh
Britannica uh Encyclopedia Britannica
and American spoilers Illustrated
encyclopedia you know it's just
fantastic so
so I'm a nerd I'm studious that's why
um I I learned a lot things uh and uh
you know that's my personality in part
okay and I tend to be very I'm a kind of
a schizoid personality okay so that
means I don't socialize much I
prefer to do things myself so basically
I just read read and study all day and
night okay
and I don't like fat I don't like
fashion or you know such as rust the
language the fashionable whatever so
so that's how I learned so the general
uh is there any general tip I can give
you guys well
I would say you know uh do things that
make you happy you know and if you are a
programmer if you are not type of people
uh person then you just you can study
and don't follow fashion in fat like
what's the current you know the first
the current rust
pop language you know the current Trend
you know the you know you go study
programming practical programming right
right a practical software or study
computer science or study artificial
intelligence okay let me talk about
other visual intelligence neural
networks okay I have learned tremendous
okay so let's go to
uh so in the past month I've been
studying a lot you know I I've always
studied so by the way I did we did this
few weeks ago on Wolfram language
fantastic okay spectacular this is
stereographic projection and their
relation to uh relation to um
geometric inversion you know in the past
we did five or seven videos about that
recently okay so neural network let's
talk about neural network you know so of
course I know about neural networks
since 1990s you know and because I'm big
into this programming language and I
study a lot you know this is the is the
programming language for artificial
intelligence in the 1980s and in 1990s
okay but today it's mostly died okay
today you don't at least be pretty much
dead more or less so of course this
closure this is commonly this this
scheme is mostly dead Okay anyway so
I know about artificial intelligence and
neural networks but I actually never
read about you know never really studied
it until this month okay this month I I
started to read a lot about neural
networks huge you know huge number of
articles on Wikipedia
um and uh
I kind of so now I kind of know the
basic it's just amazing okay so so
neural networks from a mathematic you
know this is gonna throw you guys off
because you know when you hear math oh
math you know math math math is one of
my most favorite subject okay
mathematics
oh math my true love how I have
alienated thee and you being quite
difficult okay that's my poem poem about
math it's it's truly it's my true love
but it's very difficult and there are
brighter people you know smarter people
than you and that they all live in moms
their mom's basement they are all
mobbing toilets at the McDonald's there
are some truth to that you know
especially you know that Russian
mathematician
uh
mathematician you know
Russian you know Russia Tower so there
is you know this this guy Alexander
groudem dick he died five years ago or
so to uh he died in 2014. he's one of
the greatest or the greatest
mathematician okay this is a very weird
guy okay very weird guy
he he you know you might consider him
the top three greatest mathematician or
maybe number one you know the those kind
of questions there's no definitive
answer different mathematicians have
different opinion but in general
we would regard him as the top three
probably mathematician in history okay
you know and very weird guys so you can
read about him and and then there is
another guy I was going to talk about
you know this Gregory Parliament
so he's also one of the greatest you
know maybe top 20 in history something
you know he's of the million dollar
problem but he he lives with his mom in
basement he refused you know any other
work
so anyway so
study math okay so what what what what
what
was I go what what was I saying before
okay I forgot
oh yeah neural networks so I you know I
never studied it before so in terms of
mathematics neural network in terms of
mathematics is just this formula okay
it's just this single formula
uh basically uh nested
function of matrices matrix
multiplication Okay so
you know I can you know I'm I'm not you
know I just I just learned about neural
networks and and I have the basic idea
of how it works but I can't teach you
you know and this will take one hour
and I don't know enough to really teach
you so but basically it's just amazing
so it's just basically this function
this function
um and
that gives us charitivity and that gives
us
um
you know the diffusion stable diffusion
you know I don't know if you guys have
seen stable diffusion you know
you know I can show you it you know but
then Google is gonna censor you because
it's lots of tits and ass
but basically stable diffusion is that
the machine the AI today can generate
drawings or photos
that's my God that's really truly
amazing you know so AI is basically past
the train test so today
starting starting in 2023 we cannot tell
we it's not possible you know it's
in general it's impossible to tell if
some text is written by AI or some photo
is created by AI
you know they have photos they have
photos of trump they have photos of
Biden being arrested you know you cannot
tell I mean well maybe if you are a
photographics expert then you might be
able to tell after five minutes you know
but yeah the thing about AI is that they
create these photos or drawings
one thousand per second you know one
million photos in Joins per second
and you and you look at it you you
cannot tell whether it's real or fake
unless you are a photo expert then you
spend maybe five minutes then you might
tell oh this one is fake but they are
creating a million of it you know per
second that's that's the thing so today
you know so
in chat gbt you know pretty soon
likely you know I you know there's no
reason to say
will not happen pretty soon all Twitter
accounts or social networks account you
know half of it almost more of it is AI
okay you wouldn't know you don't know
it's real person behind it or not that's
the situation so
so 2003 you know 2023 this year I find
um it's it's it's incredible you know
it's like something too much is
happening we cannot
uh adapt the change you know artificial
intelligence you know I wanted to show
some stable diffusion but then Google is
gonna censor you sense of me because
there's lots of lots of uh tits and ass
okay so but uh so let me try maybe we
can try
uh
yeah stupid Twitter okay and there's a
lot happening in the sphere of politics
in USA as well since Elon Musk took over
you know Elon Musk
I study Elon Musk since last year
October
well before that too but but starting in
last year October which is which is
about five months ago I read every post
he has written on Twitter every single
one of them including all replies
because I want to know you know I want I
want to check out who you know the
person
to see this he's good guy or not you
know but you know and my conclusion is
that animus is one of the greatest guy I
admire okay in
it's tremendous you know he's just a
great person okay that's my point of
view that's my opinion okay so let's
let's find the chat GPT
uh you know Cheetos has got a bug if you
just press page down it will
cycle to the Top If You You See
you're just uh sometimes it will just
repeat go into a loop
but anyway so I want to show you you see
now we are at the top again for some
stupid reasons so let me show you by the
way this mouse is fantastic okay this
Logitech spin wheel you want to get a
mouse with spin wheel okay so
digressions and digressions but so let
me show you
go to my website search for Sally
dot info oxali keyboard blog okay then
you can see all you want to know about
trackball or you want to know about
Mouse and this spin wheel is just most
most fantastic you want the mouse with
swing wheel so by this one Logitech
g604 or get the Logitech
g502 okay either one of these buy them
actually the MX Master is also good
so anyway back to a you know stable
diffusion let me see if I can show you
some of it
you know I digressed a lot let me get
back to your questions
I need my coffee okay why not
[ __ ] no more coffee
I need to go make coffee so how long
have I been talking
uh 30 minutes
so I want to show you
impression of lisp from Mathematica okay
effect of technology the Journey of a
firing character through internet okay
and here is a new theory in mathematics
fantastic you Max where are you from
thank you
you are saying elements is a great guy
how do you determine when something is
good or bad emacs is incorporating
three-seater and LSP but how do I
determine whether this is good change
um okay there are two separate questions
I'll get to it okay uh so here is the
Breakthrough you know I know this guy
Craig s Kaplan he's a mathematician in
Canada and he specialized in Titans and
decorated decorative patterns okay
mathematician so he and several other
people found a new theory of tithing so
apparently the theory you know I haven't
read the detail apparently the theory is
that now you can have a single prototype
a single shape that tires the plane only
non-periodically
okay do you do you guys see what I'm
saying you know let me explain okay two
minutes you'll take two minutes so when
you tie a plane let's say your bathroom
you know you can use Square you know so
you use a single tile Square you can
tile a plane and the result is periodic
that means it repeats you know you just
you can translate you know translate or
move move the whole thing and it will
match itself you see that's when you use
a square you know like a grid you know
tire tire your bathroom
okay so it's periodic means that you
know you'll repeat
now you can also use a hexagon you know
regular hexagon to tile the bathroom
which is very common again it repeats so
it's periodic okay so the tile you used
you know in in either case you we use a
single tile
square or regular hexagon right but you
can also use two different tiles let's
say one square and one rectangle twice
as large you know twice as long so you
can use a square and rectangle so you
use two tiles you can also tie a plane
in this case you know you can tile them
periodically
so that it repeats or you can arrange
them in some kind of random way so it
does not repeat
so it becomes non-periodic okay so you
get that so you can Tire the plane with
the shape
uh well lots of questions what share do
I recommend
so you can tie our plan you know with a
single tile or two or more more than one
okay
now there's a question is it possible to
have a tire
one tile let's say O2 let's say two Tire
of the plane such that you can Tire the
plane but however the only possible way
to tie our tile it is non-periodic okay
that's uh that's uh that was the
unsolved problem is it possible to Tire
the plane using either one tire or two
tiles or more than one or three or more
so that you can tell the plane you know
meaning that you'll feel the whole plane
infinitely far
but it will the result will be
non-periodic only it's you know in other
words it's not it's not possible to use
these tires to tie out
and become periodic meaning that it
repeats you know so is it possible so
well the the the the last solution is
yes okay and that timeout is called
um
Penrose tiles okay
so you can read Wikipedia about it let
me show you my art okay let me so we
started to digress into mathematics okay
quickly I I want to go back to the topic
okay so anyway you can look up Wikipedia
Penrose titing okay this is the tile to
using using two shapes okay that it can
tie out the plane meaning that it can
feel the plane infinitely far
but only in an unperiodic way okay
so that's the answer yes it's you know
there exist
shapes such that you can tell the plane
but only non-periodically so when this
case happens we call a periodic title
meaning that it's it's the only possible
way is is non-periodic okay so it's
called a periodic Tiding okay beautiful
you know this is this is the beauty of
math okay
so but there's a there's an issue you
see in this Penrose tithing the minimum
minimum number of tiles required is two
so the question remains is it possible
to use only one single shape
to fill the plane Tire the plane without
gaps you know and extend infinitely
using one only one single ship such that
the only possible possible way to do it
is
non-periodic meaning it doesn't repeat
is it possible now apparently here's the
answer okay there's a new Theory now
I haven't read the details but so you
can go read you know read this guy uh so
that's a new Theory you know just this
month
91 page okay so so that's about tiling
so since we are talking about tithing
let me mention you know I want to
mention some of my own stuff
books geometry Titans you know tithing
uh you know I have lots of
um
I have lots of Articles you know um
uh beautiful uh you know let me just
show you a few okay so
so here is the Wolfram language
Mathematica I wrote 20 years ago that I
creates this decorative Islamic patterns
you know with um group Theory and so on
so this is the package I wrote 20 years
ago
so let me show you a next one uh what's
going on so wait
okay so next one
yeah some Tidings Tidings and patterns
okay so let's see for example here is a
kind of a church window
decoration
okay and okay so let's show you so
here's a bunch of uh patterns random
random
Tidings and patterns okay so let's next
next next next next next next beautiful
all these are periodic you know because
they repeat okay
and they are 13 possible ways how they
repeat that's called
symmetry groups wallpapers groups okay
that's mathematics topic proper in this
example you are seeing kind of nested
Tiding or fractal tidying so you can
you know so so you you know basically
it's a pattern you'll see infinitely
a number of them okay so next you know
you know and here's the links a very
interesting fantastic okay so let me
show you the next page
oh yeah so here's the Titans uh and the
the and here is
um
you know here is something I found
online very interesting it's it's a plot
of gas physics something okay but
okay so you can see it move just you see
beautiful
pressing the arrow key okay
uh and here is a book I recommend I
talked in my video before uh if you are
interested in Titans and patterns the
mathematical aspect of it I recommend
this is well this stick is out of print
but Dover printed again so you go buy it
okay search my website sorry dot info
Tidings and patterns okay so so if you
want to know all about the Tiding
theories we talked about that's this
book you know I read it
20 years ago okay
so about Thailand's a pattern so let me
go go back to the things we were talking
about okay
so we digressed a lot we yeah I was
going to show you stable diffusion okay
so let me show you some stable diffusion
and we'll move on and by the way I
bought a new flat shoe this is a healthy
you know you can you can go check out my
Twitter and you can see my website about
this shoe okay
and by the way feet oh hot sexy hot
the the the the the the subject matter
here the topic here is which part of the
feed is Spore which part of the feed is
so which part of the feed is
um
and uh heel okay a very confusing
terminology you know normally I you know
I thought this is Sport because it looks
like a ball but no this part is called
heel and the Palm part of the foot is
called
um
ball okay so this part is for this part
is here and the whole the whole flat
bottom is called Soul
okay that's what this picture is for
okay the you know linguistics
uh next oh yeah so this this is another
this this this one is generated by a I
okay by artificial intelligence it's
just amazing
okay I think I'm up you know I'm gonna
answer questions now okay so because I'm
kind of rambling uh over uh and I want
to uh yeah safe and woofa I'm very
interesting uh we uh you know Stephen
uh I want to stable diffusion let's
forget about it okay so let me just
answer the questions now
because we've been talking about 40
minutes already
are you able to use effectively org mod
with the soft light keys of course but I
haven't you know I don't use Oakmont
much yeah I use you know raw HTML I
talked about that many times because
I've been coding HTML since
1996 okay so
um
so have you ever put interaction
interactive wolf and programs CDF no no
I don't I haven't done that
no uh CDF is not a good thing okay
I mean I I you know I would I would
rather recommend you just get the
Wolfram language you know the Wolfram
engine that's free or just buy it pay
buy it okay you know subscribe you know
for a year uh CDF is kind of the
in my in my view okay CDF is kind of the
marketing thing that doesn't do good
it's not good okay
so let me answer this question with
money okay so you are saying LMS is
great so two questions about how do you
judge a person okay the other question
is how do you judge
whether a thing you know a computer
programming technology is good or bad
okay so let me talk about how do you
judge your person first how do I judge
you a person
well that's um you know so the way I do
it is you look at the Integrity you know
what the guy has done you know it like
depends on what aspect you want to judge
the guy you know you know you see
qualified is he a good programmer that's
one question
you see you know so if you ask me if
lmus is a good programmer I would
probably say no okay you know he he's a
very he's a technical person he's an
engineer but I'm not sure he's a
programmer I mean well he might be you
know he he can he understand program he
being you know I'm pretty sure he has
programmed before but he's probably not
a professional programmer like like us
you know so anyway when you judge a
person depends on what aspect you want
to look into for me
for me when I look at this you know this
Super Rich manga rich people or
politicians you know the most important
aspect is
whether they have integrity
whether they lie what have they done you
know do they are they are they you know
are they unctuous are they like sneaky
are they you know like fuzzy about
things do they have integrity
that's the most important thing when I
look at at politicians or this may God
rich people do they have integrity okay
I care less about what they believe okay
for example politicians they believe you
know they believe they are Christians or
they believe something you know or they
they are you know I care less about what
their policies they they what they
believe okay I care more about the
Integrity is most important so if they
are Christian you know
do they you know did they say anything
sacrilegious
before when they are you know before the
election time something like that you
know do they do they do they you know
sway around you know because today this
year if you say this thing people will
vote for you but next year if you say
the other thing people will avoid vote
for you do they sway around
okay that's the thing I look for
integrity of the person for example
beaten Hillary Clinton are the most
worst scumbags okay in U.S history
Hillary Clinton and Joe Biden you know
this these are professional politicians
in the worst sense of that word you know
they just you know they do whatever
because most people you know you don't
study you know most people don't know
and you don't you you don't have time to
study you know you are not going to
spend your life to study the guy you
just care about whether you can you can
drive how much is the gas the American
life you know Starbucks that's all you
care everything else you just you can
sleep over Starbucks and chat about Alex
nothing you know it doesn't affect you
too much
so when when life is good
you really don't care about the
politicians and the politicians can do
whatever that's that's the situation so
Integrity is how I look how I okay so
how do I judge Integrity you you look
you don't don't
listen to what they say they say oh I'm
a good person or they say oh we did I
did this or I did that that's
you know that's marketing okay you want
to look at
statistics
you know in the past 10 years in the
past 20 years what have he done what are
the known controversies
you know not you know then you look at
the each each case of the controversy
what is it about what is the nature of
the controversy then then you make a
judgment okay because you know
basically every politician every famous
people they will always have enemies and
one bunch of idiots they will always
attack famous people for example I'm you
know you will find a bunch of people
attack me but they don't have content
they just say exercise idiot you know
whatever they don't have content so for
each politician you will have a lot of
haters too so so not just you know just
because they are haters doesn't mean
they are bad okay so you look at each
case of any controversy they had if any
you know you judge then you know that's
how I judge you know so for in summary
Integrity is the most important thing to
me okay the their point of view their
policies their abilities is secondary
almost almost not even important these
days because these days
the reason USA and you know the bad
things there's a lot of bad things is
not because
what politicians believe is rather
because corruption they don't they they
don't believe [ __ ] anything they just
believe making more money for themselves
that's all
okay so the other question is you know
emacs is incorporating three-seater and
LSP but how do I determine whether this
is a good change okay so how do you so
that's that question is about how do you
judge a technology uh programming
language operating system or you know a
package like you know three-seater
uh that will
that will depends yeah that will depends
that that depends mostly I think
okay that depends on two major things
uh one is one is your own experience
about the technology so if you
are a Emax user
then you are far more qualified to judge
three-seater then someone who never used
emacs before
you know then they're gonna have
opinions about whether three sitter is
good thing or not in emacs obviously
it's City because the guy never used
emacs even you know so
so so first of all how you judge your
technology first of all depends on how
how much you know about it okay
so so obviously you are a emacs user and
you heard about tree sitter so you
probably an LSP so you so you have to
make a judgment yourself
oh you can you or you can trust someone
you like for example me so in my opinion
three sitter is great LSP is no good
okay three-seater is one of the best
thing
I plan to study I plan to dive deeper
into a three-seater
especially Incorporated you know in
emacs is one of the best thing LSP is no
good LSP is a good technology but the
RSP 2E Max is [ __ ] okay in my opinion I
have an article you know just search for
you know um
I have lots of articles about those I
have one specific article about why LSP
is harmful okay uh did we get that name
right I don't think is it called LSP or
is it so let's go to emacs web search
LSP oh yeah language server protocol
that's right so language server protocol
kios emacs okay I don't like it I do not
recommend it
LSP by itself I think is a good
technology it's useful it's you know
because you know it serves a purpose but
I do not recommend it in emacs and I
don't like it because in my opinion it
it stops the progress of the most
important progress of emac bisp emac
this powers emacs and emac this
in recent years there's some progress
but but we need a lot more okay A lot
more in compared to other languages emac
this
progress is very little okay PHP
JavaScript python they have lots of
progress over the past 20 years IMAX
this is like no change almost okay a
little so we need in my opinion my own
personal opinion we need
we need to get emac lists better okay
and more specific you know
I cannot talk about specifics which part
you know but that's another topic uh
well I don't like LSP and three-seater
in Emax is a great thing because
because tree seater
um
you see you know you know I I can't go I
cannot go into details
and I might be wrong because I actually
never tried three-seater myself so so
far I want my opinion about tree sitter
is just
what I feel because it's a it's you know
essentially it's a passer engine okay uh
it's a passer engine specifically
designed for for passing syntax it's not
a compiler okay I mean well it is so
it's kind of it's it's a it's a
you know it's a password designed for
manipulating syntax so I think it's a
great thing but I don't know the details
yet
okay so to judge a technology first of
all it depends on how much you know
about the technology that's the first
thing
the second part is it depends on what's
your preference
for example you know for example we know
there's Unix there's Windows there's mac
you know and there's different operating
systems they have different philosophy
or for example in programming languages
their score line there's lisp there is
Haskell there is you know rust each one
have different philosophies okay and
there is also for example compile
languages versus scripting languages
high levels such as python Ruby
JavaScript
Lua versus you know Golan C C plus plus
Java C sharp you know
so there are different philosophies and
different type of Technologies so
when you judge them part of it depends
on your own preference Okay so
if you preferred
Dynamic language if you prefer
mathematics for example like me you
prefer advanced mathematics then you you
know for me for example I prefer high
level languages I don't like C
I don't like anything's assembly [ __ ]
okay I don't like anything memory
detailing [ __ ] like the rust [ __ ] okay
you know you can go you know or GPU
whatever I like proof Theory type Theory
you know those you know high level
mathematics
so because of this preference then
certain technology I judge them to be
better than others for example
Okay I uh we're gonna shut down now
what chair do I recommend that I uh next
time okay
okay so that's it for today thank you
guys for watching if you like my stuff
pay me okay
pay me go to my saudi.info
and uh
sally.com code and go to the bottom you
can see my patreon Amazon gift card
PayPal and Bitcoin
okay I think that's it for today
so how many people do I have uh four
people okay fantastic
thank you
thank you Max okay shut down shut down
in one minute I guess anything else
let's see
close copy back here let's go back let's
let's uh paste what we talked about in
today's talk show show the pink window
go here
so type link show
so here is language server protocol
three-seater I want to study but so much
to study you know so I'm learning neural
networks uh and lots of things so
and the one of the thing I want to study
is homotopy type Theory and that's
that's huge
and also differential geometry you know
like I said you know although I
interested in math but I haven't really
made
really uh
becoming a professional mathematician
level you know for example
so math this neural networks yeah so
yeah so let's copy that neural network
copy close
back to emacs paste it here link select
go top and paste it there and Titans and
patterns okay
Okay so
so you can see
I don't have to click I just move my
mouse and it'll switch window I
recommend that
close close yeah this is a great book I
mentioned again
because
keyboards fantastic Penrose typing
fantastic Mouse
Google censorship [ __ ] Google
and Wikipedia you know lots of Wikipedia
stuff Wikipedia information uh
copy the search
okay so we need to do something about
that make a link okay bye guys
sound like keys so yeah fantastic
oh yeah so there's a lot
work on soft like keys in the past two
months
so now the Escape key
by default will
toggle to command mod command mod
so you can read about the detail about
design about whether Escape key should
be the default or not there's intricate
issues because of the terminal okay so
anyway stuff like keys
if you haven't already try it out
uh what function what's the function
what's an operator very interesting
article so I've been working on okay bye
guys hey rat
bye