hello guys welcome to another episode of
sound talk show
so we are going to uh today we are going
to do emacs workflow demo so I'm going
to work on my emacs a simple task and
mostly so I'm going to show you emacs
work workflow so what is the most
efficient way to open a file what is the
best way for window Arrangement and
things like that efficiency okay my
workflow
so emacs workflow and then I'm going to
show you let's see so yeah mostly just
emacs workflow and uh
that's it okay just emacs workflow so
I'm going to what so what I'm going to
do is to create let's go to my emacs
tutorial okay
showing browser my emacs tutorial so you
can see I'm going to add a page add a
very basic page that says how to open
file close file save file save as you
know I'm starting to feel the gaps of
the very basic emac stuff to my emacs
tutorial of course it's covered
somewhere else but for the very
beginners they don't know so they want
to search for how do you open a file in
emacs so I'm going to add the page for
that that's workflow and then
okay so that's it so it's probably gonna
be 30 minutes okay so anyway so let's
begin so I'm going to uh so I'm using
this keyboard This is the uh you know if
you go to Saudi search for my keyboard
review expose night okay this is uh one
of the best okay I recommend you you you
go get it okay so you can see ergonomic
keyboard reviews and best ergonomic
keyboard so so that one you know I've
been using this one for long and but for
a change and this one is one of the best
okay these two I recommend the most
Expos okay
uh so that's Expose and I'm I'm using a
borax keyboard layout uh let me show you
okay so since I'm doing workflow today
so let me show you uh kind of the keys
and stuff so vorac keyboard layout so
you can see over here you can see a
bunch of layouts so this is QWERTY
everyone knows quality q w e r t y the
circus quality so you have vorac the
most common
ergonomic alternative layout so quality
and comac comac DH Walkman asset Norman
and so on so I'm using a vorac layout
okay
and
and I'm using stuff like keys so let me
show you fly Keys okay showing browser
so this is the most efficient key
binding system for emacs so if you are
using emacs
try this this is more efficient than Vim
okay
more efficient than Vim
uh okay so
so okay that's so I'm using vorac I'm
using Xposed keyboard and I'm using uh
for example you can see I can jump
through this is stuff like keys that
again jump through paragraphs easily I
can delete a paragraph delete undo undo
uh and I can select the whole paragraph
if I want to select more you know things
like that that's soft like Keys okay
and everything there's no control meta
things there's no modifier so you can
look at the pink window uh let's turn on
uh highlight current line so the pink
window shows all my command course so
you can see as I delete this paragraph
go to the pink window you can see that's
that's the command because RTD context
block okay if you search the command
name chances are you are mostly most
likely to find it on my website with the
code so you can use it okay or you can
just use stuff like keys so undo so you
can see and do there and the on the left
side of the pink window that's my
keystrokes okay there's no control
there's no meta there's no old you know
up your fingers
so because after that Keys okay that's
the background that's what I'm using the
tools tools is actually important of
course you can use notepad
nobody is stopping you you know
sometimes you have the thought you know
to be the greatest programmer you don't
need all these tools you can just stick
with notepad or you can stick with
let me show you you know sometimes you
see that
Windows paint you know I have seen great
artworks uh done by people using
Windows paint okay
yeah that's great but actually but the
tools helps you a lot for example if you
have a geometer and you you need to draw
you know geometry with my
you know you you want to draw a circle
yeah you can do it with the hand you
know you don't really but if you have
compacts compacts
precise measurement you know tools help
you go to the Moon without tools you
don't you cannot go to the Moon okay so
yeah you might think okay there are
cripples we can do great things with
their feet that's true but however
uh without
um good tools it limits your potential
that is true okay so never worry about
the true stuff yeah you know if you have
better tools use it so that's about my
tools okay and emacs is great so what
else so some fly Keys okay copy that uh
so I'm going to show you workflow so
let's go to some talk show so this is
one of the efficient way to open uh uh
page okay so let's see what is this page
so everything you see I do
carefully you know look at study you
know
you know that's what you're interested
is if you are looking at this video if
you are watching this video about the
efficiency about my workflow okay so
what is this one so this is yesterday's
uh
so
uh yeah that's yesterday so today
today's talk show is this one open it
and go down and let's go down paste the
link here
paste the link link if I make a list
showing browser okay so you can see
today's talk show I you know that's my
topics I want to talk about so there it
is stuff like Keys Okay so
okay now now let's let's start to work
so let me show you okay go to emacs blog
okay not extemp
using emacs bookmark feature okay open
it and this is my local mirror local my
local file of my website sorry dot info
okay go to emacs tutorial so what I need
to do today is under this file section I
want to add a new page that says how to
open a file how to close the file how to
save a file you know the very very
Basics so because there are of course
there are people who wants to learn it
so begin let's begin
uh so first of all I'm going to do that
okay and explain some of the tips about
the workflow then I'm yeah okay so let's
do it so
uh so start a new section so let's say
uh I want to copy actually so go to diet
you know I have keyboard markers so this
so this is exposed and that keyboard is
Ultimate hacking keyboard both of them
has the greatest uh visualization marker
setup uh the two or twos to remap the
keys or record record markers okay so
actually so let me why not um let's let
me show that okay
so you can look at this one
so am I doing good hello guys
immortality good morning
so this is Ultimate hacking keyboards
software called uhk Agent
this is fantastic the most easy to use
and the powerful most powerful software
to record key markers or control your
keys for example uh you know my ultimate
hacking you know I have reviews on my
website just go to it so you can look at
let me show you my current uh keypad
windows so that's that is my system you
see
select or copy paste new page new tab
new new file new tab refresh close
current tab next tab previous tab copy
the URL so you see this copy URL Ctrl L
Ctrl C so if I want to copy your url I
can just for example I can press one key
done okay
hand saver saves your hand pain you know
maybe you are young but after 10 years I
didn't you know I didn't have any hand
problems until after 15 years of using
keyboard
by now I'd be you know by now it's 30
years I'm getting old so this ultimate
hacking keyboard uhk agent is one of the
greatest uh
uh keyboard software okay it's also open
source
okay ultimate hacking keyboard but
automatic hacking keyboard is kind of
expensive and okay anyway so let me show
you the other one the other one
is vile okay this is new okay
um
yeah so let me show you
so this is vile software now this file
software is a user interface to the qmk
uh firmware system so you know for those
of you do it yourself people you'll love
this you know extremely easy to use okay
between these two they are both
extremely too easy to use I do not you
do not have to look up manuals like the
qmk you know qmk is the worst
possible you have to go to the website
and and drag keys and a bunch of cryptic
things like the quantum Quantum my ass
you know cryptic things and and jargons
then you have to spend days if you are
capable at all if you are a tech nerd
programmer there is to to
flash your firmware you know after you
after you set up configure the keys then
you have to save to a file then Flash
the firmware you know complicated if you
made a mistake you break your keyboard
qmk the worst possible
but now there's open source via software
that is a user interface to to qmk so so
this so I'm using it for my um
for my Xposed keyboard so let's look at
myself so I you see exposed keyboards
okay so I can program it I already did
some of it uh I I did program some Macro
for uh for let's see what what markers
do I have Mark was Zero marker one Mark
or two yeah so anyway so you can see if
I go to a browser I can press
F10 foreclose the window
close the tab f11 is previous tab F12 is
next tab so what they actually do is
control tab or Ctrl shift tab
okay okay so that's the Via software
fantastic so if you buy Xposed you have
that you know
where's my Xbox keyboard okay so did I
close it yes okay so
okay so that's about the keep so so
those are great Okay so
by our software for qmk fantastic and
the ultimate hacking keyboard software
uhk agent is also one of the best okay
so for example you can see the mod layer
you can see the function layer uh
and and so I don't like layers myself so
I don't usually I I have none of it no
layers one layer okay
screw the rest then I don't like the
layers I like the most typical because
they are inefficient you know what
layers do is that you have to hold this
key then press that key you have to keep
holding it after you release that key
then you have to release the modifier
Keys modifier fire one two three four
idiot
okay one single key press That's the
operation you don't want to hold
something something get you know get
your hands into a spider fingers uh you
go see your doctor
see the Spiderman doctor okay so let's
go back to emacs and let's start to
write yeah so we want to write a page so
let me show you okay so emacs showing
browser one single key press so I want
to uh so let's go to emacs emacs
tutorial and let's go to diet okay I
want to copy this link URL so press one
key copy it press another key back to
emacs now I can
press that that's a you see that's a URL
and make a link of it and make a list of
it showing browser one single key press
is fantastic there it is okay why do I
want to copy make a copy of this page
because I want to duplicate by copying
the content of this so let me let me
just do it
because remember right now I want to
create a new page
writing a tutorial about how do you open
a file in emacs how do you close it how
do you save it okay so let me so watch
How I do and watch the pink window okay
that's all my command cores and keys
okay so copy that paste I'm gonna just
do it fast okay emacs open save close
open save
save as close and let's add a quit
okay and let's
replace Space by comma space okay do it
do it no do it do it okay
so you can now show in browser
there it is now the page now I need to
change the rename it okay so let's say
emacs
open save close
okay now you can see this is there are
spaces there that's magnified okay you
can see I want to change all the spaces
to
low line okay the the character is
traditionally called underscore let me
show you what that character is you see
that character is traditionally known as
underscore but in Unicode it's called
Low line
a better name okay as far as the science
of terminology goes low line
descriptive everyone understand it a low
line not the underscore you know by
the way what does underscore where does
it come from why is it under what what
is the score you know then one time I
looked up etymology score is that you
know eight you know two thousand years
ago you have a stick you want to tally
things you make a cut you you know you
make a notch on a wood or bamboo or
whatever that's a score that's what it
is yeah
so that's why so okay so you can see
this I want to change all space to the
low line so what I do is uh I cut this
command there it is they become hyphens
press it again press a repeat key they
become underscore that's what I want
okay so
um so now open the diet and copy whole
copy the whole buffer how do I do it
press two key then look at the pink
window okay it's done now press this key
to close it now move here press enter
fire does not exist do you want to open
it yes okay paste it there it is okay
save it close it let me just walk it uh
fast okay so now I want to you see this
line they are all lowercase I want to
title case them not all caps not caps on
every
first letter of the word but title case
so what what does that mean title case
for example is
the
a you know those those uh articles the
part of the grammar articles are not
capitalized so anyway let me just do it
do it you see done okay so now copy that
go here now I need to change the title
and over there and there okay so I have
a command size tml look at the pink
window you'll see the command name
to it there it is what you want to
change your name new title paste it
there okay do it you can see it change
it in both both places there and there
okay
and I want to update the date you see
this is a copy from the diode page you
know so this is 2021 last update so
press again press a few Keys uh press
that that you see now it's today's date
now since this is new uh wait what did I
do since I pressed that
another Marco Key by mistake so since
this is a new page I don't need the you
know so I need to modify this okay and
and all this part just basically delete
diet okay so actually delete okay now
showing browser this is the new empty
page based on the
based on this diode page template why do
I need to based on on another file
because every file they have different
navigation panels so that that is why I
want to copy instead of just creating a
new file okay so now
okay now the content okay this is the
now this is a real part of writing a
Blog okay okay that's gonna take a while
but basically you open file uh you can
just say let's see open save save as
okay so let's um
now now I want to make them each uh
let's do it let's let me just do it okay
open save save as okay
uh
open let's see do I want the table or do
I want to make a list uh open file is
okay let me just write it out fast
find file you know that's the command
name you use you code to open a file
because emacs has all these cryptic
names you know a new person have no idea
what they are like what the when
you open a file you find file I don't
want to find the file I want to open it
you know this then it confuses with the
Unix terminal command find you know you
know yeah but the excuse is that emags
was Asian 30 years ago 40 years ago 40
to 50 years ago so back then Emax is the
first
to to invented these Concepts
so save file is save buffer okay save
buffer I've been using emacs for 20
years so I remit I know them by heart
save us is Right file okay kind of
cryptic and close is
um
so so right now I want to type a arrow
right arrow so what I do I just type R A
and press space they become a right
arrow
how does that happen well that that is
the magic of emacs a brief okay let's
see
emacs a brief mod okay so uh so let me
show you open that emacs agree the most
fantastic feature to me one of the the
top five the greatest feature of emacs
for me
I believe is one of them the top five I
use it extensively for expand for
abbreviation of an English word or for
abbreviation of a Unix command or
Powershell command you can look at you
can see my Powershell here
uh where is it here okay so Powershell
you know anyway I showed that before so
you a brief can be used for English
words can be used for command
abbreviation
you know the command can be arbitrarily
long sometimes it can be used for
function template for for example when
you are programming for example in emacs
in um for example
smart when you want to define a function
I just press d space it becomes
different space again oh oh my God
fantastic saves you
hundreds of keystrokes okay for example
let's another example JavaScript
turn on JavaScript mod then I want to
define a arrow function and assign it to
a constant so constant Arrow function
CAF okay let's magnify okay space oh
then fantastic okay that's a power of a
brief you know so if you want to look at
my brief file
bookmark so wait cancel
open it so I have 400 lines actually so
I have you know 800 here but for each
programming language I have few hundred
more so yeah I have literally over a
thousand abbreviations okay
uh wait you guys you see so you see
thanks uh so all these are abbreviations
not most powerful and uh you can read my
tutorial about how to set it up okay
you know understand
understanding you will your yours
usually you know those are the most
common then you have English phrasal
brief I will I should it should be it
would I will and then you have English
mosque Okay so
years finally realize realizes another
anything thing looking at you know then
you have
uh you know lots of long words science
academic science screen shortcut
screenshot solution similar okay so a
brief okay fantastic close it close it
don't save close it don't save so we
have demonstrated a brief so now
uh what are we doing what is this page
okay a brief mod by disco close it close
it close it
okay so back here so that's the right
arrow okay R A you can Define it you
know just by in one minute you have this
shortcut as well so close is r a and
what else uh yeah so how do you close in
emacs you call the command key or buffer
you know another another cryptic jargon
what the is buffer
you know 20 years ago I argued with this
emacs phonetics I say it shouldn't be
named buffer just say key or fire okay
kill file open file open file you know
what the is the buffer then the
Emax this techno Unix phonetics Linux
phonetics this this techno phonetics
they're gonna argue if you prefer is the
proper name
proper name they are ass they have no
idea no idea what's going on in computer
science a buffer is a temporary storage
location okay that's what buffer means
and do you know why emacs name it things
buffer because
40 years ago
40 years ago you cannot you cannot save
the whole file in memory even it's you
know you only actually so in emacs it
literally is a buffer because you only
view just for you know 40 lines of a you
know part of the file is saved is is
created in a buffer a temporary location
so you only can see part of the file at
one time that's why it was buffer but
not today
so buffer is a bad name okay so don't
don't be a tech
techno techno no nothing okay like the
most typical Emax phonetics Unix
phonetics and Linux phonetics okay they
don't they don't know and their way of
of you operating emacs is like the least
efficient
another story you know 10 years ago
15 years ago 2000 in the 2000 starting
around 2016. you know I complained emacs
key binding is bad you know they say no
no you are a troll you should everyone
should stick with emacs ski binding
because
that's what they say you know back then
that's uh you know then today you have
you have evil mod you know the Vim based
very popular you know it's widely
accepted in fact recommended by a lot
emacs phonetics not so not so 10 years
ago because they they
15 years ago they're gonna say you are a
truck
you know you you are not helpful to the
community because to be a good citizen
of the emacs community you must promote
whatever the emacs you know the Emax way
the default Keys the worst crap since
lots of people to see doctors ruined
their career ruin their hands okay
so anyway I digress now this this this
this video is becoming a rant okay so
next quit Okay
um so quit is kill
um
what is quit the command for emacs
uh I believe is exit emacs
QR buffer something like that okay so
actually I have to look up on that one
so let's see
oh yeah so say buffers kill terminal you
know that's a mouthful okay so and then
you need to say what's their key Okay so
okay let me let me do it okay so
actually
this is becoming a long page so let me
just quickly write it okay so first of
all so okay so we need to
say what what what what is the key okay
so find uh so save file
I mean find file is
c um
control X control F okay and save buffer
is Ctrl X control x s
Ctrl X control S I think we are double
check okay right file is
I don't remember I don't know if right
file has a default key so let's look
so
so you know in my custom mod I have lots
of custom keys so okay so by default is
Ctrl X control w
a bunch of idiotic
key or buffer is Ctrl X con control x k
I believe this okay so let's see yeah
control x k so let now let's double
check find file
fine fire what is the key yeah and the
save buffer
uh
that's correct right file okay kill
buffer
is correct and uh and this is Ctrl X
control Q okay
yeah well I mean Ctrl X control C okay
very cryptic okay anyway that's the
that's how do you open save save as okay
so now newbies
King all
be happy you know okay now showing
browser there it is okay let's leave it
just like that I'm going to work on it
maybe make it into a table format or
something else
uh but anyway so wait hold on a second
undo undo so let me why don't I show you
okay so let me show you so first of all
this part so let me show you three
formats okay
so the first one is gonna be list okay
just like you like what you see there
okay the second one is gonna be
um
uh let me show you okay so let's change
the arrow okay let's do this
um this is all my own HTML commands Okay
so control U then tap F then separator
rejects between entries okay
so that's gonna be a new line and the
separator rejects between term and
definition okay and that's gonna be
that an arrow okay do it okay
showing browser so the first format is a
bunch of lists the second format is
definition list okay
the third format I'm gonna use table so
I'm gonna show you how so you need a
separators so let's change the arrow to
uh okay let's change the space space
Arrow to
to a vertical bar okay so wait
how do you type a vertical bar there
okay do it do it do it do it do it okay
and we also need it here
okay now I want to turn these lines into
a HTML table so you can call this
command
which is
um
which is sa wait not that one okay so
which is uh this one okay so HTML lines
to table okay let's let's do it
do it now what's the column separator
okay vertical line there it is okay now
showing browser so we got three formats
so so now this which format is the best
this is the issue about writing a
tutorial which is not today's topic okay
so I think in this case we we want the
third
um we we want the table format so let's
let's use a table format and let's add a
capture caption
okay caption
um
basic emacs commands Okay the caption
copy it and paste it uh paste it here
okay showing browser
okay I consider this page done now I
need to add this page as a entry point
in the file section of the navigation
bar okay let's do it so the navigation
bar is here at the bottom so so you can
see this this
dive tag so search for diet so you can
see so what I'm going to do is I'm going
to copy paste the key it'll copy the
whole list
okay now copy it and I'm gonna call one
of my package to do find and replace
this package is called fine now if you
look at the Ping window you'll see the
command name okay probably so I'm gonna
do it okay so you can see starfine
replace text paste this this is what I
want to find
and enter okay now cancel now what do I
want to replace now go back here I want
to copy the current file copy the
confile path and paste it there you can
see I want to linkify it link okay make
a list remove the URL tag
and then remove the emacs word so I want
this to be the entry
you know here open save okay and
actually
uh remove the crit Okay so
copy copy cut cut this line okay save
the buffer then
watch the pink window you can see
find replace text
up Arrow the previous replace text enter
what do you want to replace by replace
string okay up Arrow again and here okay
so you can see you can see we added uh
you know there is some I think there's
some bug with ah God
let's do it again
find that text yes
replace that okay so I need to paste
that okay replace that okay
yes now which directory this directory
current directory yes now file path
regular
expression.html yes
uh minimum the depth zero yes Max the
depth 99 yes
write changes to file yes fixed case in
search yes fixed case in replace yes
make backup yes okay
So This is Gonna Change
for hundreds of files there it is
complete okay so you can see
uh you can see this is
you know one the one of my command Okay
saw find replace if you like my stuff
pay me okay pay me and get it it's a
donation so you can see all these are
changes you can tap go to go through and
press enter to jump to it and open it so
we just opened another file this one is
list buffers and you can look at the
panel you can see
there it is open save save as close
click on that you can see it has been
you know so the panel now the navigation
panel is spent okay
so close that close that
showing browser okay the network
navigation panel I'm done okay
so I think that's it for today that's
the primary that that's the thing we
want to do so one uh so now we talked
for 40 minutes okay that's it so open
that back to emacs close it close it
okay what is this page open it emacs
block okay we created that fantastic now
we don't need the we don't need that one
anymore so
select that delete showing browser
fantastic close it back to emacs close
it show in browser so back to the talk
show today okay
I'm done so we explained
we did the Emax workflow so okay what
let me show you one more thing emacs
workflow this is more general not just
for what I'm doing today so you know for
many people they have a habit to full
screen
don't do that okay when you use emacs
don't don't walk full screen like that
for example you can Emax is a
you can you know you can you can split
windows in arbitrary ways you know
so many people maybe they came from IDE
so they get used to the idea you full
screen then you have several panels you
know this panel is maybe for a list of
files and and and let's let's say this
panel is for uh
for Xiao
and you know let's see do I have the
command dates oh oh that okay anyway so
or get status you know this is a git git
command get status you know so Xiao
where one panel is shell one panel is
whatever uh wait
you know when when panel is fire one
panel is
compilation output and whatever
full screen full screen workflow no good
okay why because every time you do
something emacs will constantly up
your arrangement
because for example if you do describe
function you know what is save terminal
so you see now your shell panel is gone
then you do something you know emacs
with let's say uh let's say describe
child okay so for example let's go here
let's see let's add Emoji okay
hot and wait I want did I press let's do
it again you see now I got a heart
magnified magnify okay now I want to see
I want to see what character is that so
describe Char so you can see
uh this is
um
hot black suit you know
but but then you see
I mean the point is that it screws up
all your you know configuration of your
windows then people started to you know
use packages that revert you know
basically so and another issue is that
you there's no easy way to switch to a
particular pen basically then then they
then you use another package to allows
you to type something then each pen has
a letter identity then you type that
letter to jump to that no good okay
idiotic you can save all these problems
by adopting
not full screen okay let me let me show
you okay so
uh what
what where is it
okay I want to get out of full screen
and get out of you know window is
annoying because you have the concept of
full screen then you also have the
concept of Maximum window so this
sometimes they they are basically the
same thing but very confusing
so anyway so
instead of full screen what you should
do is
every time you start emacs you know
instead of full screen you should just
set up two
you should use Windows or what emacs
called frame so now you have two frames
so for in my case now I have three
frames you see
so when you have Windows okay let's call
them windows because that's a universal
term in Mac or Linux or
or Windows
so when you have a window you know emacs
will never emacs will never
close your window okay and emacs will
never
change the size of your window okay so
you are you have a stable condition so
you can if you want to you can for
example you can double cut your kind of
you know your your full screen frame
situation you know you can
you know you can you can arrange them
that way
so and you can change switch the buffer
in any one of them you know so this way
is better okay don't use full frame but
use a window based and anytime you can
because emacs is free flow okay that's
what I do so I can freely open any
open or close or resize
you know I don't resize of often so
that's why I don't have a key
there's some key but I don't remember
you know I don't use it so usually
typically in my usual workflow it's just
two pins when I'm when I'm not doing
video because when I do video you have
to set up in large font you have to
really large founder a lot so other
people can see then you have to have the
command log and you know but normally
in my daily workflow is just two pins
and I can
and sometimes three then you meet then
when I'm done after five minutes I close
it so okay don't use full frame and I
have article on that
uh full detailed explanation okay emacs
workflow full full screen versus
multiple frame okay that's it now
another tip is that um
uh another tip is that I'm not going to
go through is the Hoover to
Hoover to activate window okay so this
is very convenient Hoover to act survey
so you can so I show you how to how do
you say that set that up in Windows or
Mac mag is the best okay
or you can how to set it up in win uh in
Linux okay I show you how to there
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
hey Daniel Langlois long time no C the
Neo Langlois is a guy who did who
rewrote the starfly keys engine you know
the the the Fantastic efficient key
workflow we are using he rewrote the key
key map engine fantastic thank you
Daniel
he and will he and another guy you know
okay that's it for today bye guys
just in person how you compile a launch
interpreter in it uh what do you mean
what language
okay so he says Justine says yeah buffer
is a copy of the file in Ram that is
true but you know you know
you know yeah that's it's true but look
at browser look at any application IDE
xcode
any editor okay
they are all buffers okay what do you
think this is you know a browser what do
you think this is
technically the your whatever you see on
your computer they are all buffers but
do you call them buffers that's the
thing you know think about the human you
know
human work with files okay file file
file is or window window is kind of a
workspace or screen you know that is the
concept human wants not buffer not
memory you know yeah they are perfect
but take the right word you say delete
the bytes do you say that that's a point
that's a point okay so we are talking
about the
Judgment of terminal terminology you
know there's an entire field of it
scientific terminology math jargons
you know there's actually standard about
terminology chemistry especially when
you know when you do science art
Sciences chemistry you know chemistry
engineering you know they are jargons
standards for
and they are good and bad you know
judgment Judgment of the jargons okay so
anyway that's it bye
shutting down in one minute one minute
one minute shut down
so I talked today for 15 minutes yeah
uh is there anything else across this
window is there anything I want to do
today uh that's it
so I showed my keyword stuff like his uh
workflow tips full screen versus
multiple flip frames okay uh
oh yeah there's some other tip at the
most efficient way to open a file never
type a full path to open a file more
than a few times use
bookmark so instead you know use
bookmark use recent F use last open last
course you know I have my tutorial on my
website just go uh you'll see it easy
so you can see
so if you go to
um
so you can see
uh bookmark that you know here's how to
do it bookmark and so on and open
recently closed okay set up Keys you
know just follow the tutorial bye guys