good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of saw talk
show I haven't seen you guys for a while
I haven't done a talk show in the past
two days so what we gonna do you know
the spice must flow you know that the
thing is this the interesting thing like
when you ride a bike with your friend to
some place you don't want to stop or if
you are running marathon you know that
like you can go slow if you want but
never stop because stops makes a huge
difference like if you stop for you know
ten seconds
your friend will pass you you know far
ahead so you know that's an interesting
thing I observed you know it doesn't
matter what thing you are doing running
or bicycling you know obviously you know
marathon competition you know the moment
you stop doing something it makes a huge
difference you know it it doesn't matter
as much if you you know if you are
slower good morning break the loop
haven't seen you for a while yeah so the
spice must flow have you seen the movie
doom that phrases from that movie so how
have you been doing so today I'm going
to do I'm thinking I'm going to do two
things one is light coating of Emacs
Lisp there is some there is some command
I like to modify so let's see I'll start
command log mod ok so this would be good
for any of you you know learning Emacs
or Emacs Lisp then I think I'm going to
do a JavaScript like coding
which is let's see JavaScript live
coding this is my talk show page of some
things here yeah Celtic knots let me
show you so here is the page so I'm
going to do eMac this coding and Celtic
knots now I'm going to code JavaScript
and I'm going to create this thing this
animation you know this will actually
take 40 minutes you know so I'm not sure
you know we are going to cover all that
you know just then the other thing so
eMac this code in JavaScript coding then
just random you know ask me questions
you know because I don't have a goal
like dashboard so okay so so let's see
should we start eMac this coding do you
use Emacs break the loop I think maybe a
little bit not much oh so so let me just
talk random me about this you see this
is XO loto axolotl this is a creature in
I think in Mexico some some lake in
Mexico and this creature is well-known
for one thing that is the regenerative
abilities like you can cut the limbs of
even part of the brain
there will be generate I mean they they
are the most they are the creature with
the most regional creative abilities you
know that's interesting because imagine
if you your limbs is cut off your hands
cut off you know and you can just square
it out again that's that's fantastic so
you know that's one of the dream of
human humanity you know we like to have
that so they're so this creature is very
interesting in that respect I think I
learned about this creature in the
science-fiction dune and that is epic
you know because they mentioned this
creature you know the act Rhea it's very
deep and dark they mentioned this
because of WAMP I think so there's a
yeah this thing called Axl Axl Axl Otto
tank I think let's look it up let's see
tank axolotl tank housing in captivity
no okay no the weight no not tank but
doom okay okay so they they have a
variation of the spelling so it's called
X little tank so the straining is
different so this is part of the
universe that don't story it's
fascinating you know you might check it
out so and by the way I also learned
this meme facial expressions it's called
a hey go and this this thing oh yeah I
think you cannot see it I mean you
should let me move it here
okay so this expression meaning is
called a hey cow you know it's pretty
much I'm now going to describe it but
and there's a history of it
it's from Japanese comics you know since
1990s okay well let's start coding in
Emacs least within yeah let's let's
start to do that and the command I want
to call is let's see
hello extract URL so so let's go to a
page for example computing blog showing
browser and there are several
interesting things but okay let's go to
a JavaScript so javascript javascript in
depth you see so this page there are
several links no okay I'm gonna open
that page and you see basics so so this
section correspond to this source code
in HTML and suppose I want to get all
the links you know of this block of text
so I have a command you can just call it
like that you see the command is called
saw HTML extract URL and here's a result
result is automatically in the clipboard
so I open a new buffer paste you see I
can get all the the file path of the URL
now there's a feature of this function
command that is if I call universal
argument first then it will get the full
path of each of the file for example let
me show you so control you then I call
my command you see that's a result so I
go here paste you see now you got the
full path of you know each of these
value of href attribute okay so you have
this option to get the full path but
what I want what I think is more
intuitive is get the full path by
default you know when you press control
you then you get the short path by the
way this command works if if you have a
URL that is you know start with HTTP you
know not local link that will just
return that you know HTTP full link for
example let's see if I can try that for
example here is a link I call the
command and I go here and what you got
is that okay that well that's not a good
example because that's not a HTTP link
you know this this starting with a
double slash that is a I think it's a
new feature around ten years ago in H in
HTML so this is code basically what that
means what this uija means is that you
just link to http if your current page
is using HTTP protocol and it will go to
http if your current page is using HTTP
protocol so you know that's because
that's that was the issue for people but
anyway so back to the Emacs command so I
want to modify this command HTML extract
URL
this command is let me show you the URL
so here is the source code for the
command and here is a URL and if you
like to use this command you can just
copy it and put in your emags
in it okay hi guys so say something ok
so today we're gonna do eMac this
javascript live coding and any random
questions you have
just post posting type in the comments
okay so back to Emacs so we have this
this command so you can use and now we
need to I want to modify it so that by
default it will copy the full path so I
guess first of all copy this new buffer
paste it here
sorry max least smart save it as some
temp name okay al okay then we're gonna
just modify this file so so the task is
so this so this command extract URL in a
file of a selection or text block if you
press ctrl ctrl you first it will create
the full path so what we want is the
default behavior to be full path so what
we need to do is
so I'm wondering if I should explain the
code because I guess for most people you
know yeah most people don't know emag
Lisp so this is in comprehensible anyway
no I think well if you have a question
okay if you don't know if you like to
know then just type the comment I think
I'm just going to directly code it
because to explain the code from the
ground up that'll be too much that will
be you know take a long time so anyway
so get country fix ox that we owe the
value of that variable is is what is is
the value of when you pressed control
you so that's a universal argument so we
are getting country fix OGG
so I want to modify this okay so so when
full path okay so I think you know I
think he is what are we gonna do this is
okay there there there is a lot to
explain but if I do not explain I don't
think anyone understand you know very
few people understand a thing then it's
going to be boring but anyway so this
function takes three arguments the
reason it takes three arguments is is
that so that if you are calling this
function in a Maglis you know not not
interactively but in eMac this code this
is very useful so you can call the
function PI for example for example 1 to
1000 ok Oh to 800 okay you can call this
function just like that and it will
return the URL in a list you know in the
selection from kusa position 1 to kusa
position 800 set so that's how you call
this command in email is but if you are
calling this command interactively
interactively where does Emacs gets you
know the these arguments well the way
they get the argument is peak is due to
this interactive cross you see that that
is the purpose of the interactive cross
for our function you know it's actually
not a function it's I think it's a
marker
anyway the interactive thing the purpose
of that is to generate by some means to
it to generate the arguments for the for
the function when when you are calling
this function interactively
you know for example I go to a HTML page
you know I want to go I want to extract
this this URL path so I I can just press
a key I call the command you can see on
the left side side camera extract URL
then I can paste it
you can you see I got the path so when I
call the command such tml extract URL I
didn't give it I didn't give it any
argument how does Emacs get the argument
you see because this function is
supposed to take two arguments begin
position and end position so where does
where did Emacs get the argument so that
so Emacs has a mechanism when you define
a function or command Emacs has a
mechanism that is by this interactive
function call in this interactive
section you can specify you know you do
tell you max how to get an argument for
the function when user cause the
function interactivity so here's a code
so you see we we check if you know if
there's a region user region position P
then you set p1 and p2 p2 to beginning
region position and end up region
position so p1 and p2 are two positions
like two numbers that is a starting
position in n position of the selection
if you have you know if you switch on P
is true returns true that means that
basically just means a if there's a
selection selection means you know um
you know a text selection so if there's
a selection then let P 1 P 2 P the
beginning and end of position of a
region but otherwise we say you see we
search for work with such backward by
empty lines
you know or tapped space basically by
two empty lines to empty beaten
characters such as these such as this or
over over over here over here it's you
know basically every beginning of a
paragraph so we move the cursor to there
then we basically set p1 then we move
the cursor to the bottom of the next
empty line then we set p2 here so
basically if there is a no if there is
no kusa position then this command will
take the current block of text the
cruiser is in you know a block means you
know separated by empty lines like this
so that's how it got the p1 and p2 you
know p1 and p2 is the beginning and end
position argument and once Emacs got
that you know those numbers it will just
pass it to the argument you know
beginning you know as you know first two
argument so that's how basically that's
how these interactive block works so let
me summarize so in the interactive block
of email is command is designed so that
when you call a function the function
require arguments but when you call a
function interactively you know you know
by o'keefe s or whatever then you need
to feel the argument so interactive
the interactive function is a way is a
mechanism such that when you define a
function you can tell Emacs how the
function should feel the argument
arguments when user code this function
interactively so that is what
interactive is for so
so what what is it that I need to do we
all need to we need to yeah they need so
we I you know so I need to explain so we
explained interactive I need to explain
how you get universal argument okay so
you know I think we changed the nature
of this talk a little bit because I was
going to just call this eMac this
command but I think few people and that
we all understand that that so instead
of we we start to explain some of the
basics of Emacs Lisp so let's go through
let's go to Emacs blog okay so so I have
an email is tutorial here you know you
can buy it if you you know want to
support me like my stuff you can you can
buy the whole entire you make this
tutorial so but what we're gonna do is
we have explained the interactive form
so there's a tutorial page here you can
read you know it's more precise and
detailed so that that is the interactive
form now the next thing we want to
explain is the universal argument now
you already know let me show you a MX
command that use you know let me explain
what is the universal argument so in
Emacs when you como command let's say I
mean diet you know the directory utility
to show the directory so I move the
cursor now there's a command let me code
the command is called tired copy file
name as keel you see so what does that
come and do that when you call that
command basically it will copy the file
path
of your kusa wherever your cursor is on
for example let's say my cursor is over
here and let me call that command so the
command has a shortcut W so I just
caught it you can see it prints a
message here but now it's on the
clipboard so I open a new buffer I can
paste it you can see that's a file name
let me try another example so I move my
cursor here then I call that code the
command W then I paste it you see I got
this file path so that's a very useful
feature in Emacs when you want to get a
file path now but notice this file path
is not the full path because the full
path will be like that the full
directory path so what do you so what if
you want the full path so so this so if
so this command tired copy file name is
Keo this command has a feature so if you
want to get the full path what you do is
you call the universal argument first
that's a Emacs thing so so what you do
is you press ctrl you so I prefer for
example let's move my cursor here okay
control you okay let me try it again
control you okay now actually let's
start over control you okay now I call
the command W press the key W which
caused the tired copy file name is key
oh okay now I call that now I go to the
buffer and I can paste it oh I made a
mistake so instead of control you you
have to press let's try this control u 0
then W ok now paste it you see you got a
full path so what's going on so
basically the
man copy tired copy filename skill it
has options to let you whether you know
whether you want the full path or not
but how do you invoke those options when
you are calling this command directly
especially if you are calling it by a
key you know keyboard shortcut so the
way so Emacs has a mechanism another
mechanism that is to let user optionally
feel the arguments to the command so in
the case of the command saw in the case
of the command where is it so in the
case of the command tired copy file name
is key oh it has options to let you copy
full path but in order to access those
options what you have to do is you have
to press control you first then press 0
then then then press the key to call the
command that's how you give it the
option now this is the general mechanism
this works for every Emacs of a command
so in other words anytime you call Emacs
command you can always try to press
control you you know that gives it some
option and but however not every command
supports that so so in other words Emacs
has this mechanism building to supply
arguments to commands when the command
is called interactivity so Emacs has
this you know this feature building but
however not every command use that
feature because for many commands it
doesn't make sense to have you know lots
of options so anyway so so that is the
universal command ok so
so you so so Universal command is you to
call Universal command you just press
control you then then you call the
command whatever command you call you
want to call such as MX something the
command name or or by a keyboard and
also the control you can can can be
followed by digits like zero to nine so
anyway so that is universal argument let
me see I have a article here well I have
a article here about get universal
argument so this so I think is it
confusing because we just talked about
two topics that are very very similar
one is interactive form and one is the
universal argument both of them are
related to passing arguments to a
command when the command is called
interactively
yeah but you see they are different in a
way that the interactive form when you
call the interactive form the purpose of
the interactive form it's a email is
function you know it's a you know email
is construct that tells Emacs how to
feel the arguments when of a function
but the universal argument is actually
is slightly different
it's not about feeling in the parameters
of a function but rather it's about
extra extra options of a function like
variant behaviors of a function so
whenever you create an Emacs command you
know typically you have the parameters
you know the the the arguments that
tells the function you know what what to
do well not what to do but you know the
input for the argument for the function
but sometimes you want you know so
typically in every programming language
you if you want a different behavior of
a function you create a new optional
argument you know you just pass the
argument and you you know signify to the
function you know what to do but in
Emacs there is another way like a new
way so you you could you know just like
every programming language you could
create a new parameter you know optional
parameter you know that indicates tells
the function what very and behavior to
do but besides that Emacs has a
different way and that is the universal
argument so and this universal argument
is is when you call a function
interactively you can press control you
first then give it a number so that's
how a max find out you know whether if
you want alternative behavior of some
command
so does that does that all make sense
let me know so so we explained you know
we expand eMac this interactive
interactive form and we expand universal
argument so now so what is the next next
should we continue to work on this
modify this Emacs base code wait am I
still broadcasting I think I am okay
good okay so let's see so so let's
continue modify this this this command
then so so this command HTML extract URL
now remember it takes a universal
argument so that if you press ctrl you
first it will copy the full path so the
way this function works let me explain
yeah since we explained about arguments
and options a lot let me explain how
this function works so the function you
know as a Maglis argument arguments it
parameters it takes three parameters
speaking and positions and a optional
parameter called full path and the value
should be either true or false so if you
know it is true then it returns the full
path of the local file path in in URL if
it's false then just you know the
filename
not without the directory name so we
have these arguments it's all nice you
know it's very nice it's it's
you know and you can call this function
in Elise like this too so so it has
these options and how does Emacs get
these odd these arguments when you call
interactively we have explained that
that is done by interactive form okay
now what if what if user code is
interactively and they want the full
path you know they want the full path
that is they want to be able to pass a
the optional argument true you know as
the the third argument so that way is
done over here you can see the code over
here so it's again it's part of the
interactive form so the interactive form
basically automatically returns a list
returns this list so this list contains
three items p1 p2 and current prefix
argh argh the p1 and p2 are the
beginning and end end position and the
third argument current prefix ugh is the
you know is the full path parameter so
it the value of that is true or false so
what is the current prefix ugh now that
is a building function basically if user
code this function with control u that
is the universal argument if if if he
press control you first then the current
prefix are the value of that will be
true otherwise it will be false so in
this way when we have this interactive
form here and it returns the list you
can see it returns the list here so the
list contain three arguments these three
arguments are corresponds to the
parameters of this function so this is
how
a mask it gets those those arguments so
let's look at the documentation for
current prefix Hogg so you see its value
is new documentation is a is the value
of the prefix argument for this editing
command and you know it may be a number
or may be a symbol negative sign or just
a minus sign you know ba ba ba that's
the details but but anyway this is
called universal argument in Emacs so
this is how this command gets the
arguments when when you suppose it
interactively okay that explained that
so the way we want to modify so you see
we want to modify oh yeah so now we
understand this it's very easy to modify
this all we have to do is to - not this
argument you know that just pull in turn
it reverse the boolean value so if it's
true return false if it's false return
true yes so so that yeah that's so easy
to modify now so let's see but we have
to modify the name though because we
just reversed the meaning so it change
for path P by the way then the name - P
at the end that is Emacs convention for
any variable or function that returns
true or false so if you have a function
that returns either true or false you
you want to name it with - P at the end
the the P stand for predicate now
predicate came from logic predicate
basically means a statement or sentence
that is true or false so anyway so
function so we want to change the name
to
full path P then change it to not full
pads P okay that's what we want because
we just changed its meaning here so okay
now it's done its evaluate the buffer so
Emacs knows the new definition of this
command now let's go back to a HTML file
and let's test test it so go to
JavaScript blog actually go to
JavaScript web site which is JavaScript
in-depth go to the basic section so we
want to extract URL of this text block
so let's call the command Co it and we
got a full path that is correct
excellent we open a new file paste
verify that it is all full path that is
correct that's great
now let's try press ctrl you then call
the command
okay now that works too it returns the
justifier name so that's a success so
that is successful so let so what we do
is we copy this command copy it go to my
excit ml mod paste it in remove the old
tech code save it because this command
HTML extract URL is part of my side HTML
mod you can try if you like it so that
completes our first topic and yeah that
that is actually good I think it went
smooth that completes our first topic
of live Emacs coding and we explained so
let me summarize we explained the
interactively interactive form and we
explained the get universal argument
fantastic so what is the next topic so
guys what will be the next topic you
know type something let me know I'm
drinking tea cheap teabags
so the next topic let's go to clothes
that we don't need it okay so this go to
the next topic
so get Universal argument Celtic knots
transit tires combinatorial patterns
this is okay so I'm thinking you know
maybe we stopped coding for now so you
know I'm just going to chat randomly
like maybe interesting things this this
this one is about math now this thing
you see here it's you know it's isn't
that beautiful
that's called rancette tiles
it's named after you know some guy
tranch it's something you can you can
look it up on Wikipedia there's a
Wikipedia page on chanchad tiles but
anyway it's a technique to generate
interesting patterns as you can see all
you have to do is you you start with a
square and okay this is a good time to
use you know digital pen like maybe I
can play with that I have a digital pen
I'm not sure this will walk and it's not
connected so let's try you see let me
show you so you see I got this thing
this is oh yeah let me mention this so
it might be fun for you guys to buy it
it's $60 or was it $40 oh yeah so this
let me talk about something interesting
you know the ok trench it tires okay you
can you know you know what it is right
so let's go to your keyboard keyboard is
the fascinating subject okay you can go
to my keyboard block let me show you
there are some some news about keyboard
yeah let's talk about keyboard so this
guy created this this Do It Yourself
keyboard this guy is on Twitter now he
is I suppose his anonymous so he created
his Do It Yourself keyboard so his name
is shipping something like that so it's
interesting it's an ergonomic keyboard
you know you know it's similar to the
one I am using you see the one this is a
keyboard I am using this is called
Kinesis advantage to keyboard and you
can see it on my blog okay so you can
see it on my blog here that's that
keyboard and but this guy's creation is
something similar yeah so let me talk
about this Canisius advantage now this
so yeah let's give me let's give a
history of this economic curved surface
key
concave surface keyboard so the first
one as far as I know I think it's
actually true
the first one invention of this keyboard
is called matron now they began in 1977
I think he's the first I've seen
references kind of I'm not you know I
think I've seen say my reference is
saying that there's a IBM one before
this but I wasn't sure of that so as far
as I know this is the first one 1977
they you know we are talking about the
curved surface keyboard with a curved
poor surface for the you know fingers
keys why that because this way is more
ergonomic like when you put your hand on
a keyboard you see let me show you you
see this is my G as you can see the
means even try this
okay I'm going to try to make the video
I'm going to try to make the video full
so I might blank out for 30 seconds so
bear with me
you
check
so my audio is back let me turn on the
video this video let me turn on the
video this this software OBS is pretty
good it's an open-source software but
sometimes the video settings and audio
settings they get corrupted or crash
something like that so you can see that
is my keyboard now that's a up snake
let's do that again
so modify big ok now you can see me I
think so anyway so that's that's my
keyboard
that's my mouse this is fantastic with a
spin wheel infinite spin I showed it
many times in my video talks so oh yeah
so I was going to say so if you look at
the keyboard you know so this is curved
you can see that it's you know it's
going down you know so when I put my
fingers there you know no more keyboard
it would be like that because it's flat
you know I'm normal keyboard you your
your wrists pens up that's no good so
that's why they invented this curved you
know curved concave surface curved
keyboard you know which is ergonomic so
if you type a lot that is good for you
so in a beginning beginning in 1997 1917
1977 this motor on guy you know they
have a history on their website Stefan
hopped a lady and linear Lillian mode
she I think she designed and invented it
and you know
so anyway so this is the beginning it
was in the beginning it was for disabled
people you know people who have problems
who type in have hand injuries but
anyways this is this is fantastic if you
are programmer or writer you use
keyboard but this one is very expensive
though you know this motrin is like five
hundred dollars no it's not so it's too
expensive so what you want and the one I
have is this one Canisius advantage now
they began they began in 1990 or 18 I
something like that
basically they borrowed you know the
story I heard is that they they try to
the motor on is pretended you know
patent patented but I think you know
Canisius talk to them and something
didn't work out so can it Kinesis just
created their own basically just copied
them but removing all the number keys in
the middle you know I don't think you
know you can pass patent by doing that
because essentially you are still you
know borrowing other people's inventions
but I don't know what's a deal between
them you know legal deal or how they
work things out but anyway Kinesis came
up with this you know also concave
surface concave surface keyboard without
a bunch of keys in the middle so it's
very good you know I've been using it
this is about $320 now don't quote me on
on the price because price changes all
the time you know like sometimes you
watch some video they say oh this is
hundred dollars it turns out 200 or it
turns out $50 then people get annoyed so
anyway so because price price actually
changes all the time but anyway you know
if you like it buy it on my website
links you know just such Forks are
decent Canisius advantage so this
keyboard is very good you know it's
designed so we I have explained why
the concave surface keys you know I can
show you some typing on it but actually
I have already you know videos about it
so you can watch it there so that's that
so you have these you know commercial
versions of concave surface keyboard but
people started to be oh they are own
today so let me show you for example Do
It Yourself keyboard so you know
beginning with 3d printing you know like
five or 10 years ago it became popular
people start to create their own stuff
so you have this one which is right now
it's the most popular do-it-yourself
keyboard
it's called tactile and you know if you
are in kind you can you can build it
yourself you know you just buy the parts
but however it's not going to be cheap
needle it's a it's like he told me it's
going to be like 350 or 400 dollars
actually you know cost you that much
then you have to build it yourself you
know so during you know you know by the
keycaps by the parts 3d printed and you
know soldier at everything he doesn't
sell you know this so this guy created
it you know this is a great guy he is a
Emacs user he is also a crucial Lisp
coder you know he loved closure by the
way he's also Mathematica user
Mathematica is my favorite language he's
also actually he's he used of all the
people I know programmers because in the
industry you don't you really see a
program used that uses Mathematica I
mean maybe they have used it in college
you know for a month or something but
that doesn't count you know you have to
like use language and he so this guy met
other if he actually codes Mathematica
so he's also he's a fan of closure in
emacs as well so he created this
keyboard so he can go to his website you
know he's this github you got all the
information which you know the parts you
need to build this keyboard so this is
one example of do-it-yourself keyboard
with the concave surface but then people
started to create more I mean I don't
I'm not sure doctor is the first one
well this is so it's the first that's
most popular okay it's one of the first
then you have also this tactile manual
form which you know people created by
the way so today there's like tons of
them you know so there is one called
manual foam keyboard which which kind of
looks like that you know the
distinguishing feature of the men who
form keyboard is this thumb keys is
weird thumb keys so but someone I don't
actually I don't have a page for the man
who foam keyboard but you can search the
web you'll find it so someone created
this menu from keyboard let's see images
those are not the audio these are not it
in fact most of it is pictures for my
website so you have to actually go to
get I guess yeah those are not manifold
you have to go to
okay here github Jeff Jeff Graham annual
foam I think this is the one he doesn't
have pictures this these nerds you know
waking why can't they just for the
picture you know you need a picture or
two this is this you know so people can
understand it you know because this nerd
side my complaints about these nerds
this you know this open source or UNIX
did they they are unable to think they
are unable to think properly when it
comes to you know user interface or you
know convenience for users they are
unable to they are the typical Steve
your typical nerd of the engineer they
look like inflexible like unable to
comprehend thing well except technical
things so this submenu from keyboard
they don't have a picture well you can
find it somewhere
but anyway so someone combine the menu
from keyboard design the thumb keys with
the with the tactile keyboard design so
they combine them so they created this
doctor manual phone keyboard you know so
you can I I think there's also a github
page you can go to if you want this so
so you have man new tactile menu foam
that you know then there is more so
people have the this one is from Japan
the Japanese have created this colloseum
keyboard now I don't think this one is
based on tactile yeah I don't think so
you know you can see the thumb keys
arrangement huh you know and the curves
are very different you know they they
may be inspired by it but anyway so Jack
you know this one made by some people in
Japan Japanese
and you can you know go to the there's a
Japanese Japanese website you know you
can buy the parts I have no idea how
these lump Keys supposed to work you
know I I can't imagine so I suppose this
you know with this keyboard normally
like oh my oh my Kinesis even the thumb
keys you press it down so on this
collosseum keyboard I suppose you kind
of press inward I'm not sure how I feel
about that you know I I cannot imagine
it's that good you know but you don't
know PQ you actually have to try it to
know and here's the interesting you know
they got a spinner a key cab I really
should have you know I'd love to have
that you know a spin on a key cab so so
you know Japanese Japanese created that
then someone this guy created this
keyboard he said he's going to this is a
prototype he said he's going to clean it
up and stuff you know he sent me
messages on reddit but I don't think
it's done you know it's been a year now
yeah so anyway so there are these you
know variations of keyboard you know
with this concave surface and this one
is most spectacular I'm not even sure
how it works this oh go wrap okay
oh go Wolfe keyboard I'm not sure what
that boy is for it looks like a
trackball but I can imagine how you use
a trackball like that you know I don't
even know where do you put your fingers
on this thing so anyway we'll go up
keyboard so yeah so there are all these
variations
you know people created so that is why
you know I find so this this one is a
new one
you can see this one is new one anyway
so that's about keyboard
let's see how many people are watching
find people okay about keyboard I think
that's about it today the JavaScript
will do another day then so we have live
coding of emag DS and concave surface
keyboards intro okay so that's today's
topic so thank you guys for watching
possibly I'll do another one the next
one coming up in maybe six hours so see
you guys have a good day
can I break the loop