Good evening, everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Xah Talk Show.
We are going to code Emacs Lisp, very
technical, extreme.
So, if you don't code Lisp, you don't
know what I'm talking about, and this
video is boring to you.
You don't want to watch it, okay?
So, I'm going to code Emacs Lisp, and
I'm going to have this red wine, and by
the time I finish this red wine, we
shall be done.
It'll be 30 minutes, actually.
I can do it fast, it'll be 20 minutes.
If I do it slowly and talk, it'll be an
hour. Let's go slowly, okay?
So, meanwhile, let me enjoy my red wine.
And now, show my screen so you can see
what you are dealing with.
Emacs, okay? The most powerful editor on
Earth.
Lots of work on web dev, but today we
want to go to Xah Talk Show.
This is are looking at, and xahlee.org,
which together has 13,000
pages written,
character by character,
in the past 30 years, okay? So, Xah Talk
Show, that's today, and let's go to Xah
Talk Show episode 791, that is today.
Now, today, this is what we're going to
do Emacs Lisp.
Write a Emacs Lisp script, so let me
actually modify this because
So, let me let me talk, okay? Let me
tell you what's going on. So, can you
hear me?
If you are here, raise your hands, okay?
I'd like to see it. Can you hear me?
Uh and last check, video check,
audio check, I'm alive, okay?
Now, talk show.
Now, today, episode 796.
if you don't code Emacs and Lisp, you
would not be interested, okay? You can
go watch a movie.
Uh and let me explain this, okay? So,
today is just um Emacs Lisp
write a Emacs Lisp
script
that
adds width and height to all thumbnails
uh all thumbnail HTML mark up in
>> [snorts]
>> about
13,000
files.
Okay?
Okay? Now, let's um show in browser.
So, that is what we're going to do.
Okay? And today's talk show is part
three of the past talk show. So, showing
browser so you can see
part one is episode 787,
done about a month ago. Part two is
yesterday, or actually 2 days ago, seven
episode 795, and today's part three.
So, previously we talked about why we
need to do it, such as uh cumulative
layout shift. That's one of the web dev
issue. And uh you looked at browser
tools, browser dev tools, and networking
tools, things like that. And yesterday
we wrote a command in Emacs Lisp in
Emacs Emacs Lisp
that such that you press a key, it
something becomes a button, okay? Let me
show you what we did yesterday.
So, you go to Xah keyboard website. So,
let's see, do it yourself keyboards,
also lots of keyboard reviews. So, copy
the
uh URL and switch back to Emacs. That's
a keyboard macro, by the way, using
AutoHotkey. Search my website, you'll
find AutoHotKey
tutorial.
Okay, now press press press. That's
another Emacs command I have, which will
open the file path in the clipboard.
You see. Now showing browser, you see
that's the same page. Now press a key to
switch back, okay? Now go to the top go
to the top so
so you can see
uh
Dactyl keyboard picture, okay?
Uh this one is Dactyl manual form.
Manual is etymology of manual. The
prefix means hand, okay? Like manual
workers. You manual laborers.
unaffected by AI today. That's nice.
Make money.
Hello WeHam.
Good morning and good evening. You can
hear me, that's fantastic.
I forgot where you are. WeHam, I
remember you being on my show a few
times, but I don't remember
where you are. You
Where do you hail from?
Germany.
Okay.
But today I guarantee, you know, in the
past
it's been once or twice that I drunk
I got drunk. I cannot code, okay? But
today I guarantee we're going to finish
the job, okay?
Uh so anyway, so so back to this so you
can see this is uh
image file
in this directory and this directory has
600 image files. For example, you can
open actually open lots of them. The
power of Emacs.
Actually, I wonder can VS Code do that?
Let's see. Uh
VS Code. So open VS Code, that's Emacs
command you can find on my website. So,
open it open this
file in VS Code. Let's see this can be
>> [laughter]
>> VS Code.
A [ __ ] idiot. VS Code cannot display
an image. This file is not displayed in
a text editor because it is either
binary or use an unsupported text
encoding.
>> [laughter]
>> Very nice. Very nice. The modern editor
VS Code. [ __ ] idiot.
[ __ ] [snorts] them.
So, anyway, this directory you can see
6,000, I mean 600 files. This is one of
the image directory.
So, you can you can open it. Okay, let
me ramble. Shall I? Well, if I start to
ramble, I cannot finish the coding, you
know. So, by the way, so that's that's a
PDF, okay? So, anyway, so you started to
look at images, okay? So, all these are
images in VS Code. By the way, I got
this keyboard cheap China cheap.
Not very good, okay? But looks looks
looks good. So, for example, let's try
VS Code again. Open this in VS Code,
please.
Oh, it can open. Wait, what?
It can open JPEG. So, what's the problem
with uh is that what?
What?
Open in VS Code. Oh, it can.
So, what was the [ __ ] problem? This
uh
ZTM mech keyboard, okay? So, let's see.
So, this one
Let's try again. Wait, so it's so it's
when it's a binary it, you know,
it gives you a warning for the first
time. Then you can click open anyway.
So, anyway, stupid.
So, let's do a screenshot of this, Okay,
so we have a record of this thing.
What? What?
Okay, wait.
Uh
>> [snorts]
>> cancel. Let's
So, are you guys following me? Is this
interesting? Okay. Do you like uh guys
like me to like focus on the uh
coding Emacs or do you like the way I
talk now?
So, first time I have watched your you
was probably 2014 already. Wow, 2014.
2014 that's what that was
I didn't really do live stream. I only,
you know, did one or two videos.
Uh that was the my poverty days.
Uh your unique strengths were legendary.
I'm so glad you are still around and
still coding. Thank you very much. Thank
you.
Yeah.
But, you know, so my but my life is a
tragedy.
Which I consider, you know, I'm going to
write a
uh what they call uh autobiography.
You know.
>> [laughter]
[gasps]
>> The academic mumbo jumbo list would say
autobiography.
That's what I used to be, you know,
that's I, you know,
you know, I am, you know, the academic
like professor stuff.
So, I uh
anyway, my my my my life story is uh
kind of a tragedy, okay? Like the the
Greek tragedy tradition tradition.
So, 2014 that was 10 years ago. So, I'm
10 years older and so are you.
So, what do you do?
Okay, so let's put that aside. So, let's
So, yeah, so control print. Now, we have
a screenshot, a record of history of
this VS code creating this error, okay?
Cancel.
By the way, yesterday
I installed a new image viewer. This is
a great one. This is This one is called
Glass View.
Okay,
uh God, I'm rambling all over. Okay,
anyway, this one is a is open source,
cross-platform. It's called Glass I
believe it's called Glass View. I forgot
I just installed it, okay? Glass View,
okay.
And by the way, you are seeing you are
seeing this funky layout, that's because
I I did a new thing about
control T S in Firefox to open the
settings.
And Firefox new version, you know, last
week they just changed the the
how the
settings
look, so you got a different look.
Anyway, in settings, you go to
appearance, then you go to
customize zoom in font. You know, before
it's right here, but now you have to
like
click to a next to a page. Then, you
see, what I used to do is just say
default zoom 150, okay?
Whenever I start a live stream, but
today I I did something different. I go
to the font settings and I set minimum
font size 32.
So, this way
this way typical
pages, you know, the font size increased
huge, but the image stays.
Uh
and but there's some technical issues
about the CSS, you know, the web dev
layout. So, for example, my website
still works fine.
But when you go to the
the you know, the Google search or you
know, the Brave search, they become
you know, this is
you know, they become [ __ ] okay? So,
anyway, GlassView
uh
inventors of the emotion. No, that's not
it. Okay, GlassView
uh
Not GlassView, okay? The edit I I I but
uh ImageGlass, okay? I ask AI, "What's a
good open-source image viewer on
Microsoft Windows that supports WebP?"
And it tells me uh ImageGlass, okay? So,
that's one. So, open it open it paste it
ImageGlass.
You see they got [ __ ] up. Now, let's
try Google if Google
Okay, now let's just uh play with it.
Press press press press
my Emacs command. Cuz now I look up
Google. Fantastic and beautiful, you
see? So, now this is a Google website
image search when you have the text
magnified to
um
32 uh
pi- uh pixels. And uh but
um
So, as you see
And okay, so so they don't you know,
they look okay, you know, like So, this
is uh Brave search. This is Google
search.
But my website still looks the best, you
know, you my website design. But you
see, look at the Google website design,
you see? The sign in button got [ __ ]
You know, but not too bad.
But I I'm going to tell you right now
right now. If you go to one of those oh,
I'm a designer working at Google their
website.
You know, you go to their website like
like like the I'm the design guru. They
lead, you know, the project like they
they they are the thought leaders.
Everyone every [ __ ] idiots coders
follow them. Like like like the that the
Ruby on Rails guy, okay? Those type of
people.
You know, they they say things on their
blog, you know, every everyone follows.
Oh, you should do responsive
responsive action. What they call
What the [ __ ] is it that they call?
Uh
Um let's see.
Um
I remember I know the word, okay? By the
way, I'm not angry, but I'm putting on a
show. This is what you are watching, a
show cuz I talk show.
You know, so you want to be a little bit
dramatic.
Cheers.
Uh responsive design. Wait, is it is it
they call design? But anyway, so this is
my visual CSS fantastic I've been
working on
a lot updates in the past two month
three month have heavy heavy update,
okay?
So
and I did live stream, you know, in the
past two weeks about how you need a PhD
to
understand CSS today. Oh, look at this
funky multi-column not not they become
looks like that.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh wait, it's it's called responsive
um
Let me Wait, I need to remember this,
okay? Is it responsive design? No, they
they have like the zoom a jargon like
responsive [ __ ]
Um
Cheers.
Oh, okay, they call it responsive
design, you know, the media query.
Anyway, we are digressing, okay? So
anyway, that's uh
We finish. That's a um
side remark about my VS um uh
my CSS
my CSS website, okay? Now back to
Google,
okay, back to Google, back back to Brave
Search. What I wanted to tell you is
about this
Image Glass.
Which is a great so far experience. My
experience is great. Actually, I only
downloaded an hour ago.
But I, you know, so but I think it's
very good, okay? So, Image Glass
open source and cross-platform, okay?
So, I think I think I recommend I don't
I don't know actually. I only use it for
like um
an hour, you know, so I can't really
say. But anyway, so
Anyway, we digress so much, okay? So,
wait.
Reopen that, cut cut close close and go
to Xah Talk Show. We want to have a
record of the fact that we talked about
Image Glass, okay?
So, showing browser.
Okay, and and remember we did a
screenshot of the
uh
of the VS Code showing this arrow, okay?
So, that's in that directory, but now
press press press press that we'll move
that image file to this directory and
showing browser.
There it is. It moved the image file to
this directory of the Xah Talk Show, but
also it created a entire figure image
tag
to show it, okay? So, and and also
automatically optimized the PNG, you
see, huh?
Amazing, powerful, the power of the Xah
Emacs system, the most efficient
in the world, okay? Xah Fly Keys, which
is
uh open source, you can get it, okay?
Anyway, so now but I want to rename
this, so
this is VS Code.
Um
image like display image error, okay?
Let's just say that, okay? And this is a
PNG file. Now, let's change it to WebP.
Now, about two or three
live stream ago, I talked about the new
image image format.
The wide color gamut, okay? You should
watch it.
You know, a few days ago.
Wide color gamut. So, there's new image
format WebP and actually WebP doesn't
support wide color gamut, not really.
Anyway, the WebP that you got HEIC, you
got
um AVIF
and you got um JPEG XL, okay? So, if you
go to talk show
go to talk show index page
you see a few days ago, episode 794
on
2026 June 16th, you got this in you
know, I talked about that for a long
hour, wide color gamut. And the HEIC
AVIF JPEG XL and WebP image format,
okay? That's, you know, so
very interesting, okay? So, now
and I've been working lots of So, I I
worked I So, for example, let's convert
convert this to WebP. So, how do I do in
Emacs?
Like the typical Unix idiots, they would
they would the way they do it, they go
to bash.
Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> The typical Unix idiot idiot, okay? They
go to bash and they
see they C W WebP. That's a
command line utility from Google to
convert any image to the WebP. Okay,
then you type the path. Well, how do you
type the path? Well, the type is the
then you do completion. Uh doesn't work.
now exactly what is the S wait VS code
okay so
because we renamed it so you go back so
you need to VS code completion
that's how you do it okay
and also okay
and you need to say lossless okay dash
lossless
that's how you do it typical Unix idiot
but the way I do it okay so here's a PNG
file that says
um
press press press
you see three key press
and
it calls the command side HTML convert
to web P so the link is already changed
for you that web P and the LS means
lossy well so web P support lossless and
lossy two two modes okay actually I made
a mistake I want lossless but anyway I
got a lossy one so you can press enter
to open it and you can drop into the
directory so you can magnify full screen
so you can see here's original PNG it
got it's deleted renamed okay and the
new one is lossy dot web P
open showing showing Emacs fantastic now
can you actually
show open in VS code I want to know if
VS code
supports displaying web P image format I
suppose it does
okay it does
oh god
so is it fun are you guys enjoying the
show
that's it okay I got I got I need to get
to work
because I haven't start coding yet I
haven't started coding emails this week.
I work as a language tutor helping
Chinese people who want to build a life
in Germany.
That's that's nice. So you teach German,
right? You teach Chinese people speaking
German.
Nothing related to computing. That's
interesting.
I but I always had a programming as a
hobby. Okay, very interesting.
Yeah, because normally non-tech people
they don't get into
you know, the programming as a hobby.
Some do. I mean so usually you have
Yeah, well.
So what's your favorite programming
language? That's a frequently asked
question and those who people who ask
that means you haven't watched a lot
many of my videos in the past five
years. So I've like
By now I have 700, you know, today is
700 episode.
And more than 100 of them actually more
than 300 of them about
programming. Okay, I would say more than
100 of them
about
programming languages. So I spent hour
just to rant about programming languages
like attacking Python or this or that or
telling you what is my favorite. For
example, Wolfram language, okay. So
So in short, okay, let me give you the
short
sweet answer.
Wolfram language. Wolfram language also
known as Mathematica, that's the most
powerful language on Earth by a
magnitude, okay. It's not like the okay,
you know, by the way, you know, pay
attention like very carefully to exactly
what I say.
It is the most What what most about
what? The most powerful
programming language. Not not the most
easy to learn.
Not the smallest programming language.
Not the fastest. Not the the most used.
Okay, but it's the most powerful
programming language
on Earth.
Oh, well, it's most powerful, but by how
much? Like twice as powerful as Python?
Or like how much? By a magnitude.
Meaning like 100 times, okay? So,
Wolfram Language is is the most powerful
programming language on Earth by a
magnitude. So, Wolfram Language and I I
have over 100 videos about that, okay?
But it's not suitable for industrial
programming. That's typically
what you guys are thinking. Like C, C++,
Java, C#, Python, JavaScript. This kind
of [ __ ] okay? These are what I call in
industrial programming because they um
they are the bread and butter of the
like computing industry.
Um and their purpose is not about
mathematics. It's not about computer
science.
Oh,
>> [laughter]
>> C is not about computer science? No, not
at all.
C and C++ are the are the [ __ ] the
ass of computer science, okay?
So, oh but all of them, C, C++,
JavaScript, Python, PHP, Java. There,
you got six of the most popular
programming languages in the computing
industry, okay? They are basically all
[ __ ]
So, anyway, so you you got uh you you
get my opinion, okay? But let's get back
to this, okay? So, uh yeah.
>> [sighs]
>> Uh we at this rate we're not going to go
anywhere. Well, I mean, I guess it's
entertaining for you guys, but
I'm not doing anything productive, so
Now, I need to
Okay, I need to get back to to get the
things I want to do done, okay?
And okay, so this WebP image, yeah. So,
we just press you know, we just scored a
command that converted a PNG to WebP,
okay? So, and you will not also notice
by the way, wait.
So.
Okay, so the original is 57
kilobytes. The WebP lossy is only 40 is
49. That
it didn't save a lot.
That's interesting.
Because it's lossy, right?
Okay, anyway, that's a digression, okay?
So,
I don't want a lossy, okay? So, let me
redo it because I don't want a lossy.
Because for a screenshot like that, you
know, basically
your computer screen, you don't want it
to be lossy. You So, this is a like a
little tip, okay? So, basically you want
it to be lossy only when it's like a
photograph, okay? So, for all those of
you new guys, if you don't know much
about these technical details, let me
tell you. So, there is By the way, Xali
immortality.
Xali AI immortality. Xali has achieved
AI immortality. So, all these um
AI bots are telling you I'm in their
data set. Chat GPT 5.5, Chat GPT 5.4
Mini, Claude Opus, Claude Haiku, Quack
4.2, Gemini, Kimmy, and Deep Seek, Lama,
and so you know, so they scored me.
>> [laughter]
>> So apparently George showed me this
website
intheweights.com,
okay? So you type a name, they will show
you like like typically people type
um
like Shakespeare,
Mozart, you know, famous people or
singers or Michael Jackson.
So they get high score. So you know, so
so you kind of see you can see
uh you know, popular people. So so but
if you type my name, I'm also in the
database and and it says I'm top 3%.
>> [laughter]
>> Fantastic.
Uh Jesus.
Okay, that's fun. Okay. So I I was
digressing into about the image format,
okay? So image format intro.
PNG is lossless. JPEG is lossy.
WebP is either lossless or lossy. It can
do both, okay?
And GIF is lossless. Now the lossy
format is kind of nasty because every
time you save you lose the image quality
degrades.
Anyway, so we digressed, okay? Let me
get back to what I want to do.
Okay, so anyway, so yeah, so we don't
want this uh
Okay, this PNG. Now press press press.
Now we have a lossless version, okay?
The loss The lossless version is
actually smaller.
You see for Let me press okay. Let me do
this. Press, press. Okay, 42K lossless
version. You see, how do I know? Because
I
the file name has LL in it.
Now, the lossy version,
the file name it has LS in it. Okay,
it's actually larger. Can you see? You
see, very interesting. Because when you
have a image that's like a drawing, you
know, like you not not a photograph,
then the lossy may in fact be I mean the
lossless version may in fact be smaller
in file size than the uh
lossy version. Okay, so anyway, that's
very interesting technical detail about
all the image image formats. Okay, so
we've been
like we've been researching into image
format for the past uh 40 years, you
know, JPEG, WebP, GIF, you know, like
why do they create new formats like um
you know, so it's because it's very
interesting. Okay.
So anyway, so so yeah, so we got the
lossless version. That's what we want.
We don't want the lossy version, and we
don't want the JPEG PNG version anymore.
So, delete them.
Uh what?
Delete them.
Delete them. Close that. Okay, wait. Uh
okay, so you want the
lossless version. Close, close. Okay,
let's re- recreate this figure tag and
show in browser.
There we have it. Lossless
WebP format. Okay.
Oh god, what we doing? So, image class.
So, uh yeah, write the image this
script. So, let's do that.
Jesus, so how long have I been talking
for
uh 30 minutes. Is that right? Yeah,
okay, 32 minutes. Okay.
I rambled for 32 minutes. Um, so some
questions. Let's see.
I'm curious, what is your take on Julia?
I'm interested in graph theory and it
seems Julia has pretty good intuitive
syntax, also good for plotting. Yes.
Julia
I don't have any experience with it.
Okay, but I've heard and I believe it is
so that Julia is one of the best
functional programming language,
especially for mathematics and
scientific programming.
So right now I'm learning F sharp. So my
my my choice has been I wanted to learn
OCaml, F sharp
or Julia or Haskell, you know, one of
these.
Haskell is like
turned out, you know, eliminated. So
basically Julia is one of the
programming language I wanted to learn.
But right now I'm sticking with OCaml F
sharp. Well, OCaml OCaml is very
difficult to install on Windows, so I
went to
F sharp instead. They are basically
almost the same thing, okay?
OCaml and F sharp. So Julia is
very close to these groups, okay?
Haskell, OCaml, Julia, F sharp, okay?
Uh, and Julia is one of the thing
I think I consider very good and very
fast, faster than F sharp and OCaml,
okay? And Haskell.
So good choice, I would say great
choice.
And Julia is not typed, it's not
statically typed, so that's very
interesting. But they claim to be faster
than any, even C.
Uh, I mean, very close to C, okay? So
faster than C++ or Go land, like in this
realm. They, you know, it's very
competitive. That's So that's a very
interesting character- characteristics
because Julia is like almost pure
functional programming. It's a
functional programming language.
So, so yeah. And so yeah. So, if you you
know, I would I would recommend it
highly, okay? You know, there's the one
slight
offensive news I knew about Julia
because I heard
in a social justice warrior days, you
know, the Julia like people uh the
creator or whatever, you know, they they
are like sponsoring Oh, oh, we we we
believe in the social justice warriors.
We believe in trans. Therefore, we we
sponsor
uh this feminist group, something like
that. Very annoying. But, anyway, back
in the day everyone is doing that
because, you know, it's a power
struggle.
Because if you don't believe if if you
don't raise your hand,
they're going to do something to you,
okay? That's a nasty of the you know,
when when some political two tumult
happens.
So, back then everyone is doing that,
you know, including Golang, including
especially including the Rust, you know,
you go to the What's Rust website? Oh,
rainbow flag, you know.
Anyway.
Um
Okay, so.
Hammers body Hammers body says C C++ and
Java greater than
Python, PHP, and JavaScript. No, that's
not um
Hammers body, that's not a good idea.
That's actually
>> [laughter]
>> It's actually idiotic idea. So, Hammers
body says
Ham- Ham-
uh Hames body, something like that. He
opined that C and C++ and Java is
greater than Python, PHP, JavaScript.
That is a um
bad uh
opinion, okay? Basically, that type of
opinion is kind of like believing how
um low-level languages is better than
higher-level language. That's worse
That's a worse idea, actually.
You know, so
you see, there are many ways to judge a
language in a scientific way. Okay, even
in a scientific way
Okay, so first of all, you know, you
have scientific way and you have
non-scientific way, okay? Non-scientific
way is the most people
believes. You know, "Oh, I like C
because Well, because I like it." Okay,
the [ __ ] Most of their opinion
about programming languages, which is
better, are just idiots.
Most of them vast majority of
programming language opinions belongs to
this non-scientific way, okay?
You know, like So So what is a
scientific way? Well, scientific way you
need to define
what is your criteria. Define it
mathematically so that anyone can, you
know, can evaluate, can come out, you
know, like
quantifiable.
You know, so you can come out with a
score with respect to that, this
language score 90. With respect to B,
this
language scores 50. You know, something
like that, quantifiable. And you have
many criterias.
Well defined needs to be well defined.
It can't mean, "Oh, well, on my computer
it works." Okay?
>> [laughter]
>> The [ __ ] [ __ ] them. Python and C and
most industrial coders, okay?
So it needs to be scientifically
definable criterias. So, given these
criterias, then
you can judge, you can come up oh, by
this criteria, this language is the
best, this language is second best, this
language is worst, okay? That's
scientific, okay?
Uh then, okay, then they they so
but even with scientific criteria,
you can have a lot of variations.
For example, for some people, speed is
the most important thing in a
programming language.
For example, according to the C [ __ ]
>> [laughter]
>> speed speed and nothing nothing matters
except speed, you know? But, you know,
to code the same thing in C requires
1,000 lines.
In Python, 10 lines, okay? But, the C is
100 times faster than Python. So,
according to the, you know, speed is the
king, the C [ __ ] they they will say,
we we you know, C is the best because C
is just faster. Look, it's faster, you
know, so
C [ __ ]
Then, you have of course C++ [ __ ]
They they think, oh, but but you know,
speed is very important, but you must
also have some kind of abstraction.
C++ comes in, you know? So, according to
C++, C++ is the best because, you know,
on the speed aspect criteria, they they
score high, you know, pretty high, and
on but
abstraction, they also score very high,
while the C is very low, right? So, the
C++ [ __ ]
you know, they claim, you know, you
know, it's
So, anyway, the point is that you you
need to be scientific, okay?
Quantifiable, a list of criterias. Then
you can judge which one is better with
respect [snorts] to these criterias. But
also,
even with, you know, within scientific
criterias, you you have different sets
because different people emphasize
different things.
For example, why do I claim Wolfram
Language is the most powerful? Exactly,
the most powerful.
Which language allows you to have the
fewest number few the most few number of
lines to do to do the greatest possible
number of things?
That would be Wolfram Language.
Wolfram Language, also known as
Mathematica, okay?
So,
you know, how do you judge a language?
Criterias, okay? Depending so
But then but then but then
there is a question about what about the
a set of criteria that is the most
generic and reasonable.
So, in other in other words, is there a
like can we actually say which language
is the best? Period.
Without like elaborating with the
criterias and so Yeah, we can, okay? And
the answer would be not C and not C++.
For sure, okay?
Because
among the criterias, you can come up
with
another set of criteria, meta criteria,
that judges which set of criterias
is the most generic generic and useful
to the most people
for judging a programming language.
Okay? So, you can have this meta
criteria, scientific,
to create a list of the most basic,
important, and generic criterias on
judging what is, you know, like the best
programming language.
It exist.
Okay, different people may not agree a
little bit detail, but roughly it does
exist. So, in other words, automatically
the consequence of this is is that there
exist
truly scientifically
few language like like you can you can
determine scientifically like some
languages are better than the others,
for sure.
Okay, you can you can you have a handful
languages that's truly determined you
know, judged as like the best.
Like the best, okay.
Yes, you can have that, okay.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Okay, Hamspit Hamspit says, "I don't
like dynamically typed languages. I just
hate Python."
Uh JavaScript has too many weird edge
cases, that's true, and it's still quite
a bit better than Python in my opinion.
In Python and PHP, you can make a typo
and it's a bug, that's true. So, well,
you know, so if you're I mean so the
question is about dynamic languages
versus statically typed. Okay.
On that question,
you know, that is not a settled
question. In other words, there is no
um
absolute way
absolute you know, there's no consensus
that would absolutely say that
statically typed is better than
dynamically typed or otherwise or the
other way.
So, that's a opinion. Okay, so I mean
there's no consensus because because
dynamically typed language languages
they have a lot advantages that you
cannot deny.
For example, you know, let me let's talk
about this. Let's say bash.
Let's say shell, you know, you drop into
a shell.
Right? So, you you're going to CD to
your directory. Uh wait, let me cancel
that. So, you know, you're going to CD
to your directory.
>> [laughter]
>> But,
imagine you are doing this in Java.
Oh, how can you [ __ ] [ __ ] go [ __ ]
yourself? How can you possibly CD to
something empty? No, you need to define
a variable that's a home directory. You
need to define and you need to specify
the type for the home directory.
You know, that's what you're saying. You
don't like dynamic languages, but
but you you use shell, right? That's
dynamic language.
Okay, so the point is that you you know,
so there are advantages of dynamic
language. Like like for example, if you
wanted to calculate a calculation,
you know, 1 + 1 + um + X.
Okay, you need to define X, right? You
know, simple calculations.
A fact like for example, MCMR on your
calculator, you need dynamic languages.
If you're going to stick with typed
languages, you're going to be [ __ ]
You're going to be
completely useless.
You know, imagine on your calculator,
every time you save store number, you
need to say, "Oh, by the way, this
number I'm about to save is a type's
number, type int." Actually, so you need
to distinguish int and float. You know,
like
that's that's what you're saying. You
don't like dynamic languages, so you
need static types. Anyway, so the point
is that
statically typed is not suitable. So,
dynamic dynamically typed has very
strong advantages, okay?
If we look at
programming languages
>> [sighs]
>> on the whole, okay? So, anyway, I'm kind
of like
40% drunk and we haven't started to
code. So, let's start to code. So, I
talked for 45 minutes and let's code
Emacs Lisp now, okay?
Let's concentrate. I want to code, you
know, I guarantee you that today we're
going to finish this, okay?
So, we want to code
Let's start to code it, okay?
the
which is the goal of today's talk show.
Okay, so let's do it.
Emacs Lisp code, okay? Copy it out and
defend D for defend. Let me tell you
what it is going to do.
Uh
Go actually, so let's do a comment
commentary, okay?
Go through
all files in my website.
All
HTML file in my website.
For each, open it, okay? So, for each,
open it.
Search for
Search for what we're going to search
for. Let me show you, okay?
Uh search for
So, let me show you, okay? Search for
this
tags like this, okay?
Add a width and
height attribute.
Okay?
That's a goal. Okay, so so go through so
okay, that's a goal. Go through all HTML
files on my website.
For each file, open it, search for tags
like this,
add a width and height attribute to all
of them. Okay?
That's a short description. Okay, how we
do it? Let me show you, okay? So first
of all,
set path.
>> [sighs]
>> Root dir, okay? So actually
well, so what is a root dir you want to
set?
I'm not that, okay? Actually, let's just
open a process one file.
Let's write a function that just process
one single file, okay? To begin with.
The file path, okay? That's a file path.
Now,
open
the file path. So let's let's start to
document it.
Uh
So what does this function do? Let me
explain.
Open this this the file path,
search and then search for um
search for tags like that,
and then
Okay, now this
Okay?
Date created today, version today.
Fantastic. Let's begin to code this
single file, okay? So you need to sub
process temporary file name, okay?
Open file and process it.
What we going to do? Well, going to
search for that. So, how do you open a
file? Okay, usually is find file.
By the way, I've done videos like this
like focus on coding Emacs Lisp like
over a hundred of them. So, if you want
to watch it, just go to xahlee.info.
My home page xahlee.info xahlee.info,
okay? Then just go to Emacs. So, let me
so that you can go to the Emacs
tutorial, okay? Practical Emacs
tutorial. Then there is
video tutorial. So, there is a
collection about like 20
of my best videos on
Emacs and Emacs Lisp. For example, if
you want to learn about Emacs Lisp,
there is Emacs Lisp from ground up,
okay? Episode
This is so long ago. I don't have
episode number, so but it's 2022
September 7th.
Emacs Lisp from the ground up, okay? So,
anyway, so remember
I got this Emacs and Emacs Lisp video
tutorial page, so you can see go watch
them for my best video tutorials on
Emacs topic, okay?
That's a digression, okay? So, you don't
want find file, but anyway, so
So, now we want to open file. What's the
best way? Well, the best way is
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> I have documented it before, so
because you don't want to use find file.
You need a little trick, okay? So, you
go to Emacs Lisp section, then you go to
practical Emacs Lisp Lisp, okay? So, you
need open file, let's say text
processing
uh
core shell command
get user input file buffer layer.
Read file layer. Read file content as
string or line. Open and read file,
possibly right, okay? That.
So, that's what you want to do. Copy,
okay?
Back here.
Uh paste it. Okay, so we just paste it
this.
Great, okay?
So, actually so see let's delete that,
okay?
Uh
we don't want find file. So, the part we
want is just this, okay?
This.
Okay, with temp buff buffer create a
temporary buffer inside of insert file
contents Z
file path, okay? Then do whatever you
want to do, and if it changed uh save
it, okay? So, you want the local
variable uh file changed P.
P -P is a Emacs Lisp convention
meaning that this variable's value is
either true or false.
Why P? Because P stands for predicate,
which is a old convention. Predicate in
logic meaning meaning true or false,
okay? So, that's a old like math and
programming convention. When you hear
predicate
a a variable of a variable or function
that means this value or the return
value is either true or false, okay?
That's what it So, Emacs also follow
that convention. In Ruby, for example,
they the convention is
the name ending in a question mark.
And that's a also the case with Scheme
Lisp, okay? Ending in a question mark,
the function name or variable name.
Okay.
So
create a temp buffer, insert file
content from this file path, then if it
changed, write region. This means save
the file, basically, okay? So but for
now
don't save it, okay? So what we going to
do so we going to go to uh so
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Oh god, we need to go to we need to
write this faster. Go to char mean, go
to um
home mean, okay? So that means go to the
beginning of the buffer, then search
forward. Uh god, we going to write this
faster. So we going to
we search forward for
something like this. Actually, we need
regular search forward, okay? Are you
guys uh
still entertained?
They should have a keyword like let in
JavaScript.
Okay, so let's continue coding here. Am
I Oh, seven people watching, okay.
Right now I'm like
uh 30% drunk, okay? But I can still
code, okay?
God, I need to finish this quickly.
Oh god.
Can I get another drink?
Now I'm thirsty.
Let's see if
9:54 California time, 9:54 p.m.
>> [clears throat]
>> at night.
Okay, so search forward. So what do you
want to search? Let's see. You go to
Okay, so
So let let me let me let me show you
guys. So you go to a page
like
close that
close that, okay? Uh close that, okay?
You go to a page close that. Me Oh,
yeah, you go to a page and you search
for this kind of tag.
>> [sighs]
>> What you want to do. Okay, so let me
see.
Okay, search for thumbnail. Okay, that's
actually what you want to search.
Okay.
So, so,
what?
Right, and do
Yeah, so what?
Escape the string, wait.
Press, press, press, escape the string.
So, what you want to search? You want to
search the image tag or the thumbnail?
That's the question.
Okay, let's use the regular expression,
okay?
So, yeah, so you want regular
expression, okay? So, let's rejects
abbreviation. Let me demonstrate my
power of abbreviation. Rejects um
string, okay?
>> [sighs]
>> Do I make sense? Are you guys watching?
If you enjoy
what I'm doing now, say hi, okay? Let me
get a drink, okay? Let me get a drink.
If you are enjoying what, you know, you
understand what I'm doing, you are
paying attention, say hi, okay?
Yeah. god.
Hi. Hi.
>> [clears throat]
>> Coffee philosophy.
Coffee house philosopher. Thank you.
So I got another uh
200 ml of red wine.
Okay.
Let's get back to this. So we want to
search a string like that.
And what's the regular expression? Well,
it's going to be something like this,
okay?
>> [snorts]
>> Any um
backslash needs to be double backslash,
but not all of them, okay?
So you need that and uh Jesus, that
backslash. You need a backslash there.
So you need Let me copy that. So that
string
regular expression would be something
like that. d d d d d d
delete
delete, okay?
You are searching anything except quote.
Okay, that's what this is for.
Then
it says thumbnail, okay? That's what you
want to find. Yeah.
Yeah, [sighs] that's what you want to
find.
Is it Is that what you want to find?
Yes. Let me document it so so easy
people can understand.
Find string like this, okay?
Then what is the rejects? Well, the
rejects is that one, okay?
Then
optional bound
uh no, because sometimes a page
doesn't have that at all, so that's
okay. So bound neo no error true.
Okay.
I mean, don't don't don't bound it like
search to the end. And if there's not
not found, that's okay. No problem. No
error true. Okay. So, if
So, you need to say if if that, okay?
Okay, find string like that. Okay, then
if if you found it, then
then what you going to do? Then
if you found it, then here's what you
going to do. Then you going to
Okay, then we going to declare some
variables.
X begin X
what
X begin X end.
And the file change, let's start the
variable name by X because that is my
convention, so.
Okay.
So, you add begin end local variables.
So, when you search it, when you found
it, set
match beginning Actually, set X begin to
match beginning zero. That means the
whole matched string, okay? And
set
X end to match end zero, okay? So, that
will give you the position of the
beginning of the match and end of the
match of these thing, okay?
Oh god, we need to go faster.
Cheers.
So, what you doing? So, so you you find
this string, okay? That's yeah, you need
to find it.
It's not within height height. Okay, you
find it. Then get the beginning
then you need to
Okay, actually what you need to do is
you
Okay, set
path begin. Okay, let's declare more
variables. Okay.
Oh God. So let's declare
path begin path end. Okay.
Path begin and path end two more
variables. Okay.
So we going to
set path begin to be the beginning of
this
of this captured group. Okay.
How do I know? Because I'm a regular
expression expert been doing it heavily
for like
30 years. Okay. Yeah, that's true.
That's a regular expression tutorial for
Python for JavaScript like covering
their entire regular expression syntax
and all possible functions of Python and
JavaScript.
In fact, I have that also for Wolfram
language and also for Emacs Lisp. And if
And should I show it? Yeah, I should
maybe.
God, all right. Like
My life is a tragedy.
Uh
Coffee says, I love about your streams
and videos is is the flexibility of
Emacs. Yes.
Yes, Emacs is very flexible. Okay, let's
digress. Okay, so let me digress a
little bit.
And let me show you about
my regular expression. Okay.
Like my articles like what I'm showing
you is my expertise of regular
expression. Okay. Sorry info search.
rejects
index okay
Not
rejects index
search for regular
r e g u l a r okay sorry regular
expression articles index okay.
So you got JavaScript regular
expression. You got python regular
expression reference. You got Emacs
regular expression
reference and you got Wolfram language
regular expression tutorial not a
reference.
But the other one JavaScript python
Emacs they
contain complete tutorial and complete
reference like more than five pages.
Then you got go line regular expression
just a tutorial actually that's not much
of a tutorial and then you got pearl
regular expression tutorial then you got
power shell regular expression
tutorial. Okay. So among them the most
complete and comprehensive of my own
work
not copy of the official documentation
is a JavaScript and python and Emacs. So
let me show you. Okay. So go to the
JavaScript
one so you got JavaScript regular
expression tutorial. What is regular
expression beginning explanation and
stuff and patterns and flags. So
basically this section you got about 20
pages. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
11 12 14 16
40 16 18
So you have 18 pages on JavaScript
regular expression.
Part of it is tutorial for example the
page you are reading for the beginners
like who have no idea what the [ __ ] is
regular expression they have no idea.
So, this page is the first page for
beginners, you know. Oh, by the way,
regular expression can, you know, it's
match patterns. And uh what what is a
pattern? Well, here's a some some
example, and there's a flag thing. You
need to understand about the flag
concept from the C and Unix [ __ ] that
you regular expression, you know.
They they they they invented the flag
thing. Anyway, it's another story, very
complex.
So, anyway, that's that's the JavaScript
part, okay? Then you can go through like
complete
documentation of regular expression
syntax. First of all, okay, so after you
finish tutorial, then you have the
complete list of regular expression
functions in JavaScript, okay? Cheers.
Like what do they do? They ask
So, you have functions from string
methods, and you have functions that
that are
regular expression methods. So,
you know, it's complicated because of
the OOP [ __ ]
you know, like some some of the regular
expression functions are from are
methods of the string. Some of them are
methods of the
of the regular expression object, you
know.
Anyway.
So, you complete documentation about the
functions,
the facilities
in JavaScript on how to do regular
expression, okay? Like a sum summary and
detail for each.
Then you got a complete coverage of the
regular expression syntax.
And also, by the way, they, you know,
each of the function in JavaScript
Uh different languages, you know, they
deal with
regular expression in a different way,
but in JavaScript they return object,
okay? So, you got the regular expression
object.
Well, well, actually
more complicated than that because
regular expression when you
in JavaScript is an object, okay? That's
what it means, but but the result is
not, okay?
The like the result of of matching a
regular expression is is not
object, okay?
It's not like it's not a special regular
expression object in JavaScript, but it
is in Python, okay? That's another
story. We We We are going ahead of time.
Anyway, so then you got the page of the
regular expression syntax
complete documentation reference, okay?
For JavaScript, okay? That's the
JavaScript part.
Pythons
Python, I have a full
uh documentation and tutorial of regular
expression, too, okay?
Uh which is
old and ugly because I got into a fight
with the Python [ __ ]
So, this is about year 2005.
>> [laughter]
>> Year 2005, okay? Before many of you were
born, okay? I got into a fight
with the Python priests. [ __ ] Python
priests, you know? They're going to tell
me, "Oh, Python is great because this
that way, you know, Python document
documentation is the best." Anyway, I
got into a fight. So, the challenge is
that I write a complete
Python regular expression documentation
which I believe is better.
Okay? So, this page is a result, 2005.
And you can read about the historical
account of this incident on this page.
How to improve Python doc, notes on
rewriting Python rejects documentation,
2005. So, there is you know, you can
>> [snorts]
>> actually see the new school post. So,
you have proof of this
occurred. Okay, not just on my website.
So, because for example, you want to see
the proof, you can go to like um
Uh
well,
God, where is it?
It's posted to the Python mailing list,
okay?
You can find it somewhere. I forgot
where, but I
It's probably somewhere here, okay? I I
like I I showed the original um
somewhere.
Did I delete it? Maybe, maybe not. Okay,
so
Anyway, okay, I'm advanced drunk now.
[ __ ]
>> [clears throat]
>> Okay.
So, there it is. Complete documentation
of the Python, okay? Regular expression.
But anyway, this is this is kind of old.
I haven't updated for more than 10
years. So, this is mostly written in
2005, okay?
So, you have the complete documentation
of Python regular expression.
Uh what is this? Check if string
matches. So, this is a tutorial.
Then you got the regular expression
functions, like all the possible ways
you can access regular regular
expression in Python. So, that's this
page.
But I haven't updated them.
No, I I haven't really them.
Then you have the complete regular
expression object and method because in
Python
the result of using a regular expression
method or function returns a special
object of regular expression. Okay, so
so in Python you have this uh
like they they they the regular
expression pattern itself is a regular
expression object.
Uh but they their result is is also a
object, okay? So, you know, you can read
about it like here.
Regular expression match object.
So, all of these methods and functions
they return this
match object. You know, they they don't
return like the string or whatever
result directly. They return the object.
All the information is embedded in the
object. Then you need to use the methods
of these object and stuff to like
extract info. Anyway.
Okay, I'm digressing all over, okay? So,
anyway, so what I was telling you the
point here is that I have a complete
documentation of Python rejects, okay?
Here's Python rejects syntax.
And with example of like common
understandable example of each.
Uh but anyway, I haven't updated for 10
years ago, so I would not say this is my
best documentation. And then there you
have a page about regular expression
flag, okay?
So, let's go back. So, that's Python,
okay? So, we So, we talked about
JavaScript,
Python, then there's Emacs. Emacs here
is more is the most complete and the
most up-to-date because I keep updating
it every like almost every month
since 2007. Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> So, there's like 20 30 pages on Emacs
regular expression, okay? Then I got a
tutorial on Wolfram language regular
expression.
And by the way, this is
speci- especially interesting because
Wolfram language has their own
regular expression syntax and they call
it string expression. So, this is like
entirely new thing
from industrial programmers because for
most vast majority of industrial
programmers, they
only know about regular expression
because and and regular expression to
them,
they find it like so complicated because
backslash and so on.
But Wolfram language, they have their
own
like new syntax. They call string
expression, okay? So, I have like a
detail about them here, okay? Wolfram
language.
So, that's why Wolfram language is
pretty special special in in programming
language design. In part because it's a
complete term rewriting system.
Okay, in computer science, we say term
rewriting system, okay? So, anyway, so
you got Wolfram language, okay? So, then
I got a Go lang
tutorial about regular expression.
That's it. Just one page, okay?
Then in Perl, I have a tutorial about
regular expression. Just one page, okay?
That's this page.
Uh then I pointed point
out the references. Then, you know, if
you want to know more about them, you
can go to um
these links.
Similarly for PowerShell. Uh so, I have
a like I have a like
some examples here, but basically
basically one single page
of regular expression tutorial for
PowerShell, okay?
Truly God's son says,
So, I'm curious. Have you ever
considered what Emacs Lisp would look
like if it were turned
into a full-blown OS?
Well, Emacs Lisp, so you mean Emacs. You
you are thinking about turning
Emacs to a full-blown OS.
Well, the
historically, that would be
Lisp operating system, okay?
Uh, Lisp.
Okay, I'm drunk, okay? Actually, I'm
like
70% drunk.
>> [laughter]
[gasps]
>> So, anyway, so to answer your question,
your question is basically, you know,
Emacs, you know, like have you ever
considered Emacs Lisp would look like if
it were turned into a full-blown OS?
Well, the answer to your question is
basically Lisp operating system. There
exist
um, I believe more than one, but the
most popular is this one, Genera, okay?
So, [snorts] the Genera is a commercial
operating system and integrated
development environment for Lisp
machines, okay? So, basically, it's an
operating system that runs on Lisp
machines, okay?
That's basically what you are thinking,
and
it is true. Emacs, you know, today
this machine died since about like early
1990s, okay? You don't see them, you
know, you won't see them.
They die.
Uh but
if you want something closest to this
machine, to to this operating system,
like the Geneva, that is Emacs, which is
I've been using, you know, all this
livestream.
That's that's like the closest, okay?
So, I think that answers your question.
Uh it's sort of already has. Okay. So,
let let let me go back to uh code, okay?
So, let's uh let's see, you know, I
promised to finish coding this. So,
let's go back to code.
Huh. [sighs] Okay. Finish coding, okay.
So, get the path begin, path end, um
then
Oh, yeah. So, you want to set the path
begin, match beginning
one, okay?
And set
path end match end, uh not match
beginning, so
match end
capture, the first capture, okay? So,
you set the beginning position, set the
end position of the entire match, and
set the beginning end of the file path,
okay? Then, let's declare a new
variable, let's say file path.
Uh God, I'm 50% drunk. Uh path, okay?
So, let's So,
so path would be then
set path buffer string no properties.
Okay, so that would be
path beginning and path end. So, that
sets a file path which is
like this part, okay?
You need a file path, but because then
you need to get the image dimensions.
So,
So, let's declare no new variables X
width and height, okay? Uh
Where is my brief?
Oh, god.
Uh, there. So, new variables width and
height, okay? X width and X height. I
have a prefix as my convention of X so
that my variable names do not easily
conflict with normal English words.
That is the reason, X.
So, now you um
Okay? So, now you want to set the width
and height, okay? So, that would be set
Q.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Yes, there. Okay, so set
width and height. And what How do you
get the width and height of a image?
Well,
cuz I get image size we talked about uh
in 2 days ago in live stream, okay? So,
you can see the source code.
Cuz I get image
size. Then on Windows, you call
Yeah, that.
Uh
Hm, yeah.
Okay, so call that, copy.
So, that
call that and file path, X path there.
Okay?
So, you can see we are setting the width
and height.
Okay?
Now, one more thing. Um
>> [sighs]
>> So, if the search if you did not find
that, what you're going to do? Nothing,
okay? So, that that means let's just
change it this to when.
Okay? So, when you found this tag, then
do it.
When you did not find it, do nothing,
okay?
And you don't need this prog anymore,
so, okay? So, now we lessen one next
nested level, okay? So, beginning end of
the string, beginning end path,
beginning
uh
beginning path beginning Okay, so, then
you got the width and height, then what
you're going to do next? What you're
going to do next? You You're going to go
to
go to char
X end
go to the end of this tag and you're
going to
Hm,
go to the end see
See, move 1 2 3.
>> [snorts]
>> Hm, let me see like, okay.
Uh
back with char move character backward
three times. That will move it to
1 2 3, okay?
Then you're going to insert
you know, let me just tell you so
because otherwise you don't know. Let me
just do it, okay?
You know, you might be confused, but I
type it fast, you'll you'll see it,
okay? with So, insert with
height and what you're going to insert
that
that is the uh
dummy variable. And what it would be the
value of this dummy variable? That would
be within height.
Okay? So, can you see? So, we go back to
we go back we go to the character move
the character to move the cursor to the
end of the tag, right? Here. Then we
move backwards three characters, 1 2 3.
Then we insert we need a space here. We
insert space with space height, so let's
see.
Here, 1 2 3, insert space within space
height and with a with a height, that's
perfect.
And would that be done? Would that be
all?
Uh actually
yes, I think so.
Okay, so when you are done, then
then you set
Okay, so when you find when you actually
found this tag set this variable
file change to true.
Okay, in Emacs
in Emacs this T means true, okay?
Um actually
actually actually when you after you
insert it
you set it to true, okay? Now
when
file change is true, you write region,
you write the entire thing to disk.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Do I make sense? Are you guys like
watching this like do I like this is
like sensible human
interaction?
You know, human animals, we communicate
and
it makes sense to some of us. So, at
this moment, am I making sense?
You know, like when you are watching a
movie, like Hollywood movie or whatever,
you know, where when there's some funny
moment, you laugh. Make you makes you
laugh.
When there is some horrible moment,
makes you scared.
Right? That that's a
That means the human communication human
is communicating to each other.
So, when you are watching my
South talk show, like are you in you
know, do you see what I'm doing?
Because if you do, then I have a
satisfaction. You know, like oh, what
I'm doing, you know, people understand
what I'm doing. People are listening.
But if you don't, like people are
You don't want that. Okay, you see. This
is is like when professor is talking and
[snorts] everyone else is sleeping, you
know, so that you see you don't want.
Okay, I think that's that's the code,
you see. So, this code will process one
single file.
And I'm pretty sure that's like actually
correct.
So, actually, yeah, so oh, you need a
while loop because this only do one
shot. Okay, because it this this only
finds the first image tag and then it
stops.
Okay, but anyway, so we can try it
first.
Let's see what you guys saying.
Uh
Let's magnify control scroll. Okay, will
this it work? Yes.
We wrote a lot code even though I'm
drunk, but um
but I'm pretty sure this works. Okay.
So anyway, let's see the comments.
Uh
Should there's an entire package
manager? What do you mean?
Uh cuz how do you even run Emacs in your
Android phone? No, I don't.
Uh I think you might be seeing some of
some of my article
because I just showed an article here
about running Emacs in Android phone.
But that is
uh
like some someone was watching my show a
few years ago
and he is a guy who insist on running
Emacs on Android.
Uh let's see. Where where is it?
Was it Did you be Were you asking that
question because you were seeing some of
my website?
Because I just opened it. Anyway,
so there's a guy who watched my show
like few years ago who insist you know,
he's running Emacs on Android phone.
Like I don't understand. Don't you have
a desktop?
I mean, how how is it possible and he's
a zoomer by the way. He's a zoomer and
he's into social justice warriors. You
know, he's like poor poor trans and
stuff politically.
So anyway, he's running Emacs on a
phone. So I why do you do that? Because
on the phone Android like it's tiny
screen.
You don't really you know, if you really
if you are a coder,
you know, you don't run Emacs on a on a
Android phone. You don't you
you need a desktop. All right, doesn't
matter if it's on Linux or Mac or
Windows. You need a desktop to actually
dev to dev work.
But he he he's like insisting
like very very much insisting working,
you know, uh
Emacs on a Android phone.
So so I don't understand but he's like
truly like working in you know,
like learning Emacs tricks or whatever
on Android phone.
I don't understand but
So truly got some So I'm curious, have
you ever considered what Emacs Lisp
could look? Okay, that's a Lisp.
That's a Lisp OS, okay, Geneva.
Uh
So depends on what you mean by OS. Some
people will say that an operating system
can be as basic as an interpreter that
runs on bare metal.
Uh some Unix people will say that's what
runs in kernel space.
monolithic kernel
Some people [snorts] will say it
includes things like the web browser and
other programs and utilities.
Oh god, that [ __ ] I'm drunk.
>> Okay, so
Okay, so
Okay, so let's keep
going with this, okay? So, we wrote a
program. I think it'll work. And but it
don't only work on the first find of
this tag. So, can it work?
Can we try it? Okay, so let's see.
So, let's go to this page. So, this page
search for thumbnail. Okay.
So, you need to search for thumbnail
that does not include width and height,
okay?
So, the first one so this page does
does include. So, you can see
they all have width and height. So, this
page is not good.
So, you want some other page. Let's say
that one.
Okay.
Copy the page.
Open
Now, go to the top. Search thumbnail,
okay?
Now, this this page contains a image.
You see 1280. Fantastic keyboard.
It does not have width and height, okay?
So, we can test on this page.
Copy the file path.
Close it.
Go to the top.
So, we want to operate on this file
path, okay?
So, you can Can you guys see what I
mean? So, you see
open it.
That's this page, ergonomic keyboard,
and this is the first link, Glove 80
icon.
Does not have width and height. See?
Close it.
Uh reopen. Wait, close it. What is this?
What?
Oh, yeah. Okay, so
here's our code.
Yeah, so this page, open it, showing
browser.
Page down, page down. Yeah, that.
Close.
Open it again. Open it again. So, this
this
this image
markup does not have width and height,
okay?
Make a backup of this file, close it.
Now,
copy the file name,
go to the bottom,
call the function.
Call the function on this argument,
okay? So, you see it's our process file
and this file path, okay?
So, if we run this,
it will
it will change this file, the first
image tag, and add width and height.
Let's see if it works.
Close it. Wait.
Uh
let's double and let's double check,
make sure it works, okay?
Double check one more time.
Create the temp buffer,
open the insert the content file content
of this file path,
Okay, that is the function's argument.
Then go to the beginning of the buffer.
Then try to find the
image tag with thumb down.
But no width and height. Okay.
So search.
When?
So when this return this will return
true when it's found. Okay.
So when when it return true,
we set the beginning position and
position of the match
and the path beginning position, which
is the uh
which is kind of starting here path
beginning
and path end.
Then
extract extract the file path.
Then set image width and height by
calling this function
given the file path. Okay.
Wait. So wait. So this this should be
just file path. Oh, we found the error.
Right.
Okay. So in this case, we actually don't
need uh this uh you see we don't need
the beginning. We don't need the end. We
just need the file path beginning file
path end.
Extract the file path. Then set the
width and height by calling this get
image size on the path.
Then go to the end. Uh so we need the
end here. So we then we go to the end.
Then move the cursor backward three
times. Then insert
width and height.
Okay. Then set file change to true. Then
if we file change, save. Okay.
Now, I'm going to run the whole buffer.
Okay. Execute the whole buffer. So when
I done, when I do it,
open this file,
this location, it will have within
height, okay? Which is the which is this
first
link on Google AT keyboard, okay?
So,
So, let's do it.
Okay? Let's run this. But, before we run
it, make a backup, go to the directory,
compile by compile it to see if it
works, okay? Close it. Wait. Make a
backup, go to the directory.
B for bad compile. Yes. Okay, you got
some errors.
Warning.
God, reference to free variable path
begin.
Reference to free variable path begin.
That means
why is it a free variable path begin?
Oh,
spelling error. You see, this is
XPath-begin.
XPath-bg.
But, here we got XPath-xbg.
That's incorrect.
Okay, correct it.
And also this one, correct it.
Save.
And another error here referring to
fpath. So, again, we need to fix it. So,
fpath is should actually be
XPath, okay? Paste. Delete, okay? Now,
backup.
Wait.
>> [groaning]
>> Do it. Back up. Go to the directory.
By the compiler,
yes.
Okay, still
the file has no lexical binding, okay?
Okay, let's add lexical binding T
my a brief system. So now we have a
uh
lexical binding, okay?
There, okay? Save it.
Make a backup.
Go to the directory.
By the compiler, yes.
Now unused lexical variable X begin,
okay? It's complaining about unused
variable legs begin.
Um okay, so we can kind of
like delete it. We don't need it, okay?
Make a backup. Go to the directory.
By the compiler, yes.
Is there any error? No.
Fantastic. Now we can run this code.
When we run this code
this file
this line, line 55
will
add width and height, okay? Let's do it.
Run it.
Ah,
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Jesus.
No such No such file or directory. What?
No such file or directory. What?
Okay, that's because Oh God.
I think I So I know what's going on. The
error
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> You see, the error is that it cannot
find the file
from this relative link.
You see, this file path is actually not
file path.
It is just the value of the HREF.
Okay?
So, this is actually just not file path,
okay? It actually is HREF value.
Okay, so let's make a uh, variable so
it's
more easy to understand.
Okay.
>> [sighs]
>> There.
HREF value, that's a value of from the
HREF, okay?
So, not file path, okay? So, once you
get the HREF value, you need to turn it
into a file path.
HREF value is most of the time a
relative link.
So, hm.
So, you need to turn a relative link to
a
full path
because this get image
size, the width and height,
requires a full path, okay?
So, how do you get the HREF value into a
full path?
There are many ways. Okay, the easiest
way is
if you are sure this is relative link,
then you can just use
uh, you know, then you can easy just use
my
my Emacs Lisp tutorial reference.
Go to Emacs Lisp.
Then you go to
Uh,
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> I'm 50% drunk. Um
So, then you go to your file path.
You want to turn a relative link to full
path.
Easy.
So, you need to go to the section about
file path. Okay, get file path functions
there.
Click it.
Get file path parts. Okay, so
you can get the the
>> [groaning]
>> the directory name
return the directory part or the
non-directory part
the base name of a file or you can get
the file name extension or you can get
the file name without the extension.
Uh, you know?
And you can
turn a relative file path into a full
path by using this
file [snorts] relative name.
That gives you a relate relative file
path.
On the other hand, you can expand file
name to get give you a full file path,
okay?
Like that. That's what we want want.
But
Okay, I'm 50% drunk. Okay.
You see?
You see, you can do that.
Okay. But, however, sometimes the href
value is not a relative link.
Sometimes it's a full URL, like http
s colon colon slash slash, you know?
So, then when you do if you do this,
this would be incorrect. You
returns error.
But, I have already written commands to
deal with these kind of situations. So,
what we want is
let's just use this, okay?
For now, let's just assume
because
because I've been doing this live stream
for over hour now.
And so by now it's 1 hour 40 minutes,
almost 2 hours, okay?
And now I'm getting tired, so
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> so instead of extending everything
let me just quickly do it, okay? Expand
file name, let's just assume that's a
relative path. Okay, once you if you
assume it's relative path, then
you need to
say a default directory, like what is
relative to.
Okay, and you can get that by that's
just you know, you can get it by
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> by the file path, okay? So, let me show
you.
You want to get a directory name.
How do you get a directory name from a
path?
You want
>> [sighs]
>> you want the directory name from a file
path.
File name directory, okay? That is the
function you want.
File name directory, okay?
So, this file path argument is a full
path, you get the directory,
and you are feeding it to the expand
function.
So, href value with respect to this
directory, that will give you the full
path, okay?
So, you need set
set
full path
file full path, okay? Let's be verbose.
File full path equals that. That's a
local variable, okay? So, local
variable, okay, put it here.
Uh and what is X path? Actually, you
don't need uh
Just set X path, okay? The X path is
what you want.
You don't need that.
Okay. Are you guys still with me?
Uh you should do a special juggling
tutorial stream sometimes. Mm.
I'm too old to juggle, you know? That
was what I do when I was like
teen.
Now, I'm 50-something,
uh and I haven't practiced for like over
10 years.
So, I'm too old to juggle.
Anyway.
Uh coding is what actually Emacs is is
what actually what I do best today.
Uh meaning that it's valuable to the
public, okay?
Because if I do juggling, you know, for
those of you don't know,
I used to be a juggler, like when I was
a teen, like a very like I wanted to be
the greatest juggler in
human animal history, okay? So, you can
see
me juggling. This is like 20 years ago.
This is like 2003, 25 years ago.
Okay? And even at that time, I was
I have not juggled
for 10 years.
Anyway, so I was a juggler when I was
like
17, 16.
And
ambitious one.
But uh now I'm too old to actually
revisit.
Anyway, so
>> [sighs]
>> So we back to the code. So we got the
file path expand file name of this href
value by that directory. Okay,
fantastic.
Then what you're going to do next? Then
you're just going to Oh, yeah. So XPath.
So you see
XPath.
Then you get get width and height of the
file path. That's a full file path.
Okay?
Now save it.
We're going to run this. Okay?
Then again again we After I run this,
you will see this file open it.
You will see width and height here.
Okay, for this
file for this image.
Close it. Now let's do it. Okay?
Run this file.
Okay, it's done.
Now
the time to see if we
you know, have wasted the past 2 hours.
Okay? Now we're going to open this file.
Okay, open it.
Wait.
Open.
Do you see width and height? No. [ __ ]
we failed.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Jesus.
What?
Did we actually delete the image file?
[ __ ] we not only
didn't see the width and height, we
actually [ __ ] up somehow.
Because the file is not showing now.
For some reason, we [ __ ] it up. The
file is not showing correctly, you see?
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> What? [snorts]
Close it.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Oh, [ __ ] We write to the wrong file
path. You see, we are you know, when the
file changed
we write to the file, but we we wrote it
to the image file.
That's why we [ __ ] it up.
Instead, we should write to the Z file
path, you see? Okay.
But now, let's do damage control. We
need to reopen
this file, okay?
How can you do damage control? Easy.
Drop to e-shell,
then do
get
check out
this file path. Do it.
Fantastic.
Now, this is like Borg technology, Borg
from Star Trek. So that any damage you
do, it can fix itself, you see? Now, you
if you open this file again, open, see?
We're back.
>> [laughter]
>> Fantastic.
So now, you see now you see this needs
width and height. Close it. Let's do
this again. Now we change it, okay? Now
we run this file. Run.
Okay? Now open this file. Fantastic! you
got width and height.
and 1
12.
Let's double-check, okay? So,
double-check. Let's go to e-shell. Let's
see.
>> [sighs]
>> Is that how you do it do it? Yeah. So,
magic image magic identify file path.
Then you got JPEG 282 *
2 12.
Close it.
Is that correct? Yes.
Show in browser. Fantastic and
beautiful. There, we fix it.
Okay, that completes today's job. We I
reached my goal. Well, not quite.
Because right now we are only processing
one file. In fact,
we are only processing the first
incorrect markup.
But there's more because there's there's
this one, okay? This one also doesn't
have
width and height. Okay? And there's
more. And this one? Okay, let's fix it.
Let's fix it, okay? Let's take 10
minutes
more to fix it. Can we fix it? Yes.
Because all you have to do is instead of
just
when
the search
results true.
Instead of when, you replace it with
while, okay? The keyword is while, so
there.
Delete delete, okay, wait. Delete.
So, now while
this is true. Now, first of all, go to
the beginning of the buffer.
Then, every time you find it,
do the fix.
Okay?
Now, let's
save this script
and open this file showing browser.
Let's make sure
we have it right, okay? So, you see,
let's highlight all thumbnail, okay?
Shall we
uh
do it? Okay, so all the keyword
thumbnail
is highlighted in red yellow. So, every
line
that has a thumbnail but without image
width and height
should be fixed. Needs to be fixed. You
can see
you can see there's a lot of them. So,
you see. You see, one of the advantage
of being drunk is that you just focus on
one thing at a time.
You become stupid. You can't think of
too much, like what I'm right now.
So, anyway, so you can see all these
lines, each one is got
thumbnail but no width and height, okay?
Now, make a backup of this file. Do it.
Drop to the directory. Refresh.
You can see we made some backup, okay?
Close. Close.
Now, we're going to run this again. It
will it will fix all those thumbnail
markups, okay?
Run.
Okay, done. Now, open it.
Now, you need to uh highlight the
thumbnail again. Let's do press, press,
press.
Uh what?
Press, press, press. Highlight yellow.
What?
Wait. Uh
Oh, yeah. So, okay. So, you see now all
the thumbnail word has been highlighted.
So, are they all So, let's see.
It does does this line got within
height? Yes.
Does this line got within height? Yes.
Fantastic.
Check.
Check. Oh, Jesus.
Does this thumbnail has
within height? Yes.
Okay, check.
Does this one?
Check. Yes.
Jesus, I'm beautiful.
Check.
Check. Okay, successful. Showing
browser.
Fantastic. You see the web page is also
valid because every time I showing
browser, it will call a command to
validate to see to tell me if this
all this HTML is valid HTML. They are.
Showing browser, you see HTML valid.
Okay. So, showing browser, so um
yeah, so
all thumbnails has been fixed.
Okay, so we completed
our goal today. Actually, not quite.
So, we So, because right now this is
only processing one file.
But, we got 13,000 files.
So, we need to map this command map C
map a lambda. What lambda? No, not
lambda. Just this
command name, okay? Into
a sequence of directories.
Uh basically 13,000 files.
Okay, can can we do that? Actually, yes.
All we have to do is to just go to Emacs
Lisp tutorial again.
And just go to the Emacs Lisp
uh
get all file names in a directory
recursively.
How do you do that? You just go to
text processing,
get buffer string, work with lines, get
user input, file and buffer there.
Read file, buffer file, write file, file
directory there. Get file info, file
path, walk directory, right there.
Okay?
So, all you have to do is just call this
command. Actually, we want recursively.
So, you need, you know, I've done this a
hundred times in the past.
So, let's not do it today because, you
know, just just just this one single
line will do it. It will check 13,000
files
>> [sighs]
>> of my
uh let me show you, okay? CD
web.
So, that's xod web.
Okay, CD xodly info, okay? Yeah.
Okay, now you want to duh
all files,
filter
anything ending .html,
and
pipe it to
measure. This is PowerShell, okay?
So, we can see in xali.info, there are
five of them. Actually,
No, because you want recursive, okay?
You forgot recursive.
Yeah, file and
recursive.
Recurse, okay?
So, in xali.info, there are 9,000
HTML files.
What about um
Okay, now what about
CD
xali.org?
Do it again.
3,500.
So, all together,
there are about 1,300 or 1,400
HTML files.
So, that's what we need to do, okay? So,
actually, I can do it. I can just show
you how uh it's going to be done
like this, okay?
The sequence is going to be uh wait.
Uh
okay.
So, are you guys like bored? Uh does
that
make sense to you? Because I you know,
this is what I do. I've been doing this
for past
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> 20 years. So,
um
So, what do I want now? I want my uh
home page. That's for example, copy
that.
Okay?
So, actually, no, not web.
Okay, yeah, so here.
Okay, yeah.
So, you need Oh, wait. You need to
recurse. Okay, so
Yeah, let me just do it, okay?
Uh, so let's go to website
per request tutorial.
Uh, here at this locate directory files.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> This directory and all sub dir, that's
what I want. I want recursive, okay? And
you can copy
copy.
So
this function
will return a list of files, okay?
Now, what the is a root path? The root
path will be that.
And all HTML files. You see, you call
this function directory files
recursively
on this
file path.
And  HTML as file extension name.
And if the file name does not begin with
a dot, okay? So, if you run this
it will return
9,000 files. Can we try it? Yeah, I can
run it.
So, you see
go to the messages buffer.
So, you see this is like 9,000 files
file path truncated. Okay?
So, okay, so so
>> [snorts]
>> so you just map this function to this
bunch of files and that's it.
So, if I now run this, it will basically
fix
the entire 9,000
files in solid.info
by adding a width and height to this
thumbnail. Okay.
I don't want to run it because
because usually when I do this, I need
to like prepare. I want to be careful.
You know, I want to like make a backup.
I want to you know, like what you know,
what do you mean make backup? Basically
means git commit. Okay. Git commit. Then
you like double check a few times
because
if you make a mistake, that means it
will change hundreds, thousands of
files.
Uh maybe you know,
it won't delete them, but you know, it
will make mistakes, you know, like
if it's a mistake, so you don't want
that. So, you want to be sure it's
correct.
But anyway, so this is what we wanted to
do today and it's successful.
Okay. Now, that's it for today. Now, I'm
just going to read the comments and shut
down.
Interesting. No, I saw it independently.
Uh
So, who is coming How many people
watching? Okay, so YouTube, let's see.
11. Jesus, a lot of people relatively.
Okay.
I think I'm done. Okay. So,
monolithic kernel. Okay, in some of the
AST
books, he says something like an
operating system provides two functions.
An operating system
provides two functions. One is
abstraction and the other is resource.
Okay? But, his books are specifically
about modern operating systems.
He also gives the definition that is
only the code that runs in kernel space.
Okay?
Okay, I think that's it for today.
You are using Windows. Okay, that's a
frequently asked question.
So, Wilhan Wilhan says, "I'm both
surprised and amazed that you run such a
large website with thousands and
thousands of interlinked pages with
manual HTML files, not even
utilizing a static website generator
like Hugo. Yeah."
Uh yeah, that's because I'm kind of
oddball and
I'm so I'm kind of oddball and I'm kind
of special and
yeah, kind of and tragic.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Hemanth Paday says, "Why do you think
Vim is more popular than Emacs?" It's
very easy. Because Vim is bundled in
every Unix install.
Okay? That makes a great difference.
Just like how browsers are bundled with
Microsoft Windows or whatever, you know,
whenever you have something bundled that
makes it popular.
And people will say, "Oh, Emacs is
bloated." But, compared to a lot of
other software on their system,
it's really not.
You know,
well, that you know, I suppose you are
young you are younger people because
Emacs back then for 30 years ago,
it was comparatively
to all other softwares at the time, it's
truly bloated. I mean, meaning that it
requires
more memory than
other system. A lot more, a lot a lot
more.
Okay, so let's go to my Emacs blog. Let
me show you
you know, so I'm done today.
I've done what I wanted to do. The Emacs
coding, fantastic.
Uh but now, let's let me just talk
randomish for a few minutes, okay?
So show you browser, so if you go to my
Emacs tutorial, you'll see this poem.
The Church of Emacs feeling of char us
lispy and binding.
Buffers, insert, yank,
meta, sexp, ad hoc, 8 megabytes and
console swapping, okay?
Now, if you are young, you may not
understand this poem because this poem
is based on
uh kind of like the historical
understanding of Emacs.
You see this 8 megabytes and cons You
see every term in this poem
refers to some concepts in Emacs.
Uh for example, the Church of Emacs,
that is often referenced by
Richard Stallman, for example.
Because Richard Stallman of often makes
a joke that he is kind of a saint in the
Church of Emacs. So the phrase Church of
Emacs is
common joke. So, you can see this
picture of him,
you know, with a halo.
That's a joke because he's considered he
you know, he joked by himself that he's
the saint of
Church of Emacs. Okay, so Church of
Emacs is common understanding. Because
why?
Because religion, you know,
religion are usually you have a lot of
phonetics. They believe, you know, they
they just believe in something.
Which is true for Emacs. Which you know,
Emacs has that repu- reputation,
religion of Emacs. Okay. So, the Church
of Emacs feeling feeling is a word used
in Emacs because that refers to
fill region. Okay, because Emacs has
this bunch of commands, fill region,
fill paragraph, auto fill. Okay. Let me
show you.
Uh so, you younger people may not know.
So, there it is, fill region. Okay. So,
there is
fill paragraph. And there is auto fill.
Auto fill mode.
Now, if you don't use Emacs, you know,
this are foreign to you. You don't get
the joke. Like, you know, what what what
do you mean fill? Like, what does it
mean? But if you use Emacs, then you
understand. It's like
this fill is like one of the most
important um
I mean, frequently used command. Okay.
So, the poem refers to
The poem refers to Emacs Church, you
know, the Church of Emacs feeling.
Okay.
Of Chass, Lispy, and binding.
So, what does char chars mean? Of
course, a character, you know,
programming languages, you have the
concept of a character. And what's uh
what's
>> [laughter]
>> What what what is a Lisp? What what is a
Lispy
uh
binding? Of course, Lispy means the Lisp
programming language, which is what you
see here.
Okay. And
so, this uh Lisp programming language,
okay? Uh let me show you some more uh
like
Okay, there, okay?
And so, what what do you mean by uh
binding? Well, binding is a
jargon
used in kind of the tech geeking
computer
engineering sphere.
They refer, especially Emacs, they
refers you to they you know, they they
they mean
that you assign a value to something.
They call it bind. You know, which which
is extremely idiotic. It's a fact
jargon, okay? It's idiotic jargon,
binding. For example, Emacs refer
you know, like when you like for
example, on Microsoft Windows, you have
keyboard shortcuts.
You can create your own keyboard
shortcuts if you want by using some
tools such as
such as PowerToys.
I highly recommend.
Uh let me let me let me show you, okay?
So,
uh let me show you some, okay?
PowerToys, you can create your own
keyboard shortcuts.
Well, so um
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Um Jesus is PowerToys becoming bloated,
but let me just show you the keyboard
shortcut
feature. You can create your own
keyboard shortcuts.
And there, okay. So, open settings.
Yeah, so here you can create your own
keyboard keyboard shortcut like control
or something, control C, whatever. Okay,
you can create you can
create your own, or you can use
Uh [sighs] you can use AutoHotkey, okay?
So, for example, I have a tutorial for
them.
Microsoft Windows keyboard shortcut
tutorial, so you can use PowerShell,
PowerToys, okay? Fantastic, or you can
use AutoHotkey. So, I got have a
complete tutorial, keyboard shortcuts.
Now, you see in Windows they call them
keyboard shortcuts.
Effectively, what it does is that you
assign
a key to invoke some commands, okay?
That's the idea.
But but in Emacs and many kind of the
nerd sphere, they don't call it
they don't call it like shortcuts, they
call it binding.
Okay?
They call it like you bind a key to a
command command. That's how they call
it. So, on Windows, the way you say it
is that you
you define a a keyboard shortcut,
or you assign a keyboard shortcut to a
command.
But the way Emacs people say it is that
you bind a key
to a command command, okay? And this is
this is also the way like the idiots
like it's actually part of computer
science, but I really despise the
terminology. The way they say is that
you
you bind a value to a variable. Like in
you know, in programming you have
variables and you
you you assign a value to a variable.
For mathematicians, you say assign.
But for for like
kind of like part of the computer
science, you say bind. Bind a value to a
variable, which is extremely idiotic.
Okay. So anyway, the Emacs adopted the
terminology key binding. For example,
you can find
uh
binding for you know, so like you know,
it's over the command names suggested
key binding, whatever that is. Okay.
So anyway, I'm digressing over. So
back to my uh my poem.
So you see of chars, Lisp and binding.
That's the Emacs Lisp like Emacs code
would understand. Okay. Buffers, insert,
yank. That's all Emacs jargon. Meta sex
and ad hook. Meta is another Emacs
jargon referring to the meta key.
Very dramatic and sex sex
S-E-X-P is another Emacs jargon that
refers to that means symbolic
expression.
It's a it's a short for symbolic
expression and it refers to basically
the Emacs Lisp syntax of paren like
this. Okay. So for example,
that's a symbolic expression. Okay.
Ad hook. Hook is another Emacs jargon.
Okay. Then then then this is the most
famous
um
innuendo, the reference is this 8 MB and
constantly swapping.
Okay, the full phrase, original phrase
is
MB
and constantly
swapping.
You know, that refers to computer
engineering when you have memory when
you have
insufficient memory
the operating system will do a swapping
like
you know, it's like technical jargon,
okay? So, this 8 MB and constantly
swapping is a jargon from 1980s
or 1970s
that refers to Emacs. Because when you
start Emacs, Emacs will start to swap
because you don't have enough memory.
Emacs require a huge amount of memory,
okay? So, that's why this 8 MB and
constantly swapping. You see, it says
it's a humorous backronym for GNU Emacs
referencing the text editor's high
memory requirements in the 1980s
during that era, 8 MB of RAM was a
substantial amount of system memory, you
know, costing thousands of dollars.
And the phrase highlights
that Emacs often exceeded available
physical memory, you know? So, remember
this is 1980s, okay?
So, Emacs
today
you know, Emacs uses like 50 MB.
You know, today we have gigabytes.
But Emacs typically use like, for me
60 MB, okay? So, where where can see
Emacs?
Here, 61 megabytes. You see, of all the
things we did running this code,
uh
you know, like 60 megabytes, okay? But
if you look at the VS code, we only
opened three
um image files. VS code is like 500
megabytes, okay?
Uh
where do you get VS code? Okay, Visual
Studio Code, 100 megabyte there, but but
it is a lot more, okay?
Uh
VS Studio.
Did they improve because I you know, I
know for sure
when you open one single file in VS
code, it's going to cost you
400 megabytes.
Uh but can I prove it today? Like right
now, did they improve?
Uh
okay, anyway.
So anyway, right now you see 100
megabyte.
No, this this shouldn't be right. So
because
you see, in VS code I have
three files open. Let's Let's say 1 2 3
4 5 five files open. Image files.
And they cost Okay, now it's 200
megabyte.
But I recall if you just open one single
file, text file, it'll it'll cost you
400 megabyte, okay?
So VS code today is 10 times more than
Emacs. 10 times.
Okay, so let's put this back. Bring this
back. Okay.
Okay, I think I'm done. So, what I'm
saying is that the concept that Emacs
sucks memory
is true and it's back then, 40 years
ago.
But today,
almost any editor, they sucks far more
memory than Emacs, like 10 times more.
So,
Okay, so do you guys like
know what I'm saying?
So, why do I think Vim is more popular
than Emacs? Very easy, because Vim,
well, the the the 90% of the reason is
because Vim is bundled with every Unix
and today every Linux.
When you open Linux, there's Vim. So,
that's there's a significant
advantage because
it's considered default, you know, so
you have to learn Vim. It's available
anywhere.
Well, Emacs, no, you have to install it,
so that's why.
Uh and the second reason is Vim is more
like
it's just the editor. Well, Emacs tries
to do lots of things.
Okay, uh I think that's it for today. Uh
bye, guys.
Bye.