hello guys welcome to another episode of
sound talk show so today we are going to
continue the Advent of code day 7. we
started yesterday and we did for two
hours but we did not complete
uh yesterday the Advent of code day 7 is
a tough problem
and the problem is so we're gonna
continue coding it in Wolfram language
okay if you are here comments and
questions posted okay and uh for those
of you watching off offline you know
post time stamp you know I love you to
see your comments okay be on topic
Okay so yesterday the problem is
basically construct a tree at the end of
code okay you can see advantage of a
code here you know that's a website they
do this every year uh about 24 problems
programming problems story problems so
day seven each problem there are two
parts so day seven you know they go by
day you know anyway day seven the
problem is given this input which is
essentially the Unix uh command line
prompt navigation directory so you have
the command CD
CDLs
and your job is to given this input as a
string you need to construct the tree
that reflects the directory structure
and the file size and the actual
question is to compute the sum of
directories find which one is what size
you know that's the actual question you
have to answer
so
so you see uh so here is you know here
is the input and you have to construct
the tree so yesterday we did we did a
lot of analysis of the problem and
decision about how to solve the problem
how to represent the tree uh eventually
so there's two reposition two
representations of a tree one is nested
list the other one is nested dictionary
or key value pairs we decided the key
value pairs is small is easier
so so we did the code so let's start the
code okay so let's start the code uh
let's copy let's start to code it okay
start move from language okay and let's
go to yesterday so we can copy the code
from yesterday
okay so I mean here is the code
okay so let's
okay so copy it close it
go to today's talk show
and paste it here to remove that
pop it into its own uh buffer okay we
so now let's start wolfam language
we're gonna continue from yesterday
uh with some language okay start the new
new file start the Wolfram engine and
let's magnify it so it's easier to see
let's put it here
okay so I can easily get to it
okay so Wolfram language
so yesterday the code you know we here
is extra input so you know let's copy
the code let's let's just copy it
so here's the code yesterday here's a
huge input
uh and let's see so we split the lines
we
the path is uh we first of all we build
a list of file paths then
from a list of file path we construct
the tree so we succeeded yesterday in
this in building the list of file path
okay so we start with a global variable
empty list then we start to add things
to it
and here is the function that does the
bulk of the work this function we map
this function to
the line part list line part list you
know each one is basically a line of the
input but separated into a list of
strings so let's uh line parts list so
we map a function to all elements of
that
line basically
and then in this process we build we
build the fire path XPath
so okay so now let's uh yeah let's
remove this one this one is not needed
okay let's just eval eval the code
uh where did it go
what
uh 150 okay
okay
we I think we
I think we changed the font size uh okay
do you need it did the whole thing
now we don't need this part copy the
whole
paste it here
run it
okay it's done now let's see X path so
you can see that is a
result we have let's show them in column
form
okay so each of these
sublease represent a file path you know
but each directory name is is a element
so you can just join string then you'll
be a file path okay
and uh
yeah okay so but do we have a
distinction between
a directory or a file
now obviously if the name is something
not something that's a file but
but is that always so let's check the
input
so here's the inputs
okay so let's go check look at the input
talk show talk show yesterday
search for input
okay so here is the input copy all new
buffer paste it and let's delete all
lines
let's list our lines uh that begins with
the dollar
okay
let's do it again
Okay so
let's remove all those
delete matching lines that okay
then
Okay so
so you can see some of them out there
now let's list all
uh all lines that contains the word the
space
okay
so you can see all directory names do
not have a dot in them
you can see
yeah that's correct
okay that makes the problem easier
so directory names do not have any dot
in it now let's delete all directory
space okay now all these are files now
you can see
okay so some files
has start something but some files not
so some files has done something but
some files not okay so we have to so
this is ambiguous actually so I mean our
list is ambiguous hello crazy frog I
have seen you seen seen you before
so
some
some of these file path
you know we don't know it's a directory
or it's a file that's a problem let's
see how do we solve the problem because
we are going to turn this
into a nested
dictionary basically a tree
so do we actually so to turn this list
of final path into a tree a nested
dictionary
do we actually need to distinguish
whether one is a directory or it's a
file
now we know that if it's a file
that's always the leaves of a tree
you know so and you know if it's a
directory then it's not a leave you know
big wait
okay some directory may also be a leaf
nod
because it just so happens there's no
fire seeing it
okay so we need so let's uh let's write
some notes we this is important to know
so let's go back to the talk show
uh that's yesterday go back to talk show
today
uh no that's yesterday
so today's talk show is this one
uh
some notes
some file names contains a DOT but not
all okay that's important to know
the names never contains a DOT
okay so let's put that so the name
directory names never contains the dot
okay but some file names contains the
dot but not all okay
uh and uh you know we are asking this
because we want to know is it possible
to determine it's a file or directory by
by purely just the final path so the
answer is no
is it
possible to determine a
for a given full path
is a the whole file
from our X path
okay
the answer seems no
because
those reasons
okay
so let's comment out that this YouTube
the name never contains the dot but some
file names contains the dot but not o
okay and we also we also discovered that
files are the
whole files
any file
is a
Leaf nod meaning they don't have
children
but hey the maybe a thief knot
or a non-leaf nod
because
when a the
uh the may have zero children
or
no ALS is performed
on the
okay so that's some findings
okay
so
any file is a leaf node but a duh may be
a leaf nod or a
or a non-leaf knot okay
so a directory may be your Leaf nod or
maybe your non-leaf nod
okay and uh
again we are trying to build a tree from
this given file path now is it necessary
to know
if this food if a given full path is a
fire or directory
no because
because it doesn't matter it you know
this full path basically
specifies the structure of the tree
it doesn't matter it's a file or
directory okay so that's important to
know so let's write it down okay
we are going to build a tree
using nested dictionary
from
a list of four
path
which is our X path
okay
is it
do we need to know
if
a path
is a the or file
okay answer no
because
a full path
at least a full path
fully specifies
the
tree structure okay so okay that's good
to know so one step further okay so now
we are we want to turn this into a
nested dictionary how do we do that okay
uh it should not be difficult okay we
essentially this is how how you do it in
Wolfram language so the tree
the tree is a Association list we talked
about yesterday
uh let's go to Wolfram language okay go
to my website you'll see your complete
tutorial and in Wolfram language there
are two major data structure list is the
primary one just like any list
programming language everything is at
least
then but there is a special data
structure
and that is called
Association
okay so Association is essentially in
Python it's called dictionary info and
Ruby it's called hash table in Java in
JavaScript it's called a map
object uh you know it's basically at
least the key value pairs Association
in woven language and in lisp it's
called
either hash table or Association list
okay it's an old name it's a variation
name Association list
from from which you have hash table and
in fact the word the jargon dictionary
is not from python the jargon dictionary
is also very old it probably the first
one so they are basically the same thing
at least the key value pairs okay hash
table
uh association association list
dictionary or the same or map
it just so happens we have different
names uh unfortunate
so in Google fan language you use
Association okay key value pairs so we
use this to build a tree uh so and the
way you do that
close that the the way you do that is
something like that okay so the tree is
Association we defined
we defined here so you know in the
beginning it's just the empty list of
key value pairs then
then you can do it this way the name one
the name to the name three something
something
uh
equals to so let's let's so this is what
we're gonna do now
so the input
so this is a function okay so we want to
map a function to this list of file path
and in the process it it should build
this Association tree okay so map of
course obviously you map a function
to
X path okay
and uh
at level one by default it's level one
level one just means just like every
every other language is map but in
Wolfram language you can specify a level
by default is one you can say two then
you just map to like the the children of
the root only those knots and you can
say three
that means the children and Children of
the root only those you know or you can
say negative one that means map the
function to only the leaves of a nested
list
okay so you know the map is super
powerful extremely powerful in Wolfram
language
so this is worth mentioning because this
because
list is the primary data structure in
fact the whole language everything you
see every code is the least just like
least you know list these data data is
the least
um and so in Wolfram language you use
list
everything is the least and you use
nested list extensively you know
you may not see it here but in fact this
is one giant nested Beast you know even
the code code or data whatever it's
honest at least
so nested list is used everywhere okay
and uh
and then you have the concept when you
want to map a function to a nest to this
you you can you can you know specify
which level at what depth or
uh you know third depth to seventh step
you can do that
you know one specific level or a range
of level you know in Unix you call it
depth usually just like when you do
um
you do uh find some file name in dash
depth you know anyway so map is very
very powerful this so if you are
programming uh learning Wolfram language
uh you you want to master this concept
of level okay I don't even say I didn't
say here because
you know I'm trying to make beginner
friendly
but you can see there's a level you see
you can
um so a bit digression you know so map
say you see there's a level spec
and let's turn JavaScript
you see so this is kind of the standard
syntax when you want to specify level
you can see also say infinity that means
mapped through all levels every nod and
every leaf of a tree so this is
extremely powerful this feature
where you can map a function to any
particular level or range of level is
not found in any language I know of you
know you don't you don't see them you
have to code it yourself and it's not
trivial it's very not trivial you know I
so because I I tried I did this in the
1998 I did a lot of these three stuff
so if you're gonna write this function
in Python it's not trivial python
whatever JavaScript has whatever even at
least
they don't have this you know they
usually you know you'll be not even a
library you'll be hard hard to find okay
so so in most industrial languages when
you have at least typically it's flat
you know you don't work with Nest at
least that much unless you are doing
linear algebra you know computer
Graphics then at most you have like
two-dimensional
uh a matrix you know basically a nested
list where each element has the same
same length as every other
two by two Matrix two by five makes
tricks three by seven Matrix you know
that's all two dimensional
Matrix and and all those are nested
least okay but in Wolfram language
you know you have that but you can you
know the each element may not have the
same size as the other so it's a tree so
you know next at least represents a tree
and you can map to you know you have
this map function map to any level okay
so now we want to map a function to the
list of path just just level one and so
the question how to the question is how
do you define this function the function
will basically do something like this
okay and we have to think about it now
let's see the comment
I prefer watching people programming
actually programming okay that's
interesting
um so
are you joking you know sometimes you
are joking because what's the point then
if you don't program just watch
I I guess that I guess that can be
likened to watching sports you know
right now the world soccer football is
going on you know a lot other countries
South American Italian French England
they are crazy about football so you
know you're gonna have a riot
yeah so that's watching sports you know
watching American football or you know
the you know the the non-round but you
know American football
or Rock by
you know sports baseball basketball NBA
and so on so you have the sport of
watching sport
so I suppose you can also have you know
programming of the of the uh spectacle
of watching other programs
is that fun that would be New Field I
think that would be new I haven't heard
of it
how am I doing
so how many people two or three I
suppose two or three watching me oh oh
five okay say say something okay say hi
okay let's get back to you direct you
know how am you know my style you you
you tell me and I'll go that way
okay I'm still alive I'm doing good
voice check yeah okay so right now our
problem is to write this function okay
okay so but before we do that we it's
prudent
it's a very good idea to
to try a toi program first so let's do
that okay
so delete that put this back in browser
and start a new Wolfram and let's just
do that and let's maybe copy this list
okay
and paste it here
and the color syntax color it move this
out so we're gonna work with this
you know example just to just for this
part create a tree using nested
dictionary out of at least the file path
okay
and we go back to browser you can show
it
show it so here is today's code so far
essentially from yesterday okay but
we're gonna work on this
feel the tree okay so you begin with
um you know so first thing we want to
make sure is that
the list of file path is ordered by
their length
you know that way we can make sure we
don't encounter a deep
nod before
its parent
but I think from the input you know they
are already that way yeah because you
see before you see a new directory you
do have the parent happening before it
you know so you have this directory then
you create children yeah so I don't need
to we don't need to worry about the
order we can just
map a function and go through them one
by one
okay so so here this is the input
and it's uh
let's say xx1 okay
let's say
hex path list okay
now
uh now let's see so this is the first so
up to here
we build a directory let's shorten it
even further so let's try this
this is building one
uh one tree okay so let's try that
use random
okay let's try something like that
simple
a very short tree
okay now we want to turn that into a
tree so
um
let's just use x okay
X1 okay
X2 equals to
Association okay empty Association
okay then we want to map a function to
it
okay and how do we do it
um
so so the first item is just
let's see let's see even shorter
so you know let's let's say
even shorter
wait
oh this list we got the extra
bracket
why why is it extra
let's try again okay let's see what's
inc's path
why do we got the extra
brackets
let's copy it
copy
paste yeah there's no extra must be
copied error
okay so hmm
what you're gonna do okay so so this
this part is wrong
and this part extra bracket and it's
let's remove that
let's fix this
format them nicely okay
copy replace replace that by that that
okay uh that's not okay so make them
into one line and do this replacement
okay now it's much better
yeah
okay so now X1
equals to
yeah I can do that
yeah so we want to go up to here
let's see
okay that's good
that's is that is good we just wanna do
this next one equals to
uh okay so you need a
bracket there
okay so here is a toy
this is the final path we want to build
a tree okay
so imagine the first item so the first
item when you yeah okay so wait
so let's just manually fix this
okay so imagine you just got two final
paths that
okay so you don't even worry about this
need a
okay so if you're gonna just have this
two-file path what you're gonna do so
the first one obviously you want to do
something like so X2
let's let's make it that way so the tree
you're gonna have the names uh that
how you gonna do so
Association
so Association
so the yeah so you're gonna add a key
slash
you're gonna create that key but what
what is the value
the value is gonna be a another
Association right
so
let's think about how Association
corresponds to the tree I mean a list of
key value pairs nested correspond to a
tree so a tree you have a root
and how do you represent that root
one way to do it is you have Association
of a key
and that key is the the name of the
route you know in Unix tradition that's
a slash
you know you can think of the slasher as
the name of the root directory
even though it's not the directory it's
technically a file system mounting point
you know that's the Unix anyway so
you can think of as a directory so the
direct the root directory
name is the key
so these associations have only one
single key that's a slash okay
then
it has children okay
but the children is of course
Association but do we do we say no here
or do we say
empty Association like do we which way
do we go
I mean for each step do we say
um
so when you have a directory
yeah obviously
yeah okay I know the answer when you
have a directory
it correspond to a key in dictionary and
the value
must be of course
a list of children's so it may be empty
it shouldn't be no
because the directory means a folder
folder means it's a container so it's
going to have children so so it's
appropriate to say A you know there's a
new Association just empty okay so yeah
so each time you encounter that you do
that
uh then so let's say then we got into
the second part let's let's make this
this way so it's clear
you know we have a list of two items
so then you get to the second part
you
so you start to have children in it okay
oh God so so maybe at this point you do
need to know
if a knot is a file or not because it's
a file
you don't want to you you don't want its
value to be Association
yeah that's uh you know that's either
way we can go actually
because in the end we can just determine
those empty associations
wait
so actually we it's it would be better
if we do know
if we do know it's a directory or a
file
yeah but to add that information that
means this list will not just be at
least at least this list will be a pair
of these
you know with the second part being
telling you it's a duh or a file
and maybe perhaps you can also add file
size
yeah we can do that so
so that but to do that that means we
have to modify yesterday's code
okay and yesterday we also have this
lookup size table oh okay I know what to
do so look up size table is basically
all files
so look lookup size table is again a
dictionary of key value pairs
the key is a file path okay for example
that's the final path the value is the
file size and all the keys in this size
lookup table they are all files
so in order to determine if a pharaoh
path is a file or directory we can just
check the lookup table if the key exists
there it's a file fantastic
fantastic
perfect design from yesterday Real Chad
hello
second Dario account hello
great yeah nested map okay so fantastic
we so we carefully
thanks to my method
methodological analytical
style of programming you know we get it
get the thing right the first time so
after two hours carefully thinking
yesterday this structure
this design it's really good I mean
that's
the way I I approach there are other
ways you know there are better
programmers they can they they do trial
and error kind of exploration and they
can
um you know some of them can finish
faster that's good but I usually take
from you know I approach problem from a
full logical analysis first
so anyway the point is we got this size
lookup table very useful
uh now go let's go back to this okay so
so I guess first of all we need to find
first
check if the full path is a fire order
okay
by checking
the
yeah what what is the What is the
size lookup table
yeah
then
it equals to
if
is the
so if it's a directory then you the
value is a Association empty
meaning a folder a container if it's a
file
oh we're starting to build a tree
fantastic
this is gonna be one shot
operation one shot run it and it works
and it would be correct
so if it's a file
yeah so first of all you need to check
the lookup table so let's look at the
lookup table okay so
let's Define a variable
uh
couldn't path okay couldn't path
current path is you know that or that so
current path so now you if you want to
see that current path exist in the the
size lookup table okay so how do you do
that you go back to wolfam language we
go back to Association
Advanced pattern matching function
Association okay then you go to check
existence
okay key exists
there it is
so you say key exists
and the association is a size lookup
table and the key is the current path
okay
is fire
another temp variable so is Phi or
equals to that okay is file Q
Q in Wolfram Language by wufan language
convention Q means the question
which means a predicate which means
anything ending in capital Q always
return true or false nothing else either
true or false always so this is similar
to the predicate in lisp where they
usually ends in P like file exists P you
know number P is it the number number P
you know that's this convention ending
in p in wolfen language ends in capital
Q in Ruby and in skim lisp they ends in
a question mark this is very
nice to know uh let me show you okay
let's go digression
so I have an article on that
I talked about that before uh predicate
yeah I don't have it here so you have to
go search study such
p-i-e-d-i-c okay predicate in
programming night language naming okay
so in wolf in
lisp you have bound P both are modified
p
f-bound P feature P file directory P you
know they return true or false that's
list of convention in scheme it's
question mark scheme this closure list
and the Ruby question mark okay in Wu
from language it's capital Q Q stand for
question
now this is interesting the naming of
things
so which one is better you know why why
doesn't wolfam language follow the
conventional computer science
and and use p p for pedicate
well because credit card is kind of a
esoteric jargon it came from logic you
know it came from you know the field of
Math logic predicate in logic it the
meaning is slightly different
in computer programming languages in
logic a predicate is a assertion you
know something is true
you know all people all people are good
okay that's just that's not a question
like programming languages you know when
you have a credit card it just you know
it's a search and it's a it's a you know
it's a statement okay it's a assertion
but in programming languages you don't
have that in general unless you are
talking about logic programming
languages a very Niche specialized
language but in all other languages CVC
plus plus Java python Ruby whatever when
you have a credit card that just means
the function returns true or false okay
so so Predator is a jargon originally
from logic so but programming
is kind of came from math you know in
the early days there's no programming
then started so you borrowed a lot of
jargons for math so you have predicate
in lisp
meaning a function returning true or
false and you have a convention it's
just end in p but this this got a
problem though like some function ends
in P that but it's not a predicate so
it's not very well
the naming of the this list convention
is not very well done in common lisp in
emac this because some functions and
ends in P but it's not a predicate okay
for example there is forward sex
there is pop you know let's magnify
you know there is pop there is
a different group there's make Spas key
map they will end in p but it's not a
predicate obviously while the others
list p number P string P symbol p Vector
p0p they are predicate meaning meaning
that they always return true or false
uh and there's inconsistency
in emac this
for example sum is Dash p sum is just P
so you know it's a problem you can look
into these different aspects
these are things that I find um you know
many times the in my study or
programming language is you know you
find these kind of things but you like
you never
ever seen the industrial programmers
talk about these issues like never not
not once in in my 20 years reading slash
dot Hacker News Reddit or whatever you
know online you know the hackers you
know the python forum mailing python
mailing list the emac this emac Dev
meaning is these issues they never
thought of you know it's like kind of
strange
they never talk about this but the
designer programming language they do
they have to
because why is least why is game this
skin release crochet lisp they have a
Convention of using a question mark and
it's absolute if a function ends in
question mark that always means the
function returns either true or false
okay this is this is good this is good
who came with you know who did it
you know well whoever created scheme and
crochet is for example crochet is the
the guy
uh what's his name
rich hiki you know it doesn't come out
of nowhere you know you have to desire
you have to implement closure so they
know these these people they they
thought about they they have you know
thought about things okay skim these
closure this question mark which is
excellent
okay now so but what about Wolfram
language why is it Q
you know why don't you just use P just
like you know be a good boy follow the
convention P predicate
well the issue is predicate what the
is the Predator do you know nobody
knows unless you are a logician
or mathematician
so the credit card is not intuitive the
naming of things okay intuitiveness is a
one of the good quality in the naming of
things so the Wolfram language stepped
from Wolfram
he he went with q q means question so
everyone understand you don't need a
math degree
you know that is why
question is also good question mark is
also good but in Wolfram language
question mark is used for you know
because it's used for other syntax so
you don't you don't have you know
question mark is not allowed
uh what is question mark Yeah question
mark is a shortcut for help you know
anyway so it's not not allowing
identifiers
that is why wolfam language use q and
Ruby uses question mark okay now Ruby is
actually
um
Ruby came from lisp and pearl Ruby you
can say Ruby is a synthesis of least
pain Pearl so you can see a lot of Ruby
programming language their structure
convention is kind of a little bit
similar to this
so anyway that's a digression about
predicate Okay naming a pericard
okay let's go back
okay I want to copy this and put this
into talk show
um
so today so let's just put it somewhere
since it's something we talked about
okay
now back to the code
okay so back to the code so
is file Q okay is file Q
so if it's a file then
then you do something otherwise you do
uh
Association okay
so what if it's a file
okay so when it's a file you want to
assign it
just the size okay yeah let's do
okay let's do this let's see
so this will return
wait let's see how do you how do you
access a dictionary
Association okay
so that's how you check if it exists
but there is also uh get value okay
so lookup Association key but if the key
do not exist it returns missing
okay okay for Simplicity let's forget
about
efficiency let's just have clear code
so people can understand because most
people are new to Fan language so let's
go with more code okay so Inspire that
and uh
if
and file size okay let's just say file
size
file size you look up
lookup Association and key okay
Association and the key
okay so if it's a file
you just add this file size
yeah let's just do the multiple
variables okay yeah
so the tree
something something
path okay the tree
can path
wait
okay so this is assuming that the
current path is one single element
usually it's not okay
so now let's say
say current
path
let's let's pick one example okay yeah
let's say that yeah
okay what you're gonna do there
so current path is that
then what you're gonna do you want to
do something like that
okay that's probably what you want to do
so the first part gives you the yeah the
first part gives you a Association
the container for that then the second
part
which is
hmm
okay we're getting closer though
uh
second part
if it's a fire
so if it's a file then just put the file
size
otherwise it's a directory putting
Association okay yeah okay that that
also
uh
so these are two scenarios of our code
does that work I mean does what if we
have let's say
uh
something like that
so given a full path
you
construct these
then sets its value
so herbal says you are going to have a
new pointer error why
why
I don't I'm not seeing a new pointer
error okay
so anyway so here is the
okay let's start to build it now
before we build it
you know essentially we want to put this
section into this function
before we build it now notice the this
path
you know when a given full path is
actually a list of things
so for each of the element you want to
make it make it into these key syntax
so one way to do that is to build this
sequence of symbols then you call Eva
you know just like other languages Eva
that turns that into an expression and
evaluate it that's one way but that's
usually not efficient because in just
about any programming language you want
to avoid calling Eva as much as possible
especially in industrial languages such
as CC plus plus I mean c doesn't even
have it but in in Python in JavaScript
you know you can do Eva and in this
image these two but usually you don't
want to do that because you have you
know first of all you have security
issues but also but mostly
it's slow okay it's kind of meta
programming it's meta programming meta
programming is very powerful but you
want to avoid meta programming as much
as possible okay most this
beginners don't know about that they
think medical programming is you know
traumatic they always use that like this
Mark was no you don't want to do that
you want to avoid mid-high programming
as much as possible until unless you
absolutely there's no other way then you
do meta programming okay
um okay so back to the problem so now
so we want to build these syntax is
there a way without having to require
you to use eval yes I think so
how do you do that uh
yeah let me show you okay so you are
given a list of things let's say you are
given ABC at least you want to turn that
into
is that right you want to turn that
equal let's you can know that you know
you want to turn that into that
but
but what you can do is you can Nest okay
you want to
this is a short syntax what is a full
syntax let me see
uh so Association
add a key
okay so this is this is one way to do it
add a new key value pair that's
this syntax is traditional I mean like
in in other languages Pearl JavaScript
python you also do it similar to that
but that's not a functional there's a
problem with that
using operator this is you know you can
think of that as a operator form
and when you do a lot of functional
programming you do not want to use
operators you want to use the functional
form always use the functional form why
because when you use functional form you
can manipulate you can use the full
power of functional programming to
manipulate the function to take the
function as input to another function or
output a function and you can you know
manipulate the past whatever argument
you want
but if you have a operator form you
cannot do that you know you have to just
in in Python in JavaScript you have to
build a string of that then eval that
string no good okay so you want so that
is why
you want the functional form this is you
know one great tip about functional
programming
I mean it's a it's a tip you'll get to
know if you do a lot of functional
programming so you want to use
this instead of the assignment operation
um
but in Wolfram language actually they
are equal if they are equivalent because
this actually
the compiler will turn this form into
that form
oh yeah that's right so actually we we
can
we can do it something like that yeah
fantastic
but anyway I was going to show you using
Nest okay but okay let's get on to get
get the result let's get to work
okay God this is already one hour
oh anyway that's not talk show
oh God
so we can do it this way or we can do it
this way but what is how do you do it
this way so let me show you okay so
associate variable
key
value okay right that's uh how you do it
okay so the second argument
associate two
okay so you use associate two
right
so so let's write it out clearly
so that is equivalent to
so that is equivalent to that how do you
know you can do this
let me show you okay so you can do this
let me show you okay because this is
interesting
Wolfram language
you see
let me show you the other way so you see
uh wait
that's not the full form
um
okay yeah we don't want to use this
but why is it not
let's go let's look up the documentation
okay
this is a function
Let's uh so Association you can assign
you can add a new key value Pair by
associate two
now let's go back to Association
and see how they explain
oh yeah okay here's some tricky thing
going on okay anyway we want to use this
phone okay
but how do you Nest it
okay how do you get
um okay you have to do Association how
do you get a value
and see
let's so let's use the function form
okay so you can do Association key
lookup key
look up a key
a
then
look up B
okay let's do this lookup C
that's how you Nest it okay
yeah look up CBA okay
you Nest it three times
then the result is a Association
which is a B's uh okay
wait so
you look up a
then you look up B
yeah yeah I should be in this order then
the last one is special okay hold on a
second
so you Nest him like that
this will be equivalent to that okay
that and that should be
equivalent
but if you want to assign
let's do it again okay if you want to
assign let's say
then what you do is that
um
then what you have to do is that
okay you look up a and look up B then
you want to
associate two
yeah God you cannot use associate too
can you
because associate two requires a
variable back
so I'm thinking
well you can just say that
that's not good
okay we have to dive into Association a
lot
it's
18 minutes
uh how do you so how do you
we need to build a
tree a nested dictionary from a list of
file path
and right now we are taking apart the
final path component
you know basically we want to write this
function map a function to at least the
file path
and this function will essentially do
things like that each line is one
example
but right now so we but right now we
want to turn this code into
kind of a function
so the function input will be a list of
directory names or file names a list of
directories and file names
and you want to tie it into something
like that
is yeah so why can't you just um
if you use eval Eva that'll be the
easiest
so actually so Association in Wolfram
language is actually a function
yeah because that's uh esoteric detail
I'm not
too familiar with yet Association is a
new thing about years about eight years
ago in Wolfram language
so anyway so
so why don't we just write this directly
it's so simple
yeah so okay so you want to map you want
to map a list of names
string
turn them into that
so you you so you want to write a
function
uh you want to turn a function into
given these values into that
head head head
so this would not so how do you do that
should not be
too difficult
so
let me think
so you got a list of items let's say ABC
you want to turn that into that
okay the easiest way is to use Nest
actually just like we are trying to say
here
yeah so let's let's let's go here
so the easiest way is actually just use
nest
let's see
Nest something
length of the list okay
okay and uh
yeah let's see
for example three
then let me show you how it works okay
so let's try the tree is that okay
that's
that's empty but let's say
Dr okay the tree that
that
okay what's this Nest what's the syntax
expression in Okay so
you have to oh you cannot use Nest you
have to use fold
yeah because for each time you need to
take an argument ABC
hey ring tingle
thank you
so you cannot use Nest you can use food
do you guys understand like do you guys
can are you guys making sense what I'm
doing
you know I'm guessing from language is
new to you guys so
am I actually making any sense at all
so anyway fold
so Ford for example let's let's see fold
okay food is like pythons reduce okay
so f x and this okay
again four is like pythons reduce okay
so you can see okay but so let's do that
here
so the list is gonna be ABC for example
directory names or find our names
so you're gonna fold it into that uh
okay you don't need the three
okay so let me show you how this works
right
what
it's not folding
right
oh f
F needs to have two arguments
wait something is wrong here
oh yeah you forgot the comma okay in of
course in Wolfram language your item
needs item needs to be separated by
comma okay there it is
you see so
so each time it takes two arguments
but you don't want it to fold it that
way you want to you want to create this
structure okay not that
uh but using fold is a key okay but we
have to think about how to do it
Okay so
I'm getting tired
yeah
don't forget the comma
okay
so
fold hey B it takes two arguments at a
time
you want it to return for example fold a
b you want it to return that
yeah so
so
okay so you want the function here let's
write down the function okay
let's make that a function
and here is what you want
first argument
second argument okay
let's try this
okay let's check yeah that's one thing
do it
close
okay now
let's close we get in there okay let's
see ABCD
okay something's still wrong we don't
want it to go inside at all
but this is getting close
you know let's let's do this so you can
see
now we can use range
had 10
you see
there is a nesting going on but not the
way we want it you see
F2
there's F3
F4 you know some kind of we want we want
to to sequentially go to the phone okay
let's think about this
it
so each time you just add you just kind
of append a thing to the end
each time you want to append the thing
to the end
uh
ABC yeah each time you append a thing to
the end
so
when it begin
so when I begin
you know it begins with two arguments
but you wanted to not begin with two
arguments
each time you take these two things
I got a better idea
so we are doing this all wrong
let's hope it doesn't crash when I do
this okay
okay so fold
[Music]
some examples
each time
[Music]
okay I got it
wait fault must take one argument or two
[Music]
Ford takes two arguments
the function I mean the the function to
the fold
takes two arguments
the function for folding takes two
arguments
so we don't want to use fold
wait
ah God
why can't we use nest
well because we need a list of input
okay let's read a bit let's read about
sequence fold
sequence fold okay sequence fold is new
2015.
okay
sequence fold
sequence a sequence B A to sequence A3
okay
for least fold pair list Nest list
functional iteration
[Music]
third sequence for fourth pair
on his forward pair fold pair is also
new
2015 okay full pair
let's see what's fourth pay at least
gives a list of successive X1 X I
obtained by applying F2 pairs of the
form
but
okay let's go back to functional
iteration Nestle is Nest Nest graph for
list sequence fold fold wire
fixed Point Nest wire
you know all these are basically loops
in a in a functional programming style
okay
uh
um
so the function the function takes at
least we want to turn that into that
okay anyone does anyone know
uh
this is very very interesting problem
and pure Wolfram language term rewriting
problem
but I have to think about this though
uh
so you are given a list you are given at
least you want to go through them
by a loop or by a map or by nesting or
by recursion however you do it given a
list you want to
basic basically turn it into this
expression and this expression in
Wolfram language is actually
nesting
you you Nest a function in front you
know so this this expression in Wolfram
language is actually like this okay let
me show you
Okay so
so you you consider that a as a like
that okay
okay this is how it actually is
um
you can
you know so
so basically
this part is one function
then this function
this function name is actually that iPod
and this function the function name is
that so it's actually nesting in front
that you know that's what that means
so um
so okay so we can yeah so that's yeah oh
oh I got it oh yeah good I got it
so now so what we we we do is that we
nesting front okay remember Nestle in
front
so for each time
so you want to put this dollar sign I
mean the
thing
wait why is that not correct
how is that
let's see what's the Precedence
that's right so
the problem is
can't can't we do it
okay so something like that
uh the problem is uh you know
very pure mathematical problem here you
know you don't need to know who from
language you know anyone you can
try to come up with a solution
uh
you are given at least you are given at
least
you want to turn that list into that
so
so the first one is the 3A
so you map a function
subsequently to the list
so you want some kind of nest
or fold
now you cannot use nest because if you
use nest
each time Nest doesn't take a list of
arguments
because in this case each time you need
a different arguments argument ABC
and you want the function to take
one argument at a time
so you want the function to take one
argument at a time
but for fold the function return you
know must take two argument at a time
now wait what's going on
so you see
this xabc you want to somehow avoid that
X
you know you want to avoid this
you know remove that X
wait but but all these are function of
two arguments you see this is one
argument named B
then
so it always the function to fold always
takes two arguments
okay the function to fold always takes
two arguments
so
so you have a case of
for example function
and given the arguments A and B
then
you have let's say you did this
then you have a b then you are given an
argument of
you know well first of all you have the
argument of A and B
then suppose you get that
let's suppose okay
then
then you have
that and C okay and what you want is
let's let's make let's make this let's
put it here
okay A B becomes that that's that's
right then you have the argument like
that
okay let's put comma okay
so that should become
that
okay so that
should become that okay
so yeah okay so now it's clear so you
begin with f
you begin with f and each time you get
argument
you just append it yeah so it's so
obvious
you know
but since but then why but how do you uh
why is fold
so you basically you want it to be a
single argument
so the second argument you don't care
okay this if if you don't care about the
second argument no you cannot do
well if you don't care about second
argument
then you get f a
let's see maybe even read that's all we
have to do
I don't think so
here
yeah if you don't care about second
argument that's what you get so what if
you say two
okay so the problem here is
somehow you need to turn these two
arguments into
one
wait what why is it not work so
it's very very simple
each time you take an argument
suppose your function only take one
argument so each one you take an
argument you just append it
right so F A is that then
you get
you basically Nest it
so you want the recursion you you want
the nest
you know you want the neck you you want
the
Nest okay you want to call that
but however Nest does not take
um
it does not take any
a list of arguments
Okay so
okay I know what to do now
okay nice well is also new
oh this one is in 1999 okay that's not
so new
okay next well is what we want okay
uh no not this well actually the the
thing we want is just fold okay
yeah the thing we really want is just
Ford but we have some logical
problems
okay so let's think
we have logical problems of trying to
resolve forward
let's write them out
so people looking and watching me
staring at the screen
can understand the problem we are trying
to solve
so what we what we really need is food
but we need to resolve the logical
kind of the Paradox so fold allows you
to take at least
okay let's think about this
so fold
takes a function the function always
takes two arguments why
well the the essence of fold is that it
allows the function to take
a list of things and apply it
recursively
each time taking one element of the list
okay
so
so fold you apply when you do fold
you know when you do fold
you can have these forms but essentially
you take you know at least
and it returns that
Okay so
function a
X so it takes two arguments
two arguments
so it essentially nest
do we do we have a fold right
no you don't have a fold right okay
when you take a thing and it nests it
so
so why is this
God this ABC is no good
you you don't want it to Nest that's the
problem
you don't want it to Nest oh I think I I
got it
there it is a function without head
okay without head is its syntax error
you have to have some kind of head
[Music]
okay so what about what about this we
bracket them in a different way
foreign
tax Arrow yeah but wait
actually
that
oh yeah so
you can't really do that
yeah
foreign
okay I don't know I cannot resolve the
logical issue of fold
it needs uh I need some kind of
understanding
I mean the the issue is is fold
essentially allows you to take
a list of things so fold is like a nest
basically you apply a function to its
own result
recursively but except fold allows you
except that you want to for each time it
calls itself you want to take a value
from a list
so forward is a kind of net recursion or
nesting of a function but for each time
you take a new value
okay
so
so the the
confusing I mean the thing I'm trying to
resolve is that so in a sense fold
should take one the function four-fold
should take one argument only one
argument
but why is it takes two
okay so you you so you take two
arguments you get a result
oh okay so once you when you get the
result
that's right so it's
what I want what we want is a result
applied to
to the new thing not
not repeated yeah so we actually don't
want to
repeatedly or recursively apply a
function f
you know in the case of fold
the function f is repeatedly applied
each time so you always call F
okay
and every time it takes two arguments
the first argument is whatever is a
result
okay and the second argument is a new
item from the list
however you are still calling f
you know and feed those arguments
so you do that you get a result then you
call F again
and put a new result into the argument
and another part from the list you do
that again again you call F so you call
f f many times that's fold you are
essentially doing a recursion
or nesting of the function f
the main point is that f is repeatedly
chord okay
okay that's fold
now in our case what we want here
we do not want to call a function BP to
see repeatedly there's no one single
function
that
our code repeatedly instead
we want to
I've had start with the tree function
then when we get the first value a you
know it becomes that
then when we get the second value B
we don't want to call F order 3 again we
want to call the last result as the
function
okay
so so now we'll get the result is that
okay this is the result
then we get the new values C then we
just apply the result to the to the
argument C Okay so
each time you take the previous result
as the new function to apply to the next
value in the list okay
now remember that that that is a key
that is a key
that is a logical Essence what we are
doing here
you begin with the function called the
tree
can apply it to an argument okay
you begin with function
take an argument from the least apply it
you get a result
now use this result as your new function
take another argument from the list
apply it then you get a new result then
use that result as your function okay so
what you want is some type of it's also
recursion okay
but it's not a recursion of a fixed
point
it's not a recursion of a fixed function
rather
so uh
yeah so this is not a recurs so
what's going on here so each time you
get a result then use that result as a
function so you have some kind of
functional level programming okay
right you don't have like
you know you have some sort of so-called
functional level programming
now I wonder you know the Haskell people
made
know a few things about these I'm not
sure you know I'm not sure about ask our
people but anyway so
start with the function
if I apply it to a very uh argument
you get a result
then
how this is interesting so why is there
this this is a new kind of um
yeah and even in normal recursion in
other programming languages such as
closure in skim this when you do
recursion you call a function you define
a function and in a function body you
call the function itself
you know so that's recursion in you know
other languages
but in in that case you are still
calling a fixed function you repeatedly
call it
you know so it's but in here what we
want is not there's no fixed function
so is this so this is not a so you would
say this is not a recursion this is just
a loop then
yeah so in you know if you use a
procedural language
then this is essentially like
assigned to a variable in a loop
you do something
you assign the result to that value
and you do something again then you
assign the
result the new result to that value
again
kind of combine the previous
thing
Okay so
but how do you do this
how do you actually code it
uh
so you want to
so the result
so you you apply a function through
argument okay the thing get a result
then have the result apply
okay this is two hours two hours and we
haven't resolved this I think I you know
maybe I should stop
who is watching
two people
God this day seven
today's problem day seven
we still have not solved it
although we are making steady steps
you know it's
we are I you know I don't think I'm
stuck anywhere because I'm not really
stuck you know
hate you know I may be it may may appear
that I'm stuck these but I don't think
so this is a clear problem
and I am 100 I can work it out
it just needs some time to think about
this you know and and I want to do it in
a proper way you know I'm
well yeah I'm trying to build this in
you know
in a correct you know in a in a good way
I don't want to
you know I can try to use eval maybe
that's that'll be simpler and there's
quite a lot other ways to
solve this that I haven't tried to think
about yet
you know but I'm just like
you know hitting a wall and I want to
break through that wall and I know I can
that you know I'm just stuck with this
uh idea
so I was trying to resolve you know what
what is the you know logical
uh
you know what's the difference between
nest and forward
what's their implication and what's
their relation to the number of
arguments the hierarity of a function
things like that
so and right now we found that we want a
that the thing we want is a we apply a
function to a value get a result and
this result is supposed to be a function
you then you apply this function to
another value in a list you get a result
and that result is looking at a function
okay
so
is this
I can tell you now that this is
not that frequently done in Wolfram
language because when you have a nested
head that doesn't happen that often okay
let's say it does happen but
let's say 30 percent of
you know Wolfram code you know
functional basically you have a
functional function returning function
but why is this
I mean is there a building construct
like am I I'm uh I need to figure out
where does this feeding fit into the
Wolfram language
uh
you know iteration
kind of uh functions you see there's a
tech node
there's uh you know this these Tech
nodes are originally written by
they are originally from the woofer
Mathematica book which is over a
thousand pages
and they have added new things so in
this section so you know originally came
from wolf family
it's called Mathematica book right over
1000 pages
so but if you look at them you know I
read them cover to cover
three times in 1990s
but today you you might have some new
things not not printed the Wolfram the
Mathematica book stopped printing in
2004.
so anyway so here you have functional
operations and you have
so I want to see where you know what we
are trying to do today where does it fit
in this
we can do that you know yeah I can I can
actually get it to work you know we we
could
we could actually what we can do is just
use nest
and write a function such that the
function contains this this list of
items so each time it calls itself it
takes one of them
reduce you know it remove one item until
there's no item when there's no item the
function returns itself then you get the
result yeah we can do that
okay
okay but okay for now
I think what we are going to do is we're
going to take a break and let's see
maybe after the break
then that's it for today uh
maybe after break
I feel like coding it then let's
continue because right now it's already
two hours okay yeah I know these
I know these functions okay
sequence
sequence is okay
Okay so
so be right back five minutes okay
okay
so I'm gonna take a break be right back
five minutes and maybe that's it for
today
uh you know we stuck with this problem
okay
so let's highlight it so other people
can
uh
see
okay
foreign
gonna turn my video off
China Cheapo
foreign
thank you
okay we might do another break let's see
two people
two people okay
okay let's try something let's try
so we don't want to fold we want
um
we want the nest okay so let's let me
just write it
we want the function that call itself
we want to Nest a function
so when you do nest
when you use nest
you
are also
when you are doing when you do a nest
you are also
recursively calling or fixed function
you are calling the function
it returns something
then
you see
then it um
it calls itself again
on the result
so you want to do Nest okay yeah
okay next function
start with
start with nothing
Okay so
you need to start with something but we
don't want to start with something and
we don't want a fixed number of times
the number of times we repeat the code
the function depends on the
the length of the list
so
we don't want to use nest what we want
to use is fixed Point okay
fixed point will call F on the
expression
repeatedly until
the result no longer changes okay
so
so F apply the expression
then it returns something
let's see fixed Point let's try it
let's say full okay
yeah normally you just Nest it it just
called the function itself four times
okay next call here for again
call info again
cool if again
so if given the argument it returns
something then you call F again
you see that's a problem we don't want a
fixed function we don't want to
we want the result to be a function
yeah this is interesting issue
this is an interesting issue we don't
want
to repeated the core function instead we
want to be repeatedly have the result
becomes a function
okay
so that is that is the main problem we
have
and what and what is this thing we want
is there a name in mathematics in
functional programming
where
you start with at least
you know each time you apply the
function then the result
you want to use the result as a function
then apply to the next next thing
is there a name for this this
thing we are doing Harold hey Harold
where are you from anyone knows against
nobody
replace repeated okay let's see replace
repeated
it's not
ah okay so we can ah pattern yes we can
use pattern
so we want to turn this pattern
into land pattern
huh
pattern matching
okay let's let's try to sketch out the
idea how do you do that
okay let's sketch out this idea so if we
use replace repeated
so we begin with that
and we begin with the least
um then we want to replace repeated
and the pattern is gonna be
a
rest okay
you can say rest okay
becomes
becomes a
foreign
whatever
wait
yeah we want something like this
okay
becomes
hmm
not sure if that will work
let's see let's hope no recursion limit
reached okay
yeah it says it cannot be combined
right so when you have that oh okay wait
you got the arrow here
yeah that's just ABC
I know more
becomes a
and uh
rest okay
no
something like that
okay it doesn't apply because you need F
here
okay something like that it's
it's let's do it here this way okay it's
okay so instead of ABC let's just use
one two three
okay
let's say that
and uh
okay that's I think
that might work
stick
that is the solution
fantastic
for the last one we need to do something
about it
okay this is fantastic
this is
the way to go
this is pattern matching
okay this is transformation of
expression
now
yeah again this is interesting because
we want we want this this this some sort
of recursion or Loop where you apply a
function to a list of things
first you take the first element you
apply a function to it you got a result
then you want to apply the result as a
function to the second element you got a
new result then you apply the result of
that
to the Third
element
you do that with pt3
until
Okay so until there is no more element
in the list okay so we can do it this
way
fantastic that's that is what we want
Okay so
yeah but the last part you want to
um
so so so essentially this is what we
want to do yes this is
this is what we want okay
and uh
right
so what does this what is this pattern I
mean what how do you call this in
functional programming parody Or logic
is there a name you see your name for
this
kind of
Loop or recursion so is this a recursion
recursion
yes this is a sense of recursion but
it's not nesting it's not the typical
recursion using a fixed function
well it can be it I think it can be so
in any case I think this is a recursion
this is a recursion because the function
apply an argument it returns
something okay
and you
apply
can you can we make can we turn this
something into the function itself so
you need a function such that it takes
something
returns a result
and if the arguments
you you wanted to return a result such
that
such that the function does not appear
in the result
so this is not
so the the the question now is is can we
call this recursion
this part is either recursion or not
in some sense it is it's always a loop
but in some broader sense it is a
recursion okay
in some broader sense
or maybe it's not I don't know this is
actually interesting because you are not
calling a fixed function
repeatedly
but that might be a narrow definition of
recursion
so what does Wikipedia say let's look
let's look
so recursion
you know so recursion there is lots of
you know uh
what uh what they talking about
so this they are talking about the
general concept of recursion you have
recursive humor
and it doesn't that's idiotic so here in
mathematics
recursively defined sets
recursive definition example the natural
numbers
okay and you have proof procedure
another interesting example is the set
of all provable propositions in your
axiomatics
system that are defined in terms of a
proof procedure which is inductively or
recursively defined as follows
okay finite subdivision rules okay
functional recursion a function may be
recursively defined in terms of itself
so function is recursively defined yeah
you define the function
involving coding itself okay
a famous recursive function is the
Ackerman function okay which unlike the
Fibonacci sequence cannot be expressed
without recursion okay
proof involves recursive definitions
okay recursive optimization okay
uh
the recursion theorem in set theory this
is a theorem guaranteeing that
recursively defined functions exist
given a set X an element a of X and a
function f x to X
the theorem States states that there is
a unique function f natural number to x
square n denotes the set natural numbers
such that f is 0 equals to A and
what the for any natural number in
the recursion theorem
okay so then you have the computer
science recursion
uh
a common method of simplification is to
divide the problem into sub problems of
the same type
so we have here another typical
programming language
except uh
recursion okay
so today we run into a kind of an issue
about nesting and recursion what do they
really mean
so this is when we need a exact formal
definition
because the thing we are trying to do
you know turn at least into that
this is uh this is kind of strange this
is new to me is it new to me
you know he's due to is that a recursion
or is that just a something
can you call that a recursion
so you are defining so if you want to so
what how do we formally State the
problem
we want a function that take at least
and return
is somewhat a nested function call
so is this
how do you call this function or
how do you uh or is this just
or how do you you know if you define
this process procedure is there a name
for this
this
um
well first of all it is certainly a
recursion because this procedure
repeats itself unchanged this procedure
which
which you may begin
you know this procedure you may begin a
list with the function itself so
you know you may begin with the f
okay maybe maybe not but anyway it you
know it's it's repeating a procedure or
a process
and this procedure never changes so
first of all it is a loop
or repetition it is
repeated repetition a
loop okay so it is a loop
it is a loop because you have to do this
many times however how many times you do
it depends on the given least length
Okay so it's a you know maybe you might
say indefinite Loop or a while loop
or you know in programming languages you
might call a it can be done as a for
loop as well
so in procedural languages or imperative
languages you just assign
you know you just Loop through the list
and each time you assign a variable to
be the value of a function applied to
that
and you assign that to a variable and
this variable is a result
then you take the next element then you
just apply the result as a function to
that element
so definitely
yeah definitely you can do this as a
loop
in a procedural way
so there are many so there are a few
questions so how do you do this
functionally of course we can do it this
way this is one functional way to do it
without assignment
you know because you replace you replace
this form into that form and repeat
until the result Remains the Same
you know so this is a functional way to
express this
you know that which came also be done by
assigning them to a variable so you can
do it procedurally or imperatively
or you can do it functionally but but
now what what is this
what is this thing I mean what what is
this the you know what how does it
relate to
uh recursion or um
I don't know I don't know so
but anyway that is the
this this is the thing we want it works
it works now we all we have to do is
just to make sure
you know each of these F1 F2 you know
those one two three four are directory
names
in a in a full path you know those are
components of the full path so each F1
will return a Association
then
you take the F2 2 is another another
directory name he'll return a
Association
and until you reach F5
then then the you know
the last one if it doesn't exist you
create it you have to say equals to you
know either a file or uh
like we did here
you know this this part depending on its
file or not the file if it's not a file
we create a container
Association
if it's a file we just
set it to the file size
okay
so we can modify this and move on modify
this so that it actually works so what
we really want to do is originally here
you know we are given a list of
directory names like that a list of
directory
path full path
represented as a list of you know each
directory names
so given a full path a list of them we
map a function to that list
two
this function will create a nested
uh
Association key value pairs
a tree
so we we build a tree
but right now we are at the problem of
of writing this part this function
so this can be you know we we know how
to do it now and
but right now we are stuck with the
logical issues of this
I think that's it for today okay
maybe continuing on our I don't know
so but
that's it okay thank you guys for
watching
yeah because I want I want to you know
normally
you know you should just move on I
should just move on but um
very interesting I need a break okay bye
guys