hello guys welcome to another episode of
star talk show
so we are going to code emacs lisp today
i'm going to code it live and i'm going
to give you a tutorial
and uh
and and uh
so oh
sorry about that this is good because my
other video started to broadcast
let me stop that
sorry about that
so um we're going to code emaclisp and
we are going to write a script
as in just like a python you know like
python pearl ruby where you just run the
script in a shell
without
even starting up emacs so this is a
using emac list to write a script and we
are going to
write a script to compute
emac this function frequency use of
frequency so we have i have a page here
that this emac this function uh function
called frequency
for example set q is used the most often
in emacs source code
and then if then define and let
and and you know these are the most
commonly used uh emac these functions
and this script you know this
this statistics is done
if you go all the way to the bottom you
can see it's done in python
you know back in uh this is about 10
years ago 2006
15 years ago 17. so
i wrote a python script to compute the
function frequency oh yeah 2006 wow long
time ago so but today we are going to
rewrite this in emac beast okay let's
begin
so um
so let's name
emacs function frequency good morning
good morning a run
so dot e l so you can see the ping
window shows my emacs keys and command
codes so we're gonna create a file
create yes and let's start to write the
code and docs string okay let's begin to
write the code version give today's date
and documentation
um
go through e
max list
source code the
and compute
function
usage frequency something like that okay
go through emac so okay so first of all
what directory we're gonna go through so
the easiest way to find the emacs emacs
source code directory is you just
describe function and let's say diet you
know some building function
diet is a directory edit
so you arrive at the documentation tab
to here's the source code so let's turn
on yeah so highlight source code you
jump to it so here is the source code of
diet
and you diet jump so go to to go to the
directory you can see and go to the top
you can see here is where the emax lisp
code
are at you know these are building emac
these functions the emac this
powers the entire emacs
so
so which directory we're gonna go uh you
know go through so we're gonna open each
one you know the script is going to open
each one of these files for example open
a brief
skip all the comments and it's going to
basically
uh
use regular uh use uh
search you know string search and find
every
left parenthesis then the first word for
example this eval when compiled as a
function
then for example this require then
define group define custom you know
we're gonna
tally them so every time you find a
function name you put into you put it
into a hash table
and uh if it's or it's not already there
otherwise you
increment you know the key the hash
table key is a function name the hash
table value would be the count of that
function so that's what we're going to
do so
okay so
so let's go back to dia jump so you can
see the pink window shows my command
calls and keystrokes i'm using volva
keyboard and this is kinesis advantage
too
this is ultimate hacking keyboard i use
it as a
key micro pad
you can find it on the web side keyboard
you can uh find my reviews
okay so
we're gonna okay so this is directory
let's go up a directory yeah so that's
other um files so this is the directory
we want copy the file path close it
close it close it close it close it now
um
let's let's
let's put the file path here so just
actually let's put it here so
we're gonna dive into so first of all
we're gonna going to
traverse the directory
okay so let's let's write it out
work the directory okay
then
for each file
open
it
then
find
text like
left parenthesis
something
something okay something something
if
that's um
it in a hash table hash table is
basically key value pairs okay let's
begin let's let's just begin to do it
okay so first of all the problem is
given a directory you want to to visit
each and every file so how do you do
that
uh sorry emacs i have a tutorial which i
use for myself
so
practical emac please
go there
and turn javascript
okay so
in my tutorial this section writing a
command
is mostly about interactive commands
then here is a section of writing script
that's what we are gonna uh do the the
type of tasks
we are doing today is here so
over here you see uh you see read file
right firework directory that's what we
want okay
so directory so
this directory no subject no
subdirectory that's the function we want
copy it
so uh directory files okay and then you
give it directory here we already we
copy copy it
instead of let's put a variable okay
so that's a local variable we set it to
that
okay so
should be your directory
by emacs list convention directory name
but directory path should end with a
slash okay that's the emac this
convention uh basically you have to do
that okay
so uh so let's uh so yeah so we got a
directory so we don't need this line we
got a directory we want to visit the
directory and visit every file path okay
so
so this function directory files visited
an optional full match
uh no
sort so return these the name of files
in directory if full is the neo return
the absolute file names
yeah so we want absolute file names for
true if match is in the neo
only return the
matched files
okay so i don't i don't think
think that's probably it let's let's say
describe function directory
[Music]
if matches the neo mention only file
names whose non directory
whose name directory part matches
regular expression match okay so match
is a regular expression
uh
that we want to visit every file so
well we want to visit every
dot el files all the files there are dot
el
oh yeah so there's also elc this is
compiled emac list so we don't want to
visit that so we do want to use a
regular expression to match the file
name extension okay
so here is the regular expression match
file name extension that should
you know that dollar sign
matches the end of
end of end of line or end of the string
so technically it should be
something else because you don't want to
match end of line but anyway file names
don't have multiple lines so dollar sign
should do
so
and and in emac this that
you know regular expression dot means
match anything so if you want a little
dot you need to say slash
uh backslash backslash dot
okay directory files so okay so then you
need to give a
another local variable
and in this case you can
okay so let's just do it simply this way
okay
so that's the files you want to set
a list of files to be
that okay so let's see directory files
yeah
and for now let's just message print it
okay print
um
okay
eval the function and let's just run it
let's just run it okay uh we need to
give a name actually so
file name so
report
function frequency okay let's just say
let's just name our
function that for now okay
so
evaluate the code then
evaluate this it should print
all the file path indeed
so if we go to the messages buffer
you can see
there's lots of files you know each one
of these for for example copy new buffer
then
then make them into lines so you can see
oh you see some of them got elc so erc
that's wrong so
okay and also okay our regular
expression is not working close that
because that
so our regular expression
directory files okay let's look let's
look again directory files directory
optional full oh yeah so
first of all you need the full yeah we
missed one argument
let's do it again
okay go to the messages buffer
copy that new buffer
replace space by a new line exactly so
this is what we want so we got a list of
files how many are there 270 okay that's
let's go with that
um we don't
you know we are not diving into the
directory
i mean there are sub directories for now
you know
we let's just skip them
uh but later on after you know the video
i can do them full
okay we need to go faster okay so
so work the directory for each file open
it and uh yeah so okay that's basically
that's what we are doing okay
so now we got
a list of files
now all we have to do is
uh so we don't need that all we have to
do is we
want to
map a function
to the list so for every file we open it
and do stuff okay
so map a function so that would be map
c okay map c
uh
map c is like map car
except it doesn't return results
so here's a documentation so it's it's
like for each in javascript and other
languages okay so map c
so the sequence the sequence would be x
files
and the function would be a lambda
function okay
and
so x is a file so
and body
so here the body part would be
open the file
okay so we got the structure open the
file so um
so what's the next thing so
you want yeah so you want to open the
file so normally you can use find file
but that's super slow because find file
has lots of hooks
uh for example uh let's see
for example describe variable find file
hook you know and its value is all these
you know its value is all that new
buffer
replace space by new line so you can see
every time you open a file all this
function runs you know so it really
slows down you don't want you you don't
want that if you are writing a
emax script you know these are useful
functions so that when you open file it
loads
the mod it syntax color uh and you know
many other conveniences when you are
using when you are using emacs as an
editor but when in a script you usually
you don't want that because it slows
down significantly like 10 times 10
times especially the syntax curling
so so if you don't want
if you don't want to use find file to
open the file how do you do that um
so i have written down the tips here
read file so read file is what we need
we don't need to write to file so um
yeah so here is how you do it okay so
let's copy the thing and
put it
here let me show you okay now yeah so
so let's say
don't use find file okay
so
here is the part we need so we don't
need the defense so this is how you do
so with temp buffer
uh
that function means it will create a
temporary buffer then once you do that
you insert file contents
into the buffer then you do something
you know once you have a buffer then you
can you know
grab or whatever
so that's what we gonna do
so um
so let's actually let's use the variable
uh
let's not
okay let's use it here so so
yeah so lambda
file path given a file path you
create a temporary buffer you
insert the content into the buffer then
then you go to go to the beginning of
the buffer
okay
uh go to char point me
that's how you move the cursor to the
beginning
then
then you search for word
you want to search for the string
parenthesis
okay we want to use regular expression
so search forward is a function that
search a given string
but it's plain text it's not regular
expression
uh in our case we want regular
expression so let's use research for
what okay
this is a regular expression version so
we want to
the regular
expression is going to be left
parenthesis
then
anything not space let's say anything
that's not a space so the way you do
that
is let's magnify okay
you do that is that square bracket not
space
and
and a
plus sign means one or more occurrence
so
then optional bound we don't care
bound
bound near no error true we don't care
about error and don't
and uh let's
we don't care about the count
the the count the count parameter limits
how many occurrence you know how many
uh occurrence
beyond that it will just ignore so we
don't we we want to go through the whole
thing
so
so let's research forward
anything good hey thank you thank you
flamio
hey thank you
so we we go through
so search forward
search for the uh left parenthesis and
the function name the function name
is anything not space yeah because
you know another way is that we can use
uh anything a to z a to z lowercase and
zero to nine and also include a dash
that's
that's uh that's a regular expression
another way we can do it but however
some emac these functions they are for
example plus
uh one plus
you know some imac these functions are
not just alphabets
so that's why we do it this way not
space okay
so now we got the wood we want to
extract you know we want to remove that
once we got we we we want to remove the
parentheses and
okay so let's capture okay so let's
capture this part
let me show you how to do that
uh backslash backslash
backslash backslash parenthesis that's
how you capture because the imac this
the parenthesis is literal so if you
want to actually capture you have to
have backslash so this way you will
capture the
the actual function name okay so remove
that so capture the function function
name but how do you
so
how do you get the word okay
uh x
fun
name okay uh
function
so we want to set function name
to
match string
okay match string one what means the
first group okay so that should be it
optional stream we don't care so match
match string is the last whatever
regular expression
uh the capture group the first one and
we assign that to function name okay so
function name that's another local
variable let's put it here
let's shrink the buffer a bit
okay let's uh
let's compact our code
okay so
now once we got the function name
now we need to add it to a hash table so
let's
let's do this fast okay
hash table
okay so how do you create a hash table
uh i
you you use make hash table okay
uh but i don't remember the syntax
exactly so let's go back here i'm
familiar with my own tutorial which i
use
often when i code
so
you know let me show you another way so
first of all you can you can go to list
advanced
and
emac this data structure then there is a
hash table
another way is to you know
you know if you are not uh
read my tutorial of course buy my
tutorial you know if you like my stuff
but but normally you uh you can
so right now we need to find a function
that creates a hash table how do you add
to a hash table how do you remove item
in hash table stuff like that so how do
you do that in general you
you do um
a propose okay so you meta x a prop post
okay then you just type hash
that that will list
all functions in this that contains the
word hash so this is how normally uh
you know you can you can find
uh
how to uh find the function you want for
example here is the hash table
okay uh
okay so but that's not the one we want
the function to create a hash table
there are a lot so every time you search
something there's a lot that's why i'm
you know i use my own tutorial
so here is hash table so here is what
you want to do make hash table
okay so we want to make a hash table
make hash table
returns a new hash table that's right
okay so
so
so actually we can just put it there
and the test
should be string equal
equal will work but
let's be more uh
more
precise
so that will be faster
uh string equal yeah so
you know there are several different
comparisons for in emac this for example
you can compare between numbers you can
compare between strings or you can
compare between a integer and a float so
for different purposes you have
different equality
functions for example you have eq
you have equal
and you also have the
equal symbol
so you know i have a tutorial about this
but anyway so
the way we want is just string equal
okay
so
this when you make a hash table you
specify a test for equality that's when
it determines that's how emac emacs
determines when
a key already exists in a hash table or
not okay
so
so now you have a function name so do we
have the variable yes we have a function
name then
you need to check if that's already in
the hash table if not add it okay
so
check key exists okay that's how you do
it get hash
get hash
key will be x function name
table will be
x hash
optional uh default
okay so
yeah so check
this will check if the key already
exists we don't care about default okay
so if
git hash if that's true
if the key the function name already is
in the hash then we increment
so
so we put hash so we
put hash
okay so if it already exists
then we put hash
that then the value will be whatever
existing value plus one okay so um
yeah so this is getting tedious so the
value will be existing
okay so that's the way you do it the
value will be
that
plus one okay so
there
okay let's let's uh let's pretty find
the code so it's more readable
okay so put hash
so check hash check the key exists if it
does
then
we
increase the value so you we put hash
function name the key
then
the existing value plus one okay
that's
that's if this do not exist
now if it exists
i mean that that's if it's it the key
already exists so if it does not exist
we
simply do the same thing
but the hash value will be
uh one so you know
okay that's it you know you see we have
used this code twice you see this
uh
this get hash you know this
you know happened twice so we should set
it a variable let's do it
let's say
key exists okay
key exist
okay
so
yeah so
[Music]
so this way we don't have to call the
code twice
okay so let's
let's put it here
local variable okay
okay
so let's um
i think that's about it uh let's see
yeah so now i think that's it
now after this code block is done
we can
we finished
generating a hash table so now we can
actually print the hash table so
it's trying okay so uh
get all values uh print hash table uh if
we print it it's gonna be huge huge um
these
of things okay let's just print it
okay that i think that's it that's the
that's the whole function
how long have we been going
30 minutes not bad okay so
yeah so
evaluate it and run it let's just arrow
invalid hash table test okay
what arrow invalid hash table test
string equal right
it should work
yeah but let's just say
let's just say that okay because i want
to finish this first uh fast
uh it's strange that string equal
does not work it should really should
just work okay
um i don't know okay let's just say
equal
evaluate the code okay it's done so now
go to the messages directory
so
so we got a hash table here copy it new
buffer
now
make it into a okay something is wrong
because there are not many entries
so hash table test equal hash size
data
uh well this is strange
i think our regular expression is
incorrect
don't save close it close it
what's going on so
map
a lambda
file path
so this
map this part maps and then we map to
the files
and
it's um then lambda file path with temp
buffer
insert file content file path go to
chart point main go to the beginning
then search forward
is it possible our regular expression is
incorrect
let's
let's do this okay let's just instead of
that
let's just say a to z a to z
0 to 9 okay
then
also include the dash
okay so regular expression search for
word we want to search the function name
let's look up describe function regular
expression
bound
bound we don't care no error that's true
and we don't care about accounts so
so you do that then you set x function
name to be the to the
capture
excuse me
then
uh i'm using a red switch this is silent
red actually
this is my sec this is my second
uh kinesis advantage i bought the first
one they sent it to me you know i do a
review for them then
the first one is a brown switch then i
bought i went and bought a
linear red switch which is this one
because i prefer
linear switches lighter
so
x key
exists so
get hash
okay so if it exists
that should work
so if it exists then
let's reduce make it them smaller so we
don't need
put hash so let's let's
compact the code okay
so
if the key exists then put hash the
function name
then
increase the value to 1
put it to this hash table
if it does not exist then just put hash
one so that should work
so what is wrong in our code
okay let's try it again now we did
change the regular expression let's
do it
okay let's look at the hash table now
the hash table is wrong
you see the hash table the result hash
table
doesn't have much values so what are
these
so without happened once heart happened
once normal top level happened once
one happened twice
okay something is wrong so
hash table okay so
auto load happens six times
c happened
258 times something is not right
so there are total of 65 so because
are we just going
over
just one file maybe let's close that
and
so for now for example let's uh
with temp buffer
let's comment that out okay
and let's just
print the file path okay
do it
go through the messages buffer
there we have the file path that looks
that's correct
so we are visiting each and every file
okay we are doing that
now let's open one of these let's look
at the source code
so are we so we are trying to
search for left parenthesis and
and a variable name
left parenthesis and the variable name
so so what is okay so what is wrong so
this is correct
okay so what's going on so
with temp buffer insert file contents f
path that's right
and go to
[Music]
minimum then search for that
let's just say print okay
debug
let's print the x function names okay
and
okay
evaluate it
go to the messages buffer
so same thing happens you see it just
nt so it's not actually
22 times 10 times
it prints c ten times it prints c ten
times
now something something is wrong
so it prints c 32 times it prints c 33
times okay
something is wrong with my
here
so let's see what is match string so
[Music]
return the string of text matched that's
right
so
yes
okay debug debug we need to okay so
let's
let's get
more elaborate debugging
current file
so we can see what is a current file run
it
go to the messages buffer
so current file
oh that's
that's right i know what's going on
you know what happened is that it
actually
so once we found it
for each file once we found the first
occurrence then we just exit it
so for each file we only
tell it one function that's why
so
so now you need to put a wire loop for
the search for that's right yeah
obviously
while
so while
search forward that
then
you
want to
do this
whole thing
okay
so while you search forward first of all
you go to the
point beginning the point mean beginning
of file then start to search function
names
then
you found it save it to the function
name
then
print the function name then if the key
already exists in the hash
you know
then you
increment the hash value otherwise you
add to the hash
table with value of one okay
run it
no now it's we're talking
fantastic
so you can see it's taking a while to do
fantastic because we are printing so
much let's stop
so we because we are printing you know
this message is printing thousands tens
of thousands let's run again
done okay so now go to the messages
buffer
this is going to be one giant thing
so emax has a problem you know this is a
the message buffer now has this one
giant huge long line so we don't want
that
because you know we are because we are
printing a hash table so
emax
has this problem when there's one huge
long line it's super slow like if you
know i press key it's not responsive it
takes you know five seconds to
respond to a keystroke
but emacs 28 has a new feature
called so long mod so if you turn on it
will
make this problem less severe so let's
turn it on so meta x
you know even even koni meta x takes a
while so
so long mod
okay so that's a new feature in emacs 28
so do it
okay now
it's it's still slow this line is just
this line is just too long okay so
anyway close it
so we don't need the message so instead
of printing hash let's just print them
one line one by one that'll be much
faster so
well first of all you don't you know you
want to sort the hash by the
by their frequency okay so so the hash
by the frequency let's let's get this
going fast
so you want to turn a hash into a list
okay
because we need to sort it
add entry remove entry apply function to
all entries check key exist get all keys
get all values hash to list okay there
is a function
and i believe in emacs 27 also they have
a building function to do that
do they have that
let's see uh
a purpose
hash
okay let's see let's search for list
hash table keys
um
so
hash to this return a list that
represents the hash table each element
is a list key value okay
so we need to
turn a hash table into a list so that we
can sort it
now there are several ways to do it now
i'm wondering if there's a building
function maybe in the past few years
they added that
so you have hash table key i don't think
there is okay so
so if we open
hash table keys then we search for
defend
so hash table values hash table
yeah it it has function to return keys
and values but we just we actually just
want the um
yeah okay let's let's just use our
function so
i have written this a while ago let's
put it here
hash to list okay
so hash to list uh
so
so let's
name our function that okay
so add a variable here
okay so
set cue
that
and
sit
there
so set cue function name this hash to
list
okay then
then we can print
so for each x
message
x
okay
evaluate it
yeah okay it's gonna take a long time
okay done so now go to the message
buffer fantastic
so we can see each line here the first
element is the function name the second
element is how
is the occurrence the number of times it
happens okay now we need just to sort
this okay so sort
so sort
is the function we want now let's look
at the documentation
sort
uh sequence in predicate okay the
sequence is
that okay
uh wait yeah so
the sequence then the predicate is a
function that does the comparison so
so the function to do the comparison
would be your lambda okay
lambda
a and b takes two arguments
and uh
and yeah so the
okay this is going to be inefficient but
let's just do it okay so we
so we
so each element is a key value pair so
let's let me show you okay
so lambda each element is the key value
pair let's let's copy that and put it
here so
so we want to
it's a list okay so cutter
cut the car
yeah so it's something like that okay
i'm i'm not gonna explain
okay it's it's gonna be like that a and
a and b represents each
element so a
a is a pair key value pairs it's a list
okay and b is also same thing
so we want to compare them by this
function less than
okay so this sorted version will be
um let's remove that
swords
we we we want to assign it back to the
okay let's just
let's forget about efficiency
efficiency be scoot and it's neat let's
just push this
uh code and let's you know push this
code to get on
so we can finish this let's try to write
okay
go to the messages buffer show the pink
window go to the message superfa
do we have it sorted sorted
yes we do fantastic you see the the
earlier we go the
number becomes smaller
so we are actually interested the in the
most used there it is so the most used
function
in emac this source code is set q
that sets a variable so the second most
used is if statement
just like the way we had with you know
the way we did with our python script so
15 years ago so you see
so so actually so we we have finished
complete so now we just um
yeah we we we've done it
and uh yeah i think that's it so it's
long enough 50 minutes okay so here's a
full code
so we can you know this
code right now is not the most efficient
because
you know
because uh so we can do some cleanup
but essentially
you know i think that's that's it for
today we i mean we showed basically how
to do it so we can do a lot clean up
rename function names
you know rename variable names so they
are more intuitive and remove some
redundant functions i mean redundant for
example we don't need to set q twice
here
so instead of so let's remove the
you know we don't we don't want to set
this twice
okay function list
so we can
you know that way we removed one set you
know usually functional programming you
don't want to
change the value of a variable so you
always set just once
so
oh wait wait we got it wrong so this
actually this goes here and this goes
here yeah so hash to list hash then you
saw this hash and set it to function
named list
so this function name list should be
sorted list
yeah so let's rename it
something like that okay
okay so basically that's we are done
thank you guys for watching if you like
my stuff you know buy my emacs tutorial
by my emacs tutorial
and
donate
thank you guys so i'm gonna see answer
questions
see if there's any questions we shut
down in two minutes or so
so the code so
you know we're gonna do some cleanup so
copy the code close it
close it back to today's talk show
and add emac this code here paste it
show in browser
so that's the code we did today so
color it
refresh fantastic
oh yeah so actually the main thing i
want to show i have i yeah yeah let's
continue okay so there is one more thing
i want to show okay so
for example we have this file
right we have this
e max function frequency
now remember we want to do this with
without running emacs without you know
interactively running it we want to do
do it purely as a python script you know
like we talked about in the beginning
so
so let's go to powershell
let me show you okay so let's
uh go to powershell let's magnify
powershell so we
we want to run the emacs script let's do
it okay so to generate a file so
so there's a few there's an option let's
go let's find it
so hash table go to emac this tutorial
go to um
practical emac disk
and in this writing a command
section
and writing a script
run emac this
this code in shell so that's how you
want to do it okay email you know so
let's do it
so emax
dash dash script
then the
the script name so
x okay
x
there it is okay
now if we run that it should print out a
bunch of things
let's double check
i'm pretty sure it work let's see
yep
do it
ah the term emax is not recognized
so so i so i i need to give the specific
path
where is my emacs so
yeah
let's
oh yeah so yeah okay so you you got a cd
to emax
beam
then you have
emac uh emax
okay so now we now we need to uh yeah so
let's so here is how you want to do so
let's copy let me
so file path will be that
and the script
okay
so it's gonna be something like that
there
do it
and debugger entered this error file
missing cannot open load file
what
oh yeah so my file path is incorrect
so this is
redundant let's do it again
fantastic
oh uh you didn't see it i think i guess
so it's
printing lots of things stop it now we
just
redirect to a file name let's say xxx
something okay
do it
ah it still prints out wait what
happened to the powershell redirect
anyway okay so that's it so
oh we are in emacs directory well that's
not good no good anyway so
thank you for watching uh bye guys
yes in this tutorial my tutorial is on
you know includes the emacs and emac
disp
so you can you can find it just search
saudi emacs
and i also have javascript tutorial i
talked about this often in my video so
let me let me okay so let me tell you so
you guys can buy my stuff you know
support me so
emacs and emac these tutorials they are
great you are looking at xari.info
and
my also
powershell script is very good
python and my goal line script is also
pretty good and but mostly the most in
depth is my javascript uh tutorial so
my javas all these are free you know you
can read all of them are you know
available online
but
the most you know it has a thousand
almost a thousand pages that's the emac
this in javascript
okay bye guys