welcome to another episode of star talk
show
you are watching star talk show and
today is 2020
may 17th 17th
uh 2021
may 17th and today we are going to do
the first 30 minutes or so
we are going to do emacs this coding
live coding
of emaclis and on the pink window on the
left you can see all my emacs command
cores
because if you are new to emacs and if
you are your emacs user remember that in
emacs
the keystrokes is the uh critical thing
the primary thing
every keystroke is ultimately calling a
command
so you can on the pink window you can
see all my keystrokes
uh i'm typing for example let's see a
new page okay it's
except insert uh anyway so you can see
all my keys keystrokes moving closer
forward by word backward backward or
down up
or jump by paragraphs and you can see
the corresponding command
names so if you don't know what i'm
doing you can always search for the
command name
and you can find the code for example
start beginning line of block
copy it and type it here and search
uh github problems github there it is
uh well so the code is where is it code
the code is
star talk show uh the code
okay the code is actually in my uh
software keys
yeah so here there's an issue i i guess
the
search engine is not so good what what's
the issue that's a very old issue
2. four years ago but anyway so you can
search for the command and find it
okay uh find the source code uh
okay so we are going to code emacs lisp
okay if you have comments and questions
post it on the site and on on the live
youtube okay
so let's begin so first thing i want to
do is to
code a emac list command let's see
let's start a emac list uh e-lisp okay
let's start coding and let's show this
in browser okay let's start coding so
the fun uh we don't have people here yet
uh so what what does the command do
convert seconds
to minute
second format or
vice versa
on current word
okay or vice versa on current word okay
okay and let's put the date uh
version today's date okay we are going
to write this command
and uh
and okay let's do so so so so the
what we want to do is that for for
example let's say
um
what what's going on so
what
oh yeah so here is a number for example
i want to convert this to a number of
minutes and seconds
so let's do okay so the input so the
input is a number okay so
uh first of all we want to grab so
we want to grab the word under cursor so
which is a number okay so how do you
grab
what number under cursor i believe it's
a current word okay let's see if that
that's the right function yes indeed so
describe function
to look up current word is a compiler
this function blah blah blah can't word
option or strictly uh
really word return the word at uh at
or near a point okay as a string
okay so that returns the current word
for example
uh
current word okay so let's do this
so uh
so then we want to print it print
the current word okay that is basically
our code
for example i mean we let's just testing
okay
uh the function name will be convert
seconds to mean
sec okay so copy that
so evaluate the buffer then let's
put a random number okay here eight
four two eight now we want to so put the
cursor there
call the command meta x convert second
to
uh mean second okay press enter uh
symbols value as variable is void
current word okay so
what's going on symbols value is what
oh yeah so here this should be that okay
uh let's rename this
word x okay okay evaluate the buffer
now put the cursor on this word call it
let's magnify okay call it
call it and you can see the message
buffer printed you see
that's that's what the that's what the
code does right now
so we want to so that's how you grab the
word
but actually we don't want to use this
uh
function this this current word function
because our command is going to turn
this into
okay that's let's change another number
let's say 70.
so if the cursor is on the word 70 it
should return
it should return 110 one minute
and 10 seconds right so i mean
it should just replace the word the 70
by
by this 110. so that means we need to
also need
to know the posit we need to delete the
and in order to do that we need to know
the beginning position
of the word and end position so
so this current word function does not
do that it only gives you the
the word under cruiser so what do you
need to do
so you need to call thing at point
instead so thing at point is uh
is part of the emac list function okay
so thing at point takes a symbol as
arguments so if you say what it will
return a word
so so this function
is basically the same as that and that's
that's not what we want
what we want is bounds of thing at point
okay this is getting complex bounce of
thing at point
so what does does that do it basically
it's the same thing okay same thing as
thing at point except it returns the
boundary
that is the it returns a uh cons pair
two elements the first element is the
beginning position second element is the
end position of the
word under cursor so okay so that's
that's what we want okay so
so let's add new uh more variables
v-o-u and d-a-r-y-x
so let's name it boundary x so
set boundary x will be
that okay then then
let's add two more variables position
one position two okay
then set position one will be
uh car
boundary car means the first element of
a cons pair
so boundary is a cons pair two elements
so
that's the position one and the set
position two
cutter boundary x
so that's p two is position position two
okay
now now we want to get the word
so so now we have two positions we want
to grab the
stream between them so how do you do
that set
word x buffer
substring no properties okay it takes
two positions p1 and p2
exactly good okay that's our code so far
and this line we no longer need
okay so so now we have the boundaries
we have the beginning position p1 and n
position and we have the word
now we can do so now what we need to do
so the word x
is a is a string which
actually is a number okay we need to so
we need to convert the type string
to uh string two number so
string two number okay there is such a
function
so string two number
what okay then okay so actually
so actually let's uh let's
let's clean up our code so it's all
better
you see so
instead of that we we we want to say
this instead okay so
actually let's make it pretty prettier
kind of okay so now word x
is a number so uh let's so
so it's not let's say uh seconds
okay so actually so yeah let's let's
make the codes
easier to understand since i'm doing a
kind of tutorial so
so let's be elaborate with all the set
set set you know we don't need that mini
set actually if you
so anyway so here's the seconds now we
need to turn the seconds into minutes
and seconds
so we need to first of all add another
two variables
mean x sec x by the way why do i name my
variables this way because i prefer to
have variable names that
that is unique that tends to not to be a
english word
for example the word x can simply be
named
word but
but if you but when you need to search
the variable world you you tend to find
lots of places that's
not a variable so in this way word x is
kind of
unique you'll just find the variable
name so that's why that's a preference
in naming of variables
and same thing for functions that's my
own preference so now we have the
seconds now we need to turn these
seconds into minute
and minute and seconds okay
any comments hello guys ruby
uh good evening central europe fantastic
hello everyone
sid and potato hello so second
so now now turn the second two minutes
in seconds how do you do that
what you need is mathematics modular
arithmetics
okay so how do you do mod in uh
in in in emac base for example in python
in many languages you do that so you
have 70
the percentage sign is the operator you
know so you do that then you need to get
the remainder
so but i i don't remember what's a
function in emacs
so go to xr emacs tutorial just search
it
search for it you'll find it emacs list
okay
e magnus basics magnify
magnify and go down arithmetic
so here is the division here is the
integer part of a quotient
and here is the remainder okay that's
what you need that's what we need
close it so i'm using my own tutorial as
a reference
so integer part uh so minute okay
set minute x
uh m-i-n-u-t-e
not to be confused with minimal so let's
say minute x
uh and let's change the second two
seconds x okay
so we have so set minute minute will be
mod okay so so minute will be mod
uh
wait the second must be um
[Music]
okay total seconds so
so first of all you have total seconds
then
means that x uh yeah so let's let's name
our variable like that okay
so
so here this will be total seconds
so the minute will be
total seconds divided by 60 okay
pretty by the code then
set
okay so let's uh
okay then we set the seconds seconds
will be
the remainder okay yeah so that's the
that
yeah so uh here then total seconds
divided by 60
right so that's uh that's the that's
right so
d d d d d prettify the code
and we don't and and
so the 70 example input
okay and here is example output
okay so now we have the minutes and we
have the seconds
all we have to do now is to delete the
original text
and insert the new minute and second
so let's do so before we insert we need
to delete
delete region okay two positions that's
right
p1 and p2 beginning position and end
position those are numbers
then insert so insert
we will be inserting uh okay let's say
format
okay then two uh variables
minutes and uh
six
okay so hold on second six
okay then
there it is okay now now we don't need
this uh message
part did it purify the code fantastic i
believe that's it that's the whole
function
actually we haven't done the vice versa
the reverse
conversion yet but first of all so this
is i believe that's it
so let's uh verify uh before uh
you know let's avoid trial and error so
so minute
then seconds those are um
those are oh actually uh yeah that's
right so minute is the
uh quotient seconds is the remainder
that's right so let's try it okay
evaluate the buffer let's show the pink
window evaluate the buffer then
let's call uh let's just put 70 okay
70 put the
70 then call the command convert second
to minute
sec okay press enter we should get one
colon 10. let's see do it
fantastic complete
complete guys let's try some let's try
some um
let's try some bigger number let's say
seven hundred and one let's see what
happens to that
okay now this is just like
testing okay do it
11 minute and 41 seconds that's probably
right okay so
uh
that's yeah well it seems right so so
let's try another example 59 okay
do it 0 colon 59
fantastic we assume we presume this is
correct
no need for the testing okay now
this this is done the next thing
we need to do is write another function
or modify this function so that it can
convert
the reverse way
okay uh i'm going to read the comments
take a break
but let me tell you so so now there's an
interface
issue now you have to make a decision
one
is that use the same function that do
both
you know by pressing a universal command
so
so if if i want to convert from mini
second format to the second
format i call the same function
except right except that i press
ctrl u first then i call it then i'll do
that
so that's one option using the same
function the other option is just write
a new function
for example writing a new function so
this you know writing a new function and
um so which one should we do i'm i i
i'm going to use the same function you
know there are
pros and cons in either case okay i'm
gonna
use the same function uh the advantage
is that it's just from
one function name and the function can
automatically detect
whether the word or the the sequence of
strings under cursor
contains a colon or not so if it
contains a colon then we know we want to
convert it to seconds
format if it doesn't we want we know we
want
you know we we know which way to convert
so i'm gonna just use a function
once one single function for it
fantastic now let's read the comments
howdy so scott hey scott haven't seen
you for a while
uh it's doing pretty good i did my taxes
yesterday
now that's after 16 years of no doing
taxes because i don't make enough to do
taxes
but that yesterday i did taxes and now
i'm going to get
1 000 800 from
federal government and i'm going to get
and and and plus some something like
2000 stimulus you know corvid 19
stimulus money uh
you know my life has been changing
for the better the turning point is 2020
and the reason
my mom died a sad story but it's a
a bit detail okay i'm not going to go
into
so uh have you played with emacs 28's
ability to do native
jit just in time com compilation of emac
this no i haven't played with
emacs 28 that would be a great feature
uh i haven't played i'm getting old you
know i
haven't played with these things i'm
just gonna i'm just wait for the day
when i come out
and i just install it and it just it
works i don't
you know i'm not too you know unlike
when i'm younger we are getting old
scott and scott's by the way scott is a
c and c plus plus programming language
expert working on cpus and gpus and the
textures
designing cpus and uh and gpus
so anyway so let's uh yeah let's finish
this
um let's see let's do the reverse
conversion and maybe that's it for today
i've been talking 23 minutes okay so
today
maybe today is just gonna be pure emac
there's no random
you know sensitive topics random you
know
stuff okay now let's do the reverse
conversion
so first of all design the interface so
how do you want it to be
so let's uh let's write documentation
let's let's let's
explain so convert seconds to uh or
you know two minute second format or
vice versa on current word
okay now explain if the current
word contains a colon
then do the reverse uh
to the
to the reverse direction conversion so
it's basically automatic it will
automatically
detect which direction to go okay
that's that's what we decide you know
that's the user interface
i decided uh to do so now comes through
the coding part how are you gonna do
this
so first of all you know we grab the
word
we grab the boundary then we
uh we got the word now we need to
put a if statement okay if
something we want to see
check if what x contains
colon so that's essentially that's what
we need to do
okay but before we do that there's a
issue because when you call
bounce up thing at point
um i i i was eating something
in my teeth so when you cope on the
thing at point
we wheel it grab you know the the whole
minute and second part so what i mean by
that for example
if you have this let me let me just code
it okay so
it's easier to uh instead of me spending
several minutes through experience so
let's comment this out
so now let's just print
print what x to see what it returns okay
when
uh to see what this what this uh
thing at point actually grabs i mean the
question is if we will
just grab part of it or will it actually
consider the whole thing as a word
yeah actually i know the answer because
the thing at point
the the thing at point package i don't
like it because it
okay it's a it's a bit more complicated
because emacs
you know in emacs and emac these they
have the concept of
of syntax category okay let me let me
quickly explain this
so so if you go to the emac this
basics you go to the yeah so
so you go to the more advanced emac list
writing a major mod okay
then we you will see this section about
um
define face syntax coloring syntax table
okay
so in emac this you have this concept of
syntax table what basically it means
it classifies each and every character
in unicode into uh
into groups for example all the
punctuation characters comma colon
question mark you know space those are
punctuation group then english letters
russian letters alphabets you know
and all chinese characters those are
kind of another group
words letters or words then you have
another group
that's um that's um
uh that's that's what okay let me let me
concentrate
uh string yeah uh you know
then then you have another group about
syntax classes okay there
there you are so you have white space
characters you have what's considered
word
you have what's considered symbol then
you have punctuation
class of characters you then you have
string delimited
delimiters then you have the left
bracket red bracket and so on then
common
character so this is a
uh feature building into emac lisp
or emacs how emacs works each character
is you know each character in every
character in unicode is
classified into these kind of funky
groups okay this these funky groups is
not
mutually exclusive by the way for
example
for example common start character
it can also you know usually for example
in python pearl bash
powershell the common start is a pound
sign
but but in english writing
that pound sign is considered a pound
sign or a number sign or you know it's
considered punctuation
so so sometimes the letter can belong to
multiple categories and also
word and symbol that's very confusing
word basically means english word and
symbol means
this symbol basically it means allowed
characters in a
identifier of a programming language so
anyway
in emacs it has the concept of
syntax table which is a table that
classifies
characters into each of the these
kind of the groups and
and here's the thing for each buffer
it can have its own syntax buffer
i mean syntax table so depending on what
major mod you are in
same character maybe may may be
classified into different groups
so for example let's say the parentheses
okay in lisp it's considered a left
bracket
in english you know for example in
fundamental mod or text mod
that's also considered a left bracket
but however you can
you can write the major mod for some
language where the
parenthesis is not considered a bracket
rather it's considered to say let's say
a comma character
i mean a a string start character or
something
so so there there's a lot of problems
about this
emac syntax table idea it's very it's
it's pretty bad okay
this is a bad thing however it's very
fundamental because
every command that that move cursor
is dependent on the syntax table
so what so why is it bad first of all
you have this classification you know
which is kind of fuzzy you know it's not
mutually exclusive
and and even so you know it's not
it's it's difficult to to define them
you know to to to create a syntax table
to
say which which character belongs to
this this this that group it's
it's it's a huge huge mess okay
so first of all one of the problem of
the syntax table is that
it has these funky classification you
know categories
which is idiotic okay
so what's the example that's not idiotic
for example the unicode specification
unicode
okay let me remember okay maybe let's
ramble about
uh about about these things okay so
we're getting into linguistics and
stuff uh okay let's go through my
unicode
um page okay just search for you
sorry unicode you'll find my unicode
page so unicode standards
uh you know they they also have okay
let's magnify the browser hold on a
second so let's magnify
the browser uh
once for all instead of doing it on
every page
appearance uh magnify
125 okay okay so
so so my unicode page so let's go
let's go down to the unicode for
programmers
okay so i have uh oops
i have quite a lot articles on unif code
for
programmers the technical details about
unicode
which is about characters about
languages you know what's a unicode
what's utf-8
what's the code point uh you know this
kind of thing so
you go there and read it you know if you
are new to
programming okay
okay and i talk about encoding so so
okay so so the thing i want to say is
that unicode has also has a way to
classify
each and every characters into letters
group
into numbers group for example what
would you invite by
by numbers group for example one two
three you know arabic
numbering system one two three four you
know
up to nine and zero but that's not all
because in chinese
let's go let's let me show you okay in
chinese you also have
okay in chinese you also use the arabic
numbers you know
like three for example three or five
but however you also have it also has
its own
you know chinese characters characters
to represent one two three so
for example this character that is one
okay actually let me show you some other
thing okay so here is actually so here's
a chinese text from wikipedia
about this poem and you can see
you see here is uh two numbers okay
let's magnify okay
so look at this this this is a number it
means five okay
and here is another another number it
means 10.
so in chinese it has its own
number characters for number so
so these characters needs also belongs
to
the group numbers okay digits okay
uh similarly for arabics or indian you
know different
indian languages or you know many
languages has their or
or you know many languages has their own
digits you know they are specialized
digits so
when you deal with unicode you know all
the characters or
writing systems you know in unicode
that's what unicode is
you have to consider these things you
know so
so you have a group for numbers digits
then you also have a group
for um punctuations then you also have a
group
okay let me let me let me so unicode we
are talking about unicode so
we are talking about the classification
i mean the general idea the concept
everything about classification of
characters into
different groups you know we started to
talk about that because of the emacs
syntax table
so let me show you some some other
groups categories okay so
so you have letters so these are our
letters you know
in this case chinese letters also
including english alphabet
uh latin alphabet you know spanish
special characters
spanish french with carets and accent
science
german umlaut
things like that those are all letters
group then you have
digits group then you have punctuations
group for example you look at this
character
that's a chinese punctuation for period
okay
and here is the chinese punctuation for
karma okay
so they both also belong through the
punctuation group
in unicode okay then let me show you
other so
i want to show you other categories uh
okay so for example
sex you know sex symbols so what is this
this
so this is a character right and this
character
uh it's you know in unicode it's in
unicode therefore it also has a
classification so
what's this group it's it's symbols okay
uh and
and also you have emoji then then you
also have um
let me show you some of the characters
so it's for example uh
for example some of these some of these
crosses okay
some of these are ancient for example
these
uh and the and and chiro those you know
some of these are 2 000 years old uh
symbols and also the christian cross the
you know the greek cross and so on and
and you know israel sign
and so on so these are also um
uh uh
so there's a group to classify this okay
so i'm
actually the one i want to talk about is
there is a one called letter like
symbols okay anyway
you know you know the best thing i don't
have article for that
so the best thing is to search for
unicode
uh character classification okay
then you'll find you know there it is
uh a categorization of unicode
characters you know they
they talk about details how they assign
categories
so anyway so what i'm saying is that the
unicode cut you know that's
actually better kind of categorization
uh since i'm talking about these let me
show you some programming articles
related to it
okay so for example
so search for javascript in depth okay
that's my tutorial of javascript in
depth
and you can go to javascript reference
okay and go to uh javascript
regular expressions okay regular
expressions
then you want to so javascript regular
expression provides a way
for you for for you to use regular
expression to
match or list all characters that
belongs to a certain category
so how do you do that uh here okay
regular expression syntax
okay uh
character class okay so you have
character class
that's right
somewhere here okay let's search for
unicode
uh
yeah unicode property so it's called
unicode property
so so you can you know this is just a
javascript regular expression
syntax to match any
characters of a specific unicode
property the property is typically you
know property name
and property value so for example let me
let me show you an example okay
so for example and you know i already
have examples here so if you want to get
all punctuations you can do this okay
uh you know here so here's the full code
you can run so
okay let's let's do this one currency
symbols okay let's run it in e-max
so open it paste it here magnify
save it xx.js okay
so so you can see we have a string here
here's our string we want to
we want to grab all characters that's
considered a currency symbol
currency symbol is one of the unicode
category so you run the code
learn it encode syntax zero what
what the invalid regular expression
what
what what what this is bad
okay this means my tutorial is wrong
what
and called uh invalid property name
okay maybe it doesn't support
currency in my current um
in my in my um
in my demo you know i'm using deno as a
javascript engine
so i don't know what's going on actually
so this is bad so let's try this one so
get
letters okay so we have now
four characters here now
okay we i'm getting okay let's just run
it
unquote syntax error what's going on
they know
okay deno doesn't support
this feature is new you know this
feature is new in
um javascript 2018 deno should support
it by now uh
what's going on ah anyway
that's too bad okay let's try this let's
run this in browser then your work okay
so copy this okay let's go to browser
press f12 to show the javascript console
there it is magnify paste the code here
run it there it is okay
you see it shows it return value is two
dollar signs because that's
currency symbols so out of this string
you know we want to get the currency
symbols and that works
let's try some euro euro character okay
let's try some euro character
so let's try
okay so so how did i just do that
that is magic okay let me show you
okay that is that is the command star
input
change to symbol and that is in the
package some math input dot el so open
it
magnify magnify magnify so this is the
emac this package
where you can type all hundreds of
unicode
characters by using abbreviation for
example
all these triangles squares and
currency symbols and so on so if you
like it use it
okay it's on melpa okay so let's go back
uh wait open it
uh let's um i want to i want to go to my
talk show and
write a note about it okay so as a
documentation of what we talked about
okay
so save it let's go back okay so anyway
so
digression close that let's go back to
yeah
so now we type a euro copy the code
back to browser magnify paste the code
here
return enter so you see it got euro
so that's about unicode uh category
categorization of of um
uh characters okay now back to the emacs
least you know the emacs idiotic
um
uh uh where where do we go yeah the
let's go back to emacs yeah emacs
syntax table so so in my opinion emac
syntax table is
pretty lousy but however it's hard to
change because
it's very fundamental it sits in the
core
of emacs
so anyway that's here is a tutorial
about emacs syntax table so
back to where we what what we were doing
so we were doing
so close that uh so we we were doing uh
let's go back to our code okay
sweet okay so uh so let me read the
comments
uh uh yeah six i will give you a summary
of what's wrong with
unix and c
okay so let's go back to um
to the code okay so okay so what
what i was saying is that
did we try this yet okay so yeah let's
try it okay
we want to know if this bound of thing
at point
you know we tell it to grab the current
word under kusa
but we want to know what does it
consider a word
for example i know that digits sequence
of digits will consider as a word but
probably not the colon sign
you know in e-max syntax table it will
consider that as a punctuation
so it will not do that so we can try it
okay
eval the code now show
the message buffer then call the command
on these text okay my
i put the cursor here okay
you see it returns 41 which is
what not what we want so that means
you know because we want to grab the
whole thing so that means we need to
change
this boundary of thing at point okay so
instead of calling that we need to do it
manually so
let me show you how do you do it
manually okay
so so let's um
so let's um
okay so so so
okay we're gonna finish this and that's
it for today so today is just emac this
okay so how do you do this we want to
replace these lines of code
uh basically these lines of code we want
automatic
ultimately get the current word under
cursor okay yeah so what do you do that
let me show you okay uh save excursion
okay i'm gonna uh ignore that okay
look it up okay you see my emacs
tutorial so what
what what i want what i want to do is um
search backward okay
search backward by space okay
uh bounce no we don't care uh we don't
care search backward by space that
we'll move cruiser you know backward
until it finds a space then
forward charge okay i'm just going to do
this uh quickly
then set p1
point okay so so move the cursor
backward until it finds the
space and it will skip it okay
then then forward one character
then that's our beginning position okay
then
search forward and i'm going to do this
fast okay so
search for what we don't need that then
backward char uh
search search forward by rejects okay
research forward okay uh so it's either
a space
or a um actually i should use that okay
let's not do that let's just do that
a space or
all return okay line return
okay so space or line return okay so
let's let's do it
let's not worry about complex situations
okay
then search forward by that then
backwards character
one okay then set
p2 the point point is the
position of the current cursor position
which is a number okay uh integer okay
so that's it okay so that
so this this block gives us
the p1 and p2 beginning and end position
now we have that once we have that
everything is easy okay now we just do
this
uh grab our word okay
so instead of this instead of using the
bound of thing at point because it
have problems with the colon we manually
code it this way okay
then that that should be it okay so now
we evaluate the buffer
now we show the message buffer okay
now watch the end okay now we're gonna
call the command on this
uh part okay
okay so yeah i'm trying to
okay so call it do it
it worked no
no it also grabbed the example part
okay so we so what it grabbed is
this whole thing which is not what we
want okay so there's some
error here
this is a search regular expression
search for
space or
for simplicity let's just say space okay
oh oh oh
here is the what's wrong okay we got
this line we don't want
okay so again
about the buffer try it again call it do
it
nah now it grabs the
okay now it grabs the two right
parenthesis
okay what's going on uh space
or
ah let's just do simple ones search
forward okay
search forward by space okay comment
this up
okay we are assuming we're gonna have a
space here
sim okay let's you know so okay evaluate
the buffer
put the cruiser here call it do it there
we go
we got the you know 11.41
now why do i first about these things
before because because if you just have
for example if you just have that online
by itself there's no space afterward
you know turn on show space mod so
there's no space
then your code will not work that is why
i was
you know first thing about you know
tricking it so it works
well but for now let's not worry about
it turn off space okay
so let's continue okay so let's continue
so once we got
so so far so good so so far so good now
now let's go back to our code now we
don't need this anymore
delete it okay let's leave it okay
actually
leave it so other people can see what we
tried
so now we got the word now we want to
check if the word contains colon okay
if
string match
colon and our string is word
x okay so if that is true
then then we want to convert the mini
second format
to the to the seconds format otherwise
otherwise this code will work okay
otherwise run this
code okay so let's put that there okay
pretty fine
okay so for now so okay so now but what
if it's a
so how do you do that so so here we need
to convert mini second format to
two seconds to all seconds so let's code
fast let's just do this
so so split string
speedy string word x
let's see the documentation of split
string
it returns a
split string into substrings bounded by
match okay it returns the least i think
okay let's do this fast okay
uh let's just say this text okay
add a variable split string
set this x split string
separator oh yeah we need separators
okay
separators will be comma okay amid noise
uh don't no it's not we don't worry
about that
so put it here so first of all we split
string
then then we have two parts okay so
so the first element
so how do you get the element of
a at least the nth okay
nth zero
list x
okay let's use a let okay let
okay yeah
set
minute x equals to that
okay
then set
six seconds to
nth first element which is also the last
element
okay so we got minute a second then
then multiply
minute by 60 then add
so this is where the parenthesis
syntax is painful okay can you guys see
this okay
i guess now you can
okay so that's your total number of
seconds
then
okay then delete region p1 p2
then insert format
that okay i think that's uh that's it
yeah i don't know uh i don't i don't
know
for certain let's hope
shrink let's
uh let's remove this okay
okay now now that's uh that's our code
okay
let's hope it works evaluate now first
of all let's try working on the 17
to see the old behavior still works call
it
fantastic 110. now let's try this
1141 it should return 701
okay try it
oops wrong argument type number two or
mark p
here
oh yeah because remember we don't we
have the space problem so let's try it
over here okay
do it okay
uh number mark p wrong argument okay so
what's going on
wrong type argument number or mark 11.
undo
so what the split string returns okay so
we are almost done
yeah so it returns at least okay
so because it says there
so it returns the list what about nth
nth returns the nth element that's right
so minutes is the
the zeroth element so split string
let's let's just print okay let's
let's debug so these prints are debugged
so let's evaluate the code
show the message buffer call the command
on that so we got
minute 11 second 41 okay we got the
input correctly we
grabbed them correctly so something
wrong about
the output i mean something wrong after
that
so so far so good delete region p1 p2
it should be good then the format part
is
wrong okay i believe
run type argument number or marker 11
so 11 is the minute part
so oh yeah so so the minute part
that's right it needs to be a number but
however what we have here is a string
so we need to we forgot to convert
string to number
okay so here
we need we just need add string to
number okay
that's what we need to add
and same thing for here string two
number
okay then we don't need the comments
anymore do it
eva buffer
put a cursor on this over here
call the command do it fantastic
seven zero one
and let's call it again okay let's call
it again so that it convert back to
11 41. do it again
oh fantastic complete mission complete
now of course we can clean it up so we
we can cover situations where
when you have you know that by a line by
itself uh yeah
in fact i think this should work i don't
know let's just
call it do it no
it doesn't work so search for what let's
see if search for word
regular expression search for what i
don't know why that that's not working
but anyway we we have the
let's read the comments and maybe that's
it for today
get line get paragraph uh what are the
there
are there so dion says are there no
building functions for get what
yeah we okay you are late dion we
have we we talked about that before that
is
there are two you know if you you know
watch the video so there are two
building ways one is current word you
know the function named
current dash word
that gets you the current word under
cruiser and another way
is thing at point however
we cannot use those because we cannot
use current word because
two problems one we need the boundary
okay
we need the beginning position and end
position because we need to delete the
word
you know we we you know we not just only
need the word we also need the position
because then we need to delete them you
know replace it delete region
so we need the boundary therefore we
cannot use current word
now but we can use thing at point you
know
we we i you know we talked about this in
the beginning of the video thing at
point we we tried everything
thinking a point that gets you the
boundary but there's a problem about the
syntax table because it does
it does not consider colon
you know as part of a word so it will
only get 41 or only get 11 you know so
so we have to code our own manually okay
that's it for today
thank you uh yeah thank you guys um
well if you like my emacs tutorial you
can buy it you know support
sponsor me for my you know trouble
uh emacs tutorial you go there and uh
you know you can easily find my where
you where you pay
okay so buy my mac tutorial or you can
paypal me
amazon gift me or patreon
uh not no not uh yeah so um
okay so dion's question so not get what
okay
you know actually you you should look
you know
uh watch this video because we we we
spent like 10 minutes
on those the function name is let me
just type
it okay here's a function okay
current word that grabs the word under
cursor but however it doesn't give you
the boundary positions also it doesn't
deal with the colon sign
so we cannot use that the other thing
is thing at point okay so that's a
function name
so you can say thing at point what it
has the same problem with current word
and however if you want boundary what
you say is
bounds of thing at point okay that's a
function
and this version returns the boundary
but again it has a problem of not
getting the colon sign
so so you know actually i i talked
for 20 minutes about emac this syntax
table it has to do with emac this
syntax table and categorization of
letters okay that's it
thank you guys for watching so today's
opul emacs
uh bye guys yeah
oh 17 people so we have quite a lot of
people today okay so how long have i
been talking
yeah uh one hour okay shut down bye guys