check voice check video check
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
today we are going to do wolfram
language mathematica coding
fantastic and i'm going to code emac
this
i'm going to write a major mod for
wolfen language
you see this beautiful torus beautiful
uh so let's begin so uh head count
good morning box good morning
uh mining god bruce
and and good morning see strong crazy
and
celtic orthodox and uh
okay and okay so if you comment in
questions okay i love yours
see your comments comments get me
talking so we are going to do
female wufang language uh so first of
all and first of all i'm going to
tell you i'm going to code i'm going to
let's dive into
explore the realm of mathematics
parametric plot
okay surfaces i'm going to explain
parametric plot and
show you some great features of wolfram
language i discovered yesterday
you know i it's been a long time hiatus
i haven't been
really coded with language for 20 years
uh in the 1990s
i was one of the great expert of wufam
language
but thank you cortes
god bless you thank you cortes for the
donation
and so wufang language i haven't been
really you know in the 1990s i called
almo
every day you know for several hours i'm
a master of language but it's been 20
years and 20 years so much
has happened and you know wufam language
and
to this day back in 1990s wufam language
is the greatest language beyond them all
beyond them all
in the 1990s you don't have that much
okay the the most high level
highest level language is pearl pearl
that's it
uh uh yeah and but today
but today wufang language is still a
magnitude beyond
all languages moscow erlang
you know all the other fantasy languages
so you know has got a language you know
a magnitude beyond not just twice three
times the magnitude you know it's
highest level possible in fact like i
said before you know watch my
uh youtube about three or four months
ago i did some five videos on wolfram
language okay
i give you in depth many perspectives on
what is the wolfram language why is it
great
okay so why is it magnitude so one way
you can consider wolfen language to be
the
artificial intelligence language
building
like you know today google has a lot of
libraries right libraries for ai
you know tensor you know tensorflow
whatever crap
google you know oh they well they are
pretty good you know they they build the
you know google is uh the empire today
the empire on earth but
then but you have to be a programmer you
have to learn
you know neural networks whatever you
know you have to learn you
have to spend years to study all these
things in order to use to be able to use
the google's
you know ai library or image recognition
and so on
but in wufang language it's all built in
you can like
okay i'm not that's a digression into ai
but i'm
i'm just going to show you you know for
image recognition for example
is part of the building you just call a
function in wolfram language okay i'm
not going to go
over it anyway digression so i'm going
to show you some of the parametric plot
feature i discovered yesterday and let's
start with uh language okay and
so some some part of mathematics and uh
and uh about um uh you know uh
you know yesterday we did uh spheres so
part of mathematics and also
um yeah okay so let's
uh what is
parametric surface okay that's
what i'm going to explain today a part
of mathematics
mathematics okay then show
a feature of wolfram language
that plots parametric surface
can you see it uh magnify that that
plots parametric surface of a
specific region okay arbitrary region
why you know how does that work what
does that mean i'm going to explain okay
show a feature of wolfram language that
plots parametric surface
of a given
region of any shape okay that that's a
key
any shape because in g because normally
when you think of
a mathematician you know when they think
of parametric surface
you know you have a parent parametric uh
formula you know parametric equation
you think you you begin the domain you
know when you have a function you have
the domain range
domain is way the beginning uh where you
begin
range is the output okay so domain is
for parametric surface is usually a
square okay
a rectangle not not necessarily square
rectangle
but with wufram language this feature it
needs not be a rectangle it can be a
triangle
it can be a circle and it can be a
stripe it can be a circle with a hole it
can be arbitrary shape
that's the power of this feature i'm
going to show you okay
good morning we weenie mathematicians
love tora shaped pastries
yes indeed okay i'm going to show you
and
uh so what is parametric surface i'm
going to demonstrate using wufang
language and i'm going to
show you this particular feature of
language you're plotting
parametric surface of a given
arbitrary shaped domain okay then i'm
going to write
then it's emac this time you know i'm
i'm starting to do
a lot of uh language coding and i need i
need
you know to code it in inside emac list
write a emax major
mod for wufam language okay so soon we
are going to have
you will be able to download for free uh
you know work on wufang language and
before we
forgot let's uh let me mention you go to
my website wolfram languages for free
okay
they gave me a copy uh so um
so you know you go to some language
website and you go
you know there are several videos i did
these are great okay
i recommend you watch it for science
sake okay get yourself to know some
science and mathematics not just
programming the idiotic c
and unix crap okay good get to know
mathematics
and uh get to know found language you
give you a far more different
perspective than this
okay then at least well haskell okay
this man has got they are not
comparable at all okay so
watch these videos i give you several
perspectives on language
uh and there's more but i didn't put it
here but anyway here is the download of
language for free
you can get it free from if you buy a
raspberry pi
or you can download from engine or you
can download from script
with ram script is when you want to use
powershell for example i'm using
powershell here uh when you or
powershell or bash or tc
or z shot whatever shall fish shall you
know this unix crap
now if you want a shell scripting
language
that's a magnitude more powerful for
example you can construct
you know even skin shell you know skim
this has a shower called skin shock
it's a old news you know it's actually
it's been dead for like 10 years
but whatever shell wufam language has
wolfham script which is just like a
shell okay
so but instead of using bash or whatever
you use the wolfram language syntax to
to do sysadmin okay that's what wufang
script is you can download for free here
okay so that's about that okay so but
let's begin
the let's begin the talking of the
the mathematics okay so let me show you
a parametric surface
uh can you do this same thing in groups
no plot no
no gnu plot is the one of the worst
possible i don't mean exaggeration
okay let's remove the drama okay
let me say this group plot is one of the
truly one of the worst
plotting software for mathematics you
can you know
there are so many granule plot is one of
the worst not just
you know worst okay you know
you know the meaning of words in english
is the worst like you compare
all like there there are hundreds
literally hundreds of plating software
you know i have a website that
i talked about yesterday just go read my
website okay i should i talked about
there are literally hundreds of plotting
softwares you know
usually written many of them written by
university students
you know when they were young when you
when i was young i wrote a few
in language okay so there are many for
windows for mac okay
you you ca you compute you you if you
actually take time to study all of them
gnu plot is one of the worst
possible
scum you know in terms of
quality you know
if you are really if you care about the
design about the power
about permanent language design about
the elegance about whatever
about the the power what it can do gnu
plot is one of the worst
and and it so happens no it's not
no surprise to the unix people in the
linux
unix linux all the everyday
they say is group plot
glue plot sagemath
and the tech latte these idiots okay
so that's my opinion about gnu plot
just just buy go spend
you know 300 for if you want a student
version go just
you know depends on what you want what
really what do you want
in your life do you want to become a
professional
become a mathematician be become a great
programmer
is that what your goal is in life or you
rather prefer to
you know spread the open source uh
ideology like what you what what what is
it you want
if you think you for you to spreading
you know you know what gnu or ideology
of the free software foundation or open
source
yeah sure yeah go you know
or use linux use group plot spend every
day
hours on it uh first about nothing
you know a do much you do about nothing
that's you know
your time it's your choice if you truly
think oh yeah open source and you
you will not be thanked you are just a
minion
you are just a minion in a million
okay so avoid you know
you know let's hope to avoid swearing
because google is gonna you know
censor me or google is gonna you know
say my youtube you know a few days ago
last week or so that one of my youtube
is like
flagged this this video is not suitable
for advertisement
google okay i and that video is
nothing it's it's just about math or
something maybe i swear too much
okay so let's you help me avoid that
okay so so okay let's let's get on to
the main topic parametric plot so
uh so i want uh so what is parametric
surface okay
so so what is the parametric surface
this topic okay the
that's what i'm gonna show you so
parametric surface basically you have
three functions okay um
let's write it so uh we you know when i
write it down
uh you know it's slower for those of you
watching my video but however you it's
more coherent my whole video
if you watch offline you can you know
fast forward or you know
the speed of 1.5 something so parametric
surface
is a surface okay i don't need to
explain surface surface is just a
surface okay dude
i mean there you know if you go to very
technical mathematicians way this
surface is designed is a surface in
math is defined as a
how do they define it it's a um
yeah you know it's not that i mean i'm
not um
you know i haven't done math for a long
time but you go to some you know you go
to wikipedia and you'll you'll see the
official definition let's let's go to
okay uh
manifold okay let's say manifold so the
proper name the more
general name is manifold in mathematics
so you can see there it is uh
woofab this is a wikipedia okay and this
this a real projective plane this
surface is called boy surface okay
yeah so this this surface is you know i
have a page of it this surface is called
voice
boy surface and this image is actually
plotted in wufang language
this is pretty old this is like 20 years
old image
and and i would actually
presume this this surface is actually
from my website from my a professor you
know from
my i think i'm pretty sure they copied
you know you know that's what that's the
nature of uh wikipedia
they grab things on the web you know
they they don't have to copy my image
all they have to do is copy the formula
they plot it
using wufang language then you put it
they put it here then
this you know it's part of wikipedia but
anyway that
okay don't take my word for it but
anyway i mean this formula is public
you know where do we get it where did i
did i get it i got it from my professor
friend where did he get it he didn't
invent this one
he's a you know richard palace my friend
my mentor in mathematics is one of the
top differential geometer
in the past uh you know
50 years or so one of the top
differential geometers so
but anyway this surface is both surface
okay it's
it's uh you know you know wikipedia will
give you information about
who who is the guy boys okay
um anyway so digressions okay manifold
is a general name
for surfaces of any dimension in fact
in fact a curve is actually also a
manifold a curve
you know a plane curve is also a
manifold it's just a one dimension
uh one-dimensional manifold okay so
manifold is a general name for
surfaces uh can be any dimension so this
this surface for example we see that's a
two-dimensional manifold because it's a
you know a surface like a paper you know
it's two-dimensional x and y
but it can be three-dimensional thing it
can be a
four-dimensional so study math then
you'll know so
so well where do they define so one of
the important thing about surf
about manifold is that they must be uh
smooth
okay differential uh differential mana
um
okay let's read it okay in mathematics a
manifold is a topological space that
locally resembles
euclidean space near each point
you know that's a bit complicated way to
you know
if you haven't studied math you have no
idea what c is talking about
and it says more precisely an
n dimensional manifold or a manifold for
short
is a topological space with a property
that each point has a neighborhood that
is
homeopathic to an opus open subset of
n-dimensional
euclidean space okay that's kind of
mouth
mouthy uh too many words too many words
okay so what is the manifold manifold
is just a surface okay it's just a
surface a smooth one
okay one of the important criteria it
must be a smooth one
because in algebraic geometry you could
you can have surfaces that
that has kinks like like one sharp point
or
or self uh cringes you know those are
not considered manifold technically
those are called algebraic varieties
anyway digressions okay so surface but
so actually you know i'm not
um i'm not a professional mathematician
i'm barely uh
amateur so you know don't don't take my
words on math too much okay you need to
study
so anyway manifold okay we digressed uh
yeah so anyway let's let's go back so
parametric surface is a surface
that are defined by
three equations of
uh three three functions okay functions
of two variables okay
so that's basically what a surface is a
parametric surface
so what how do you define it so you say
it like that
traditionally you you you write it like
this okay
let's type it fast x y
z y z
f g let's say f one
then f two then f three okay
so you know in in three dimensional
space we have three coordinates
x y and z okay
then you have three functions okay
actually this is incorrect let me
correct it u
v okay
so x the value of x equals to a function
a function of two variables u and v
two parameters okay this function
returns one single number
and you assign this number to x okay
that's
that's the x component of the coordinate
and same thing for y and z so
so the thing you need to remember is
that
all these three functions f1 f2 f3 each
one
of them takes two variables u and v okay
and typically so what we say is that u
okay you i need to uh you
goes from let's say a or b a to b
a to b let's say uh 0 to 10
to be a concrete and same thing v goes
to 0 to 10.
so this is a domain so what does that
mean so
u and v are parameters you know just
like a function you know
for example let's say function x
you know if you want if you want a bunch
of values of this function
you need to give it you know many values
of x
let's say x from 0 to 10 you know 0
f 0 f 1 f 2 you know so on so you got a
bunch of values
so in here the parametric surface you
have three functions
f1 f2 f3 each one takes two parameters
and the two parameters
you know the u goes from zero to ten and
v
also goes from zero to ten or whatever
number okay
negative something to something okay so
essentially
so anyway so so you so you for
each value from 0 to 10 of u and v
you feed them into these three functions
and you get a point
x and right and y and z and you plot
that point
in in a three-dimensional space okay so
after you plot you know after you plot
all these infinite numbers zero
you know zero to ten zero one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
zero point one zero point two you know
everything
then you you got lots of uh xyz
points then they form a surface okay so
let's for example
uh let's
uh start to write an example okay let's
let's see so let's
so we have a example of a sphere of uh
you know let's the easiest simple
example is the
is the torus okay taurus is a very easy
to illustrate
so let's evaluate it okay let's evaluate
it so you got a torus
okay and let's uh let's do
let's do this okay
let me show you how how the parameters
forms okay i did this yesterday
okay so
r equals to three let's not use the
so i is three so let's magnify so you
can actually see better
so any comments common question sorry xr
no problem
uh what about about what sorry what
uh thanks our greetings from peru
jaguar donut
about donut what about it go for it
homie
uh coco points okay
whatever so let's let's let's get back
to the surface okay let's remove the
capital r
the variable we don't want the variable
and remove the lowercase r
because let's just say it's constant
okay
okay so there is our surface okay let's
now add some
uh so here is you
you see i have a service here so again
like for example let me show you what's
going on okay
so you can let me predify the code so
you can actually see
uh the syntax
you see like we talked about we we said
before a surface
is uh three functions right so there you
have it
three functions x you know the f1 f2
and f3 and they take two parameters u
and v okay u and v
so now we need to say you know the
domain
u goes from you know where to where v
goes from
uh what value to what value so that's
what these these two parts are
so here is u goes from zero to two pi
okay so let me just plot it so you can
see
okay so let's plot it here
so okay so that's uh that's a parametric
surface okay
but now what i want to do is that i want
to do a dynamic
visualization okay so this is another
great feature
you know this is a great feature of
wolfram language so
you instead of u2 two pi let's say u2
uh uh variable uh umax okay
and for v also we v goes from v
to v max and then okay so
watch the structure of these uh the
syntax okay so you have the parametric
plot here
then you have manipulate the first
argument is a you know whatever
expression the second argument
is gonna be umax from
let's say zero to uh let's say zero two
six
okay
copy it then we say the same thing
v max from v zero to six okay let's just
show it
okay we got the arrow okay let's i
uh probably a typo so
what's going on
uh one two six so what is zero
endpoint for you in that must have
distinct machine precision
values okay whatever let's
say 0.1
okay we have it so actually now let's uh
okay let's magnify so okay so let's um
shrink this a little bit so
now let's increase u so as we increase
you now this doesn't look so
good okay let me let me redo this so you
can see what's going on
because when you change the
you see why you see one of the question
is why is the graph kind of
jumping around you know why is the graph
jumping around
i don't want the whole frame to jump
around i just want to see the tube go
around you know
so the reason it's jumping around is
because
every time ufam language plots something
it shows you the best
choice of perspective you know how far
you are looking at the thing
so when you're you know when you're
whole
uh when your whole plot is just like
that
wolfram says that this is the best
percent perspective
but when you have more stuff you know
ufam says this is the best
perspective so in each frame it changes
you know the
the distance and angle you view the
thing so
what we want is we want to fix the
viewing angle okay so so we can do that
uh by an option in the parametric plot
okay so
uh so what is option i don't remember
let's see
uh let's see uh viewpoint okay so
there it is you view point
let's say front okay let's see what
happens so this is the option
okay that's still that's not good okay
uh
viewpoint we don't want front we want
uh let's say you know wufang suggests
several values let's say what is the
what is the range here so from
four to four
okay if we change this to one
okay now it's a fat doughnut fat
doughnut without a hole
close the whole
okay let's see let's change the two okay
this is good
so the value that you know so you can
see the axis
so it's about
five across okay so let's see where how
how far where do we want to view these
things so let's say
three three three okay let's say four
four four
four four four okay so view point
four four four you know that's a point
in space
okay that's no good okay
another okay now we have fixed viewpoint
but why is it still jiggling around
well that's it that is because
you know why is it still jiggling around
that is because
okay you have fixed viewpoint so
viewpoint doesn't change anymore but
however it's still jiggling around
because every time you plot
wufan language also automatically decide
you know by artificial intelligence it
figures out
the best plot range i mean the the best
how many how many how many how much
things you want to show
you know in a plot for example when you
don't have much things you only show
this part
it doesn't show the whole empty part
so we also want to fix the plot range
okay so let's fix it
plot range okay
okay so we need to type this this is a
tedious two type okay plot range
you need to specify x
arrange for x arrange for y and arrange
for z
okay so so x will be
negative 3 2 3 okay
and y will be negative 3
2 3 same thing and z will be
let's see negative one two one now let's
say negative two to two
okay okay so now we have a fixed
plot range you know don't don't
automatically decide for me i want
it fixed so let's do it okay now you see
a fixed box
even there's nothing it in it so now
now you can see what what
okay our viewing box is too small
okay you we are not seeing the whole
thing so let's uh
increase the range i mean increase the
plot range okay
so let's say four 4
negative 4 2 4 and
2 2 the z from negative 2 to 2 is good
enough
do it
there we have it fantastic let's
let's magnify this thing can we
yeah so you see there we have it
there we have it let's see let's see
that
that and that you see
fantastic now this
okay so so what's my point
okay so in the past five minutes i
showed the technicality of using
manipulate function in wufang language
so we
first about it we expand why viewpoint
changes and so on so we
now we got what we want okay so now we
got what we want basically
this and this and why are we showing
this because this
illustrates illustrates what is a
parametric
surface you know any basically any
parametric surface it goes like this
okay three functions
two variables uh
and uh okay okay but there's another
thing i wanna you know about wufang
language is because you see when you
manipulate it
it doesn't show the high resolution only
when you stop it
it shows the high resolution
so so how do i fix that
i don't know i have to look up the you
know the documentation for manipulate
but that's not important for today let's
worry about that you know i have to
worry about that
later so i have to read you know spend
half 20 minutes to read the
documentation you know for
for the manipulate function so that you
know
okay so so the point is you know
so this is about parametric surface
and the the one thing i really want to
tell you guys
is that the form you know this is about
mathematics
okay so parametric surface now remember
so u u and v has a range you know
u 0 2 10 0 to 10 so essentially u and v
they are just a rectangle okay imagine
your x the u axis okay 0 to 10
and the v axis 0 to 10. so u and v
actually they are just a patch of
rectangle on a plane okay
like this paper you know so this is u 0
to 10
and this is v 0 to 10 you know they are
actually just
a plane and these three functions
you know x y z of two variables
f one f two f three these three
functions
are taking essentially what they are
doing is that so this is a geometric
perspective they are taking points from
this plane this
rectangle they transform this rectangle
into a torus okay that's what they are
that's what happens okay that's what
that's what every all parametric surface
is about they are taking a rectangular
they are transforming a plane you know a
rectangle
into a you know into a surface okay
including this one yeah i believe that's
uh that you know
including this this surface including
you know
so yeah here you see here they show
the the the parametric formula for this
uh surface which you know again
each one has two variables you know in
this case it's a bit more complex
they they goes into the uh you know the
complex numbers
but essentially it's the same three
functions and two inputs u and v
in in the case here the u and v i
believe they are imaginary part of the
complex number and
the real part of the complex number is
it's the same thing okay
you can rewrite this formula in without
complex numbers
yeah i'm pretty sure yeah yeah the w is
a complex number so
so anyway so so that's
that's the first point i hope the
i hope i um you know i i hope that's a
good explanation
of parametric surface uh to any
people who are not you know who haven't
studied math that much
do i did i did i could did i do a good
job is it successful
okay that's one break now we can go on
to the next
topic so how long have i been talking oh
for 40
40 minutes almost 30 minutes okay let's
sip a drink
we are almost done okay actually so
so today's talk show we completed
explanation of a parametric surface
you know which is essentially
you know from technical point it's three
functions
each function takes two variables and
then you specify the the you know range
of the variable then you get a surface
that's a technicality
technical perspective the kind of the
essential the math perspective
is that it essentially transforms
a rectangular patch of plane
into into a surface okay
now the next time okay so that gives
that so so so so now
now we're gonna explain the next thing
okay
uh let's make this um
okay so now we are going to explain the
next thing so we explain the first thing
what is a parametric
trick surface the next thing is show a
feature of wufam language
that plots parametric surface of a given
region
of any shape not just a rectangular
patch
no more so that's the next thing
comments no comments comments
okay actually so before we do anything
let's um
i need to show some spectacular image on
the on
on my screen so that google can pick it
up
so actually this is the one i'm going to
show okay so let's go back to woofing
language
save it and let's paste it here
and look at this spectacular
image
now now what are you looking at let me
explain okay
you see before we did this whole
parametric formula thing you know we we
did the whole
uh tube donut thing okay so you can see
as we vary the parameters you know it
generates the donut okay
complete donut okay not complete because
because our maximal value is six
now if we change it to uh pi which is
two pi so one pi is three point one four
one four five six okay so two pi
is uh six point uh two eight
okay six point two eight something like
that or i can just type two pi
okay two pi okay so
so that's uh u u
max okay now v max is also 2 pi let's do
it
so now if we do this and
if we do this you can see
if we close this up you get a complete
torus okay complete it
okay you can actually play animation
this is a fantastic feature of wolfen
language
and while it plays you can let's say
let's say go back and forth okay
while it plays you can rotate it wait
can you
yeah you can what wait stop
i cannot rotate it i don't know if
that's because
i'm limited to one cpu or something but
i think
i'm not sure normally if you can rotate
it while it's doing it
i it should yeah i think it's
uh let's let's check let's check my gpu
usage
do i have enough juice if my
machine is powerful enough yeah my
machine is
powerful enough but
okay stop stop this and also also
let's rotate both of them together
okay but stop let's change your
perspective okay
okay that's enough of that let's uh go
on next
am i still a mess your life check
video check voice check good
okay so what is the
okay so now the next thing
okay so so yeah watch this carefully
okay i'm gonna explain
what you mean by arbitrary shape domain
okay so you see
it's a regular rectangular patch and
match
you know so you can observe the shape
of these things so you see
so when you plot so for example you can
have that
you know this is what you get
essentially it's a
warping whopping a rectangular patch
but now look at this torus this this one
is is not like that completely different
you see
this the the equation is exactly the
same okay for example let's copy the
equation here
let's copy it okay
then let's select this part
delete it and paste it you see
the equation is exactly the same but
however
you get this thing why because
we are no longer doing a rectangular
patch
you know you've you know u from zero to
something v
from zero to something that forms a
rectangle but but this time
we are saying the u and v are here okay
let me clean up the
the syntax here so you can see what's
going on
okay so so so this is uh
you know i cleaned up the syntax so you
see
the u and v here is different here
instead
here the u and v are actually just
inside a circle disk okay
that's that's what that's that's how you
get this
you and we are inside the circle
okay so i think that's it that's it for
that uh
now instead of this can we try something
else
let's see you know we can try a triangle
you know actually we can let's see
you know it's not it's not so
interesting though
because uh you know why don't we do
something else i think
yeah why don't we you know next time
when i found some other interesting
feature i mean the point i want to make
about this is that you can use
you can do parametric plot in language
however it has the feature where
the domain the input parameters needs
not just to be a rectangular patch it
you can specify
any region any shape triangle circle or
any
even even whatever lake you know
shape and in order and to do that
all you have to say is this part okay
let me show you this part element u v
so this function you know this element u
v
says that u and v is inside this disk
this disk is centered on zero zero and
uh with the radius of three
okay so if we increase the radius it's
going to plot more so essentially it
competes
so if we decrease the radius let's say
two
you know then you get this you know
you get this thing so so that's a
that's an interesting part now there's
another thing interesting you see
the patches on this uh on this
on this torus is no longer rectangular
you see
over here the patches are rectangular
but here it's not i can tell you why
it's not okay
so and i can tell you how do you
implement this function
okay now do you know how to now you
should be able to know if you are a
programmer okay you guys
python or whatever javascript you should
be able to implement a parametric plot
you know not not using gnu cloud you can
actually implement yourself
you can uh yeah you can use the
javascript and svg
yes you can implement yourself
you know just just you know like i
explained if you
paid attention just just do a you know
just compute a bunch of u and v
then feed them to the three functions
then you got a point
okay once you got lots of points in
space
you need to connect them you need to
connect connect
connect them in forming uh into polygons
you know like
like like like here okay how you connect
them that's easy because
okay let me explain how you do how you
implement this
normal parametric uh plot okay
so you basically again you start with a
rectangular patch okay here's you
and here's v so you draw a grid not grid
but
lattice point you you know so u from 0
to 10 like 0 1 2 3 4 and v same thing
so you got lots of points points on the
grid okay
so this squared essentially is kind of a
matrix or nested
list okay nested array or whatever
depending on your language
so you got a bunch of bunch of
two-dimensional points
okay then you map these
three functions x y z okay uh do i make
it clear here
you know you map this function
you know this these three function f one
f
two f2 f3 into this bunch of 2d
coordinates
then what you get is a bunch of
you got the result is a nested list
of three dimensional coordinates you
know points
in 3d now so essentially you got
a the same structure you know nested
list or matrix depending on how you
view it so you got the same structure
but now each point is now
three-dimensional point then
then you have to plot it okay then you
have to you know you got these data
points of the servers how do you show
actually show it as a service well that
that's when you need to draw okay okay
that's um
that's when you need to know some linear
algebra
you you know three yeah um okay so
basically essentially you need to
project
your three-dimensional points into a
two-dimensional plane so you can
actually see it
that's what we are that's what we are
seeing so you see this taurus is in
three-dimensional space
but but this but my screen is only
two-dimensional but how do we see it but
you know we project it just like camera
okay
just like a camera so anyway that's how
you implement this thing
now in the case if you if you begin with
a arbitrary region that's not
rectangular
then our previous method
doesn't work anymore because
it's not just a grid it's not you know
just u and v
uh rectangular grid
now you just have like arbitrary shape
you cannot you know it's not a nested
metric how do you do it
so essentially what you do is you
generate a lot of random
points inside that um
that region you know you can do you know
you generate a random point and check if
that's inside the region
so if the region is a circle that's very
easy
you can easily check if a point is
inside the circle or not let's just use
a circle as an example
so you you you generate a bunch of
random points and check if they are
inside the region if they are cubit
okay so what you end up with
is a bunch of points inside the region
then
then the next step is that you want to
triangulate
this bunch of points uh
to form a mesh okay two-dimensional mesh
and when you after you do this you get a
structure like a matrix structure
where each triangle is three points
um okay so so anyway the high level
thing is that you just
start with the random points okay bunch
of random points inside the region
then you um triangulate them you you
you know you need the algorithm to given
a bunch of random points how do you
triangulate them that is connect you
know nearby points by
by by a line so you have a bunch of
triangles like that
once you have that then again it's very
simple
all you have to do is just map these
three functions to that structure you
know like the map
function in python and so on but but the
map in python and javascript they cannot
do that because they are idiotic
they can only do simple list
one-dimensional list
when you when your list is nested
necessary matrix
the typical python golan pearl
whatever this industrial language crap
including cc plus plus c sharp java
they fail because their notion of this
is
typically array flat flat
they don't have you know function
instrument to work on to map to
you know the leafs of a matrix or the
atoms of them in the matrix
or any arbitrary nested list
so that's another power of wolfen
language which allows you to
do that so we are talking about
implementing
this uh parametric plot of uh of a given
region okay
you don't have to i mean it's building
in language but
you know if you are curious that's how
you implement it
okay so now
i need to take a break so i talked for
50 minutes now so the next thing
i'm going to do is to write
a uh emax major mod for wufam language
okay
so let's uh so so we've done the first
two parts the next part
is write a
write a e max major mod for wufam
language okay let's do that
okay let's do that uh but give me a
minute break okay
any comments comment comments guys
i got money fantastic money
that that's you know those those live
donations
are my primary income from youtube
you know you know about maybe 20 a month
and mostly from the live donations thank
you guys
the ads they don't you know they don't
give me nothing
okay now let's get serious let's
let's do emac list coding emac this
coding to write a wolfram language
major mod for wufam language why do i
need to do that because
the woofam notebook despite all the
great features you know it lacks one
thing
it's not it's not very
at you know for example emacs and vim
are known for their power of
manipulating text
you can like move to arbitrary positions
very fast you can delete certain
specific part of the text very fast
but in the wolfram notebook they don't
you know you i cannot do that you have
to
essentially type everything sequentially
it's a pin
uh so maybe as you know possibly
sometime in the future possibly i can
help i can have full fun research
at that feature so wufang lang you know
from notebook is going to be
soft like he's notebook i don't know
yeah so but anyway so for now
since i code uh language a lot i want
you know i want to write
i want to create a major mod so i can
just type everything fast
with completions with templates for all
the functions for example it's very
tedious
you see you type you have to type the
whole thing you know what
you know next time i can just type p
p parametric plot pp3 means parametric
plot 3d
space it'll complete the whole thing
so that's what i'm doing going to do
okay let's go to let's begin let's
let's begin let's not talk too much okay
so you go to my emacs tutorial how emac
this how to write a major mod okay this
section
covers everything for beginners so you
you can start to write a major mod so
that's what we are going to do
based on my own tutorial so let's begin
so what what what are we so uh so
write a major mod for language okay so
where do we begin
so first of all i need to go to my git
directory
so you are seeing my git home directory
and let's hide the details so you can
see
uh you know a bunch of my packages all
my emac list
packages create a directory so create a
directory this
gonna be called xsa
wolfram lan mod okay
so here is the directory we just created
okay so is that right yeah sound family
mod
open it empty okay now we're gonna
create a new buffer
okay save it as kasawufan
mod.ell okay go to the directory there
it is
okay open it uh then we start to code
saufen language mod okay so first of all
let's just copy the whole thing here
you know this is my tutorial how to
write the major mod okay so
no no comments so i need to do this
quick um okay so i guess no comment then
it's just
uh myself then okay so then i'm just
going to do this
um okay so wu fam land mod
uh major mod for editing wufang language
okay
now in order to do this uh it's best
if i look at my actually microsoft like
keys
mod because so you see
this is microsoft like his major mod
well actually let's look at my emac this
mod
because that's more similar so
describe key space space space e
so you can see here is my emac
this mod source code open it
okay uh hold on a second so
let's close the uh looks are this one
let's close
the
right okay so
okay so this is my emac be smart copy it
close it paste it here
okay so we're gonna
modify basic essentially starting by
copying my image smart okay
so first of all rename so whenever there
it says emacly smart change
to firmland mod okay first of all
okay then language mod a major mod so
delete the that
language in my major mod for editing
emac that's right
so also let's shrink it a bit
um
okay so date 2001 uh by
sardis and blah blah blah version
fantastic version
version 1.0 something okay 1.0 let's say
zero
create date
okay package requires package requires
emacs 23
24. yeah 24 okay it's good enough
this language is keyword list languages
who farmland okay
and mathematica okay
license gpl
you know they they they do me uh not so
good
let's remove it for now i'll decide what
license probably free you know probably
open source but i'm but i don't want to
you know i don't
want to give it to the free software
foundation they're being harmful
uh home page okay i don't have a home
page here yet
uh okay let's let's just say that okay
the file is not part of google emacs the
the
new emacs template okay let's keep it
commentary major mod so let's
let's let's start the code okay let's
remove this bunch of
crap let's worry about them later
so first of all define the you know let
me let's get to the interesting parts
writing a major mod okay requires least
smart do i require this mod
not really okay anyway let's
um so i'm starting to write the mod you
see
right now there's a lot of things here
uh
and what i want to do is actually just
tell you the interesting parts
instead of me tediously going through
the whole
so the first let me tell you what we
need to do first okay we
first of all we need to generate the six
thousand building function names in
wufang language okay let's do that first
okay
we may not be able to finish this mod
but that's the beginning that's the
beginning okay so first of all
generate um let's see all
seven okay let's see let's
uh let's you know fan notebook is just
like oak mod you can have title and
subheadings and so on
so style subtitle
o2 chapter subtitle
what i want to do uh subsection
oh six okay subsection o six
g e i t e o
u fam land keywords okay function names
okay so the way you do that is you can
just type question mark
asterisk okay so
then my god you gotta get a whole bunch
of things okay this is huge
so this is about six thousand uh wufang
language keywords i need to put it in
emac list
okay so
but before we be before we are able to
do that
let's um before we are able to do that
let's delete it let's
we need to find out what the full syntax
for question mark okay i want to
find out the full syntax for question
mark
okay
okay so it's not i remember it's in for
something okay
so let's show all functions starting
with i
and f
okay so i believe that's a function
information
information expression gives information
about expression okay
so so what i'm saying is that the
question mark name
for example let me show you okay
so this syntax question mark some name
display the help you know the help
documentation for that
for that function okay but what is the
question mark that's
that's just a syntax right but however
in language remember it's a
it has a syntactical uh layer system
systematic so everything has a function
named full version okay so
what is the full syntax the full
function name for the question mark
shortcut that is information okay for
example let me show you
you see that is that one so for example
now we can do
instead of instead of question mark
parametric plot 3d
we can say information
then bracket then
then then a string
okay parametric plot 3d this is the full
syntax
you see this is the the actual
the the the code standard standard form
of the of this uh question mark
shorthand in
language okay so now
now we got information now i need to
look up the
what exactly the information returns
you know for for example we showed
before
you know if you just type that it
returns uh you know all the 6000
function names
but however i need them to output in a
string form
in a you know string not not the pretty
display
table column and stuff so that i can
once i got the stream form i can copy it
to uh
emac emacs so but in order to know
how to do that i need to know the
details of the information you know here
so the help that returns that tells me
uh what
what uh what what what it returns how do
i control it okay
so let's see six people
okay so information give information
okay detail information
expression properties gives a list of
available problems okay pattern
something something
uh the special input from that you see
we talked about question mark symbol
name heights information other than the
usage okay
so for simple input the following
properties may be included okay
attribute we don't care about that
okay let me let me just try something
okay uh let me because
because if i try to explain everything
we are never finished so my goal right
now is to get all the
6000 functions in language in a string
form so i can copy two frame language
i mean so i can copy to emac this for
example if i copy this
i'm not sure what you get so let's try
so open a new buffer
paste it okay so you got this
you know formatted thing so let's so
let's see
let's change it to raw control shift
r now
you cannot really do that
and
yeah so it it generates a kind of a
formatted way
so any way i want to see
[Music]
okay that's short so
so what is the output the output
so how do you control the output
so okay i have to read this a little bit
in detail okay
for simple inputs the following
properties may be
included okay values
options supported data objects
expression type includes okay
uh supported system object expression
types includes
okay supported machine learning object
expression types includes okay
so you see some of the machine learning
functions
in language okay so
information information display just the
usage message
uh get the attributes for sign okay get
information about specific
data being okay so
there is there it is let's see names
gives a list of names of symbols that
match the string
okay i think so that's a better function
let's use that
names
that's what we want okay this is what we
want instead of the
fancier info so now we just say names
a string asterisk that returns
all wufang languages
symbols okay building functions okay
so now we can see how many are there
okay so let's go to the top
let's go to the top
and wait wait is it not going to the top
okay
okay so you have to this let's just
press the up
so names so let's say length okay
there it is so as a wufang language
what what version do i have as a wufang
language
wufang desktop about
from desktop i don't want to show it
because it might show my license numbers
and so on
but i'm on latest i'm on the version 12
or something
but anyway as of this year or last year
there are 78 building functions in
language and in language everything is
just a function okay so there's
you can you can consider that it's all
you know wolfram language does
everything is a function there's no
special
anyway anyway so so we have um
okay so let's write this into a file so
let's
uh see let's see if this works
text okay let's just do it there it is
fantastic it's done where is it written
too
is it desktop
now i don't know where is it written too
it might be
written to in some wolfram home
directory so
okay so let's try this again in a
different uh
let's try this again
here because this notebook is already
saved so it should save to the current
directory i believe so do it
now go to desktop refresh
okay i don't know where is that file
returned too so let's forget about that
you know we actually we can look up we
can look up
um what
i started some feature about
about with python integration oh my god
python not js sql
sql jb jdbc julia julia r
ruby well hey wait
i pressed some key by mistake and i got
this
so does that mean i can
um i'm running python let's see let's
try some python syntax
p three plus four
start start external session for help
configuring the python evaluator c
configure python for each external
evaluator okay
so there's a python integration and and
a bunch of others
python not js sql
and julia julia is a great language okay
and our i is no good ruby is pretty good
okay so interesting so anyway i i what i
want is
actually this so let's copy that
so now back to emacs
let's go back to what is this untitled
close
yeah wufang language mod okay so
so let's um
define var uh let's let's not require
this mod okay let's let's
ampersand was functions okay delete that
okay open a new buffer paste it here
so here are the all the wolfram language
keywords okay now
now i want to make them each one by a
line by itself so
replace quote comma
by
quote return quote do it
okay there you have it so there are
seven
there are seven thousand something okay
and also this thing is wufam language's
way
to continue align so let's delete that
okay good so 7000 so
and
fantastic okay and we don't need these
characters so
we delete that you know there's a lot of
these characters
so we delete that actually
delete that okay delete that
okay do you eat that okay so a
also deleted that because okay a is not
actually building uh
okay so now we have a list of
all fan language uh keywords
okay let's go to the bottom and then you
have a bunch of dollar sign ones okay
let's keep it
okay now copy the whole thing
so we change them into a list okay
so now you see some of them has a
comma trading comma after it some of
them does not
all of them should have one okay so
in order to fix this all we have to do
is
find and replace is your friend
you know the reason some of them don't
have the karma is because i did it by
mistake
you know before when we replace the
slash or backslash okay there you are
there we have it
so here now we have the 7000 functions
of wufang language
we want to basically copy the whole
thing
and paste it here as a list you see here
is a list
because it is functions so this should
be changed
to
frame functions okay
so list of wolverine language okay
this is the wolfram language functions
okay let's delete that that that that
that that okay move a list of wufam
language functions
then here is the real list let's delete
them
with let's
that and let's paste here
the whole thing here paste
then remove the the bracket
okay let's eat that
what
yeah so there it is
so we defined the function okay this is
kind of
long yeah you know big ass long function
i mean i mean very many lines okay
that's
so we are writing the major mod for
wolfram language let's continue
so what else do i need i don't need this
i don't need this
i don't need this it's
no need no need no need
no need no need delete
map atoms whatever delete
delete so
so we have completion code for
completion i don't know
let's worry about those later okay now
let's
shrink so i can so i can
so you can see what are we doing
here so basically dd all these functions
now a brief i want okay a brief
saw fan landmark a brief table that's
what
we want abbreviation because the brief
gives give us
function templates
oh finally bob says someone says
something but
don't even bother running python it's
almost as hard as getting an
audience with the
you know python is the most one of the
most popular language today
because of google
okay so a brief we want but we need to
rewrite all these
briefs okay so so let's
you see you see this thing uh let me
show you okay so
you see so you you see each one of this
line
they are for emac bisp so when so this
function for example we are x
expand to you know the full syntax of
that function
so this is very useful and
i'm you know i'm going to do this for
film language as well
so you actually need to find the
templates
of you know the the function you use
frequently you want to agree for
so for example in e magnesium if i type
c
it expands to concat you know if i type
d
it expand to different now these single
letter abbreviations are
the most used uh functions in imacbs
so you know i for insert so we are going
to do similar for wufan language but for
now let's do
them so okay so also delete that
so we just want you know we start with
the basic template
then emac this command name
command face delete okay faces we don't
care
emac this symbol let's forget so this
this are about defining the font
you know color color of the font syntax
coloring they define special
format of the keywords for
my emac be smart so i don't need them
you know i might add them for wufang
language later on but
wait what did i do delete okay
this we want so
because it is font like words yeah so
font log so first of all
change your e elites for to wolfram
yeah so change or emac these to
wolfram land
okay yeah
what okay i did a lot of changes
okay so anyway the package now
uh you know i hope to get to a state we
can
reach a state where i can actually start
a package
show you some of the most simple um
you know show you it actually works
so uh but okay so in order to do this
i'm
under heavy pressure my my friends
okay so so let's define a simple a brief
okay let's say
pp three okay pp3 will stand for
parametric plot
3d you know like the way we used today
why why we have another eddy sphere
let's see
oh yeah change change okay
change change okay
so
so okay so actually this is so
parametric plot so pp3 is parametric
plot3d
then we need a we need to
have the template for parametric plot 3d
so okay i'm gonna show you how to write
that
i'm gonna write here right here so um
parametric plot 3d
sign let's say let's say this okay
let's say f1 okay f1
f2
f3 so we have again we have
three functions why is it not
so we have three functions then we need
two
parameters u
a b okay
u mean umax okay let's just say a b
um okay so that that's that's the
beginning that's the beginning of the
template this
okay copy that so so put
here then remove that then we need the
cruiser
let's put where do we want to put the
cursor i don't know
let's say here okay then you
this part you don't need okay so that's
it
that's it for these briefs so we have
two of briefs
pp3 stand for parametric plot 3d
it will expand to that then parametric
plot 3d will expand to
you know with arguments template
okay then whatever whatever that
okay so this is getting long
i need to work on this wolfram language
brief table
okay so so this those are specific
details about
a brief then
syntax color related so this is how
syntax curling works
yeah so um so actually you don't need
that dollar symbol add symbol
uh cap boss okay i
don't want that uh okay
so then ampersand words
no we don't we don't need that then what
is this fulfillment function
that we want okay so that we want
this no this
macro no commands no
use options okay use options
no okay i need to just to get it
to work now okay so i'm just gonna code
this quickly
front lock building face what is this
okay you need that
clean pretty fine
pretty fine pretty fine
pretty fine okay so that's that now
syntax table
syntax table oh my god the syntax
table
syntax table um subwoofer
lan mod syntax table okay
what syntax table should i want um
you know i know that
um
let's have none okay none of none of
this
you don't need anything next you know no
special syntax table
so syntax table make syntax table okay
no no inheritance okay
not going to be based on
so wufam language syntax table is just
a syntax table based on fundamental mod
meaning there's no special thing
uh because wufang language is you know
rather different from
the syntax is rather different from all
the industrial languages
uh then key binding okay key mining is
important
very important but we have we worry
about that later okay
so tab for completion yeah we want
actually we want that
but actually we don't have uh did we we
don't actually have a function to do
completion
uh yeah but we need to so
so i need to write that function
completion
um but okay let's comment that for now
let's not
worry about these too much because i you
know i do this later
right now right now my only one goal
let's say
is just to create a wolfram language mod
so that when you show a wolfram language
source code it will syntax color or
building functions okay
let's just say that and also let's say a
brief
abbreviated template these
just these features features nothing
else okay
so woofam lan add paren around symbol no
preview the expression yeah we need that
but um
okay but but but it's coming out
remove parent pair okay um
yeah we need that competitor okay so and
and
uh from land complete symbol yeah we
also need that okay
but for now nothing
so i menu okay i menu i i don't i don't
want no eye menu
what is i menu the eye menu is the e-max
thing
when did i add i menu to my emac this
mod
i don't
i don't think i i don't remember i did
because i don't use it
so anyway deleted no i mean i menu crap
auto load okay there is the here's the
main part
of the mod defining the actual mod okay
so auto load define derived mod
yeah based on programming mod okay
then wolfen land
okay so let's let's let's make them um
let's make them a little a bit short
major mod for
ufam language okay okay
okay so so this documentation let's
ignore for now okay
documentation ignore
okay then from front lock defaults yes
we want that
yes yes uh comment starts
comments there's no such thing i mean
i mean the in language the comment is
nothing
it's it's like it's it's like a
haskell's okay there's a matched
parenthesis
pascal actually it's the same thing uses
a pascal
comment so yeah so that's a good idea so
i can actually
borrow the you know the syntax table for
pascal
language mod when we
uh when we work on this
uh so common delete so i menu i don't
want a menu
so indeed line function yeah
yeah god yeah what are those
no no
so what what is this so when calling
emacs complete single follow convention
we press tab dupe subway yeah
yeah let's worry about this later okay
i don't know what is that make local
variable
okay
oh god uh
display page breaker slide no
pretty symbols at least no
version
yeah okay okay group
at least total mod okay wolfen language
mod is
um
dot m okay also
dot mb okay let's see that
okay so that's the end
now now let me show you the structure
okay so the
so so the structure of what we have so
far
of this source code from language mod
major mod for emac these
for wolfram language so the first you
know the first
7 000 lines uh
are basically uh language um
you know the the keywords okay
so let me show you here okay so
paste it here you see 7000 lines now i'm
going to compact this
i want to i don't want one single thing
you know
yeah this is what i want i want to
compact them
so that you know so that you don't have
to scroll 7000
lines to see you know so now it's just
20 000 lines okay
um yeah so make sure the syntax is
correct
now can we actually evaluate this make
it into a list let's see
yeah so the syntax is correct so okay
cut it then just
paste it here then you don't need
this font anymore okay yeah
so let me show you the structure of the
the source code so far
so we have you know the first
you know this is a long found language
okay so the first two thousand lines
is als or what language keywords okay
and they are named wolfram language
functions okay let's search for that
okay so copy then
a brief we we define
a brief table variable then we define
what is this yeah then we
okay then we define yeah we define
basically two abbreviations okay
then we have uh overall mr boob table
uh then enable function yeah we need
that
enable function okay because without
this won't work so let's let's get
back to my xr emac this mod to retrieve
that function
so here is our elise a brief
enable function we need that okay
so this function
okay so so so that's a function
let's put it here and uh
let's copy the wolfram you know instead
of the elis
say wolf and then okay
okay so we have that function good
now next syntax curling related
let wolfram font lock mod okay that's
good
then rejects up to from functions
okay example fam land functions it's not
found
let's go to the top why is not
oh so okay so
instead of wolfram now we have wolfram
land that's uh inconsistency
so yeah so change oh fam land to wolfen
basically essentially okay so
copy that
okay let's uh find and replace wolfram
land
change to wolfram
not that not that yeah
do that do that to that
do that do that do that
no
okay actually
okay so actually
okay so let's rename all ufam land
just to woofan so rename the package
now instead of someone from landmark
just say woofer
mod okay so because because otherwise
our functions are
all too long it might be it's simpler
just to have
you know simpler simpler is good
instead of woofam landmark just saw
woofen mod
okay so do we have any more
woofam land
yeah yeah oh okay so this okay yeah
so good so yeah wolf um yeah because
woofer has many products who from alpha
wolfen land
language wolfram mathematics you know so
it makes sense to have you know some of
them for all fam
stuff kind of you know it it's
good enough
where i where so gula gulemon says where
can i find your
extension what extension you know you
mean the woofer mod i have not put on
the github yet
hello jack hello jack jack i need to
talk to you i need to go to the chinese
video i need to start to do it i mean i
know i talked about that long time but
okay you know yes you know
i i'm gonna contact you okay from uh
from
wechat you know help me
out on that
okay so so this is getting long
no i talked for how long so
this video is one hour and
40 minutes almost yeah but we did we are
doing a lot of things
so so essentially this major mod is done
let's look at one more time okay so
so the first
will find functions let's search for
that yeah so
that's good yeah so
the first 2000 lines
is basically your list of wufam language
function names okay
there are seven thousands of them then
someone from a brief enable function uh
yes we need that that's for abbreviation
then
then we'll find mod a brief table we
need that
okay this is for abbreviation
okay so this is a brief part you know
then we're gonna add right now we just
have two upgrades
we're gonna add like about probably a
hundred
later on um then you know and probably
probably not seven thousand of them
because this is
7000 functions it will be nice though
but i don't know
then syntax color related
okay so this part is syntax coloring
then
syntax table yes this part we also we do
actually need um
okay so let's let's test something i
want to go to fundamental mod
so in fundamental mod if i have does
this uh oh
uh let's see
text mod uh
okay so actually i need to um
back to in back took side emac this mod
so actually i need to add some syntax
table for the
double quote so that they become strings
you know they become highlighted as
string so how do you do that
go back to emacs tutorial writing a
major mod
then you go to um
sync syntax table okay
syntax table is very painful to work
in in emacs emacs syntax table is a
pretty bad idea so how do you add a
syntax table for
um for quotes
you know double quote as the
as the
[Music]
double quote as the you know the
delimiter
for a string i i i don't know i'm trying
let's go to javascript mod so
cheat and copy and paste okay so
let's look at my javascript mod okay
actually let's look at
css mod because it's easier here
let's see syntax table
what where is syntax table oh there it
is okay
so you want
so syntax table
what is a string for syntax table yeah
string denominator double double quote
okay i i guess it's here
no it's not
wait why is that
what
okay quote should be already let's
ignore it for now
so now again so syntax table let's
ignore it
and key binding we also ignore it for
now
define prefix command
when mod map or from leader map
okay we'll find leader map define prefix
command
and we'll find mod map okay that's good
and then then we have the main
definition
define derived mod okay so we'll find
mod
okay based on programming mod okay good
enough
uh and the the the
short name will be let's say capital w
and let's say lowercase or
lowercase okay and
it's capital capital okay so major map
for wufan language and
then double check make local variable
okay
what is this do we have it
cause i will find expand a brief
we need that okay we cannot find it
yeah so we need that function so look
let's look at the
xr emacly smart to find that
function
okay there it is search for it there it
is
copy it okay
so this is
expanded brief expand the symbol before
cursor
okay so this we need copy that
and we need to go back to the
brief section and paste it there
okay paste it here yeah and
also change the name
from elise to ufam okay so now we have
the function defined
let's change the version date
okay okay got that yes
now a bit more turn it on now
if version is less than e max 25
make local variable and so on yeah
that's uh
i mean i do separator okay okay
okay okay okay
okay i think that's it that's that's the
woofah language mod the draft version
now my hope is that if i run it
then try it it will work okay my style
of coding
no no trial and error one shot
and also i don't like you know let's
let's remove the
let's remove the you know this
this line
those are the
control form feed
those are invisible control characters
called form feed
used in emac this source code to
indicate a
section in source code but that's uh
30 years ago convention you know because
nobody use invisible characters
control characters in their source code
anymore you just
use visible ascii so let's remove those
you know it's displayed as a line
because you know because of
emacs i have special things to make this
display
align but this is actually you know the
ascii character called form feed okay
ascii code point 12.
okay so remove so remove that
paste that instead okay so actually
yeah okay so
so do we have another form feed no okay
so
save it
turn off that what is this close that
don't save turn off that
so now we just have two windows
let's make it another window okay
so this is the mod so this is uh this is
this is it so
evaluated fan
error wrong type argument
stream p u from uuid
okay so we have some syntax error here
what
wrong type of argument backslash okay
there's some backslash here
arrow
what
i think there's a a missing coma or
something
okay i don't know so
let's evaluate this and let's see what's
going
on it works so why is it
evaluate both a wrong type argument
stream p
slash comma
okay so i think i we got a
empty comma oh i forgot you know in
emac this
you don't use comma to separate values
in a list
okay so let's copy that and let's
do some surgery so
okay so first first thing we do is to
make all these into single lines okay
so replace that
by that okay okay
then we're gonna replace
comma you know we're gonna replace
double quote comma return
by double quote
return no comma okay do it do it do it
all
fantastic now make it into
[Music]
okay so what
make it into a
yeah so that's what we want so fantastic
now
copy it close that
paste it here delete the rest
okay fantastic
so now shrink evaluate this
evaluate this fantastic now evaluate the
whole buffer
fantastic check the
error messages check the error message
the error
the messages buffer is there any error
there is no error
okay so oh we closed it by mistake okay
so fantastic now it's working now make a
backup just in case we up
fantastic now we have a wufam language
mod now it's time to do unit testing
okay so create a file
let's copy some woofing language syntax
okay let's see
let's see let's see let's see
where is my beautiful uh curves okay
here
so let's copy this you know this
language source code
go back to emacs paste it save it
xx dot m okay m is
woofing languages package
by convention wufam language
source code uh filename enzyme.m
and if it's a notebook it ends in dot mb
okay so go to diode so you can see we
have this file this
is a test file let's let's rename it
test okay
okay so wait so so you can see
so we have two files okay so let's open
the test
dot m so now we are going to
oh wait syntax coloring didn't work you
see we are already in wolfram mod you
see at the bottom
full fan mod but syntax scaling didn't
work
let's debug but let's try something else
let's see
pp3 now if i press space it should
expand to parametric plot 3d do it
fantastic it's
now if i press again it should expand to
a template
with the arguments do it fantastic
okay we are almost done now there's a
little error okay so you can see
symbols function is void because i will
find ahf okay i can i can fix that
quickly
let's uh let's go open let's uh yeah
open
um let's open another
emacs window so we can actually so let's
go to
xa emac this mod let's fix the
um a hf
thing so copy that
okay so do that so now let's go to ufam
language mod
okay so let's go to from language mod in
a brief section
okay which is here then paste
here then change the ellipse to
frame that's good
okay so that's good that's good
so that fixed one problem now the other
problem is syntax coloring so why is
syntax currently not working
uh let's see
syntax coloring okay syntax coloring
not working ways uh
i'm getting tired
okay syntax curling that's uh that's
called funtification in emacs
so so where is it so
it's okay
so function names then then abbrev
okay then curling related okay
so here
some wolfram functions for somehow they
are not
rejects out
okay i don't know why is the
it's it's not i don't want this
complex
okay now evaluate the buffer
oh one type of argument wait
don't type argument this p for log
function name
face okay so
okay so actually yeah
this is pretty uh okay let's look at my
tutorial emac this tutorial
let's look at the
syntax table major mod naming
writing a major mod syntax hurling font
lock mod
now there's a special structure when you
define
uh let me explain okay so you see
you see this set cue front lock font
lock
defaults the value is basically at least
a nested list that list essentially
tells emacs how to syntax color the
buffer okay
now however that this needs to have a
special
structure uh and i think
what i have done is i up the
structure somehow
uh wait wait
that should work why is it evaluate
okay no error let's go to messages
evaluate
no error now go to this
close it reopen no
color what what the let's search
for parametric let's let's do a string
okay string is colored
string is colored fantastic but what but
why is the parametric 3d not
colored
you know building function should be
colored also the
the word element and also the word disk
i mean here and also the word directive
you know the word plot points max
recursion and so on
so so um
uh so okay so let's i don't know so
okay so before we do anything let's just
quit emacs
you know we this today is two hours talk
quit emacs and restart maybe everything
will be better
you know it's like when you have problem
just go to sleep when you wake up
everything will be better
so much for one shot
but i'm close you know the the it is
fantastic guys look
what one shot now synax current is back
it's not working because you know the
variable is messed up because i did
multiple
evaluations you know so now
welcome to the xa emacs this mod
okay there's something else wrong you
see this smart line
it says object c like what the
what
close go to the
okay let's magnify okay so
go to settings let's magnify the font so
because otherwise you cannot see
[Music]
16 evaluate okay that's better
close that okay now
now close that okay wufang language okay
now open the test close it open the test
again
what what the objective c
on one hand it's showing objective c on
the other hand it's
it colored all the wolfram language
keywords
wait only some of them
what the is such a objective c
now let's open the wolfram language mod
we haven't evaluated this buffer yet
so let's evaluate the buffer
okay now go to test open
okay now it's woofing mod
yeah it's not coloring so is there any
error
okay
oh okay so you can see we reached a
limitation
of emac lisp you see error doing this
error during redisplay jitlock function
one
signaled invalid rejects
regular expression too big
regular expression too big my friends
that means our wolfram language you know
the
000 you know the 7 000 functions
is too big for emacs to handle
what the so one solution
immediately is to split
to split the you know the
these these 1000 functions okay let's
let's just split split into into
two then make then do two rejects okay
so
that's what i'm going to do so let's do
it
okay so let's show you wolfram um
[Music]
now i've been sitting coding and talking
for two hours now
oh my drink is dry
but what you doing watching my videos
all day i mean
it's late for you
uh don't you go to work
woofam dollar sign okay so so um
dollar names okay dollar names
from dollar names okay so delete that
what what
okay actually i it up
what
oh i up some
parents i think
okay so said wolfham dollar names
that okay that that
then cut that okay
that that that
that
okay so we got mistake
yeah so
okay so i split part of the you know
seven thousand into dollar names then
i don't think that's enough still
okay let's split again
okay let's do this quickly yeah
god i'm just gonna do it okay
[Music]
so
okay so there are six thousand seven
hundred
so half of that is three thousand
and four hundred okay so let's go to
three thousand four hundred let's say
four thousand okay
so after four thousand then
then n start a new one okay
so nakamaka
distribution so let's do this copy copy
copy do it here
paste it here okay
so these will find functions two okay
functions two okay
then that's going to be everything
starting with
with n okay so
n to z okay
so there it is
paste it so you can see what we're doing
so we split
the wolfram functions into two
okay so functions let's rename it to
one okay
no no no one
okay let's see then copy this line
copy functions2
then another one dollar
dollar names
okay so so you see
here who find functions one two and
dollar names okay
i'm getting tired so now make a backup
evaluate the whole thing check the error
messages buffer is there any error no
error fantastic
and now go to diet go to the open the
test page
close it open the test page again
nothing
no colors no you know it's not
color syntax colored so
look at error pages ah
emacs limitation error
regular expression too big
okay so four thousand functions is still
too big what
what the
i remember it should be able to handle
it let's go to emac this
i mean let's go to my emac be smart how
many
how many function i have in my emac this
mod
so i do remember i also have to
split it but it is functions okay let's
copy it
new buffer okay only fourteen thousand
i mean one thousand four hundred
okay so in emac this we reached a
regular expression error
uh talking about something like too many
regular expression uh
expression too big
we can i you know i'm pretty sure we can
solve the problem by splitting again so
let's try
try one more time split the functions
into
into into more okay what is this
okay close that okay i'm just going to
do this quickly okay make a backup first
then uh these functions one
okay functions one two okay
[Music]
okay okay first of all
new buffer make it into a
okay so where do we so wait where is the
middle
so 1096 so about 500
of them so e
so let's split
so d and e okay let's split d and e
okay so now shrink
let's go back let's go back to the mod
we need to split d and e okay
function one function two okay
function one
function two
in function three okay let's say let's
get the structure right first
function two function three
functions 4 and set
okay
okay that's what you need then set
okay that's what you need function three
four and the function two actually
needs to be moved to function three
okay paste it here and the function one
needs to split starting with uh
e okay earth so search for
earth there it is so starting from here
to here okay cut
then
there function two then function three
function three also needs to be splitted
okay now where do we split let's see
close that
new buffer now copy the
copy the function three
copy back to here paste
let's see so there are a total of 740 so
about 400 or 300 oh
there's only 740 now now it's simpler
740 emax can handle it we don't need to
do anything
close that okay so
wait i don't think so yes because
700 lines but each line has
five names
so that's gonna be three thousand
something okay so better to split it so
let's split it okay
okay i'm getting hot and i'm getting
tired
and uh okay so
there's a comment let me read it okay so
this
700 lines so let's go to 400.
so 400 um
s okay
so let's start with s shall we
ah ah
okay right here
there it is okay so we split into two
now the first part so start with same
text
same test that's the third one
i mean that's a third you know the
fourth one start with same test so
search for
same cue not same test
what search
same cue okay here
so starting that go down
cut okay then put it
in this number four list okay
okay i'm gonna i'm tired
evaluate the buffer go to the error
message
no error good make a backup
close it open our test file
close the test file open it again
[Laughter]
beautiful now we see some of the
functions are now colored some of them
still
not and i suppose the same error
regular expression too long
you know so we are seeing the limitation
of emacs regular expression too long now
so parametric 3d is not coded so it's
it's you know so we can find out where
that function is but basic basically we
solved our problem you know regular
expression too long okay let's
see the comments tanner says sci looks
like
you need to add performance score
quality to your code to parametric
plus 3d inside the manipulate to not get
the ugly effects
oh okay so let's see thank you for that
are you a so you are a mathematica coder
so we have an expert giving me opinions
on
on on this now so saves me time
from you know uh half an hour reading of
this so let's try that
so he says you need to add performance
score quality
okay fantastic now i believe that's a
option
in manipulate yeah so let's
um yeah so let's
let's uh so that here
performance score okay
he anyway something wrong
wait why is that not allow me
spinning arrow
you know i'm you know it's it's probably
a spinning error but i'm
usually i do take the pen to actually
check
why is it it's not spreading error
i i have no idea why is it doing that
but okay so let's just continue
that's strange you know you should we
should look into
performance score okay uh then
then quality okay
do it
wait why is it yeah no it's an option
two parametric
that's why okay so cut it
so plot range there it is
do it do it
do it
okay but oh fantastic
thank you so that solves the problem
yes so that that thank you very much
okay so i think we done today that's
more than two hours
uh long talk today so we did so
summarize and you know
we closed down in two minutes in a
minute so we did
we did a lot of things actually today
although it's long but it's rather
fairly condensed and we
let's go to talk show okay let's review
what they've done
so today we talked about
what is parametric surface from a math
point of view you know about math what
is a parametric surface and in summary
is it is a transformation
from a rectangular patch rectangular
you know plant two to a surface okay
by by these three functions and we
also showed uh demonstrated a wolfram
language feature
where where it can plot parametric
surface of any region
not just a rectangular region but any
circle
or circle with hole or any irregular
lake
shape any shape and we also talked about
how do you actually implement such a
parametric plot function you know the
normal one or with any
region you know we explain that how to
do it
you know if you are interested you know
if you are into
discrete geometry computational geometry
you know if you are young and trying to
learn something you know you so you can
try to code it in javascript or python
to create your own parametric plot
then we we the last one hour we
wrote a emac this
you know in emac this we wrote a major
mod
to uh to code wufang language
so we as we kept show we have uh
you know
parametric plot 3d okay we have
completion
you know we have you know abbreviation
we have syntax coloring
we still have some bugs to fix because
the
regular expression too long problem in
at least
okay that's it
okay uh yeah paste so you know
youtube does not allow you to paste
links
so you have to find some other ways uh
try to munch your url or something okay
so or
you can join this code you know we have
a discord so
anyway thank you guys for watching
oh okay so um well
okay so you know uh custom nice front
end you know i
i i yeah if you can you know
if you cannot paste it that's okay so
thank you
guys for watching uh if you like my
stuff of course donate
patreon me paypal me you can see the
link
on my website you know it's not hard to
find
or buy my emac this tutorial or
javascript tutorial
thank you guys bye
uh today today is like 90 minutes
concurrent viewers now so eight people
watching so today we talked
for it's the longest ever yeah so it's
the longest i
ever ever done two hours and 18 minutes
okay bye