good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of xl talk
show
so today i'm going to code javascript
and yeah i'm going to code javascript
related to keyboard layout
graphics
so if you have comments comments okay i
love to see your comments
and uh yeah i'm going to call javas uh
code javascript
uh you know
let's just uh go through let's see what
i'm going to do
javascript i'm going to talk about
javascript yeah i'm going to you know
live coding so this is something i have
to do for my website
so let me begin by showing you
okay let's show you uh today's talk show
page
uh what am i what do i have to do
so first of all so if you go to my
website you'll see
you know just search for saudi keyboard
and click on layout you will see
these um let's let's let's do
a second
keyboard okay so go to my keyboard blog
hello break the loop uh
so you go to my keyboard blog then you
click
on layout
so and you can see so these are articles
about keyboard layouts
so for example you have let me turn on
javascript here
so you can have uh so here
is the layout for quality
and you can see the heat map so i can
click on vorax
here's a layout for rack and you can see
the heat map so
e is the most used so you can see for
borac
most frequently used keys are on the
home rule
and back to quality uh
so and and there are many other uh you
know layouts
so here is call mac comac dh and so on
so this is one of the
this is written in javascript and this
image
is svg so you can see it's svg because i
can select
you know the text it's not a bitmap
image
so that's one of the javascript projects
you know
a minor one i did to you know
a keyboard layout diagram
for all these uh different layouts
but it's not perfect so there are quite
a few things to do
so for example so this so this is one of
them let me show you some other ones
okay so this is one of them
you click on layout then you go down
uh then you click on character frequency
plotter
so here is where you type for example
delete now
i start to type something
and you can start to see the
frequency of the occurrence
of each letters so this is interactive
you know so you can see t and e is
used most frequently so far
and if you are a programmer you can get
the data you know
or you can copy for example it let's go
to emacs
so i copy the whole buffer go back to
the browser
click here select all paste and you can
see
you know you so you can you can see the
frequency for those characters
so you can copy and paste any
programming source code
haskell java javascript c
python or whatever language you program
so you can see actually
you know which character occurs more
often in in those languages
this is especially interesting if you
if you are studying keyboard layout for
programmers
in fact i have a special um
i have a special page on that i mean
basically you want to know
which punctuation character such as less
than
greater than or dollar sign or
double quote or parenthesis are most
often used in which programming language
for example underscore uh yeah i have
article on that you can just search for
it somewhere here
yeah computer character so here is a
you know computer language character
frequency
so anyway uh
and you know when you look at this chart
for example they focus
on the punctuations so this is a
combination of
basically most popular languages you can
see
underscore is the most frequently used
character
and followed by parenthesis this is
combination of
c c plus plus java javascript
uh perl bash html
css you know and python and ruby you
know combination of them
and you can see the distribution for
each language for example here's
javascript
where equal sign apparently is the most
uh
most often used punctuation symbol
character in javascript
different projects they may have
different styles so for example
we have three different javascript
projects so this one
parenthesis comes second then the period
and for this one p parenthesis comes you
know
seventh place but the period is second
so you can see
the equal sign and the parenthesis i
mean the equal sign in the
dot is the most frequently used in
in javascript but actually parenthesis
as well because in in another project
so then you have a combined
anyway so this is javascript then you
can see java
patterns for java frequency then go lan
then c plus plus you know in c plus plus
you can see that underscore
or low line in unicode this character is
called lower line which is a better name
it's most often used and also in c
and php of course is a dollar sign
because every variable starts with the
dollar sign
and in python also underscore because
they prefer
underscore you know snake case
and ruby underscore again so underscore
is
everywhere then pearl dollar sign in
bash okay so
uh so these are the frequencies
of uh punctuation characters for
programming languages
okay so you can see so so far we have
two projects okay so let me go back to
uh let me let me show you another second
so copy the url open a new buffer paste
it here
and pick you know paste it there and let
me let's go back
to uh
to this one okay so let me show you so
right now so i have two
javascript code one is for the
illustration of the diagram
the layout and one is the character
frequency which is dynamic
now so so these are already written
so but what is it that i want to do i
want to make some changes okay to
make them better let me read the
comments looks like
benford law okay so did you program the
character frequency part what do you use
uh well i use uh uh
you know so yeah so it's asking
uh what you know it's written in
javascript
and it output svg in both of these uh
both of these the the the layout diagram
and also the character frequency
and which library i use let me show you
that one okay
wanna i need to be dramatic
so look at these uh comics whoa
which plugin have you used to do this
thing
none so this is my that is that is my
javascript
style i don't use none of the libraries
it's all
plain javascript no not one single
library from
from from npm or wherever so anyway so
and i'm gonna you know i can i can show
you that's what i'm going to do
today i you know you and you are going
to see the code i'm going to show you so
by the way i have a so you know you guys
may know i have a
javascript in-depth tutorial i i spent
two years
to code this javascript in depth
yeah two years basically full time so uh
if you like my stuff
you know my style of explanation and the
tutorial by it okay so you have
javascript
and javascript references you know the
global object
the you know infinity you know that's
the javascript reference
and all the methods for example all the
methods
for array
you know so you have array prototype
reconstructor prototype is arrayed from
of then if you click on prototype you
see all the
array methods so you have javascript
script in depth that's a tutorial in
depth then
you know you have reference for your if
you are daily code of javascript that's
useful
then the most important thing is storm
because if you are using javascript to
program the web
basically the most the time you spend
the most is with the dom
so what do i do with them you know so
there are lots of libraries for example
angular react view and
thousands you know quite a few five more
others that's very popular
i don't use any of them so i
and uh i you know i prefer to use the
raw
technology and it's not too complex okay
i teach you the the raw things how you
know so you can actually write
you can write a react yourself you can
write your own
you know framework so anyway so so you
have javascript in depth tutorial
object reference storm uh but you
also have also have svg so you click on
that
webdav tutorial you you also see a
complete tutorial for svg
so this tutorial will show you for
example let's see
something more fun so you can write this
clock
with javascript and here's a code you
know not many code
only 100 lines of code and
you know you don't need any libraries so
in the same way that's how these
how these are programmed and it's not
it's not hot okay
um yeah so okay so anyway
i have these two projects you know this
layout diagram
and this um frequency chart
i'm going to show you the code but first
of all let me tell you what
what is it i need to uh code what what
is it i need to change
um uh okay so let me let me
start to explain okay so let's shrink we
don't need it to be in that
big okay okay so so if you click on
layout let me show you some
uh characters so this article is talking
about what's the most frequent
uh what's the most efficient keyboard
layout you know you have so many today
and and even today people are still
adding more
you know creating inventing new layouts
like
uh yesterday on my excel discord
i learned about this speaker layout okay
so
it's a new layer so actually i should
focus you know maybe
i should actually focus on you know the
code in javascript
because if i uh ramble
on different things so this so by the
way this is a big layout and they have
reasons for they
for why they designed it this way this
is new
you know in the past few years past four
years
the be code layout and i don't have it
in my
blog so i want to add them so anyway so
uh yeah let's focus on javascript that's
the main thing
so so what what is it i want to program
today so for example look at this page
what's the most efficient keyboard
layout you know people want to know is
it
vorac is it cormac uh why do you agree
why do you disagree or is it bicol
is it capwell xeno and you know walkman
and norm norman and quite a few others
so i this article i explained and it
includes
a chart you know this is my essay
talking about
why you know which layout
in my opinion is the most efficient what
does it mean
how do you determine you know how do you
measure what you know
and my criticism of existing studies
so that's this article what's the most
efficient keyboard layout
and i also include the graph here now
this is a bitmap
image okay so let's open it this is a
bitmap
image from uh this is actually data from
google
and this chart is from
from peter norvig okay peter novick is
a very old you know this guy peter
novik he's a very old common lisper
he's a bisp programming language pioneer
he's also a artificial intelligence
pioneer
so if you uh being around in 1980s or
1990s
he is essentially the most you know the
top most
expert on lisp and artificial
intelligence
you know he has written commonly books
uh or
books on on list called ai in this
something like that
you know those are pretty old 30 years
old books now
so anyway he wrote a blog you know he
wrote a blog
and he's working for google uh you know
in in 2013 i'm not i don't know now but
anyway
so he wrote a blog using google's data
showing you
bi-grams diagrams is a sequence of two
letters that occurs in writing so that's
called bigram
and diagrams are very important when you
want to study the efficiency of keyboard
layout
okay so i got this chart from his dia
from his blog let's show his blog
because you know i
let's give credit to people so he has
got this
article english letter frequency counts
mine's revisited you know miser is
apparently a very famous
uh measurement of you know layout study
i mean
uh letter frequency studies if you don't
know later frequency is critically
important
in crypto analysis you know crypton
decryption you know
uh like sending your credit card to
amazon
you need a lot a lot of uh encryption
decryption technology
and when you do that um
you need you know uh frequency you you
need the static
statistics for of
a letter frequency of you know so you
can actually
you know if you got a secret message
let's say from your
enemy in world war ii or in world war
three you want to decrypt it
and the letter frequency is a very
important information
you you know then you know you might be
able to
know oh this this secret message is
written in english or
in in german language or in french and
so on
so letter frequency that's very
important
for encrypted analysis and also for
uh keyboard layouts you know when you
study keyboard layout
why because you want to uh you know yeah
i think you get what i mean
uh comments more comments how do you
update a graph in real time okay let me
let's go let's start to talk about
javascript so anyway one of
so this image is a bitmap image
so what i want to do is one of the
things i want to do is
want i want to write a javascript uh
application
to generally generate this myself
so i don't have so so this will become
dynamic i don't have to rely on
you know his graph
i can just let me hold on a second
i can just for example
generate it dynamically so you
so you know as i type then then you'll
see
you know the chart of diagrams
so that would be fantastic that's that's
what i
one of the thing i want to do and when
you measure when you study this
you might as well including ink to
include trigrams which is
a sequence of three letters this is not
difficult to do
so in order to code this there are two
parts
basically one is a program
that you know gets a bunch of text and
return return the percentage count of
diagram you know bigrams or trigrams
which is this part is very easy
i think most of you can probably do it
in any language
in your favorite language so that's one
part
of the job the other part is to generate
the svg
graphics now that will be a bit
more difficult because you need to know
the svg technology
okay svg basics so for example here is a
my tutorial is you know here's how you
generate a line
here is how you generate a rectangle you
know you just use javascript to generate
this tag you know this rec
x equals to equals to 0 where the
rectangle starts you know
so this is svg technology you just use
javascript to generate
generate this in a browser then you'll
show
for example this rectangle will become
you know is used to draw the bar
so this is one of the projects to you to
write a javascript
app to generate diagram dynamically
okay so two parts one is to just you
know
given a bunch of text you want to
generate the
frequency count by percentage of
diagrams
the other part is to you know given a
percentage of the diagrams you want to
generate the bar graph
two parts okay now the other question
you know the other kind of aspect is how
do you do it dynamically
so it's different because you can do it
statically you know so you just you know
so you have a bunch of text input then
you have a chart
you know you press draw it then you have
a chart but how do you do it
dynamically as you type that's also very
easy
if you know javascript in particular
what you need to know is
doom okay so let's go back to my
javascript tutorial
uh you can you go you you click on
javascript then you click on doom
uh you know if you call javascript you
know what i mean but basically you have
to learn
about doom events so i have article
intro to event based programming so what
does that mean so that means
whenever user type types you know type a
key
presser keystroke that's one event and
javascript will
be able to know and you know
and call a function so essentially what
happens is that whenever
a keystroke happens javascript knows and
we'll redraw
the whole thing so like i
i type something that's one event
javascript there's a function
corresponding to that event
you code you know you put in javascript
then your you know for example if i keep
typing e
uh if i type period period we
you know will uh so you know event if
that's that's why it's called event
based programming
that's um that technology is part of
dome okay so and i have several examples
um
let's see
uh let me just show you some um
some interesting ones okay uh
web scripting example
image rollover so image robert is
you know you see that very commonly by
the way
you can do this with cs css you don't
need javascript so but i want to show
you something interesting okay hold on a
second
uh
so you have digital clock so that's a
digital clock
and here's a code you know that's how
you do it very easy
you also do you also use the event
okay so then you have a stopwatch
start stop
and here's a code you know less than 100
lines
but i want to show you and then you have
fade
a element you see unfade so all these
are
plain javascript technology with dom
you don't need any library uh i want to
show you one more thing okay how to
create a tooltip so then then
also you have two tips you know you
mouse hoover and your shows
and two tips is used
uh in this project very useful project
okay not this one saw unicorn search
so for example food cooking
uh pancakes
uh let's see pizza where's pizza
pizza is rich man's food
pizza so you got you know that's that's
how two tips are useful oh unicode
uh so i mean i mean all javascript
you know you can use javascript to do
that this
involves javascript dom and css and html
technology to create
two tips and i show you how to do it
here you know 100 lines
uh then let me show you another
application let me show you another
just another one okay
okay this one falling snow you might you
have seen this
uh this is also pure javascript dom
and css you don't need any libraries
a hundred lines okay 150 lines or so
so that's uh that's javascript and
that's how that's about javascript how
do
that's about how do you use javascript
to compute the statistics then also use
javascript to generate
svg for the chart then you also use
javascript
to have interactivity so that as user
types
you get the chart updated which is
uh you see it everywhere in stock
in stack overflow in in in stocks
stock chat chart you know they update in
real time in lots of places
uh okay so um
so actually i should uh i've been
talking actually for
quite a while now 33 minutes oh my god
i haven't begin okay so i actually
uh i went now i'm i'm
i talked a lot but i haven't started to
code yet
um and now i fear that i cannot
i won't be able to actually code this in
in 30 minutes
well okay if i cannot do it that's fine
okay that's that's better
don't worry i don't i shouldn't worry
too much about it
uh let's go back okay hold on a second
let me go back
to
yeah god yeah
where is my diagram oh here
okay um hold on a second okay uh
open a new win new tab
so that article is about most efficient
keyboard layout
and i want to write a javascript to to
to do this uh
diagram and
okay so that's and there are more okay
so actually there are more i want to
now i need to think about where am i
going um
okay so here is another project okay so
you can see
this is another project of things i need
to update
so you can see in this article it's
talking about
motron layout versus vorack keyboard
layout
you know i'm talking about which one is
better
and in this article i have a
illustration of character
frequency and this is using my code
you know this is using my javascript
code there
but however on this page it's just
a static image you can see you know it's
not
dynamic so one of the thing miner
i want to i need to do is that i need to
[Music]
modify this code so it became some kind
of
module so i can use in
different pages for example in this page
you know motron versus vorack i can
simply
include the code not just the screenshot
of the image of an image result
i should be able to include the you know
javascript module code so that this page
is generated on the fly and
possibly also allow people to start to
type and change it so that's
so that's the second project i need to
do so the first one is remember the
uh where's the so you know the first
project is remember to
create a diagram uh in javascript
then the second project is to modify my
code so that this becomes
a module so anyway and there are more
okay so there are more
well the other one is okay let me talk
about the other one the other one is to
modify this diagram
so that so that this program showing the
keyboard
layout heat map is combined with this
character frequency
so that you can as you type it will show
you
the keyboard layout heat map plus
the character frequency
then you can choose to hide one one or
the other
so yeah that basically that's what i
need to do i need to write more
javascript for my website so they become
better for all these okay so let me
let's start to look at javascript code
let's see
which one we are going to do and let me
read the comments
uh how do you update so just start and
you can continue in another stream okay
yeah okay so
so yeah good okay so
so let's yeah so i guess you guys want
to start to look at the code so which
one should we
yeah every time i begin to code live
i have a fear you know then i i started
to get
kind of nervous because because people
are watching
me code live and coding live is not
so easy because
uh because you know you have to talk
and and understand your code at the same
time you cannot
stop and uh you know think you know look
for what for half a second because that
gets boring
because peop you know people are just
gonna stare at your
screen and not knowing what's going on
and also you have to anyway
so so where are we going so
uh so okay let me let me just go
with the flow okay so you are looking at
so this page you are looking at is the
source code
for these um you know for these
these uh this layout
heat map okay so it requires
two javascript code here
again no libraries it just takes these
two library to
javascript code so let's look at the
first one okay so
actually yeah so let's look at the first
one
okay so the first one is actually kind
of a library okay
so you can see first of all i define
a bunch of uh
quality tool map so all these are kind
of nested
a nested uh array or hash table
a map actually yeah hash table in
javascript
a diction a dictionary or hash table is
called map
just like java you know different
languages
they use different terms so you know
perl and ruby calls it hash table
python calls it dictionary
java and javascript calls it
map map is new in javascript
around 2016 which is different from
object
object is also kind of a hash
table but map is kind of better
and uh okay so anyway so so
so first of all i define you know a
bunch of
hash tables or dictionary that maps
qwerty keys to vorack then to cormac
then to comac dh then to walkman you
know different
uh layout then to asset layout normal
layout so these
are the key maps
then you define
okay then here you define the letter
frequency
for example let's see you know how do i
know
for example how do i know e is the most
used frequently used where do you get
that
well you get that by pre-computing from
statistics from you know
from corpus so you pre-compute that
then you then here's a result so
so for example here is the letter
frequency
for english language then you have this
map
so in english language e the letter e
is used like 12 t is 96
uh nine percent a is seven percent and
so on
and for p in p
is kind of a chinese input system so if
you use
ping p is based on uh
english alphabet so you use your you
know standard
uh qwerty keyboard to type in
so if you type chinese with ping then
you have this frequency
i is 11 n is 10
and so on and for the french
language you know so here's french is
you know
so you again you have that percentage
so you see i started to add these kind
of
statistics so that eventually you know
you should be able to choose not just
for different layout but you should
be able to choose you know your language
german english french
you know any any language that based on
uh latin
alphabet so i started to add that's why
you see this
then you also then you have um
okay yeah so this this code needs
some cleanup so so this part you are
seeing
is um
source text so
basically this part is the stat
statistics
from from a great
a great short fiction called uh
i have it somewhere here on my website
but
but uh where is it
let me show you okay let me just talk
random we don't i don't
you know if i um
let me show you okay uh keyboard layout
so let's drag that here then you go
down to
correct layout ah let's go to french
okay let's
go to something interesting so go down
uh
you know let's keep this interesting
german let's see german okay
so here's a german layout again here's
another project
i need to do so you see this image right
now is bitmap
i i need to code this into svg
with javascript so that eventually i
should have a system
that that shows the layout
and the the heat map
and also the character frequency
and also choice of different layouts
and choice of languages and also
choice of different uh languages layout
for example
german you know it's not trivial to
simply add this right now because
well i it takes some more explanation
the reason
it's not trivial right now because the
way
i did this
anyway let's skip that so let's see so
i'm gonna so i'm gonna continue
explaining the javascript okay
uh notes vo llc
says is it over where overthinking on my
part oftentimes if i have any populated
maps such as this i would generate a map
using some config file
well yeah that's so he's saying
yeah well that's my minor coding style
and
stuff issue that right now i'm not
concerned
anyway so because the data is pretty
small
so anyway and they are in js they are
basically
well if you do that i mean let me
explain okay another
this is uh there's an interesting
question from from from nutsveo's
question
so he's saying why don't you just use
jason you know why don't you use
json let me let me explain that okay so
why don't you just use json
to as us data for this uh
quality to other layout key map you know
why don't you use json there there are a
few problems first of all
json is invented 15 years ago around
okay 2004 json becomes very popular and
becomes actually the standard
even beyond javascript so what is json
json is basically
javascript the javascript script
syntax for any nested
array or hat or hash table object okay
javascript object an array nested in
arbitrary ways
that's what json is
okay i i need to show you my so you go
to my javascript in depth
and where is my javascript depth
so you click on javascript language
reference
uh object reference then you go down
so there's a json object
uh then you can learn everything about
json so what you are looking at here
is json okay that's so essentially it's
a
mix of nested javascript array
or object for example this part is
object and this part is array for
example
anyway so so that's what json is so what
but
so the question is i mean why don't you
use json for this data well
the problem is so why why do you want to
use json because json is more
common and interoperable between
different languages
almost every language supports it but
why don't i use it because
if you use json json is created created
15 years ago
at that time java does not have a proper
map hash you know the proper hash table
map data type object okay so let me show
you
um what is the map
data type so you go here uh
javascript object reference then you go
down
you can see javascript special object
and one of them
is map now you see the those stars those
stars means they are new
in 2016 okay so you click on that
new in 2015 new in ecmascript 2015.
you know javascript beginning in 2015
you have a new specification every
year so there's job you know ecmascript
2015 ecommerce script 2016
every year so that's how fast javascript
script is
progressing so map object is new so what
is this
this is the proper data type for hash
table in other words
key value pairs why don't you just use
object since
object javascript object is key value
pairs not really
why because you can see explanation
if you go go down go to map object
tutorial
so there's a section what's the
difference between sub
uh between object and map well maps
okay the the map object keys can be any
type
but not object objects key can only be
string or symbol so that's you
you see there's a big you know there's a
big advantage
in short map is the proper data type for
key value pairs
while object is just happened to be that
way
lots of hack you know because javascript
is the one of the worst language
created and implemented in
10 days literally
so another advantage is that uh
you know if you use object you know you
are actually using properties
then you have complex issues
such as inheritance because each object
has a parent
they may look up the parent's properties
your opinion so
so you so your key map becomes confusing
you you have to look up
parents you know sometimes by mistake a
key
a property exists not in object but
rather in the parent
so that's you don't want that so map
is the proper data type for
for key value pairs and other and
other reasons such as if you use object
you cannot know there's no way
impossible to know how many you know how
many keys do you have
because when you use object everything
is actually a property
then it becomes very complex because you
have
properties that are called symbol
property then you have properties that's
not you know string property
then you have properties that's not in
in not
innumerable you know it gets very
complex
so if you want a key value pair you
don't want to use
object you know javascript object you
want use the proper
key value pair you know this this uh
point might be minor
but you know that's what if you are
talking about the best
you know program you know practice of
pro coding that's one of the important
thing
that's a point that's the reason they
created
this key value pair object in javascript
in 2015 you know a proper data type
but if you are just you know if you are
just coding you know 1 200 you know
even 1000 lines of a you know code
it's not too important okay but for me
since i'm doing this leisurely you know
i want to go with the proper way
so so that's why i don't use json
because if you define this conversion
map
in json then you have to write another
code to convert
object data type to the map or
or stick with the object data type then
it becomes more complex because if you
do not use the proper you know key value
pair the map data type then
you if you use object then you have to
worry about
inheritance your code becomes more
complex when you want to
say for example merge two frequency
uh tables you know it becomes more
complex
so anyway that's a little details about
that okay so anyway
looks like i'm not going to start coding
i'm just going to explain things
i hope that's you know useful
information for those of you
interested in programming languages in
javascript
yeah because actual coding is gonna i'm
gonna be stuck
here and there and you know reading
about my code
anyway so let's continue okay uh
yeah okay anyway let me continue okay so
so you have this section it's about
letter frequency
then this section is about
a the frequency
count of a specific input
so so for example in this uh in this
data
the space happened sixteen thousand
and hundred twenty-five times the letter
e
occurred eight thousand in seven hundred
forty two times
and so on so this is one specific
capture
of a certain input text why do you need
this
uh i mean compare this to the to the
things on top
so you have the frequency count
by percentage of english opinion
and french and i need to add i need to
add german
you know and others so what so why do
you need
these because the idea is the idea is
is that if you
you know have choices of different what
languages to show
for example let's say i want to show
just english you know i don't i'm a mono
linguist
i'm an american i don't care about
french or german or whatever
so i only care about english language
okay
but then you still have an issue because
in english writing depending on your
source text
the frequency we are very significantly
you know very significantly to the point
if you are designing a keyboard layout
very different you know for example if
you are using
shakespeare's writing you know
shakespeare's poems or plays
that kind of writing is you know the
frequency count the letter frequency
will be very very very different
from uh from let's say what you type
on discord or twitter you know on
discord we chat
we chat random things everyone is oh my
i went to
uh have eggs for my breakfast today
you know so this kind of style of text
is very different from shakespeare
and also if you if you go to time
magazine new york times or whatever fake
news cnn you know if you
if your text input is from journalism
so-called journalism
then the characteristics of that later
frequency is
again very different from common chat
and also from
shakespeare very very different okay
and also if you another another type of
text is for example from novels
old man and the c let me show you okay
yeah since i'm doing the talk show you
are look you are watching
talk show so let me show you some
literature
search for worthy english
so this is my blog
so worthy english so in this page
you can see uh vocabulary so i'm a nerd
for
vocabulary for like 20 years i have
meticulous
meticulously look up looked up every
words i don't know
and write it down so so i have a
compendium
of some 5 000 words here
unflappable oh it repeated okay so
here's the mistake
um flap oh okay actually it's
intentional so you have different
i give you three different usage
examples of the word unflappable
then you know so what does that what
does that mean
look it up okay so on
uh anathema in other words anathema
different usage
cognate you know cognate larceny
you know so so you have uh you know
random odor
or you need to turn javascript on
so let's say random order m t
reticent vernacular i'm using vernacular
english speech right now want
agglomeration
so anyway so you you have a list of
words
vocabulary study of vocabulary
fascinating
subject then you have literature
another fascinating subject let me show
you this
i talked about these arabian nights
quite a few times
now this is a picture the that's
anathema to americans
uh to american culture so
anyway i do you know i shouldn't show
this too much because
youtube is gonna censor me anyway these
are the real this is these are the
actual stories
and illustrations of of
the the real arabian nights
you know the tales of one thousands of
one nights
very different from disney okay this is
the actual story of
arabian nights uh and illustrate
illustration of it i love this
so anyway so i was saying i was saying
so if you
um if you are you know if you want text
if you gather all the text from
languages
and you know and here are several
different novels
novel is a very different uh
you you have very different character
frequency
than journalism or shakespeare's writing
or poetry or chat
you know you know verbal you know chat
uh
chat words very different
characteristics
so so i'm showing you some of the
you know classic literatures time
machine science fiction
by uh h.g wells i love you know oh i
love
i love all this work flatland a romance
of many different dimensions
five five how i frantically square my
talk
that that is me exalted troll uh
yeah a modest proposal
the origin of the meaning of the word
offensive a modest proposal by jonathan
swift
and little writing little red red
riding hood the origin arrangement
of women's studies okay now you
modern millennial generation young
people
you love this little riding hood
okay and cubic and psyche this story
is 2 000 years old you know you wonder
what are people thinking 2 000 years ago
read this one okay 2 000 years old the
story of cupid
and psyche and you can see you can begin
to see
how human animals think about
things like love things you know about
love about jealousy about
you know about mating mateship
and things like that girlfriend you know
you are
concerned about those issues right like
if if you are today's youngster
you are probably familiar with the term
chad
you know so this is this story 2000
years old it's about that
okay it's about beauty it's about fat
it's fat girls beautiful
you know this story is part of it you're
talking about that
those things the story of cupid and
psyche
to build a fire now jack london is a
famous uh american
novelist you know he's one of the author
that americans are proud of
and i'm proud of as well i'm american
you know i
i love jack london story so he is a
short
fiction to build a fire the essence of
this story
is that you are going to
build a fire if you failed
you'll die okay that's the essence of
this short story
you can finish it in like 20 minutes if
you read fast
fantastic story a struggle between
men and nature
so anyway a bunch of uh literatures so
and uh telltale heart uh
edgar allan poe another famous american
writer
fantastic okay so
so back to our topic back to our topic
of
uh keyboard layout and character
frequency
so that's that's what i'm saying so i
want to
create a javascript so that
so that you can choose different layouts
and see their heat map and you can type
as you type your draw those things as
you type
and you can choose also choose what
language you are interested
french english germany what are what
what some of the
spanish for example or even chinese
japanese using
using certain input systems
and you then you can also select
which type of uh corpus
you want to be the input for example do
you want to
suppose it's english then do you want
the
stat statistics based on
novels or do you want them to be based
on journalism
like all the news articles you know
words from those news
articles or if you want to based on chat
for example like
from discord
uh you know chat from discord from from
what you say
from your mom and pop you know give
different styles of input
okay so let's go back to javascript so
that is
why you are seeing this part okay
so here you know this one i named it
e and easy fiction mix so my intention
is that this part is about
english okay this is the statistics for
english and from easy fiction
so i i want to add for example
uh i want to add for example
let's see what's going on what oh wait
why is that like that
i want to add uh english
chat text okay then i want to add
from lit uh novels
okay novels
or poetry then i want to add
from
journalism so you know these are the
things i need to do i need to collect
the data
and compute and so i have the data
for these uh
okay so then so let's continue looking
at the
javascript let's just random chat i
cannot
i probably cannot start to code
uh so this you know then then we started
to see
functions okay so here's a function
inverse map object
so what does that mean so uh returns a
new map object that has the key and
value
of map of key and value swapped you know
so here's the function
then you have this function this is
convert key so convert key source layout
target layout and given a key converts
a key from source layout to target
layout so you see
so this function requires
our quality
map we defined before you know all these
quality to work quality to
uh call my quality to work one
you know and so uh
hold on a second okay so let's go down
so this function
then then this function if you call it
it will
yeah so this function is this function
change day out when you call it it will
actually change you know the layout
okay so how long have i been talking
maybe
[Laughter]
i'm thinking of chickening out now
oh one hour and six minutes okay
uh it's kind of slow talk today but i
think i'm
kind of solid so any comments
n go go says thank you
for your explanation you really helped
thank you
i haven't seen you seeing you before
where are you from
uh go go okay so what
uh what next we've been already talking
for one hour
uh i could close down today but let's
let's why not let's continue
so here you started to see the
actual functions that draws svg
you know the circ you know the circles
um
you know draw these circles and uh the
keyboard layout
so here is a draw heat map so you can
see
let me show you some interesting things
okay so draw heat map is a function
then you given the arguments are
a key in the language
yeah so you have you know the language
is gonna be english or french or so on
even though i don't have the feature
here but i started to
you know i started to add them
so given a key it returns
draw okay it draws heat map on a key of
a keyboard layout
so so for example
and it says a key is a svg text
element of the form
yeah so given
yeah so it's actually it takes an svg
element so we started to get complex you
need to know what the svg element is
which is very easy by the way if you
studied svg
svg elements as we talked before
it's like that so this is how you
represent a line
that's svg element so in in javascript
you be
it becomes a
let's see where you know get attribute
so get attribute so svg element is
basically this thing okay
you see that text y equals to some a
number
x equals to number the x those numbers
are the coordinates like where does it
appear then you say
you know so this is quality then you a a
is a letter right so
so you first of all you get attribute
which is finding out what coordinate it
is at for x and y
then you get the frequency frequency you
know
you so because we have the data we
showed before so
you can actually so you first of all get
the
key text content so this
this part is actually getting
you know getting the a or abc or
whatever
then you feed so you get that
then you feed it to the language
frequency
hash table what you get is a number
so you know you're assigned to the
constant frequency
and so on and then you then you have you
uh then you
um so then you hue okay why is hue
important you know the color the hue is
important because
the bigger the circle you want that you
want it to be more red
so it becomes you know heat map so it
stands out so
the color will depends on the frequency
of the
letter so you can see so hue
is defined by math round
frequency divided by some number and in
you know a formula so that's how you
then then you can see
set attribute yeah so you actually
change the font size so you can see
in this diagram the larger
anyway any never mind that part
this code currently doesn't do anything
interesting they just
make every letter larger but same for
every letter
you know so this code doesn't do much
you
you don't need this code to be in this
function
but why is it there because when i was
doing this you do a lot of experiments
when you write code for example
in the beginning instead of drawing the
circle
i just want to have a larger font
the more frequently used it is the
larger the font
then that turns out drawing circle is
more
uh intuitive so
you can see yeah so this is you can see
this picture
that what that's what how it was before
then i decided circle is better
and you know since i'm talking let me
make
another point okay so you have seen heat
maps before
on other website right and
i was showing bitmaps using their
website let's see
keyboard layout let's search for it
so keyboard layout heat map you'll see
this website
very popular uh and what you know very
well done and so his website shows you
the layout i mean the heat map just just
like mine but he
draws them differently now this is very
interesting this is cool you know you
actually
this is traditionally this kind of
drawing style
is called heat map you know because you
can imagine the
the hotter it is it's more red and you
know like
heat in air it kind of you know it kind
of
merged into neighbors cold and hot
but why so i wanted to do similar
but when i started to code my version it
turns out i find that the circle is
small is better
you know so i mean i'm just randomly
telling you
telling you a interesting thing i found
about
so this issue is related to gui
or visualization the science of
visualization
so you know you know in other words
you want to draw character you you want
to
visually demonstrate the character
frequency
okay so there's a question for in the
visualization the study of visualization
is it better
to have like a circle style or is it
better to have this kind of heat map
style drawing
which one is more clear to the reader
like
the readers see it immediately they can
understand which one is more frequent
which one is clear which one is more
precise which one is more intuitive
so this is part part of the study called
visualization
in fact if you um
you know if you just search for
visualization
science it became a thing you know it's
unwarranted in my opinion but anyway
there's huge articles talking about
the science of visualization and there
are also books about it
so you are looking at you know huff post
huff post is a fake news website
uh you know science of visualization
okay
and you can see lots of you know blogs
or articles and books talking about it
so anyway so i'm telling you a concrete
example of one of the issue about
visualization which one style is better
so for me
i learned i noticed i learned you know i
or
i claim that the circle style is
actually
better because
primarily because it actually you can
actually tell
the differences between a
letter frequency that differ by a little
for example r
versus s you can see clearly s
s it's got a bigger circle but if you
use
if you use this heat map style
okay let's let's compare let's go to
quality okay
so yeah so asd okay compare s and d
so s is most more frequently used than d
you can see clearly here but if you uh
use the heat map style
okay you can still kind of you can still
see s is more frequently used
but it so you can see it's kind of
blurry for example
y versus edge which one is more frequent
so if you look at here you can see in my
chart actually is much much more
frequent but actually
i'm using a different source than than
he's using
so for a fair comparison we need to use
the same
input source anyways that's so that's an
interesting
thing about visualization science that
i found so anyway back to the javascript
function so you can see
so here this part is the actual drawing
of the circles
so you can see create element create
elements
circle then set attribute cx
and cy that's the center of the circle
then
you set attribute r that's the radius of
the circle
so the radius will become will be equal
to
frequency times five you know so that's
how
this is a formula after some trial and
error i you know uh
so the radius of the circle is frequency
times five
and feel and stroke and so on
okay so that so this function is about
drawing the circles
basically then the next function
you have actually remove heat heat map
because why do you need to remove it
because every time you change the layout
you have to remove the old one so you
know so that's
actually you need this function okay so
next function
count characters characters return a map
count characters given a string returns
a map
a hash table where key is a single
character
and value is the count of occurrence of
the character okay
so some of the basic functions then
then you have a function this is
truncate map
so given a map and given
a number you want to return a new map
but containing
only n entries basically you want to cut
off
truncate why do you want to do that
because
because for example let me let me show
you okay so
so suppose you have these um
character frequency plot right so
you can type and see
data now in english you only have 26
letters and also 26 capital less
capital case and also plus maybe 10 or
20 punctuation so in total you have
maybe
100 different type of characters
but however if you started to
um let's go to a new page okay
let me show you so if you started to do
this for
japanese or chinese you started to see
the problem
let's go to japanese okay
so this page you are looking at japanese
character frequency
so you know in my study i also want to
know japanese
this is part of japanese the japanese
phonetics
which is part of the japanese writing
system but anyway
if you start to use japanese if you want
to compute japanese character frequency
you run into a problem because japanese
phonetic alphabet there are about
uh i think
i think uh there are about 100 of them
okay
same thing but okay so there are about
phonetic characters for japanese but
japanese writing system also includes
latin alphabet by definition it's
officially part of japanese writing
system
so 100 100 japanese phonetic characters
plus 100 english
latin letters in alphabet but plus
japanese writing system also includes
about 3 000 chinese characters
so if you um
let me show you let me demo okay so
let's go to character frequency
let's go to uh uh
latin okay
let's say latin alphabet any random
article on wikipedia okay
so we have this article on that latin
alphabet
now you go down on the left panel you
click on the japanese version
now they don't have japanese version so
let's click on english alphabet okay
so article wikipedia article then you go
down to
the japanese version
you know japanese wikipedia on english
alphabet
then you select all copy
then you go back to to the
character frequency plot then you select
all
you paste it
let's see
so you got you got something like that
because now you have literally like
almost
2 000 distinct characters it's a problem
you know the the chart is the unreadable
now so you want actually to truncate it
so so i made in this page i made choices
so no chinese
if you eliminate all chinese that's not
enough
you still have too many uh why is that
yeah so japanese you know so yeah that's
when you want to truncate you see
now you want to truncate top 30 only so
you click on that
now you get a good picture of the top
30 most frequently used characters in
japanese so that is why
when you go back to the javascript code
that's why you see this
uh truncate map function
that's why it's needed okay i think
maybe i should stop here any more
comments
uh you know i
explained some javascript
okay let me continue some more okay
because
then you started to have a lot of
functions that
helps you create svg elements
for example
for example in this chart you need to
draw
lots of rectangles and you also need to
lines for the grid you also need to draw
the text
you know bigger font and you also need
to include the frequency
all those are svg so you need to say
document
dot create svg rectangle and you know
getting tedious
so i have that's why you need so this
function for example
this function uh create svg that creates
an svg element
the you know like you know uh
the parent svg element then you have a
function that you know it's getting
detailed svg detail
translate uh then you have
translate and scale translation
is like moving some drawing to another
place
and scale is like magnify or shrink
then you have this function
draw a rectangle you know you just give
it
two positions and you draw the rectangle
and you also give it
you know the width and height of the
rectangle
then you have this function
[Music]
and so on i guess draw grids okay
okay draw grades rectangle then
draw text that's this function draw text
then you have a function draw chart
then you have a function you know draw
draw
chart will draw the whole um
the whole chart using previous functions
okay and that's it
okay so we finished we actually finished
looking at this javascript
uh source code this this is kind of the
library
okay only 400 lines 400 lines of code
so close that now we are back to this
file
this file which is um
yeah this file is is the library for
creating this page
now but there are a second file so so
let me show you okay the second file
javascript file
and this this file is short so that's
all there it is
the javascript file basically this just
this file just calls
the you know the library functions to
to actually draw the whole thing here
okay that's it i think that's it for
today thank you guys for watching
an hour and 25 minutes that's a long one
uh so if you like my stuff
uh paypal me donate
and uh
by myself okay my javascript tutorial my
javascript
in depth okay thank you guys for
watching
bye guys
what's going on stop streaming