good morning everyone
welcome to Santa show today is July 9th
2019 4 o'clock p.m. California time
today we're gonna talk about two things
okay so the first thing is the first the
first thing is about unicode there is
this problem of unicode so we cannot
talk about that then the other thing is
we are going to do a live coding of : we
are in first tutorial so wow I'm coding
it I'm gonna explain how to do it so you
can learn it's good for : beginners so
if you have never learned : I recommend
that you can learn you know you can I
hope it inspires you and also as a
beginning course :
you know : is the most popular one of
the most popular industrial language
it's fantastic it's my favorite
industrial language so we have one guy
watching say hi and we're gonna begin
talking about today's topic let's let's
begin begin at the beginning let's begin
talking about it
so let's get the window up here so you
know so there is this problem with
unicode you know so you your writings
you know you write you know in
mathematics suppose you write you know
you know let's say let's see this
okay oops let's say okay so you you
what's going on what oh okay it's so
long
okay so you write a change to be okay so
a let's say not AP but
but let's say you say that okay so you
like that and you know you write that in
your let's say PhD thesis or some you
know online publication in your blog or
you know something somewhere important
you know you want the words
mathematicians to read it you know a
proof of something some theory then in
your code you know after a few years it
becomes this so you see your double
double headed arrow usually you know it
becomes this emoji it's pretty [ __ ] up
okay and so that is a problem with
unicode and this symbol by the way this
symbol usually means it's usually means
if and only if or it it can means
implication
you know necessary and well how they say
necessary and sufficient sufficient and
necessary condition but anyway it
usually just means if and only if the
easiest way to remember such a property
is that when you have something if and
only if that means a implies P P implies
a or in other words a and B are kind of
almost like the same thing okay when you
have condition a you know it's the same
as P well I mean not the same but it
implies in both ways so so so in other
words you know when you have this in
math that means the a and B are of the
same condition not not the same
condition but the same kind of
requirement like some sort of
requirement requirement structure anyway
that that's
that's math you know so that the problem
here is emoji you know the emoji the
damnation of the emoji and this happened
with Unicode you know they did so let me
give you another example then we're
gonna explain what's what's really going
on so in my articles I have you know
describing keywords I have I wrote this
you know okay so this particular
keyboard you have more type media keys
this is this
you know those multimedia keys like stop
play pause fast forward fast backward
and mute and you also have sound control
keys you know you can increase the sound
or lower the sound so those are typical
multimedia keys on a keyboard computer
keyboard and also you have typically
represented by these symbols so you
wrote this but a few years later they
they become these you know they become
is this this like inconsistent crap you
know part of it is in this character for
example the stop sign or square black
square is not emoji but then the
fastball for fastback word and play
button becoming emoji and also the sound
you know mute symbol they all become
emoji but you know it so it becomes this
it's this is a problem you know this is
a problem due to what's called I think
it's something called emoji and symbol
much something like that but basically
the history of it is that you know
around 2007 also that Unicode invented
in emoji which are you know emoji which
are this you know these characters emoji
you have all sort of emojis Unicode
didn't invented it it was kind of
invented in Japan you know it came from
emoticon by anyway so
so around 2007 also Unicode introduced
emoji to to their you know characters so
that you know it's a good thing because
the idea is that so we can unify I mean
all the emoji you know this you know
smiley characters you have a code point
you have a code represented so it's kind
of like standardized you know so
everyone will have these kind of you
know emoticons you know X facial
expressions characters so so so you so
Japanese you know began to use it around
year 2000 okay then Unicode in around
2007 also they they introduced in emoji
you know from they take it from Japan
you know based on the Japanese emoticons
you know emoji so Unicode introduced
emoji around 2007 but then what happens
is that then some of the characters are
not emoji for example these stars you
know you have a bunch of stars in
Unicode or you have for example let's
say costs you know different causes you
know all this sort of dim bats you know
game characters you know chess chess
characters playing cards characters so
these exist you know many of these exist
in Unicode you know such as the star
signs stars okay so so this already
exists in Unicode then you know Unicode
introduced emoji you know which are
these smiley symbols then apparently
some companies you know it becomes you
know some companies companies when they
see your star sign for example they try
to render it like that like emoji you
know they try to replace it with us you
know into a colored you know pretty
picture why do company do that of course
they so that they think the product will
be better you know so anyway so so some
some characters even though they are not
emoji but they there's a you know
there's a situation where people render
them as emoji you know like a pretty
picture
anyway so so so Unicode began to kind of
standardize these as well you know these
único started to say okay which
character should be emoji which
character should remain a symbol you
know not becoming a colored you know
pretty pictures so they started to say
that and that is over here it's you know
they started they started to specify on
that but what happened is that they just
[ __ ] up you know they just totally
[ __ ] up so so let me explain what is a
current situation you know the technical
you know SPECT regarding when is a you
know a character is a emoji when is a
text so basically you Unicode
specification says there are some
characters came be rendered as text and
some characters can also be rendered as
emoji okay so they so a character can be
rendered as text or emoji but únicos
specifies that certain characters can
only be text the can only be rendered as
text for example you know English
alphabet
you know letters ABCD those are just
text you can you know you would it is
incorrect to render them into emoji you
know well you can do that but that's you
know just technically incorrect so some
text
can only be text according to unicode
suspect okay now some other characters
are always emoji they can never be
rendered in a texture you know symbol
fashion so what are those those are you
know for example the it is emoji you
know some of them is how explain okay
but anyway let's check out food okay so
all these characters I think of them by
according to Unicode they must always be
rendered as emoji I mean they are
classified as emoji on the other hand
there's the third a third category some
texts have both emoji and the text
textual representation so this is what
Unicode consortium you know the standard
says so some characters can only be text
some characters can be rendered as emoji
I mean can only be rendered as emoji and
while another set of characters can be
either way and they also introduced let
me show you they are also introduced a
variation character now a variation
character is basically an invisible
character for example like the tab key
the tab character or the return newline
you know characters those are invisible
also the space characters are in this is
a example of invisible character so
Unicode created two they created a bunch
but you know some of the they created
these invisible characters they are
called variations selector so there are
sixteen of them so the purpose of them
is that when you have this character you
know this variation selector after
another character it tells you know
whatever the application to render the
previous character in a particular way
so for example
for example the soccer ball let's look
at this soccer ball okay so this this
soccer ball is a Unicode you know
character like every other character in
Unicode so according to Unicode Specht
this soccer ball has both emoji
representation and also a textual
representation so this soccer ball
character can be you know represent in
either way now if you wanted to be
textual you can add a variation selector
15 after the character that should tell
the application to render the soccer
ball like this here you know as a text
you know that is a simple not not
colorful pretty picture but if you want
a soccer ball to be rendered as a emoji
you know a pretty picture then you you
can use the variation selector then it
should be rendered that like you know a
pretty picture
so in summary unic expect you know they
say this is the this is the way to go
so some characters can be okay are
always text only some are always emoji
while others can be text or emoji and
also unicode created created this
variation selectors invisible characters
that allows you to kind of specify how a
character is represented on you know on
your application so this is what unico
Specht did but it turns out it's it's
crap it's very bad okay so you see you
turns also these characters so this set
of characters you can see all of them
here they are not many like 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8 9 10 10 times like 2010 like 200 of
them they can both be when
emoji or text okay oh and there's
another concept of default like if you
do not use any variation character
variation selector then what should be
the default rendering should it be text
or emoji
so anyway Unicode says these characters
can be both and they must they should
default to emoji and único says these
characters must be wait a second okay so
so then these characters can also be
both but however they must default to
text okay then Unicode says the
following characters you know there are
hundreds of them these must always be
emoji okay yeah so this so so that's
what Unicode says but you know it's very
confusing it's very it's a very bad
SPECT because first of all in practice
you know a few application actually
follow Unicode for example in this in
this box these characters they can be
both text or emoji but by default they
must be shown as emoji but as you can
see here all these here they are not
shown as emoji you see at the bottom
these two lines and I did not use any of
the variation selector so technically
technically they should be rendered as
emoji so in Firefox you can see
apparently it's incorrect it's incorrect
you know almost everywhere because
nobody actually follow this standard and
nobody actually follow this standard
because the standard is really bad okay
so here is seeing brave browser which is
chrome using the convention you can see
okay
still many of them are not rendered as a
text I mean not not as emoji they should
be they should be rendered as emoji so
anyway back to Firefox and on this box
can be emoji or text and default to text
you see so all these are wrong you know
all these you know you know Firefox is
just incorrect now let's see chrome you
know it's same on Chrome you know just
or incorrect because nobody actually
follow follow this standard so so why
why is that I mean what's going on so
you know if you actually look at these
characters you see Unicode says you look
at you know the Unicode spec you know
what which character must be default to
emoji which must be text they doesn't
make sense at all they you know some of
the characters for example for example
let me show you this multimedia symbols
you know mute these symbols the mute
symbol the increased volume symbol the
decreased volume symbol over here they
are rendered as text over here they are
rendered as emoji now according to
Unicode this mute symbol and this you
know increased volume and decreased
volumes symbol this you know sound level
symbols according to Unicode they must
be always rendered as emoji let me show
you where you can see here you see this
speaker with 3 sound waves speaker with
one sound wave and a speaker with
cancellation stroke you see these three
characters they are in this group of
characters we scroll to the top and
let's see so you see they are in this
section which are they must be always
showing us
emoji um be so that this is what Unicode
spec says but that doesn't make sense
because you know these mute symbols they
are very typical you know on keyboard
you know everyone sees it every day but
now you interview you know you are
saying Unicode is saying that they must
be rendered in a similar stupid you know
and also if you look at the emoji who
you know where does this you know do you
ever see an emoji symbol showing this
like this it's almost like doesn't exist
but Unicode says you know these
characters are always emoji it's like
completely idiotic okay so that's the
situation with this this único emoji and
the text situation okay that that can
concludes that topic let's see how many
people are watching two people watching
say something here say hi so the next
topic I'm thinking I'm going to code :
so are you guys here anyone here want to
do : because I'm planning to start a
live coding of Golan first tutorial
so you know just type what do you think
type it so anyway so okay so you know
you guys know how to be funny but so let
me see let's see what what what we gonna
do problems of decorative animation okay
so I think I'm going to code go Landon
okay so let's let's do code goal and so
goal and so what am I going to do with :
let me show you so let's go to Casa lead
that info okay
and it's just sorry sorry dot info this
is my website and and you go all the way
to the bottom you can see a site map and
see if you can see that actually okay so
let me move the window left so there is
a site map click on that and and you
have a list of basically all the
articles on this particular website so
you have you have I have like let's see
three thousand six hundred forty eight
articles let's go to the top now you can
randomize the order they are shown so
you can random nice and see
yeah okay so when you click on that it
just go to that page you know it opens a
new tab on this page
close your meta data okay working
progress okay let's open let's open some
of the carcass of some of the pages this
just open them
so so this this is these pages called
sitemap you know the word sitemap used
to be popular around 1900 in 2030 mm
when we when you have a website
typically they have a site map you know
basically tells you okay
of all the things on the web site you
know like kind of give you a overview
kind of like table of contents you know
for the articles on the website so you
can easily find the information you need
but today you don't have you know you
don't have a site map anymore I think
they are you know they are it's because
they are gradually replaced by such yeah
Google such like few people like you
don't see site map anymore anymore
but if but also it used to be like on
each web site usually you have a search
button that lets you such you know the
stuff on on the web site on that
particular web site but even that kind
of disappeared like I don't think I've
seen them much anymore so today it's all
replaced by you know Google people just
use Google search or Bing search or
other you know search engines to fight
to find info they don't you know they
they don't even use a search button on a
web site so anyway I have this site map
and let's see some of the links so here
is one of my unicode page let's see it's
the page is stuck stuck for a while okay
so this is a Devanagari language you
can't close it so here's another article
this is an essay about yes I wrote how
to not engage me now if you don't know
ye-es I is the famous guy Eric s Raymond
he is known for
you know he's one of the leader the
engine of kind of founder co-founder of
the open source organization the open
source movement movement in 1997 okay
around 1997
it's a offshoot of Richard Stallman's
free software foundation so in a
beginning you have Free Software
Foundation which is copyright
I mean copy left or new project you know
it's so good new project is the project
to create a operating system of kind of
you know freedom oriented up in his
operating system and that's called new
project and good new project is created
by Richard Stallman and the organization
he created is called Free Software
Foundation so kuno is a you know a
project of the Free Software Foundation
they are the you know they are they are
the creator of the GPL license
GNU GPL eyes license so anyway so so
Richard Stallman began that around 1980
was at 80 84 87 something like that then
it became popular because of Linux in
1990s then the open source movement
began around 1997 or six ninety you know
1996 or something
one of the major force is the ESRI Eric
s women he is known for having written
the the art of UNIX I think he has
written several books the art of UNIX
which is crap okay and his proponent of
UNIX philosophy which is which which is
code he's you know it's a total total
empty content other than code stinks and
he is also known for
Cathedral Bazaar and Cathedral and he is
also the maintainer of the of the jargon
file ho also known as hackers dictionary
you know he is the he's not the original
creator or editor he he is the
maintainer and he changed much of it to
suit his unix preference preferences and
you his UNIX philosophy code so anyway
he you know he's well known so he one
day he blogged about how to not engage
me okay this article is funny you know
so this is when this is 2012 okay he
wrote a blog about how to not engage me
he's basically someone send him your
email okay someone sent him an email I
forgot what's a content but basically
flame him or something so and so he you
know he blogged about it you know with
for part of the email content and he
basically ridicuious it you know
basically he gave his reasons or
whatever but let's see yeah so I found
this out article because someone
mentioned me you know in his comment you
know he says you know someone mentioned
Sally the writer was maybe Sally you
know some someone mentioned Jack Jack
both Smith said that and yes si is
probably not the name given was quick
not Chinese and a Google search
indicated that it corresponds to a real
person okay so yeah so someone sent him
an email a frame mail or something and
he disagree and he oh he opened it up
you know to ridicu it and then someone
mentioned me that's that's how I found
it so I went and and read his blog
I read his blog and you so it turns out
you know to me
that the guy who wrote the email
actually made sense but he doesn't make
make sense okay
this is why I have problem with all
these so-called hackers okay this hacker
culture I find them idiotic okay see
well I didn't plan to talk about this
subject but since we are on it let's
talk about it and it's I don't know what
we're gonna do the goal encoding maybe
maybe we can do that more you know so
let's let's talk about this ESR Oracle
you know how not to engage me
so let's see magnify so he says
considering concede considering the
extent to which I'm still a public
figure
it is perhaps surprising how seldom I
get email that deserves a floor up one
side and down the other
flaming I got I got one today which I
shall reproduce here was a perfect
example of how not to engage me okay so
you know these guys pompous the word is
pompous Eric s Raymond he's a [ __ ]
pompous guy we all consider the extent
to which I'm still a public figure it's
perhaps surprising how seldom I get
email that deserves a through row one up
one side and down the other framing what
the [ __ ] anyway so you know he is gonna
say he's gonna showcase the email he
received okay the email reads I just
finished skimming through your guide how
to ask questions the smart way that that
is a very popular or used to be very
popular article on the web he wrote it
you know the ESL wrote it and and that
are Co the content it's kind of idea
okay I'll explain okay it's a good
article but it's kind of it's just like
everything not too idiotic like
impractical and ineffectual this hacker
you know UNIX philosophy hacker types
that's what they are typically you know
very accurate very precise very you know
what they say seems and seems to be true
but however they are total in effect of
what they are doing it tends to be
nothing like English actually in fact
harmful to themselves like look at
today's you know like they used to fight
spam they used to fight spam by you know
by by by by by plunking by what's that
the code is a word oh god it's been so
long
by blacklist by you know it's the slang
is flunking by well basically it's a
filter in new scoops anyway let's
continue to read this okay so he saw the
email the the guy who emailed him says I
just finished skimming through your
article how to ask questions the smart
way I am sorry to say that to say I'm
alarmed by the kind of immature
mentality that runs through it this guy
so this guy is a flamer okay then he
says I will not begin to analyze how
many of the assertions you make are
simply illogical and unjust because it
upsets me to think about them okay and
he continues I would like to ask you to
consider the reasons why you are taking
this stance if it's out of sympathy for
the superior case of hackers an idiotic
and misapplied term if ever there was
one
that's right okay do you realize that
you are describing real people with
serious psychological problems and that
you are feeding their pain by your
writings okay
then he last sentence I hope you can
balance the effort you have put behind
this document with some social
responsibility okay so this guy is a
good writer okay yeah he's writing this
you know this just few sinners sentences
excellent excellently written you know
we are very well written by the way ESI
is also a master of writing okay that I
cannot deny ESI is very knowledgeable he
is he possessed the expertise of the C
language and I think also see prosperous
you know he's very you know he's very
knowledgeable guy he's a very skilled
programmer expert in C at least and also
he is a top writer okay I can
acknowledge that and he knows a lot of
things you know quite a lot you know if
you want you know let's say he's euro
tight you know meaning that man you know
you learn things about you know not just
programming not just a mathematician not
just a nerd but you well still or not
but you you learn you know variety of
things in you know academic subjects or
even outside of academic subjects anyway
so yes is very knowledgeable skilled
programmer and good writer but the guy
who emailed him is also you know judging
by just this six paragraph a graphs you
know he also write he he writes well so
so anyway so this guy wrote to him that
and then ESR says
I swear to all of you I swear to all of
you I did not invent or modify even a
word of this I wouldn't have been
capable I can simulate galloping
stupidity that well here was my response
okay this is our guy
[ __ ] what a [ __ ] pompous [ __ ] okay
he you know he's not just well how would
you know yeah I have quite a lot of
things to say about this year's our guy
from his political opinions to his UNIX
philosophy crap okay
by the way one thing I haven't mentioned
is his political stance you know he's
also well known for it and a lot people
hates him he is you know he's kind of I
guess you know some people call him new
account you know basically he is for war
he is like pro-american for war you know
he he he supports invading Iraq you know
during the Iraq war
and he is a cantata you know he collects
he has guns you know he he advocate for
gun rights and for you know those those
kind of things so he's a so so he's not
just you know outside of programming
he's hosing like people call him it's
like a new new account
I think knio knio kong is the proper
term to describe his political
inclinations you know at least the
critics of the right-wing anyway yeah so
he is also known for that you know you
know and I don't I don't agree with that
okay I I this more to say about that it
gets very interesting because so you
know so he is you know kind of white
right-wing okay so many programmers
don't like him and also also the way he
right is very pompous you know look at
this I swear to all of you I swear not
just he'd you know he he has to say
something but he needs to sir swear it
but not just to like one one guy owed to
my audience like you know to you know he
has to state that he swear to whom to
all of you and what does he say what
does his way ok he swear to all of you
that he did not invent or modify even a
single word of this so he just pasted
you know the email he received ok
normally you know like different people
person different people have different
writing styles right normally you pay
something then you start to talk about
it that's you know that's it what do you
pay state but he you know you don't have
to say it's not necessary to say I
didn't modify it unless you know maybe
the content cause for it you know maybe
because it's a leaked email or something
you know something leaked or something
you know there's no need in this case
there's no need to to to like to repeat
or emphasize that you did not modify it
but he he has to you know this ESR [ __ ]
you know I swear to all of you I did not
invent or modify even a word of this
then he says I wouldn't have been
capable I can't simulate I can't you
know I can't simulate kalpen stupidity
that well that's a good description ok
and he says here's my response but hold
on ok let me finish talking about his
the political situation his political
inclinations ok so he you know as we
mentioned he's kind of a neocon oh all
right wing ok I'm not sure a new account
he actually espoused that word I don't
know if he you know typically it's a
negative you know what I mean it's a
derogatory
you know it's called derogatory
but anyway so let's see yeah let's go to
his house so so so he's kind of neocon
oh right wing okay let's just say right
wing day but now you see that is back in
mm
but since around 2010 the social justice
can arose you know and the landscape of
American politics in gnomes
it's like changed entirely 180 degrees
you know like about face it did a
about-face you know it used to be
conservative rules you know the country
God you know stuff but now it's like Oh
or every day is like gays and transient
trends you know women's right and this
and all ladies immigration in you know
victims and stuff so around 2010 let's
just say 2010 the social justice can
arose it's a major change in particular
in 2016 there's a major change in u.s.
culture or politics kind of and I don't
like that well because I'm anti the
social justice cat okay I I think they
are not just the you know it's not it's
not like I don't agree with their
opinions but actually I think they are
like criminals they are evil they they
are you know lying scumbags they are
corrupt with many of them the leaders
are super rich
like not just rich like the millions and
billions of you know money you know they
do these kind of things so that that is
my opinion of the social justice type of
people I mean not in general not just
you know not particular person because
in you know this that's that's my
opinion but a social justice movement
so I don't like them okay so they are my
enemies but however the ESR guy Eric s
Raymond he is you know so of course it's
not his friend the social justice kinds
is are not his friend
in fact is his enemy so he he fight them
you know he do what he can to fight them
you can see it constant you know often
in his blogs and I agree okay I you know
even though I'm you know I don't like
he's you know yes his political opinions
about war about guns you know all these
guns and stuff like oh we you know he's
right you know
yeah it's you know it's like you know
you can hardly go that's fine you know
American that's how American history
happens to be that way
and it's not necessarily bad okay you
know and you know this foreign cause I
mean many issues in society there is no
right answer you know so as far as gun
goes you know legalization of gun you
know to me
I don't think you know I my opinion is
like I'm not against it I'm not against
you know owning a gun but no am i you
know thinking that you know American
with guns is just bad okay I don't think
he's that way so I'm not for comment I
think it's just there it's okay so
anyway he so why so yeah so so in
general the so good doesn't matter to me
but you know either way but ESI is like
you know this is some there are certain
type of American they heard like they
have to talk about guns all the time
like oh I would you know rights and
stuff so yes I is one of them you know
and in fact I think he collect guns you
know he like some of these people it's
almost it's like it's a subculture it's
a hobby you know like you have this
typically white ruh-roh
Americans I think okay they you know
they like to hunt you know gun
collection to practice target you know
shooting stuff you know and they collect
you know some of them collect you know
war memorabilia or you know they they
like to in tango they like to practice
civil war you know like fake you know
how they could have they could in being
act ccc american civil was good stuff
you know so it's it's kind of hobby it's
it's all tied together
so anyway anyway so but one thing i
really don't you know so yes i don't
like him anyway so his political
opinions neocon you know for war and you
know to him and to this new accounts
opinion I mean people their opinion you
know he said Oh America is democracy
therefore we must spread democracy to
free free you you know we're gonna come
in free you drop a few palms that's the
opinion you know they think they are
helping they are helping the world you
know the into democracy into a you know
so yes I is one of those guy so I this
particular point
I hate very much okay yeah III think
it's it's it's the worst it's kind of a
criminal and this this mentality it is
anyway so I don't like him for that at
least
but then the social justice can arose
you see and he started you know of
course obviously he start began to fight
with the social justice but now I
support him
I support ESR I support Eric s Raymond
even though I you know I find him to be
a very problematic guy but the very fact
that he is against associates the social
justice can I
support Eric s Raymond okay because in
my opinion the social justice candid odd
any people as you know especially that
the top you know like today you have the
leaders of the you know basically the
CEO of Google Facebook you know they are
all doing it you know they do in social
they've seen the songs of social justice
they seen the songs of you know there
are words I don't want to mention
because you know google has censorship
right now anyway that is the I think
that's the worst evil much worse the
social justice can to me is it's much
much worse then the let's say let's say
the I can say which one is actually was
you know because the neocon you know if
you talk about the neocon you know they
they up for war they they invade you
know other countries all the time for
the benefit of of America for the
benefit for the benefit of American us
okay counting me so you know but anyway
so new account they you know they do war
and you know in the pretext of democracy
democracy is just a pretext really you
know so that's not good that you know
war you have meaning that you know you
have hundreds of thousands dead you know
for example in Iraq war you have like
how many servi civilians dead 300,000
something like that you can you know and
you know so that's not good the new
account is no good but however this is a
social justice the way I see social
justice it's it's it's not better okay
so so I so if you press me to say which
one is was that actually depends on
depends on what you're talking about I
mean if you're talking about war already
happened you know we you know we have
you know
hundreds of thousands people dead or all
over the globe because of US invasion
because of a USA you know the you know
it's it's euphemized as what what they
say tulsi gabbard
he often says that you form Isis regime
change okay yeah no we'd only we don't
you know we don't kill we don't invade
other countries we simply just do regime
change
we always that's all we do you know so
anyway so if you talk about you know war
and you know actually a lot of people
you know dead so that aspect is surely
was in the social justice at least the
social justice can has not caused a war
well actually is so you see so the sort
of Justice can is extremely bad
extremely bad in fact they are also for
poor war they you know that like today's
democrat party they are a very poor war
just like exactly like the right the
right wing knee accounts you know these
rich powerful corporations in people in
politicians so anyway but what I'm
saying is that at at a personal level
like everyday life you know I I think
the social justice is far worse than the
the typical American culture and you
know before let's say before 2010 the
social justice is very bad that is why
if I have to choose either support Eric
s Raymond or not support him I choose to
support because when it comes to a civil
war you have to make a choice that's
what civil war happen you know you know
$0.02 many people say that civil war is
coming if it's not not already happening
that's very bad you know when civil war
comes you gonna you gonna make a choice
you know
enemy or friend and that choice will
happen upon your friends your relatives
your family your sisters your mama and
you know you're gonna choose neither
either they die or you die that's what
the [ __ ]
social justice people who has created
this the the Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey and
and all these scums Google you know
whoever's current as CEO right now
anyway so that's a lot rent right off
the bat I got maybe the comment so I Sam
Morris's how about the six million
Muslims held in China how about that are
you a true are you like joining me
answer that are you is that a serious
question
are you trolling me do you know me
before you are you just came to this you
know you just came to you know you have
to say you say it then answer because I
don't know if you are sincere so anyway
back to yes yes ah okay so yeah I don't
know I don't know it maybe you are
follow you know you are like I'm a nerd
I'm a programmer I'm kind of you know I
being in the programming you know I'm
knowing some small you know programming
communities so I don't know I wonder if
you you know of you following me and
know the okay so well yeah okay so you
you you ask me about this
you know I don't you know I don't you
know I don't want to mention those
things because that's that's that's
censorship you know Google is going to
censor this video but anyway to answer
the question okay I don't actually know
the details about the China situation
you know the the Muslims out you know
but what I know is
that I I know it very well you know in
Weston because I because I'm American by
the way I'm American citizen I a oh you
are it is back okay great so yeah you
are you my we are in the same community
so I am an American citizen I live here
for the past 30 years basically most of
my adult life since I was since I was 21
before that three years in a me in
Canada so basically since I'm 17 I lived
my life in three years in Canada and the
rest of it in USA I'm 51 today like
halfway into the grave I have begun
pretty soon so anyway 30 years in USA I
know exactly what you know Americans you
know the all the newspapers you know
when they talk about China I know
exactly what they say doesn't matter
what what year they were what they want
to say is that and also this is also
what most Americans believe because you
know those are from newspapers they you
know they push it out every day so you
know after decades yeah it looks like I
look younger
no but you know I've you know I'm like
hey I think Asians usually have the
characters you know you you don't look
so older so so fast but also you know
I'm getting old like my eyes I'm going
blind
anyway anyway so so I know you know so
basic typically like you know let me
tell you you know my opinions okay so
basically whenever Americans say
something about China they have only one
call you can just say they have a call
like their goal is to say China is like
inhuman like they are violating human
rights they or whatever this or that
they are not free they are communist and
we must take over we must spread freedom
we must spread democracy we must spread
human rights China Evo okay and we must
you know do something like invade China
or whatever that is
see basically every article in the past
since I've read in the past 30 years on
every issue from every publication every
major you know mainstream publication
that's it it's all say that you don't
like you don't even have to know what
what is the the thing they are talking
about what is the issue you don't have
to know
but the every article they basically
have the same premise China bad you know
we need to free them we need to like
liberate them we need to regime change
so so that's what that that is my
opinion okay you can you know if you you
know you can you can if you trust me you
you know you maybe you take it to heart
you think about it if you don't you know
you know nothing I can do so that is my
basis basic opinion my perception about
the situation now so this specifically
about the Muslim in China how you know
China is doing you know bad things to
them I don't know that specific but but
again I'm like I don't like I don't it's
not it's not like oh maybe I should
think about it all China is really doing
these bad things no I don't even think
about that because first of all I just
wash it off I think it's just it's a lie
by the by the by the American powerful
because they want you know and also it
but but so so why does the typical
American that nimma stay address that so
why does typical American believe that
because we are all human beings human
animals okay we all have biases so if
you are American especially if you are
white American you naturally believe
whatever that benefits you you know
China is bad you know they always
something we need to or some me
something something whatever you know
what I'm saying is it's just that we all
have biases but however you I mean what
I'm saying so if you are if you are like
me for example you if you are Chinese
you know you didn't you know you are not
white you came from elsewhere immigrant
okay
my immigrant but I'd buy the way but III
think the socialist is the Democrat
today are scums okay I was a illegal
immigrant in Canada I make $3 an hour
you know I didn't dollars an hour
working in clothing factories and all so
anyway that's that's my history but
anyway back to the question about so I
was saying everyone has biases you know
you can you cannot blame you know
average American for their beliefs or
the you know you can say you can i
cannot say they are idiotic because they
simply believe all the lies the US
government spread about China okay
meanwhile for example let me let me give
you another example of bias in China in
China you know if you go to China oh if
you are Chinese by the way I was from
Taiwan I have never been to China but if
you are Chinese you were born in China
you ask them Oh what they think about us
you know they are not going to tell you
all us is gonna help us we need you as
China but oh my government is very bad I
need you know because this because they
put more servants you know in imprison
or something I need please come help us
you know hey nobody nobody says that
they've in fact if you press them they
all say USA is evil bad just like what
you are thinking about China okay that
is my opinion on this issue so you know
I'm not saying you're you know you know
so American is biased and Chinese is now
everyone is biased but so how do you
solve this problem you know yes you have
to be reasonable anyway on the
particular Muslim issue I can I can
refer you to if you are interested you
know most people are not really
interested about truth like you know
like if you can actually find out you
know what really happens about that for
example you can if you really want to
but there's a price to pay
meaning that from now on every day you
goodness you have to spend one hour look
for the truth you know you will find
what exactly really happens you know if
you really want to spend one hour a day
for the next 30 days for a month you I
bet you know I will I can you know I'm
confident to challenge you that your
opinion will change after 30 days you
look into the issue you you you know you
questioned exactly that issue spend one
hour a day try to look for you know
truth whatever you know it is spin wild
a day after 30 days I guarantee your
opinion will be quite different in
nature from today about that issue okay
that's that's what I think how I made
book pro what is Hawaii made mate put oh
wow I wow I made wow made book okay
that's the power laptop anyway so we are
where are you from by the way are you
are you American are you in the u.s. USA
so actually I think that's it for today
I think because you know we I could you
know ice I started to rant about so we
we talked about the Unicode the Unicode
emoji versus text issue that is about
the first 20 or 30 minutes okay then we
started to talk about sitemap yeah the
purpose of sitemap and how it became no
longer used then we started to talk
about this es aha person okay and you
know he's interesting and very
controversial guy and very controversial
opinions then from that point on I
started to win in
to Arendt about quite a few things about
hacker culture about you know the
arrangement of open source free software
foundation and then I started to talk
about neo Kong you know the opinions
about you know in the social justice
people so okay you are from Britain okay
so you know and yeah so so now it's
being on our way anyway I want you know
so I think that's maybe we can let me
talk about five more minutes to finish
more minutes to finish okay thank you
yeah a few more minutes to finish about
this this topic about what this ESI is
talking about you know how to not engage
me so anyway someone sent him an email
kind of flame Flemish and he be taught
you know and he says proverb rah and you
know you can you can read it so anyway
yeah okay yeah so I guess that's it so I
you know so so thank you guys for coming
thanks for watching
yep thanks so by eyes and bye guys