thank ice I'm going to show you some
fatties today so what is life like he's
it's a it's a key binding system for
Emacs so that you don't have to press
ctrl Keys much and you don't have to
press meta keys anymore
like not even once for it for everything
you're doing in Emacs there are only
like four control key combinations you
need to press so why that you know
because you know for Emacs usually you
get for many people you get hand pain
repetitive repetitive strain injury so
supply Keys is one way to solve that
problem you almost never need to press
continue no never never need to press
metal and only a few few control keys so
so let's go through it I'm going to show
you how to install it first let's start
Emacs so this is cool
Emacs without any in it let's install it
so I open the file open my Emacs dot d
ok it's empty
now create a file in it DL and I'm going
to install it through male path so in
email PHA you need to put in some config
so it will find the male power
repository in the Emacs libraries so
paste it here and control key control
control X control e to evaluate that
this code so now the map is there and
save control x countries now let's call
meta x
list packages okay now search for
fly keys there it is so enter control
excel switch pain install yes okay
installed now they are few let's go back
to suffer keys now they are few config
lines you need to add so copy that copy
back to Emacs now I open my innate file
again and paste it here
okay control hex one to expand the panel
now
so this is required Suffolk is loaded
then you said a key binding I mean on
keyboard layout code is a standard
layout but I'm using borax so let me
change that DVLA kay then after that you
just turn it on stuff like he's one
means turned on so I'm gonna select this
code then then call give region so
that's loaded everything is good now
actually accept like easy song you see
now I can you can see my keystrokes at
the bottom here so you see I press G it
actually just to backward forward
without pressing control you know I can
I can navigate my course are very easy
or delete stuff or redone do you know
and do the whole TV the whole thing and
do so so that's that that's it so that's
the installation from you know default
playing cannoli max but now I'm going to
okay say this say say save this I'm
going to use my setup because you know
because I have lots of other command I'm
going to use my setup to show you give
you an intro of Safa keys so lets you
know get out of this control X
control X control C exit you know I
haven't used Emacs Deepak Advani for a
while so okay so now I'm back in my
Emacs settings so let's go to refresh so
that's the unit we just created we don't
need it anymore quick close close now on
this pan you can actually see what
command I'm using on this pan like every
time I do a command you can see it show
right here and the keystroke I'm using
the keys the keys I'm using is actually
black so if you are using quad eat or
something but anyway let's let's get on
with it
so I'm going to wait didi this directory
yes and and develop of yes and I made a
backup just before I did that
so that's today's date so let me rename
the file close close that okay so this
is my Emacs settings you know lots of
stuff help eyes my packages so anyway so
so soft like he's there are two months
command mods and insert mod when you are
you insert mod like I press a key to
switch to insert mod you can see the
command code is sawfly insert mode
activate when is about anything I type
is just inserting text now okay
switch to insert mode and switch back to
command mode
he said mark my mod you can tell by the
cursor shape like I press a key which is
for a cue and and and now I'm in insert
mode now I press another key which is an
key on my keyboard I'm using a Kinesis
advantage to a fancy keyboard so n keys
near my thumb so now I mean insert
milanesa mod any kinky I type
is doing is doing commands like those
are commands are just cold let's see
okay why is my key not showing any more
so anyway so so that's so command mod so
one way to tell is the cursor shape
inside mount command mod in some alchemy
mod and you can change the key that that
switch the mod to to almost any key you
want like you can you know there's a
customization I can show you right so
anyway so insert modern commandment so
what what's what does the command mod do
okay so this here's the basics the
command mod
so in general on the right hand side the
cursor keys up down left right
the ijkl keys and a basically the right
hand side right hand keys are all moving
cruisers yeah let me show you show you
quickly so up down up down left backhoe
chart right look at the other panel so
right up down left right and I can move
by word left and right which is this key
backward and move to the right and
beginning of a blind or end of line and
I can move by paragraph like you know it
it moves like paragraph which is really
convenient basically so so that's the
right hand side keys that's the the
basics the these six keys are the most
important and and the edge is for
beginning of file and S is for end of
file so let me show you beginning of
lying or beginning fire like if you
press wait wait so
yeah HP is beginning of line and if you
press it again it's a beginning of the
paragraph and if you repeat you'll just
go you know above paragraph so with
these two commands you almost never have
to press page up and down anymore they
just move by unit in your code or
whatever you are editing so so back here
so you can see so on so that's the right
hand on the left hand is usually editing
tasks for example like I it's you know
copy that create a new buffer wait let's
do that again
so move up here copy copy and copy and
create a new buffer paste you know so
when I do copy and paste those are the
left hand keys so you can you can look
at the graph and you know learn it right
but but that's the basics so command mod
and insert one what what else I want to
show you so
okay I want to make this this intro
short so what was so what what else are
important oh yeah so so switching mod
okay instant mark my mod and and and
there are another concept which is
leader key commands so so with soft like
is you never have to press ctrl X
anymore
like never so in Emacs remember that
every command every key press is
actually bound to a key bound to a
command eventually so whatever you do
any Mac Emacs it's always a command call
in the end so any command you know for
example switch to buffer by T for the
piece control XP but in Sophocles is
just space F so let me even close that
so because that showing Safari and I can
actually I'm using I'm using more
actually I can press a key and show Iraq
yeah so let me show you the little key
commands so so instead of using control
X something or control X you know
control C or whatever control something
you instead of that you press a key
sequencing instead instead so when you
are in command mod you can I can switch
buffer by press control you so let me
show you control you so you see it it
pumped me to you know to to go to you
know the buffer I want it's it's just
calling this command switch took to
buffer so so in this way it's almost you
know all the commands instead of instead
of using ctrl key you just space
something key sequence you don't have to
hold it down so that that's the that's
the thing so that's the leader key for
commands that's my alarm clock that
tells me to get up and walk every half
an hour okay so that's I think that's a
basic ok ok there's a little bit more so
Emacs MX
you know that that the command for MX is
he's actually called execute extended
command and you can just press a to do
it you know like for example let me go
back here open a new buffer I just
pressed a you can see I press a and it
cause smacks smacks is a package that
that has more convenient function also
replacement for execute extended command
so you can press a when you are in
command mod or you can press space
return so let me try that space return
you see in the this time is calling the
execute extended command
so that's how you do meta and you don't
have to commit anymore because all the
key is for meta the commands have a some
other more easier keying supply keys and
also the standard control key shortcuts
like control over open control in for
new buffer control Z for and - they are
also supported by default but you can
turn turn it off so in this way actually
when you are using Suffolk is you you
can still use all the Emacs default keys
if you want you know so it's convenient
for if you are still learning it you can
you know fall back to Emacs keys just
make sure you turn this off and such
forward you know the default search for
word is control X but here I just cuz
that it just be just a single key P so
in for example P and I can search let's
say Phi you know then I press arrow for
next backward arrow for people you know
so so that that is the basics so I I
think that you know I'm Ted I just want
to give you a video demo introduction so
for those of you you know who might find
it difficult you know after video you
know it might be much easier so you get
a sense they are tutorials
you know this tutorial so you can read
and customization and also if you are
using a fancy keyboard
you know like kinases or you know like
this one this one is from a friend you
know he sent me this picture which is
very nice he's learning it and this is
almost like half a year ago so if you
are using fancy keyboard that's good but
if you are using no more keyboard like a
laptop it also works because you know I
try to make it so that it works well for
normal keyboard as well as in terminal
you can also use it right in terminal so
let's see what else
so these tutorials you can go through in
customization and recently I also added
a discussion on reddit so if you have
questions I mean usually like I'm the
guy to you know answer questions but
sometimes you don't want to you don't
want me to answer questions like you
want to ask other people's experiences
so you want to maybe criticize that you
or you want to compare to Evo mod or God
mod or you know you can you can do that
in this forum so that that that is it so
I hope you like it I hope you like it
and if you have questions coming on you
know the youtube comment
okay that's it thanks thank you for
watching