hello everyone so today I'm going to
show you how to write JavaScript to
create a part math curves for example
this is a spiral this is equal angle
spiral or called log spiral and I have
some example here all these are created
in JavaScript you can see they are not
static images you see they are SVG's so
these are examples it is so this is one
of my project
and my project is to let me show you
some so this is my friend curves website
you see there are lots of very
interesting curves this is probable ah
this is conic sections you know I wrote
this in around 1997 1995 - you know 1999
basically so there are so many curves
and they are written in Mathematica
except this this image this image is
generating in Perret so so these curves
are extremely interesting because you
know you know about parabolas hyperbolas
ellipse you know they are all these
curves parabola conic sections
you know so-called conic sections they
include hyperbola parabola and Lisp they
are they are shadows of a bowl of a of a
sphere as you can see the red point is a
light source and you shine if you shine
a red light source above the ball then
you get it is a shadow and if you
move the light point below the ball you
get hyperbola and if the light bone is
just at the same level as the ball the
top of the ball what you get is Elise
elite not a parabola so so above the
ball at least under the ball below the
top of the ball hyperbola and on the
same level
parabola so they are also conic sections
anyway so these curves are extremely so
many very interesting properties yeah so
I wrote them these are written in
Mathematica you can see for example I
still have Mathematica notebooks you can
download yeah on the web
and they are pretty old they are like 10
years old some of them may have being
updated a little bit but I haven't been
coding Mathematica for a long time but
anyway so today I'm going to show you
how to do these in JavaScript you see
this project I'm going to I think this
year 2019 I'm going to convert them all
to JavaScript so I'm gonna show you how
to do that in JavaScript so I wrote some
prototypes you know they are you can see
it here
I have JavaScript down they are you know
prototypes so it's let's start so we're
gonna do this without using any
JavaScript framework it's all gonna be
just raw JavaScript so does that sound
good
let's try so now it's 135 let's try this
for I think 20 minutes over 30 minutes
I'm not sure I can do it but I'll give
it a shot so 125 135 right now
at 2:00 2:00 o'clock so okay so we're
gonna write a JavaScript so what are we
gonna do and see
um you see where we want to start okay
let's just start a CH t ml 500 ok let's
create the new file save it as test 1
HTML so it's
okay let's say test one so there is HTML
file copy the path close it right
because I put it here let's get rid of
title so test one close link to it
so there it is test one so you're gonna
here and you're gonna start a JavaScript
page so let's go to the directory coffee
yet
well actually it's just
create a new file name in JavaScript and
link it
now the file is empty of course create
yes empty and we gonna just say because
showing browser it's empty
and we can say for example you can close
it show this in Safari and show it the
debugger
ain't no wanna come
wait why is that okay
control shift I don't race Chrome for
some reason that's not what we want
so it's I mean command ship that
launches it should be command option I
okay so you can see the output hi there
is the is the output so we're gonna
write some JavaScript right here and to
protocol first of all so how is it done
you know okay so to plot we're gonna use
SVG so if you don't know SVG let me show
you what are we doing how are we gonna
create the curves how we're going to
prod graphics with JavaScript
there are two ways let's go to actually
let's go to Safari
so there are two ways to create graphics
in JavaScript
one is SVG the other one is canvas and
you can you can read my blog you can
just search sorry cameras versus
SVG c VG JavaScript
so there it is there it is my website
you can you can you can go to it SVG
that's my SVG tutorial course that we
are just going to use local my local
files so there are two ways SVG and
canvas now chemische is basically bitmap
basically you creating a bitmap image
and we're gonna use SVG because SVG is
more suitable because SVG is basically
vector graphics meaning that instead of
you know pixels you know you create
pixels for each you know the window
viewport you actually draw lines like
you specify line from what point to what
point but let me show you it's very
simple recipes you know SVG basic so SVG
so SVG is just XML so this is X SVG this
is the source code you can see let's
copy so if we copy that go here Oh sad
cosine now this remember this is our you
know HTML basic HTML page now we just
paste that now look look at this this is
SVG tag it's a sweet and hate and then
close it here then you have this part
this this part is just a line it says a
line x1 y1 that's the starting point and
x2 y2 that's the end point and if we
show end style back if we show in
browser you can see it creates a lie so
so this is what SVG is I mean that's
that's basically that's all there it is
- SVG of course it's you know you got
that I mean that's the the structure as
as
of SVG so all you have to do is just to
create these tax VG tax with their
coordinates to create to draw things and
you can just go back to Safari so you
know you can draw a line basically you
you have several elements you can draw a
rectangle using the react element and
you can specify round corners circle
HISP and polygons and it gets more
complex but basically that that's a
basic you just the basic the basic is
just to create the SVG tag with
different elements it's just like it
HTML so for example here is a croc yeah
so so we cannot draw a we're going to
draw a curve what curve to draw let's
see let's say let's draw a beautiful one
let's try that shall we
this is beautiful this is this is
usually known as spirograph 144 okay we
out of time yeah so you see you can see
how they are generated by rolling
circles on another yeah we can try this
we can try to draw that okay so let's
knit start then curse this console so
close that so we're gonna stop drawing
SVG okay first of all we need a type
element to place our SVG so it's just
give it an random number here
so here and we're gonna add some CSS
style let's say border
solid solid thing red okay
switch to HTML mod and didn't walk
because the grass didn't work because we
don't have things there okay that didn't
work because crash board a solid thing
Oh red not great there it is and we're
gonna say we're gonna put let's just
start okay so that's a dive so first of
all in our JavaScript we're gonna insert
a SVG tag how do you do that let's go
back to SVG reference is VG basics
so we cannot use the tag I don't
remember so there it is here is okay
yeah that's how we want to do it hmm we
can just copy this mmm you know that's
not let's do it one by one copy okay we
got 15 more minutes I don't think I can
make it so create a SVG element so yeah
remove that save view viewing Safari
okay okay we got that and we want to
okay we have SVG element you can see by
control hub hi
script dive oh yeah we create an element
but we didn't insert it this is this is
you know it's quite painful to work with
um I don't remember how to insert it
back to a transcript in depth to change
element well actually what we want to do
is to kill element by ID
and app in child I think it's just right
I paint child so X except in child SVG
one
so we basically adding the SVG element
to to the anchor to these two here so
save it I think I need a document yeah
I'm pretty sure
yeah
yep
that's what we need save
new is not an object evaluating except
in child X get element by ID help in
child type error new is not an object
what
okay some of the same tanks with the
pain child I think
I have encoded JavaScript for like four
months
also so javascript is pretty painful is
it's the worst thing I think it's a
worst language the way you work with
JavaScript on the webpage of all the
languages I know
for example compared to Perl Python PHP
Ruby :
I would say javascript is a worst not
just a language but also the dome the
way Tom walks and it's an extremely bad
so anyway so let's so what we want to do
now is to create incident yeah we should
use this instead of JSON element that's
better than a pen child actually but
even targets
so that she'd walk I should why
document.getelementbyid d and why is it
not working
yeah this is ID not class we need to ID
save it now let's see
reload there it is now let's put a
circle there shall we it's for the
circle okay what is what is the scene x4
circle no hanumant
we want to go to SVG reference
no circle is SVG basics
yeah the the thing could be very painful
but the thing is we're gonna write a
library you know to make it everything
simple so we want to create a tag like
that so there you know there are a few
ways to do that actually
one way the easiest way is in just use
in HTML and see but well the more proper
way is to actually create this tag and
append it like like the way we did with
the SVG tag but it's more cumbersome
let's just do that so circle create
element that and we want to create
circle element then we want to set
attribute okay see us he said attribute
that's right set attribute we want to
set c/y - let's just say 50 yeah I
remember how painful it is in CX CY 6 cy
how painful it is but of course you can
use libraries but they are they are
pretty much amazed as well you know in
JavaScript the community the way you do
things you load a hundred libraries
nobody has no idea like it becomes the
programming becomes you don't have any
idea what libraries do you just load
hundreds you know 100 something typical
project we all need 100 libraries you
know like you loading libraries and each
one load staying other libraries and you
really don't like even 5 lines these
libraries you know most programmers have
no idea how to do things wrong but well
so you know that's why we are doing it
you know I just want to show you how to
do it so this is how anyway so CX CY is
say 50 and ha
so we are adding this attribute of
course I mean I'm showing the most basic
way now once you have this you start to
write a function you know you start to
write a function such that for example
how a function create circle then you
just for example XY radius you know X a
and Y is the coordinate n radius then
you just put a circle you know I have
written a library already it's it's this
one it's actually written in typescript
but let's look at type script so so far
it's you know a few hundred lines 500
nice and here is the generated
JavaScript so you know for example to
create SVG that's such for SVG the area
is to use this function f creative SVG
then you just
this is JavaScript JavaScript you know
yeah so javascript you have to compile
it you know because we are using
typescript create SVG here is our
function yeah here's a function create
SVG and here are the parameters you know
the parent is the element you want to
attach it to with and hate is the oh
yeah that's the SVG element so this
function basically does these and these
let's put that together so that function
basically does this the these three
lines and let's say circle so here's a
q8 SVG circle you know you just give it
X & Y and radius and an element to
attach it to but we are good we are
going to do a raw one so so this new I
associate attribute so now after we set
attribute then we we have to set the
style okay so let's do that
sent us down let's just say that feel
yellow stroke blue stroke with five then
we gonna attach it to the SVG so so it's
gonna be a paint child lets me g1
appendchild
suck now let's hope it works let's go to
there it is okay
actually we I can't you know I cannot
finish the sort of plan the plan is
we're gonna draw these the product okay
should I continue
umm morning should I continue
yeah actually if I continue and for
another 30 minutes I'm not sure I can
finish it you know that this seems
complicated but actually it's not that
complicated I come let me show you one
so these are all variations they just
differ they differ by parameter but
basically they are parametric plot so
here's a formula you can for them you
know just parametric plot
yeah so to to write them to to show them
do we yeah we yeah you could be possible
we could finish in 30 another 30 minutes
but it may not because it's not actually
not that complicated
well let's but yeah let's stop it now
because right now I mean it's it's
simple you get idea of how to do things
and that serves a purpose and maybe
Nikki next video will do that so let me
know if you like to see that in in the
video you know next next week or you
know next few days let me know you can't
in comments if you like to see that
otherwise thank you for watching that's
it for today bye