good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of books on top show today is
October 1st Tuesday Nyak Rock a.m. San
Francisco time
good morning Bartholomew so what is
today's topic type a topic okay I'm just
going to start random so let's refresh
this window and random okay
so go to South Hawk show and on the left
you can see all my Emacs commands
okay create a new page Saur Saur talk
show okay stop these thing okay back to
Emacs san talk show today's date is our
new page make a link copy paste it here
open it
showing browser okay random topic today
random topic so what's up san talk show
so let's go to let's see what's in
keywords keyboards drugs what what is
here something I want to talk about
today let's see let's go to I woke up
about three hours ago four hours ago
and so keyboards we talked about that
yesterday and keyboards let's go to so
yesterday we talked about yesterday we
talked about d3.js lots of things math
see Xiao none proportional font no mo no
space proportional found for coding
actually I just reverted back and
JavaScript drain and Mathematica and
stuff
okay so what what is today so let's see
cause that snot talk show so let's go to
my home page and let's go to programming
let's see what's new fix colon sink yeah
so we you know so we can talk about
Golan Emacs Python stuff stuff in a
description I'm kind of I'm kind of lost
right now because I'm kind of lost right
now
so web dev micropayment Michael Feynman
this is a Asian article this is 2010
you know Michael paymon the concept
began you know even back in year 2000
and over the years we just never had
anything you know many companies come
and go like at one time you have flipper
or something then you know especially
among the open source
you know there's several companies that
came in one anyway
Mike was micropayment the story of XML
the story of XML there is this this this
chant jargon chant phrase that says be
conservative in what you send be liberal
in what you accept that is the most
damaging chant that happens happened in
in the industry let me let me find the
original author
so bottom you say something let's see
let's see if I can find it JavaScript
actually actually search for it search
for that in this directory search or
HTML files
be conservative in what you sent be
liberal in what you accept that is the
mantra for HTML 4 HTTP servers you know
for treating HTML for example many
people make a lot errors in HTML for
example and the tacks are not closed ok
let's let's look at some of my articles
and let's just talk start to talk about
that ok
the story of a XML and in fact that
mantra is reason one is responsible for
the rise of XML XML is became very
popular
it becomes the future from around year
2000 to 2008 you know everyone is
thinking pushing for it to the degree -
it's so significant so popular to the
degree that many UNIX software and the
apples of ware and including Microsoft
software they started to change their
config files into XML format you know
like before it used to be you know
especially UNIX config files you just
save furniture of lines each line is a
unit semantics semantics unit unit then
they they change it to XML format that's
how popular it is so it has a lasting
effect I mean today good morning Quinn
deck today XML is kind of dead nobody
cares about for it you know html5
replaced it so XML is dead but however
during the day C was extremely popular
for for almost 10 years starting around
1999 is it has lasting effect in in the
sense that in on a Mac for example and
UNIX and also Microsoft you can still
see many software whose config files are
XML files so so that is kind of a proof
evidence you can trace if you are young
- you know how the impact of XML
popularity was so why did XML rise you
know we have HTML why did XML rise
because HTML backing from 1995 to about
year 2000 - every browser tries to
create their own tags for example CSS ok
let me show you some of the examples
HTML you have this marquee you have this
markys let's see let's see where I can
find it
you see this this was very popular back
then this is in fact this this tag
marquee is invented by ie Microsoft
Internet Explorer around year 2000 or so
you know and the most famous tag is the
blink okay the most famous tag is a
blink let's show you it's not up show so
let me copy the topics here so we have a
record of what we were talking about
Marty's okay let's see Marquis swapping
control
yeah that's another story of XML and
HTML dark-type validation xua compatible
and why do I hate hackers that's that's
a that's let's say oh the article that's
from 2011 okay so today we talked about
these smart keys so let me I'm talking
about the history of XML and also the
major part of the the hacker culture
why did XML right rose and and how we
got the phrase you know the this phrase
be conservative in what you send Balibo
in what you have said every programmer
was quoting it every day almost every
day this from about from about 1995 to
2010 let's say maybe 2005 no 2008 okay
so back then in HTML every browser is
creating new tags the most famous being
blink you probably have heard so the the
tag is blink it looks like that okay now
today it's gone in browsers you can no
longer have it like this okay so the
blink tag okay so
it doesn't work in browsers anymore you
know before when you have a blinky this
text or whatever is inside it will blink
you know like every two times four
seconds something like that so it
doesn't work anymore because about
around 2015 Google removed it firefox
removed it so you know they removed it
but if you are in IE you know if you are
an old version of ie perhaps it will
still work okay let me show you that
blink tag so blink tag was invented by
Netscape you know Nick netscape browser
and this is one of the most you know it
was very annoyed by people uses everyone
hated you know hate in kind of english
sense because they hated but but they
hated you know every hacker type of
people like programmers like us hate
hate it but however it's very popular
you know like most people are not you
know the hacker types they just use it
because you have blinking text that is
flashy you know it's dramatic that makes
your webpage stands out so Netscape is
the blink is the most popular
non-standard tag invented by Netscape
back back back then 1995 to 2000
Netscape was inventing tags all over the
face all the time and also you know
javascript is amended by Netscape you
know because every browser company you
know back then you have Netscape versus
ie they are trying to create new tags
you know and in their browser you know
it's not supported by other browsers so
and so ie followed you know ie invented
the Marquis tag that does things like
that so you create a situation where
every corporation just create whatever
you know they want in and it's a mess
and that is
standard you know becomes the very
popular you know HTML standard they
people started programmers started to
say oh we need to follow standard
standard is so important standard
standard you know they chanted like a
mantra so that's back then in you know
from 1995 to year 2000 every browser is
creating tags then the and people okay
and and and and what about this phrase
we consulting be conservative in what
you send believer in what do you accept
that phrase that phrase is what made you
know the messy okay let me let me
retract let me backtrack okay so back
then everyone is creating new new tags
you know new tags so when if you are
programmer it's it's it's a hell because
then ie does one thing that's supported
in ie but the Netscape if you show your
website on this scape it does something
you something else so if you are
creating HTML pages you have to check
every browser that's a situation and in
by the way by by year 2000 apple also
have an version of ie and apple also
have few other browsers that is you know
Apple don't doesn't have Safari yet
Safari came around around 2006 2004 so
so so every browser is creating tags and
that's one thing the other thing is the
other thing is hTML is a mess for
example for example let's say let's go
to let's look at this HTML page okay so
this this is my HTML page right suppose
I want something bold something okay
showing browser see so you see you got
something bold but suppose I made a
mistake I forgot
suppose I also want italic okay
showing browser so something italic
right bold and italic let's say vote but
now suppose I made mistake this happens
a lot you know so this suppose I
mismatched my tag like that then what
happens you see it's no shows okay so so
what and what what if I missing a I'm
missing a greater greater sign
let's try showing browser you see it
still works so why does it work because
because of this mantra okay because this
mantra this is the most harmful mantra
be conservative in what you sent be
liberal in what you accept so why does
this all work I mean even though it's
you know clearly so bad you know the
syntax is in please if it's a
programming language it basically it's a
syntax error it won't work okay but
however you HTML it's you know loose you
know the HTML compilers try to make it
work they try or they can why does this
happen because vast majority of people
they are not very technical especially
when it comes to HTML creators you know
they are not very thick technical so
they make these arrows all the time you
know they don't know what this compiler
means they don't know what you know
every means that they are not you know
programmers they are not you know
professional programmers so when I
create a page like that and if you are a
browser what you're gonna do well the
best thing to do for making money is to
try to make it work even though the
syntax is incorrect
you know because then then if I'm a user
you know I don't necessarily know that I
made a mistake
you know I you know typically I don't
know so I show in browser for example
you ie it works okay then some
people complained my webpage does not
walk in netscape browser why because
because I have a bad coat you know the
code is wrong that that is not supposed
to work but however in IE it works but
to me non-technical person I would think
II's better because I don't even know I
got the error so you know oh I know is
that every time I have web pages it
works in IE it does not work in Netscape
or vice versa
you know so you have this situation so
if you have a browser maker it's your
it's to your interest to you know if you
want to make a lot money you you want
people to like your browser you just you
just try to ignore the errors you know
that that is why this phrase become
popular among programmers among the
programmer idiots every everywhere you
see back then today you have something
else today's program are idiots in some
other you know many other examples so
some programmers started to chant this
face like every day you can see among
programmers every day specifically in
particular of these hacker types this
UNIX philosophy types these Python
people Perl people you know they think
they are you know they know better than
you they tell you what to do they tell
you to follow southern styles style
guide idioms and things things like that
and they will quote this all the time be
conservative in what you sent believing
what you accept you know because they
don't think they don't have a brain this
these are the typical programmers and
why do they say that because you know
because you know so it's better ok but
however after you know five years people
programmers started to realize they
started to realize oh this is actually a
bad thing when you have an arrow it
should you know the browser should tell
you you got an arrow the browser should
not you know simply just try to make
things up you know and and show it you
know because if you do that you know if
every browser does that every you know
browser they create their own tags and
they do not pass the document correctly
you know they add you know they try to
you know add things so the behavior is
different so to the programmer when you
create a website especially with
JavaScript then its hell because you
have to test with every browser you know
so this idea started programmer started
started to realize this idea and they
started they began to realize this
phrase is actually bad okay you can
actually leave me if let me find you the
origin of this phrase there is one
programmer that I created that phrase
okay let's see can conservative by this
guy okay Jon Postel this phrase we be
conservative in what you send believer
in what you accept is is is said by this
guy this is this guy is a internet
pioneer so he was born in 1943 he died
in 1998 okay so he is you know he is he
is a non-prime principally for being the
editor of the request for comments
requests for comments he is one of the
earliest standard for UNIX stuff you
know and it's a worst possible
request for comment typically I could
you know really common so anyway
he he is a guy who created that phrase
and it became very popular extremely
popular every programmer chanted every
hacker types of program which ended
every day then after five years these
people started to realize that's wrong
okay because you know then you create a
prop the problems of each browser
you know behave differently you create
the hell
so program and so this is when this is
when the idea of XML rose why because it
solves to two problems one is stops
browsers from creating new tags
you see XML stands for extensible markup
language so instead of each browser just
creating tags so they created you know
the XML concept is that is that it's
it's extensible you don't have you don't
need browsers to seem to create a new
tag for you you you can you know you
have this uniform standardised syntax
that every browser if they want to
create something not necessary but you
know every corporation or every
organization they can create a new tag
if I want to and it's supposed to be is
alway are defined that is what XML is
about you see so that solves this you
know this arbitrary tank creating
problems by browsers so that XML solves
that problem
XML also solved the arrow problem the
parsing problem so one of the one of the
rule of XML is that if you have a syntax
error in XML for example if you are
missing if you are missing you know a
you know ending if you are missing a
bracket or if your tag is incorrect like
that then it should stop
you should not render it you know XML
that's one of the fundamental principle
of XML us you know it will not show up
in browser I mean if you view it in
browser you'll just tell you there's a
syntax 0 for example let's try it
okay so let's so let's go to diet copy
this file and copy write copy paste the
name XML so we have an XML version here
it's open it
we need to do something to it hold on a
second let me see if I can do that
remove the script remove Google script
and remove the Google ads let's see if
we can do that
okay so hold on second so okay let's not
use this browser you see you see when I
show this page XML page in the browser
it simply tells me that you see in
Safari it just says this page contains
the following arrows arrow on line one
had column to the start tag invalid an
element name yeah so this this is
invalid let's remove it let's let's try
it again
okay again it's wrong error on line four
eight column twelve
el arrow yeah so let's remove that
that's no oh these this this line
viewport is invented by Apple because
they want to show HTML because of the
iPhone when they amended iPhone they had
to invent this you know long story about
XML so anyway so now it's still arrow
arrow on line 38 so you get idea the one
of the core principle of XML is that if
there is an arrow the browser or
whatever application will not show it it
will simply tell you this arrow okay so
that's about that I mean let me go back
to let me quit Safari so on the other
hand if you show that it's exact same
page as HTML then it will display fine
just like this page so so XML serve the
two problems one is you know you know
stop browsers from creating arbitrary
tags the other problem is stop sub users
from creating bad syntax you know
because when you have a bad syntax the
browser will tell you right away
then then you will fix it you know you
will try to fix it and here it's valid
so this way this way you know the same
HTML source code Oh X X HTML source code
should be
this rate in any browser any you know
standard conforming browser so as a
developer you don't have to worry about
checking you know testing with 1000
browsers hold on a second my roommate
woke up you mean close the door so that
so that is why XML Rose and I think it's
a very good thing let me show you
actually a XML file so you go to my
programming programming blog and you go
to the RSS RSS I'm using the atom feed
so this is the RSS file file blog dot
XML so ISS has many versions one of them
is called atom so atom is a XML file so
you open it magnify so this is a use you
are seeing a XML file and it's it's XML
is very strict and regular you see every
tag must be closed you know it's
different from a HTML in XML every tag
must be have a corresponding close tag
and they must be close unless otherwise
I mean oh there there are two ways to
close the tag one is with a you know
closing tag the other way is with a
slash greater than sign okay so you see
this link tag it is also closed it's
closed by you know by just slash greater
than sign so anyway this is XML very
very regular you know like few days ago
we were talking about regularity of
syntax you know we were talking about
list Mathematica and Mathematica
systematic syntax and APL is also a
regular language syntax so XML is also
one of the language
whose syntax is you know like 99%
regular it's not 100% regular so X XML
is excellent okay in my opinion X XML is
very good so XML became very popular but
however they got killed by html5 around
2008 okay so so anyway the now we
conclude this concludes the talk about
about about this topic
the story of XML basically that's a
history of XML the evolution of XML okay
so I'm going to read the comments and
see how long have I been talking 30
minutes great so that was a great start
we focused on the topic topic of history
of XML and also again remember part of
this story is the hacker hacker
programmer culture specifically the
hacker types they chanted this phrase
you know be conservative in what you
send believer in what you accept which
is very damaging it damaged the you know
HTML the web industry for for about 10
years
okay
that's about that so let's read the
comments
green deck Windex says have you heard
about Russian IT companies like
Kaspersky Lab yes and Yandex yes are
they known in u.s. yes they they are
known in u.s. in fact they are often
frequently on on the news
Kaspar Kaspersky Lab is a virus company
you know the antivirus or various
research morwe a research company
something like that and you know I not
everyone knows it
you know programmers in USA you know
because there are so many topics so if
you don't study JavaScript if if your
job is not front-end you know web type
you may not know about XML or many
things related to the web for example so
but however if you work or if you are if
you are you know interested in security
issues virus then you we are in USA you
will hear about Kaspersky Lab often it's
kind of well-known so so but I don't
know any detail about that company I
think it's it's pretty big company
because I remember I read you know this
some it's it's quite serious when it
comes to virus and more where this kind
of thing it can get very serious in the
sense that it involves the government
you know the FBI the CIA you know as we
know today all these government
organizations you know virus is critical
it's a weapon you know it's a weapon in
software you can monetize your enemies
you know infrastructure information
things like that or you know it's it
said that for example us some company I
forgot maybe USA or something
created a virus you know that that
disables the nuclear facility in Iran
something like that you know if you read
Wikipedia you know security or you'll
find it you know there are tons of store
about viruses every day so and you know
it's so it's very significant the
cryptography all these issues so and
also China every government you know
China is also doing their things so we
for example we have heard that China has
in field they have they have they are
you know they have hacked Google Gmail
you know they are they have hacked
Google Gmail and stuff they have you
know in many cases many young people's
when it comes to these things a lot of
young people are doing it like teenagers
they walk into CIA
you know they hacked into CIA or FBI
stop stuff like that so I don't know
much about virus how they works you know
it's very yeah I don't know how they
works you have to it's a big it's a big
topic I mean it's a very big and
in-depth topic you have to be focused on
that to study that thing you know and
today we have the USB problem like
you're just plugging a USB and you know
then your computer will be
because they have you know USB it
appears that the USB protocol itself it
can Bob it cannot be solved
you know the USB protocol itself has
some vulnerabilities you know that's a
term they use so called vulnerabilities
so such that there's no way I think
there's no way to permit prevent it you
know you just you know so it's a it's a
it's a mess it's a major problem and
Yandex is a Russian search engine that's
what I know because people are talking
about Google replacement
well Yandex is not exactly a Google
replacement it's just I think it's a
most popular search engine used in
Russia right right green deck I know
this because
I pay attention to these kind of things
you know so I I know this for example in
China
Baidu and several others very popular
search engines in Russia in Russia you
have Yandex I think and in Russia you
also have several you know popular
social networks that's popular in Russia
like like like Facebook or Twitter
around in USA yeah so good mornings send
center yeah it's a rare case where some
company is more popular than Google so
it's more popular in Google I didn't
know that I mean it's sure it's not
bigger than Google right
you mean I know it's more popular than
Google in Russia anyway
revenue 2.19 billion oh yeah so that's
pretty big so let's see Google how much
revenue is Google Google Wikipedia so
Google revenue let's see
industry founded founder headquarters
area served a number of employees they
don't say revenue here we have to go to
alphabet I think
so we go to alphabet or revenue 136
billion okay so that's a hundred times
more than Yandex yeah okay so what about
Baidu so let's check the China's by do
this this is the most popular search
engine in China and it's owned by it's
owned by I don't know but anyway the
let's see revenue revenue
okay Chinese Chinese yen UN is hundred
billion so hundred billion divided by
seven roughly so it's about thirteen
billion US dollars fourteen billion US
dollars okay yeah so that's about that
so bathroom use of bingo and good
morning dingo so so dingo says i like
you on the x disc program the fact they
have a linux version is pretty neat disc
program but it is that virus virus
checking program
okay so dingo where are you from again
dingo bottom you say is do you use VCS
for anything
VCS what is VCS I know CVS / VCS virtual
version control system well yeah I use
kit a gives github for example I mean
not well I also use github but I use
skip for example I go to my Emacs page
CD ok and let's see git status ok ok so
that's my Emacs
oboe Emacs start oak website so we have
I made these changes
so let's commit get add ok git add git
commit ok it's committed then usually I
think - I used to sync to my website to
a a website that's alternative to github
but it's all it's free for personal use
I forgot the name but anyway I haven't
been doing that it's owned by Alex
something now
anyways bitbucket I think it's bit back
pocket
I haven't been you know anyway so yes I
do use git so I use kit and before gate
I also used for example let's let me
show you ok go to you max Bob cross a
max blog go to language tutorials before
kids I was using SVN so I have a
tutorial here SVN it's kind of dead you
know
today every everyone is using it and
before SVN
I was using CBS CBS is the granddaddy of
version control CBS ok get lab is also
good yeah okay so let's see so father
may say it's do you see a sense in
comparing Jason and XML Oh Jason is
pretty much it's better than X XML okay
because XML you know the the reason
Jason Jason is created by this guy okay
this what's his name say it okay
type it Jason Jason is created by this
guy I have several articles about him so
Jason so let's so let's go to my Emacs
tutorial let's go to Emacs keys and
let's go to Emacs pinky and let's go to
Y Emacs keys are painful now this this
article discuss in detail why the Emacs
default keys are the worst possible okay
and and in the bottom you will see oh
not this page okay so not okay anyway
that's about that but there is a page
where I talk about let me see
okay that's interesting I might tell you
about that
[Music]
why Emacs keys are painful okay so
anyway so I don't know where is that
modernization of Emacs okay go to go to
the section Emacs modernization now this
page is the index of all articles
related to things that I think Emacs
should change to make it more popular
and okay so this first article
modernization of Emacs simple changes
Emacs should adopt in my opinion if you
just change these things Emacs use a
wheel double within let's say within two
years I guarantee you but however and
and this change are easy to do you know
it just takes Emacs dev two days then
it'll happen
but however you know I wrote this in
2006 it's not going to happen because
you know the Emacs people is a code
they will never adopt these changes
anyway so in this article at the bottom
you will see this guy crack fold okay
crack fold let me show that in one
second let me go to the talkshow page
let's put the topics here so we can
remember
okay and the SV and we talked about SVN
okay and then we talked about Baidu
Yandex but I do Yandex Google popular
search engines and stuff okay close that
close that what he sees oh this is XML
example cause that story of XML close
that Marky's close that okay show this
so we were talking about this guy okay
the jason-- jason-- versus XML okay so
we were talking about Jason versus XML
okay and we need to go to that web page
so open you paste here so on this page
modernization of Emacs simple changes
Emacs should adopt at the bottom you
will see look at look at this ad this is
ad this ad is is yeah this ad must be
addressing the target of this ad is
American left you know who hates Trump
so this ad you know make a fund of Trump
he says Trump ends another Obama era
program in blah blah blah recalculate
your house payments you know so in USA
you know you have you know people are
trying to buy a house so you know they
you want to click on that anyway that's
an ad so anyway so so on this page at
the bottom I give many explanations and
free and frequently asked questions
you know I saw I suggest some changes
people should adopt so that I guarantee
Emacs user will double within two years
but you know they want they want I know
you know because Emacs is a code and
every time I write you know opinions of
like that people will attack you like I
talked about this many times in my past
videos or people will call you a troll
they are attack you they think you are
idiot they think you are 100
saying you know you they think you are
you know they think you are a bad person
without thinking at all they don't it's
like you know you just because it's like
a coat you know you have these thing in
acts in common least in purl groups in
Python like every time you say something
negative or you know contrary to to to
some of those people you know what
hacker types they tell you what to do
you know they attack you so and you know
so I went when I write this page you
know people those you will say oh no
that's not true because this or that you
know for example so I have this section
frequently asked questions you know some
people say oh oh yeah you are wrong
because I find scratch paper useful okay
then I explained you know no you are a
idiot okay
then people will say oh the maitake is
logical it shouldn't be renamed to oat
okay then I explained oh you are idiot
you know one of the one of the
suggestion is that I suggest you know
Emacs in has you have meta keys right
everyone knows where it came from it
came from this absolute Lisp keyboard
the keyboard from this machine okay you
see that meta it's a physical actual
physical key called meta but that but
this keyboard has been gone for 30 years
now you know when I wrote this pad
article that this keyboard has has
disappeared nobody knows for 15 years
nobody have ever seen it unless you are
a historian you know most programmers
did they don't know the meta came from
didn't they never seen this keyboard
okay so so that's why you should not
code meta you know he Emacs you should
just call it out because by default on a
Mac on Windows on Linux
when you start Emacs the Alt key by
default that's that's meta that's you
know that's meta you know that's so in
practice in theory and in practice
there's no matter key anymore it's just
old key you know so you should you know
just don't use the name meta
just say oh you know changing Emacs it's
very easy to change this okay in
documentation you know just change it
but the Emacs people you know they will
not listen they will not have it because
why I can tell you why because Mehta you
know the Mehta is it has a hacker
association this UNIX philosophy
you know whenever you have something
like could you so that it's like it's
like a cool jargon it's like chewing
machine lambda calculus tail recursion
monad you know all these kind of jargons
again so you like you know so these
hacker types of programmers they love
the meta when when they see MIT has
super hyper they get excited you know
because not because it's actually
practical or efficient or anything like
that because just you know simply by the
name meta super high but it gets them
excited you know they want to talk about
it you know like the list mark o/s cow
you know these fancy things so so that's
why you know this is why you know part
you know this is the one of the
significant reason this Emacs people
will not change it because you know most
you only you know people like to talk
about that it became it became kind of
like the identity issue of Emacs like
when you say meta what do you think of
you think of Emacs you know it becomes
like a proud identity issue you think
just like for example the rainbow flag
for example the rainbow flag the rainbow
today is associated with what you know
with case right the case not just case
the LGBT you know the casein and
lesbians and trans community and queer
so you go to unicorn page let me show
you
so you go to Unicode page you go to
whether turn on auto click then you go
to whether you see you got this rainbow
you know on Twitter you're on social
network you will often see it what is
that that that is now becomes
identification for you know associated
with gays in you know that community in
the same way in the same way the meta is
associated with Emax you know so it can
be cooked become that like that anyways
we digress so so on this page but anyway
so on this page I also mentioned I
mentioned you know I was explaining many
things you know history of the keys and
so on so that these people yeah they can
listen again you know if you are
thinking type of people you read this
page you're kind of you agree
you know let's say 80% of it like you
are know right away but most people are
not did they are they are just following
code code you know whatever code you are
in including the open-source ideology
free software foundation ideology you
just chant you just chant it every day
so anyway on this page I also mentioned
fold Crockford guy okay this video
is one-hour video I highly recommend it
this video the title is the title is
Crockford on JavaScript Volume one the
early day the early years okay so
supposedly he is going to explain the
history of JavaScript okay well actually
that's not a case by the way crawford he
invented jason he is also the guy he is
the one that the guy who is responsible
responsible for making javascript
popular beginning around 2008 okay he is
a one
we'll begin to make JavaScript popular
and also the functional programming
features in JavaScript popular because
before before 2008 every programmer
think javascript is the worst possible
you know nobody no hacker types
programmers respect JavaScript you know
they think it's it's for you know
designers what for for stupid people
that's what people think but he made it
he made JavaScript popular so he's so
anyway he so in this video this video is
came out around I think 2012 wait 2012
yes
no 2010 this video is created in 2010 he
gave a talk back then Yahoo I think you
know back then yeah ed yahoo so he gave
a talk but anyway the actual content of
this talk is actually about the history
of of computing okay it's not this this
this Volume one it has it's a series
okay so you have volume one I think you
have two and three but anyway this first
one is not about history of JavaScript
at all rather it's about the history of
computing in the early days around
nineteen you know 1970s 1980s to 1990s
so I highly recommend you watch this
video because they because you will
learn a lot of you know opinions you
know how programming languages what
people are thinking back then you know
if you know you you you watch this video
in fact it's it's almost like watching
many of my videos what I'm trying to
tell you you know what do you think you
know like if you are a typical program
of today what do you think think is true
is actually just patently false you know
like most of the things you think is
true what you know you think this way is
better or programming styles or
programming idioms or what should be
right you know the correct correct way
to do something it's all wrong it's it's
more likely those ideas is
actually the worst idea possible
meanwhile some other ideas you think is
the worst those are the best if you look
at the programming language history you
know you you see so I highly recommend
this video ok now I'm mentioning him
because he invented Jason so let's talk
about Jason versus XML ok so so so XML
what we were talking about what's very
popular around 2000 to 2005 then Jason
came along around cheese and maybe 2006
or something I don't remember the name
Jason there's a website Jason thought
okay I think Jas is in eson good morning
jack hey Jack mone haven't seen you Jack
can we do a video can we can you I'm
thinking of gate creating a Chinese
website someone like a Billy Billy I do
you can you help me on that I don't know
if you want to but good morning Pablo
okay so Jason not not this how do you
Jas how do you spell it
geez JSON yeah Jason oke so this is his
website you know the rock folk this guy
the Ford guy is pre out now he's I
think 60 something maybe 76 he's you
know he's he's getting old he's I think
I think he's a you know you don't see
much of him talk much anymore because
he's gonna imperio 60 or 70 something
you know he's a you know when you get
old
you are going to retire you know it's
inevitable like like like me you know
I'm even though I'm just 51 but your
brain gets you know it's not as good
you're gonna retire so anyway he's an
old-school kind of guy and he you know
you see this this this graph this graph
is called there's a name to this graph
does anyone remember Jason right does
anyone remember this graph the name
something something called them I
remember I there's a name like train
graph or something anyway this this is
old-school graph you know this this this
illustration they are they are designed
to show the syntax
okay of something but you don't see it
today much anymore this is popular in
1990s so he's showing the syntax of
Jason you have first of all you have
object you know it's you have these
images so anyway Jason the rock folk guy
is very is an old-school guy and he is
found of the language self okay
JavaScript came from two languages I
talked about this before scheme Lisp and
self from scheme list it inherited the
functional programming kind of thing
like functional function returning a
function function taking a function
that's from skin and from self
JavaScript inherited the prototype
object system from the self language so
anyway so Jason versus XML well Jason is
much better for sure
Jason is you know it's it's a concise
and meanwhile XML is is it's too
elaborate it's too elaborate
okay so so let me read a comment and
that maybe that's it for today it's
anything else
yeah that one hour we let's yeah that's
two you know five minutes something like
three minutes five minutes so Green Dex
says I'm in Russia and China and their
satellites are the only countries where
Google is not most popular search engine
what do you mean that doesn't make sense
like I mean the grammatically what do
you mean
Yandex this is like Dropbox or Google
Drive oh yeah oh yeah so I didn't know
so good so so Yandex Russian is doing
that yeah China has their own version as
well
so Bartholomew says I have my own idea
my own kid idea what get your instance
and use it for most of my stuff I only
use github for stuff I won't need
specifically public ok what do you mean
get here thank you get here interesting
what so what's get here I find XY
interesting no you are idiot okay Pablo
says I'm just popping up to say one
important thing I recommend everybody
supporting Saudi through patron thank
you oh yes so Thank You Pablo for that
and thank you for your patron I also
like to thank Justine you know I'm not
very good about these things so many
people you know on patreon supported me
thank you guys like typically when you
when you watch youtube videos by other
people you know yeah let's talk about
them okay let's go to random YouTube
you know like oh this YouTube account
YouTube you know you go to YouTube
actually yes just go to youtube you know
like every video they most of the
youtubers you know they they create
YouTube videos they they have a one goal
you know the goal is to make money which
is not exactly you know what I'm doing
like like for example if if my goal is
just to make money if I the if that's
what I want to do that's most people
okay most people vast majority of people
on earth whatever they do basically is
focused on making money one goal you
know whatever they do it's almost always
the case vast majority of people and
that's reasonable because you know money
is food that's what you know what that's
what you do but anyway for YouTube
people you know most of people almost
anyone you know especially those kids
popular they are one go they just make
money you know so when it comes through
patreon you know people who support you
like you'll see almost in every video
they all say ok you can you know this
video is sponsored by something
something oh if they don't have a
sponsor yet they all say oh my youtube
is not on you know it's not monetized so
I rely on your you guys support to make
this video better you know everyone have
different styles depending on what they
do you know and every day you know there
are many different styles you know some
will just have those who paid you know
yesterday screw up like credit you know
something oh thanks - thank thanks
thanks to Scott Jason David you know
something for patreon you know that's
you know that's good I mean that's not
bad but but well my point my point is
you know that they are making money that
you have to do that it's kind of its
kind of like the marketing you know
think
anyway you know so I think some day next
day or tomorrow or something we can we
can talk about random you know random
YouTube topic this is because then you
have lots of very interesting things you
know this all kind of weird people
boogie the guy boogie and so anyway
thank you
Thank You Pablo and you know those
people supporting me anything else guys
anything else
Jason weather
okay then that's that's that's it that's
it I guess thank you guys for coming I
hope to see you guys next time
read your spam email after stream so how
did you send me something or something
okay I'll check my spam why do you not
read your spam email because there's so
many spam switch why should one read
what why would one read it there's so
many but actually I do there's some
sometimes the spam they ate some of the
valid emails but I haven't been checking
I haven't even been checking my emails
much since about half a year ago since
when I started to do video it's kind of
like almost avoiding it okay yeah I'll
check it so I guess