good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2020 august
4th tuesday 12 30
p.m in afternoon san francisco time
and uh so today's topic is going to be
emacs
and emacs list i'm going to do a live
coding
um first of all let me show you guys uh
the background image okay so you go to
uh the we got the background image of uh
emacs logo emacs sorry okay search for
emacs sorry you'll find it
so you go to you go to my blog
and
and let me show you this so so this is
interesting this is
emacs logo and here's the svg
images and here's a he here
is a photo i just found someone use this
trackball and put the emax logo there
uh so that's a background image for
today and this trackball is
one of the great trackball you can buy
it costs about 110 dollars
and um so you can go you can check out
on my website just search for
uh you know this url
uh eltrack sally l track trampo
and so here is the photo
and with the happy hacking keyboard
so that's about that that's the
background image okay so let's get
to the xsa talk show today
good morning guys alan cortez
el direo muskie
and bots and zetron crazy
okay uh let me do that
okay so we got we are going to start
coding emacs list
today uh okay and first of all let me
mention i want to mention this
thank you those of you who have donated
to me
and especially patron uh guys so
since 2017 june i
started to have a uh july 2017 i started
to have a patreon
account and you know i started to got
money
uh 50 a month then
they're near then over a hundred dollars
a month now i have like
uh two hundred dollars a month so all in
total in the past three years i have
about
four thousand so thank you guys very
much and uh the four thousand dollars i
can
buy a big juicy fat computer
uh so thank you guys okay so let's do
let's look uh let's let's start to code
okay let's talk about emacs and emac
these
so what i want to do there are several
things i want to do okay
let me magnify
let's see if i
[Music]
uh let's see if i can
show everything is good okay i guess
okay emacs so i'm going to write some
commands
in emac list emacs commanding emac this
today first of all okay so let me begin
let me show you okay
so if you uh questions for emacs and
just post it okay
ask me questions i'll get to it
so let's begin so i have two commands
that views uh that launches
the current page in browser chrome for
example
uh let me magnify okay this page okay
and
okay on the right side this pink window
is my order emacs command you can see
whenever i call i press some key it
involves a command
you can see the command name on the
right side
and okay
and so let's so let me show you this
command
chrome okay so i want to open this page
in in safari okay i press the key
it's in safari now let's go back and but
i have this command cause i'll open
link in chrome uh okay i call it
open okay because html open in chrome
browser press enter
you can see it goes to the chrome
browser
and i have another command that is
html open link in chrome okay so there
are different commands okay
so one is the opening chrome
and the other one is open link in chrome
so let me show you the open linking
chrome
let me demo okay so for example this is
this youtube url
that's a link so i'm going to call uh
open linking chrome okay
enter so you see it gets
you know it it opens the link in chrome
now so i have these two commands often i
want to send
you know the the page to the chrome not
not the default browser the default
browser i have is 5x
so what i want to do is to combine them
together because why because
often suppose i want to open this page
um or if i want to open this link
in chrome i have to make a mental effort
to choose which command i want to use so
i want to combine them so that
if the current if the cursor is on a
link
then you'll just open the link in chrome
if the cursor is not on the link
then you just open the current buffering
chrome so that's what we are going to do
okay so so far so good okay so let's
just do it okay so
open so we are going to so let me going
to show you
um
source code okay so actually we can call
this uh let's
let's show the source code so
open chrome in browser control h
f okay so you can see
here is the command it's defined inside
html mod so let's open that
okay and magnify so here is the code
um the code is let's see how
it's not too big okay
so here is uh open in chrome browser
and then there is open linking chrome
let's
let's make let's drag this here so again
so you can see bigger
okay so then below it is here is the
open linking chrome
now i'm going to combine them
okay so what um
okay so what are we going to do we are
going to
so first of all let's just copy this uh
copy these two code
so and
okay copy it open a new buffer
paste it magnify
and save it okay
dot el okay today's date
okay we have the two commands
okay so let's just write the command
open in chrome let's just
start to do it different
open in chrome okay and let's do a
documentation
version today state open
current buffer or
link under cruiser in
chrome browser okay google chrome
okay um
so first first thing first of all we
want to determine if the cursor
is on a link how do you do that
we can do that by
uh let's see what's the command um
we want to grab the cur i mean
we want to know if the cruiser is on a
link
or not okay so
how do we determine that we can
determine that by
uh get thing okay get thing at point
that's that's uh that's the command okay
so let me show you get
thing at point
what
get thing
uh thing at point not get okay so
thing at point yeah that's a command so
thing at point this command will grab
the thing under cruiser and that thing
may be a word maybe a symbol maybe a
list
maybe a lisp expression or maybe a
function
or file name url things like that
so so let's just try to do it okay let's
let's do this
in the simplest way possible then we if
we have time we'll refine it
questions any questions
okay questions uh posted okay let me see
if i'm still
yeah okay so seeing it seeing a point
okay
um let's see declare variable
um let's say url okay
url or file path
okay we have two uh
set url
thing at point okay and
this case will be url okay so
remove that
okay this will get the url and we
let's try one more thing
let's try set
file path
and the thing at point and this time we
want
file name you might be wondering why
are you doing them twice because
because because if you have a local link
let me show you okay
actually um
yeah let me show you okay so for example
on this html page you can see
sometimes so for example this link this
link is a local path
so it it is actually a file name on the
other hand
some other link for example my patreon
link
start with https now that is a url
well technically both of them are yeah
so
so the patron this one is a url but but
the other one
is a file path
so so that is why we need to try both
okay that is the reason so let me close
that so go back to the code
and uh um
you'll see what i'm doing okay so so
first of all get the url here
and get the file path okay
and for now let's just print them print
not print message now message the
message command is how you print things
in image list
okay so let's try print url um
url is and let's do it again
this time file path okay
path is pretty prettify
it uh okay so here is our command
currently you just
print whatever the thing at point does
so what it what the thing at point does
it grab the text under cruiser and
then we are setting it to file path or
url okay
now evaluate last command okay done
save the buffer now let's go back to our
html page
and let's call on this let's you know
let's put the cruiser right here and
call the command and see what happens
okay what's the command name opening
chrome okay so
go back so let's try it code
open in chrome okay enter
okay so you see on in in the mini buffer
there's messages
now let's switch switch to the messages
buffer
to see um what we got
so message buffer okay
there it is you see
so so in this case it says url is neo
then path is you know path then we got a
path here
so you see that is how we determine
whether it is a url or it's a path now
let's try it again this time let's try
it under
um under a real url for example this
uh patreon okay let's call it meta x
open in chrome
enter
okay so now you can see
the ui url and paths are both
both valid
okay so in that case we don't actually
need
uh because if you say get url
so before wait let's see what's going on
before
so before the url is new but the path
is valid
when you do it on a file path but if you
do it on a url both of them
are valid so that means we only need one
of them
so we just need the path okay so that's
of the that resolve the
uh problem so let's go back to the code
okay so actually we don't need the url
part
okay let's just comment out for now okay
and now let's let's start to
okay so if
if
file path is not neo then
we
uh then we just call our command okay um
there okay so here is what we want to do
so if file path is valid then we just
call we simply call
open linking chrome if the file path is
near
then we simply call opening chrome okay
that
that should be it but let me let's uh
fix something let's make sure
let's try our code one more time
so what if the cursor is somewhere else
let's say here
yeah let's say here okay let's call it
and we want to know what uh open a new
buffer go to the messages buffer okay we
want to actually
let's just
go to the message buffer and i'm going
to call the command
while my cruiser is here not on a url
okay or
path okay call it opening chrome enter
oh because well we already changed the
command uh
let's let's go back we want to make sure
uh okay so we want to make sure
let's go back to the previous okay
eval buffer go back to our code
and let's call it uh turn on message
buffer
call it while the cursor is in empty
area
correct yeah okay so it says url
is near neo and path is near let's try
some
some more okay just in case let's say
now let's put the cursor in a tag let's
see what happens
call it
okay url is near but path is figure
so you see what happens so what what
that means is that
you actually do need to check the ui out
[Music]
you want to make sure both are new
then we know that
the cursor is not on a ui or a path or a
path
because right now if the cursor is an
inside the tag
is is simply uh grab the tag as a file
path
so that's no good
okay but but but but let's let's do
let's fix it later okay
let's just do it let's fix it later so
i'm showing that you know the live
coding the details you
you need to figure out so let's just do
this you file so we get
so we get the file path file path here
we get the file path with thing at point
and if the file path is near then open
if the file path is is not near
then we open link in chrome if the
file path is new then we just call open
in chrome that will open the buffer in
chrome
okay evaluate buffer
go back to our code and let's just call
it
code fantastic it works
it opens the buffer in chrome because
our
cursor is not under file path now let's
say i put the cursor here
okay which is the file path okay now
code
great now that is image so it opens the
url uh
in chrome that's what we want uh by the
way here's a question from someone okay
so here is the question
uh thank you tian uh
oops uh you know this is the email but i
guess it's uh
you know there's no private information
anyway he's asking me a question about
oakmod
um you know
on my website i have ogre mock tutorials
but anyway that's um
maybe our answer later so anyway
so far the command seems to work uh
let's try some more okay so
uh let's see
yeah you know it works okay close it
close it close it back to emacs
let's say let's put
the url on a on here okay
on this on the put the cruiser here
which is a file path okay let's call it
so that works it opens my programming
block which is that link
uh let's try try one more time let's put
it this on
on the youtube link okay go ahead
okay so it works so that is
today's well that we that is our
uh purpose we finished that code let's
go back look at the code okay now let's
yeah let's keep it simple so today let's
just
that's that's just that let's clean up
the code
so it looks more traditional
so you know so uh otherwise we get
complaints from the emacs phonetics you
know oh your code is not right it's
not intended correctly you don't know
how to code
okay so now it looks better
uh so here's our our code okay so let's
let me copy the code back to the html
site showing browser and we
have it done here one hour code
let's create a elise
tab here paste the code here show in
browser
fantastic go back to emacs
then clarify it okay
then show in browser now you see it's
colored fantastic that's that's uh
that's successful any questions
questions
close that hello good morning emily
okay so now what we're gonna do next
okay so i'm going to ask you guys so
we did this code very uh quickly
so i hope what you learned
so what we learned primarily is how to
use thing at point
think at point grabs the text under
cruiser
but i can i can now go over to start to
explain
how does the opening chrome works how do
you get emacs to open a link in chrome
or firefox you know in a browser by the
way
emacs already has a building command to
do that but i have some enhancements for
my
personal use that's why you see um
html open linking chrome and so on
so now i can go over to explain how that
how you know
about the command how do you open a you
know
buffer or linking in chrome or in
firefox
i can do that or let's see the next item
okay the next item
is i have a youtube command let me show
you okay
so we go to a youtube let's go to
youtube command
i mean i'm going to show you a command
youtube okay let's go to youtube.com
and let's search for some emacs stuff
okay so emacs
org mod okay let's see emacs ogmark
tutorial so there are some
great oakmark ogmod tutorials
okay let's see this one augment basics
in doom e-max
okay now
okay stop it so if you are a blogger
you know if you write blogs often about
emacs or about other any other thing
you want to embed this youtube into your
blog what so let me show you what i do
okay
i copy the url i have a macro okay so
now the url is copied i
switch back to emacs okay
now i'm back in emacs and i paste the
url
okay magnify so you can see the url
there
okay you can see the url here
now if i show in browser that's no good
because it's
you know it's just show a url you want
to
make it into a embedded url
uh youtube so so now look at
look at the pink window okay on the
right so i press the i
press two keys beside html any linkify
now you can see it becomes that now show
in browser
scroll down there we have it you see so
so this command um
html link if i actually it's not that
command actually because that commands
is a wrapper that calls other command
but anyway basically it just
turns a youtube url into this
iframe thing okay this iframe thing now
let me show you what the
what command exactly do that okay so so
we
undo we back to the youtube link
and we want to call xa
youtube html youtube
linkify okay this one
enter you see that that does it
so that's a command so uh let me show
you okay
let me show you and copy it here
so here is the command okay let me show
you okay
show there is a command
html youtube link if i that turns
a youtube link into that
and these these commands so far
we talked about they are in the html
mod you can either use that it's on
mailpad
uh i think it's like it's on my github
i don't know if it's maybe it's not alma
it's
on my just search folks you know you'll
find it
it's on github now so you can either try
to use my html mod or you can use the
you know you can
grab the individual commands i think
these are
independent so you can most of them
so anyway so what i want to show okay so
so you see
you have seen how this works let me undo
okay
actually copy that and do and do we
show the polish and do and do and do
the emax undo and redo roller coaster
okay let's see where are we okay we are
back to where we began
with a youtube url okay now let me show
you some things okay let me put it here
uh wait let me okay let me show you
something
so copy that copy that so i'm gonna
linkify
and you see when you linkify you got a
link like that
okay let me put it here you see they are
different
you see one is the normal youtube url
the other one is with the embed
so if we for example let's try to call
the command we just
uh defined open in chrome okay let's try
it
so we're gonna call opening chrome
on the first link you see that's a
normal
youtube link okay
close it go back now let's try the
second url opening chrome okay
you see now it's different because now
this is the url pointing to the embed
now what am i going to do what i'm
so there's a task i want to do
uh so so let me let me answer the
question okay in a bit
if you have a questions post now okay so
what i want to do is
if i call the command youtube linkify
on the second url it won't work you see
if i do it on the first url it'll work
because let me show you okay
sitehtml youtube link file you see it
works
but if i do it on the second url let's
do it
it doesn't work because it does just it
doesn't understand this format
so what i want to do is i want to modify
my my youtube linkify command to work on
both of these commands
so in summary i can either explain how
the emac list code to open
open a url or buffer into a browser
or i can we or we can start to work on
this one uh we so which
which one you guys want to do let me
know
okay which one you guys prefer type it
now type it
uh and how long have i been talking or
maybe that's it for today so
how long have i been talking let's see
uh
34 minutes maybe that's it for today
okay let me answer the questions and
we'll do it tomorrow you know i'll try
to do it more regularly now
so emily informatic hey good morning
daniel hey
good morning danielle so uh roman
romario says how to show
a keyboard history
uh how to show a keyboard history okay
there are several ways depending on what
you mean
so one way one way is via this command
so let me show you
that command okay
okay so i have a command that's called
command log okay and that is basically
a wrapper to the command log mod
uh uh uh library
emac this library that is on mail power
okay so let me show you okay
so let me go to the uh so here is my
wrapper start command log
so what that does is it basically create
a new window
make it pink you know
and you know that's that's the way i
have it but
the actual code doing you know
logging this command and keys this is
fantastic if you are doing a demo
is the command log mod okay so let's
describe function go to it
and go to it here is the file
you can download it on mailpad now
actually i have
modified this file for my own use
so so if you download for mailpie it'll
be a
a bit a bit different so anyway it's our
mailbox by these people
nick ferrier lei wang um
and originally by michael webber
michael webber is interesting he's i
think he's uh
so michael webber he's a creator of the
full
uh wait did i get confused maybe not
uh wait for dark oak let's see
fold the oak okay so anyway so this guy
silicon valley interesting
okay so
silicon valley so he's a silicon valley
like me
so anyway you can check out so anyway he
these people wrote this
uh very useful okay especially for
presentation
okay so that's one way to do it just
download you know download that
the other way building emacs is you call
control h l okay let me try it
control h l okay so you can see
it pops up the window let me magnify
now this window so this window will show
you
all the you know the the 20 or 30 or so
the command and keystroke
you used so for example i've been doing
a lot
end of line or block which is this you
know
i've done a lot next line uh copyline or
region
uh xr lookup web uh and
set mark forward word
so let's see so you know all these are
navigation commands
start text scale increase that's where i
magnify
the font and uh
and we go back enough we'll see the
chrome let's search for chrome
okay actually it's not there because
when you when you code in emacs it
scroll fast you
actually coding a lot of commands so the
top ones just scroll off
so anyway so this command is ctrl h l
okay
ctrl h l and the command name
is called view lossage that's a funny
name from emacs
that's a e-max history view lossage
okay actually i don't know what's the
etymology for
losses
yeah that would be something interesting
to find out
okay view losses
you know there's a coding emacs lisp
coding laws
there so actually we have some entries
on what what
what's the meaning of losses
so let's try
okay yeah so it's a hacker okay oh okay
great it's from the hacker's dictionary
the new
hackers dictionary that's from eric
raymond esr guy he
you know he has modified the original
hacker's dictionary which is very least
oriented and pd pdp machine
he modified it he modified it
so it becomes small unix oriented you
know
unix philosophy crap so anyway
the last stage very common the result of
a bug or more function
okay this is a mass or collective now uh
what a loss
uh what the losses okay okay
anyway yeah so losses came from
loss or something result of viewing a
bug or something anyway so
emacs call so when you call view lossage
it shows your
uh your commands and keys
so that's the second way to do it the
third way
the third way okay let me show you
another way
let's call frequency show okay so there
is a command
okay hold on a second okay okay okay
okay
frequency show okay let me show you
command so it pops up a window
so what is this good for this is this
this command logs all your commands
uh ever since you started to use this
module
so let me i'm going to show you what's
in my for example let me
let me first of all show you for example
it told it tells me
i have called the command self insert
command
for 1 million times 1 million and
199 000 times i have called
the command previous line for 4 000
times
and next line for this money you know it
locks basically it's a lot log your
command and keys
so this file is about i forgot how
long is this log starting when like two
months ago or three months ago or half a
month ago
half a year ago i forgot anyway the
command is called
let's see let's call describe function
okay
describe function frequency show okay
uh keyfreak
show okay describe function key
freak show okay now
here is the command okay now this
this command is defined in this uh
this module this mod uh keyfreak.er
it's available on melpa now this
so you can look at the source code okay
so here is the source code
and magnify go to the top
so this uh wait uh
okay so this is done by david capello
well the first version is by ryan okay
ryan and michael
mike ryan this this begins in 2006
when i was chatting on irc because
you know i want a command to log you
know i want to know when you design your
keybinding for emacs you want to know
which command you use
most often so i was chatting with him
you know so ryan
what ryan is a great guy he's the author
of irco
rcirc in emacs
so let's try it okay rcirc it's a
irc client written in emacs list
so you see we i can now i can start to
log into freenot
uh the emacs channel i haven't done so
for a long time
so anyway close it so so ryan
kill it yes kill it
yes okay uh what
kill it do i want to save no okay so so
ryan yes key
i believe he's in canada he wrote rcrc
but anyway he quickly hacked up you know
like 10 lines of code
that tells you what command you've been
using you know a log
then michael nasa raised in 2006
expanded greatly i modified it
a little bit then david capello we
rewrote basically the whole thing so
that it saves to file
when you when you start emacs again it
reads log
and so you have actual history the of
the
entire history not just the con session
so yeah you so so that's the third way
to um
to have a log of your keys so let me
recap
okay
one of the way is command log mod
let me let me show it let me put it in
my blog okay
close it close it
open
close it okay let me put it in my blog
command log mod
is one way
view losses is the second way building
emacs
then the other way is show frequency
okay from from these
okay i think that's it for today you can
see
these are the three ways to see a
key log
anything else
30 for 34 minutes 46 minutes okay that's
it for today
thank you guys for watching and if you
like
my stuff buy my emacs list tutorial okay
i have a tutorial on e-max and e-magnus
and just go to uh sally e-max list
logo emacs okay so you have
emacs list tutorial from the very basic
you know nothing about emac list
i'll get you started in no time
uh you can learn you know you start to
learn
uh yeah you know just read it
you know guide you from from scratch
thank you guys uh bye so
bar says uh
so boss says when will you use stream
again okay so let's
let me set up a time okay so that so
that
i i so i have a bit more regular
schedule let's say so today today is
tuesday tomorrow is wednesday
um
well the okay tomorrow i don't know what
the topic okay
so let's say wednesday okay tomorrow
okay
tomorrow 11 o'clock in the morning
okay san francisco time san francisco
time
wednesday 11 o'clock
in the morning okay and the topic will
be
i don't know yet maybe javascript maybe
golan maybe technical
uh possibly non-technical i
have no idea i'm trying to get away from
uh controversial stuff like politics
because that's endless so you know maybe
tomorrow
bye guys thank you
you