hi I'm going to do a demo of Emacs
for Emacs Sal find package now this this
is a package that's like grip but
without coding the UNIX script so you
don't need it and if you are on Windows
it's very useful because you don't have
to install any grab utility so so this
package you can you can this is a
website let me go to here Emacs so fine
dot yeah that's a package name let's see
so that's a github page and this package
provides you these five commands so fine
text so fine text rejects so fine count
so find/replace reject replace text
suffer and replace text rejects so
basically you have a version for fine
finding text and you have a version for
replaced text and each one you have a
plain text version and regular
expression version you have different
versions because sometimes when you just
want to find plain text it's convenient
to use just a plain text version instead
of using regular expression and turning
it off because sometimes you forgot or
you have to quote lots of things so it's
pretty simple just these five commands
so let me do a demo so it's a let me do
a quick demo so go to my home page it
looks like that so so let's see so I I
have prepared here the Emacs Lisp manual
here you see that's that's about 1,000
pages he makes this menu and Emacs menu
that so that's 700
800 pages so together they are about
1800 pages okay so let's just do some
fine let's say I want to find whole text
containing let's see something something
okay
imaginary so I want to find Oh Oh text
okay we're gonna do this again so here
here are the results so let's let's do
it again so I have a key for that so
okay it's just cool
so find text very so find text and I
want to find the word imaginary okay
enter and it's asking your directory
enter and this is a regular expression
for the file name it's going to match
actually it's going to match the whole
file path so if you want to just search
for Oh files whose name ends in dot
html' and just use this so let's do that
and here is a result after you get
result page you can use up arrow to go
go to occurrences or down arrow to go
next one and if you use the okay I'm
sorry this is the left arrow going up
right arrow to go next occurrence and up
arrow is to go the previous file down
arrow is next file so so let's if your
quiz is on one of the currents you can
just press ENTER and you know you'll
move to the page the the position where
the Texaco in this case it's this page
so let's view in browser so that's
that's this page
so okay so so this is and on top it make
creates a report on the date this
program this is called the command it's
called
directory path and so on so so this is
very convenient especially when I'm for
code for especially for programming
languages because it can reasonably walk
up to 5,000 files in few seconds you can
quickly search stuff so let's try
another example let's see
so some find and shall find rejects find
count find count just report then you
can let's try it
so let's say I want to find okay
fine count okay let's say I want to find
he met the word imaginary and it's going
to ask you greater than I mean time so
greater or equal to or equal to not
equal to so I want to find all files
that has more than one occurrence so
let's say so it's greater than greater
than one okay that directory and that
suffix okay so I found for files that
that contains two occurrences of the
word imaginary in in in the list
directories okay that's a fine count and
let's try an example Safa and replace
text rejects yeah let's let's try that
this one let's see what we want to do
okay let's say
okay let's try that so let's say we have
something like that it's open ooh Bubba
paste that we want to find anything any
nehi href link that is a email and okay
let's just try that anything that's an
email so here we we want to do so this
means any RH href that begin with mail
to and then just anything anything
that's not the double quote until it
reaches double quotes so this is a
regular expression we want to use so
let's try that
you know I'm quick I'm using this buffer
just to type this regular expression
it's easier then if I type it in the
mini buffer so anyway so I'll copy that
go back to the file so now I want just
call find the place text bigger
expression yes that's the one
find rejects so this is the rejects we
want and okay well we could have just
tried to find but now since we are doing
a lot replace let's let's say so let's
we let's say we want to replace it by
st. to you know that that's not a valid
protocol it but let's just try that so
remove that so instead of mail to and
followed by email address we use sent to
and what means means the captured text
with which in our case is the email so
let's do that so this directory yes
Oh HTML files yes
right change to files yes fixed case yes
this case in replacement yes show
context before I after output okay
make backup yes it's it's asking about
five questions okay so so here we have
it so here's all the results let's go to
lots of results okay so let's go to the
top let's see okay it's all new so is
there anything not for the dang guru so
so what just happened is that it's it
replace this one all the other
currencies are highlighted in yellow and
all that replacement are highlighted in
green so that means in this file if you
go to the file let's split and go to the
file so okay we we want to jump to the
currents actually so let's press that go
there so so there it is you see so it's
is sent to but no but no Emax canoe okay
so it's done and if you look at the
directory refresh you can see it's it
made all these backup files in case you
made a mistake it made for these backup
files okay now let's go back here but
what one thing interesting is that does
it does the eMac list manual actually
contain email other than these so we can
try to find out we do that but select
the whole thing and replace it just
query replace replace it by space so yes
yes yes replace all okay and so after we
replace them all of them then we try to
press the right arrow key to go to the
next occurrence and apparently there's
none so that means also tells us that
there is no all the emails in the Emax
list list manual email link is actually
just good new Emacs that's interesting
okay that's that's it for this video I
think is there anything else yeah so so
so this is okay so why not just use
square PO said well actually that there
are good reasons because for example
let's go to my email
Emacs block you know I work on website a
lot so I have like thousands of pages
like thousands of pages and remove those
and so for example so I do find we place
like about every - every three days on a
thousand or few hundred pages or up to
five thousand pages every three days
I've been doing these for 10 years and
there are so many ways to do that in
Emacs but eventually this is what I
found to be the most convenient so I
create a package for it so so why not
use set or why not use square there are
a few problems for example it let's see
let's say when are you squared okay so
let me go to a Unicode page on my
website so this is my unicode page for
example so so so there are so many
Unicode here and I want to find for
example how this so this is a rabbit let
me show you so you see we are we have a
rabbit head here I want to know if I
already cover that the rabbit head you
in one of these or maybe I missed it so
I want to so I can use again let me
return the phone to Omo so I want to I
just called saw find
so fine count yeah that's useful there
so it's already by default it's already
rabbit because it's been selected you
use the selection as default so yes
rabbit
let's see greater than less than what I
want to do is equal okay let's say not
equals to 1 well not equals to 0 so I
want o to find all pages that has at
least one occurrence so this directory
yes yes so he actually showed a few
pages that contains that rabbit head
character so let's go to one of them
Unicode animals okay yeah it makes sense
in all these files Unicode eight so what
why is it in Unicode hating also Unicode
7 so let's look so open that file so
this is Unicode eight characters and oh
I know why so so when you may go to
Unicode seven
well what what happened is that and it's
copy the rabbit head so copy that go
here find it and raise it
well here here's here is the rabbit
right here so you see I'm because I'm
using it in a link that's why that's why
the rabbit occurs on this page and you
saw also occurs on because also occur on
this page
search yeah
so you see that link okay so so that's
the Frank okay we were talking about why
not using grip so easy quick grab you
should you have problems with Unicode so
let's try that
so I mean I shall now I have this grip
shortcut let's paste the rabbit in this
case your walk actually but some other
case you want okay why is that so many
okay the reason it's not okay so let's
let's go to the we don't need that okay
let's go through the III actually I gave
the reasons why not using grip because
what basically the reason is that when
you use script there are bugs in the
UNIX Square command mid-six oddly grab
Emacs is why not
so if you rely on grep is this gonna
have lots of problems there it is so so
in this page I actually give you all the
detailed problems of using web external
program problem you have to install it
you in UNIX shell called escape problem
right so for example in my page let's
say this is a I work with the web web
HTML a lot so I want to find this is a
google google analytics tracker
basically so i want to find all pages
that miss that's missing this is this
this text so if you want to use web it's
going to be problematic to quote it you
know it's it's gonna be a headache
headache but you can put in in a file
like create a new file and save it and
modify the grab so that so that it uses
a file as the regular expression input
but you know that's not convenient so
there are problems like this you a unix
quote escape problem then you have
dependence on familiar family
familiarity of UNIX shell syntax because
you have great you have equal you have
program they the options are different
depending on if you are a goon Linux
kernel Emacs no utilities or PSD utility
utilities so they are all different
options and it's and the the UNIX UNIX
crap is not
Emacs crap so that that's that's kind of
also a problem because when when you
work in Emacs because that close that
when you working in Emacs usually for
example query replace
you know Kari replays you are used to
the way Emacs regular expression looks
and it's different from the UNIX regular
expression and Unicode stream problem
yes and and especially if you have lots
of Unicode you're gonna have problems
because when you when you go grab Emacs
has to call external command and in the
process eMac has to encode your
characters into into into the shell
yeah so anyway I document I documented
this problems long stream problem and
and okay so what about said what is the
problem with with with said you know
it's already there is so convenient well
the problem with said is that usually
it's lying oriented for so so for
example I want to replace all these by
by changing number here you know let's
say Google says my ID changed so I need
to change the ID globally and and this
block of text contain line endings and
set doesn't work well with that you know
you have to it's just not very
convenient like you have to use lots of
things like that then the code doesn't
work single quote or double quote things
like that so anyway so that that's the
that's it for the the package let's see
where is it so yeah so I I hope you like
it thank you