Good morning. We are going to install AI
chatbots today. We are going to install
Deep Seek. Okay, let's
begin. If you are here, say hi. Love to
see your comments. Uh if you are not
here, play at 1.5 speed because I
ramble. Okay, so we're going to install
Deep Seek, which is a AI chatbot. This
is going to be exploration. This is
unprepared. So, you know, uh let's see
how it goes. Okay. Uh let's see what uh
let me prepare my video. So, video
check, audio check. Okay. Let's move
that there. Okay. So, can you see my
screen?
Uh yeah. Okay. So, yeah. A video. Okay.
So AI chat chat bots play at 1.55 speed
and say hi. Hello GU Emacs. Hello
Louise. Uh I want to be the
first. Hi
GCS. So the best way thanks to uh we
have uh some experts about AI chatbots
such as chat GBT. So Mr. Splendid is one
of the expert you know he has installed
uh chat chatbot locally. He has
installed many uh and he also wrote he
actually wrote a chatbot for
um for my discord for example type s
let's say uh
artificial intelligence and it will
search all my websites containing that
word you know link to it. Fantastic. So
Mr. Splendid wrote that uh you know so
he has installed several of the chat
bots because I don't know for because
it's related to uh his job and uh Frenzy
also helped uh Francie also install
local
chatbots. Uh Francy somewhere
here some somewhere here. Okay.
Somewhere Fr where is frenzy?
uh this guy frenzy. Okay. So we um why
do we why do you want to install it
locally? Because you know because if you
use the website you know chat GBT or
whatever they have censorship you know
if you want to ask some questions that
is politically sensitive
uh it may be censored you know but if
you install locally for those AI
chatbots that comes with open source and
open weight such as the
deepseek then you don't have that
problem okay so deepseek Uh Deepseek is
one of the amazing one from China you
know
because you know like in January three
month ago they they they released
Deepseek opensource not just open source
but also open weights that's the
critical point about AI chatbots
uh because when you have open weight
that's actually what
matters so they released it and the USA
stocks lost cost $600 billion dollar
something like that.
Okay. Uh so anyway, so so I'm going to
try to install DeepSeek. Uh let's see
how it goes locally.
Okay. So the one of the great site to
install it without knowing you know lots
of technical details is this lama o
lam.com. Thanks to frenzy. So you say
download. Okay. So, let's turn on
JavaScript. So, let's just see uh how it
goes. Okay. Uh so, there are so many
chatbots today. There's Llama, there's
Deep Seek, there's FE minstro GMA. Okay.
So, let's click download. See what
happens. Okay. So, it's downloading
Lama. I suppose that's a wrapper. Okay.
So,
um did it work? While while lama
downloads sign up to get notification
and updates. Uh not now. Okay. So I want
on wows.
Okay. Requires Windows 10. Okay.
Download. Okay. Executable. Yeah. One
gigabyte. Okay. Do I trust it? Well,
since um you know I I think I trust it.
you know, you you need to make sure
because otherwise you download virus,
nobody knows, but since FRY installed
it. Um, so, you know, I think I can
trust it. I'll just trust trust it.
Okay.
So, so
um so is it downloading yet? Yeah, it
is. Okay. So, so
this you can download many of the
different ones. Okay.
So
um let's click on OAMA. So there's a
menu here models discord. Now why is it
not showing
um go to their
homepage? Ah stupid. They are not
showing the
menu. Okay you because the windows is
not big
enough. Okay now it
shows. Uh okay so hold on a second.
So you you can click on models then you
can see the different
um kind of opensource and open weights
AI ch chat bots gamma 3 is from Google I
think so QW something I don't know where
is that oh that's from uh China Alibaba
I think so you got you know minstro
that's another one from USA I
Llama is from Facebook
uh and FIFA I don't know so there are so
many of them so you see for each one
they have different um you know like 1
billion 4 billion 12 billion 27 billion
that B stand for billion that means the
number of parameters so the more higher
it basically means requires more memory
okay so if you click on deepsek Okay. So
let's click on
deepsek. You can see you know you have
1.5 billion 7 billion and you click this
menu it'll tell you how much local RAM
is required. So if you use the 7 billion
model it needs about 4.7 gigabytes. Okay
I can do that. I want to do I want that
one actually. Uh let's try the 8
billion. Let's see. 14 billion requires
9 gabyte. I have 16 gigabyte of RAM.
Okay, let's try the 8 billion. Okay,
let's see. Click on
that. Okay,
so wait, do you actually need to
install? Um, okay. So, I don't know how
to do this. So, this is the first time.
That's a point of this live stream to
install
it. Voice check, video check. So lots of
comments. Uh let's
see. Okay. So is it download finished
yet? Uh yes. Okay. So executable it's
done. So I got that. Okay. Let's see in
download directory. Let's so let's go
there. Download directory. Uh okay. So
let's shrink this. We don't need Emacs
much today.
So there it is. So let's see. One, two,
three, one, two, three, kilo mega one
gigabyte. Okay.
So okay, it's
executable. So what do you
do?
Uh shall we just run
it? The nice cute logo. Is it safe to
run? Yeah, let's run it. Okay, enter to
start. See what
happens. Okay, it's uh loading and
loading.
Okay, let's get you set up and running
with your own large language models.
Click install to continue with the
installation.
Okay.
So, okay. So, let's say
install extracting files or Jesus. Now,
do I have enough disk space though?
Let's
check. Uh, old
enter. Okay, I got enough space.
So, by the way, this photo is me voting
for
Trump. Wait, why is it not showing? You
know, the Windows got problems. Even if
you have like, you know, you have flash
disc, it's slow when the processes are
running. So, shift control escape. Let's
look at the processes.
Yeah. God, it's running. It takes It's
not coming
up. Okay. So, you can see, let's see
where's the install
box. It's still going. And uh let's go
by
CPU. You see, whenever the process is
running, it slows down your whole
You see whenever the disc is running it
the whole thing slows down
Windows. I got a SSD drive
there. Let's see what you guys are
saying. Nvidia SMIX show us. Okay. Let's
see. Oh, you want to see my um graphics
card? Uh hike. So, very good to
come to the LLM world. Okay. Uh I use LM
Emacs a lot. Oh, nice. So, you got uh
interface
installed. Uh hi
expert. Uh run or locally 100 plus
models.
Oh wow. Exa
gigabytes. See semantic linking uh local
models are still censored. You need
an abated model. Oh, okay. That's
interesting. But I mean at least this
the degree is less as far as I know for
um
deepseek. Uh so Chinese models win.
Sadly true. New Google pro model is
pretty neat. That's gamma 3, I think.
So, you know, there's a lot to learn
about the chat bots. You see, I spent
quite a lot of time since last year to
study about machine learning as because
of chat GBT and all of a sudden you can
generate images, you know, like amazing.
Uh yeah, let let's let me show you that
images. You know, everything is slow now
since um let me just random. So you go
to Emacs
tutorials. It's amazing the AI bot. It's
truly a revolution. So there's a lot of
danger and you we don't know what's what
what will happen. Oh, it's
done. Um okay, it's done. But let me
show you this
um Emacs the AI generated images. Click
on that. Come on. Show up. You see it's
got
a Okay, is running clear. Click here to
get started. Click.
Okay. So, it started in a
shell and uh it's taking time to
load. Okay. Welcome to Oama. Run your
first
model. Okay. Okay. Finally. Now, enlarge
the
screen. Okay. Now I need to enlarge
this. So this photo, by the way, not
dead yet. This is uh in January. This is
Yeah, this is in
January. Okay, cancel it. So, okay. So,
it runs in a uh terminal. That's
right. Okay.
So, but let me finish showing you the AI
generated images. You know, you guys
probably have seen a thousand of it. So,
you see, I love
this, you know. So, so this is done by
Flux. Flux is a image gener generation
AI bot. Uh, and I'm going to install it.
Okay. Uh, so you see all these pictures.
Fantastic. I was using them for my uh
for my live stream
uh
thumbnails. Okay.
So,
so now it is running now. Uh Deepseek.
Okay. So, let's see how do we um Okay.
So, don't you need to install it? I
think so. Deepseek. Which one we want? I
want the 8 billion. Okay. 8B.
So, so I
need
671B, you know, that's
67 671 billion parameters, you know, and
as Mr. Splendid told me in order to do
to do that, you need 10
uh A100 GPUs and each one cost like two
$2,000 in order to run that model. He
explained
here. Okay. So he he explained
uh here in this message you see in order
to run that deepseek R1 600 something
billion parameter you need 16
A100 and 80 gigabyte RAM each and each
one is
$20,000 and I checked that is true.
So you know so there's a lot to learn
about uh this AI stuff. So I spent
like uh studying last year or two years
ago. I started to learn about machine
learning and neuronet networks. I
learned a lot. So you know I have some
basic idea how it
works. But then you need to for example
to understand what he is saying you know
the quant quant um you know he says for
example most people run quantized models
in case of deepsek simple simple
hobbyist may run distilled quantized
models. So you need to know what does
what does quantise mean and what does
distilled mean of course now I know. So
I spend like three hours just to
understand what he's
saying. So let's just get back to um so
I want to run this 8 billion uh model.
So how do
I Okay, so I want distilled model. There
it is. So this is the code you want to
run deepse
R18B. Okay. So let's see. Paste that
there. Enter. Let's see what happens.
Pulling manifest. Okay. So it's going to
install the weights, I
suppose. Oh Jesus. It's five gigabyte.
I I you know I'm not sure I
can like how long does it take 5
gigabytes? Five minutes or something.
Now it's going to take it's going to
take 10 or 20 minutes to download that.
Now I'm at I'm at 14 megabyte per
second. No. Okay. This is going to take
half an hour or
more. Oh wait, not really. Five minutes.
Okay. Five
minutes. Okay. Massive download. Now is
my YouTube healthy.
Okay. So, it's going to take a
while. So, let's see.
Nvidia
SMI. What do you
mean? GPU RAM.
Okay. Oh, GPU
RAM. Oh
Do I have
enough? Let's see. My
GPU. My GPU's got 14
gigabyte. Wait, six gigabyte. Oh
Okay, maybe I maybe I cannot use
this one.
AB Deep Seek R1 AB. Okay, it needs 5
gigabyte. So, I have barely
enough. Okay, it's it's a good thing to
have a GPU. That's what I'm have GPU
for, not
gaming. Okay. Yeah, maybe we cannot do
it today because you know this download
is going to take forever. And actually
it says one more minute, two more
minutes.
Okay. Okay. So,
llama.cc CPP inference, but I don't know
how to install
[Music]
that. You know, llama
llama.cpp. That's a C++ file,
right? I don't know how to install
that.
GPTEL. Okay. Okay. That's a good tip.
GPTEL for
Emacs. Okay, that I probably want to
install because I don't want to go to
the Windows terminal every
time. Almost done.
Success. Is my live stream back
healthy. Okay, it seems done.
So, looks like it's
done. Let's say let's see who are
[Music]
you. It's working. Greetings. I'm
Deepseek R1, an artificial intelligence
assistant created by Deepseek. I'm at
your service and would be delighted to
assist you with any
inquiries. Fantastic. I'm
done. Now tell me, is my live stream
healthy? So what questions should I ask?
Okay, let let me ask uh it a
question that um I've asked
before that something
about so my GPU is doing fine because I
got now this gaming machine Nvidia
GeForce. Okay.
So, so successful
actually you see it answered the
question. Fantastic. So, the next thing
I want to do is uh to install the the
Emacs interface. Uh, someone suggested,
let's see, doy
Bellum
suggested to use
uh a
EMAC. Where is it?
Gail
something. God, this is okay. Hold on a
second. Okay, I'm back. So, basically we
are successful.
Everything is quite
simple and uh actually maybe that's it
for
today. Uh but right now I want to find
out what's that EMAC interface.
GPTL. Okay, GPTEL is a cool interface
for Emacs. Okay, let's see if I can
install
that these packages.
Okay. So, search for
GP TEL. Okay. GP chat GPT
shell.
Uh oh. Okay. So, there's that. Let's say
GPTEL. So you also got you got chat GPT
shell. You also
got
GPTEL. Okay. You got a few. Let's see.
GPTEL. Then you got
GPT eyeball. Okay. What's the
difference? AI an AI writing assistant.
I don't want that. Okay. So you got two
choices.
GPTL and chat GPT
uh interface. Okay. So, I'm going to
install that offline. That's for
Emacs. Uh but now it's working. So, I
think maybe that's it, you know.
Fantastic. It's so easy. So, just go to
uh just go to the
uh the Olama website. Okay. Then
pick then just download O Lama. Then you
just you can just run it.
Fantastic. Waiting for my LLM
package. Yeah, the question. Yeah, but I
do not know how to install Llama CPP.
That looks like a
um llama CPP that looks like a um you
know C++ first
thing. Okay. So let's see
uh so for for Emacs install GPT or chat
G chat GPT interface. Okay, that's for
Emacs. And then somebody mentioned llama
cpcc. Let's see what is
that. Okay, so there it is. GitHub llama
g uh llama
cpp. Let's see Wikipedia.
So, Llama CPP is an
open-source software library that
performs inference on various large
language models.
Okay. Okay. So,
fantastic. Okay. So, next thing I'm
going to try to install
this. So, does it what does it
require? So, CPP just means written in
C++. I guess it it's not
uh wait it's a
library because if it's a CPP C++
library then you know it takes some
trouble to to know how to actually get
it to run. So anyway I think that's it
for today.
uh is easy good clone and follow few
commands compare models find finally
caught you live hello
Diego okay I think that's it for today
fantastic success
success yeah uh is there anything else
yeah so deepseek is very interesting
from China open source open weights
um and we will see how it goes because
the landscape of the AI is tremendous,
you know, it's it's it's changing like
almost every day.
Uh yeah, so we'll see how it goes, you
know. That's amazing. Bye, guys.