Hello, good evening. Welcome to another
episode of S talk show. We are going to
do randomish.
We are going to code F. I'm going to
write my F tutorial notes.
So, this is randomish. Probably boring
for you. Let me have a drink. This is
koala. Something called koala drink.
Cara rum coffee. Okay,
it's pretty good.
And my keyboards Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard 80 UHK80.
Search my YouTube, you'll see my
reviews. Okay, now let's go to my
screen. Can you see it? Yes. And uh can
you see me? Yes. Can you hear me? Yes.
Now if you are here, say hi.
If if you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed. Okay.
See, let's see. Uh sometimes I cough.
I'm quitting smoking, by the way. That's
a big thing. So, I quit smoking about 5
days ago. Fantastic. No craving at all.
So, where's the audio? So, this uh
thing.
[clears throat]
Quit smoking. Fantastic. Cheers to 2026.
[ __ ]
Okay, that's code. Now my finger is a
bit sticky. Let me fix that.
Okay, now I'm ready to code. Now,
every time every every hour or two, I
walk I get up and walk back and forth
with my iPad or Surface tablet. So I
take notes and take notes and uh write
down what I need to do for my website
and then I sit down and do them. So this
is one example. So let's here are my
notes and let's do them. Okay.
Okay. So this one array prototype slice.
I already did it. Okay. So this is about
JavaScript. So go to JavaScript.
JavaScript in depth.
JavaScript in depth array proto type. So
this is um array prototype slice core.
So wait actually that's about function
call. So you go to uh the function
section function define function uh
whatever and go down there's all topics
about function then you have a section
about core apply bind very complicated
crap in JavaScript okay so I made a
major update to my tutorials so in this
page I wanted to uh remove those small
examples because they are rather
irrelevant
irrelevant okay so this is about uh
core.
So here is a core page and blah blah
blah blah blah blah. Yeah, more
examples. So delete them. So copy the
URL. Now go back to Emacs.
Open it. Uh open that link and uh here
is uh here is more examples. So just
delete delete delete delete delete. Show
browser. Fantastic. It's gone.
Okay, I'm updating updating JavaScript
in depth. My JavaScript in-depth
tutorial. So, this is done.
Uh,
okay.
Delete that. Now, if you don't know, you
just go to my JavaScript, search for it,
you will find it. Okay, go up uh
function JavaScript object reference. Go
up webdev tutorial webdev JavaScript in
depth. Okay, now go up webdev blog. Go
there. So you can see this is all the
updates I did in the past week related
to JavaScript and HTML and CSS. So you
can see I've been working on all these
pages today. That's January 20th.
Um,
can you see me? Yeah. Okay. So, so I've
been working on all these pages January
20th and then yesterday been working on
all these. Okay. So, that's where you
can find all the links. Just search for
webdev blog or search for
xah JavaScript in depth.
That's on.info
http no s. Okay. So next most used in
number max. Okay. So there's another
thing I need to do. So you go to the uh
reflect function prototype apply and you
want to mention on this page. Okay. So
open that. You want to tell the story
when it was used. Okay. So uh I can tell
you. So we need to add uh
let's see added bottom. Okay
here
[clears throat]
function. So this uh wait
[cough and clears throat]
uh was most
used
to apply
number max. Okay. So, where is the math
max? Okay. Well, I got JavaScript. Math
index. Okay. So, that's not so good. No,
not math. Go back to JavaScript. Uh,
wait.
Math. JavaScript. Math methods. Okay.
So, let's open it. So that's a math
object which functions as a namespace in
JavaScript.
It's a static basically static name
space. So let's search for max math mark
uh math domax. Okay, that was the that
that is why it's that's how it was used.
Okay, so let me just um show show it.
Um,
wait.
JavaScript, not C. And let's add a
section. And uh, let's
cut that and p it here. Paste it there.
And remove, remove, remove. Make it
paragraph. And make it code. And uh,
let's say example. Okay.
uh header three. Now,
now this is the example. So you want to
know the maximum you so you have array
you want to know the maximum. So that
was so the way you do it. So this is the
way you do it today. You use triple dot
which is known as the spread operator.
Okay. So run it. You get one to 185.
Okay. So you can actually copy that
paste it here. So you you so run it.
Okay. When one single line no variables
now but in the past we do it differently
because that's before you have the
triple dot uh spread operator. So what
you do before let's copy let's show it.
Okay. So what you do is you
very complicated. Okay. So you say
uh you say math max dot uh wait dot
apply. Okay. Then you say you want to
apply to this uh Okay. So let's say my
array. Okay. So to make it clear, wait
to make it clear, let's declare a
variable. Okay. Because uh because
people understand when you have a
variable instead of instead of
everything in one line. So let's have a
variable here. Okay. So my array then
the way you do it before 2015 is that
you say math.mmax.apply
then x array is the array and uh um
and that's it. Okay.
So, and so, okay, now you just say print
it console log. Okay. And remove that.
Okay.
Purify the code. Evaluate the code. You
got infinity. Uh, which is incorrect.
What is going on?
[clears throat]
Uh what
you need um [clears throat]
what?
Okay, that's how you do it. But um
[clears throat]
Okay, let's put it back. Syntax color
show in browser. So go down. So we are
explaining that example function
prototype.apply apply was most used to
apply
to to find the maximum num uh to
find the
max
number in a array like this
before 2015.
Okay,
that was the story. That is the story.
that's right. Okay, but today you do it
this way. Okay, now uh now you need to
link to the math section. So let's link
to the math section. Okay, math section
linkify and d that part show in browser.
So you are looking at my workflow in
Emacs. This is how I create 10,000 HTML
files in the past
20 years. My blog all the mathematics
and tutorial. Okay. So here you got the
example uh function prototype apply was
most used to find max
max item in a array. Okay. So this
should be to clarify uh this is about
technical writing. So you should say max
item that one that that way is better
phrased max item in array like this.
Okay. Now you go to math name space and
uh and then you go to uh search for uh
first of all you need to update. So
right now it's 2025 May. So, press press
make it 2026 today. And search for max.
There it is. And uh pop it out.
Okay. Let's put array here. So, just
make it one line so it's simpler. Okay.
Put it back. Syntax color everything
showing browser. That's it.
Fantastic. Okay. Find the maximum.
So close that. So uh so this nodes is
done. Most used in number max. Okay.
Delete it. Next. Okay. So showing
browser. Close. Back to emac. Close.
Showing browser. Prototype. Apply. Let's
double check. Um,
so now let's have some red wine.
So is that good? Yes. Function.prototype
apply was most used to find max item in
a array like this. Fantastic.
Uh but should you say you know today
it's done? Well that's yeah actually uh
you can say today
it's easier
using spread operator. Okay. So you just
say
let's say um
you you don't need that complexity
dot dot dot spread it like like
spread okay
word spread operator okay eval and
insert the result here okay
now put it back syntax color edge
showing browser. Fantastic.
Okay.
Now, do you guys understand?
Is there anyone watching here? Nobody.
Okay. You see this? This this
JavaScript.apply
is a very extremely complicated thing.
Okay. Now, if you don't know, should I
explain?
Should I explain? Well, watch my video
like to the day before and you know two
of them before today. There are two
videos. Each one is one hour. I
explained how this the whole prototypes
based object system inheritance works.
Okay. So I'm not going to explain today.
Close that. So I want to tell you close
that. I want to tell you web blog.
Close. Close. Go to today's talk show.
Okay. Go to talk show. So
yesterday episode 769 JavaScript in
depth compare array and object equality.
Okay. Then the day before has own
property versus object has own. So watch
that one episode 745 that has kind of
indepth
talking about the object system in
JavaScript how in inheritance works.
If you understand, if you watch that,
you understand you you will understand
kind of this apply uh you know function
call apply you see function call apply
or function call or function apply is a
functional programming concept
you know when you have a function you
want to call it but typically it's it's
I mean it's not that much of a concept
usually all you do is you just put the
parenthesis after for the argument after
the function you know just function name
parenthesis the function may be a named
function or maybe a lambda function
anonymous function or whatever as long
as it's a expression function always a
expression okay you got a function then
all you have to do whatever the it's a
name or it's like lambda or non function
or like 100 lines of code as long as
it's a function expression
all you have to do if you want if you
want to call it in a welldesigned
function or programming language is just
put a parenthes parentheses after the
function. Okay, may it be a name or
expression. Okay, just put a parenthesis
or in some languages you don't even need
a parenthesis such as uh f or or camel.
Okay, those meta languages you don't
even need parenthesis like hascal too.
But in lisp
it's got a problem you know that. So
that's why the lisp you know they
created a name called fun call that
allows you to call a function because
the list got a problems you know idiotic
bad design. So they can't they can't
just normally you know the way they call
a function they can't use that it came
from so so this function call uh kind of
thing came from this. The other thing is
about
the other thing is J uh is JavaScript.
JavaScript it's you know it's uh
complicated. Okay, do I make sense? But
anyway, so you got function call is a
problem. Okay, in in in a programming
language not that's not well designed.
Then the other thing is about function
um apply. Okay. Now function apply that
is a thing in functional programming
languages. You apply a function to a
list of things. Okay. The the essence.
Okay. So let me explain this one.
Okay. So let me put the link here. Okay.
So we we we did um
we did let's go to my JavaScript
blog. Okay, search for function. Okay,
now copy the all extract all URL. Okay,
now close and let's paste it here.
Linkify or make a list and uh I want to
delete some of them because we didn't
talk about them today. So let's just
leave those two. Showing browser. So
this is today's talk show. We did these
two. Okay. So let me tell you about
apply. Now, now I was saying,
are you guys confused? You know, I was
saying,
"Hello, Kasali Emacs. Hello, Lols. Who
are you?" Hello, Lux.
You know, I'm starting to get drunk. You
know, I'm I'm not a drinker. So like
this is 100 m millers of red wine
that will soothe my soul because why do
I need to drink? Because sometimes I
read about politics.
Every time I read about politics, it's
very sad. You know, it's a it's the
collapse of USA. Not just USA, it's a
collapse of the like the western
society.
Okay, we starting to get into politics.
Okay, now let let me now do I make
sense? So I was saying that okay I was
saying that
the function apply is a concept in
functional programming languages. Okay
it's a good one. What it does the
function apply what it does is basically
you have when you have a list or array
you want to apply a function. So
basically you want to pass all the
elements in the list or array as
arguments to the function. You see the
function doesn't necessarily take a list
like normally it takes you know like a
bunch of arguments but not the list.
So in that situation but you got a list
you want to pass you know you want to
apply the function to the all the
elements in the list that that is what
function apply the concept okay so this
is a this is kind of universal in in all
functional programming languages okay
but not function call now function call
this function call is a misery
like I talked before. Okay, the function
call whenever you see you when
programming language they have like a a
function can called like call of you
know
that is a abomination that is watts
watts okay that's a disease that's a bad
design that's a symptom of bad design
and this happened in JavaScript and in
lisp including common lisp uh I'm not
sure about skim lisp but including emac
lisp when you have something like call.
Okay. So because in these languages they
they are not well designed. You can't
just put the function argument after the
function like the way normally function
call happens. You can't do that.
Therefore you have to do it this way. So
in JavaScript
why can't you do it in JavaScript? You
can actually you can today but let me
show you. Okay. So we are digressing. Uh
we are kind of digressing.
Uh we didn't actually actually I was
going to work on my uh F.
Yeah, I started to I need to work on my
F tutorial but um I started to talk
about
digression. So you guys do you want do
you guys want to hear this story about
the digression about the function um
the about programming language design
and why is that whenever you have
something like a function call a
function named call for the purpose
purpose of of calling a function
whenever you see that in a programming
language that indicates the programming
language is badly designed it's a
symptom of of a bad design. Okay, that's
what I I wanted to say, but I haven't
started to tell the story yet. Do you
guys want to hear it or should I like
start to work on F? Let me talk about
that then. Okay, so in in JavaScript,
okay, in JavaScript today, you have
arrow function. Okay, fantastic. Okay,
so let's name a constant. FF is a
function and here is the arrow function.
So you define a function. So what does a
function do? Let's just say x + one.
Okay. Plus
one. So you got a function. This is uh
lambda.
In computer science, it's known as
lambda because it came from lambda
calculus. Okay. And so in JavaScript,
this is the syntax for for a function
lambda. Okay? also known as a nonf
function and you can assign it to a
variable. So in this case it's a
constant. So now this function is named
ff. Okay. Now how you call the function?
All you have to do is ff. That's how you
call it like just like every other
function in JavaScript. Okay. So we want
to print it. So console lock that. Okay.
Run it. So you can see result is four.
Okay,
this is how you call a function. Okay,
just like every function. So
just like every function
you can also do it when the function
is
is not named. Okay. So let me show you.
So here's a function. What I want what
to do if you want to call it? Well, what
do you do if you want to call a function
normally? You put the paren and
arguments after it. Okay, do let's do
the same thing.
Do the same thing just like that. Okay,
now you want to print it. Okay, so let's
uh console lock print it. Okay,
run it. You got four. Okay, and what
about this part? Uh renet, you got four,
too. Okay, this is JavaScript.
Supreme. This is normal. This is normal
way of doing things.
So why why is that in JavaScript you got
this you know function.proto type
fuck.core
very complicated. Why? Because 20 20
years ago back in 1995 30 years ago you
don't have arrow functions.
the functions in JavaScript is like one
[ __ ] up [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ]
So you cannot do that. Okay, can you
actually do that? Actually I think
actually you can
but let me explain. Okay, let me let me
go on to explain. So actually you can.
So you define a function in a normal
function way. Let's say okay so here is
a function. So you want you want x +
one. Okay let's do it. x + one and here
you need to say return okay return the
[ __ ] okay now that's a function now put
the par in in a paren so it you know so
because so we can group them and we want
to call it at three that will work too
okay so console log and this thing and
put it there will it work yes okay run
it oh error um What?
[laughter]
Uh, wait. Do we uh
Oh, you you forgot the parameter. That's
of course how idiotic I I am, isn't it?
Okay, you got four. Okay, it works.
Okay, so we have this back in 1995.
So, so what are you saying? What you
know you were saying that JavaScript got
a problem therefore you need a function
code. Why? Okay. Why is that? Because
uh
because okay because JavaScript whenever
you a function runs there is a hidden
things going on. There is like a hidden
things [ __ ] hidden. It hides from
you. You don't know what's going on. hit
something is hidden. Some hidden
argument is passed to a function
whenever a function call happens except
the arrow function. Okay, not the arrow
function. Arrow function is new in 2015.
But before 2015 such as this function
keyword fu n
whenever it's called there's a hidden
argument passed through this function
and that hidden thing is called this
binding. Okay. So that is why this the
entire prototype call [ __ ] happened.
Okay. So in order to understand you have
to understand this binding. This binding
in JavaScript when a function is called
it it has a associated value called this
binding in function body. This binding
is represented by the keyword this.
Okay. The purpose [snorts] of this
binding is to allow a function to
implicitly work with a object. Okay. So
basically whenever a function is called
there is a hidden things going on this
implicit you know value is passed to the
function behind your back. You don't
even know it. You don't see it. You
don't see it in the function argument.
Okay. So you got this this this binding
is going on. So that that that this this
[ __ ] up the entire JavaScript. That is
why you have this function.prototype
call which allows you to explicitly
specify
an arbitrary disbinding to a function
you want to call. Okay, that is why that
happened.
Okay. Um
so we dig I I I I started the rant and
digress. Uh I don't think anyone of you
understand it but anyway cheers.
Uh so
SM Gamma says do you ever work with
Spring Boot? No. I suppose that's a Java
thing, right? Is that's a Java
framework? Is that right? No.
Did I answer your question? SM gamma.
Okay. You asked me an a question. I
answered. Now I asked you a question.
Is my answer satisfactory? And why are
you asking that?
Are you you know a lot of people today
the Zuma generation they cannot think
you know they are unable they are
incapable to to express exactly why are
they doing something you know they you
know so
so are you asking it asking that
question because you are a Java Java
coder and you are curious something
about is that right spring boot and what
is it.
Cheers.
Okay, I digressed on this. I'm not sure
how people will like it.
I And I don't know if I did a good job
or not, you know, because uh I should
write it out though. Um I could,
but I've written it out like a million
times over on my blog. So anyway, let's
go. Let's uh keep doing what we wanted
to do. Okay, let's jump to F. Okay, so
next slide that I want to do is the
triple quote. Okay,
so let's go to
F tutorial. Okay, F learning notes. And
this page is about string. Okay, so you
go to string. So you can learn
everything about string and there's a
section about triple coordinate string.
What I want to do is I want to make that
a new page.
So separate that section into a new page
by itself because this triple quoted
string is
like is important enough to have its own
page.
Do you guys understand?
Uh so go to string section and search
for search for triple
uh like t r i pl. So there it is. And
let me just do my thing. You guys don't
understand. So because I you know if you
look at my pink window that I the
command I just called is HTML split
section to new page. Okay. I have a lot
custom sections you guys. Um well it
it'll take too much time to explain
everything. So let me just do the things
I want to do. So I want to rename the
page and uh let's just say that. Okay.
And you need to add
so by convention every programming
language tutorial
title began with the programming
language name. So F then followed by a
colon. Okay. So that's the name I want.
And uh this is a real verbatim stream.
Uh okay. So open that page and change
the title. Select or paste. There it is.
Uh and close it. Okay. Save it. Close
it. Show in browser. Okay. F string. And
we need to update the update date. So
press press
show in browser. Fantastic. Okay. single
quoted string. Uh that that that that
that that allows list does not allow
that. Then you got triple quoted string.
Okay. So we created a new page.
Fantastic. Now it's missing the topic
box. You see go back. You see every page
you got a topic box. All these links are
related to stream. Okay. So for example
you can go to print. when you want to
print you might need to do some format.
So it's you know all the convenient uh
related you know this is the topic box
this navigation box. Okay. So but now if
you go to stream and then you go down go
down go down you go to the triple quoted
stream and then there's no topic box. So
we need to add that. Okay. So uh so uh
search for triple. Okay.
Uh,
copy the link. Okay. Go down and uh,
let's see where do you want it here.
Okay.
Make a list and remove that. Okay. That
we have it. And press press.
You can you can see update everything.
You can see the command name in the um,
in the pink window. Okay, that's the
command there.
Uh, so showing browser. So string then
triple quoted string and go back to
Emacs. I don't want this link here.
Showing browser because because now it's
it's part of the uh here. Oh, you need
F. Okay. So let's add F.
Let's add it back.
Press press press press update or show
in browser. Fantastic and beautiful.
Now go to triple quoted string.
Fantastic.
So this slide
triple quoted string new page is done.
Delete.
Now on this slide, next thing to do is
that this link title we need to change
to add verbatim. Okay, so let's go back
to Emacs. So this one. Okay, so just go
a command press press
uh then you want to say verbatim
completion. Okay,
do it.
So in F you actually have two verbatim
string syntax. One is the real verbatim.
That's triple quoted string. So that's a
real verbatim. Okay. Refresh. Okay. Now
the other verbatim is when you put the
add sign in front of a string. But
that's not real because because there's
one exception that when you have
consecutive
uh quotation mark
they stand for one single quotation
mark. Okay. So for example consecutive
quotation mark means one single
quotation mark. So technically it's not
verbatim or another way to
explain this is that it's a verbatim
except but but when you have two of you
know when you have like
two consecutive ones then they become
one string. So yeah so it's actually
hard to explain. It's it's not so it's
not really verbatim. Okay. So anyway
back to Emacs. So it's done. So you can
see all the changed pl places you can
see because I'm calling my own command.
So I'm calling a command fly command
mode activate. No, not that one. I was
calling
HTML rename links or allows that will
rename
an article on my website of 10,000 HTML
files.
So it will find all the links to the
article and rename it. Okay. So we just
renamed we just renamed
F uh s string but and we renamed adding
a verbatim parenthesis. Okay. Now do you
guys understand what I'm doing? So you
see
we got that. So we can go there.
Fantastic and beautiful. And you know
it's changed everywhere. Okay. and and
[snorts] okay so back to this slide this
image is done screenshot is done delete
so next is that we want to change this
article's title by deleting the
interpolated okay so this article is
about f dollar sign string template okay
I don't want the word interpolated
because that makes it too long and uh
interpolate the word interpolated is
less relevant
I mean it's it's less well known. So
it's not
so as far as title goes. You see,
the art about titling an essay or
article or part of a tutorial is that
you want to the you want the title to be
as short as possible, but to be the most
dense full of information and the
keyword that people are likely to search
as much as possible. Okay? You don't
want it to be like 100 words, you know,
or of course you can add, you know, this
is interpolated,
you know, uh allow allowing you to have
uh variables or expressions, you know,
you you can have that. But the
but then when people search for
expression expression or variable they
find like 100 200 articles you know it
gets confus confusing. So it's not
always better if you just have like long
articles. So you want the title to be
like as dense of information as much as
possible yet as short as possible. Okay.
Like a balance. Okay. That's a so in in
in terms of mathematician's view this is
a optimization problem.
Now are you guys still here? I guess
not. Okay. You guys don't know what I'm
doing. Okay. So let me just delete that.
Okay. So uh actually
uh what what was it? Uh
okay. So let's just rename. Okay. Wait.
Uh what was it? You need to original
name
what?
Okay. Yeah. So, rename all. So,
template. Okay. Let's just say lower
case. So, that will rename everything.
Cheers. 2026.
So we do have six people watching. Who
are you guys? Are you guys Batman?
Fantastic and beautiful showing browser.
So F. So I'm working on my F tutorial
and making making some progress.
You see? So right now I have everything
about string.
Well not [clears throat] everything yet
but most of it you know. So you got
string you you explain what is string
how do you quote them? How do you create
them lit literal expression? Then you
got triple quoted string what how is it
different and so on. Then you got assign
string. Uh then you got dollar sign
string which is a template. Then you got
um then you got escape string sequences.
Okay, let's go to next one. Okay, I know
what I want to do. So this name change
is done. So delete it. So now this part
is um yeah. So this part is about code
template string. So you need to go back
to the template string page here. Okay.
Copy the URL. Go to Emacs. Open that.
uh string uh actually press press okay
so uh what where are we
yeah dollar sign string template so
there's a code we want to change okay
so first of all update the code uh I
mean update the uh let's update it Okay.
Uh, search for pre. So, pop this out.
So, let's run it.
Uh, I have three TT things. So what I
wanted to do is that um
yeah so what I want to do is that I
wanted to check if this
this uh works for double dollar sign.
No. Okay.
Uh, I didn't explain what I'm doing
because
well, I'm not going to explain because
because I'm not explaining much F anyway
because if I'm doing a F tutorial then I
probably should but I'm not really doing
doing F tutorial. So it takes you know 2
minutes to explain what is anyway. So
error this construct is deprecated.
Dollar sign
is not permitted as a character in
operator names and in
and is reserved for future. Okay, you
cannot have double. So
you cannot have double. That means uh so
that means you remove this part. This
doesn't make sense.
You cannot have double double dollar.
Okay.
You c you can have a double dollar only
only when you have um let's say let me
show you. Okay. Uh
whatever h okay so double dollar but
then you need to have also double quote
uh what
I mean triple triple quote. Okay. So if
that will work, run it. You see that
works.
Okay. So anyway, I'm not going to
explain. So run this.
Yeah. Okay. So let's just put it back.
Syntax showing browser.
Okay. This part is done fixed. You know
this because I want to remove the
comment because the comment is
incorrect.
Uh so remove it and on this page. Okay.
And that this screenshot is about
is about this page string escape
sequence. And what my note is saying is
that I need to link to an ASI page
explanation. Okay. So let me show you
how to do that. So search for
escape. So open that update today's
date. Then bookmark open as keyi. Okay.
So this is a page about aski characters.
All you want to know about aski
characters. What is it?
Very important. In fact critical for
programmers. If you have like the first
two years or five years, you may not
know it much. But as you you know keep
programming for more than few years then
you started to know ASI
you know is you know very important like
all the unprintable characters the new
characters and you know their
representation I mean their ID the hex
decimal you know that like the
you know you you you started to know
these things. Okay. So ask character
copy the URL back to the page close it.
So what I want is at the bottom add the
link. Okay. So paste it linkify
make a list and make it a related links
box. Okay. Showing browser. So go down.
Go down. So you can see now you got a
related articles box. Click on that. You
can see ASKI characters which allows you
to see the the ID of the nonprintable
characters you know basically allows you
to know what the [ __ ] they are because
otherwise if you look at you know the
string escape sequence that's
you know this happens in Goland in
almost all every language in Python in F
in Python in in in JavaScript in Ruby,
in Java, in C, in C++, you know, almost
every language. This this is a result.
This string escape sequence is a result
of the C [ __ ] brain damage. Okay.
Now, if you don't know, let me mention
this. Okay, this is important.
This C [ __ ]
go to my talk show page. Okay, about a
month ago, I did a full hour explaining
the damage of the C scumbags, the C
[ __ ] damage, huge damage in every
programming language, their nasty
destruction
because of their escape sequence. Okay,
so just search for
string.
Okay to uh so EP episode 743
unic code point programming language
design of string bytes versus code unit
versus char. So this is uh a week ago
not that one. Okay but that one is also
very good. So watch it. Episode 743.
Next.
There it is. Episode 702.
the C print F crime and you new syntax
for string rock string. Okay, so this
episode
I done last year September 16th. Okay.
Episode 703
that details the crime of the C
string syntax of this escape and fox
that
harmed the entire industry for 30 years
because of the escape fox.
Very nasty. Okay. So if you are curious
like you like what are you talking about
like how can you make such a talk claim
you know like you might check out this
video. Okay episode 702
the sea crime the sea [ __ ] idiots.
So anyway so in this screenshot what I
wanted to do is uh did I do it close
showing browser? Yes I did. I added a
link to asky characters which lets
people understand what the [ __ ] is phone
feed, what the [ __ ] is like backspace,
what the [ __ ] is alert, like you know
like modern computer programmers, they
don't know because you don't you know
like you never like if if you want to
voice you record the MP3 or you know
like why do you have a alert character
like what the [ __ ] is it like in phone
feed character and new line what's the
difference in car carriage return like
today's people call us you may not
understand but
anyway so those are kind of history and
we stuck with it so those are part of
the ASI
so-called ASI characters from 1960 and
they they are still with us in fact they
are part of the UNI code UTF8
identical okay because of backward
compatibility reasons okay so these are
asy characters let's escape okay so you
kind of need to it's good if you
understand it if you are a programmer
okay so this screenshot is done delete
it next
okay so next I think we I've done all my
F uh screenshots. Now it's just some
JavaScript and but I think I'm done
today.
Hope you guys liked it.
Best chio coding stream. Very educia.
Thank you very much. Charlie
Charlie, are you Charlie Cook?
Okay, bye guys.
Okay, bye guys. We shut down in 1 minute
or 30 seconds or something. Okay. So, I
did, you know, I did the things I want
to do. Yeah. Reasonably well. So, what
is this? Okay. Uh, close it. And what is
this page? Dollar sign. We renamed this
page. That's good. Back to Emacs. Close
it. And what is this page? This is F
string. Back to Emacs. Close it. What is
this page? This is F learning notes last
update 2026. That's good. Close. Back to
Emacs. Close. What is this page? This is
Sound Hawk Show today. Okay, we did
that. We did and we did F several F uh
learning notes. Good enough.
Good enough. Bye, guys.
Uh let's mention okay so we mentioned uh
talk show that important talk show let's
uh search for that so that one is good
to watch and search the other one this
one watch that one okay open it episode
the C print F prime and new syntax for
string okay watch that
So, let's put a link here. Let's just
link them. Yeah. So, that the crime of C
and uh Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Fantastic.
Bye, guys. Love you guys. Pay me. Go to
Kasa Talk Show. Go to go up kasadi code
kasadi.info.
No s in http. No s. Then go down. Go
down. PayPal me. Okay. Paypal me.
Patreon. Amazon. Give me one shot. $100
something. PayPal. Amazon.
Not famous. Unfortunate. Okay. Bye guys.
Spy.