good morning guys
welcome to another episode of talk show
and uh let's see let me go to the
the trendy stuff
video watcher um
stupid youtube okay let's try this
full head
okay today we're gonna talk about i'm
gonna answer some of the questions
people ask me in comments and we're
gonna do a little bit
emacs demo uh you know
meanwhile answering questions various
things
and we're gonna talk about keyboard key
mapping
veeam efficiency we did yesterday and
possibly we're gonna do some javascript
to
fix up uh to make it pretty
so but let me first prepare you know i'm
preparing my screen to see the comments
uh so it will be what's new
settings uh other features
you know youtube uh keeps changing
their interface like google keeps
changing their interface in the past 10
years
more than 10 years let's see live stream
live events live stream now
um
yep so you know google changed their
user interface like every month for the
past 10 years so everything changes all
the time
okay looks like okay i'm live okay
good
i'm kind of late i'm like 10 minutes 10
minutes late
uh so let me answer the questions then
uh
okay so talk show and let me mention let
me talk about
okay uh so david cappello uh
one of my friend who mentioned this
editor so there's a new editor
cocoon kakune okay
this is another word that's a japanese
word i think
kakune code editor so it says it's model
editor faster as in less keystrokes
multiple selections
orthogonal design okay interesting so
there's a new editor in town
so uh who wrote it
multiple selections i don't really care
add text editing tools
several tools advanced text manipulating
primitives
learn about cocoon philosophy so who
so who created it and
what's what is the context what is the
situation you know i always wanted to
know
uh about these things because
this information give you you know the
background
i i you know i always check the
background almost everything i see
for example when you go to a news
website on twitter or whatever social
network
read it you know people post websites
uh especially mainstream news websites
i never read them you know i don't click
them
well you know i have to like spend you
know
30 minutes i have to know who wrote who
is the organized
organization who created that website
who runs it you know things like that
then
possibly i will visit that site you know
uh
because that's a good information
because today
it's like info wall you know like
information people are just
uh everyone especially uh powerful
big organizations with money they spread
false information all over you know uh
so easily
because nobody checks you know do you
actually have time
you know every day like every day um
every day there are tens of news about
all the
anger or injustice or whatever you know
you don't have time to check them you
know make
um you know um if you really want to
check an
incident you know at least it takes like
30 minutes or an hour
and you and those time you cannot just
spend by just hopping around news
website
because you you know they are almost all
the same they are just you know false
information
you have to actually spend the time to
check
who wrote the article yeah and look up
check up the history of that person you
know what kind of articles he wrote
before
are there controversies what's his
background where he came from where you
know where he
where do you came from uh you know and
and also find out the organization the
website
when did it begin you know what
organization runs it you know things
like that
for example there are many uh you know
there are many crackpot
cult uh organizations falun gong
is one of them okay they have like tens
of websites
international in all languages uh
and in fact it's becoming popular in in
the last few years
uh they you know they are against china
i mean china there are many bad things
in china right
especially two americans okay i'm not
gonna go into that but
but you know the this organization like
constantly spew out fake news you know
just like new york times new york new
york times is one of the worst
uh fake news website they chung out fake
news every day day after day
it's like it's it's actually a powerful
propaganda
machine uh since the past few years
let's say three or five
five years good morning green
deck so green deck you are in russia so
i suppose you don't know much about uh
rush
uh american uh politics right
so do you know much about it like the
social justice scan
the the things they do
um so anyway so this uh
so back to the topic there's this editor
uh
i suppose that's a japanese word is that
right you know the
the americans idiocy you know they have
a
especially among programmers they have
always have obsession
of using like foreign japanese words
uh let's see what it is what let's see
kakune if
if that means something um
k a k okay
uh let's search for
that word good morning dion
good morning green deck yeah not much
but social justice warrior i know of
course okay
yeah so uh so so kakune is that
a japanese word or what
okay maybe maybe not
let's see let me adjust the window so
that
it's not hidden behind other things
as uh hold on a second
sorry about that so that that
okay that's good so i don't know what
the word kakuni came from
but anyway kakune so it's a new editor
but who wrote it uh that would be
interesting to know who
wrote it and what is his uh
issue why do why does he
rewrite this editor
i don't know i have to find out so
anyway here is a new editor so it began
apparently since 2012.
okay um you know a new editor so
check it out so kakune and uh
and also someone asked me
you know on my youtube
on my youtube channel someone asked me a
question about
about um well let's not go that
anyway so it's you know it's in one of
the comments he asked the question about
uh this command uh let me start
so first of all let me start the command
log mod so you can see
all the commands i call in emacs
on the left window and i was using this
uh editor so for example i was using
this command
start find text let's say editor
let's say let's say star find replace
text
let's replace emax by haskell
okay and in this directory
or html files right change to file yes
fixed case oh wait i don't want that
change to file
so let's start over so search for
emacs replaced by haskell
in this directory all html files
right change to files no and fixed case
fixed casing replacement so you see this
command
uh this is my package that allowed me to
find all occurrences
you know uh and replace them
you know so it does the replacement all
in one shot
and highlight uh make a report and you
can just go to
you know it highlights them and you can
just press
enter go and jump to that page for
example this
you know the emacs the word emacs
occurred here so
the question is can you do it
interactively
and the answer is no because it's it's
not
interactive by design because i do find
and replace uh on
um about 5000 files almost every other
day you know like three times a week
for the past 15 years uh because
i have i run you know static website so
when you have static websites you do not
have
you know footer and header templates uh
so whenever you want to change header or
footer
footer such as uh for example here you
see
uh you see this side you know copyright
1995 to 2019
that's a footer so it's the same text on
every file
and when you want to change your footer
for example 2019
you have to change thousands of files
so i do find that i find and replace
almost every day for the past you know
over 10 years so i have explored all
possible ways to do finding replays
and eventually i wrote this command
that's the most efficient
uh you know there in emacs there are so
many ways to do find replays let's let's
show
let's so i'm going to do a demo of that
let's go to emax okay
so let's go to my emacs blog my emacs
tutorial so if you go to practical emacs
you'll see find replays let's see
uh find file uh file topic
copy paste topic unicode topic font
topic
uh there is a file topic buffer topic
emacs find replace okay topic
and in so
here are a comprehensive tutorial about
all the ways to highlight a text
search your text or find and replace
and it may be all files in your buffer
or the current buffer you know so
it covers uh all these things
so what we want to do is find and
replace let's see
find replacing your directory
so here is a tutorial that shows you how
to find and replace
in a directory
uh let me check the comments monet
is a word but google doesn't realize
that maybe
okay so find replacing a directory
uh let me show you a demo then of this
emacs technique of find replace text
in your directory and interactively
now first of all let me say yeah so i i
have used this method you know for
several years but um
but eventually uh it's not
as useful i mean if if you if you have
to do find replays on
on over 5000 files every day
then this way is actually not efficient
because once you do
you know when you do this interactive
replace
it's kind of annoying like you have to
check every occurrence
you know suppose there are 100 files
changed so you have to go through 100
you know occurrences to make sure they
are correct
i mean of course this this is
interactive but you can make you can
press a key and
and tell it to do all replacement but
still it's
it's very tiresome to even just look at
a few examples
uh to make sure that's what you want you
know first of all you have to do that
you know you have to go through you know
check examples then they leave the files
unsaved
you know all the buffers let's say 100
files has been you know let's say 1000
files are changed
so you have 1 000 buffers open
then you have to save all the 1000
buffers
of course there's a very convenient way
you just press like four keys
uh save change files so you press four
keys
literally um one two three four five six
six keys if we can't shift key as one
one key
so you press six keys to save all
1000 buffers but then you
also have to yeah so you have to do that
so when you have to do this multiple
times a day you know sometimes i do
more than more than one uh
find replace on thousand files a day
sometimes actually a few times
per hour so it gets tiresome you know
it's it's not efficient
so instead what you want is one shot
operation you know you you specify this
find replace
you you you want to do it one shot on on
000 files in a directory but
the question is sometimes you are not
sure that's the right pattern
you know especially if it's a regular
expression right
so what you do is that you do it one
shot
without saving to file then
then my command okay for example it you
know uh the command i just called
uh it's this one let's repeat it okay
you see this uh this command makes a
report
on all the possible changes and context
and the file they are associated
associated
in you know the the pink is the file
name
so you look at this file and you you can
make sure yeah that's a pattern that's
the correct pattern
and all these occurrences i want to
change
then you just call the command let's see
uh for example i'm just going to
do it again you see uh so the list
list code is this and all i have to do
is
change the neo to t uh
the neo2t and the neo2t
here then you just say you know you just
do this
operation again and save all the files
so
so that that is why uh this is more
efficient so by the way so this is um
this command is called software and
replace text
and it's in the package because i find
el
okay so and here's the source code and
you can go to the website
uh and it's all written in emacs list
you know so it's on mailpath so go use
it
so but but uh let me but for a situation
situations where you actually uh
you actually want interact to interact
interactivity because uh
sometimes you are not sure sometimes
like the patterns
is not consistent across files so
so for some files you want to change for
some web files you do not want to change
and there is no mechanical way
to distinguish the two situations
the only way is to buy eyeball you know
human
eyeball so when that happens then
you want to use the emax way the emax
way of find replace
text in a directory and actually the
command is called
um here
die uh wait uh here diet do query
replace
rejects okay so let's um
let's let me show let me demonstrate an
example of how to use that
um so let's um
okay first of all let's go to uh ergo
emacs
let's go to first of all i want to make
uh wait
not here uh
okay so let's go to start talk show okay
so go to the saudi info directory and
first of all
i want to make a git commit and
get a status
okay it's clean so in case so we can do
a backup
i mean we can do a
revert once we demonstrate this because
we are going to do some finding replace
so let's go to diabolo diode buffer so
here is our
files let's say we want to do find
replace
so first of all mark the files you want
okay
let's say all these files uh
or if you want to do the whole thing to
a directory
then you just go to the directory and
put
cursor on the directory then in you know
when there is no mark mark it will
do fine replace on the file or directory
your cursor is at
so for example if you want to do the
whole directory just you know
put a cursor on the directory now if you
want to
actually only uh do find replace on some
specific files then you have to mark
for example let's say i mark this one
mark this one
or you can use a regular expression to
mark it
for example or html files uh okay
so let's just say i want to do in this
directory okay so let's
i don't mark anything now you press the
key
q okay q is for direct to find replace
and re
uh diode do find rejects
and replace that's the command name key
binding is
capital q in diode okay let's do that
now it says query replace in marked
files
uh yes and that's um
you need to give a regular expression so
in in this case let's say e max
okay
then you need to get give a replacement
pattern let's say
haskell okay
uh
wait it's actually running or what oh is
emacs stuck
now
emacs is stuck
that's odd
cancel yeah emacs stuck for some reason
uh why is that that's strange let's try
again
so let's just mark these files
so mark is uh mark
mark these files and press capital q
capital q uh
and do that okay it works
but why is it not working before so
let's close that close that
close that let's try it again
q do it
well okay i think i know why cancer
cancer cancer
q yeah it's annoying you know emacs
i think emacs behavior changed uh
it um into the emacs 26
yeah i'm pretty sure that's why you know
you see
before if you want to to find replace
our whole directory
basically when you when you press q okay
which causes the command
uh diode to find re rejects and replace
that's a long name we so when you call
that command
before emacs 26 i think it will
basically
try to do find replace on all marked
files
and if there's no marked files it will
uh try to define replace on wherever the
cursor
is so if the cursor is on a directory
name
then it will do that directory so that's
how you do a directory
but i but but right now it seems that
if there's no marked files then it will
simply do the current directory
instead of the where wherever the cursor
is
so let's try it again to see if that's
the case so i press q
i press enter
no matches for emacs
okay so i'm not sure what's going on
yeah it's stuck again you know it's
taking a long time i'm
so anyways let's let's just try to do
the marked files
uh we have to figure out
whether something actually changed we
have to figure it out
green deck says how do you cancel a
command when emacs
stuck ctrl g control g is the
you know that's the way control g
it may not be successful i mean control
g
uh is the general way to
when whenever e emacs first you know you
can press ctrl g
it it is also used to cancel key
sequences
but however uh it does not always work
depending on you know how exactly emax
is stuck
you know when emacs is running a command
that that's taking a long time such as
find replace you know
or search or texting fi in files
it's actually running a process when
when emac this
is running a process uh from a command
from an emacs command
it will periodically check for control g
so it should work but sometimes it may
take you a few seconds to
for it to uh react but however
sometimes it does not work for example
especially when you have like remote
remote uh file access things like that
and of course when emacs actually flows
like there's a bug
it won't work you know so anyway just
press ctrl g is the um
oh e-max gets stuck for you at least
once a day yeah sometimes changing
window size
unsticks it you know there's a
bug with emax26 like sometimes the whole
screen becomes
blank for a second like the whole buffer
uh i noticed um but
anyway let's try to finish this um
i don't know what's going on so but we
can figure out
figure it out usually like let's let's
try it okay so i mark
so this time i mark this directory and
let's tap to
q let's press capital q and enter
now that's wrong because it shouldn't
take this long because
in that talk show directory there are
only 10 files you know
so i don't know what it is doing now i
mean is it trying to search the whole
current directory which is exactly info
because sally info has literally like
20 000 files uh
so it's stuck so let's cancel ctrl g
ctrl
g g okay so
marking doesn't work so let's go here
okay now let's try ctrl uh capital q
again
okay so
okay so right now the behavior is
actually just
trying to find replace on this
particular file
uh basically it's it's um
where the cursor is okay so let's
close it close it uh let's try this
again
capital q enter
yeah it's just doing one file now
let's try it again let's try mark and
see
i mark these files capital q enter
wait oh yeah okay it's doing several
files you can you can see the green
the green lines here that's one file
that's another file so
so if you have files mark marked in
diode
it will search those files
but what we want is to try on a
directory
so
let's go up a directory so let's just
leave the cursor here and press ctrl
i mean press q enter
and definitely that's wrong
you can we can wait for a while to see
what it actually comes up
then we all know uh what directory
exactly is
working on
so okay so uh let's let's wait for
for a while
so so what else is new
so because i talk show okay um
so let's go back to some talk show so
so yesterday we did the arrow keys
efficiency
let's go to it
yesterday we did that let's open safari
uh actually let's not open safari let's
let's just open here
so you can so so this page is computing
the arrow key efficiency
of vim's hjkl versus
the inverted inverted tijkl
and we recorded this yesterday and it's
looking spectacular now
you see uh
you see it interactively computes
uh the key frequency you get the
interactively computes the
efficiency of the key binding
the v the vim key binding versus the
inverted t
key binding
okay the emax result came up so let's
see what
it is uh trying to do
so cassandra show star talk show
okay so it's it is actually
um if you look at this window
oops what i just closed it by
mistake
so what um here
so if you look at this window
so it is actually doing the right thing
it it is uh just
working on the textual directory so when
you don't have
uh marked files it will work on
whichever you know your current cursor
position is
you know if your cursor position is on a
directory
then it will work on the directory but
i'm surprised it takes so long to come
up
is this because of emacs 26 uh i'm not
sure
so anyway there you have it you know how
to work on directory but
but let's go through it and let me show
you what happens
when you use that command you know how
do you how do you actually change things
you know
uh so for example so let's mark these
files okay
now i press ctrl now i press q
capital q and
so replace the word emax by haskell
okay pascal
okay then then it will pop up two
buffers one buffer
is called is named xref
now the xref buffer lists lists
or occurrences of all uh
all files that it found
that emacs found
then you have another buffer um
which which just opens one of them uh
you know
so for example right now i can press uh
yes to change it
i can press us some key options let me
see
so so yeah the here's the result window
uh it shows like that so you can press
one of these keys
y to replace the current uh occurrence
no to skip it ctrl
g to abort the whole thing about the
entire operation
and you can press the exclamation
key to replace all occurrences in
current file
okay
and you can press n capital n
to skip further search
of of the current file or you press
capital
y to replace
all files okay so you have all these
choices
so let's say you know so i see one
occurrences
i say no okay so i press n
no uh wait uh
ah wait so i
did let's go here um tab
tab what
what's going on
you know i know what i think i know
what's hap what
what is happening because i have soft
like keys
so it kind of all uh
okay it works now um
yeah yeah because i it didn't work
because i uh i exited
so let's try it again so i i mark these
files
let's let's mark all html files so i
press
capital q and replace e max by haskell
yes then okay
then you know i can press yes or no to
y to change no n to skip so skip
skip skip skip skip
so let's say i want to change over here
so i press y
change so and another one let's say y
change let's say n
n n n n
y y
y y okay
okay let's say i'm done you know i i've
done so i want to
so i now i press capital n to skip
all possible replacements for the rest
of the files
so let's press capital n
actually
actually let's press ctrl g to avoid the
whole thing
now let's go to um
yeah now now if you go to i buffer you
will see that you see
all those files that you've changed
which is this one
and you see this there's a asterisk
there
that means those files are changed you
can open it
you can see we made a change here and
uh go to i buffer again oh i already
saved it uh
too bad so so another one here you can
see we also
uh changed somewhere here
uh here you can see we
we made a change here haskell
so if we oh okay it's here
so these two files so now
and you can you can imagine there are
like thousands of them
thousands of files changed and now if
you want to save all of them you can
just um
go to uh i buffered then press
then press star u
that will mark all files
that are not saved okay now you press
capital s to save them all
then you press capital d to close them
all
so you ask me really key or two buffers
yes
okay so that's how you do it you know so
you can do this for thousands of files
and imagine you have thousands of
changes so emacs will have thousands of
buffers
open and unsaved and you can do the
you know this operation on all of them
so i've been using this method for like
uh for five years or four
four years or something you know
sometimes i use um
you know i've been using this is one of
the method you know i've been using for
a few years but
eventually uh if you need to do
find and replace for thousands of
thousands of files several
files several times a day you know for
years that's no good you don't want to
you don't want
interactive interactivity
on the other hand let me show you the uh
star find
example first of all let's go back to
let's go back to let's revert the
changes we've just done so let's go to
ishow
uh e xiao uh git
okay what's the command for revert so
let's go to git
uh git tutorial
revert changes uh get ah
right check out
so get check out
exa talk uh
what oh wait
kasa talk show
what uh
oh talk show okay talk
okay let's do that and
let's go back to talk show and let's
search for haskell
okay so actually but anyway
the file should be reverted back uh
let's see
git status yeah clean
that's good so now i'm going to
demonstrate
saw find um so i call the command cause
i find replace
uh let's say emax replaced by haskell
enter and the directory this directory
correct
file path rejects html
write changes to file no fixed case yes
fixed casing replacement yes so you see
i got this report
so i can look at that you know i can
quickly look at all of them
all the places and if i decided i want
to make the change
i call this command you know which is
which is uh mx repeat complex command
and it will actually show the emax lisp
code you can see at the bottom
then all i have to do is change it you
know let's copy it copy it
new buffer paste it here
here's the command now i can just change
that
to t and t okay so that means i want to
uh write file right to file and also
make a backup
you can you you can call describe
function on
on this command so uh for example
describe function and here's you know
it'll tell you
what the arguments are
so anyway so so i i am now ready to
run this command so i just run this
command
it's actually done so you see all these
uh so for example i go to this place
you see the file is done you see it says
insert
math unicode emoji in haskell actually
originally it should be in
in emacs right so now it's you know all
these
changes has been done now if we go to
ishow
git status you see those are changed
now i don't want to the i don't want to
change of course
so i go back and also and also if you
look at the directory
uh you know backup are made for you
they are backup made for you so close it
go to e-shell
uh good check out talk show
revert them
okay so we you know so that's an example
we just reverted
all the changes we don't need that
anymore
uh you see this is back to emacs that's
correct
close close
uh close close
close okay close all the start option
windows
so let's go to talk show okay that's a
demonstration of that
find find and replace so
so we have demonstrated demonstrated two
ways to do it
one is the uh emax way using
the command called
the command is called diet do query
replace
rejects okay
and we also demonstrate the other way
which is
casa find okay
now because i do find replace on
thousands files several times a day for
for more than ten years i have
uh several other ways i've you know for
example let's
let's say i want to
let's say i want to let's see how many
people are watching
uh five let's say i want to you know i
have
i have written ghost script python
script perl script
that to find replace uh let's do example
so let's go to go find okay
fine so this is a script
so let me show you um
so here's a directory that contains
goldlandscript python script python3
and postscript for find
file or find and replace file
and with or without regular expression
so you have you know many many choices
so let's look at the
ghost script for find
let's go back to talk show copy the file
path
so let's and go back to the go go line
script
now the input directory will be that
startup show and let's say we want to
find the word
emax okay that's it
this script is like a 150
lines okay now let's run it
okay here's the result
uh just like the sci-fi emac list code
it it creates a report now this report
is not
syntax colored but we can syntax color
it by calling the command
xr find output
mod okay so we if we put it into that
mod
then we would color it just like you
know the sapphire
uh uh report because they
because i made sure they they the output
format is
is the same so you can press the arrow
keys
to move up down to occurrences or you
can
press uh the up and down arrow keys to
move to all the uh occurrences of files
so left left right arrows is to move
through the currencies
so you can see so these are all places
that contains the word emax
so if if if you press enter you will go
into that file
you know for example let's go to let's
go to here
enter oops enter
you see it will jump to the position in
the file
so so this is a golan
script let's close that close so this is
a goal line script
to do find and replace and
in fact
you know so why do i write uh why do i
write the goal line script
to do it and why do i write you know a
python script
for example here's a perl script doing
find and replace it's written in
this one is written back into year 2000
and here is a python 3 script for doing
find and replace last
updated 2019 i originally it's written
in 2006
so so you have uh find and replace
and you also have just fine for example
this is a python 3
script for find text
uh you know i separate find and and find
replace a separate
scripts because you know they are
distinct
tasks so sometimes you just want to
search for some
occurrences you know like grep you know
find is like
grape and other times you want to find
and replace
okay now when you do find and replace
also there are two versions uh
for example here you have a version for
replace
rejects which is a go
script for find and replace
with regular expressions then you also
have a i also have a go script
for find and replace without regular
expressions just plain text
similarly i have i have two versions in
in python as well so why do you separate
them
because when you want to do simple find
replace and without regular expression
uh if you have a single script it's
usually annoying to
to escape you know to do escapes in your
find string
and it's also error prone so it's
simpler if you have
a script that's uh
that's not using regular expression when
you just want to
uh do find replace uh
you know on plain text so that's why i
have two versions
so anyway so there's another feature
uh let me show you another feature for
example this scoreline script
you can see that you know sometimes when
you do find and replace sometimes you
want to find
certain files in your directory for
example all files ending in html
and other times you want to find all
files in your directory
and serve the subdirectories but
some sometimes you want to uh
to find and replace on a specific
set of files that you have the file path
for example um so so my find
and replace script has that feature
you know you can specify you can give a
list of file paths
and it will work on only these files
so what are some examples for example
let's go to javascript tutorial okay
for example i have my javascript
um let's see object reference
okay uh let me let me find the example
and let me show you
okay uh well
hold on a second
so uh how am i how am i doing how are
you guys doing
is it interesting you know if you have
questions comments opinions just post it
okay
let me know how am i doing
uh but right now
right now i'm trying to find the exam
example
where i need to uh pick out a
specific list of files that i want
um to find and replace to work on
uh okay i found the example
you see so here is my um
good morning avocado avocados
do you think of deno yeah let me talk
about that
in a second wait you asked for math
art right algorithm math art i was
waiting for you to come on
so but today is kind of late we we
should talk about that
uh you know come on early and let me
know i'll talk about that topic
algorithmic mathematical art
yeah that's a fascinating topic but
anyway back to the
back to find replace so look at this um
this javascript object reference page
now if you go to any of the page you can
see uh
wait uh let's say i go here wait
let's say i go here hold on a second
what's going on
yeah okay so if you click on regular
expression prototype
you see the there is a navigation button
on the upper left that says
back to up javascript object reference
okay
this this is this is correct now that
should happen
on all these pages but however it's not
because for example
if you go to object.prototype it says
back to javascript in depth
which is incorrect so
what i want to do is uh is to
so for all these files here
on this page for all these files
i need to change any occurrences
occurrences of the spec to javascript in
depth
two two uh
back to javascript reference object
reference so
let us do that so first of all i copy
this file path
open the file in emacs show in browser
you can see that is a file
and now these are the files i want
to change find to do find replace so i
uh hold on let me show you
so so this section
and i then i call the command site html
extract url
so that means all the url will be
extracted
open a new buffer paste it you see these
are the files i want to find replace
but however i want the full path so
let's do it again
uh select all control u
then call the command so now i got
open new buffer paste you see now i got
the
full path full path for all the files i
want
okay close that now i just go to
um i go to my golan
replace script
okay now this is my goal line go
land find and replace uh script
i paste the file names here
now and delete the previous one this is
the one i
used you know days ago so delete that
then i need to make them into the right
syntax
which means each one must be a string
and with a comma at the end so i have a
command
watch that
that you see that command is called
quote lines okay you can just search the
name
on the web you'll find my code you can
use it
uh the the code is here software lines
uh so anyway so so that is done
so i want to do find replace on all
these files
and okay so what is the
find text okay let's go to it let's see
so open the file the find text will be
this one not this one okay uh
because that one is correct open this
file
back okay this one so this is the text i
want
copy close
okay so the fine text will be
[Music]
you can see here paste
that's my uh find string
and what is a replace string let's let's
get the replace string
this is a replace string i want
javascript object reference
close okay and now
we put replace string here
okay you can see we have the find string
and we have the replace string by the
way you can have multiple pairs
so you have multiple if you have
multiple pairs of fine replace you can
you know
repeat them you know so it it's nice to
do them
everything in one shot so i got that
find replay string
is good now at least of path is good
uh now i can now write to file is true
that's good do backup
is true that's good now i can i can run
the code so let's run the code
you see it makes a report all these
files are changed
i'm good to go so now i'm go back to the
browser
click on object dot prototype
you see it's good that works let's click
on another one
it's good function prototype it's good
go to string that's correct
so it's you know so this is uh
convenient
so the the feature so why do i write
this so go
lan so i have several of these find
replace scripts
um you know in e-max or using greb or
using
e-max diode query find replace or using
you know golan or python i
experiment because i have to do this
multiple times you know every day
so i you know uh
you know i want to find the most
efficient way because i do this you know
every day
so right now if i want to find if i want
to find and replace
or multiple on specific list of files
i cannot do it with i cannot do it with
uh the question find out yeah because
cliffhand.er does not let me for example
uh specify which files you know
specify a list of files to work on it
just work on a directory
with a regular expression to filter out
uh you know either file names or
extensions or
you know directory name
so actually that that is a feature i
might add
you know in the future you know uh i
might add to find
software
so but anyway right now i'm just using
my golden script by the way
these are also on github actually it's
on my website you can see the url is
here
you can go to the url shown in browser
uh here's the code go land find replace
script by the way you can also find my
python script python find replace in
your directory
you can also find my
pearline pearl version
this is per version written into year
okay so and there's also
you know so there's a link you can you
can you can use them
uh so go land so uh so
now we did the find let's go back to
isiah okay
uh what is this close close
close
uh find go close let's go to
talk start talk show and go to e-show
go up a directory let's see my git
status
you see so it actually changed about
seven
ten files so that's good so right now
i'm just going to
uh brief interactive casa interactive
brief rsync
so sync to my website
so that's actually that's good so i
think that
that that concludes the talk
on the find replace issue i think
so that's a i i guess so that's a full
talk on the
find replace issued you know why i
do them why i have so many versions of
the script
so close that uh talk show
so what what else okay so uh there's
there's a question let me answer the
comments
so uh what do you think of denno so
avocados told me there's this dental
thing so let's look it up i checked out
uh i checked it out it it's a
um you know it's in the javascript
land there are so many things every day
new things every day you know the
technology
in the uh web web dev is changing
you know every month
so i didn't know uh about them
deno until you know uh avocadoras told
me so deno is a
secure runtime for javascript and
typescript built with
va rust and tokyo
okay t-o-k-i-o
so it's a secure run time for javascript
and typescript
oh so is it just like not js
i mean you can actually for example in
emacs i can
instead of instead of not just you know
a file name to run the file i can
actually use denote to
run it by the way
otherw avocados
do you have a do you know deno like do
you have
experience or you're just asking me so i
didn't know about daniel before
so it looks like um
you know if it is a replacement i mean
if if it can run or say not js
then i would have interest i would be
interested because
in emacs i'm you know i'm running for
example when i have
whenever i have for example uh let me
show you
on okay close that new buffer
uh type something save it as xx.js
so it's a javascript file and
console.log
let's say print3 okay and i want to run
it
uh run it it prints three
so so when i run that i'm actually
calling the command
um run current file you can see
here and
and this sauron current file is a
command i wrote
it allows me to run python php
perl ruby golan haskell you know and so
on
any script in the current buffer i just
press the key here run
the way it works is that that it you
know it calls a shell command you know
so for javascript it actually calls the
node
so if deno uh can work i'll just use
deno because
you know i i don't like the npn people
the sk the mpm leader whoever you know
created npm
that guy i think he's a scumbag okay
he's uh
uh you know one of the uh
bad person okay very very uh
bad uh uh here's a scumbag okay
he and another guy also the guy who
began
ruby on rails okay at this now i haven't
looked into this
these two guys exactly you know what
they are you know i haven't looked into
but
from what from the some incidents i
looked into in past years i look i i
think they are very bad person
you know the guy who event who created
ruby on rails
you know by the way both of them are
very popular you know because
one began ruby on rails and one begin
npm
there's one thing in common both of
these people
they are like uh they are okay
um
now when people say someone is asking
sometimes there is a
positive connotation meaning that you
know they are capable and you know
they are like a leadership you know like
steve jobs
has been called
no but no well some someone some people
just think
i'm an okay but anyway i i think
these these two persons i think i i
think they are scumbags okay they are
uh arrogant and they are you know they
are scumbag
scumbags in in in other ways
uh
so uh so so yeah so i don't like npm
and but however the
the ryan uh ryan guy who created not js
he is a great guy okay he is a great guy
not just in person i mean he is a great
guy
in in in as us in ethics morality okay i
think he's a great
person but also as a programmer
or a technologist i also admire i
actually admire uh this guy ryan
uh ryan uh doll uh his last name is star
or something
anyway he's a he's a guy who created not
jazz
because uh he's you know he's a
mathematician okay he
he he's a mathematician you know he's a
mathematician you know he he was doing
post doc
on some esoteric math subject then he
got bored and he started to do
he invented not js okay
and so he's extremely capable of
um of
of of you know he he knows math and he
also is an extremely capable programmers
so so i actually admire uh
this this guy because and also because i
have read
several of his articles in the past you
know his
thinking his philosophy the way he
thinks the way he
talks you know um i like him you know a
lot
so so not just i liked a lot well
i don't actually necessarily like not js
the product
you know he created that but i do like
he
him okay his ideas and his philosophy
and in general he's
you know whatever he likes will have
influence on me
he likes javascript a lot a lot for some
reason
and he also likes typescript a lot but
anyway
but anyway the sad thing is that he gave
up job uh not js
like five five years ago he gave it up
he passed on
he passed it on to the mpm guy npm
you know the guy who created npm the
scumbag okay
let me let me look up the name so i can
get the name correctly
mpm
creator
so i want to be specific you know uh
so what's what's his name by the way
you know these days when you since about
10 years ago these hacker types they try
to
like they they do not mention their
names in in whatever they created
you know they like you know as some kind
of gesture
being uh humble but actually they are
like the scumbag
the worst scumbags you can see you know
this social justice scan they
they they always do things superficially
like on the surface
they they hide you know they hide for
example
for example i created stuff like keys
okay if you like it good if you don't
like it good
i stick my name there okay if there's
anything
the bug or whatever if it caused the
disaster
my name is there you know be responsible
okay
now if if it's so good everyone loves it
you know gives
me money made me rich that's good you
know i stick my name to my
whatever i say my essays my product you
know
that that i considered good but
since like 10 years ago even before the
social justice scan this open source
including many in the emacs
community
they do not you know you you look at
their project page github or whatever
they do not put their name like they try
it's like implicit okay nobody expec
explicitly say why but they you can tell
you know they they try they do not
associate them like
they have this they try to put out this
gesture
as if like i'm trying to be humble you
know i don't want my name there
it's a open source project everyone
share you know it's not
you know you don't thank me you know
it's like everyone's
uh thing you know they do that since 10
years ago
since at least 2005. i think i think
they got scumbags
this is how uh it became social justice
today
you know they they okay for example one
of the guys who did this that
is the a lot a lot of the emacs dave i
dis
i don't really like okay um
for example one of the guy who always
had argument
with me but he's a good guy okay he's a
good person is the
emacs wiki the guy who created emacs
wiki okay
uh and he's a master then you know i see
his post now and then you know sometimes
he follow me
and sometimes i follow him you know
every like couple years sometimes i
we begin to follow each other you know
just to see
after a few after a few weeks then
unfollowed you know he unfollowed me i
haven't followed him like
i don't agree with your ideas like
this social these white people
especially
this social just justice kind person you
know they are always like white people
they are
they are liars and scumbags they they
lie so they get more power
and they lie and they always shine like
oh we i'm
we are the good guys i'm trying to do
good you know because but ultimately the
the the worst scumbags are them
okay the emacs wiki peop emacs wiki
the guy who started with imax wiki he's
a
uh a white person in germany okay um
you know by the way i don't mind he he
probably he knows my opinions okay we
we've been arguing about things since
since in 2005. you know so emax wiki
this guy
um you know he is he he doesn't really
um
let's see uh suggestions problems you
can find his name you know you can you
if you really try to find this uh who
created the project
you'll find them you know on the surface
they try they don't associate name but
however
you see they do not truly you know if
you are truly a good person let's say
let's say i'm a good um
i z iz yeah that's the guy who began the
uh
npm uh
sure okay so let me show some i'm gonna
get back to the comment pretty soon okay
because i'm on this topic this this
person these people okay they suppose i
i i i'm a good guy suppose you know i
let's say i want to donate money
so let's say i want to i have 10 let's
say
just a thousand not much okay let's say
i have a thousand i want to donate to
this nonprofit organization okay
what is the best way you know if you are
really humble
if you are really good you know in the
in the utmost
sense i go there i donate
anonymously okay they cannot they don't
even they it's impossible for them to
find out
i did it okay i don't need to for
example red cross
okay i i go there donate money
that's good but however usually that's
not how things work
when you donate you always you almost
like 1999
okay you always want your name to be
there because
that that is how that is how you derive
uh a pleasure or you know
you benefit you benefit from from from
it
but anyway so all these projects you
know they on the surface they try to
hide you know
the fact that they they they are the
creator
of it but actually that's not true you
know actually
they do not try to hide on their resume
on
on whatever whenever something there is
money
they they say i created it like you know
they then they put
out their name all the way you know it's
almost
always like the the case okay
and he this guy imax wiki guy what's his
name i i need to get uh
okay he he his nickname is uh
uh can can cancer
kensara or something let's find
[Music]
let's find the change category uh
let's search for ken okay yeah you
cannot even
find the name you're the these
people try to find
uh okay drew adams i know drew adams
true adam is a very old emacs
hacker
ah yeah this guy alex shorter
shorter he's he's a guy you know he's
he's a guy in germany
okay he created emacs wiki back then i
told him you know you should
use you know emacs wiki is written in
perl he's
he it is one of his pet project okay
4 000 lines of pearl he refused
to use the wikipedia software i told him
you know in order for emacs wiki to grow
to
to be general to be all powerful okay uh
to be
benefit to all people and and and the
full of information
you need to change the format so that it
stops
being a kind of a dialogue like a chat
you know pages like every page is full
of
you know random chat you want to make it
like wikipedia like
you know each page is a specific topic
and nothing but the
the content of the topic you know your
information about emacs you know
commands
emac list or you know each command how
do you change
font you know very focused no no chatty
things
if you want to chat then there's a
separate separate
page you know corresponding to that page
about
you know chatting about that page you
know i told him you know
this is the way to go but he doesn't
agree
but why why he did we argued a lot you
know i
if you search for xally uh on your emacs
page
sorry emacs emacs wiki you'll find my
essays about this
incident so we argued a lot but
basically
he doesn't want to change to to use the
emacs to
to use the wikipedia
wikimedia it's called wikimedia software
and he refused he also refused to put
onto rules that that
shapes the direction uh for imax weak
wiki to grow into like a encyclopedia
kind of format he refuses that
he rather prefer his idea of emacs wikis
that
it should be like like a commune that
uh
open source uh free software foundation
commune
you know so his idea is like everyone is
equal
and we can just go to any page we can
talk anyone anything we want
you know we can chat you know that's his
idea
of the emacs wiki so today on emacs wiki
you go to
almost any topic okay uh let's say how
to uh
appearances what you know you go there
it's like a bunch of
irrelevant information people chatting
about things
and
uh what are these uh you know people
chatting random things
and some chat is like 10 years old and
there's no date
so you got bunch of dialogues you don't
know you know sometimes
this is 10 years old sometimes this is
yesterday and random it's
it's just like random
so anyway so so that's a technical
disagreement
on how we see the direction
for emacs wiki okay i think he's idiotic
many of the open source people that's
why they can never build anything
successful linux or emacs so many things
sucks okay
i don't i i well
i like to say i kind of i kind of don't
get them you know these
uh open source unix philosophies idiots
they don't get it they they cannot think
but anyway so this is our
difference uh on opinion on the
direction
of how emacs wiki should go okay
he he doesn't he don't agree but look at
today
imax wiki has degenerated into no
traffic basically
my website has like 10 10 times more
traffic than emacs wiki
so anyway that's our difference between
direction but also
you know the reason why he doesn't want
to change it
he doesn't want to use the wikipedia
software
uh called wiki media
or media wiki okay it's written in php
he doesn't want to change change because
emacs wiki is written by his pet
pet project a single
file perl script of 4 000 lines
you know back then this is like 2004
okay
you know i i was also a pro coder so
i also i wrote a pro uh a bug database
on the web you know the whole thing is
one single
profile and also four thousand
a bug database but anyway so emacs wiki
so yeah so he wants to he want to stick
with his
pearls uh you know script that's selfish
okay
by the way i don't think he's wrong to
be
selfish i totally support you know he's
he's his desire to stick with his own
software
that's perfect however what is not good
is when is when this kind of people
start to say
oh i like to use my software but
meanwhile
i'm like i'm a you know a very humble
person i'm nice i'm for
open source that is when things go bad
go bad okay now if you are such a guy
that
you say that i don't give a about
you okay i just run emacs wiki the way i
want
okay kassadi you have that opinion you
go create your own
you know explicit you know you know say
that okay i like this
let's run out you know let's you know
let's do our own things
uh that's totally fine
but these kind of people they they don't
do that they
usually don't do that on one hand they
want to be selfish okay
whenever you know name is credit is
concerned they want to be selfish
but on the other hand when it comes to
like you know uh public
you know pr like public um
uh um you know that you know like
marketing
wherever there's money and and uh you
know
things like that is concerned they they
put out their name
so so the word is hypocrite
that that is a proper word okay now
by the way the alex stronger guy
i don't think i don't think he's a bad
person okay i'm kind of
but he's kind of that type of people
okay but he's he's not he's he's a good
guy okay he
he uh he's a good guy but i we disagree
but however what i'm saying is that he
kind of uh
represent this typical
open source this typical kind of a lot
of a lot of that
them are like that in emacs dave
community and and open source in general
especially white people i state
these white people
they are scumbags and today they become
social justice warriors
it's these people fake you know they
fake they do one thing for what
themselves
they they represent something else on
the surface but anyway
alex ronda is not i would don't you know
don't
uh uh you know he i think he's good okay
but he but anyway he's his mentality you
know i've seen his
i've seen his writings everything seen
his uh tweets and post posts and
he has this mentality every day is like
oh help
help help help the world help women
help minority you know he is like that
so today
some of these extremes there's a a
you know a minority of them becomes
extremes and they become the social
justice
gang which peop which
blatantly lie you know day and night
uh
okay so so so we're back to
so so back to so you actually
uh so npm package so let's see where in
my um
let's see how long i've been talking
one hour 25 minutes okay that's about it
so let's read some comments so isaac
shouted yes that's the npm guy let's
come back
okay uh
so let's see
so try deno rn okay
so you like deno avocadoras you like
deno i guess
console.com
yeah so let me tell let me let me finish
this um
you know the social social justice
people today is
extremely very bad okay they are they
are like
criminals like i mean let me put this
way okay
you know in america the white people
among these you know they
talk about certain countries certain
certain political party back
you know in 1940s in germany okay you
know what i'm talking about
they keep talking about that every day
like
you know day and night this is somehow
they have like
it's it's kind of idiotic okay because
if you survey
you know the if if you survey the world
history
the most people killed that's not you
know that
that country that's not that group okay
there's
quite a few more than others more than
that okay
but they don't know anything about that
though every day is like
you know these people n z and z and z
every day
but but you know actually what happens
is that today they are
they are this group the nz such social
justice scan
so um so you know you you
we need to do something about it so if
you are
now if you are in russia you know uh or
other countries you may not know you
know oh in
spain i'm sorry you know many of you
guys are not in u.s
so you may not you know this topic may
not sound interesting to you but
but it's pretty bad today you know in
white countries in uk
in you know usa uh in
in australia you know it's it's actually
it seems
worse in uk uk is the worst then
australia u.s is actually kind of still
doing okay but they are very bad yeah
you know um
they are actually you know it's so
serious i you know i've been observing
you know for the past two years you know
i've been spending
hours studying the situation you know
u.s
u.s is falling apart you know western
nations
uh i'm not a christian okay but
christian is
you know your u.s is falling down you
know it's
it's very likely in fact if if according
to camille paglia who is you know
who is an expert in history and cultural
studies you know
he she observed you know she she has
videos uh lectures and so on she has a
observed you know in in the history of
humanity
there are no lack of empires there are
no lack of great
you know the greatest empires that rules
the world okay
but however you know they come and go
they don't last forever they come and go
so you can so you can observe when when
they fail
why they fail you know why why this
sometimes you know the
most powerful nation empire of the whole
world
it's like impossible to fall like you
know maybe like today's google for
example
but however they do fall they you know
after a decade 10 years or 20 days or
maybe a hundred years for empires you
know they go away they went away
and you want that so so you observe you
you can study them of course a lot of
historians
he historians study uh it you
you can you know different historians
may have different conclusions
you know but you you could
obviously you can make observations and
make your
conclusion so camille pacquiao say
observed you know she says that many of
these great countries you know one
thing happens is that when they begin to
uh
fall is that when their arts
uh became uh no more
became um became elaborate because
he became like without uh without shape
without form it becomes
like uh a more amorous
of us you know without definite form
well actually it's it's like it became
gay so there's no masculine
you know there's no more masculine
beauty very definite
uh you know strong sharp masculine
uh beauty or the feminine beauty which
is you know
you know has certain definite shape but
the society when you observe the these
empires you know
there are it becomes you know
wishy-washy you know this all that
fluid you know that that kind of thing
that's
that's her observation when empire falls
and if you i mean if you look at usa of
course
it's a similar thing is happening now
so according to her you know she says
you know this is a dangerous
this is a phenomenon when a a
great country is falling apart you know
it's it's about to
end well yeah i mean you you can
disagree or this
you know or not agree it may not be true
i mean
of course after it's just the
observation
observations do not always come you know
true you know we have to see what
happens
and also maybe now that we are aware
we can start to change it you know stop
that thing you know
but anyway so that's what she you know
that's one observation so
but if you look at usa it's kind of like
that you know i'm looking at china you
know
all the china the uh technology growth
it's incredible i don't see that in usa
you know especially
you know in the past two years you know
china you know this that and you look at
the photos of their
cities it's amazing the skyscrapers you
know
it's all new and it's not just one city
you know there's like tens of cities
amazing skyscrapers
and with with you know neon signs like
over the
the whole building like you don't see
that you don't see that in usa not in
new york not in san francisco you know
like new york san francisco los angeles
uh you know chicago all the major cities
they don't change
they haven't been changing and there's
no
anyway lots of things you know so so
what i'm saying is that this i
you know i feel this is you know us is
kind of like
it's not growing and of course a lot
economics
uh you know statisticians you can study
you know uh
economy and you know so in in any in
many
all aspects you know china
is really growing you know uh and u.s
u.s is i think
maybe is a second now in
economic growth or something like that
or activity or output you know
or you know gpd or something you know
but anyway so so that's
that's that's bad i mean that that's you
know if you if
you know we don't you know we don't know
if this is true i mean
it's it's not a good thing it's not a
good thing
for us americans and also in general
it's just
you know you just because you want to
grow you know you want to
doesn't matter what country you are you
want to you know progress
when you see your country is you know
stagnate it's
it's not a good thing so anyway so u.s
you know i think so there's this
dangerous
um kind of you know situation usa
um and uh to me okay
uh the social justice is one of the
primary
problem in in our society it's it's
it's uh it is i would say it's the
primary problem
because once you because social it's not
just you know the
ideas about gay or you know it's it's
not just that because
they are tied to political the democrat
party
and heavily tied to corruption and in
fact the whole
academia the universities is crumbling
down
you know people students do not learn
anything there
and then you have the students you know
uh you know violence against teachers
you know like
they don't respect teachers they don't
respect professors
when you have that situation
that's very bad your country is falling
apart you know usa
when students or you know can
uh you know you know threaten violence
to professors
that's not and the administrators are
like
kind of helping the students doing it
you know
the professors you know actually and
then also the college
fee is exorbitant so there's
a lot of things wrong and then it ties
to bribery to
political uh parties to the you know
politicians to the how the government
run
so it's a very bad situation so i think
you know we should
you know you should know if you you know
you if you are a us citizen you know you
should know about this and
you know do something about that
um so i want to some i want to summarize
kind of
since i've been you know i since i've
been talking about this issue
so i just might you know i want to
um kind of give my thought
because i mentioned because this topic
has been
uh coming on to my you know talk show
very often because because it's there
it's not
it's not like as a programmer even if
you are just focused on tech
you know programming stuff you cannot
avoid it because this social justice
scan
i mean no mistake about calling them
again
they actively it's one of their goal to
actually
to actively
encroach every field they want to
actually go into every
they want to touch everything so for
example in the programming community
then you have the feminism then they say
you know women is not you know equally
represented because
because of you know this or that then
they have you know uh the
they then then they uh spread their uh
code of conduct
which is a a a heinous uh
crime okay not a crime but it's a
heinous
tactic um
it's it's it's extremely uh uh bad it's
it's
because it is well
that's another topic okay because when i
talk about these things i have to
so many topics then i have to spend 10
minutes to discuss or describe that
why it's bad anyway so i want to i just
want to summarize
so so this social justice scan they
it's one it's their act it's their
actual goal to
to go to to attack to crumble down
everything they want to touch everything
so we have to you know fight it back we
have to
i think you know i i'm not kind about
these people you know
you have to wipe them out you know if
you know for example like the french
revolution okay the french revolution
now i
i don't know much about that but i do
know it's a you know revolution where
you
the there were there were kings and
queens you know
who are supposedly very bad and rich and
powerful
and they got be they gone they got
thrown out and
beheaded you know gulatan i want gulatan
to
i want okay let me let me say i want
justice to happen to this
social justice scan okay i want it to
happen
so i don't want to you know um
you know i want i want social social
justice to happen to
this ex to to any of those people
who are extremely bad
um
okay so i think that's it that's it for
today
uh i think i guess that's it for today's
topic so any any
comments any final um
thoughts
so not afraid so daniel says i'm not
afraid of social justice people i
picture a few over-educated mexican
lesbians
maybe uh maybe i need to wake
up yeah so
so you know i don't know how you know
it's hard to say you know i i think it's
the what really
is going to happen it's really hard to
say you know like on one hand
i mean i look at what what's happening
you know
every day it's uh many things are really
bad
happening you know like for example uh
people get fired because of the social
justice doing things
you know um things happen every day and
also in
among politicians you know
but on the other hand maybe you know
they say you know it's really just a
minority
really a very small minority uh
activists you know who are doing these
things
and on the other hand we still have
law you know u.s we still have us law
and u.s law is also
it's still working in most case
you know in general it's still working
so people
have been suing you know lawsuit of some
of these
social justice scam people you know and
uh
you know it's ongoing uh we don't know
what will happen yet so
we don't know um
and uh you know uh trump you know trump
is the enemy of the social justice scan
you know i didn't care about trump but
it looks like you know he is
so he's helping at least you know i you
know
he's at least helping to you know fight
again against the
social justice and also meanwhile also
the social
justice the extreme left people
they created this chaos you know because
they have this
uh spurious theory about things so
so internally what happens
eventually is that they create chaos
among themselves like today the feminism
is fighting the trans
you know groups like when you have like
whether trans should be in sports you
know what rules should there be
they cannot you know they are starting
to you know they are actually not
starting but they are
already you know fighting among the you
know lgbtq
you know whatever jargon they created so
on on one hand you have you know
feminism or women
then now there's this trance which is
making
you know uh you know
shouting things every day in politics so
and they don't agree you know because
women you know
trans you know especially for men
you know male turned into women so
you are you know you're busy you know
physically you are still different you
know you can hurt
you can hurt females easily
so there's the issue you know so they
are fighting and
and the twitter is spamming people
because of that and so
you know there's a lot of things going
on um
so what will really happen you know in
five years we don't i i think
i mean i'm trying to figure
figure it out and i don't know i cannot
say whether we'll be
you know maybe the social justice scan
is just an
just a fad you know just you know
uh uh um you know your past i don't know
i mean i i'm sure i'm 100 sure it'll
pass
for sure but the question is how many
how long
i mean it's different for if if it's
going to
go away in five years then then if it's
going to go away in 100 years that's
that's very different picture
so anyway so that's it for today so
thank you guys for watching
uh so
yeah let's see
yep okay okay um see you guys later see
you see you guys bye