good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of our top show today is August
5th 2019 now it's 9 o clock p.m.
California time and today I'm going to
teach you how to write a Emacs major mod
and I'm going to write it I'm going to
do a live demo and code it and I'm gonna
explain how it works
so let's if you go to my Emacs blog my
Emacs tutorial you go to write a major
mod so check out this tutorial you know
this has this contains everything you
need to know about writing a major mod
now if you are impatient of watching
videos you can just read these but I'm
going to go through them I mean
basically just one you know I'm going
just going to show you the basics today
let's see how many people I have so I
have no nobody's here yet and I'm going
to wait for five minutes so I'll be back
in five minutes you know maybe people
will come maybe you'll be better it's
better even there are a lot of people so
be right back in five minutes okay
start at 9:08 okay and there you go guys
I'll be back in five minutes and we'll
do a Emacs ninja mod okay so
and back morning everyone so today we
are going to write a major mod tutorial
live coding first tutorial on how to
write a Emacs major mod for you know for
programming languages for anything it's
you know major mod is very powerful
hi good morning Alessi aversives recives
where you from
so let's see how many people are
watching three people good so let me put
my full my drink and we'll start this is
raspberry and berry juice sugar free and
energy drink mix so how to write a major
mod so you know major mod is very very
powerful
okay let's begin begin at the beginning
so let's go through my my Emacs blog my
Emacs tutorial and in this section Emacs
Lisp and down below here write the major
mod you will see you know all the
tutorials about writing a major mod and
today I'm going to give you a basic
basic introduction on how to do that so
a major mod it's opened a new buffer and
on the Left window here you can see all
the Emacs commands I call for example
hope for world world backward word for
word cha backward cha previous line you
know so if I'm doing something you are
not familiar you can always look up on
the Left window he will show the command
name and you you know you then you can
look up the web search the web and
you'll find it so let's open a new
buffer so let's save save this as X X
let's say X X yeah so that's you know
that's Emacs Lisp so writing a major
model so so this is my Emacs blog let's
create a new section writing a major mod
okay that's what we cannot do and so
okay so so major mod making a major bot
so major mod involves several things
first of all it involves colouring
syntax coloring for example you see how
you know my buffer are colored you know
that's the most useful when you do a
programming language you know you want a
major major mode for that programming
language so so a major mod components of
major mod not components but features of
major mod ok
they include
the syntax coloring you know currents
and words and and this is what we are
going to do today syntax coloring then
comment command okay
then comment uncommon command so what
are they for example this is a Maglis
let's say d fun let's say define a
function you know we have we are trying
to define a function and let's say I
don't want this you know I can't come I
can come and it out you see this is
common comment or uncommon oh I can
comment the whole thing so you need a
command to do this you know you need to
write a command to comment on comments
so that that is one of the thing feature
for major mod so syntax Korean common in
comment and that is basically it that is
the call I mean that's typically that's
the 90% features of major ma that's what
you want was what you need there are
other things such as you know you might
have command to format the buffer to to
look up the documentation of a function
of that language or - oh and key binding
you know typically in a major mod you
have specialized key bindings to code
your commands for your niche major map
you know so that depends on the language
you know depending on the language for
example different major mod :
Ruby Python you know JavaScript maybe or
C you know a Java C++ maybe you need a
command to compile the file maybe you
need a command to to you know they are
depending on the language so other
features there are many other features
but the most two important feature is
syntax colouring
and a command to comment and uncomment
so what we're going to do is we are
going to write a major mod 4 syntax
coloring and that should be it for today
for this lesson and since we cover
syntax current that will also cover the
basic fundamental structure of a mate of
writing creating a major mod so let's
let's begin so if you go to my Emacs
tutorial you can see I battuto here
let's let's just follow the tutorial so
this is kind of like the textbook so
guys if you have comments opinions
questions posted ok the more you post
the better it is
recive yeah hi so posting comments ok so
so let's say you have this language now
this is this is actually mathematical
language okay suppose you have this
language you know this is math sine
squared cosine squared equals 1 you know
this is the code and you want to color
the sine you want to color the cosine
you want to color the pie and some you
know some and also infinity so cosine
and sine are function names you want to
and some function names you want to
color it in let's say blue then pi and
infinity are constants let's say you
want to color in green there's something
some other color so so this is your you
know your language your code you know
you want to color it so how do we do it
so we start by it's very easy ok so this
is the code that's all you need
let me show you let's just copy and
paste and you know let's show how it
works so let's go back to on our second
let me paste that here
sample code of your language okay
sample code of your language is this
okay and code okay showing browser
see that's the sample code then you
let's write the major mod for it so
let's go back to Emacs Lisp but for here
here's a code let's see set and defined
we've mark okay that that is it that's
you know just these few lines will do
now what we do is going to we are going
to save this file as my maths mod okay
so I go to the directory we name it my
math mod yeah you see this line okay
save it my math where did it go okay
it's here so open it so this file is
saved as my math - mod dot dot year now
we run it eval buffer we want to you can
call the command give a buffer to ran
the code now Emacs actually now know the
code because now I can't because I we
just evaluated it and now we can for
example I can do MX and my math you see
there's a command my my math mod so now
let's go back to the file let's go back
to the file where's my Emacs blog okay
so let's go back to the file and save
this as my math dot text okay let's say
this is and now in this buffer now we
call the command meta X my
math - mod enter you see you see how
they are colored you see sine cosine are
colored and some is also colored blue
and pi is you know pi and infinity are
colored green because they are constants
you know so that works so so what does
this mean for you practically so that
means you can copy it is just this six
lines of code and now you can change
these words sine cosine change the PI
infinity to any words you want you
basically now have your own custom major
mark and when you are in any file you
want those words colored you can just
meet our eggs you know and my math mod
can do walk okay so so far so good
so guys comments okay comment post say
hi hey green dick great thank you so
comments okay keep the comments coming
then you'll be better so now you see so
this is the basic of writing a major mod
it's so simple you know just this lines
now now let's go back to the Emacs
tutorial so so all the code you need
sample simple major mod code okay and
put it here
color it show in browser so this is what
we have covered so far you know so we've
this is a sample code we want to color
and this is the Emacs Lisp code that
actually creates the majima okay now let
me explain how this works okay so you
see so first of all we set you
we said variable mass my math highlights
you know that's just a variable name
then we in this the value of this
variable is a list you can see the
structure if I do it this way one second
you see it's simply a list of two items
one two a list of two items and now now
list this list is a invert list meaning
that the value is not evaluated okay so
so so we in this whenever you have
something like that some thing okay
let's say a PC this is exactly equal to
that okay these two are exactly the same
what basically what what it means is
that it does not evaluate the items in
the list and this is called quoted list
it's called quote so and this is a
variant syntax they mean exactly the
same thing so let's go back here so we
create the variable and the value is the
list we don't want to evaluate anything
inside so this each item is a each item
is conspire this is called constant pair
can spare
okay I'm not going to explain what
conspire is but basically just follow
the syntax it basically just means a
pair of two things
counts pair you know least in disp is
made of cons pairs actually but that's
any anyway that's a language detail you
don't really need to know if you are you
know just started with Lisp so anyway in
this list you have two items each item
is is called a conspire and the syntax
is you know you have a thought in the
middle like the first part then last
part and the thought in the middle so
what does this mean so this this mean in
this context is you know the first part
is actually a regular expression so
essentially here we want to say whenever
you see the word sine cosine or Sun you
want to use this this font value you
know font lock you know it means color
and font size and so on so basically
whenever you see these words you want to
use this font
you know font lock font font face it's
called face in Emacs face and when you
whenever you see these towards Spiro
infinity you want to use this face okay
so anyway so this is the variable we
define the value there and now we have
this function define derived mod now
define derived mod is a list macro that
kind of that helps you create a major
mod don't worry about the details
you know like for now just just code it
like this so so define the derived mod
it takes three arguments the first
argument is the major mod name the major
mark name you should include the word -
after it's a major mark name the second
second argument we have fundamental mod
here what that means is that from which
mod you wanted to inherit from you know
basically so the second argument is a
parent mod you can say you can specify a
paramount so you can say for example
Java Script mod ok please if your
language is similar to Java Script then
you can you know say the parents pyramid
is JavaScript mod that way you will
inherit many of the features from the
parent mod so that's a six second
argument but if you do not want it to
inherit it you inherit from anything
then you just say fundamental mod
fundamental mod because in emacs
fundamental mod is the most basic mod it
you know it doesn't have any features it
just mod so that's the second argument
second argument is the parent mod the
third argument is a string and this is a
string that shows up in the in the mud
line you see there is this bar here like
when you start a Emacs you will see this
spa at the bottom that shows the
information like like the file name you
know what mod what is the major mod
can't mean too much information like
that this spa it's called mod why okay
let me write it out mod like that that's
the name of the you know technique or
name you know sometimes you call status
spa you know because test satisfies the
most popular name in browsers you know
status you know he gives you status but
anyway it's called mod line so Amala
you notice right now in this buffer you
say is text here now that that thing
that means
right now I'm making a major mod that's
called text summation text that that is
actually my my own techsmartt so for
example let's switch to fundamental mark
so so let's do meta X matrix fundamental
mod you see notice how it changes to
fundamental we can also let's switch to
text mod okay you see how it changes so
this text indicates to the user what is
the current major mod but however this
text is not the actual mod name this
text is just a display to tell user what
mady's so it's like a label okay so this
text is this third argument here the
define derived mod third argument you
give it a string and you can put
whatever string you want so when that
when people call meta X you know call
you know switch to your major mod that
text will be displayed in the mod line
okay so that's the third argument then
the fourth argument is just a
documentation string you know you can
say version or whatever
okay now the heart the heart of the
function is in this slide you see it
only has one line the body version okay
so the body is this single line now this
line it says set set the variable font
lock defaults to to a list of one
element and this element is what we just
defined you know my math highlights so
what does this do you see it seems also
simple and but but so what what does
this do so
so in emacs when you write the major in
Emacs you have this you have this
building variable that is called font
lock defaults okay this variable this
variables values should be a list okay
and lists this list will determine
essentially or it tells Emacs how the
how to color the buffer basically you
know so let me let me summarize let me
repeat that so he max you have this
building variable called fun dog
defaults now this variable came from the
font log mod ok fun font lock mod is a
bo Dean package so what does that mean
font lock mod it's it's a minor mod it's
a mod that color syntax color the buffer
so Emacs has this font lock mod it's a
minor mod so in any buffer when you turn
font lock mark on your color the whole
profit like right now you see but if you
turn front lock mud off then there will
be no syntax coloring for example let's
turn it off so meta X front lock mod
enter you see all the colors are gone
because the font log mod is not on now
let's go it again font loud mod now the
color is back because fun lock mod he's
on that's a minor mod meaning that being
any buffer you can have it on or off in
a buffer basically you have a major mod
and you have many minor mods you can
turn on and off but each buffer is
associated with one major mod major mod
means you know the primary language you
know a bunch of commands and features
that's designed for working with a
programming language Java JavaScript
Python so on
okay so I met so am I getting confusing
okay so so you got these font lock mod
okay
that turns think that that does syntax
coloring you can turn it on and you can
turn it off
it is the font lock mod that does the
syntax claim now in front lock mod it
has a variable called font lock defaults
essentially it's a convenient way for
you for any coder to specify how do you
want the syntax coloring to be done so
the fun lock defaults is a variable it's
it's a value its value is a list and
depending on what's in this list that's
that's how he max know how to color the
buffer okay so in this code we have we
are setting you know this value to the
you know this list to the fun log
defaults so that's how it works so you
see do you so so is that the is that
clear
am I making sense green deck and as if
let me know okay so you see so we we are
calling this defined the right mod that
defines this command my math - mod okay
and when this command mod this command
is called you know do whatever it's in
the body and in this body there is only
one lie it just sets the font lock
defaults so when you call this command
my math - mod Emacs will set the value
to the fun lock defaults and when that
happens the buffer you know we are real
colors will start to color you or your
words you know because you have fun like
ma mano
so I'm hoping that makes sense
and now this is the this is not the only
way to syntax color buffer okay but this
is the most used way this is the kind of
the conventional way you see the font
lock mod the fun log mod you know it's a
minor mod that the syntax coloring and
you can think of it as an API
you know application programmers
interface to control how a buffer colors
words but it's not the only way in fact
it's actually a high-level way in Emacs
you can you can actually color any text
in a lower level command by by giving a
property to any text in a buffer so you
can say you know I want to give this
property to this sequence of characters
and you know the property can be you
know color red or something or can be
any other thing then you'll be red so
Emacs has a you know call a fundamental
way to color text in a buffer and that
is code
let me show you how that is called okay
that is called text properties okay
let's see if I have it covered here
create key Maps syntax table I I think I
have a curve have it somewhere here but
anyway that's so anyway let me let me
try to summarize again let me write it
out so maybe now be clear
emacs has two basic way to color text in
a buffer okay and one is called text
properties okay - is called text overlay
okay yeah text property I cover text
properties here and I let me show you
okay you can read it and I cover text
overlay here let me write it out text
overlay okay now these are the
mechanisms how Emacs Emacs Lisp color
buffer oh you know any font properties
like font size bold underline things
like that so so that's that the pate the
fundamental to Co way to to color text
in buffer
now however Emacs provides the font log
mod it is a minor mod that does that is
like a API - syntax color a buffer
okay so front lock mod is building in
Emacs so if you are writing a major mod
to do syntax coloring you can use font
log mod
okay you can use fun lock mark front
lock mod that's what we did and that's
why things are so simple you see in just
these six lines we we have a major mod
that color syntax and okay let's show
you see we colored it and all you have
to do is you know all you have to do is
space all basically all you have to do
is you just have to set a value to the
font log defaults that is all okay so
that that is the explanation of the
basic structure you know the you know
just a real basic introduction of how
color you know Cullerton in Emacs so far
so good
so okay so now you know how to write a
major mod for basic syntax coloring now
if if you are you know if you're writing
this for real programming language you
might have hundreds of keywords so I
show you you know some practical way to
do that you know we when you do a when
you write a a major mod it's actually
you know it you know because I've been
you know because I know these so that's
why everything seems so simple but when
you actually to do it and you try to you
know code it for your own purposes you
know your own programming language or
whatever you need it you know you might
you know take few hours and several
tries because because so I'm giving out
a warning you know it's actually not
that simple
that's for example let's look at the
font log defaults documentation so
described variable you can see here it's
called describe variable
okay describe there let's do it again
describe variable font lock defaults and
that will show the documentation for
phone log defaults so let's let's see
why it says phone log defaults is a
variable defined in front lock in font
Cordia its value is this list local
imperfect probable value is new okay and
it says automatically becomes buffalo
core when set this variable may be risky
if used as a fire local variable and
that's not critical information so
basically this variable this fan log
defaults is a local it's a buffer local
variable meaning that each buffer you
know each person in emacs will have its
own value you know each buffer will have
its own value and it can be different so
whenever you say the value to fund lock
default that automatically becomes you
know whatever the buffer you are in you
know just for that buffer you know not
nowhere else
that's what before local variable means
now this variable you know it also says
this river may be risky if uses the fire
local variable that's that's not too
important that that means you know in
Emacs you can set a variable so that you
can you can have some syntax in English
I'll at the end or in the beginning
such that when Emacs open that file some
Emacs code will run so so this line is
telling you that font lock defaults is
not a safe variable meaning that if you
if you you know put code to to set that
value potentially it can be you can do
do a lot of things basically it's just
warning you that like when you open
fire if it came from someone you don't
trust you don't want to when you open it
Emacs we're wrong we'll tell you you
know there's some in this code do you
want to run it if you don't trust that
the source you don't want to run it
that's what it means you know this
variable may be whiskey if you use a
sapphire local variable so anyway that's
fun Locke defaults okay but what exactly
I mean so let's get to the main point
so documentation says defaults it says
defaults for font lock mod specified by
the major mod ok it it means it means
it's a thief it's a variable that came
from the font log mod and typically it
is a major mod that sets a value of that
variable that's what this line is so so
now it tells you you know default should
be of the form so this so this this line
here that is the remember the value
should be a list so this line tells you
exactly how the structure of the list
and what the elements mean and so you
can you can read that you know when you
when you try this you know it's kind of
long and so you know I would not say
it's very simple you know you you if you
want to read your mod you might have to
do a few tries it's a bit tricky
it's especially tricky because this list
is not simply you know a flat list it
can be heavily nested you know so so
anyway we are just going to show you the
basics you know the most basic is basic
uses like that you know you just set it
to a list and the value you know you
sell it here okay hey Battle of MU
greetings
pattern of MU I can stay okay I'm on my
way to work now
have a nice stream see you next stream
okay
thank you for coming back what do I
think about helm I don't use helm for my
personal taste I think it's rather
complicated and so so I don't use helm
let's see how long I've been talking 42
minutes I'm thinking you know I'm
thinking I want to maybe do I want to
cover some of these things so we get
this done with or maybe we talk about
something else you know I don't I don't
use her mod you know I can't I can you
know I can do it
Chad you know chat about the history of
helm you know it begins around 2008 you
know in 2008 or actually maybe earlier
2005 there is a great Mac utility called
quick quick Silva
do you know that so green deck were you
for my Forgotten child like to say wait
you tell me where you from Quicksilver
okay so there is a here so this is the
application they used they have a
Wikipedia page I don't know maybe they
removed it Oh Russia okay great yeah I
think I know that city right that that
city to the west of to the east of
Moscow right I think so anyways so so
around 2005 there is this Quicksilver
utility for mac OS and it is fantastic
so what does that do you know it kind of
revolutionized the user interface in the
industry okay so what does it do so what
they do is they do you press a key and
it will pop up a box like this
then you can type something like Emacs
okay then you can you know then you
press ENTER if it's an application
you're launch it now or it will search
all your files for that word you know so
so this is like one stop utility for you
to launch files for you to find specific
text or your contacts things like that
you know just one you know you just type
you know as you know as you type
interactively you know you can launch
applications or find some files so
that's that's Quicksilver around 2005
and that is the that revolutionized the
user interface you know then you know
once you have this then the you know
then then windows pick it up you know so
for Windows Microsoft Windows you can
press the start button no then you start
you can type then you know if you see
before this so this is how people do
things now and also on Linux on Ubuntu
and so on
you know you when you want to launch an
application you just type the name and
you can launch it browser Safari Firefox
and so on but however it's not like that
before you know it it's not like that
before quick suburbs
so before Quicksilver typically you have
shortcuts to launch applications then
you have another shortcut to launch an
application to find find locate you know
files you know each one is different so
so anyway so this becomes very popular
the Quicksilver way so then so it came
to Emacs in a beginning so around 2008 I
think it's called everything you know
someone wrote a Emacs package I think
it's called everything you know oh I
think it's called anything yeah anything
you know because that
kind of what it does you can you know
open files or do anything with it yeah
through via this one unified interface
so in the beginning it's called I think
anything then over the past 10 years it
then you know anything it's not a good
name because what do you mean anything
you know so eventually they they named
it helm I don't use it okay I I don't
use it because I don't like this
interface IP you know I for example this
this this spotlight search its which is
similar on the Mac you know I do not use
it I don't like it I do not like to
launch my application this way at you
know because I want full control you
know I know exactly
for example the applications I know
their names I know exactly what where
they are you know I want to be extremely
efficient you know if I want to launch
Emacs I do not want to type II M a CS
you know five keys I don't want that I
want to press one key launch in Emacs
okay I you know because I used you know
I'm a computer nerd side you know I use
it all the time so I want more control
because it you know it means less
keystrokes I know where things are and
the way I want to find a file I don't
want to you know I don't want it to just
globally try to find file behind the
scenes I know exactly where my fire sub
files are so I do not like the these
kind of the type something interface so
I let that that is why I don't use it
and in in Emacs yeah I don't use it
either because well partly because you
know I I also called Emacs Lisp for you
know for me years now so I have I have
what I want you know what I want I can
just write it you know most of the time
so and in helm becomes I tried helm you
know for a couple of times it becomes
very
elaborate and you know as you know you
could bloated you know it's trying to be
smart you know like in the user
interface space you know there's a train
to evolve into smartness you know it
like you don't have to do much you know
the computer will find things for you
and do you know do things for you behind
the scenes which is in general good for
most people but I think for nerds you
know if you are programmer you really
like you know know things you know where
they are you you you rather prefer
control you know better control so so
that that is why I don't use help okay
that that is about helm so let's see how
long have I been talking 15 minutes so I
think maybe that's wrap up about how to
write a major mod there is something
okay did we didn't cover much of the
practical things about writing a major
mounted a we we talked about basically
the infrastructure today and you know
for example if you want to write a major
mod a typical programming language has
hundreds of keywords so how do you do
that you know how do you so there are
some so in this file I show you how to
do that yeah okay so let's let's have a
look at the file so
so let me show you so okay so guys keep
the comments coming type type it so does
that so do you use green deck do you use
helm I suppose you use helm right
okay so so anyway so let's look at this
code so this this code is just the same
thing like before it's creating a major
mod let me show you where
so here oops here you see this this this
code is it's just create a major mod and
it's called my LSA or mod it's created
for this language now this is a sample
source code of our SAR language or ESL
is a Linden scripting language it's a
part of the second light so anyway so
this code has like a C syntax similar to
C us you know C++ so we want to write
the major mod for this language and here
is a sample code for writing you know
the major mod for that language you know
and this is how it colors you know it
colors integer string vector list all
these are type keywords then you have
you know function names where function
names you have you know several building
keywords function names function names
and so on you know so you want to color
oh and you have comments so you want to
write a major mod that colors that and
this here is the code here's the result
and you see that's only like ten lines
you know most of it is comments but let
me go over to tell you some some some
important things about that so if you
write a major ma typically you want this
header you know especially if you want
to share your mod to the public you know
if you want to put it to the maple yeah
Mel paw you know Mel pop repository so
you need the first line and it needs to
be
this format three semicolons then the
file name tweet then followed by three -
then one short very short sentence about
what this fire is about then optionally
you can declare the encoding and lexical
bandying true okay so you need typically
you want this line then you have some
copyright information then you have some
standard header for author version
creation date and keywords and you are
things like that then typically so so
this is a kind of a standard header you
can find that in many places online like
Emacs wiki and so on and oh you can copy
my header okay so those are headers you
know this this this is a convention this
is yeah so if you want your major model
package to be used by others you you
kind of you have to follow this this
syntax this convention then when you
have this code that's that's how you
your code began so just like before we
set the variable for log keywords okay
and you can see we have lots of
variables you know for our language as
well you have you have language keywords
you have types you know string integer
vector list then you have constants then
then you have events events is you know
specific to second life linden scripting
language then you have function names so
anyway so so just like before this the
value of this variable is just a list
you know here we are just setting up at
least then we call you know we we use
the define derived mod to define the mod
and basically the whole body of the mod
is just is
just setting that variable font lock
defaults now notice this auto load thing
that is also part of the convention that
has Emacs that that helps Emacs whenever
Emacs read this file whenever there's a
function you know it's the preceded by
the line auto load in this format
specifically three semicolons followed
by three pound signs then the world auto
load so when we max it sees that sees
that it will it will make a record of
the function name and the file name you
know so that you can actually call it
even though Emacs does not actually
evaluate the code you see eMac that's
not you know Emacs is this Emacs will
make a record of the function name in
the file name so so that you can meet
her X you know you can call the function
as if it's available even though if
Emacs haven't evaluated yet so once you
call it Emacs know the file location so
Emacs can you know run the code so white
what do you need is because this way
saves the startup time you know that's
the that's about auto load I have a
tutorial about auto load you can you
know about all those things
somewhere here load load file auto load
there so that's about that so anyway so
then you need to say provide that's kind
of like a package mechanism so if you
say provide then the more name that
helps Emacs that okay we have this
symbol available so that so for example
when you're in it file somewhere it says
you know require this mod the Emacs can
know that it's already loaded or not you
know saves no time things like that so
you know all things considered you know
writing a major mod although it's very
simple you know if you are doing it for
yourself you know you just need ten
lines that's all you need but if you
want to publish it you need to learn
about all these various details
including including the end ending here
you know that tells in Emacs you know
this is where the package ends you know
all these are little conventions so so I
you know I covered them in my tutorial
here so you can you know this much more
details there yeah there is another
thing I want to mention that's kind of
important because so far we have cut we
have covered the coloring of words you
know in a buffer you know we have
covered how to do that
cover coloring of the words but however
this is important this is critical when
you have a stream such as this this is a
stream and when you have a comment this
is a comment now
the coloring of a stream and the
coloring of concept is not handled by
the way we just explained for example
where is our code where so you know is
so coloring of string and coloring of a
comment you are not handle are not
covered by the way we are doing here so
you see the way we are doing here is are
actually just coloring words so how do
you how do you write your major mod so
that we are colors
for example like that or comment that is
that in order to do that there is you
need the the primary thing for that to
happen in order to do that you have to
learn about syntax table okay let's see
define phase syntax syntax table so I
call it a cupboard syntax table over
here and see so anyway oh this detail I
explained in my tutorial so so let me
summarize so to do syntax colouring of
words we have covered it's as simple as
that
now if you want also color string and
the comment which is almost always
necessary you know you want them colored
then you have to set up syntax table and
I'll explain about that another day
because you know that's getting too much
and also in between you see so many
other topics we you know so writing a
full-featured major mod may not be that
easy okay but you know you have to start
somewhere you can begin trivially just
like that I think that's what we want to
cover today let me read the comments so
quick green deck says I just discovered
it it looks cool for for finding files
by name yeah yeah yeah a lot of people
use it you know I can you know yeah yeah
so you know if you like it you know you
like so it's a good tool I recommend it
it's what I I'm fairly sure it's well
written by this guy
and it's it's huge you know that the
code you know that I think I'm guessing
it's like mod it's few thousand more
than ten thousand lines for sure because
it's large and also yeah so it's a good
tool if you like it you know use it but
they are a lot you know like typically
in the Emacs world there are many
alternatives you know some people like
helm there's also IV you know this IV
you can look up iby there's IV there's
you know there's quite a few and you
know the workflow Emacs is you know very
flexible and customizable so everyone
has different preferences and workflow
so so but if you look at Emacs community
for example you could read it you know
some people will say oh I love helm some
people say oh but no I like I be better
okay so you know you have choices from
for me I don't I don't use it neither of
them so green deck says it looks very
complicated really change change the way
you use Emacs yes yeah that's the major
point about helm you know helm is you
know this idea that you know you know
like based on you know typing some
things interface it and to be fair I
have not made a full study of that
interface you know because I'm
interested in efficiency like how many
kids like scientifically you know I want
to find what's the most efficient way
what's the most efficient workflow
what's the most efficient way to switch
windows so should you have one window or
should you have you know multiple
windows and should you have you know
split pane so what I mean to that kind
of thing but I have not made a thorough
study of the helm kind of interface so
yeah it's up to you
so green deck says I have directory with
many directories and lots of images in
them okay
directory with many directories and lots
of images in them same thing here so for
example I go to my Emacs directory I can
go to you know here is all my images let
me show you this directory is you know
you see four hundred images so if you
have that situation directly with many
directories and images I don't know
what's the best way to search them oh
okay so if you want to search text
that's very easy you know there are so
many okay so there are so many ways
again the way I use you know my way is
so find sapphire fire okay so we put a
plug of my own package so for example
let's go to my Emacs blog showing
browser now let's say you know so in
this directory I have like 800 files
okay I want to find all files that
contains the world Haskell
so I call the command so fine text
Haskell enter and it asked me what
directory okay in this directory and
asked me what file extension ok HTML you
see then here are all the occurrences I
can press arrow keys to navigate you
know or I can press up/down arrow to
navigate around the files you know down
or next occurrence then if I press ENTER
your open file in that location you see
this this file and show in browser okay
so this is an essay is lisps objects
concepts necessary you know so so yeah
so that so that is my package saw find
let me show you
so here's the command the command I just
called his cell fine text and it's in
this package sapphire DL and let's go to
the source code so this is the source
code about 800 lines and I have a
website that shows you know experience
you know so you can you can use that so
and this is one of the way to find a
string in a directory it can be nested
directory you know and some people like
other ways actually so if you go to my
Emacs tutorial you will find a section
Emacs find/replace and this section
covers all the ways in mx2 to such a
string you know so and you know so I
happened to eventually write my own way
because I think it's better you know but
but but if you are not using you know if
you don't want to use any packages you
can see such texting or directory so
this this page explains the different
ways to search text you know directory
and it's very good you know I've been
using it for several years so you know a
lot of people these days you know they
like to use all the mods you know they
go to my Appa you know they they want to
do something they search for mail pi and
they there are so many packages so you
should use helm IV and you know that but
to me I think many building Emacs
commands people for God you know since
about five years ago since kind of the
the the the bloat of the social network
you know quick baits and all that so
people stopped people stopped studying
studying the core functions of a
programming language you know instead of
studying the program
which language they just you know go
find a library oh I need to trim the
screen find the library but actually you
know it's ready in the language it's you
know that's what the language is
designed for you know similar way you
know Emacs when you want to do something
you just go to my Appa and find you know
something that does that but actually in
often is often the case you can imagine
Emacs can do it and it's typically you
know several times faster than whatever
library you are using you know and so so
I use this you know Emacs default way
the Koran is code okay so you know they
are there person cons you know because
in the if you use the Emacs default way
it requires two it requires you to have
the grep UNIX utility it's required you
know so if you are on Windows and you
don't have that installed that's a
problem you know in our case you can use
my package you know case are fine
because my package is pure this it's
written in pure Lee's so one of the
advantage of you know sapphire is that
it runs everywhere every you know you
just download the package it's Lisp you
know it's building is you know you don't
have to download is external utilities
you know for some people that's an
advantage because on Windows then you
have many it gets complex complicated
you know you have many sequin you have
you know several other alternatives you
know yeah so if and so if you want to
use Emacs building you have you know you
can you can do that but you need the
crap UNIX utility which is you know on
Linux it's already there and our Mac is
also already there and and and like it
you know so there are many many
varieties then today you have people
using arc AG I think you know there are
several great replacements
that is faster than grab you know grab
is pretty old so they are safer that's
suppose that's faster typically the
speed doesn't matter to me because when
you search 1000 of 2000 files you cannot
see the speed difference that's you know
you'll see the speed defense only when
you have like maybe you tenth you know
fifty thousand files or something like
that and also much of the time when you
try to find a firing indirectly much
about time is spent on the hard disk
spinning yes you know was because once
you search the first time the operating
system today typically put all the files
into cache memory cache so once you do
it the first time then the second time
it's very fast you know it doesn't
matter 10,000 files or not so the time
the most time span is actually the disk
so you want to get you know fresh disk
if you don't have that you know yes so
there are a lot of pros and cons of
different ways
oh if you only need to such file names
then the typical solution I do is just
UNIX utility find okay this is what I do
so find name and Esther is let's say
house call so this command so a me-yow
this command will find all filenames
that contains the word has come let's
try it
none okay let's go to previous directory
do it again oops
close it okay let's do it again okay
there is no file name named Haskell with
the world Haskell let's go to my
programming block okay go to the
directory go to a directory there it is
so I have actually several image files
with the name has cow
open it okay this is Haskell
documentation open it this is a Haskell
documentation this is yeah Unicode in
Haskell this article I talk about
Unicode yes has cow in math symbols you
know like summation sign then you have
this this this this one is about the Oh
engine of the Haskell syntax you know
Haskell syntax where does it came from
that is that about so you know I have
several files about Haskell and okay
okay and then you have this article
history of Oh Cameron Haskell syntax the
next 700 programming languages now this
is interesting because in Haskell DoCoMo
they are syntax you know like most
languages today Java JavaScript C press
first c-sharp you know they are all
based on C language syntax and then you
have this family but where does Haskell
ok mode and f-sharp you know their
syntax is similar where do their syntax
came from not more mathematics okay
where did it came from they came from
this article this article in 1966 by
this guy PJ London that's very funny
because you can read this article if you
go through my website let me show you
okay so this is the URL that's let's
this is your let's go look at file wait
wait for loading so this essay 1966
basically he published this article
titled the next 700 programming
languages now this is the father of
clickbait okay
the next 700 programming languages
and it appears to me you know I'm doing
my research so it appears to me this
article this this this is publishing
we're in one of the let's see let's
magnify this is published in I forgot it
doesn't say here it's publishing some
programming you know research journal or
something like that the next 700
programming languages so this this
article seems to be very popular it cat
caught programmers fancy you know it
seems to me that this article is
supposed to be you know this is the
final say about syntax you know oh you
guys arguing about syntax you know get
out this is the you know the ultimate
answer about see that how you should
design a language is syntax so it so it
turns out you know this is very
influential paper and that's how oak mo
got its syntax then Haskell basically
kind of copied it you know so you have
the family you know the ML language meta
language or camo meta language camo
standard camo SML the oak mo f-sharp
Haskell Miranda I think also Miranda and
cream you know this functional and
languages they they kind of all just
copy copycat you know from this article
now this alko is actually I don't like
it because I try to read it the writing
style is pretty it's it's the writing
style is very unclear its convoluted
okay I don't like the writing style and
also this is like 1966 so maybe there's
some change in writing style but anyway
you try to write it you try to read it
it's difficult to understand and you
know then you look at you know what he
say
you know and I don't agree okay I know I
don't think it's in any way you know you
know good essay you know good discussion
you know i but but actually I haven't
fully digested the the essay because how
to read so okay so let's so so yeah so
we were trying to find four or five our
names you know other we want to find a
file with a specific string in the name
so that's what I do
you know the classic eunuch UNIX utility
fine and if you want case-insensitive
you use the option i name and this is
the you know this is building every UNIX
and Mac OS you know and it's pretty fast
okay so that's about it then anything
else green deck yeah that's it for today
so so if you like my stuff you like my
tutorials you can you know go by my you
can buy my Emacs tutorial or you can you
know patreon patreon me you know five
bucks a month you know like coffee a cup
of coffee
a month or something so thank you thank
you green deck thank you green deck
demetri demetri matt of wave hey sy I
find finally got you type greetings from
Moscow great so we got two Russians from
Moscow from LA from Russian so that you
know wherever I see Russian that reminds
me of the James Bond movie
what do you what is the name that we
love from Russia or something okay so
great so I think that's it for today so
anything else anything chat let's you
know let's chat for me a few minutes
anything interesting your stuff so
writing a major mod which is a fantastic
journey into Emacs Lisp and very
practical useful and actually there are
many things to go over
you know when used you know you can so I
hope you know today you can get started
to write your own major body it's
actually you know it's it's fun and
practical you know like today like if
you don't if you called Python or
something javascript or Golan you don't
like the you know default you can you
know start to write your own you know
just by starting to copy these six lines
and you you'll be on your way then you
can read you know you can learn details
about font mod you can learn details
about define defining your face like you
can customize your you know you can
customize your font size color and the
score and so on then you can you know
then you can create features you know
that's that's only useful to you you
know and you can also there are things
like how do you define how do you define
your own keys yeah this is a major thing
you know you have to add your own key
bindings to a major mod then you can
define a brief this is also fantastic
for example in Emacs Lisp you know for
example because that in email is you
know that Nimisha for example right type
T Enter I gotta fun then space I got the
whole shebang you know as you know I
want to set
variable that have s said Q oh the whole
thing cutter you know that's a brief you
know am using Emacs Lisp mod so let me
show you the you know saw him actually
smart that's what I'm using let's go to
the source code and you see so it's
three thousand and six hundred lines of
code you um you begin small you know you
begin with just ten lines name
eventually you you grow it so you know
so you have a brief you have you know
you start to add up features you know so
that's a you know good journey to and
also besides when you think of major mod
typically we are thinking of you know
programming language but actually look
right now we are in tired you know these
showing directories and let me show you
this for example let's go back here
let's go back to you know so this is a
tired tired is the major mod is a
directories and we can open an image
okay this is the laptop that gave me
repetitive repetitive strain injury in
2005 so because I typed on this one for
like eight hours a day for two years
that that is my arrow began so you know
you can open the image file and what is
this this is a major mod you know so you
have a major mod that reads you know
image files and displayed you know so
that's a major mod and you have issue we
have shown issue you know II shall you
know that's also a major mod you know so
you can start to write that so it major
mod you know typically you you you it's
for programming languages but then you
can much you can write a shell you can
write a you know directory interface you
can write you know
many things that's those so Dimitri says
my problem with major mod is that
everything I need is already written
that's true yeah you know so Matthew is
salsa hey good evening Matthews so yeah
we are actually yeah we are done today
so yeah okay so thank you thank you guys
for coming that's so that's that's it
thanks bye