good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2000 2017 2021
april today is not april 1st today is
april 8th time flies
and soon i'm gonna be you know 10 more
years
10 more years you know i have a motto
that is five years will be passed
sooner or later when i was younger when
i was 20 something
30 something i had
hello to me max so i had this motto you
know
when you are young when you are younger
you have lots of questions and
frustrations in life
so now i'm 50 something those
problems went away because i have more
experience i know you know i know
what are the answers more or less you
know but when you
when you are when i was young i had this
motto
uh five years will be passed sooner or
later that was my motto because
it works for me because you know i was
worried about things you know but
then you think about five years will be
passed
sooner or later uh and your problem your
current problem will go away
so anyway that was my motto so today
i don't have a topic it's kind of
randomish so you can ask me questions
okay
uh
uh or more important would be to share
your mathematical findings okay i
i can yeah i can do some mathematica
you know one of the topic i want to talk
about is the
uh let's let's go to my let's
i haven't set up my stuff yet so let's
let's set up so this window is gonna be
let's call xa wait first of all let's go
to bookmark
emacs bookmark settings
so magnify magnify you can see the full
glory
of emac list so this section is setting
up
font okay so i'm gonna open a new window
paste it i already copied it and
and switched to xr emac this mod okay
then i go here this is setting font so
console.14 okay evaluated
so now every one of my window is gonna
be bigger font
for the live stream so close close don't
save close
shrink window again then here i'm going
to call xr
start command so on the pink window
every command i do you can see the
command name
and the and the key i
i press okay i'm using software keys so
move forward word
move backward by word move forward by
cha move backward by char
move forward by paragraph move backward
back paragraph
go to the beginning of buffer go to the
bottom of buffer so
i'm using volar keyboard so no control
key you'll notice
so that's the beauty of soft light keys
and i claimed
it's more efficient than vim okay by
measuring keystrokes
scientifically i claim
and actually we can do a vim golf
anytime you want you know just ask for
it i'll do it and let's see
uh how soft fly keys compare to veeam
okay because i i've done that before in
you know you know like last year but
that was when i wasn't you know i don't
know i'm not so
smooth in doing live streams but i can
do better now
so i'm using stuff like these and you
want to know mathematica like
uh do you have a question like do you
know do you have any experience with
mathematica
or do you have or do you already use
mathematica wolfram language
do you have specific area or questions
you want to know
because you know you want to ask your
question
that's you that you know you want to ask
me something you really want to know
instead of suggesting general topic
because that usually doesn't work well
because you know
um so because if i know what
uh what's your intention about you know
questions you know your background about
mathematica then i can address that
specifically but i've been wanting to
you know
look at my tabs so these are all my um
you know my my website things to do this
this is my notes the mathematica things
i
i need to do and this is about mobius
transformation which is a
fantastic beautiful topic in geometry
okay
complex analysis and i recommend this
book okay
visual complex analysis you go by it
now of course most of you guys my
audiences are not
mathematicians you guys are mostly
programmers so
in order to study this topic
complex analysis basically you need
the prerequisite you need you know basic
calculus you know at le that level you
don't exactly need calculus
you know that's the thing about math
prerequisite like often
when you have some topic you know they
are at least some prerequisite
but usually it's the case that you don't
really you don't it's not necessary to
know calculus to study complex and
actually you do well it's not necessary
to necessary to
know calculus when you study the subject
of complex numbers and
geometry involving complex numbers
such as such as inversion spectacular so
this is
this is an inversion okay geometric
inversion or
one over um one over
a complex number one over z
and this is uh one of the mobius
transformation this is
a plot of the square function and you
can also plot it on a
raymond sphere this is called raymond
sphere
fascinating fascinating topic in fact i
can give you a
i can give you a tutorial kind of
informal
tutorial i can explain so anyway these
are related this is
these are called geometric
transformation or
rather it's usually part of complex
analysis or vector
calculus you know depending on your
point of view and
specific interest uh so anyway so i was
saying
when you study complex analysis which is
a
recognized field in math you
you know there are a lot topic in it but
but
but part of it the calculus is not
necessary okay you can study a whole lot
of it without
uh getting into calculus but
but however when when uh in
in when they talk about math they
usually give you
they specify some prerequisite
not necessarily because you need to know
those topic
but rather because you need
to have the math maturity at those topic
levels
in order to understand you know the
kind of the talking style of the
subject matter so that's usually the
case anyway so
uh complex analysis fascinating topic
and isometries
you know one of the most uh interesting
topic in geometry
you you know it's all connected to group
theory to
symmetry theory and lots of things
so these are the things i want i need to
do
my chinese blog
then you have my wordy blog
logi bang you know lojban is a
artificial language
these days it's more often called
constructed language
that is you create a language out of
nothing
this is in opposition to
natural human languages such as english
french german germany german language
spanish and so on chinese japanese
korean you know these are natural
human languages now on the
so but over the past uh 300 years
also you started to have constructed
languages that is you just
like a programming language you created
you know you just design it
so the most famous being esperando
esperanto okay and there are quite a few
and usually
constructed languages they the history
of them usually is a utopian
vision like you envisioned you know the
word in
you know the language barrier is a
problem right so
you are english speakers you don't
understand chinese people
and chinese people don't understand you
and not just
language but also lots of cultural
involvements
and so people scientists you know in
1800 they started to
you know to design a language from from
the ground up
so it's usually it has properties of
being regular
being extremely simple to learn simple
and regular
uh you know and uh
many other artificial properties make it
kind of easier to learn you know
regularity is one of the most
uh it's it's
the irregularity is one of the most
problem in learning natural languages
like when you study english
or if you are english speaker when you
study chinese or study japanese or
german french or spanish
one of the difficulty is irregularity
because you have you just have 1 000
exceptions in grammar in spelling
everything
and and when you study a foreign
language for the first time you
started to think what the why are
you you know they just
it just have you know thousands of
irregularities
uh but with your own language you don't
notice it
you know if you you know i grew up with
chinese i don't notice all the
irregularities
if you grew up with english you don't
notice it until for example when i
started to learn english like 30 years
ago
you know then you notice everywhere you
know the the
plural for example in typically plural
chair chairs
you put a s at the end right chairs
cup cups pan pans
but then but then you have let's see
what what are some examples uh um
person okay you don't say persons you
say people
okay woman you don't say woman's
you say women and you know the the
there's also
pronunciation irregularity you know
one thousand one million examples of
irregularity
so in constructed languages one of the
things they get rid of
is irregularity everything is regular so
so the most famous example is esperanto
i mean the most popular
constructed constructed language is
esperanto about 200 years ago
invented 200 years ago then los
bang o and lark land lock
land which stands for logical language
the character does the outstanding
feature
of the lojban or laglan l g
l a n g logical language
the outstanding feature of this
constructed language is that it's based
on
logic okay so this is
a lot of you guys will be interested in
this language because it's based on
logic it
it tries to give you a language for
human communication
that is the most logical and uh again
and also not irregularity and also
uh for example logee
has a precise grammar spec you know
unlike
natural languages english french german
spanish you know they they all have a
grammar but the grammar is like
ad hoc you know that it's like uh after
the fact
you know once you have you know english
begin
it's not like someone designed the
english okay this should be the grammar
it's not like that it's just
happened like monkey monkey talk
[Laughter]
then you know after civilization and so
on and
academia then then people started to say
oh
this should be the grammar that this is
the english grammar that is the french
grammar you know
so they started to give you a grammar
the rules you know but
you know you know so some of you if
if you are a suffolk like if you
studied in college
you study english english then you know
you think you know oh my god this the
grammar should be this way that way
you are idiot okay because the english
grammar any grammar of natural languages
they are
imprecise they are like
actually impossible to specify
a grammar for a natural language
precisely because it's there's always i
mean even grammar there's exceptions
like
then then there are some uh some
some uh heart shot heart shot uh
writers and poets especially poets
you know like uh uh
you know in poetry or you know or or
shakespeare you know they create their
own words and
own grammar they break all the rules but
then the
grammarians say oh that is allowed
because when when they became an
expert a mastery of the language they
can create
their own stuff and the the word ee
cummings uh comes to mind okay ee
cummings is uh
e e cummings that's a famous
uh uh poet
you know he he's known for creating you
know he doesn't stick with the
um orthography the standard orthography
in other words you know he first of all
he used lowercase for his names like
ee comings like what the like he he
strikes
tries to stand out you know instead of
capital letters he used lowercase
and then he he he's you know from you
know
he break he doesn't use punctuations the
normal way
so each ones you know has have their own
say
and you guys you idiotic programmers
okay you guys
like okay you spelled programming wrong
it should be two m's
things like that you know the less you
know
the more like you feel like oh this is
correct you know usually that's
that's the case that's that's why they
say
sapphomora you know that what's the
etymology of suffolk
because you are semi-moron you know you
had two years of college
you become a semi because you
think you know
so uh so back to constructed languages
so
i was talking about um yeah
so so loshmang is a you know then
then there's the open source ugly war
let me talk let me tell you about that
story okay
so orange let's go to wikipedia so
it you know so you can
so you can like so instead of
instead of some people thinking oh it's
just talking
now here's a wikipedia okay
wait not language log idiotic
uh i want the
wikipedia article on lockland you know i
noticed
these days search engine started to
not show wikipedia at the top
so engineered language yeah what the
yeah
that's not you know that's not the
standard word
ah crap you know idiotic okay let's just
go to constructed languages
okay and so they in in this wikipedia
article they classify you know different
types of constructed languages for
example what's the
purpose when you created a constructive
language what's your purpose
you know so there are different uh quite
a few different purposes and
vision you know what's your vision
so you can read you know back in like uh
in the 1990s
there's no wikipedia so i went to the
library and read
a bunch of books um you know several
books on esperanto
esperanto for beginners and so on and
look uh large
and you know you read about them
so let's search for logic you'll find it
okay
phonological the language i'm trying to
look for is lag
land okay uh
you know so they you know these are kind
of new
uh explanation to me because so
apparently they divided to they divided
constructed languages to engineered
languages
and which is supposed to test some
hypotheses or
being logical things like that log lens
okay
then auxiliary languages which is
designed for international communication
then you have artistic languages
constructed languages which is yeah for
example
uh for example klingong
all the idiotic nerds are into it
klinger
i despise it klingong and
and and and also the elvish language
of the of the nerd hacker
elvish you know from that two towers you
know the
the what's the trilogy
uh uh load of the rings yeah you know
so most of you are like gets very
excited oh my god
klingong and lord of the rings elvish
and then you have then you have
articles
unicode okay so unicode let's magnify
magnify so you can see then you have
these you know nuts western white
men nerds are very obsessed you know
fascinated by runs i didn't know the
reason before but eventually i know
because runs is like actually kind of
the
the old english the origin you can you
you could
kind of say it's kind of the part part
of the origin of english
i mean or put it in other words it's uh
it's the father history of western
culture okay part of it
north especially northern europe
so run you know so you have keyboard
with run caps you know
keyboard io does that you know i so
despise this
my uh my
antithesis you know the hacker types we
are in the same group
but our opinions differ just about
everything
on computing and programming so anyway
western people white people they love
this
you know and so i studied a little bit
so you can for example i wrote an
app you can wait i need to show
on javascript so comments okay i'm going
to answer the comment then
put money in my pocket so you
can type english here
and this app will translate
it magnify magnify magnify
trn accelerated it to
run alpha bet okay so
so i studied a little bit you know just
curiosity
so apparently there are uh different
type of runs so there you have elder
runs you have
anglo-saxon runs you have tolkien runs
yeah tolkien you know lord of the rings
then you have younger lb younger st
and medieval runs then you can convert
runs to latin
so copy that select or paste it
uh what to latin okay so you can convert
it
so this constitute encryption
so next time you want to send a secret
message to your girlfriend your
girlfriend's girlfriend
this is applicable
uh so next uh
so so i was talking about constructed
languages okay
uh so okay you know and getting back i
was trying to look for the log land
where the is it
okay just search for l-o-g-l-a-n-g
yeah no link
okay uh let's search for a large bond
l o j b a n okay so we can
via this link we can find the loglan
so large bond i have a tutorial of that
you can see yeah
and by the way this this comics is very
funny okay this comic
you know try to read it because it has
meanings
uh okay anyway let me go back to talking
about the lojban okay so
so lojban is actually a derivative
of the original it's it was a language
called lockland
log lan it stands for logical
language created by this guy james
cook brown okay in 1995 1955
okay and this language the premise of
this language is that he created a
language
constructed language based on logic so
in this language everything is regular
of course but but also it's focused on
logic you know in this language the
semantics the meaning
you know usually in natural languages
each word has
so many so much meanings so he
you know he created a language that that
makes it very logical
then then you know here's the
here comes the ugly story of the open
source
mentality you know so then he got a lot
of
fans you know all the nerds started to
learn this language
then these people started to create
their own website you know
you know a fan club of sorts they're
talking about language and this guy says
no you cannot do that this is
copyrighted
because this guy james cook just like
every just like you
and me you know they you know you want
to benefit you you you want you thinking
for yourself you want money
so he says you cannot do that so they
went to court
and the court eventually said you know
you see
uh look lockland was eventually upheld
by the united
patent and trademarked office many
supported
a member of lockland institute find this
usage offensive
and reserve lag land for you know so
they had a fight
among the open source mentality by the
way this is this happened around 1970s
this so this is before the richard
stowman
came up i was uh
i was a fanatic of richard's roman for
most of
1990s and early 2000s
if you don't know like i know lots of
you guys will say oh
this guy has richardson i was a fanatic
of richard's roman
i talked i i told that story many times
in my video
but so anyway so so so they had a fight
so so they split you know just like
emacs versus xemx again that's another
history of emacs you know there's a
giant
what they call there's a word okay
anyway i haven't got anyway
so they split into two camps
so the chord says actually log
land has the right okay but anyway
so the but the phonetics the fan of
lockdown started they they thought okay
you know you don't like me i don't like
you so they split so
the lost band the the fan group created
a new language loch bion
they created new language with this
extremely ugly
logo why do i mention that because
back in early 2000s i have a big
you know i went to the forum you know i
i'm also interested in
lojban so i was talking to them but i
criticized the logo and none
and all these hacker you know they
they they think i'm they think i'm troll
they think this is great this is
fantastic logo this is the most
ugly logo okay you ask
any any people who have uh
study or visual arts they you know but
these
nerds just like just like programmers
just like the emx phonetics
the veeam for phonetics the linux
phonetics they all have none of it
you know when they criticize their
community even if you are right
they insist one plus one is three you
know
so i have a big fight with them these
idiots okay
so so and i have a written account of it
if you just search for sally lojban you
might find it somewhere on my website
this is uh around year 2000 okay
so anyway so lo lark land you know so
they split
splintered split um uh what's the word
for it you know
folk uh not folk but this one
season yeah yeah the with the word the
proper word
the prac the proper academic mumbo jumbo
is schism
you know they split just like in
politics
uh wait is that am i correct yeah it's a
division between people usually
belonging to an organization
movement or religious denomination yeah
exactly religion
that's the the the number one example
schism
like christianity like abraha you know
abrahamic religions islam christianity
then judaism then christianity have one
two three four five one thousand
divisions
uh then okay
that's uh why does that happen that's a
human nature you have to understand that
that's a
that's a human nature okay that's not
because
you know anyway so lose one look
so they split okay so so the fan club
they created their own language los bang
the grammar and you know the basically
it's just a copy of
of log land okay but however they
changed all the vocabularies
you know that's that's how things are
and uh
just like you know just just like linux
when you know this loch bomb become more
popular far more popular
than log land you know once this split
happens you know everyone's like
oh i want the free stuff i don't want
the
patented stuff you know so this legible
becomes much more
popular than the log length
uh so you know so i mostly i learned
login
i don't know much about laglan
you know that's a situation you know why
you know
if if i'm a creator of you know
you first of all it's not easy to come
up with the original idea that's why
sometimes you hear
ideas the most important thing creative
ideas so
he this guy james cook brown he's a
logician i think he's also a science
fiction writer so he studied logic and
linguistics and you know and so he's he
created
log land then of course when you created
something
you want to you know benefit from it
but then the the you know the the
open source the communism group happened
so they just basically robbed
it uh
i mean is there a is there is there uh
is there a correct answer which way
should it go not really okay
like you know there's really no
you know the proper ethical way like
whether you should
be patented or you know you should get
money or not you know depends on the
situation depends
there's no absolute answer to such this
kind
of question okay if if james cook brown
happens to be a millionaire then he
probably wouldn't care
but maybe he's not you know i don't know
much about him but you know
he wanted to be you know he benefit from
it so there's a fight
but then but what i really want to
criticize these
is the fanaticism the open source
communism
free software foundation they are all
pretty much the same
there's a fanaticism like like these
people you guys
they believe this is the only way
nothing can you know if you don't do
this my way you are that's why
that's why
linux is split to 100 this you know
distros and
you know never going anywhere
uh anyway so that's the story of
loshbang okay
and constructed languages in general
okay so let's go back to
these uh very funny comics you know
summit tasila tasita
i forgot what the tasita means
the attitudinals you know there's lots
of puns here
you know attitude you know at
altitude you know altitude is a hate
right but
it also means the attitude like like
your attitude what's your attitude
towards uh towards free software
foundation you know attitude
so here's the mountain summit tasita
and it's also known as the attitudinals
you know and here is the plan
celebrity you know plan
this is another pun you know playing is
just a flat ground
but is it also like plain green emacs
playing mouse you know i don't have a
fancy mouse actually i do have a fancy
mouse but
but then you have a play mouse and
things like that playing celebrity
selfie means i forgot
you know i haven't touched look uh
lojban for a while so anyway so i wrote
i did this tutorial like back in 2004
so you can see i you know back in 2004 i
did some recording of it and also
chinese
for the same word so yeah but i don't
think my tutorial is not very good
tutorial okay it's kind of a mess
okay so the time to read the comments
let's see am i doing have i been talking
like have i been muted
no okay good sometimes i do that
so let me read what's going on okay how
long have i been talking
i've been talking for 40 minutes okay
uh
so this russian guy i don't know how to
pronounce his name he says
he says he says that
you know he haven't studied calculus you
know you have to study calculus
he's starting to study calculus okay so
so if you are going into math you know
there are so many you know there's a
question
i got asked a few times in the past week
or
two that is how do you
like what what math to study that
depends on
quite a few things okay so
so let me tell you how okay
so where do you begin to study math what
subject okay
i would say so there can be
you know there can be two approaches
one is that you follow the traditional
path traditional path
okay so what that means is that you
study
you know basically you study
pre-calculus trigonometry
you know basics you know basic geometry
then you study calculus okay
then you study calculus calculus usually
calculus one two three four in usa
then you also study linear algebra then
you started to study differential
geometry i mean differential equations
okay those are basic i mean this
so this traditional path this is for
people who
wants to uh be your engineer okay
maybe you are a physicist maybe you are
engineer you are maybe you study
chemistry
maybe you know that's what you study
basically calculus okay calculus linear
algebra
differential equations first of all
calculus that's what you study
have to study for half a year then you
can start to study
the very basics of linear algebra and
also the very basics of
uh differential equations okay
and that's required you know because
these these subjects are
fundamental to to physics to chemistry
to
engineering to lots of things to
sciences
so that's a and and maybe you also might
take
uh statistics okay anyway so that's what
you study
and maybe you also you know on the side
you might take statistics or discrete
math anyway that's a traditional okay
calculus
calculus linear algebra differential
equations the
the introduction calculus is a that's a
traditional way now if you are a
programmer you might or if you are let's
say
just a hobbyist you know but you know
there's a lot
uh amateur mathematicians who are who
became the greatest mathematicians in
history
so you don't have to follow the
traditional way so what you do
if you don't like the calculus kind of
thing you can study
discrete mathematics okay which is about
which is very useful for
programmers for example summation
the big o notation you want to compute
the
algorithmic complexity so called
complexity of algorithm
you have to do a lot of sums you know
you you want to be able to find you know
sequence and series and sums okay
uh i have an article on that okay so
anyway
so you can study discrete you know in
general the broadcast
category is called discrete mathematics
okay so let's go to wikipedia then you
can see
if this is a broad category okay so what
does
it involves so um
okay it includes graph theory
game theory cryptography okay
of course which anyway in general the
traditionally
involves graph theory game theory uh
and uh probability okay
some basic number theory combinatorics
set theory logic yeah that's kind of all
uh oh yeah okay so yeah
so discrete math okay it involves
information
information theory which which is not
part of
okay let me let me be focused okay so in
general
traditionally involves some basic logic
basic set theory and combination
combinatorics is a big thing
and graph theory and
and some probability and number theory
and algebraic structures
uh some okay and not not of these
so anyway i mean wikipedia usually gives
you
lots of info but it's not you know for
example here
it lists these as topics
in discrete mathematics well because it
tries
you know it's very broad but i can tell
you
what it really involves okay in general
combinatorics graph theory uh
and game theory okay combinatorics graph
theory
game theory that's the heart that's the
heart of discrete
mathematics you know forget about the
other things you know that
discrete mathematics doesn't usually
involve geometry
or topology i mean that's that's that's
outside of it
you know of course you can you could
drag them in because
you know there's very advanced geometry
and topology that's discrete
this you know that's from a discrete
approach and then you have
you also have discrete uh derivatives
which is
which is actually calculus but you use
the discrete approach that you know it
gets very complex
so let me repeat discrete mathematics
is mostly about combinatorics and graph
theory
and you know number theory okay and uh
and the game theory okay that that's
kind of one way to put it
so if you don't want to follow the
traditional if you way
of studying math you know let's say you
are not a physicist
you don't plan to be you are not an
engineer you don't plan to be you don't
plan to be a chemistry
uh chemist or you know anything like
that
or you don't plan to be designing a car
or designing
you know all those things like require
calculus okay that's
that's the fundamental part of the
traditional math
but if you are just a hobbyist or if you
are just interested in programming
then you can start from discrete math
okay
and also you you might also study logic
and
set theory okay they are you know
like this these two have nothing to do
with this
logic okay let me explain
logic is like an entity by itself
it has very little to do with set theory
in general okay i'm just
giving you my common view okay
i mean technically they i mean i mean in
a technical sense all math
are very intertwined okay so but in
general logic is logic
c theory is set theory they are very
separate
combo node combinatorics is
combinatorics and graph theory scrap
graph theory
you know they don't have nothing to do
with not
you know not nothing to do with each
other
from a beginner's point of view okay
from from even
you know the main body the you know
their main theories and things have
nothing to do with each other
so yeah so if your hobbies study you
know and and
and some elements of number theory and
you know
okay so that's uh that's about how do
you
uh study or approach math you know i can
go on to explain what's the
combinatorics
uh for example the you know the most
basic wait uh where is it i want to
click
to combinatorics i want to go to the
real
article okay so here's the real article
on combinatorics
so what does this study for example uh
lottery okay
so given 48 numbers you know lottery
balls given 48 numbers if you're gonna
pick
6 out of 48 how many
possibilities are there okay that's a
very basic
classic example of combo note
combinatorics
now there's another name for the
uh for the math field of combinatorics
counting okay you can think in other
words it's combinatorics
is basically about counting you want to
be
able to count things you know it seems
silly but it can you know some of the
problems
is very hard
let me let me show you one uh one
problem of uh
famous combinatorics okay this this is
another problem
the famous problem okay uh
yes uh let me show you okay let me show
you a tool
to uh
yeah should i it depends on if you have
interest let's see the comments okay
so here's a hard question how do you
make your living
i make my living by the money
you gave me okay
uh yeah i don't want to answer those
questions because that's the dramatic
question so
you know lots of my videos they want to
ask that and usually
you know that's you you know
do you care do you care
okay uh futurism uh wikileaks
yeah okay there's a logi bang wiki yeah
certainly
razer hello do you think uh
conglom will ever see mass adoption
no absolutely that's my that's what i
realized that's what i found out when
you know my personal opinion you know
almost all conlangs constructed language
especially the older ones like 200 years
ago
they were created in you know back then
200 years ago
you know there's certain world view so
they are created by
people scientists usually or linguists
you know back then is
people are usually poly math poly math
meaning they
study lots of things they are not just
they are also they are scientists
they are physicists they are
mathematician they are also philosophers
back then 200 years ago and they they
also studied linguistics you know
polymath like me
but today it's almost impossible because
the the
you know the science science uh
knowledge growth exponentially you you
can you cannot know everything
you you could move very shallow you know
each one
you can be a you know physicist you have
nuclear physicist
you have you know a quantum physicist
you have material you know you have
cosmology cosmologists you know
you have many uh branches same thing
with chemistry and so on
and biology uh so so back then usually
these people who created constructed
languages
they have a vision you know they usually
it tends
some some sort of uh utopia you know
they have a vision
so why don't we break down the language
barrier so that
all the people can talk to each other
and remove
the culture barrier
you know so that we create a language
that is new
it's it's not tied to chinese for
example chinese language is very much
tied to chinese culture
you see in every almost in every word
japanese language has
you know a very strong tie to
japan's culture same thing with english
spanish and so on so when you learn a
new language it's not just a new
you know linguistic interest you know
you are actually studying lots of the
culture too
it's tight you know it's intertwined for
example if you study
arabic or persian you know
where iran people speak
you're actually digging into lots of
cultures
unavoidable you know so back then 2000
years ago they
you know these people constructed
languages they
have a vision they want utopia break the
language barrier break the cultural
barrier
their language often they say it's
neutral you know this
this is one of the qualities of many
constructed languages
they try to remove any cultural bi you
know so cultural bias in
in their language you know so they have
that vision
and what was i going to say
yeah so so and okay
and one of their goal is usually mass
adoption
because they are trying to create a
universal language
you know there's a latin phrase for it i
forgot but anyway they are trying to
create a language so everyone can speak
and it's also easy to learn right but
but if you look at history it never
happened
almost never it just never happened it's
like
same same fate for english
spelling reform you know if you look at
history there are quite a lot
english spelling reform so you know why
don't we
you know reform the english spelling so
it's all
systematic so it's much easier to learn
and so on you know
if it's a very interesting topic you
know you just look up wikipedia
english spelling reform you'll see uh
quite a lot of history and
and efforts and systems
okay so today we're gonna focus our
topic is gonna
uh be about constructed languages so
look
english spelling english language
spelling reform
you know history 16th and 17th centuries
19th centuries 20th centuries
arguments for reform arguments against
reform so anyway
just like constructed languages they
almost always
fail like nobody nobody ever use it you
know
at the time some famous people or even
u.s presidents
you know indoors or famous writers
endorsed this
but they always fail after 50 years or
100 years
like failed failed into obscurity
so let me show you another uh xsa page
okay so we have
unicode run then let me show you some of
the
constructed uh alphabets for english
let's see uh ethiopia okay ancient run
corn land okay so we have
desolate and chavian okay
so let's look at desolate alphabet so
desorate
alphabet is tied to the moment religion
the moment people they created their
basically their own
writing system for english okay
and this system is designed so that
it basically based on the idea of
of regular spelling but however they
don't want to use the english alphabet
speak
you know they wanted a new alphabet so
this so
in other words this system this deseret
alphabet
you can think of it is a phonetic system
for
english language you know
of course they failed you know they
failed after
50 years you know the moment religious
people they use it but you know after 50
years
is dead so that's one of them
then the chavian alphabet chavian
alphabet
is created by the famous author
playwright
george bernard saw uh you know
he also wanted uh you know
he want he wanted a regular
phonetic you know spelling system for
english so he created this alphabet
so this is a phonetic alphabet for
english
chevy and alphabet okay so this is in
1960 okay
yeah it originated from george bernard
so
but he actually didn't he didn't
actually create
it he he left a wheel
to have a competition so other people
created it anyway so
but it's tied to his name it's his idea
so anyway
chavian alphabet 1960
and desiree alphabet 1847.
so these are two systems
that actually created a english phonetic
alphabet
okay and these two are part of the
english reform
uh there are other english reforms that
does not create a new alphabet they just
use the standard
english alphabet but change the spelling
so you know there's
a long history of it very interesting
what you know
part of the reason this is very
interesting because you know we are
emacs users right
so we are emacs users and for example
uh um example let's close this window
and okay sync go back to emacs
so you can see let me open a new uh
so something so for example i have
i have you see when you use emacs or vim
you you are a programmer right you want
to you want to have
um shortcuts
for example
i haven't okay you have to type that but
i can just type
h h v n t okay no wait h
and t you see h
and t so this is a shorthand uh for
example
on the other hand uh wait uh
by the way okay btw enter
so i can type by the way just by
pressing three keys
and lots of you guys keyboard phonetics
right
you have lots of uh systems right
anyway so emacs has a brief so i have
article on that
let me show you my emacs a brief file
okay so you can see
you can see all the abbreviations i have
for example let's go up let's go up and
let's go to the
you know let's go up
you know so this uh saves saves typing
and and of course many of you are
interested in um
uh how long have i been talking i should
probably stop
but let me keep on okay many of you are
interested in
you go to some keyboards
uh you go to the stenotype okay
so stenotype is a shorthand system
this photo is from emily our our leader
and you know so it's
it allows you to type like 100 200 words
per minute
using a phonetic system so anyway the
reason i'm mentioning this is that
you know for lots of you guys you might
be interested in shorthand system that
speed up your typing
so so this is related to
this is very much related to the
english spelling reform because if you
can if you can type
is my if you can type if you type by
phonetics you save
a lots of keystrokes because
deep you know there's just two sounds
steep so instead of typing dep
for keystrokes you can just deep two
keystrokes
so phonetic system is one of the key to
save typing
so you so so that's why i
say you know the english spelling reform
and also the
uh phonetic alphabets are
one of the key to explore
uh typing shorthand a system just like
just like the stenotype machine
very interesting i haven't made a
systematic you know what
one day one of these days i want to
study
i want to make a systematic study of all
the past english spelling reforms and
there's also
not just spelling reform there's also
shorthand system you can
search for it okay that's another thing
so you search for english shorthand
then there's a wikipedia article on um
wiki there's a wikipedia
article on lists of shorthand systems
okay
uh okay so for example
this is a list of shorthand systems for
writing
english so you can you can write almost
at the speed of speaking
you know back then it's based on
handwriting but today
with computer keyboards you can also
create one
based on computer keyboards so this is
part of the reason you see
we are talking about fast typing okay
many of you programmers or nerds we
emacs veeam users are interested in that
and
what they go to mostly they go to the
stenotype
you know the the the i despise the
hackers again you know this is the
reason i despise the hackers
they have no idea what what is going on
except
except the uh what what's the
um let me show you okay i want let me
address these
interesting things like i mentioned
these lots of you know
what i'm talking about like if if you
are into keyboards
then you click on the do it yourself
keyboards
okay then we go down we go down
we click on the plank the worst
keyboard possible you know so there's
tons of people the nuts the hackers
they love this one and what they want to
do with it they want to use it
as a steno with clover you know clover
is a project
that makes a computer keyboard into a
stenotype machine
to emulate this machine okay so these
hacker idiots that's what they do you
have you you know you
see lots of thousands people fan clubs
you know doing this
what what is their goal their goal is to
allow you to type fast okay
but however if you ask you know if you
ask these people these phonetics
great oh great project clover fantastic
you know
no no disrespect by the way great people
you know uh
uh this plover project is
created basically by this by her okay
what's her name i have i have her name
somewhere here okay no disre respect
but however this hacker types idiots
they don't they don't study they don't
know nothing so they see this
this is great this is all you hear among
the qmk
again last few videos i did a video
about talking about the
phoneticism of qmk open source they
don't know nothing
else okay you ask them these phonetics
who spend a lot of money and time in and
you know exploring
uh clover and you know steno you ask
them about the shorthand the history
or alternative ways to improve typing
speed
they have no idea they don't know
so that's that is why i um suffer morons
suffer morons that's what they are
that's you know this is reason
i have problems with the hackers their
ideas
just almost everywhere i go i don't
agree with them
okay i think that's it maybe that's it
for today
so yeah so back to you know i i
digressed a lot
back to the the question about corn land
will it one day become popular so that
you know so that uh we all can learn
uh you know constructed language so i
learned
it turns out not you know historically
none of them ever succeed succeeded in
fact their
their group is very small you know the
most popular
constructed lands uh is esperanto
they have maybe a million you know maybe
a million
i don't know look look up wikipedia i
will say
but basically they go nowhere like you
don't hear it if you don't
you know if you are not nerd you would
you you you never heard of
esperando okay or anything other so
that's a situation they'll never go
anywhere why
because there's a good reason you know
there's good reason for that because um
how do i what
okay the reason is a bit complex and
social okay
one um one of the biggest reason
constructed languages will never go
anywhere
they you know they will never be popular
is because
people habit is the most
strong um how do you say characteristics
so
the habit is the most important thing
for
human animals habit okay you don't want
to learn
like a new spelling system for english
even though it's simpler but because you
already know why should
you and you don't want to learn another
language why should you
you know it because it takes tremendous
time to learn a new language
french chinese i mean if you you know
if it's free like the open source if
it's free
all of a sudden just snap a finger you
can know all about chinese why not
again i love i would love it snap a
finger snap a finger free software
foundation
then by tomorrow i know spanish i can
speak french
i can speak russian why not but that's
not the case
that's not the case you have to pay it's
not free okay
you have to pay you know you have to
take a year to learn
so even with constructed language is the
same thing you have to wait so
people don't want to same thing with
vorack you know
vorack keyboard
you know keyboard layouts right you know
about vorack
about you you know about quality right
and are you going to learn vorack it's
more uh
efficient are you going to learn comac
it's way more efficient
you know all these uh are you going to
learn for vast
vast majority of people they're not
going to bother
then let me mention another thing
related okay most people who don't
learn they don't even learn touch type
okay
you know they like this flat typical
normal keyboard
you know like the happy hacking like the
hacker idiots
they love this happy hacking why don't
they
you know why don't they study and learn
and
find find you know the ergonomic this
batman keyboard fascinating why don't
they why because
they don't touch type then you know
you have to take a month dedicated one
hour two hours a day
a month or two to learn touch type then
you can you might find these you know
ergonomic
keyboards fantastic but for vast
majority of people
including these hacker idiots
programmers
you know they think they are elite oh
i'm elite i'm gonna learn do it
yourself but then they're gonna go for
mechanical keys but they
they love happy hacking you know they
don't care for ergonomic
why habit habit is a very powerful
thing and it's it's nothing to criticize
about that's how we grow that's how
we grow you don't you know you don't
artificially try to learn something else
or new design or something just like you
know just like windows linux mac
you know once you get used to it you use
it another system maybe
you know you don't usually you don't
switch
so habit okay so this is uh part of the
part of the the biggest reason
constructed language will go
nowhere okay it's not going to go
anywhere
okay i think that's it for today
so any more questions graph theory
semantic stuff
i want to build semantic oak rome in
e-max
okay i'm ready to drop calculus
i'm ready to drop calculus i go sleep in
five minutes okay
uh if one can optimize a alphabet for
writing
speed could they also be optimized for
reading speed
i'm not i i'm not sure
i don't think so i think much less
okay so here's a question from carrick
he says if one can optimize a alphabet
for writing speed
then couldn't they also optimize
you know create a writing system to
optimize
reading speed my answer to that is not
really
because it's different from writing okay
because when you write let's say
okay there are two ways to write first
of all handwriting versus
uh typing okay let's when you write
let's say for handwriting you know so
you can create lots of shorthand systems
that speed up your writing but for
reading
it's a different story because you don't
you know when
human reads you don't actually
watch each character rather you
glance at the sentence you you recognize
the shape
of the whole world okay and actually not
just
what you know you guys you your eyes
grab a section
of words and you know you you recognize
them
that is why uh for most people you don't
recognize
minor misspelling errors okay so when
you read basically your eyes like gay
skate
skates you know there are studies of it
measuring your eyes
so reading is pretty fast so if you
create a new
you know maybe a phonetic alphabet or
something
you will shorten the number of letters
but it doesn't really
increase your reading speed okay and
in the same way he you know you talking
about chinese
in the same way for chinese so for
chinese for example
for example let's go to my chinese
article my chinese blog
okay so for example i have um i have a
bunch of chinese characters this is a
list of simplified versus traditional
let's go to some
chinese okay let's go to baidu
baidu so here
baidu is a chinese search engine uh most
popular
let's look at news okay let's magnify so
it's all chinese right
you know when i read chinese you you
don't
you don't look at the details of each
character how they you know you don't do
that
you you know for example i can read okay
let me read for you okay
let me i mean let me read it out if i
just visually read it it's faster even
so let me read it okay 128
you know i i don't read chinese every
day i hate barely
like every few months not even you know
once
once in a while so i you know
so i'm reading chinese you so so that's
a thing you don't
actually read each character's detail
once you learn a language you you glance
at the shape
of the whole words characters or sin or
a
bunch of cluster of words that's how you
read so
so for example in chinese you have
simplified characters that doesn't
increase reading speed uh let me show
you again so
in this page you are seeing the blue are
the simplified characters
okay let me magnify so you can see the
detail
for example this character means love
okay
so there are two forms on the left you
can see
it's much it's a bit simpler than the
right
one the right one is a traditional
uh character traditional used in taiwan
and hong kong
on the left it's the same character but
kind of simplified
so you for if you are writing it you can
see the left one is much you know you
save lots of pen strokes
but for reading it's same speed okay for
reading it's same speed
so again you can see some other
simplified characters so okay that's
that's about that
thank you guys for uh watching that's it
for today constructed language fantastic
topic
okay now donate or patreon
me okay thank you if if you like my
stuff donate patreon
uh buy my emacs tutorial buy my
javascript tutorial
okay i need to say this because this
that's how i make money okay part of it
okay so you can buy it
okay and
javascript tutorial
okay so you
go buy it now thank you guys
bye
shutting down in one minute one minute
because usually there's a
you know delay of 15 seconds or
something
of the chat so i'm gonna shutting down
uh in one minute thank you guys
so today i talked for
one hour and 15 minutes
this is coffee
good morning but you know i missed my
chances of going to germany
screwed up by kovite 19
and some personal uh issues
so i don't know if i might go to germany
for a week again
some yeah maybe i don't know so yeah so
i you know i
i could talk non-stop actually because
um you know i just interested in lots of
things shorthand today we talked about
shorthand
we talked about planck keyboard and
and prove a project in relation to
trying to emulate steno machine the
steno machine a phonetic system for
for writing uh you know
and then we have english spelling reform
then we also have english
shorthand system yeah so let's move that
they are related you know then we also
talked about okay
some math combinatorics yeah i forgot to
show you some interesting problems of
combinatorics so you get a flavor
you know okay another day
uh then we talked about schism yeah
e-max
versus x-e-max in 1990s
and religion islam christianity
and 1000 branches christianity
1 000 branches of linux distro
1 000 branches of linux
windows managers
[Laughter]
and schism you know that's human nature
and and also the loch land
and los bang constructed language
split we talked about then we talked
about
chevy and alphabet which is one of the
phonetic alphabet for english
part of spelling reform and also deseret
alphabet
which is one of the phonetic spelling
reform for
english phonetic alphabet created by
moments then we talked about
unicode run i mean the run the run
alphabet which is kind of the father of
western
uh writing system uh and
and and language i guess uh especially
northern europe or maybe dramatic
dramatic tribes or something i don't
know you know i i'm not a
linguist especially
i'm just you know i'm a hobbyist okay so
i know some people in our group allen
and frenzy they are certified
linguistic linguists you know they study
so so run germanic language includes
north germanic german germanic west
germanic
east germanic you know so north germanic
includes spanish norwegian swedish
icelandic pharaoh sea
west germanic includes english german
dutch
okay so anyway rune
alphabet and also the token the you know
the token the elvish language or
whatever
the lord of the rings which is
a big fanaticism of among the nerds
which i'm not interested i i don't like
the lord of the rings at all
you know as you know you know the guy
esr
you know the abbrev the
r rms i'm sure all of you are familiar
with the brief ims
you know the very the founder of
software foundation
now now
esi is another guy in the same van you
know
usually mentioned in parallel esr eric
raymond
you know he's a big fan of the lord of
the rings and he can tell you all about
it
about the run the history of the rent or
things like that you know the
token he has written articles about it
he he's very uh he's pretty educated you
know the esr guy
he has he's also i would say he's
somewhat
of a poly math too you know he he
has broad interest not just in
programming but in
linguistics especially lots of hacker
stuff
in electronics you know do it yourself
like i have an article let me
yeah let me ramble on a little bit
i have an article on him fixing
like talking about how to um
how to fix your mouse okay i mean
uh let's see trackball history
so he okay which one
uh this one i think
so this is the old logitech trackball
uh yeah so he has a
yeah you see he this is his article you
know he tells you
going into the details diving into
soldiering and taking things apart
you know heck you know fix something
about it i don't
i don't i'm not a electronic nerd
then he's talking about pins you know
okay that's esr but he's he's a penis
you know he's not very good in my
opinion his
opinions on politics
okay that i think that's it uh let's see
geometry i have abacus ecommerce okay we
talk about logic uh
constructed languages e-commerce which
is a po
poet
you know he even creates he break the
rules
then he then there's quite a few others
you know i don't remember the names of
him this is quite not
okay shakespeare e comings
he comes is particularly known for his
you know breaking the punctuations you
know the orthography
you know the by academic
mumbo jumbo it's called orthography
that is how you write things uh then
of course shakespeare then then there's
quite a few um
emily dixon i think so
and there's quite a few names you know
anyway
okay bye
hi justin you too late