welcome everyone to another c talk show
we are going to do wolam language coding
this is the third take of the Advent of
code 2023 day
14 uh and yesterday or the day before we
were doing part two and we didn't finish
so today we're going to continue that um
and one of the first thing we need to do
is to the function to detect
periodic okay we're going to C that uh
if you are watching this offline skip
around and play at 1.5 speed or more uh
because I ramble a lot uh which is often
the interesting part and if you are here
say hi
okay so uh let's begin okay so let's
start coding so um we did something fun
uh let's you know let's run the code and
uh show you what we did yesterday
because that's a fun part so here's a
code wolam language if you don't know
wolam language you go to uh just search
for Exel wolam language wolf Language
tutorial okay and uh you'll find my
tutorial this is designed for
programmers and you can find the
download button with a language has been
is free
since 2019 the you download the wam
engine and here's a full tutorial design
for programmers if you are JavaScript
coder python coder C or
C++ uh you like it okay so let's show so
here we are running the wolam language
code in um in wolam notepad so let's
remove this part because this is a
personal input
okay so here's a
codee uh here's the input and code code
code code code and okay and we did the
animation so
shift
enter
uh oh the animation where's the
animation
part okay maybe I mean oh that that's
the previous previous okay so we need to
go to this page uh this is from
yesterday we did the animation so let's
show that copy the code select or
paste okay here's a
code down down down down down down down
down
down down down we got the board history
and down down and we got this those
shows animation so shift enter run
it and okay we got a problem here uh we
need to cancel it out
period uh because the this code uh this
one billion times that's not that's not
um that's not working yesterday
so yeah okay so let's try this
um shift control D to split the cell and
we just want to run this the first part
okay shift
enter it'll take 5 seconds because our
code is not this this
manipulate is not done in the most
efficient way so it'll take 10
seconds but anyway today we're going to
write a function to detect periodicity
of a given function of a given discrete
function uh we I'm going to explain that
so we have this yesterday so this is fun
to watch you can watch uh you know you
can watch how the balls move on the
board so let's slow
down so they see they move northwest
southeast northwest southeast northwest
southeast
and the pattern changes so it's quite
interesting
problem
hello uh okay so so now we going to
write a program yesterday we made
progress almost solve the problem except
we need the function to find the
periodic okay so copy that let's see
yeah uh copy that and go to today's talk
show
and paste the code here showing browser
so oh not not that code uh oh yeah
that's a py okay let's work on that so
yesterday we got a function this
function someone else wrote it Richard
Phillips that takes a function and takes
a initial value and it will Nest the
function call the function get output
and call the function on that again
repeat uh and you want to detect the
periodicity of the function meaning that
for example the function for example if
you have a function uh let's say if you
have a function
God okay a function let's say if it
runs you know one it returns
three then if it's given three it it
returns let's say two then if the
function at two is
return one then it forms a cycle because
two gets one then one gets become three
three becomes two two becomes one so 3 2
1 3 2 one it forms a cycle you know one
of the most popular math problem a
interesting problem and extremely
difficult unsolved problem is uh
so-called health Stone numbers so uh or
collapse conjecture so let's say hell
Stone
numbers so let's show
that uh hstone number from WFAN research
you know math word is very bad resource
you don't want you don't want to check
any mathematics from the wolf math world
that's a very bad and
misleading resource okay uh so here's a
Cass
conjecture so basically the problem is
that you know you define a function such
that the function is defined
by FN if n ided by two is zero it's a
even number then you just
um uh what is
that yeah okay so here's a better
description if the number is even divide
by two okay so
F4 you know four is even so four divided
by two you get two so F at four is two
now if the number is odd then you triple
it and add one so let's say the number
is five F at five so triple five is 15
15 + 1 is 16 so F5 is equals to 16 okay
so this is a function this is the
definition of the function and uh you so
if you keep running the function you'll
notice there's a periodic for
example if you begin with
um you know if you f at
f27 uh actually this is one of the
longest periodic sequence basically this
the function almost always returns to
zero so it will always become 16 then F
at 16 is 8 F at 8 is four F at four is
two then F at two is one so it always
come down to one so here's a plot of the
function so the question is does this
function always come down to one that is
the question and that is unsolved okay
very very simple problem but is unsolved
anyway we talking about this problem
because there's a we can see there's a
period okay I mean so
uh you know 16 a241 so uh you know
the so basically depending on what uh
number is input you you become a
repetition of several Cycles a period so
there's a periodic so for example if um
the starting value having the largest
total stopping time while being less
than 10 is not
okay so so if F at n you got 19 steps
and it becomes
what uh anyway there's a period okay so
you can you know you can look at this
problem very interesting problem I
learned this problem dur uh where I was
in college in
1992 taking a recreational Math course
so actually yeah so you know very
interesting problem call lad's
conjecture very famous you'll see lots
of YouTube uh talking about it too
however it's not soled you know it's
very simple but it's not solved and some
mathematicians say this is you know so
difficult that today's mathematics we
are not we don't have the tools to even
approach the problem okay so and I
believe according to Stephan wolam you
know he has talked about this problem in
his blogs you know he's each article is
very long so he seems to suggest if I
recall correctly this is one of the
computational
irreducibility
so you know so basically his take is
that many of this computational problem
you know this is a math problem but you
can consider consider is it as a
computation as you know an
algorithm so what happens if you plug in
uh any number to and will it always come
down to one that that is a question so
it's you know you can always know the
answer by try different end you know you
can try FN where n is one one million or
a billion or billion plus one or gig
Petra you know whatever big number you
can always just compute it so any given
number you can find out the answer will
it always become one but the problem is
you you
know you know our computers is limited
speed
so uh there's always bigger number that
you cannot just compute you know just
you cannot brute force it but so Stephan
wolam is saying if I believe um I
believe that he's saying this is one of
the might be computational
irreducibility problem so there is no
actual
Theory you know so we don't know we like
he you know that like um you know you
know we don't know we cannot solve this
problem we do not know or or in other
words it's impossible or almost
impossible to
know for any number this uh will always
come down to one because computational
irreducibility the only way to find out
is just you just compute just just you
know this is so this is very interesting
issue
because hello based puffy
very interesting because for example
when you look at the super computers
okay
so you know it's interesting superc
computers let let me tell you about
supercomputers so every year or every
few years they have a list of the
fastest supercomputers you know and I
looked at you know like I this is very
interesting uh thing for me because I'm
a computer nerds right I want to see how
fast are they who who is Crea the
fastest super computer so every few
years I look at at this and uh about two
years ago I looked at it it's amazing
that China has the fastest computer but
they they they kept quiet about it
because they don't want to be too loud
because when they say when when they you
know join the
competition the USA Americans gets
annoyed because they then they're going
to you know like the USA deep state
so China like quietly do not publish
their their speed you know which is
actually the fastest F faster than uh
the this the current one the uh IBM blue
jeans is that
right uh I think so well let's look at
let's look at the fist right now so then
I can tell yeah faster than Frontier
okay I remember so there's China One
there's a China One
faster than this
uh yeah American frontier you know this
is you know you will not of course you
will not easily find the information no
mainstream media will report it they
will just say you know the look at the
American now is back in the fastest
again but
actually you but you can find the info
but you can find you know you know
you know that that China they they they
they stopped publishing the their
speeds uh so you know like this is
amazing you know China because like five
years ago starting about 10 years ago
all the top 10 are from
China uh very you know so you know we in
USA we have we have a problem now uh you
know due to Pol politics and Corruption
huge amount of it you know the social
justice gun and so on so anyway it's
back to um yeah hellstone numbers so why
are we mention mentioning supercomputers
uh because they uh oh yeah oh yeah so
one of the interesting thing about
supercomputers so I look at them you
know I was wondering you know what do
they use them for you know it turns out
the number one use of all these superc
computers is just Computing weather
what's the weather going to be tomorrow
well not tomorrow but next month and and
you look into you know you think about
why uh it you know so it turns out the
weather is actually the the most
critically important for Human animals
today as well as like 4,000 years ago
because 4,000 years ago when you don't
know it's going to R this season or not
you cannot cop you know your crop will
die crop dies no food no food you die
okay so weather be is like the number
one most important thing weather okay
4,000 years ago today two average
persons you know like like us we don't
care all we care is is tomorrow gonna
rain because I going to go shopping or
whatever you know I GNA go travel and
you know
but however
apparently the weather is still one one
of the utmost important thing because
all the you look at you know what all
these supercomputers are doing like half
of them or more than half of them is
like trying to compute the
weather uh but for what for exactly what
for I'm I'm not too sure for uh for you
know for example sending you know Elm
sending out Rockets you need to know the
WEA uh satellites you know there there's
hundreds or thousands of satellite you
know well I don't so any anyway I don't
know exactly why is the uh weather so
important today so but apparently it is
because all these superc computers are
are using are trying to compute the
weather you know so why are we talking
about that because that's related to the
kind of the computational irreducibility
because because weather you know
technically it's you know we we kind of
know the how it works but we cannot
predict it it predict it even though the
rules are very simple it's just running
a program but you just you don't have
theories for it you cannot say in a
million years the weather will be this
or that like you cannot say it you you
can we you can we can barely say say
what's weather next month you know the
the further way the the the the less
accurate it is our prediction so and how
do we predict mostly just by compute
Computing it you know running weather
simulations okay so we want to uh let's
just write okay so let's uh write a
function to compute um uh periodic
okay uh not power shell F language am I
doing
good laundry will not dry that's true
yeah you know in Germany you know in USA
they don't they don't we don't dry our W
uh clothing under the sun anymore not
not not not in all the cities we just
use the dryers washing machine so I
don't know if that's the case in
Germany in USA all the major cities you
you cannot dry your clothes because
there's no I
mean uh there's you you know there's no
no
room in an apartment or but even if you
have room usually they forbid you from
hanging your clothes in in the in the in
the uh in the balcony because it makes
the building look
ugly uh yeah it's a that's an
interesting phenomenon
um and but if you have a house like in a
in a in a in a country towns in USA uh I
don't think you they drive their cloth
because you don't you almost never see
it like you can watch American movies
you never see it it's always just
machine you know the drying machine
because Americans we like
machines but it's it's it's it's
interesting because if you look at um
you know in Hong Kong in China in in
other countries Spain they hand their
you know or Hispanic countries South
America they hand your clothes you know
Under the Sun to dry which is actually
better so anyway let's write a uh let's
see Hello uh German write a function to
detect
py of a given function okay that's what
we want to do uh so but yesterday we
found this uh we found this solution
from this Richard Phillips from you know
a w resource
function uh so you see his solution I
don't think I like it I haven't tried to
test it but you know I don't like it
because you can see he's
using plus plus tried steps Plus+ that's
like C++ that's a c thing incremental so
this is not a functional programming
code okay I haven't looked into details
but I can I can tell right away he's
using block you know so what is a block
block means it's like a listl it's
declaring local variables but however
using Dynamic scope okay so this is a
dynamic scope of local variable tried
steps so that means you know he's going
to mutate this variable over over you
can see there there you know so this is
not a you know not a very pure
functional programming style so you know
I'm going to write my own because I
enjoy writing W language code sub code
anyway so I'm going to uh try to do a
functional style okay so so what is a py
of a function for example period per
periodic of a given discrete function
this is important because
uh let's show this again so why is this
uh
what oh yeah so we want to show that so
we were showing that that's fantastic
now let's let's uh let's plus sign
okay so the
most uh obvious thing about periodic is
of course the sign
function s x
so x from 0 to 10 okay let's say 20
shift enter so you see it repeats you
know every 2 pi uh yeah every 2 pi it
repeats that's the most common example
uh let's try something fancy okay let's
say PL 3D so in two dimension in a
surface in two a function of returning a
vector that can also be periodic that
can actually be doubly periodic okay so
let's for
example if we do this uh okay so
yeah
so shift that key y from negative 10 to
10 okay let's say9 to 9 and uh X from 9
to 99 let's see what happens uh I don't
want that
um let's just say that okay so shift
enter so there is a periodic function of
sign in two Dimension but this periodic
this one period but you can have what's
soal double periodic okay so let's try
that again so let's
say uh sin x times
cosine
x shift enter uh not that wait cosine y
okay
got cosine y shift enter so there we
have it that's uh this is soal doubly
periodic because there's it's periodic
in two directions okay so I mean this is
a basic example this this is a very
intuitive way to understand what's
periods you know the function just
repeats uh but but this is a continuous
function you know because you know it's
continuous but what but for example if
we have the hellstone number that's a
that's not okay the the the most simple
intuitive example of periodic function
is mod okay so
let's my
period uh x
p okay xpf okay
got undecisive about the programming
language names so we Define a function
and that function takes a value X okay
then we say what it we we are defining a
um simple
example of a
disr
periodic function okay so mod
okay most obvious example let's say Mod
Five Okay so so let's remove
that okay remove
that so if you define this function uh
let's do a clear
okay because when you use pattern Ming
usually you want to clear it
before okay so we Define a
function uh
wait
undo shift
enter paste here am I doing good video
check audio check okay so shift enter so
we have a function now let's do a
table table of this function periodic
function add value X then X goes from
let's say 0 to 20 okay shift enter so
you can see it's 0 1 2 3 4 0 1 2 3 4 it
repeats
now let's include the input value
okay X and uh then
FX ah so where is
the where is the key for enter okay so
there shift enter so you can see the
pairs of
values uh you
know 1 2 3 4 5 so this this is a
discrete periodic
function now let's try uh okay so I'm
going to write the function so what we
want to write is a function that takes a
function and determine the periodic okay
so that's what we going to
write uh so let's move this up simple
example of a periodic function there and
uh okay and let's copy that let's just
copy that so we can
see that's a sample value and now we
going to write a function to detect
periodicity of a given discret function
okay so we want
to check period
okay uh let's say x get period okay so
that's our
function
uh okay clear then okay how do you we uh
how do we do
it Lima hello Lima says this is very
normal here arent Argentina we hand the
cloth to dry in the sun fantastic using
a driver for everything seems pretty
energy demanding yeah that's American
that's American life we uh we need big
trucks uh uh gas
guzlas and SUVs you
know
uh okay so get PE you know let me
mention another thing po politics for
the Maga people make American great
greater again you know they say China is
the most polluted you know using the
most gas but actually if you go by per
person because China has
like five times more people you know in
USA America you know USA you have
300,000 I mean 300 million the
population about 300 million okay China
they have like uh 1.4 billion so one two
three four so it's like four or five
times more people than
USA so considered as a whole yes China
uses more energy than USA but if you
consider each person you know you got
more people you got more people need to
more more food right if you consider
each person then each person USA is
using like two or three times more
energy than than the people in
China but the but we get fake news every
day from from part part of these Trump
supporters you know these SMA people
like every time I say something about
China these people will say you you are
you are a Chinese 5 cents you
know this this fake news you know this
uh you know this very hard to
fight like every time I have a
opinion you know that like like like I I
don't like to see the fake news about
China I'm from I'm not even from China
I'm from Taiwan okay but I I'm Chinese
so I know about Chinese things culture
history you know the why are the white
people American they they know nothing
not a thing they don't know nothing
about Chinese and of course don't they
don't speak Chinese they don't know who
are the president before who are the
kings or whatever they no have no idea
but then they say you know they they
they they say oh China this this or that
so sometimes I say that's false then
they'll just say oh you are you are uh
CCP how much uh how
much how much the um
she pays you
idiots okay so so so yeah let's write
this function uh get period so how do we
do it so you want basically you want to
so let's uh algorithm
description compute the function at the
beginning value okay so the function
needs to take
um a beginning init uh what inite value
okay the function needs to take init
value and
uh oh wait a
minute okay so there there's a
misconception I made um you see before
we were talking about periodic of a
function these are examples of discrete
function but what we actually want is
the periodic of nesting a function so
it's not just running a function you
know through the values but rather you
want to run a function get an output
then take that output put back to the
function and get another output so you
want a you want the
[Music]
priy of nesting this function if if that
exists okay so so write the functions to
D detect the period aresty of a of
nesting a given District uh a given
discrete
um function okay that's what you want to
do
so so uh as for so so does this does the
sign function sign function is periodic
right but does it if you Nest the sign
function does it also is it also
periodic I think
so uh yes for certain values it'll
become periodic okay this is getting
more uh ma into mathematics for sun
value of sign you know sign something
then you take the output then you put it
back to sign that you you
will is that true uh actually I think so
for some values but that's getting into
analysis you know into
calculus anyway so but we here we just
are concerned about discrete function so
again yeah so this mod example is
also okay so this mod example is a is
periodic but is it periodic if you feed
you know if you Nest it it is
also Okay so okay so now let's get back
to the algorithm so computer
function starting at init
value Nest
it for n times okay
so for
each time you compute the
function save the value
and compare if current
value is oh
is in
history save value as a history list
so every time you comput it you save the
value so you got to
list a previous you know values and but
but also every time you compute you want
to
check H this is not so trivial to write
actually every time you get a new value
you want to check the history
list oh this is not true trivial to
write detect the cycle so you want to
check the previous
list if it doesn't match then that's
good then you you Nest it again but if
however if it matches some of the value
in the history
list if the Cur uput match a value in
history
then
uh then you need to make that a state
then when you
compute the next
value you need to check
if it match the next value in
history oh God this is this is not
trivial to
write um so you have to check and check
again until you see a match until you
see until actually you you
until do do this check again
until an output is the init value
again is the init value is the initial
matched
value in history list okay okay so you
got to actually you have to keep a state
oh God how we going to do this in
functional Style
okay this getting complex we've been
talking for almost 40 minutes already oh
God no now I want to back out you know
let's just use this his code no I don't
want to look at his code okay so we need
to write
this so we know we can always solve a
problem just
by
systematically and uh do things one step
at a time that's one of the way to solve
a problem maybe a slow way but it's a
sure way so you break down the problem
you analyze the problem and just do you
know solve one thing at a time one step
at a time so you want to so every time
you compute this you want to
so get period uh get period you need a
function okay actually you need a
function so given a function and initial
value and
then then then you need some of the
max check okay that is the
maximum amount of nesting you're going
to check
okay so this is not trivial at
all I mean it's it's not very difficult
but it's not uh something you can write
you can efficiently you can write a
solution efficiently
fast uh so you get period so that's the
you know that's what the function takes
a function initial value and Maxim
maxess
uh Max
Nest which is uh okay
so so every time you compute a function
so you want to
compute okay now I want to write the
documentation for this function okay let
me show you how to do that in wam
language okay so this is how you define
a inline documentation for the function
okay so you just assign that so assign
that to a string
okay so we
say that okay so let's see let me
explain how this works in a
bit so that
function return the period
of f of a
discrete
function f
return
the
of of return the period of nesting a
discret function
f okay and it is the
initial
value and the max list is the
maximon
nesting okay something like that so this
is the this is the inline documentation
for this function uh now what does the
function do let's just say return three
temporarily you know for I can so I can
let me show you so you post this in wam
notebook then you just shift enter run
it then you can type question mark
question mark x get period Then enter
shift enter so that will give you the
inline documentation
okay so but now we need to of course
actually Define this
so um so what so so okay so what do you
need to do so you need
to so we got to go back to the algorithm
so every time you compute a function you
save okay so this is going to be a
bit I mean it's not a trivial code okay
so almost always you write a
module now what does module mean module
means just like the Lis let okay so it
declares a bunch of local variables then
body here
okay uh This Here Local variables x y
and so
on
um okay what's what going on
what okay
so so what do you want to do so so you
want to compute
F okay so you got to do while a while
loop okay next
while let's look at the documentation
for nest while you'll just nest theun
function until a condition a function uh
while condition is
reached so here's a
documentation for next while okay F
expression and
test
uh yeah so this is what uh oh so this is
quite convenient because you see the N
while they actually provide an argument
that is a previous
history very
convenient
so so the simple form is nqu f
expression test okay let's magnify
more okay the most simple form give a
function that will Nest give a initial
value and test test is when to stop okay
start with expression then repeated
apply F until until applying test to the
result no longer yields true
okay so if the test is true it will
continue nesting okay let's let's put
that
down Nest s call the function and the
init
value then a test here is uh the the
important part the
test so so first of all we can test
if if a
value has already happened
before okay first of all we can test if
a value already happened before comments
guys 10 people watching
comments uh just say hi okay I won't
digress onto uh you know things but just
say hi so you want to test so we can
start by we just want to test if a value
has happened
before okay in that case you need let's
see this one Supply the most recent M
results as argument for test okay that's
makes sense then the next one all supply
all results so far as the argument for
test at each
step that's what I that's what we want
functional programming Supreme you know
this is a kind of typical way of
functional programming of doing a loop
where the function will take the output
and feed it back to the function itself
so it's like this is a a form of
recursion
okay so next next while test and okay so
you need a function that's test and you
say all all
means you know all previous values will
pass to the test okay now we need to uh
Define this
test okay what this test is going to be
we can Define It Let's
do let's put the local variable here
okay so we're going to Define f
test uh let's use functional yeah
instead of pattern let's use a
function equals to a function
okay now this x is a list because we
said all so what but what does it do
that's here
so so the test will given a
list of all previous values what
um supplies all result to so far as
argument from okay
so if it returns true continue if it
returns false stop
okay so you of course then you need a
if let's just say for
now if
length of this list is greater than five
then
false okay otherwise
true okay so this function will run
basically just five
times I mean this is just for testing
purposes you know just just to be just
so that our function will run you know
then we have to change this okay so next
while init
yeah run this and use this test function
okay then and all previous values okay
so when this stops what does it return
it
um oh oh God so you
need okay this is not functional not
pure functional programming uh let's say
last
bar okay last value so
so this actually will return the last
value
um yeah okay let's let's just let let
let that be
okay okay so copy that
okay run it then X get period okay then
then we need to define a
function we need to Define our mod
function okay
so yeah so okay because we need a
function to test so if you have a mod
function will and you Nest it will it
repeat uh yes of course but how does it
repeat exactly so this is slightly
involved as I make sense
hello um so here is the
mod so two becomes two three becomes
three 11 becomes 1 12 becomes 2 13
becomes three
so let's say if you start with 13 you
get three then three becomes
three then is
stuck so you see when you do this
nesting a function when you Nest a
function when you Nest a discrete
function the period may change depending
on what is your input okay so actually
that collapse conjecture is a good
example the period will
change is that right or or something
um you know here's a collap collapse
conjecture hell storm numbers
okay so 13 returns three if you use the
mod 13 returns three then three becomes
three then three becomes
three so for the problem of
13 wait how do you what is the
definition of a period for our
case
uh one becomes one two becomes two three
becomes three four becomes four so if
you start with any of these
number the period is is
just one because four becomes four then
four again becomes four so that repeats
then the period is one now if you start
with 13 then you become three then three
becomes three so the period is also
one or you know maybe you say
two uh but if you start with 20 20
becomes zero so they all become so the
period all becomes just
one is that right oh
God so now we actually getting into a
issue so this this if we use the mod
function as a
example you only get period of two I
mean or
one
so so we need to
actually be more precise we need to get
a clear definition what does it
mean to Nest a function and say the
function has a
period okay it should be simple you just
Nest the function and the function come
out a sequence of numbers that forms a
cycle okay cycle means a sequence of
numbers they just cycle they repeat so
if you three comes out three comes out
three that's also a cycle so
but so how do you define the picy so for
for the number three of this function of
this Mod Five is a period one or two
so let's see you n the function you got
a sequence of numbers and if you find
the cycle of those sequence then you got
a period then then that means this
function when
nesting when when nested you got a
period because the output repeats now
how do you de determine the periodic you
take the bunch of numbers that repeat
yes minus the you know repeating initial
so in a case of three for this function
you know you just get 3 3 3 3 three so
what is a period Well you take the
period which is just a three without
repeating a three so the period would be
one so for this
function if you start with three and you
Nest it the period is three I mean is
one similarly if you start with 0o 1 2 3
4 five the period is all just
one let's see if you the input is five
you get
zero okay then zero becomes zero and
zero becomes zero so you
got you know what your five z z zero so
zero is a repetition
and you you take the length without you
know the initial value so the period the
length is
one okay so any of this input from 0o to
five the period is
one okay what about six so for six you
get one then you get one one okay so the
period is also one so in fact for any of
these so in fact for this mod
x mod by
five the period is always just one reg
when you Nest when you Nest the function
okay regardless what what is the initial
value
okay so so now we have a better idea we
have more clear precise definition of a
period of nesting a function and we know
now that this model
function when you Nest it the period is
always just one so that means this
function is not a good example for to
test our function because our function
you need some kind of um more than one
period okay
so so we still need to think about this
so now what about let's look at the um
the
collat
problem uh you know so actually let's
Hil storm let's define it
okay okay let's define the hellstone
number uh make sure we spelled it
correctly cu lad's
conjecture is also know Hailstone okay
so named after the mathematician Loa
CAD okay introduced idea in
1937 uh and uh sometimes refer to as the
Hailstone sequence
okay Hailstone
sequence let's let's say hell Stone okay
because that's more intuitive okay so
hellstone function okay so we Define
let's define this
function hstone okay
so then okay we Define the
function
n okay so
x uh so
let's see if I have
some okay so X if if
even if it is even X
then x / 2 okay otherwise it's
odd x * 3 then +
one okay so that's we Define this
function uh and we can check
let's run it let's say x is at 27 okay
uh then you have to Loop it back so you
yeah so what you do is you Nest list
okay nextest this will Nest the function
and return all the sequence of the
output
so so next list takes a function then
takes a initial value value okay so then
we can run this okay so let's let's put
semicolon so it suppress the output okay
so let's try it run
it uh next list okay what uh looks like
we are missing a value here let's
try oh n times you you need to say how
many times
uh according to you know when it's
27 it goes
to 11 and uh 111
steps so let's say
okay shift enter there we have it so you
can see it goes to you know return these
values then
421 421 421 421 so there it enters so
there's a
period so what is the period 421 421 421
421 so the period is three
okay now if okay so I okay so we I think
I we are getting clear what's going on
about the nesting period okay so if you
start by let's say
12 I mean wait okay 120 let's say start
by
12 shift enter yeah so almost right away
you got 421 so the period is still 4 421
so okay so I I know now we know this
this function the period period is
always 4 to1 okay just three the period
is three
uh just three okay
so so what does it mean when you say of
nesting a function the period of nesting
function does it depends on the initial
value so for this problem it does not
depends on the initial value we pre
presume you know we presume this
unsolved problem we always always come
down to
one you know that has been proven for
billions of billions of you know like
initial value like like they have tried
to use superc computers to compute it
so you know up to like uh up to what up
to they have we
have you know so far we have computed
for
visualization then supporting arguments
experimental evidence so we have
computed starting value of of two
followed by 20
zeros okay like 20 Z
digit they all come down to one okay
so so we just assume all number will
come down to one then the period of this
h custom function is just three 4 2 1
okay and it does not depends on the
initial value now what about what about
is I mean what about the idea that some
function some discrete function such
that such that the period depends on the
initial value is that possible
yeah it it is it's very possible you can
easily have a
function
where depending on your initial input
you go to different
Cycles yes so uh
yeah so we can now make more better
definition okay so let's elaborate on
the on the uh
let's
the period of a
function is different from
the period of nesting the function
okay for example
has period mod model number five has a
period
of uh of of five okay because it's
always
0124 0124 so if you mod a number by five
you have a period
of of of of of of
0 1 2 3
4 0 1 2 3 4 zero you have a period of
five
okay
but but if you Nest
xpf then the period is
one okay so that's that's another it's a
distinction between period of a function
versus the period of nesting the
function okay that's
important thing we realized then you
know I'm doing this systematically this
is my style of solving
problems uh usually I just I don't just
code you know Advent of code let's just
get the answer so now we getting
into you know starting yesterday we
started to
notice we need to find the periodicity
of a function of nesting a function so
that's what we are doing today and we
want to fully understand the idea
of periodic function and
nesting of the the periodicity of
nesting a function which is different
very different okay and we have concrete
examples
here and and and also so we noticed the
periodic how so what is periodic that is
just a repeating
output so what is the
periodic what
is
periodic defined okay what is period
defined it means the sequence of output
repeats okay that is a
periodic and next we also
know we also know is it possible for a
discrete
function to have
a
nesting
period
depending uh to have a different ning
period for
different input different init
value
yes okay uh but what about a
example uh well so what is a example
when you have a function discrete
function you know let's say integer
function where the input and output are
always integers and when you Nest it it
depends on which
so what is a example for these
guys guys to okay you got any idea this
should be
a should be fairly common okay is what
what is there a math
function that have a nesting period but
it depends on the initial value I think
there's a lot you know especially when
you do
chaos you know dynamical systems you
have different you know different
initial value will end up in different
cycle so the cycle is usually called
orbit you know that's another you know
interesting
thing dynamical systems
okay not sure what's a simple
example but lots in
dyn dynamical systems so this you can
look up and that would be very
interesting dynamical
systems uh what okay
search dynamical
systems so that's a branch of
mathematics basically this Branch you
know this is one of the most uh famous
example that is a loop okay that that's
a cycle that forms a cycle given certain
you know given a function and given a
initial
value then if the initial value is such
and such you'll you'll become you'll go
into this cycle you know this this very
famous Len
attractor uh so that's you know
dynamical systems which actually I don't
know much about uh but lots you know
anyway so that's a like a branch of Meth
fics and which this leads to this is
connected to Chaos Theory because in
Chaos Theory you want to
know at which point you know like the
initial condition is very important for
some initial condition they become you
know this thing they go into a loop but
for other initial condition they go into
different you know Loop which you can
visualize there are you know there are
few
but however for some initial value is is
even if it's a little bit different from
the initial value of this one it becomes
something
else uh and it may never
repeat so that's that's what you know
chaos theory is about you know just a
tiny bit different then it doesn't go
into you know like the so the initial
value is critically important this it's
like the weather you know like the
computational irreducibility we talked
before you know like WEA today if I if I
didn't talk do a talk show then next
year there may not be a stor but if I do
a talk show today if I breast breath a
little bit harder today pu the
air then after 10 years there's there's
going to be a major storm you know they
call that butterfly effect
uh
let's Okay so let's you know let's just
check so there it is Butterfly Effect
okay that's a
movie uh stupid this guy this guy this
guy Ash Ash Ashton
cure he's a he's very obsessive about
pedal about child trafficking okay but I
think he's he's he's um he's in trouble
you know because of the digly he's
into this kind of thing uh
usually these people talking about that
they have a Obsession about that they
have a
problem anyway so that's a movie so this
butterfly effect so that is you know
that's about the butterfly effect very
interesting you can go read about it
dynamical systems so anyway
so we are trying to find a function
where
we are trying to find a discrete
function where it will repeat given
certain initial value but for different
initial value you have a different
cycle uh but what is the example of such
a function I don't know I don't know of
of hand so that would be interesting we
need this function
because uh because we are trying to you
know because we are writing a function
to to deter the the
periodic okay so this is actually quite
untrivial
now in our case we want the discrete
function meaning a integer you know
function takes the integer and return
integer but in many of these chaos
systems dynamical systems they they do
have a function but they are not
discrete like they are you know
involving s cosign stuff
uh geometric definition real dynamical
systems of real uh you know continuous
time
flow okay those are real numbers and
then differential
equations uh discrete dynamical system
okay there we there we have a discrete
dynamic
system uh when T is taken to be integers
it is a Cascade or a map okay so
actually we might find the
example uh but they don't have a
article okay then you have cellular
autometer which is also you can consider
dynamical system
okay okay
so so I bet you know we can find you
know there's a lot
nondiscrete continuous examples but we
want the discrete example like of only
integers
uh so I don't know what is that okay we
are
digressing so
but so hellstone number hellstone
function it
is this is a example this is a example
um this is a
example where the
nesting
periodic does not
depends on init value it's
always
four okay that's the health no numbers
uh it's already always three 421 421
okay
okay so yeah we are just
digressing okay so now
we now we have a better understanding
let's get back to write this function
so
you call next
while call the function with the initial
condition then you test it by calling F
test and you feed the F test all
previous
values okay so when how to when when do
you want to stop you want to stop
when let's write this function so right
now right now we are just doing this
dermy dermy condition okay if it's
greater than five we
stop we can run it actually so
we can run it okay so for example let's
try it paste it run it uh
what paste the wrong place paste it run
it okay now X get period and we can test
it on the function X FP xpf that's a mod
function okay initial value let's say 99
okay and the maximum maximum test let's
say 1,000 okay maximum Nest okay run
it oh infinite Loop okay
all
all period to stop it
what infinite Loop oh yeah because wait
if the test is true
continue
what so let's print let's debug okay
print okay here we debug we print it so
I don't I don't get why is this nonstop
uh okay so
Define it okay then let's run
this let's not let's just say 10 okay
shift
enter wow wow wow wow it's printing a
lot nonstop stop old
period old period
okay okay so it's control period old
period
okay it's up now it's using up
all my
memory yeah I don't want to
it is going into a infinite
Loop
impossible old period old period I
believe old period is a board why is
this
not
yeah okay we for SC it's
it's not using much memory though but
but the program is not responding okay
let's for
scrip yeah it's too bad why why is this
did I did we get the semantic of the
true false reversed
let's see next while true to continue
right start with the expression then uh
apply F until applying test to the
result no longer yields
true right true means continue
so yeah so this should work uh
oh maybe maybe we
got okay then's start W language
again okay we digress so much that today
we are not you know we didn't finish the
V of code third
take so if we paste this here let's
see let's double check
the the
Precedence yeah those two are together
that should be right so if it's greater
than five
stop otherwise don't stop
but
um Bute uh so why is it not stopping
the function so why is it not stopping I
don't know
uh now three people watching all
the people
good
um
so it's no good
so why is this function not
stopping so you got the test this is a
test function function so next while F
initial value and test then pass it all
values now okay let's look at some
examples of the
test so even Q stop now I need to see a
example of the
O Okay so
or print and uh
un so it's a function
function print and unim so if they are
not the same
right so actually you can also say apply
F at most Max
times oh so you got to
say now you forgot to say Max times here
so that's why
it's infinite Loop you need to say max
number of times
okay
then then you can apply an extra nend
times okay
then okay so you got these kind of
variations now
now this
function okay we I can okay we can run
it so here's a function
here's a
function that is a definition we run it
okay then we um now let's rename the
xpf let's just say X Mod 5
okay so now we need to define the mod
five
function so we Define it run it that's
good then we test the modify function
paste it run that's good and then
[Music]
we then
we then then what is next then we want
to try okay now Hil storm H hail stone
then we want to
try yeah then we want to try these okay
so max Nest 1,000 so this
shouldn't let's hope it's not infinite
Loop okay because this time we added
Max n list
there okay so shift
enter okay okay stopped finally so it's
just 99
99 uh why is it just 99
oh oh xpf that's a mistake because you
forgot to
rename okay delete
this should be xart five
okay shift
enter okay still 99 what the is 99
four let's go
back so let's just run 10 times okay Shi
shift
enter initial value is
99 so why is it uh so you just print
99 so this list is 99
okay
so something is not right
yeah oh oh you actually you need this
here
so so X list so the
function takes a input X Le x l is
always
99 why is it that we said
oh let's just sa
five okay
let say next one
least okay this is
not right the test must return true okay
so the test function must always return
true
so in this
case it's a
function that just return true okay so
in our case we can make it
yep that's what I want so if you do that
and
uh this
format what no
that's what I want so let's
[Music]
see yeah well let's just do n
thing and uh so the function if the
function is true it
always so if the length is
is the length of that
is less than five then return
true
okay but uh you are not getting so what
is this function doing so that is a
problem
okay so let's test out this
function okay this is
uh let's just always return true so it
always runs okay so this function we're
going to try this again and the function
will always return true but how ever you
print the result okay shift
enter
so this is the problem you are always
getting the init as
input
um oh okay so this when you
call now I get it when you call n
while and if you say all pass all
previous
outputs to the test
function now it doesn't pass a list it
actually pass just a sequence of the
outputs that's right that's right so
okay so that's right
because you can tell you can you can
test it by because if
you you know this this list is because
here a function you just say the first
argument instead you want all arguments
okay so you want all arguments in that
case you just
say you know you just
say pound sign pound sign sign that
stands for all arguments so now if you
do
this you see it prints this it you know
it prints this
part
yeah that's right so back over here and
uh so this list so this function you you
want to get all arguments so don't use
that all argument just stand
for
um you just stand for um so you can do
this two pound sign means all arguments
then you enclose it with the list then
you got length
Okay okay so we solve that issue but but
in any case this is just this is not the
real test the real test is
you get all previous arguments you want
to check
if oh this is different this is not easy
to write because you want some kind of
double
State you know you got the current
value okay so okay here's what you can
do you can check if the all detect cycle
okay it's easy okay so here's a list
that's the all previous output you just
want so given a list you want to
determine if the tail of the
least repeats it's a new
problem okay so we break it down now we
have a new
problem let's write it
out given a
list write a uh
determine if the tail of
the list
repeats ARA
cycle for
example
9 3
2 9 3
29 okay
okay
so write a function to do this so here's
a new separate problem sub problem once
we have that then we can write our get
period
function so how do you determine given a
list how do you determine the tail
repeats
well
naively
[Music]
you well naively what you can do is you
you start from the last
element and check if that exist
previously if it does then you start
from the second last element check if
that pattern exist
okay so is
algorithm check if last two element is
same if so that is the
cycle then okay that's a tail that's
just basically one single
number check then check
if
if last
four
elements is a cycle
EG one two one
two something like that a b
a b
okay if so cycle is
two okay now otherwise check
if six elements okay the
last six element is cycle
ABC ABC okay so we started to get a
pattern
okay so bit but you always beginning at
the end
so so you do this until the length is is
less than whatever you want to check you
start with 2 4 six so that's basically 2
n 2 * 2 2 * 1 is 2 2 * * 2 is 4 2 * 3 is
6 you know 2 *
n so you take the two times n the last
that that that kind of elements and uh
basically split it in
two yeah is that is that right though
what if there's three repetitions same
thing
yeah because to determine if the tail
you know the key is here
tail so if the tail repeats you know you
just you always just check at the end so
you start with two elements then four
elements then six
then then eight you
know and all you have to do is just take
elements split in the middle and compare
the first part in you know
so and so on okay and so on
so this is how you would do it
naively now how do you do this in wolam
language is there a is there a bing
function I don't know so uh it would be
very interesting to check
let's type cycle let's search for
cycle we want to determine if the tail
forms a cycle
Cycles Cycles represent a permutation
with destroy Cycles fin cycle there it
is wait that's for
graph okay that's more complicated
that's for graph final cycle then
permutation cycles that generates a
permutation cycle find UK ukan cycle
that's also for graph Honan cycle for
graph cycle length
count count the number of Cycles for all
possible cycle length in a
permutation I think that might do let's
see show
more okay so let's see let's
try
uh well there's also find fundamental
cycle that's for graph now let's see
cycle length
counts oh God this is a again a function
Repository
so that's not what we
want yeah so that's not what we want so
we want some kind
of today we going nowhere
permutations okay permutation Cycles
true
okay I
think this is
not good
uh
we do we want permutation I don't think
so permutation group find
permutation so we just actually we want
to detect the tail
repeats so that has little to do with
permutation
[Music]
uh so what are you doing so let's go to
related guides related to permutation
cylic permutation
representation now permutation means
given a list of
things you you mix them you reorder them
and you get a of all possible reordering
so that's what permutation
is and what is a cycle cyclic
permutation
representation oh okay
yeah
so so cyclet
permutation means
oh that wow that that is you know that
is cyc
permutation that is
a
notation to spec
specify a particular
reordering
okay that's a notation to specify a
particular reordering of a list of
things I
believe
uh oh God this is not good wait can we
just simply right okay this is not good
okay we just want to find the repetition
of the tail
so so until
is greater than half the length of
until n is greater
than yeah until 2 N is greater than
length of
least
okay so yeah determine the cycle of a
tail how do you do that yeah
what is the most efficient
way so permutation is rearranging this
is not about rearranging so maybe there
is no Bing function to do this
okay we can write yeah got we can write
a function ourself so
find cyclic tail
okay let me just push
on usage
if none
return empty list okay so that's a
documentation and uh so we going to
write the
function
uh do you want to do it pattern matching
or not
we can
and no okay so equals to function then
okay then X is the input so first of all
you need to get the length so
module
uh so X is x l let's say okay so X
length equals to length
of the least okay now what the body of
what you want to do the body of the th
function is that you want
to
uh I want to God writing okay this is
not good so why don't we take a
break I sent wolf M code not related to
the problem but it does not go through
chat uh no I think that's because
YouTube YouTube
is um YouTube has some kind of filter
you know let's see live
chat yeah YouTube has some kind of
filter that's that has to do with the
setup you know like I just follow the
normal setup so it
filters uh I think it filters code and
so on I can edit actually can
it details customization
uh
playlist whatever that
that yeah so I think there is some kind
of trailer redirect live chat live chat
replay uh there is a check mark
somewhere about whether to use automatic
filter something
thumbnail playlist audience okay yes
it's not for kid okay paid promotion no
altered altered content any of the
following uh real person doing something
didn't say no fake that's basically fake
things automatic chapters okay featured
places automatic Concepts
Texs uh recording data and location
license
distribution allow
embedding comment and the ratings okay
common
moderation
um commment moderation
basic okay let's say if I say
none save now now try to post let's see
if that
works yeah anyway today is kind of
that's no good because I T too much and
no
code
um and to you know like writing simple
functions so we want to find you know
cyclic tail yeah so we have to implement
this so you get the list of the length
and so try to post the code Jolina see
if that works
so we find we want to find the tail of a
function and
uh so we can
follow you know this algorithm
that something like that
okay so we can you know let's we can use
a pattern Ming okay
so let me so this would be interesting
okay one single line of pattern matching
will find you the tail of a list of a
repeating you know tail of a list okay
so you want to
do okay Jolina says nothing yeah I don't
know you know you know something YouTube
so so if you want to paste
code you know even if I Chang the
settings here I just did but I don't
know if that has real time effect or do
I have to set it in
before
um you know Common moderation none you
see wait do I say
off comment and ratings
on okay yeah
so common rating is on and uh live chat
showing live chat so
so that's something YouTube too bad so
anyway so this so we want to find the
tail okay so what you can do
is
uh replace all
okay replace
all of a given
list then you want to
say uh
head low line low line low line that's
something we don't
care uh let's put it here
okay had something something okay so
actually a
list so give so it's a list starting
with something zero or more anything
zero or more then
then tail okay then tail one or more so
that's two low line okay then matched by
tail again okay this will match when
when this thing match that
means there's there's a repeating tail
okay so when that match just return
tail and tail in a in a list okay so
this would be function I mean this would
be kind of interesting thing we did
today the first interesting
thing uh okay so we don't need the modu
anymore so let's remove the even simpler
okay so here is a function let's try it
okay then all you have to do is try it
so let's
say F tail given a list uh given a list
one two
three two three two
okay n
no uh no
because okay so I think I can fix this
so it should be it should return 32 in
this case Okay so but it's
not uh in fact we don't want to use
replace all
because because replace or we'll check
all levels that's not what we want we
want Define a function patter matching
okay pattern matching then you want uh
transform function that transform
expression by pattern okay here's a list
of all of them so replace all replace
repeated they all do all levels what you
want is replace with the level spec
that's what you want okay so simply
replace because you can specify uh
particular level of expression level
means depth
uh
because expression is any an expression
can be arbitrary tree so this is a
tricky part of pattern matching when you
have a
tree you know it just doesn't matter it
it does not just match the flat each
item it actually when you have a tree it
um gets complicated you can read my
tutorial if you want so but anyway so we
want to say level level expect is
um we just want to say level one
okay but
uh so we can do mean we can just simply
test this
expression uh and uh let's
say this is
that and
uh
okay uh in fact this is
[Music]
repeated one or more
times okay so actually we don't need
even that so this is
superb example of the power of pal
magine okay run
it no
failed
uh this means uh this means one or more
times one or
more
so okay so
let's
try okay that doesn't
work why is that not work it's
because so we got 3 two
32 okay tell means
uh so you need some kind of longest oh
God okay let's
try
longest okay so you got
uh you want pattern name this pattern
tail and what is the pattern exactly the
pattern is that
longest
of
of one or more okay and uh repeat
it one or more times
okay this gets
complex okay let let me let me get
this okay let's try
that what
God it's I don't know what's going
on and I'm starting to get tired why is
this not
so dot dot is repeated one or more times
let's go back to the pattern matching
syntax
here and
uh repeated pmax okay repeat a pattern
repeated one to Max times okay so here
is the
expression repeat it
okay so let's change them to the full
syntax so maybe it's easier to
read okay instead of using the dot dot
let's say repeat
it okay repeated it of this p pattern
okay so now you can see now we getting
into this
one so we have a pattern that is that
this pattern is named the
tail and uh it's going to match the
longest actually you shouldn't match the
longest one or more
so yeah so let's remove the longest for
now
because
no God
oh God this is very interesting though
but we
have failed
so this is a pattern named tail and the
pattern is underscore
underscore so that
means
it's one or more
so this is just one or more of
anything but you want
it repeat
it okay so I
think maybe I should go back to this
idea
okay
so let's just
say tail here okay should
work want
if we cannot solve this I'm pretty sure
it'll just
work there it is there it is okay so now
now having understood that yes tail tail
you see tail repeated twice
now oh yeah all you have to do
is put that
there so now
let's copy the above then now do it
again this time just using
replace yes it
works the whole
expression uh zero to Infinity so anyway
so replace works now I want to be sure
about the
level level spec
okay so level spec is a bit complex if
you you know you can read my tutorial
there's a example about pattern matching
with the level stuff level means the
depth of the tree typically it's a
range um like depth zero to depth five
but it can also be a specific level like
depth five only
so this is important when your pattern
can match you know arbitrary like at
different depth of a
expression uh but in our case we don't
want any depth we want a flat because we
only care we are considering the input
as a flat list of items so if the one of
the item is a tree and it has the tail
we don't care we only want to care about
the top level that is why we are using
replace so we can say a level spec we
can limit the
level so level is level n
Only
uh so n is uh in the whole expression
okay so level one is you know we should
use level one okay
so so we we can go back here and and we
can try Okay so if you say level
one you will also
walk uh no
what oh oh right that's right it needs
to be level zero okay now level zero is
the whole expression it's it's can be
very confusing okay so this works now
for example let's try some other the uh
sequence now let's say if the tail
is 3
324 okay that doesn't work that's right
and what if it's
uh 32 4 that works okay now when there's
no match you want it to return uh zero I
mean uh empty list okay so you need to
fix this find cyclic
tail so if you say match
Q let's
see you want to determine it match or
not so that does not allow you to
specify a level you need to be able to
say a level
okay okay so you want to say
replace level zero okay so level
zero and uh so that's basic
basically just that okay and
uh then you want to say if it didn't
match yeah you you need to know if it
matched or
not okay so there's more detail pattern
matching functions
cas's position count
yeah but basically our function works if
it's just
that you know when there's no match you
just return the whole thing which is not
good when there's no tail we need to
have it return empty
least
so we need to apply match Q at level
zero Okay so we need
to apply match Q at level zero you see
match Q does not have a option for level
by default so that means you need
[Music]
to uh map
at oh God this can get very
complex uh I don't know if you guys know
what I'm
saying
because uh map at a specific
level no the map at is
for MPP to a specific list position
positions so that's not what we
want we want
to okay probably boring for all of
you oh Jolina finally able to post some
code oh let
copy uh can you copy
no okay so let's
see German German German
Molina so map map part part uh one
two and uh what evalue ENT entity
country United States versus China okay
let's see sh shift
enter now this is going to get some
information from the
web this is the using wolam
language so you
got 340 Millions people so that's
USA and uh the H and uh let's
see okay then the second one is
1.4 billion people in China like I said
so it's using 3.8 kilowatts per person
while in USA it's using 1.35 kilow per
person so for each person in
USA it's using
about 3 to four times more energy thank
you thank you for that political part we
I I was talking about
before yeah so for each person in USA is
using three to four times more energy
electricity than China okay so back to
here um back to here we have this code
you
know you know I I want you know so this
code is already
working and name but we we all we have
to do is uh if there's no match we want
to return an empty
list when there's no cycle okay we can
easily do that by you know by for
example
if uh if match Q
okay if match
q that
then then then do the you know return
this replace true okay else return an
empty dist you know this we can easily
do that so just put this part in the
true part you know however if we do that
that's not entirely correct why because
this match Q will match all depth of the
expression
let me show you a example shall
we um because this match CU for example
let's say
okay so here's a list uh let's let's try
it okay so
wait 2 five
okay s okay now now you see we got a
list like this okay okay now does this
list have a cycle no because the last
two elements is 2 five and the one
before that is a Leist so this element
does not have a cycle however if you run
this match CU it will match okay let me
show
you yeah Force
wait why is it oh yeah so you need
something what you see what I was
thinking it will match the 32 32
there oh wait the the match CU will
match the whole expression oh okay so
yeah so there's a yeah that's that's
right right the match cu will match the
whole expression not sub expression so
the match Q actually works the same at
the same level as the replace by default
so this will work so we just replace the
default here okay so now our function
works so let's you know we can try it
again how do you guys like wam language
code except you joona because you know
wam
language you know but I was I'm
wondering how do all the other people so
here is our
function now if we call this function
um uh okay we don't need that so we need
a test function
so so for example we need to test
this one R it that's
correct what about uh what about let's
say add two run it two that's correct
what if I add
three run it empty that's
correct what what if you uh let's say 2
three 2 three that will be 2 three
you know so if you add another number
let's say 4 2 3 4 2 3 4 here return to
34 so this and and you can also have
triple repeat your work so this is uh
this is a great
uh code we did today you know actually
the the the shiny part of today's talk
show so this is great okay
so now we can remove all our
previous kind of
thing okay so we got this function now
this function is essential for our
original problem
of of find the period of a nesting of a
function okay so all we have to do now
now here so here's a
test um so let's move the function up so
this this function let's move it up find
cyclic tail okay cut
it move up
somewhere paste it
okay find cyclic tail now we want to
write this function get period so the
test will
be so instead of this random you know uh
Toy test we just say
if
if if find cyclic
tail
at uh what wait me hold on a second yeah
so if find cyclic tail at all the
arguments there a list of all arguments
so if that returns
true
then uh so if they cyclic tail then
stop Force
okay let means stop running the nting
otherwise true continue the nesting
okay so let's clean up this so this is a
test function so actually now we have
this kind of a
short
uh wait uh wait so if if if the find
cyclic tail at that is equals to
empty list
okay
then then that means there's no cycle
found okay when there's no cycle found
you want to continue okay
so okay so it's a bit annoying here so
anyway so here is a function to test
whether you want the nting to continue
if the cycle is empty list then continue
otherwise false means stop okay so that
is a test function and we pass the text
function to next
s
okay good now let's test this let's copy
that okay copy that and
uh actually we going ins somewhere now
finally we actually so this
code run
it okay it run so what
the so what is this part what is this
doing X get period xmart
5 uh wait there's something not
right okay let's let's restart wam
language okay so let me do a some
screenshot
because that's some of the interesting
parts for today's talk
show okay then we're going to restart
with our language save
no and
uh CL that close that
okay now it's 2 hours and half
new
notepad three shift enter to
evaluate
magnify okay now we have several code we
we want to
try this you don't need so
so copy that copy that copy that copy
that copy that
hellstone copy that and find tail yes
then
so yeah
so copy that or select or
paste okay so here is
today so we
got mod five function then we got
some some
clarification of periodic versus nesting
of a function
period then we did we explain how to
precisely Define
periodic
then we explored on the question is it
possible to have a discrete function
whose nesting periodic is dependent on
the input yes however we don't have a
example uh then we have hstone numbers
which has which is a discrete function
that has a pery of three always not
dependent on the input okay so hstone
number
defined and
uh why do they put the why do they put
the red correct
there oh because you are missing
yeah let's
say let's say nest 10
okay then you have find cyclet tail okay
let's let's let's separate each
yeah and because this
is this is so slow today anyway so why
not
just okay so you can run that see
example okay go down and here's a
hellstone numbers
split and run that so that's a example
then you got F cyclet very good
now do we have a test no
so we need to get a
test
here did
we okay we we have to rewrite
it
932 32
okay
split shift enter run
it here's example run it 3 two now if
you got one that returns empty least
because that's not
cyclic okay so now we get back
to this function get period determine
the period of a function when nesting
it okay and uh and uh this is the goal
of today's talk show and uh looks like I
got it looks like how elegant it is you
know compare this I you know although I
was slow for three hours almost but
compare these
to to the one someone else wrote you to
the one someone else wrote
here so if we are successful that means
truly elegant so this is someone else
someone else code Phillips um Phillips
Richard Phillips from function
repository uh but our code is
just this okay we we haven't tested for
sure yet we don't know if this is uh oh
yeah you need a semicolon
there so this basically we call n file
and uh and uh of a
function apply initial value to the
function then use the test function to
determine when to stop and every time
you call the test function you pass all
previous argument to it
and uh this will stop X at maximum Nest
number of times okay and this test
function is just this it tests if all
the previous argument has a py cyclic
tail if if not it's empty then true
means continue otherwise
stop okay so
okay so that's but you know when you
stop you just stop you you still need to
know the you need to know the length of
this what this whatever this return so
we still need to modify
it okay but I think that's it um you
know
99.9% sure this will be this is
correct so yesterday you know like it's
like yesterday after 3 hours we
determined we need this function
you know the function is already there
but actually we tried it didn't work for
some reason we still don't know why yet
so today we made progress by writing
this function ourselves you know another
3 hours but we did it I mean well not
yet but I'm 99% sure it
works then then maybe tomorrow you know
I think next you know next one I'm going
to do some emac this but then you know
we do next one then we finish
this and then we can go back to testing
our event of code The
Matrix and does that make sense I don't
think anyone is following me anywhere by
now okay five people okay so that's
it so why don't we
continue this no
because we need in order to test this
function through all
the we need to find a function where
when you Nest it we need to find a
discrete function that takes a you know
let's say integer or or a matrix of
integers a integer and return integer or
a matrix and return Matrix actually we
do have that function from aent of code
so anyway we we need in order to test
this we need to find a function discrete
function that um that when given certain
initial value it has a cycle and the
period
okay yeah in order to test
that you know we could easily create
that function just by defining Brute
Force values you know to make it cycle
you know like just hard code you know
when it's two return 2 31 things like
that when it's you know 10 return 1031
you know
10312 cycle so different input we have a
different
py and the the the list of cyclic
tail yeah we can hot code it but you
know I don't I don't feel like doing
that um so I think that's good thank you
guys for what for watching today I think
that's it for
that
yeah you know I'm thinking deleting this
video today because it's like three you
know close to three hours and not doing
much
anyway okay yeah so that's our code and
what is his code doing I mean you know
he's he's uh he's
using not pure functional approach um
you know he's using the plus
plus you know there plus plus and tri
steps that's a local variable and he's
implementing it using a
block means Dynamic scope you know then
he's using width width is a constant
okay uh I mean Declaration of
constant uh okay so he's doing Nest
while and uh and
um you can see yeah so I
think I think the way we did it is much
more better and and I would claim also
faster okay so yeah this would be a good
problem so next video we're going to
thly test out you know create a function
that that does that has that that is
cyclic when nested and depending on
different initial value you have
different periodic and different cyclic
tals so we get a simple function you
know we get you know we try to find it
then we compare these two solutions and
we can test the
speed okay that's it for today thank you
guys for
watching bye
put this back syntax C show so this is
what we did
today you know that's close to three
hours but you know a lot of thinking
that's kind of
typical for programming bye