Good evening everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Xa Talk Show.
We are going to code Advent of Code 2025
day four, part two.
In the past few weeks, we've been doing
Advent of Code daily. So, you can watch
the past videos uh or live stream.
If you are watching this offline, play
at 1.5 speed or twice as fast. If you
are here, say hi. Love to see your
comments, okay?
So, let's be begin Advent of Code.
Now, you can find my website. Just
search for xali.info.
xali.info, that is my website. http no
s. It says not secure because I don't
need your credit card.
Then, you go to Xa Talk Show.
Then, you can find all the past Xa Talk
Show's episode 731 today.
Click on that. And then, you can find
all the Wolfram Language tutorial,
Wolfram Language for programmers. So,
this is complete tutorial.
And you can find a download link of
Wolfram Language
here.
Okay? So, let's begin uh Advent of Code.
Now, I still have a little code.
Cough. [clears throat]
So, sorry about that.
Hello, GCS. Okay. So, no need to
introduce Wolfram Language because I did
that hundreds of times.
And we just going to jump into Advent of
Code uh day four.
Let's see. Uh
Select all.
Copy.
And we want the text version because the
you know, this Advent of Code, they
hardcode their layouts. So, when you
have large font,
then you cannot um
You see, it went off.
So, let's read it from here, Advent of
Code. So,
uh
Uh it's not so good. Okay, so let's read
it from Firefox.
Advent of Code, day four, part two.
Okay, so part two.
Day four. Oh, you can't see the part two
unless you log in. Annoying. So, you
have to read it from here.
Okay, that is
uh it's on Discord. Okay, so let's read
from here, day four.
>> [clears throat]
>> The first half of this puzzle is
complete. It provides one gold star.
Okay, you need to magnify more.
God.
So, part two. Now, the elves just need
help accessing as much of
of the papers they can. One Once a row
of paper can be accessed by a forklift,
it can be removed.
Okay.
Once a row of paper is removed, the
forklift
might be able to access more row of
paper,
which they might also be able to remove.
Okay, how many total rows of paper could
the elves remove if they keep repeating
this process?
Very interesting.
Starting with the same example as above,
here is one way you could remove as many
rows of paper as possible using
highlighted at sign to indicate that a
row of paper is about to be removed.
Okay, annoying.
>> [clears throat]
>> And using X to indicate that a row of
paper was just removed. Okay.
So, we start with this grid.
And basically, the problem
was that
you are given So, you are given this
grid.
Um
for each at sign,
you want count how many neighbors there
are
that has the at sign, including
diagonal.
So, if it's So, for given at sign
position, if it has less than four
neighbors,
>> [clears throat]
>> then you consider that at sign position
special.
And the puzzle is how many special at
sign positions are there.
That was the They the part one problem.
Okay. Now, it says, "Once you know
an at sign position has less than four
at signs around around it, then you can
remove that at sign at that position
itself."
Okay, you can remove it.
So,
So, you you do this for the whole for
the entire at sign, then you repeat the
process.
Uh basically, it's asking you how many
at signs you are able to remove. Okay.
Now, let's
Let me think about this. So, at sign
So, for example, this one, top right,
near the corner,
it has one one two three three
neighbors, okay? So, that one
can be removed.
So, if
So, if it has less than three neighbors,
that at sign can be removed.
Okay?
So, you are just So, the whole process
is just going to remove some of the at
signs. So, is there a condition where at
sign cannot be removed?
Yes. For example, if if a place is
filled with at sign,
then like then the center part region,
they won't be removed because the
neighbor won't Yeah, so if you have the
entire square of grids of at sign,
those are not going to be removed
because in order to remove an at sign,
it must have neighbors of at sign of
less than
four counts.
So, the at sign on the edges where it
has empty space around it, those might
get removed, but it So, it will remove
near the edges and shrink shrink, but
uh
but it'll stop at certain condition.
Okay? Now, we got the
characteristics of this problem.
Now, let me think about
uh immediately the thought is that what
is the condition?
Consider this from a geometric point of
view. What is the condition when
an at sign that will never be removed?
Okay, you can start to think about that.
What is the condition like the
the shape of the at sign
such that those at signs will never be
removed.
Um
less than four. So,
less than four neighbors. So, if you
have a cross of at sign, the center one
will never be removed.
But, the
the cross, the edge might be removed if
they don't have neighbors.
Wait. Yeah, it might be. So, if you So,
if you have a empty grid, then all you
have is a cross sign. 1 2 3 4 5 5 at
signs.
Then,
they will be all removed. Because first
of all, the the ones on the side, they
will be removed because they have only
three neighbors.
Then, once the side ones got removed,
the center one
don't have any neighbors. So, itself got
removed. Okay.
But, if you have, let's say, a 3 by 3
grid, it's all at sign.
Will they be be removed? Yes. Because if
you have 3 by 3 grid, then the one
at sign at the corner has three
neighbors. Therefore, it will be
removed. So, the four diagonal corners
going to be removed. Then, we got a
cross. Then, it will be removed, too.
But, now consider if you have a 4 by 4
at sign.
Then, then let's see. Four If you have a
4 by 4 at sign,
let's see.
1 2 3 1 2 3 4 5. Then, then
um
the corner will be removed, but
but not the rest. Okay, we can start to
draw it.
>> [clears throat]
>> If we draw it, it will it will be it
might become clear. So, let's see if we
can
draw it.
But, anyway, this this is not relevant
to solve the Advent of Code problem.
This is just us um doing
kind of
exploration immediate thinking about the
um
the issue. Okay, so let's open with
snipping tool.
So, let's say if you have a grid.
Oh god, this is This is wrong.
Uh undo
undo. So, you need to be straight.
So, basically, 1 2 3
1 2
4. Consider this grid, okay? Consider
it's filled with at signs. Now, the one
on the corner, it will be removed
because it only has three neighbors. So,
corner corner corner corner, they are
all gone.
Now, consider this
this one.
So, the corner is gone, but this one's
got 1 2 3 4, so it stays. So, this one
stays.
This one stays, too, because of
symmetry. You know, they are same. So,
this this this this this this this all
stays.
And those stay and, of course, the
middle four also stays. So, you got this
kind of double thickness cross. They
will stay
if you have this kind of situation,
okay?
But, I don't think this is relevant.
Oh, did we save? we didn't save.
Okay.
So,
but that's a interesting thing. So,
because it's not relevant because the
the puzzle ask you
how many total rows of paper could the
elves remove if they keep repeating this
process?
They didn't ask you
They didn't ask you how how many
remaining
uh
S sign.
If they ask you how many remaining S
sign,
well, actually it's related. So, if you
know how many S signs remains, then you
can also answer how many will be removed
because you take the total number of S
sign minus
of the
how many that will remain,
then that's your answer. That's how many
will be removed.
So,
so actually you can look at this problem
possibly from a geometric point of view.
So, you don't even have to um
to like
do what we did before.
You look at the shape of the S sign and
you
analyze
what kind of shape
you know, how you know, we know that
only the edges of the S sign will be
cut. So, you can think of it as each
time the edge
or the corner S sign, they are removed.
You can think of it it as a way of um
eroding the thing. So, they shrink
shrink shrink, but shrink to a point
that will not change.
So, in this way,
it's like a geometrical position
analysis.
Then you eventually you know how many S
signs will remain.
Then you can find out how many S signs
are going to be removed. So, that is uh
uh
very interesting approach, but would
that actually work? We don't know, but
that's you know, that's very interesting
alternative, I think,
solution approach.
It would be interesting to see what
other people has any other people, you
know, they they are thousands and tens
of thousand or hundreds of thousand
people doing this. It would be
interesting to look at if anyone did it
that way,
because that would be quite interesting.
I know that most people when they see
this, they are not going to do it that
way. They they just do the procedural
like counting arrays and stuff.
Hi, this is just a game.
Oh, this is just the game of life with
tricks. Yes, indeed. That's very
interesting
observation. So,
yes, indeed. So, okay. So, yeah, game of
of life it's less than
four neighbors, it dies, right?
Exactly.
Good good point.
So,
yeah, so you can you can actually just
plug in this in into a game of life um
you know, grid and then
then it will just evolve and then
something will remain it will have
blinkers. Oh,
what what about the situation of
blinkers?
Okay, I got so this you know, the
difference with game of life is that
game of life also has a condition where
they add a new cell. They add a new as
sign, but in this puzzle, they don't
they don't have a condition where you
add
a new cell, yeah.
So, anyway
So, anyway, let's let's see let's see
the detail, okay? Initial state, so the
the highlighted at sign indicate that a
row paper is about to be removed, so it
can be removed. So, this one it has
three neighbors, it's so it's going to
be removed. This one
it has three neighbors, so it's going to
be removed. Okay, okay, yeah. So, okay,
so this one so yeah, so you can see kind
of the picture of the edges.
They're going to be removed, okay?
Then
then what happens?
Remove 13 rows of paper, okay? So, that
becomes that. They just replace it with
X. X means it it was just removed. Okay,
then in this picture you got this edge,
you know, you got this at sign. I don't
know if you guys can see it this
highlighted. This advent of color sucks.
They should use a color red.
You know use a color red, man, or some
other color, so it's easier to see.
So, anyway, so so then the next stage
you got this at signs, they're going to
be removed, okay? Gun gun gun. Then at
this stage this at sign
you know, on the edge going to be
removed, okay? Then
>> [clears throat]
>> so that removed 12. Then this stage
they're going to remove seven. So, 1 2 3
4 5 Wait, 1 2 3 4 5, okay? But 1 2 3 4 5
6 7. So, in here they removed seven.
And in here
right, they removed seven become X then,
but they are 1 2 3 4 5 5
new at sign that's going to be removed,
so they removed five, then you got that.
Then you remove so two more to remove
then you become that.
Uh let's see.
Okay, so once you remove these two at
sign, then you got new at sign that
going to be removed. So we remove that
one.
Oh, then another one got needs to be
removed. So we remove that one then that
one that needs to be removed. Then
remove that one that new one. Okay, then
eventually you end up with that.
So
in this stage there's no more at sign
that you can remove. Is that true? So
each at sign has
uh
four neighbors minimum.
Is that right? Correct. So each at sign
has four neighbors minimum. What about
this one? 1 2 3 4, yeah.
Okay.
That works out.
So stop once no more rows of paper are
accessible by a forklift. Twisted
language. I don't like the the advent of
a code because they
they color it by this elf, you know, by
these rows of paper. What kind of like
this is very kind of annoying thing
to talk about. Rows of paper.
Wordy, you know,
and then they represent with the at sign
uh and they talk about accessible by a
forklift.
Like twisted tail.
Very annoying.
>> [clears throat]
>> But you see, from a storytelling point
of view, like fairy tale, is this story
interesting? Not really.
Like who the what does Christmas
has to do with rows of paper and
accessible and by a forklift?
You know, at least if you want to make
into a interesting story or fairy tale
and related to Christmas because this is
Advent of Code. This is promoting
Christianity, in fact.
You know, it's it's promoting a
particular religion.
Okay, well, yeah, you know, in USA, so
that's a dominant religion. So, but you
So, you make up a story about elves and
Santa Claus or whatever. Did they
actually mention Santa? Yes, I think I
think they did.
But you got to make it at least
interesting and fun and comforting.
What the is with the forklift and
the
and the rows of paper? Very annoying.
So, I don't like the
I can tell
and by now I've done few several years
of Advent of Code. I don't I don't like
the
guy.
Okay, so once no more rows of paper are
accessible by a forklift. In this
example, a total of 43 rows of paper can
be removed, okay? So, that is your
answer.
Start by Start with your original
diagram. How many rows of paper in total
can be removed by the elves and their
forklifts, okay?
So, now let's think about solving the
problem.
Uh before we talked about
geometrical analysis. Let's forget about
that. Um let's just do
easy approach.
Wait, can can you actually think about
geometric um
You can kind of actually
um
Uh let's not go there, okay? That then
because that then it's going to take 2
hours or 3.
So, we just do
as we did before, so
So, before yesterday, we did Advent of
Code day four.
Okay. So, that is So, wait.
Video summary.
So, we did um
we padded the matrix so it's easier to
deal with to find the neighbor
of the
cells on the edge because those actually
don't have neighbors. But, if you pad
the matrix, then
you can use the indices, so it's kind of
easier.
So, we wrote a function get neighbors
that count neighbors, okay?
And then, we apply this function to all
cell positions that
is an at sign. So, that's another
critical point. You only apply this to
the
to the position where there's an at
sign.
Okay.
So, then we got the answer. Okay, so the
the
the example input solution is 13.
So, we got this So,
we got this get get neighbors
>> [clears throat]
>> that gets um
Right. So, we first of all, we turn the
matrix into zeros and ones. Did I show
it here? Maybe not. There's no But,
anyway, we turn the matrix of zero ones.
So, at sign is one.
Empty space is zero.
Then, we use our get neighbors function
to find all the neighbors, which is just
one and zero.
So, 1 0 1 0, you know, all the
neighbors. Then, for each
cell we are interested, we can count how
many neighbors it has.
So, if it's less than three, less than
four, then we consider that cell
special.
Okay.
And we remove and and now
we have to remove that cell and start
all over, okay? So, this is not
difficult problem,
but it's it's kind of tedious. It'll
take me an hour or two.
>> [clears throat]
>> Yeah.
Okay.
So, bad omen. I don't think I can do it
um
in an hour. If I don't talk, then yes.
Um but I need to talk, okay?
So, uh question. What is Wolfram
language? Never heard of it. Sorry. Can
you give me a quick context? Yes, of
course. So, Wolfram language is a
so-called computer algebra system.
Uh
In Well, in fact, I've done hundreds of
Wolfram language tutorials. So, let me
just show you some, okay?
So, computer algebra So, you can look up
Wikipedia, but basically it's a computer
algebra system.
And what does that means? It It just
means it can solve matrix equations,
integral equations, derivatives,
expand polynomials,
uh do algebraic manipulation, basically
advanced mathematics, do all sort of
mathematics.
Uh
you know, uh
solving equations, differential
equations,
and then it can do geometry like uh
visualization like um
Okay, so
computer algebra system means it's a
programming language to do mathematics,
okay? That is the origin of Wolfram
language. It was known as Mathematica
back in uh
back in 1989. It began 1989 or 1986,
okay?
So, if you go back to my Wolfram
Language tutorial, I can show you. So,
for example,
so computer algebra system, but however,
it also have a visualization system. For
example, it can
you can plot sine, cosine, trigonometry.
Uh you can plot the Earth, you can plot
vector graph like weather. For example,
you see weather maps, right? How you can
then a map of USA, then rain red red is
heat, blue is cold. You can You can plot
that. So, it's a visualization system as
well.
Uh so, let's start. Let's do 5 minutes
demo, okay?
Thank you for asking the question. Let
Let me just do 5 minutes demo.
>> [clears throat]
>> And remember, I did hundreds of videos
on Wolfram Language. So, if you can just
uh look at my um
Wolfram Language. So, I paste the code
there.
And uh shift
control T
to turn it to turn it into
uh
Mathematica typeset.
Magnify, okay?
Wait, I don't want T, I want N, okay?
For example,
paste the code.
Here's our
original code, linear, just like a
programming language. Uh close that.
See? But now, I press control shift N
to turn this, you see, into a
mathematically typeset.
And you can
format it on the fly. You can see it
smartly insert line breaks, okay?
All other programming language don't
have that feature. It does that
in real time as you change the size. And
plus, it can do uh mathematical type
setting. So, in other way, in other
sense, it replace the tech LaTeX
type setting system. So, it can do
nested uh square root,
fractions, complicated fractions, nested
fractions. I I demonstrated that many
times, okay? So, anyway, here's a code,
and shift enter to run the code. Shift
enter.
So, we are So, this is a example of
graphics programming.
So, we you got You turn this grid into
this shape, and that process is a
is called geometric inversion. It's part
of mathematics uh in the field of
complex analysis. That is the complex
numbers, okay? So, if you know math,
then you you kind of understand this.
So, this is like 1 over
X, where X is a complex number. That's
That's the graph of 1 over X, okay? Also
known as geometric inversion, related,
okay? So, this is a demo of
graphics programming features.
Now, uh so So, there are variations. You
can So, you can use this to do tidings,
pattern decorations, design, uh
research. For example, Islamic patterns.
Then, you can do this. Let's see um
So, that That's a demo, okay? We We did
this live few years ago.
So, you So, you can turn it into a 3D
grid, then you turn that this into a 3D
uh
version. Okay? Then, uh let me just show
you another one, beautiful one, okay?
So, copy the code. So, the code
one of the characteristics of Wolfram
Language is is that it's extremely
expressive. So, by this simple code
shift enter
it generates this thing. Okay, so again,
this is geometric inversion. You begin
with a grid, a 3D grid. You apply the
inversion process to each point on a
grid.
Then you get the figure on the right,
and this is a three-dimensional version.
So, you can see
So, this is part of what Wolfram
Language does, and the code is extremely
succinct.
For example, if you want to do a cube,
let's say uh
you want to rotate a cube.
So, this is what you do.
Graphics.
Okay, graphics that then cube. There is
a by default there's a cube primitive,
so shift enter.
Uh
Okay, you need the you need to remove
the space. Shift enter.
Uh no, graphics 3D. Okay, graphics 3D.
2D is just graphics. Graphics 3D
cube is 3D thing, so you need to say uh
graphics 3D shift enter.
There you go.
So, you So,
to do this in Python
or C or C++, it requires like 100 lines.
Okay.
Uh and then you can add axis.
Axis, and uh let's just completion true.
Okay, so now you have a sense where
things are.
Similarly for this one, you can add
axis. Okay.
So, that's this So, this is part of the
graphics visualization feature of
Wolfram Language.
Now, if you want to know more, you go to
um
you know, you like you you go to my for
example you just search for Wolfram
Language, okay? So, but let me go to uh
my Wolfram Language um
Yeah.
So, and you know, this for example all
these graphics um plane curves
are all done with Wolfram Language. I
did this
in the 1990s.
So, this demonstrate
the definition of a parabola
where you have a point fixed point and
you have another
and you have a given line.
The definition of a parabola is that is
all points such that they are equal
distant from the line and the fixed
point. So, that's that's the
visualization. Okay, so all these are
programmed in Wolfram Language.
And this shows the optical of uh
parabola property.
And you can see that in headlamps of
your car or flashlight.
Uh so, anyway, so that's one of them.
So, there are hundreds of them I did.
So, that those all all those are using
the graphics programming feature of
Wolfram Language. Extremely expressive.
Okay.
So, that's the graphics feature. Then,
you have typesetting for example, I
click on this one. Uh let me copy, okay?
So, copy this. Copy.
Go down.
And uh paste it. Again, I press control
shift N.
So, you see now you got typeset.
You see those fractions and they can be
nested, you know, fractions or radicals.
And you can
format this complicated expression on
the fly.
You don't have to like go format Python
black format, you know,
after you code you format then you code
again then reformat, you know, it it's
done
live on the fly on on the fly as you
type, okay.
So that's
two of the features, typesetting,
mathematical typesetting, graphics
programming and
doing mathematics, equate solving
equations, solving matrices, integral
equation, differential equation, all
kind of Okay, that's just so far we
covered three aspects of Wolfram
language.
But this but there's like 10 small,
okay.
Uh because
in the past 30 years Wolfram language
has grown and grown. So let's go to um
So let's go to my Wolfram language
tutorial.
Okay, so let's Wolfram language for
programmers the complete intro. Let's go
to
uh let's say list. Let's say string.
String everyone understand. So this is
introduction to string
syntax in Wolfram language.
Then you go down so you got string Q
Q means a question. Q means it return
whether
this object is a string or not, okay.
Then you got length familiar to
everyone.
So then you got string functions, you
know, typically in a programming
language you you got 20 of them, 30 of
them, but Wolfram language got like
almost 100 of them or 50 50. So in other
words, Wolfram language has 7,000
functions building.
You do not even need to load a library.
Like in Python you if you want to use
regular expression
you have to import
V.
If you want to list file directory
contents recursively, you have to import
uh system IO file.
Then you can you can because a
directory. If you want to do graphics,
you have to import graphics. If you want
to do computer networks networking TCP
IP, you have to import, you know, net,
whatever. If you want to pass HTML, you
have to import HTML, whatever.
In Wolfram language, you got 7,000
functions
within no loading any library. There are
lots of libraries you can load, but
by default, there's 7,000 functions like
all there.
So,
so this shows that Wolfram language is
supremely it's designed for the user.
Like I don't have to like I I want to
use regular expression. Why do I need to
find out like load a library?
Why does Python do it? Why does C++ C C
or C# or other language do it? Because
they need to be minimal because they
they you know, you write operating
operating system or whatever. You You
don't want things you don't use.
But Wolfram language is like designed
for the
for the comfort of the coder. So, it
just got everything.
So, that's one way to look at it, okay?
So, we covered several things. Then
string, so now let's go to Wolfram
language website. So, you get substring.
One of the function is you
get substring by the index, okay? So,
then you go to their website.
This is a documentation. Then you go to
Wolfram documentation center. This is
Here you can see all things that Wolfram
language can do.
So, you got Wolfram Language core
structures, um then data manipulation,
uh array manipulation, data
visualization, machine learning,
statistics.
Uh
for example, let's say data
visualization because I'm very much into
geometry. So, you got list plot, line
plot, list line, list step plot, stack
plot, list point plot, list
line plot 3D.
You got density plot. Let's show some of
them. Okay, you got density plot. So,
you got
like building
hundreds
over hundreds, you know,
bar chart, bar chart, pie chart, bubble
chart, bar chart 3D,
quantile plot, you know, uh box whiskers
chart plot.
And you know, you just one single line,
you'll plot it. Everything is uh smart.
You'll you'll figure out
how you know, the data range and stuff
and you'll figure out for you.
So, and then if you do graph theory, for
example, you do trees, uh for example,
let's see graph plot. So, you got a
bunch of functions doing uh that will
plot arbitrary
uh graph.
These are graphs in graph theory.
So, for example, uh
you know, we can copy it and and and and
and you know, run it.
Paste it.
Uh
no, not that. So, we want to copy the
code.
Copy.
Paste it.
Shift enter.
There it is.
Uh so, this
graph is called Petersen graph.
It is like a well-known uh named uh
graph. So, there's a name. Otherwise,
you can plot um
you know, a graph is defined by a list
of edges. So, this is one way to
represent graph. So, you can shift
enter, then you plot it. Okay. So, you
can plot any graph, including graphs
with hundreds or thousands of nodes. It
will
figure out in a smart way how to arrange
those nodes, so it is mostly
so it's more the most visually clear.
You see? So, there's embedded algorithm
in Wolfram Language. In other words,
so this is what I'm saying is that
Wolfram Language has
any computer science, any algorithm.
If it If it is possible to condense it
into a single function,
then it is done in Wolfram Language.
That's why you have 7,000 functions,
okay?
So, it is the most uh powerful
expressive programming language
from the user point of view. You don't
have to worry about
how to do it, how to write the program,
like vast, you know, things are
building. Okay, so that's one of the uh
feature, graph plot.
Then you got more complicated layered
graph plot, tree plot. So, this is
focused on tree graphs.
So, then you got dendrogram. So, you
know, then you got um geography.
So, if you are a
geologist, you know, you often needs to
plot maps of cities or countries. So,
you can use that. So, you can actually
copy it. New York.
Uh
to do this, it requires you got this
entity thing, which actually queries the
website. So, because you need the
database for
the shape of New York. So, let's run it.
Shift enter.
City, New York, New York, United States.
City, Boston, Massachusetts, United
States. Entity.
You know, that that's a complicated
thing.
So, there there you go. So,
if you are doing weather, you can lay,
you know, weather rain color for
temperature and so on, you know. So,
this is all part of graphics
programming.
Now, the geography I don't do because,
you know, that that's not my thing. I do
geometric um
visualization. So, as you have seen on
my website, you know. So, I don't do
this, but anyway.
So, so So, that's part of the data
visualization, okay?
This part, data visualization, focus on
data. So, you have like
maybe massive, like Google, Facebook,
they have massive number of data. You
can use that. These are
focus on data visualization. Meaning
that the input is data, bunch of
numbers, okay?
Okay, now you go back.
Data manipulation and and analysis,
statistics and whatever. Then you got
visualization and graphics section,
okay? Let's cancel that.
Click. Okay. So, visualization and
graphics, data visualization
function visualization. So, all these
Again, all these are plots, but now
the input of the plot is a mathematical
function. So, let's show some example.
So, plot 3D. So, this is very common. If
you do math, you need to do these kind
of things. So, let's copy it.
So, I had, you know, I started to use
Wolfram language since 1994, 93. So, I
had a lot of fun. You know, you just
like
typing random equations and all
functions, it will plot it. And you can
So, you can see all kind of like weird
shape going on.
So, this are
So, you got like
50 functions that
takes a mathematical equation or
function
and and visualize it. For example, this
is for complex functions.
This is related to
what I was talking about about the
uh
the geometric inversions. So, this is
related, okay? This this
this um
this complex plot, okay? This This are
functions with complex numbers in it.
Okay, then
the So, there are so many. So, all these
are plot related. Then you can do stream
plot.
Okay, vector plot.
Vector plot is also very common in
physics.
You'll see them
you know, in
forces, you know, force
uh force or even in weather, you know,
like like the force movement, the magnet
magnets, magnetic fields, and so on,
vector plots. Okay, you feed it
you feed it a mathematical function
two functions of vectors, okay? So, all
these
are function visualization, okay? So,
that's part of the visualization. You
got data visualization, which is what we
showed before. You got function
visualization, you got charts and
information visualization, bar chart,
pie chart, okay? Those are most boring.
You got geographic visualization we
which we talked about. You can plot
several different type of
uh map um
how they say projection, okay? So,
because Earth is round, you cannot
represent it as a flat thing.
So, but if you represent Earth anywhere
on Earth as a flat thing, there's a
distortion. That is why you have variety
of projections. Okay, we we showed this
before, geo list plot.
And let's show geo bubble plot. I don't
even know what that is, geo bubble plot.
So, they plot circles
on top of
So, let me show you some projections.
So, do they have like
geographics data map maps and
cartography, okay?
Uh so, they you know, so like there's
like hundreds of functions.
This in the field of geography, so I'm
not even familiar with it.
So, one very extremely useful thing is
that if you are a scientist or engineer
or if you are a programmer,
you know,
then you look at Wolfram language, you
can just learn tremendous things and
interactively. You can learn all things
about geography, for example, here.
Things I don't know, like geo histogram.
So, what is geo histogram?
So, there is like explanation what they
are and you know,
um
Okay. So, let's go back. So, those are
visualizations and interactive actually,
it can also do interactive drawing, but
this is not a
um this is not a good
um
popular feature of Wolfram language.
Uh so,
then you got
symbolic and numerical compute
computation. This we talked about like
solving equations.
Uh,
mathematical constants pi, e, degree,
Euler-Mascheroni gamma, complex number,
real part, imaginary part, conjugate of
a complex number, absolute,
uh, get the degree of a complex number,
then sine, cosine, arc tan, then you got
special functions, which is very
advanced advanced mathematical
functions, gamma,
error function, Bessel J, Bessel K, Airy
function, the elliptical function,
Legendre function,
Chebyshev function, Hermite function.
You know, those are functions usually
defined by an integral.
So, it is
you you can't just it's not like
arithmetic, it's not like, um,
basic arithmetics. You cannot easy
compute it. It's like sine cosine, but
more
by an integral, okay? By infinite sum.
And you also got zeta function. Zeta
function is famous for one of the
million dollar prize,
um,
from a mathematical organization. If you
can solve this, you got the million
dollars.
The question asks if all zeros of the
zeta zeta function lies on the
lies on certain points, something like
that, okay? You can
search for million dollar prize zeta
function, you'll find lots of articles.
So, so this section is all advanced all
mathematical functions, factorial, GCD,
divisible, quotient,
modular arithmetics, Fibonacci,
Bernoulli numbers, Stirling numbers,
integer digits,
uh, then you got
random number, then you got square wave,
you know, a processing stuff.
Then you got number and precision matrix
matrices and linear algebra formula
manipulation, equation solving. So, this
is very advanced stuff.
Numerical stuff, find root of an
algebraic equation.
Uh and
asymptotic stuff, this differential
equation
uh
differential equation
parametric differential equation and you
know, like like these are
not easy, okay? Then you got more of
advanced stuff. So, they solve equations
and symbolically, too. So, not just
numerical solutions, but
they try to give you symbolic solutions
to equations, so.
Then calculus, you know, we all know
about calculus. That's what we learn in
school. Like the
uh basic mathematician's tool, calculus,
okay? Sum, product, difference,
difference quotient, integral
numerical integral and symbolic
integral, grad, div, curl.
Um
derivative, partial derivative
um
and integrate, that's symbolic
integration.
Implicit in in uh derivative, okay? So,
those are calculus.
Very basic. Then you got optimization.
So, this are for um okay, min max, min
max linear optimization, least square.
That's when you have bunch of data, but
you want to find a polynomial function
that approximate your data. So, you got
this least squares. Okay, so let's move
on. So,
So, that's the So, this is more than
this this is like
20 minutes introduction to from
language, okay? Now,
so we will do Advent of Code next day,
then.
Yeah, I'm pretty old, so
uh Julia. Yeah, Julia. I think Julia is
a great programming language.
I'm thinking of learning actually I was
going to learn F sharp, so but
it turns out Julia is more popular than
F sharp.
So, those are you know, F sharp and
Julia I'm planning to learn.
Uh so
Okay, so Kuma, did I answer your
question? Are you still here?
So, we already talked for
um
40 minutes. Is that right? So,
we not going to do Advent of Code. So,
we just introduction to from language,
then. Okay.
Uh
I love Wolfram language, so I've been
coding it for 30 years. That's my
favorite programming language.
Yes, for sure.
So, you got mathematical functions
solving equations. Then, you got machine
learning. Okay, so again, remember 7,000
functions building. So, how do I know?
You can find out by you can list all
functions building. So, you just type
enter.
So, it will return Actually, this is too
big. Okay, so let me magnify.
So, you can scroll down endless. Okay,
7,000 functions. Okay. But because now
the font is so large, so that um
so that you have to scroll a lot. Let's
shrink them.
Now, let's redo them.
So,
now do it. Now, it will show in two
columns, okay? So, you got 7,000 of
them. How do I know? You say
backslah backslash
length. Actually, can you do that? No,
okay. So,
uh so, you in fact, you do
I believe that's a function, okay?
That returns, you see, 10,000 actually,
10,000 symbols building symbols.
Uh
then
you do slash slash length.
Okay, so, you got
well, 100 109,000
building symbols, but that's not what
you want. You don't want arbitrary
symbols. You want the functions, okay?
So,
uh
so, how do you get the functions? So,
anyway, I am not going to go into it.
So, I
So, that's Wolfram Language, okay?
Um what I want to say, okay. So,
so, Wolfram Language for programmers,
then you go down. Uh print versions,
show version help, find function by
name. Yeah, information is is this is
what you want, okay?
Uh that will just show
functions, okay? Let's look at the
documentation.
Gives information about the expression
expression expression properties, okay?
So,
um
let's just try to run it.
Okay, I don't have it.
So, you need to copy that.
Paste it there. Yeah, shift enter.
Uh I don't want system. Okay, so because
it's showing lots of things and you
don't want the name there.
So, how many
items are there? One. No, that's not
what I want.
Uh,
well,
anyway, anyway, I'm not going to go into
it. Okay.
So,
Okay, so we are digressing into this.
So, lots of things. Let's So, here this
section you have machine learning.
This section you have all about strings
and text.
Uh, let's go to machine learning. So,
for example, you can machine learning
overview and neural networks, large
language models. Okay, so this is a hot
topic. Like right now we are everyone is
talking about this.
But but this are um,
this are large language model related,
but
let's not talk about that because neural
networks is the is is what actually what
they do, neural networks, those
uh, AI chatbots. They are
implemented using neural networks. So,
this are the functions about neural
network.
So, you can you can, you know, I'm not
too familiar with these um,
this neural network networks. So,
anyway, there's neural networks and then
you have machine learning. Neu- neural
network is one approach of one of the
machine learning. So, you machine
learning is more fundamental. So, you
got predict you so you give a bunch of
data
and give a bunch of criteria. You can
use this function to predict
like extract information from the data
to tell you
give you a prediction, okay? So you can
you have predict, you have classify, you
know, we demonstrated that before like
last year or so. You have speech to
text.
How does this work?
Okay, speech recognize. They even have a
speech recognition, but
you need to record audio to feed it. So
Yeah, you you need to first record audio
then feed the function. I'm not going to
record audio. So
Okay, so that that's kind of overview of
Wolfram language. You got all these and
sound and video. So this part is fun.
Sound and video. So you can play
You can play any sine wave. You can play
any sound wave, okay? So for example,
paste it. Shift enter.
Then it'll play. Now I hope it's not too
loud or
Can you hear it?
Um
It's it's playing a pure tone, okay? But
let's show some like more interesting um
Uh
so you need to So yeah, so here is more
interesting. Copy that.
Paste it.
Magnify.
Okay, then
shift enter to evaluate this sound wave.
So this is a sound wave generated by
sine nested sine, okay? Then you play
it.
>> Is it interesting?
Okay, so any any comments?
So we talked for
close to an hour.
Uh we didn't do Advent of Code. Well,
that's and well, it's kind of
disappointing because
Okay, so we going to do this Advent of
Code another day then, tomorrow.
Um let's continue with, you know,
like introduction to Wolfram Language,
okay?
So Wolfram Language go back to uh the
documentation center.
Graphs and networks we talked about.
Uh
higher mathematical computation. So
these are more advanced
mathematics. So you got polynomial
algebra.
Okay, very simple. Coefficient, get all
the coefficient, uh get all the
exponent, variables, expand, collect.
For example, um
you know, for example, let's say uh so
where is my Wolfram Language here?
So
x
uh wait
squared plus y divided by
by three by x
plus y
th- third power
then raise the whole thing
by five
five, okay? Wait, five. Okay, we miss we
we want some square roots. So, let's add
some square root.
Okay.
We
copy that expression, then control shift
and
to turn it into a type set
rendering. So, is that beautiful?
Then, we can evaluate it. For example,
here, move the cursor here, shift enter.
Oh, then you need to say expand. Okay,
so now we use the post fix notation
expand. Okay?
Shift enter.
Then, you get that.
And similar here. You So, you can say
slash slash
Fantastic. Is that fantastic? Fantastic
and beautiful.
Now, if you and you can copy this
to a text editor, then it will just
become
your normal
your normal syntax
in Python or in other languages.
You see? So,
or you can just copy this copy this and
uh
paste it there.
Shift enter. It returns the same thing.
So, this this this are the power of
Wolfram language.
This part is about
polynomial algebra. Okay.
So, once you expand it again, let me
demo the on-the-fly formatting feature.
You see how beautiful that is?
On-the-fly formatting of
of two-dimensional type set
mathematics
and they're done in real time.
You see? It never cut you know you see
it always cut things in a proper place.
So, compared to Python or Golang or
JavaScript, you need to like, "Oh, how
many indent you need? I need this line,
you know, you should have three. No, you
should have a tab instead." You know,
people argue. Silly.
Industrial programmers, the C, Java,
C++, they they do they they they waste
time.
So, this is the power of Wolfram
Language.
Okay, so so this part is then, you know,
once you expand, can you simplify? Yes,
of course. So, let's say copy the
previous output. Then you
simplify. It will return the
shortest expression to represent this,
okay?
You see, it so it simplifies into this
form.
Which is equivalent to to this.
But, you know, so you can also say
factor. Let's say
uh
uh you know, there's options to
simplify, but
we cannot guarantee it will be the form
you want because because of mathematics,
there's no way to
guarantee what you want.
Anyway.
So, that's
about polynomial polynomial quotient,
poly
polynomial GCD, greatest common
denominator polynomial reduce, and sub
polynomial eliminate a variable in
polynomial.
Uh resolve eliminate general
quantifiers, reduce you know, so very
advanced mathematics. Polynomial
algebra, okay? So, that's one section of
the higher mathematical computation.
Then you got linear algebra. Linear
algebra is simpler. Most of us, you
know, a lot of us are familiar. You
know, you got matrices, matrix, matrix
multiplication,
dimension, you got dot product, inverse
matrix, transpose of a matrix,
determinants.
This is a trace, find the trace of a
matrix. I forgot what trace is. You got
eigenvalues.
Okay, then you got linear solve, solving
systems of equations, solving a matrix,
find the inverse matrix, and so on.
Okay. So, that's matrix
and in linear and linear algebra. Then
you got tensor algebra. Now, I don't
know exactly what's tensor algebra, but
it looks like nested matrix. So, it's
like a matrix, but each element is
actually another matrix. So,
I don't know too much about these
tensors, okay.
Then you got real and complex analysis,
which we kind of
talked about, you know, that's kind of
basic
mathematics after you learned calculus.
Uh basically calculus, but
Oh, wait. You went through calculus.
Real and complex analysis, right? It's
part of calculus.
So, after you learn calculus, you you
add complex numbers, okay.
Then you got discrete calculus. So, this
is kind of new
um
This is like calculus, but discrete,
okay. So,
product, sum,
uh recurrence, table, whatever that is,
uh numeric solution
of recurrencies, okay. So,
let's see.
Then you got neural networks, okay.
That's included in higher mathematical
computation. We kind of showed before
net neural networks, okay.
Then you got uh
iterated maps and factors, okay. So,
nesting substitution system rule rule
plot iterated function Hilbert curve.
Okay, that's interesting.
Let's just show that. So, this is what
Hilbert curve looks like. That's one of
the great discovery in mathematics where
you started to have the issue of what
does dimension mean?
Because this curve
you know, looks like one-dimensional,
but if you go through to the limit, it's
actually two-dimensional. So, is it
one-dimensional or two-dimensional? Like
what How do you define dimension?
So, that
got mathematicians busy. Okay, Hilbert
curve. So, you know, let's copy that and
let's paste it because it's
fun.
Shift enter. In this case, you
you change the
line into a B-spline B-spline curve. So,
you got this more more kind of more
pleasant uh curve.
Okay, so you can increase the Hilbert
curve. Let's say six
recursion level seven, nested level
seven.
Then you got that.
Okay, I think So, let's go back. Then
Julia set plot. This is another very
interesting one. Let's just copy it and
plot it. Uh Julia plot. Fantastic.
That's one of the factors uh
of a uh
dynamical system kind of very deep
mathematics. Let's copy Let's plot this
one. This one is pretty.
Uh
Copy.
Paste.
Shift enter. So, this Julia set is a
set of complex numbers.
The definition is a a involved. So, you
have a basically a function involving
complex numbers.
Then
you put an initial value to a function.
Then the function returns a value.
Then you
take that value, you feed it back to the
function.
Okay? Then you come out another value.
Then you take that, feed it back to the
function. Repeat this.
Okay? Repeat this and then you see what
happens. You see whether it
the the the input goes move away to
infinity or what happens.
If it does move to infinity, then then
uh it's not in the set. If it does not
move to infinity,
then it's in the set. Then
the result is this. Something like that,
okay? I I I might be wrong in the
details.
So, you can look up Julia set on
Wikipedia.
Uh
Mandelbrot set, then you can
uh
then you can have the you know, the
correct definition. Okay?
So, this is uh this is the what Wolfram
language is, very fun and powerful.
So, question, have you tried Sage
SageMath?
Yes.
It's SageMath is one of the worst
possible. I tried to use it 10 years
ago. I can't even download, I can't even
find the download link, okay?
I mean, for you open source people, if
you want free things and you really want
open source, you believe in open source,
you can try Sage SageMath, okay? But
it's just like Linux.
You have to know you have to spend an
hour to figure out what configuration
you need and how do you do this? If that
doesn't work, it's a bug. You need to go
to Stack Overflow or today you ask AI,
"What's wrong with this?" Oh, you have a
different version. You need to update
this this part or
then you add you know, you talk to
people, ask them question things like
that. Okay, so it's
it it can do basics, you know, you can
it can probably SageMath. I don't know
if it by default it can plot Julia plot.
Maybe not, but maybe. Even if it does,
then the graph is going to be ugly. It's
not going to be as nice as Wolfram
Language, okay?
For example, this you can you can copy
or you can save it. Okay, for example,
you can
uh copy graphics and let's copy, okay?
Copy, then you go to
for example, my Twitter
then I can paste it, then I can say
Wolfram Language
Julia set
plot, okay? And then I can just paste
it.
Now, it's cut in two. I believe that's
because Twitter Twitter just show part
of it. Uh
very annoying.
Uh you copy the uh you know, there's so
there's a some issues, okay?
So anyway, so that's kind of um
Wolfram Language, okay? So you So So
SageMath
is not comparable to uh Wolfram Language
because Wolfram Language is proprietary.
They got a bunch of
great mathematicians, you know, coding
it for the past 30 years.
So if you think about a lot people have
this question because today people are
on things to be free.
Open source, we need open source.
So you got Python, you got Anaconda like
one Python package that includes
NumPy
uh all kind of Python functions doing
solve equations, linear algebra, you
know, 4 GB or something. And you also
got SageMath, which is trying to do all
like combine all open source mathematics
into one
one package.
Yeah, it's it's useful, but
if you want if you think about quality
and ease of use and coherence and the
save you time to look into bugs or what
whatever, it's nothing.
They they are a magnitude
below
Wolfram language, okay? If you ask my
opinion, that's what I tell you. In
fact, I know, you know, Wolf SageMath
I have an article on that, okay?
Info search, s e g
What is it?
s a g, right? s a What do we get? s a
SageMath computer, okay? s a g
SageMath. The story of SageMath, okay?
Kind of sad story. Because Sage SageMath
is created by this guy, a mathematician,
a professor, okay? Uh his name is
What's what's his name?
I forgot what's his name.
Um was
Wait, no.
Weinstein. Is it Weinstein? Anyway, he
wrote a paper in 2016
telling the story, kind of the sad
story, okay? So, this is a math math
professor,
okay?
Uh and he has this vision. Why don't we,
you know, open source is so great.
I want to create uh this open source
software that does does math. It's like
Mathematica.
It's like Wolfram language, but you
don't have to
you know, buy you know, you know, you
don't have to you know, Wolfram language
is corporate.
They just they want your money. We we
open source community, we can today we
can create a great open open source uh
software for doing
all advanced mathematics just like
Wolfram Research.
That's his vision.
So, he tried to do it.
There's all sort of obstacles.
First of all, no pay. Nobody is going to
pay you. You know, you people, like you
people, you know, I want to use I want
to open source free.
Do you pay him? Do you actually donate?
No.
People say they do, but actually 1
million download, like they get they
they get $1,000.
You know, no nobody
give a about open source. People
especially young people, they just want,
you know, they want things free.
And then when you have a bug, you don't
contribute you complain. You know,
SageMath is You should use Python
instead. Oh, Python is you know,
actually that library. No, I prefer the
other guy's library open open source.
You fight, you know, it's it's like what
I do, you know, I I I write a lot Emacs
this for free.
Do I get money? No.
Instead, I got lots of like complaints
or argument. You also get thanks. You
also get a lot of thanks. Thank you so
much Xao for
having created Xao like he's or or you
know,
you get that, you know, regularly, but
that doesn't pay.
You know, so I So, anyway, you got this
situation.
Then also
among mathematicians
Okay, there's this thing among
mathematicians, they don't care if you
write software.
Because among mathematicians,
they have this classic mentality.
If you, you know, mathematicians are
usually very, um,
it's very much a brain competition,
okay?
For for example, among us programmers,
like, you, you know,
among men, males, basically, we compete,
right? I can write this better. I know
this programming language more than you.
I know more programming language than
you. You don't know what you're talking
about. No, object-oriented programming,
it should be this way, you know. We
compete, right?
Among mathematicians, they also compete.
But they compete on on the on the brain,
on doing proofs, okay? So,
mathematicians,
they have this classic mentality,
in general, that they sneer
coders, programmers, okay? Like us,
okay?
I'm a amateur mathematician. I came from
a math background.
So, the professional mathematicians,
in general, a lot of them, okay, let's
say,
they don't
they don't consider programming a
like
very intellectual,
um,
thing.
They it's like beneath them, in a way,
okay?
If you are real mathematician,
you want to prove things. You want to
solve some, you know, prove prove
things.
Then nobody care if you write a program
to do it. That that they
usually that
Okay, so,
things are changing slowly, because
right now there's a lot of proof
systems, but usually they are not done
by
like traditional mathematicians, like
usually, okay?
So, things are changing slowly, but
anyway, you can read this story of
SageMath by this guy,
uh, PDF, okay? And he tells the story.
You know, there's lots of problems,
funding,
the university doesn't grant, you know,
this running into problems because they
they want mathematicians to do to do
proofs. They don't want this software.
They don't like appreciate it
that much.
You see, this mathematicians one are one
of those greatest
greatest mathematicians, okay?
And there are other math softwares, for
example,
Magma, okay?
I mean, there's nothing wrong with them.
But but like
when you do um
software there there there it is,
Stephen Wolfram.
Mag- Magma, Maple, Mathematica, and
MATLAB dominate, okay? He's talking he's
telling the story, okay?
Basically, when you do research, you you
don't you know, it's it's you have
and if you do open source, you don't get
you don't get money
uh to do stuff. So, he ran into lot
prob- lots of problems.
Uh I don't know how things are, but 10
years ago, I you know, 10 years ago when
I don't have Mathematica because
anyway,
for a period I don't have Mathematica.
So,
I was looking at uh SageMath. I haven't
been doing math for a long time. So, but
10 years ago I was thinking, "Oh,
SageMath, let's try it." And
the experience is very very bad. Like
you go to their website, their website
is like 20 years old
user interface.
They tell you that you need to go to
this mirror. They like depending on
which country you are,
find the nearest nearest mirror website
for the SageMath to download. Like
how the do I know what which one?
How do I know it's not a virus on the
other
uh website, you know. So, they have that
20 like 20 years old user interface.
Then
anyway.
So, the experience is not great, okay?
SageMath good for graph theory, okay?
Yeah, well, I don't know. So,
if you ask my opinion, I I
you know, so Wolfram language
why do I like them?
So, let me talk about this social issue,
okay?
Let's see how Let's Let's go to
SageMath. Let's see how have they
improved.
Okay, so
the website, okay, not too pretty, but
Okay, SageMath is a free open source
mathematics software system licensed
under the GPL. It builds on top of many
existing open source packages. NumPy,
SciPy, math Matplotlib,
SymPy, okay, that's from Python. Maxima,
it's a it's a classic from like Lisp
computer algebra system which went dead.
You know, but this is one of the
earliest from 19 80s, I believe.
Basically, Wolfram Stephen Wolfram was
using Maxima until he got tired of it,
find lots of bugs, and so he started,
you know, I'm just going to write my
own. So, that's like
Stephen Wolfram, okay?
So, and then Maxima became open source
like 10 or 20 years ago. Then
you know, be very lousy, basically. GAP
is for group theory. Flint, I don't
know. Then R is like statistic language
and many more, okay? So, it says uh uh
So, okay, how do I download?
Learn how to Okay, so you see
when you design a website, the number
thing people want is like just download.
Uh so, what is this? SageMath cell.
Sage on cocalc.
I don't know what that is. Install 10.8
release tool. Okay. Help documentation
feature tool. Okay.
Library. Let's see feature tool. Okay.
Okay, text text text text.
Okay, this
>> [laughter]
>> This I did in the 1990s, 1994.
You're going to demonstrate that as a
feature tool.
Th- This is
the year of our Lord, 2025.
SageMath feature tool. Oh, fantastic.
And this
this
this technology is from 1990s.
And let me show you my website.
Uh
this one here. Do I have it here? There
there. Okay. I did this in 1994.
And and SageMath 2025, they are putting
these graphics here as like a
feature tool.
Do you see Do you guys see what I'm
saying?
This is just I mean, this is not
not you well, I mean, it's not bad, but
it's like
This is 2025. We got AI chatbots. And
you set math SageMath is like showing
this as like a
feature tool.
Very lousy. That's lame.
So, you know, I haven't looked at this,
you know, so now I looked at it for 5
minutes. Do I Am I impressed? No.
Do I think, you know, when when I need
to code Wolfram language, uh algebra,
solving equations, am I going to
Do I think I'm going to be like, "Oh,
easy to do in SageMath.
Not likely.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, let's look at, you know, video
introduction by William Stein. Okay,
that's the guy's name. William Stein.
Quick start with SageMath. SageMath
graphics. Let's look that. I like I love
graphics, okay? This is this I've done
in 1994.
This is This is Taylor series, okay?
Showing the
series approximate approximation to a
function. Taylor series.
Okay. Well, okay.
Region plot, okay? Now, they got region
plot, okay? So, density plot, okay?
A field plot, okay?
Okay, the multi-age graph. Now, that's
more interesting, okay? This is not easy
to do.
Because
the main thing to figure out when you
want to
plot a arbitrary graph is that you need
to arrange the nodes
and the edges so that they
they can um
be easily understood. Because otherwise,
you you can they can be all jumbled
jumbled up.
So, you need to figure out the layout,
which
there are algorithms, but
but I I I I um I remember it's not
trivial to to to uh plot a arbitrary
graph, okay?
So, can you click on that? No. They use
this color.
This color, blue, usually means it's
clickable.
But, it's not clickable.
So, that's a web design issue.
So, what the
install. Okay, so, the SageMath plotting
and graphics. Am I impressed? Uh not
really. Okay, go back.
Uh SageMath in research, okay? What kind
of thing like mathematics can you do?
Let's see, plotting 2D and 3D.
Python search show.
Okay, do I need to turn on JavaScript?
Let's do.
No pictures.
What the is this?
Can you guys see what I'm saying?
Plotting.
Tutorial.
Two-dimensional plots.
Turn on JavaScript.
Refresh.
There's no pictures.
What the is this?
Does this looks like a promising
product? Impressive website.
Does it taste good?
No.
No pictures.
Oh, Jesus.
So, that is my opinion of SageMath. It's
not going anywhere, okay? It's not going
anywhere.
If you are, you know, if you
occasionally needs to do some plot,
yeah, sure.
But, it's just not, you know, it's not
it's not good.
Okay, I did this which of Maria Agnesi.
That's a famous curve,
which you can also find on my website.
Uh
which of Agnesi. Okay, that's like
interesting dramatic name.
The name
is which, that's because of a
mistranslation,
okay? Agnesi is a woman.
Is this a mistranslation? So, I did this
like in 1995.
30 years ago. Now, I'm getting old.
Uh and so do I have animation there? So
this this animation defines the curve.
So you can see
the curve is defined by having a circle
then have a vertical line.
Okay, and and the point on the South
Pole of the circle. So you sweep a line
um
yeah, you sweep a ray around
uh centered on the South point of the
circle.
Then
then that ray will intersect the line at
the top of the circle. Then you draw
a horizontal I mean vertical line at
that intersection. You Then you draw
another line that intersects at the
moving circle on the on the circle
moving point on the circle. Then that
intersection defines the curve, okay?
So this is like visualization. So I
wrote this program. Actually, I can show
you the code, you know, I updated like
last year.
It's on GitHub. Search for Saudi GitHub,
you'll find
uh plain curve plot, you'll find code to
plot this. I can show you now, but
it's not.
So I did this in 30 years ago and
and here
you know, they are showing you
animations, you know, the
Witch of Agnesi.
The Witch of Maria Agnesi.
Not good.
Not good, my friend. And Jesus and look
at look at the code. So this So this So
this is SageMath. Look at the code.
Too long.
You know, in my package to plot this is
like one line. Wait, uh yeah. Well,
okay, let's let's find it. Let's go to
it.
Wolfram function by name, okay, let's go
to let's go to new tab. Wolfram Language
for Programmers, let's go to Wolfram
Language my Wolfram Language homepage.
Then
Wolfram Language tutorial by video
Wolfram Language package by Xah Lee, so
go there. Oh, by the way, I want to show
you guys this one, okay? Well, I already
did show that one, okay? So
uh Wolfram Language package by Xah Lee,
go there.
So, there it is, plane curve generator
package. Open that.
So, this it is on GitHub, so you go to
GitHub.
You can download it, okay? You turn on
JavaScript.
Refresh.
Okay.
Uh so, last year I updated 2024, so you
can see gallery. So, all these are
animations.
They illustrate
the definitions of many curves and the
properties of a curve. All these are
animations. You can play them here
because
these are not GIF, okay? So, you can see
ellipses, ellipses, hypotrochoid
uh or spiral graph.
This parabola.
This is uh this is quadratrix of
Hippias, you know, animation. This this
is like this one is interesting, it's a
like
parametric polar plot, so you can
kind of see this in
sub submarine radar, you know, kind of
similar.
And this is showing the definition of
tangent
via geometric mechanic mechanism, okay?
The definition this so, you know, the um
yeah, the definition of uh uh
tangent, okay? Via geometry.
So, and do I have which of Agnesi?
I think so. It's um
Okay, so you you need to load it. So,
where is my um So, let's see Wolfram
Language actually GitHub.
So, get the
uh search for Wolfram, search for
animation.
Search for Wolfram code.
Um plane curve generator, that one,
okay? So, you got you got pictures, you
know,
you got all these pictures. So,
so that this one is called conchoid of
Nicomedes, okay?
So, do I have which of Agnesi?
I think so, but I forgot where. So,
let's see. Wait, that's illustration
visual
illustration of sine curve. It This
animation show how sine is defined. Sine
cosine, okay?
So, uh So, where is the the package,
okay? So, here's a package, search for
which. There it is, which.
Okay?
So, let's demonstrate that. So, uh
So, okay, so
So, you o- open this in Wolfram
Language, okay?
There it is.
Shift enter to evaluate it. Wait.
Just click run package, okay?
So, it's evaluated. Now, you
you you go to which of Agnesi,
okay? then you open uh
here.
Paste it.
So, what's a you don't know what's a
documentation, so question mark which of
Agnesi, so this is how you use it.
Which Okay, so it will you don't need
parameters, so let's just do it.
Which of Agnesi generator, so bracket
shift enter.
There it is.
Okay, so it generates a series of
images. Now, if you want an animation,
you just say uh
I believe it's a this animate
animation video animator
Uh just animate, okay? Let's try it.
Shift enter.
No.
Uh
wait, I forgot.
Uh let's see the notebook. Do we have uh
yeah, notebook. So, open the notebook,
so I have example here.
So, there you see the animation, okay?
List animate, that's what you want. So,
let's go back here, so you just have to
say
list animate, okay?
There it is.
Which of Agnesi.
You can
stop it, you can make it loop back and
forth and play.
Is that fantastic?
So, this is Wolfram language and the
code to generate this is here. Okay,
very
very short.
Okay, not not that short. So, let's copy
it.
Uh let's
copy copy it.
So, the code to generate this animation
is
paste
is this.
Okay. So, it's
it's this part.
50 lines.
Now, control shift N
to tie it into
uh typeset, so you can see this
fraction, but there's not not much uh
typeset math there, but you can see this
fraction
two-dimensional
typesetting and you can see this power
of two. So, you you see that little two
raised above.
Okay, so I think that's it for today.
So, in summary
let's go back to
SageMath. Uh not I you know, it's like
very uh disappoint it kind of
disappointing, you know, kind of
kind of disappointing, okay.
Um
Okay.
That's it for today. We go back we can
go back to yeah, Wolfram language we
talked about sound and sonification. Go
back to documentation center, sound and
video, and knowledge representation.
That means it can it can
you know, like often times today
academics, professors, they publish
their stuff
uh in PDF. So, first of all, you they
typeset using LaTeX, right? Then they
they output into PDF, Adobe PDF, right?
But Wolfram Language you use notebooks.
So, so this notebook technology is a
representation, for example, you can
have a title.
Just like HTML. So, you can you can go
here.
Uh Alt one.
title
Uh t i t l e, okay?
Um
Uh
demonstration. Why is it uh spelled
incorrect?
d e m o s t r a y d e m o s t r a
It's not wrong.
Oh, demo. We are missing a n. So, you
see, it does spell checking for you.
Does SageMath do that? Mm, I doubt.
Okay. The demonstration of
the
power
of Wolfram Language. Okay? That's like
we can have a title. Then you can have
by
And then you can, you know, you you
don't want that to be that big. You can,
you know, you can change the font size,
format. Uh I don't use this much. Okay.
So, font.
Uh I don't want to change font. I just
want to change font size.
Okay, something like that. Then you have
like university association date, you
know. Then you can have subsections
heading, you know.
Then you can have code sections,
whatever.
So-called, you know, people these days
called reproducible
programming.
So anyway, what I'm saying here is that
this Wolfram Notebook serves as a what
they say
knowledge representation technology,
like HTML,
like PDF.
You know, it's it's a format. It's a
knowledge representation. And in the
notebook, you can have
you can have interactive graphics.
And you can have
This is fun. Okay, this is beautiful.
Then you can have sound.
Okay, so we can have a section here.
Uh alt four for subsection
demo of sound.
Okay.
Generation. We can We can say that demo
of sound generation, okay? Then you save
this notebook
uh untitled, okay?
Demo untitled something.
Then you can publish it.
Then And then you got style sheets,
okay? So just like CSS. So you you can
reformat the entire notebook
in different styles, like depending on
this is educational situation, this is a
classroom, this is a online talk, or
this is a professional
um publication.
You need to submit it to some
mathematical journal. So let's see uh
format style.
No. that style sheet. Okay, style sheet.
Let's say article. So, this is a journal
article. Let's do it.
Okay? So, you can see they they changed
some of these
these heading styles. This is
journal article. So, let's try again.
Style sheet.
Uh book. Okay, the monograph. Let's try
monograph. Okay.
And you can also have the background the
become black and things like that. You
can also have like a print
style. So, if you want to print it like
report, slideshow,
utility,
uh Wolfram
styles, uh report, reference presenter
tools, aqua. Let's see what that do do.
Yeah, I don't I don't you know it aqua.
Okay, so that's
my introduction to from language, okay?
You got other features like time-related
computation, like this time series,
signal processing,
astron- astron-
astronomical
computation.
Okay, this astro angular separation, sun
position. Let's look at sun position,
okay? Can you plot it? Yeah, you can,
but then
I haven't used this much.
You get the information of sun position
of a given time, year,
and it will tell you the exact sun
position, okay? In terms of latitude and
longitude, I guess. Then, you can feed
it to a plot, so you can
you can plot sun path and so on.
Okay, so this is astronomy, astronomical
computation, uh
astro rise set,
March equinox conjunction,
perihelion, something about the
shadow of the sun or something, moon
phase date, okay. Solar time,
sidereal time,
time system convert, okay.
Lunar number, okay. So, astronomy
section, then you got time and time
series, okay. This is like um
kind of signal processing related.
I don't know much about.
Then you got signal Oh, yeah. So,
there's a data dedicated section for
signal processing. I spec- spectrogram,
let's see. Okay, so you can plot
spectrogram. Let's copy this. Let's see
what the is this.
So, I recommend it. So, you guys, I
recommend
um
Wolfram Language, download for free,
then you can play it in in the
in the terminal. It by default it shows,
you know, it has a terminal interface.
And
if you want a notebook, you can install
uh Jupiter. Jupiter Wolfram Language has
a Jupiter extension, so
you install the Wolfram engine for free,
then you install the Jupiter, which is
open-source provided by Wolfram, then
you can have these
uh graphics. Or
you just pay. You just pay Wolfram, you
know, I think it has uh
$200 a year, something.
Then you get this notebook and all these
features.
Okay.
So, let's see what does what the what
this do.
So, you got the audio. Oh, okay. So, you
got the audio and you want to find uh
So, we got these duplicated. We don't
want to multiply them, okay?
So you got audio file, then you want to
know the spectrogram.
Okay, so that's bird chirping.
Okay? Now, well, okay. Now, since we can
do this, why don't we try the
spectrogram on the uh
sine wave, okay? Let's paste that.
And we have a sine wave audio.
So I believe can can can they do does
this output the right format? Let's try,
okay?
Spectrogram.
Then
generate a sound wave. See what you get.
Wow!
Fantastic and beautiful.
Spectrogram
of a sound wave generated by nested
sine.
Okay, that's that.
So that's signal processing.
I don't I don't I don't actually know
the definition of spectro- spectrogram.
So you can, you know, you can actually
look up.
Let's see if it explains here.
Spectro- spectrogram plots the
spectrogram of list. Okay, so on so on.
So detailed spectrogram is also known as
time-frequency plot. Oh, okay.
That makes it clear. Time-frequency
plot. Okay, so you can study that.
Then you got geographic data and
computation. You got financial data like
stocks and, you know, you got social,
cultural, linguistic data. So I don't,
you know, I'm not too familiar with
these these. Then you can also do user
interface programming like buttons,
sliders. Uh then you can
uh notebook and document presentation
you can program the notebook. So,
you see this this Wolfram notebook you
are seeing including graphics and uh
animation and audio.
And 3D graphics, you can program it.
Okay, so because think of this like
HTML. So, in HTML
like like this page, you can program it,
right? You can have this pop-up menu.
You can also have sliders in HTML. Today
you you you know there's a lots of them
like so-called single web application.
So, and you use JavaScript to code it.
JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
Now, what about the Wolfram notebook?
Exactly the same.
Wolfram notebook So, if we save it, now
it's saved. Now, we can go to the
uh
uh where is it saved? I believe
document, okay. So, let's search for
demo.
Now, let's go to
desktop.
Okay, whe- where is this saved? Let's
say save as.
Uh desktop, okay. Demo untitled, so it's
in desktop.
Oh, refresh there. So, here's a
notebook. Right now it's uh
4 MB 4.8 MB. Open it. Okay. So, you can
see the notebook is just pure ASCII
text. Okay.
So, it's kind of like HTML. You have
particular format. Basically, it's like
Lisp. It's all nested thing, okay.
So, and uh images are
images are encoded uh by uh
I forgot what's the default um encoded
by
What's that called? ASCII 64 or
something. I forgot what's it called.
But anyway,
the point is the notebook is actually
just text.
And you can manipulate all this because
this
the entire notebook is actually just
Wolfram language. So you can use Wolfram
language to manipulate all this,
transform all this
uh
text. So for example, you can
systematically change all your
uh H1 header into H2 or
or move all graphics output to the
bottom
or you can start to say figure ones,
figure twos, you know, like enumerate
all your graphics output.
You can
programmatically
control the notebook or generate the
notebook, okay? Just like HTML and
JavaScript.
Okay, so that is this part.
Uh feature about notebook documents,
notebook format and styling, layout and
table, dynamic presentation,
mathematical typesetting. Okay, we
demonstrate this this mathematical
typesetting. This shows you how to
uh do it dynamically. But actually, you
just press control shift enter.
Okay, so then you can
uh internal the zation, web import and
export. Okay, that that relates to
you can export it to HTML. For example,
let's do, okay?
File,
um
save as. Actually, you can just do save
as. Save as
uh PDF. Let's let's save it as PDF or
you can save it as a XML, okay?
Uh let's say HTML webpage, okay? Do it.
Do it.
Okay, then you go to the file location,
refresh. So, you can see
this
HTML. Now, open
open this in uh wait, we already open in
browser.
Uh
okay, it's not showing up because
uh zero. Okay, so that's size zero.
Something went wrong.
Let's do it again.
Oh, it's still saving.
So, wait, is it done?
Refresh. Oh, there it is. So, now
go to now open this in uh
in Firefox. There it is.
You see, it converted the notebook into
HTML.
You see, is that fantastic?
Okay, that's it for today.
Uh
Does it have regular expression? Yes, of
course.
Does it have finite state automata? Yes,
of course.
Now, let me say again. So, anything
possible in computer science, any
algorithm,
most of them you never heard of because
each person can only
only know so much even if you are a
professional mathematician or computer
scientist.
But, any algorithm
that exist
that human knows,
if it's possible to represent it in some
way
in a programming language, it is there
in Wolfram language, okay? That is the
goal. That is in fact the the like like
what what is your philosophy for
creating Python? What is the philosophy
of for creating Julia? What is your
philosophy when you created HTML? Each
person has a story. Wolfram language
today is like any possible human
knowledge
if it is computable
they're going to try to have like a
representation of function or whatever
in it. So you So it represent the entire
like computational knowledge of
humanity. That is the
kind of the philosophy of the Wolfram
uh Stephen Wolfram guy, okay? I'm like
rephrasing it.
Okay, that's it. Thank you guys for
watching. Bye guys.
We shut down in 1 minute. I'm hungry. My
wife is home. I'm going to have food. Uh
wife noodles, fantastic. We demonstrate
quite a lot about Wolfram language
today. So this is uh
uh thank you for the question.
Kumar
Kumar, are you still here?
Uh
No, okay.
Okay, bye guys.