hi guys good morning or good afternoon
let's see how many people are coming so
today I'm going to cover Emacs Lisp I'm
going to teach a beginners tutorial
about Emacs beast programing Emacs Lisp
so nobody is here yet so let me just
type out what we're gonna do today so
this is my Emacs blog so create a new
gonna teach him actually geekiness now
this is assuming you never had
programmed Emacs Lisp before however I
assume you have some experience using
Emacs and you have some you had some
experience programming in other
languages you know JavaScript PHP or
Python Ruby whatever so I'm not going to
tell you what does a variable mean or
what does a function mean but so in
order to program Emacs lips I think I'm
going to wait for people to come out so
but meanwhile let's see I'm going to
Emacs this so yeah let's see if it's
people who is coming
oh hi hi there so I'm going to cover you
max this so let's begin so feel free to
ask questions in fact you know to ask
questions or to comment so you know I
know where I'm going you know you can
direct me to you know whether I'm too
slow or too fast oh you know any
questions just you know comment tapping
at having the box yield comment here so
I'm going to cover Emacs Lisp so and so
what the things are we gonna do we're
gonna I'm gonna show live example and
how to look up it is function talk and
how to evals code so hard I'm gonna do
an example first and how to evaluate
eMac this code you know you have to
evaluate it otherwise Emacs would not
know your function and how to look up
eMac this function documentation you
know you need to know how to open file
how to move cursor how to save file
right to file for example things like
that how to create a string things like
that so live example how to evaluate a
magnet's code how to look up eMac this
documentation and
so okay so hi guys so anyway so this is
my Emacs tutorial I mean this is my
Emacs blog so let's look in browser and
actually I'm actually hoping for some
people to come out you know say hi so
you know like we can get started because
I'm going to start to to code a Emacs
please example like a simple example
okay so so should I should I begin
okay so let's go back to so anyway I
have a Emacs this is my Emacs blog and I
have a Emacs Lisp tutorial it's a
written tutorial and I'm just going to
do a live demo so and in this box
email is basics basically that's all you
need to know and we are going to cover
some of these I'm going to show you Mac
these basics this we probably skipped
this I'm gonna show you and I'm gonna
show you how to evaluate talk look up
and oh yeah such documentation and the
last one is how to edit Emacs Lisp code
you know because eMac based code has a
lot of parentheses actually I want to
start okay yeah sounds good thank you
for coming okay so so is that better so
I think I'm going just to begin okay
let's go back to my browser let me put
my browser here and okay before we begin
you know I have a window here and and
this window on the left it shows every
command I ever type in Emacs like every
command like I press a key your you see
the backward word there and I press
another key you see the previous line so
at leasts all the commands I go image
including typing for example including
typing so you can you can see it says
self insert command you know 16 times
and also it shows the keys I'm using to
invoke those commands you know I'm using
a variable layout so the letters may
seem funny to you but you know that's
just a key I'm using and I'm also using
soft like keys which is a mod for key
binding mod so I'm not using standard
Emacs key bindings such as control and
stuff so you want the UNC control meta
in my keys almost never accept some like
here's control g4 cube or quit so I
think I'm going to begin so yeah let's
let's begin how do you get that oh that
that is very easy I actually I covered a
few times you use this mod let me show
you so I go to my Emacs directory my
Appa alpha directory and this is the mod
command locmaria
so you can download it it's on my Appa
so you can just download it and after
you download it just run these three
commands and and you'll get that it's
very useful so let's begin and again you
know
please to comment you know I every five
minutes I checked comment to see if I'm
going too fast too slow or what
questions you have oh we we are going to
cover Emacs Lisp for beginners so I'm
going to begin so let me show you an
example
Emacs list it's extremely it's actually
very simple
you know if you learn just a little bit
Emacs Lisp you know just understand it a
little bit it will be tremendously
helpful when you use Emacs because
everything is based on eMac B's so let
me give you example so let's say I want
to write function okay let me just do it
so the fun alright you I wanted to
define a function that
name it F and this is doc strain
something okay and we don't care about
that doc string and let's just say it
just say insert okay insert a string
something okay insert something that's
right okay now I have a function it's
that's that's a function now I evaluate
the code okay now it's done now I just
go here type meta X and press F enter
you see it just so it's a function you
know it's done so I can use this
function anywhere you know I just copy
this and you know copy disk I am putting
my Emacs in it and in any buffer
anywhere I can just call it for example
let's do it here MX f enter it just
inserts something now let's see if I
want to get some a bit more complex
let's say I want to do this insert that
and insert that and backward cha for
okay so what that mean what it what does
this means that you'll insert this
string and this P and P for paragraph in
HTML then you'll move kusa backward four
times so your place the cursor between
the P so let's evaluate it okay now
let's go through here let's call the
function MX f Enter you see now I can
now now I I have a pair graph showing
browser okay so so you can see this is
how you define a function in Emacs Lisp
and in fact in Emacs Lisp the language
everything is parenthesized basically so
you can see your parentheses it's all
nested parentheses
and the whole thing is one big
parentheses so that's the that's kind of
the first item we weigh you know the you
know just a basic example let's change
it to you out here so okay interactive
okay so now well what interactive okay
so I'm gonna explain that later but let
me just give you a quick quick
explanation like in other languages when
you define a function you just define a
function but in Emacs when you define a
function you see people needs to call
that function interactivity like for
example I cannot for example I want to
call Co the function f you know this is
function f we just defined let's say I
want to call that well you know you
don't you cannot you know you don't like
normally in normal languages you say f
you know parentheses and you want to
evaluate that but in eMac based view you
do it this way you know F without any
argument since this function doesn't
have any argument but you know you don't
you don't want to type the function name
like that so you know that's the small
so basically the interactive cross just
turns this function into a command so
that you can just call em X on it you
know for example let me show you an
example well anyway we are going too far
with that let's go back to amia I'm
going I'm gonna explain the basics first
but okay
let me just show you a quick example
let's say we define another function y
okay and let's say insert XYZ okay XC
okay
let's just say insert four okay so this
is the function we evaluated evaluated
and we can call it how do you call it
like that evaluate a void variable for
okay I made a mistake so this should be
a stream so evaluate this and now we
type this and we evaluate it and it says
four right but now you cannot do MX on
on the function why because it's not
it's not a command I mean it's just a
function to be used inside this code so
for example if I try meta X and I type Y
and I say yes wait wait let me delete
that well actually the Y is e then let's
try again
meta X Y the function is not there
because you see it shows young and young
pop and Young's rectangle and stuff
there is no function called code why
because if you don't have cancer if you
don't have the interactive cross there
then Emacs we are not considered it as a
interactive function meaning that when
you do MX you cannot you know you cannot
call the function the function is not
the command is simply it's not there so
anyway we are going a little bit ahead
of ourselves so let's go back to yeah
let me go back to the basics okay so so
so here is an example you how your
define function let's save this
so let's go back to you know X Bob so we
okay so that's an example then the next
one is how do you evaluate eMac this
code so you see we can write a function
here let's try another example
first first one two so we want to
evaluate that do it you can see the
answer three here okay so let's go back
here so we want to how to evaluate this
code and how to see the result in
messages buffer so whenever you if okay
so how do you evaluate this code so
here's how to give all this code there
are many ways but I'm going to show you
two of the most important ways so one of
them is
well them is this eve our last sex and
the other one is Eve our region these
two are the most important way to
evaluate email based code so let's go
back to the email based code where is it
okay so for example I just typed first
one two and look at the left panel you
you will see the command I'm calling so
I want to evaluate this line so I just
move the cursor to the right of the
closing parenthesis then meta x Eve our
last sex okay that's a command name now
now watch the left panel I'm gonna press
ENTER so enter now you see the left
panel we will say you know Eve our last
six that's the command we just code and
on the bottom on the right right side
you can see the answer is three there
now it also shows the pound sign Oh 3
and X 3 and stuff those are octo
notations and hexo notations and and key
press you see it shows that because in
eMac these numbers numbers are also
characters I mean they are the same data
type so number three is the ASCII code
three for the for the character that has
a ski as he called three and you know
but anyway just ignore it so the result
okay
whenever you okay so let's back up I'm
kind of okay so let's go back to my
email this
so yeah so so these are the two there
are many ways to evaluate a Emily's
expression now the most useful eval ask
says sex which is this one and the other
one very useful is Eva region the way
you use eval last six six is is to put
your cursor to the right of the last
closing parenthesis then you just call
the command by the way the command also
has a shortcut because otherwise you
know every time you want to evaluate
it's painful to type the whole thing so
the by default the shortcut is let's
look at it so describe key let's do this
scrape function eval last six okay so
this is a function and it tells you by T
for the key is this one because I'm
using sulfa keys so I have a bunch of
other keys that I use but in Emacs the
default key is control X control C so
let's copy that let's put it here
so that's how you evaluate that's that's
the most useful way the most frequently
used you know the most if you take
statistics of all the ways of evaluating
a function that is the most useful Eva
Eva last six remember just put your
cursor to the last parenthesis and ko it
you see you can you can see my on the
Left panel you can see I just caught
that command now the other way is Ivar
region let's say you have a bunch of
expression let's say I type this message
something now this function message is
just going to this is like Python or
other languages print so when you want
to print something you say message
so but now let's say I want to evaluate
both of these actually let's do this
say Q X equals to 3 then X let's say
that okay but what this does is I'm
going to set the variable X - 3 and here
I'm going to add X + 2 now I want to
evaluate both of these so now remember
you remember the the eval asked sex so
I'm going to I can do that that way so
look so look at the left panel so I'm
gonna call the command by key so I do it
so now it now it's done that expression
is evaluated now I move the cursor down
now look at the left panel again I'm
gonna call the command by key so eval
last six now you can see at the bottom
it says five you know that's how we do
it but if you have lots lots of lines
for example if you have lots of you know
you you want to eval the whole thing how
do you do that so so that way you know
suppose you have a bunch of expressions
you know one way one way is you know
youíve ouch one like give our last six
eval a sex you know that's true so so
you just select the whole thing and meta
X Eve our region enter so that's how you
do that so so so these are the two ways
the most frequently used ways to
evaluate emag this expression
yeah see X C so that's good so I'm going
to okay let's this go to talk about how
to evaluate based code now there are
several other ways so I'm going to let
me show you my email is tutorial so you
go to you go to practically practically
Lisp and you can see evaluate a list
code now on this page it tells you all
the ways to evaluate emag Lisp code so
they are like five or six ways you can
you know so there's evil last six evil
region you can evaluate the whole buffer
eval buffer or you can use load file if
you don't have the file open you know
you can just call meta X load file and
you know pick a file for example you can
use this to load your init file every
time you make a change then then there's
about if an eval expression I mean we
are not going to cover that you know we
the first two is most useful for you
know when you are starting out with him
agrees so that's how you evaluation now
I'm going to okay so far you know this
is how eMac this looks like and now you
know how to evaluate email based code
now I'm going to show oh oh and the
result now where do you see the result
let me show you that the result any any
time if eMac this expression output and
result it's going to show you message
buffer so let's switch to switch buffer
messages you can see you see those are
our previous outputs so for example
let's do this again
first three two one
so I'm going to evaluate this
and you see it shows six there you know
normally it will just show at the bottom
but once you move the cursor you know
the result is removed but you can always
see it by just switching to the buffer
messages so switch to buffer messages
now by the way there's a shortcut key to
just switch to message buffer and that
that is that well view Echo area
messages that's a function so normally
the key binding for for this function is
so yeah view echo area messages that's
the function that switches you to the
messages buffer it's basically
equivalent to just cause switch buffer
and type messages so by default the key
is CH e so that's a default key control
H E ok let's copy let's copy this
function name to my email Xbox so you
can see so this this is a function you
want to do okay so so what else okay so
the other important thing is how to look
up eMac this function dock so let's go
back to so how long have I been going 25
minutes ok so let's go back to the eMac
piece of code and you know I have so
there's an example but suppose you you
want to know you know so yeah so what
does interactive mean you can find out
you can find out by using this function
described function so let's try that
meta X hold on second let me show the
left panel so ok meta X describe
function ok then type the function name
ok interactive enter then you know Emacs
pops up this help buffer basically this
is the this is the inline documentation
for that function interactive now this
interactive function it's a little bit
complicated you know but don't worry
about it I mean it's very it's very it's
a little bit complicated basically the
purpose of this interactive function is
just to allow functions you know
to be used interactively you know like
in normal programming languages in
Python or JavaScript you you write
functions but they you know they are
code in the source code
I mean you don't call them interactively
but Emacs is different right because you
met IX to call some come out all the
time so so the interact the saw the
interactive thing here basically when a
function has that line it it makes your
function available as a command but more
than that more than that because like
for example in Python will you define a
function let's say the function will add
one to the argument so the function
takes one argument and will add one to
it now you can call that you know in a
code you know you just put parentheses
in the argument and you'll return a
result but in Emacs if it's a command
how do you you know give it how do you
give it the argument you know so it you
know it's kind of like that so inter so
the interactive thing here helps in that
way you can give it a now let's just
give the example actually this is more
advanced you know we don't I don't plan
to go into that but it's let's show
example so let's say this function ask
user what's your age okay if we were ask
user what's what is your age and then
you will add one to it so so age that's
the argument and the interactive here we
can say I think it's an edge what's your
age okay
and then we say number twos string two
number
ok I think that's it so what this
function does is you know it will ask
you for your age and you type a number
then you will add one to it and return
it so let's try it now remember how to
evaluate a function I just press a key
and that's eval as six now I'm going to
meet her X type F enter so you see the
prompt at the bottom what's your age
let's say I'm 18
okay 18 wait doesn't return okay why
does it not return I don't know so let's
look at the output buffer remember
remember before we said you know Emacs
always output in the message special so
let's look at that so we split pane
split the window go to message of
messages okay I don't see anything there
let's try it again
evaluate the function mehta X F enter
what's your age let's say 20 enter now
it doesn't return anything but okay so
let's let's fix that it's you know this
actually add a message so you will it
will print so this is this is how you
can do it
so the message function takes one or
more arguments the first argument is a
stream your age first one is so this is
the first argument it's a stream but
inside this stream whenever you have a
percentage sign percentage s means
stream then it will take the second
argument and faeo it up here so so what
this will do
now is will print your age first one is
something he will do that so let's try
that again evaluate the function now
meta X F enter what's your age
let's say I'm 30 oh there it is you see
you see the reso it says your age first
one is 31 okay so so far so good
I'm getting to I mean like I'm getting
too tight you know I'm not relaxed you
know when that happens you know I'm not
doing well so it's like I'm becoming
robotic and and you know so anyway so if
you have a question let me know and let
me know how am i doing okay so we showed
we show two examples so so what we want
to do let's see let's check if if we did
what we have covered so far
so examples yes we have examples how to
evaluate this code yes we know because
the answer is eva vast says Eva last six
and Evo region okay how to see the
result that's easy
the result is shown in the messages
buffer and in fact you can just call the
function view echo area messages to
switch to that buffer
okay and how to look up Elise function
talk that's easy to the answer is
described function so let's type it here
so okay so let's how to look at
okay so in a browser let's refresh so
yeah there it is described function okay
I think okay we have been talking for 30
minutes I think actually I covered the
most fundamental parts to in Emacs Lisp
programming and I'm going to answer that
question in a bit
but let's go back to the tutorial let's
go back to the Maya Mac this tutorial so
so we have actually covered the most
important parts of a Mac this you know
it may seem strange to you if you are
the first time you know programming
email is you know maybe it's tedious or
something but it's actually it's not I
mean just remember these are the most
fundamental the most important thing
about emag this you you must know
because if you look at someone coding
eMac this you know you will see the that
guy you know he will call these
functions every few minutes so you know
you know keep keep that in mind this
actually are the functions you have to
use all the time every few minutes the
function we just covered okay so let's
go back to my eMac this tutorial let's
look at some some of the other examples
and notes I'm going to explain you know
talk a little bit about that so the
first one eMac this basics you know we
have seen some examples but they are a
lot more for example so this page is
going to give you the basic syntax of
emag Lisp you know for example how do
you print it how do you print things now
we already covered some of these
so you know you call the messages the
function named message that's how you
print things and with arithmetics like
how do you do addition subtraction
multiplication and division and things
like that so that's you know that's that
and and it also covers a little bit
other things you know email is not a
strongly typed language it's not
statically typed but values do have
types but they are like I'm not going to
go into you know the types of email list
values but if you if you begin to learn
Emacs Lisp you know usually like you
don't have to worry about it you know
but basically you have you know integers
in float and string integers floats
string list okay yeah you do have a few
types but you know if you read this page
you know later you know you'll see but
let's let's keep let's start from here
so it covers you know converting flow to
integer string to number or number to
stream and true and false okay true and
false emag this does not have a boolean
data type so what happens is that it has
a value Neill just like ni O'Neill and
that is force now everything else is
true just just remember that so one is
true the number 0 is true a string is
true empty string is also true
everything is true except Neil that's
that's basically it and how do you do
equality testing and variables ok I mean
this some
I should cover it but I'm not sure I'm
gonna you know have time to cover these
I mean I mean I'm just giving your
intros I mean you can then you know read
about it if then yells and and loop okay
so so that's basically this page that's
what these page covers let's go back
then I'm going to then okay so over here
there's a bunch of emag base examples
for example you know we have shown some
examples like how do you do one first
one or how do you insert a string but on
this page you will see many useful and
practical examples of eMac this in you
know such that you can actually copy
them and put them in your email in it
and it will be useful so you have insert
text that we covered insert text around
region we have covered select con words
select online we have done we I mean
here is an example and and and and many
more examples okay I'm kind of getting
lost so yeah as ask me questions so you
know that gave me a direction like where
I'm going so how can i mod modify tabs
in spacing is easier okay that's one
question I use this function I created
from Stack Overflow answers do you know
what eyes oh yeah I can I can tell you
what I is okay let me let me copy that
and let me show you actually that
example is is right here eMac base P
examples you can see it's right here but
anyway let's go let's show you that
okay first of all let's let's make it so
hex hex region start and you are you
encode the region between start and
buffer so okay remember we said that the
interactive cross helps between the
functional use and interactive use now
interactive use the interactive function
takes main arguments it takes many
string arguments and when you have a are
it kind of take a code you know kind of
a coded string coded character so when
you have R that means that means that
means it will pass the beginning the the
beginning position of selection and end
position of a selection to your
functions argument okay so so let me
show you examples so let's do that again
it's
beginning at
okay that's all function can you tell
what it is going to do so let's evaluate
it you bow
okay now let's call it meta x FF enter
okay now let's go to the message buffer
you see it says region begins at 5:06
reach and ends at five four - that means
Y okay that takes some explanation
so in eMac this the cursor position
begins at zero at one so in a buffer you
always have a cursor around and the
cursor is measured the position of kusa
is measured as its position so when when
the cursor is at beginning of the buffer
the position is one okay now if I move
it here the position is - now how do you
know I mean how can you tell
let me show let's call the function
describe cha ok so meta X describe cha
enter so it will tell you that the
character at my current crucifix
position which is the D over there
you see the first line - of 5:41 that
means my cursor is at the position - of
the maximum of 541 because the current
buffer has 541 characters so so if I
move the cursor down here and I called
the describe char again you see now it's
a it's 93 of 541 so so remember that the
Kusa Musa has a position and okay so
that's one thing
what is when you have a selection for
example I make a selection right now you
see it there's a selection Emacs code a
region actually active region now when
you have a selection there is a
beginning position and end position and
frequently that's important when you
call America's commands because you want
to know where does a selection begin
where does it end maybe you want to
create a command that deletes the
selection
you know maybe so you want to know you
know where does the position you know
the selection beginning end and when you
want to do that this is helpful actually
you know this is this is going way a
little bit more advanced you know it
doesn't make sense to begin us but let
me just let me show you another way it's
much more simpler don't you know don't
don't don't study I mean don't go into
don't worry about interactive like don't
worry about it
all you do you know when you call you
the email is just put these interactive
parentheses no argument you know just
just do that just do that for the first
six months of coding eMac this don't
worry about that and I'm going to show
you for example alternative how do you
do that which is more simpler and easier
to understand so in this function we
want to print beginning and end
positions whose position okay
remove the argument we don't need it and
here we just want to change that region
beginning okay and here is region end
okay that's it
so now we evaluate this function
evaluate wait hold on a second let me
split the window and show the message
buffer so when we when we call the
function we can see the result value
away on the other panel so now evaluate
the function MX FF enter you see it says
region begins begins at you know 638 and
region ends at 7 737 this function does
exactly basically almost exactly like
that one except that one uses you know
the interactive thing interactive is
it's kind of harder to explain until you
know in order to explain it you have to
know more eMac this concept it's not
actually a function it's a you know it's
a it's a mark or let's see describe
function so anyway you can you know
here's an inline documentation describe
function you can read the details
so it says specify a way past passing
arguments for interactive use of
function yeah but anyway I recommend you
know don't worry about it for the first
for the first month you study eMac this
until you know until you actually
learned you know I have basics here
actually you know just read my to do it
covers everything you know really my
tutorial first first of all read this
box this box is the most important you
know just follow them one by one order
by you know one by one then you want to
get into you know kusa for example on
this one it talks about cruises and kusa
positions how do you get coastal
positions how do you find out what's a
you know total number of positions how
do you move kusa positions and how do
you search for some texts and so on so
basically you follow basically basically
I would recommend you just take take a
few hours
you know let's say 5 5 hours 3 or 3 or 5
hours to read the first box and you'll
be covered you know then you know where
you want to go you know what kind of
command
you want to learn you know there are
many type of eMac this coding you can
write that you know you first of all you
the most practical is to write some
helpful command when you are programming
or when you are writing whatever you're
doing in Emacs you can you know maybe
sometimes you want the way wouldn't it
wouldn't it be great if I just have this
function that will help me maybe insert
something or you know maybe insert
something depending on which file it is
or something like that you know whatever
so so text processing that's text
processing that's that's one thing to do
oh you can you know maybe you have a
language of your own you you want to
write a mod to syntax color it so that's
another task so there's many ways you
you can go you know in writing eMac this
for example tired
Shou all those are written in eMac this
but they are very diverse for example
and you know this is this is this is
tired you know it shows me the directory
and for example this is a shell you know
LS date you know and these two eMac
these mods and they are written in Emacs
Lisp but their nature is totally totally
different oh you can for example I go to
you know this file this file actually
I'm running sorry max lease mod so you
know so I am actually smart now this
smart what does it do it does syntax
coing
completion things like that you know
just like a programming language mod so
so you see you know the coloring and so
the tasks are different you know these
different ways depending on what you
want to do so so yeah I would recommend
you just read the first box then you
know you kind of know where you want to
go
Weis message redacted
okay any any else any other questions
okay about your other question how do
you how can I modify tabs and spacing
easier that I'm not sure what do you
mean by that I mean you could modify
tabs I mean that's kind of a Emacs
question you can okay how can I modify
tabs and spacing easier what do you mean
okay so there is a command that converts
tab to space but I don't I don't know
what you mean
modify you mean interactively or or do
you mean set up like configuration okay
so I've been talking for 15 minutes
you know this I'm not sure this is a
great tutorial today because I'm kind of
you know tight I mean kind of nervous I
used I use a major mod but but I feel
like it enforces four spaces oh so I
guess so that depends on what major mod
it is because each major mod so so Emacs
is not that consistent basically each
major mod you know each program e mod
they have their own way of setting up
the tabs and you know tabs in space it's
not you know it's not actually very
flexible and it's it has a lot of quirks
like almost each major mod is different
and you know Emacs provide eMac lists
provided some way to you know kind of an
engine so that you know if you write a
major mod you can rely on the engine and
you'll be consistent consistent but
actually it doesn't work that well but I
can you know I have a article here
practically Magli
and if you go down to actually just
search for tabs search for tab okay yeah
whitespace topic tab space indentation
setup you go here and you can and it
answers a lot of questions about tabs in
spaces I don't know if that's useful
yeah so if it enforces for spaces but
sometimes you want two spaces so I think
in that case which major mod is it you
have to actually deal with that
particular major mod because each major
Mari so if it's just different it's just
coded by you know whoever wrote that mod
you have to ask that guy I think it's
probably just a configuration issue I
mean you can oh but
well Emacs does have a setup that you
can use
well actually I'm not sure but anyway
yeah so I I don't know if there's a
definite answer to that question eMac
does have a way to set up so that the
tab will display you know in a fixed
number of space like you can set tabs to
display in a spaces a spaces or for
spaces but that's the displayed width of
the tab that's not actually you know
that's not related to when you press tab
key what will happen exactly I mean the
issue is fairly complicated you know
there's a lot confusions because when
you press the tab key there are several
things may happen one it will insert a
tab or it will insert several spaces now
when you when you insert a tab
you know tab is a visible ASCII
character you know it's one of the
control characters when you have a tab
then how what which it shows is also
differs in editors and and you can set
you by default in Emacs it's eight
spaces so anyways yeah so you know the
indentation setup is always a little bit
complex and it's not satisfactory in
Emacs so you know you have to look
around
okay any more questions I think that's
it for today has asked more questions
and that's it for today what did I have
for dinner I had oh I had pizza
I bought pizza a safe way and I had
pizza and I actually I'm kind of four so
so anyway thank you guys for coming
and so that was eMac this I hope you
know I hope that's helpful maybe we'll
do another ones another day it's kind of
a big topic and it's you know maybe
maybe the next one will be better so
thanks for coming by