hello I'm going to make a recording
today of my Emacs workflow so this is
going to be a random ish recording it
just shows you my Emacs work workflow so
there is something I want to do and I'm
gonna show you that that first let's go
to I want to turn on my key loggers so
let's just turn off so I mean the point
here is that I'm going to walk in so you
can see my workflow I mean that that's a
point this is not a tutorial but they
are not many workflow kind of videos so
that I mean workflow is is good to watch
if it's nice to watch if you have Emacs
co-workers but if you don't have Emacs
co-workers then you can see that's a
point of the workflow you know you can
see how I access directories rename
files you know just in general like
switch projects and stuff so first of
all I'm going to turn on the keylogger
so I'm gonna call list so I have this
package it's in in my local directory so
I believe this is a package so let's run
it I just I just have our buffered it so
okay so what how do I turn it on so they
okay here is a command I think okay so
that's incorrect so hey so what's going
on
copy that
in the couette okay code without the
period okay so that's it then you have
to turn it on I mean let's see okay you
have to yeah okay this this is only for
local wait why is it not showing okay so
I'm learning into problems but that that
is the point I have tried to do a video
before of workflow and usually what
happens instead you know something like
I like to demonstrate for you know I
think might take just one minute but it
ends up taking ten minutes because all
the little problems you have to go
through but that's real life I mean
that's how things are when you actually
work on things so right now I just want
to turn on this this package which lets
you see all the commands any commands I
call it will show up in real time but
okay so this is what's going on so okay
let's go here I switch buffer so this is
my message buffer so it says it's not a
valid command name so did I load it and
try it again okay so so now it's working
you see
if it's working then if I delete some
things you should show so okay I
remember there's issues so that's this
is how I get to my init file so let's
please match in lines okay Braga your
tear no okay I just have to think so
there are two files here Rock command
now this is the whole package I think
let's see because I remember there's a
newer version like every time I I tried
to turn this on I always have some
problems the old versions got problems
the new versions got problems so the the
issue I remember is that to see the log
buffer oh I don't have had don't have it
on so of course how idiotic so MWe
yeah because I don't have the mod on
that's why why ruin this command it's
trying to show that log buffer but but
the mod is not even sorry sorry hold on
okay I'm back
so to see the log buffer do that and you
need to so this is a command - Tonino
yes okay now I know I show the rock
buffer yes yes there it is
so now is this global no it's not global
yeah so that you see it only works for
that buffer so this is really annoying
so it's it's there is a global command I
remember gob
gia will be know okay so like so
brainless quacking the keys doesn't look
I have to actually think about it and
can read stuff okay so this ion can be
used to eMac them all the way keep
keystrokes get logged into a designated
buffer to enable use that while keyboard
commands
I already enabled it to see the rock
buffer coded command but GL obal but
where is the okay let me turn the new
window so I mean a new frame Emacs frame
which to me is just a new window and so
a new window I want to switch to the log
buffer here okay and yeah lots of
problems with this this package because
you see it creates a buffer here called
command lock but actually actually that
the buffer is hidden so you cannot even
see it in the you cannot switch to it
so it's extremely idiotic and right now
my problem is I want to turn it on
globally I remember I struggle before
with it okay so what is the key so to be
sure it's working in this buffer but
it's not working in this buffer so it's
not working globally so
open command lock
that
okay
so cue it do you want to save no can we
do that again okay so you can instead of
switching to the buffer you can always
just call that command to show it but
but I need to enable it for all of us
and I remember I had this problem before
and there's a solution this I don't get
me used to telling you Maxine okay so
maybe the old write this I think yeah
this is the old version there's a new
version I think the old version does not
support global enable globally so let's
go to in this case let's just go to my
Emacs directory I don't wanna show
actually so this is the way I navigate
to to my Emacs directory then you won't
go to L alpha oh how high is the
packages then just search for log ok so
this is a new version that's the version
I want to use I try to avoid actually I
wanted to write my own but a few years
ago because because this shouldn't be
too hard all you have to do is the the
key thing to lock command is let me show
you there's a variable called this
command and if you see the documentation
you can see its value is okay so so the
documentation this command now being
executed basically this is a variable
and the value of that variable is
whatever the command you just called so
you can you can just for example let's
see message yes
you know you just this suppose this is
your list code so you just evaluate this
line and it's my messages okay well it
shows you see you just evaluate that
line and you print it to the message
buffer and it's printed here so that
means the command I'd last digest code
is Eve our last six that's exactly what
it is because I just call that command
to evaluate this line so so I mean
that's the essence I mean and and
there's also there's some complexities
there's also this there's also this
variable B oh this command this is like
this command except that command should
never modify it the reason for this is
that some command when you call it for
example some command they are kind of
like wrappers so when you call it you
don't want that command to be you know
the last command you want actually you
know whatever it wraps to or alias to to
be the real thing yeah you know that
situation turns up so there's also this
one but basically this is the variable
you want to to write this log command in
real time so I try to write it a few
years ago and have to ten minutes I run
into some problems but problems about
something about printing it out to the
Burford I forgot so but I never
continued so that's why so anyway it's
good just go back to turn this song so
yeah so this this is a newer version so
originally there's an old version
written by Michael Weber very very old
tooth from 2004 then other people
divided but okay so this new version so
okay now what we want to do is we want
to restart Emacs say both entitled no
that's my master then so so okay let's
go back to so I'm using a Mac so on the
Mac that's how I start my Emacs from the
terminal
I started my Emacs few times a day
because it's actually the most efficient
way to cream everything I mean
theoretically anyway let's let's move on
with this so okay I want to restart my
Emacs because well because because I've
already loaded the old one and if I load
the new one it's going to have problems
because I know that because I tried it
before you know I loaded the old one and
tried a new one and something went wrong
so I just restarted so now I have this
I just restarted now I give a buffer so
I have this buffer content evaluated and
now I just follow the instructions
to enable do that okay so now let's call
that command now it's enabled wait Globo
let's see there's
define we're in the mud
okay I think that's the one so wait
second so let me open a new one put it
there and and how do I show show the log
okay - yeah no use that to see log
buffer qualities right so I'm just gonna
call that so there it is close that wait
so reopen it yeah what yeah so this
is another annoying thing it won't let
me use my keys or my keys doesn't work
now in this buffer so I cannot like for
example right now I'm trying to switch
to my previous buffer and stuff and it
won't let me say so window is strongly
dedicated to this before
you know what in my opinion when you
write Emacs stuff you don't want to
restrict users freedoms shall we say
because you know whatever Emacs
you know user have their keys or
whatever you don't want to restrict it
so you want things to be everything to
be generic as possible so for example
this is a buffer so in this case it's a
special buffer because it doesn't you
can use your code or command you can but
this and like it doesn't let you switch
out you know change keys and stuff I
mean your keys doesn't work so you see
because it's specially and and if you
look at the buffer list log you see it's
not even there it's not there this one
is the directory you see so it's a
special hidden buffer the only way to
turn it on is to
is to call these open command log buffer
so that's not good because normally if
you are you know you are habituated you
know how to switch buffers you know you
know the Emacs system so you thought oh
this a buffer name this is the name
command log you can just switch to it
and command log and then but you don't
see it because it's made to be hidden so
I don't like those kind of things so
that that's why I'm you know I have a
strong desire to create my own but
anyway here you know it's already there
so let's so right now I have it turned
out only for this buffer you see only
like when you might click somewhere you
know go back go forward but doesn't work
here because it's designed so that
there's also enable globally so let's
it's what was command ok this this is a
command so first of all I decide is
about it and now I want to enable it
globally so now it should you see
yeah okay go back here you see now it's
good so so that's good
so finally fine finally so now I can
close that buffer finally we have it on
so what I want to do is go to my Emacs
blog so this is my Emacs blog I just
wrote a new item today September night
18th so Emacs may ask ok many people ask
for Q align behavior in self like ease
and it's being added a few months ago so
but some people didn't know so so now
for example I my cruiser is here I can
press a key and Q line you see you see
that commercials here
try it again and do I move my cursor
here let's say here and do it you see so
the key is space i space ice actually
i'm using borax so unquote akibo is
space G when you are in command mod okay
so let's put it back so but actually
what I want to do so this is my new blog
but what I want actually want to do is
to so I have this command so I press a
key and this is blog dot XML this is my
RSS feed so I press a key and this feet
gets added to here you see that part so
let's close this don't save you see so
this is my new blog section section
section you can see now but I need to
add to the ioss so I just call this
command and it's here it's a new item
and so okay so okay but what what is it
you want to do so but let me show you
you see this this entry doesn't have a
heading like this is a heading
Emacs delete selection modesty for you
sometimes I do have a heading so for
example let's to keyline behavior and if
not keys okay
let's modify psyches you can do Caroline
yeah
that way it's small readable to people
so now I added a heading and I want to
add to the RSS feed you see now the
title is automatically filled and and
the heading is added here h3 but
actually I don't want this part to be
there because I noticed that well it's
kind of redundant because there's
already the title but I added that
because because ok let's save it it's
saved save this and view it in browser
ok
you can view browser so here you see the
header becomes bold that's why I added
it because well sometimes you know you
click on that and your browser doesn't
have eyes as readers or something you
turn it off these headings helps you to
see you know which one is the new one
otherwise it's all just you know text
but but however I noticed that in in in
in some readers if you have the heading
it repeats for example for example from
you know this is Emacs have RSS
aggregator it repeats twice you know
this part is the title and this part is
the my h3 heading so you know I thought
let's just let's remove that ok so so
let's do that
so my this this code you see the command
I call to do that is
the command echo is stomach
Adam entry which is somewhere they are
okay another problem it won't let me
strike any any anyway yeah I was saying
this is another problem with this
special buffer because right now I want
to go here I want to select this line
and normally my key is just this key
won't let me do it but instead I have to
okay maybe what happened you said my
command I try to select a line it
actually works but because it's keep
adding stuff so it just removes it right
away so anyway this is a command I want
to call so this is a trick you know this
is a trick to save you time in opening
files like whenever you have a command
so this this is the command and this is
a key I have for it did he Spacey and so
whenever you know a key or a command
name you can jump to the file easy
without using bookmarks bookmarks and
stuff and so that's how I jump to all my
email Emacs Lisp code files so for
example I just describe key and this is
a one press tab and there it is
so I'm now I'm ready to modify this this
command so in order to region h3 so
there it is
this is where I had the h3 so if if
string match at age three then let's see
okay this is the title text we don't
want to do the title text okay so there
is only one instance of h3 here so let's
search for title text
okay so I see what's going on it's
problematic the what happened inside if
I call this command it does not actually
try to add this h3 rather what happens
is that it just grabs between the
sections between the sections and you
know ignore the date line and then
whatever is in between is just it's just
get inserted so if I want to if I don't
want this h3 line then then I have to
actually write code I don't want to
write code let's let it be for now well
you know since I'm doing a video why not
you know he'll be disappointing if I
don't okay so open last one so let's try
to okay so it's gonna take a while
though it's going into maybe ten minutes
where is it make an atom entry so make a
backup first Naruto region so okay input
string coverage you know going attribute
okay so
and somewhere here so input string with
the texts
I'm trying to find hints of atom entry
title text new item ID okay input string
is the part we want ok this heart is ok
but for substring no properties right
you see the code here it's trying to
find the beginning of section and the
end of a section and set it to p1 and p2
that's the beginning and end positions
then you grab them by buffer substring
no properties then here we do some
transformation on the input string
because in Excel in if you want valid
XML then you you need to you know
there's some tags that's not allowed
in video and and other things you know
it's it's fairly complicated at the web
technology so anyway so so what I want
to do is insert input string
let's see he said oh wow
okay so let's just do that good shot go
chop point me okay
and such forward h3 I'm just gonna write
a simple one no boundary and no arrow
yes so no boundary yes no arrow
yes okay wait bound me oh no arrow true
count you know
so such forward then line beginning line
beginning position wait beginning of
line that's what I want
yes C code got the beginning of line and
actually just te the whole I search for
word and
okay not Caroline Caroline is the
command for it's an MX command it's a
high level command underneath it's
fairly complicated actually you can see
you know it's doing a bunch of things so
usually it's best to not use those when
in Emacs list this code you want to use
something simple so for example let's do
this DVD Region position one and this
beginning flying beginning position
right my in position that's right
so that does what I want you know it
just delete that that line you know we
make some assumptions like we assume h3
and is is on line by itself which may
not be the case but usually it is okay
it's a case for my blog anyway so that
that should be a 10-person so let's
press a button and reform and everything
so that's it and let's give our defense
so this command is evaluated so let's
close a buffer save it
it's trial again there it is great so
you see we I don't have the h3 anymore
but there's another problem
easy normally the title is automatically
added it from the h3 but now it's gone
because okay close this don't save open
last open last no it's not there because
because you remove it behind removed it
so what happened so I should do this
so get the title text first then you do
the transform transform on an input
string so that's good
Evo it cross say cross try again yeah
yeah okay yeah that's it that's it
I'm taking already what - our something
like that so so that's that's good
says that's what I want and now what I
have to do is just upload it and it's
gonna upload okay then so
Bogg yes well there there it is there it
is this this one yeah so without the
header lines it's it's hard to read if
you actually want to read raw XML files
but so I don't know I may revert it back
in in the future so anyway so this this
is this is going to be it for this video
thank you for watching and I I'm a do
more I'm thinking of doing more videos
like you know one video every two days
something like that so the idea is that
you know it's a good thing to do videos
regularly and you know I can be chatty
and any topics people are interested you
know yeah you know so yeah you know
whatever discussion comes up you know
like Emacs
on Twitter or on reddit and because I
make every time I try to make a video I
tried to think have a master plan and
you know to do a perfect one like you
Mak this tutorial or stuff like his
tutorial and it always ends up not very
good not very good so so anyway I'll
start to do these chatty videos I hope
so regularly so so anyway thank you so
if you like it - - you know a thumbs up
or something I'm gonna put this on
youtube
yeah because otherwise I find that you
know I do I write a lot and you know ten
people read it and then it's disgusting
you know discouraging and you know
what's the point so thank you see you
then