hello guys welcome to another episode of
c talk show so ad Advent of code
2024 day two let's begin
coding okay let's see maybe we can do it
fast uh video check video am I alive yes
alive and audio check Advent of code
number
two wam language
okay we do we have wam language ready
new uh new notepad shift enter to
evaluate it and uh this needs to go here
and uh
magnify okay and this needs to go here
okay so can you see it yes day two okay
let's let me try to do this fast maybe
maybe 20 minutes or 30 there are people
people who finish it in like 2
minutes
uh okay so the input here is the
input what is
this okay let's start
here w f
language okay
code uh
okay so that there it
is uh the usual data in consider many
reports one report one report per line
each report is a list of numbers called
called levels that are separated by
space okay this example data contains
six reports six rows each containing
five levels okay so rowes and the levels
the engineers are trying to figure out
which reports are safe okay The Rednosed
reactor safety system can only tolerate
levels that are neither either gradually
increasing or gradually decreasing so a
report only counts a safe if both of the
following are true the levels are either
all increasing or or or decreasing okay
any two adjacent levels differ by at
least one and at and at most three okay
so they need to be gradual and uh okay
and all increasing or or decrease okay
in this example above the report can be
found uh 76 421 check safe because 76
421 all decreasing and no more than a
gap of three
okay yeah so second 1 278
9 7 1 278 9 no no because there's a gap
of
four okay
97621 unsafe because 62 is a decrease of
four okay yeah I get it okay so in this
example two reports are save okay number
one and and uh the last row analyze the
usual data from the engineers how many
reports are save oh
easy okay so first of all you
uh X2 you want to uh converted into a
matrix okay
so
uh
string
split okay
x one okay let's say x
input so evaluated
now it
becomes uh okay so yeah so okay so it
becomes one thing um
then what uh then what you want to do is
all these are actually strings so what
you want to do is you want to
um okay two expression that converts
string to actual numbers okay
so two
expression add add is the prefix
notation for the square brackets so
evaluate
that we get the same thing then apply
another function in front of it
um which we partition the list into two
elements okay so we can do function
partition partition take takes two
argument the first argument is the list
the second argument is uh how many rows
are there one two
three uh six uh five
okay okay
minute there we there we have it 76 421
764 check okay once you got that uh so
for each one you want to check if they
are ordered okay
uh there is
a there it is order Q let's look up the
documentation wam language the most
advanced programming language on
Earth okay it gives true if all the
elements are can canonical order okay so
let's
see uh so we can do a test you know
ordered that if that's true or not
Force well that's because they are
reverse order so use the ordering
function P to
determine okay well you
can you know you can do it
twice you know so if you run this this
will be
true right so you see so you can you
know so you can do a all so let's show
okay so
or either
that or
that okay true you see so but all has a
syntactical shortcuts that that would be
uh that would be um vertical bar
vertical bar so let's let me show you
okay syntactical shortcut fantastic
so but if you use this a lot then wam
language becomes hard to understand uh
but but uh what where is my comment oh
the W language comment there's only one
comment block comment like that okay so
if you run this
all uh failed
because uh yeah okay so you need
actually the because of the space you
need to to have the operator there so so
all we'll do it check the row is ordered
okay so now you just want to know what
you want to know uh okay you you want to
know the order but the other thing you
want to know is is if the difference is
in the list is um no more than
three so if it's three does it
work let see the uh
at most three so when the difference is
three is still
okay okay
so let's see if there's a function that
um compute the differences of adjacent
numbers so
check documentation difference is least
give the successive difference that's
that's what we want uh let's
see done
it fantastic and uh you want the
absolute value
okay so you want to apply absolute value
to each one of them and you want to make
sure they are less they are less than
three less than four okay um less or
equals to three okay so you apply a
function so absolute
value map okay so you
map the absolute value to this
thing to the to the differences um
actually let's let's let's
um let's put the output here so we kind
of have some
idea okay you know here's a whole code
very simple okay now we're going to to
do the apply the absolute value to all
of them so you got all positive that's
right then you just um make
sure all of them are less or equals to
three so
yeah so
um so you can
map you want to make sure all of them
are less or equals
to uh two three so you you you can do
less than four because they we know they
are all
integers implicitly
so so you can you can can map you can
map um uh there other ways so let's see
uh yeah you want to make sure all of
them is uh okay anyway let's just do the
dumb way because the you know I got
tired of the Advent of code because
they don't care about efficiency they
don't care about the like in other words
if you spend real time
if you are a master of computer science
you create the greatest code it doesn't
matter
because because
the you know or it cares is the answer
it yeah lots of issues so so let's just
uh do the brandless way okay so apply a
function and to each one of them and you
want to make sure is uh less
than I believe yeah less than
less than x
uh okay so X less than less than what
number uh less than
four okay you'll give you a bunch of
true and
false uh no wrong wait oh yeah okay so
the list it should be
here
okay okay so let's uh what is this uh
less than code with two arcs one
argument is
expected oh yeah that's right uh
what
what look at less than less then takes
one argument operator form that
yields oh okay so operator
form e x less than y okay so this is new
2015 2015 is a year I have I was not uh
keeping up to date with wolam language
so they added this new function so less
than text just one
argument um in that case you don't need
to Define your function you just say
less
than you see see fantastic and all you
have to do is just apply
and apply the end end function to all of
the uh them so that this a shortcut yeah
you
know uh wait a minute uh oh yeah uh okay
wait so yeah so it when this pass that
means this row pass okay so now you just
need to apply this to every row okay
okay okay so let's I guess uh clean up
the uh something clean up the code uh
let's start a new
one so let's start a new one so let's
just make them like one shot uh remove
the um the intermediate
so this is
all um
or so
what so you need
map map
to the
X2 and you map a function to it and what
does this function do the function first
of all needs to apply ordered
okay the function first of all needs to
apply let's let's put the let's make it
functional I
mean let's not use a shortcut okay
so and this is just
x x
so simple
so if one of them is older that means
it's increasing or decreasing it pass so
then you need an
end okay so and so first of all one they
must be increasing or or decreasing the
other thing you need to do is to check
um so order we don't care uh you need to
check the difference and this actually
this line
okay so that so basically what this does
is you map you find the differences the
absolute value of it and all of them
each one of them is less than four you
map to it then you just
say you got bunch of true and false then
you apply and you map the you apply n to
all
them so if either one of these condition
is
true uh both of them must be true then
you got it okay so that is a function so
the
expression we don't need so that is a
function map to the list and you don't
need that
okay uh wait so what you get then you
got a bunch of true and false I think
yeah so true false false false true true
okay uh in this example exle only how
many are true one two so I got it
wrong so the difference so they are not
just less than four but also not zero
so it it should
[Music]
be wait let me see less than four and
not z0 okay yeah okay not zero so so uh
not less than four and
uh actually you you need a function
okay yeah let's do a function so
function and uh this expression will
be let's just
say
four less or equal four
actually X here and uh greater
than zero okay now that's clear run
it true false uh what true uh this
got another one
wrong
what what is what is this so let's see
move from
language shift enter okay so let's say
if this is three shift enter
true if this is zero shift enter
Force ah where is it
true Force
true true Force
true true Force true so what's wrong
with this
97621 so that's
decreasing oh not it's it's not less
okay it's less than equals to three okay
run it
again there it is seems right and uh
then all we have to do is apply and
across okay so apply and across like
before uh by the way this add add sign
that means so when you when that's a
syntactical shortcut when you have f f
two symbols F add at then another symbol
that
means uh that means this okay
uh that means um yeah that means this
exactly okay just syntactical shortcut
uh you know you can I can show
you
um full form bracket paste shift
enter uh well yeah that where does The X
come from um this is wrong
uh this x needs to
be oh yeah so it needs to be um
list a b c
okay uh shift enter there it
is uh actually so what you let me show
you again okay actually you need what
you need to do is you need to
H let's do it here so I'm trying to show
you how this syntax is equivalent to
that so what you do is you for
form and hold hold is important because
otherwise that expression gets evaluated
so what you want to do is
this okay so you see apply FX so that
apply is similar to functional languages
apply like the in emac list it just turn
the list items feed them into the
function okay now in language because
it's
symbolic term rewriting system so anyway
so uh so so let's let's remove that
let's put it here so let's like
extra okay back to the code close that
back to the code okay so run
it uh wait so you don't want to end you
actually you want to count so okay yeah
so
count you want to count how many are
true so okay so you let's write a
function uh then then use the building
function count count X and uh you want
to count how many items are true so this
is a function so now a function now you
just apply the prefix notation apply to
this this thing
okay so run
it
two two rows pass so is that what we
want yes okay so that is a solution and
uh um okay that's fantastic uh it it's
um uh yeah okay
so that is a solution and uh make a
backup and what we want is the do our um
okay
so okay so let's let's make a copy of
this and do it
new okay now let's do the uh get our P
input okay a big one
we don't care we just like boot for
it
3:42 I don't even have time to drink my
coffee let's see 3:42 are you sure yes
shut the up paste
submit that is not the right answer
okay
why why is it not right oh oh oh that's
right because oh you see this tricky
you see not all numbers are the
same uh same number of items you
see yeah okay so that means yeah okay so
we need to
um okay so we need to get the number of
items
per you see It's Tricky the the input
the toy example doesn't show cuz I
assumed you know I just plug in a number
but uh it's trying it's trying to be
tricky so you uh okay instead of okay so
so let me just work on that so instead
of string split so string split this
time you just split
on uh you split on
the end of line character
then then you
map you map spr spring uh string split
again okay so
function uh okay you map it
to you map it to here of course you map
to this thing uh and this time you split
by y spaces okay
uh uh by default is split back white
space okay so actually you don't need
the function you just say
that okay so that gives
you uh so that gives
you yeah so each row is different length
then you just need to say two expression
there and you don't need partition okay
don't so don't partition
it okay so I think that's that so remove
that now comment this
out okay so let's try
it uh no well that's because you know
you actually you need to put this here
because uh emx
w w mod okay there we have it now let's
try to reduce you know some of the
length Okay run it
and there it is 135 okay so
now now we just remove this whole input
and use this input okay uh
and and and and and put this
back
okay run it
606 are you sure yes yes yes please so
how do I resubmit
uh make sure something something return
to day
two
okay page
606 that is the right answer of course
continue to part two celebration
hello
ju Pomo okay I don't know what is Pomo I
forgot so how many minutes 30
minutes okay so the result is
606 okay so that is our code for uh day
one
put it
back and now let's do day two okay I
mean part
two part
two syntax showing browser there is our
code oh God I hate this uh you know
so yeah part two okay
okay what is the part two let's
[Music]
see uh
what part two
okay part two the uh the engineers are
surprised by the low number something
the problem dampener the problem
dampener is a react something something
some something tolerate a single bad
level okay
tolerate a single bad level okay
something now something same rule apply
as before except if removing a single
level from an unsaved report would make
it safe the report instead count as safe
okay okay the pro the nature of the
problem
changed somewhat significantly so let's
see so 13245 is now save
because you
[Music]
remove oh God this problem becom in
complex so you remove three it
works oh
so if you can remove one number in
a
row then it works
well you can do trial and error what
does it take this thousand
numbers I don't want to call
this so you see there are two conditions
one condition is that they must all
increase monotonically
or decrease
monotonically so that's one condition so
if you have a bad number there you know
let's say you have 1 2 3
100 then 4 five six okay so that 100 is
a bad seed you just kick it out then
it's increasing order again
so so one of the issue is that the order
so if if you can remove one element
then
then then it counts okay but the other
condition is that the difference must
be oh
God in well actually in fact these two
can be
combined yeah it's well not
necessarily
um okay so you know so I'm going to
show okay so anyway so you can remove
one number so that's one thing older so
okay the other thing is that the
difference so if you remove one number
and if you remove that specif
specific
item and if that fix the differences
problem all the differences are less
than three or equal to three then it
also
come you see you cannot apply these two
conditions separately
because because whenever you remove one
item it must be that item it then
satisfy
both okay so what you can do is
that H you can just do Brute Force you
know so just go through these numbers
for each row that fail then you try to
take out one row one
element and try it again actually that's
that will work there's only 1,000 items
let's see yeah for each row you the
maximum number of try is like
10 yeah Pro Force
Works uh let me give it a thought about
if there's some
trick you remove I one item so if
removing one item works
yeah
let's let's just do it
okay so if you you know we can go to the
wfam language and paste it there so you
can see the
code now it's
clear oh we got we got a nested function
screw up that's why it's red I mean not
necessarily screw up that just means the
syntax
is potential problem because you are
using X in uh it still works because
function has a tighter scope but better
if you just change it to Y okay let's
change it X to y
y okay so copy
that paste there that's
beautiful and uh copy that paste here so
now it's like looks beautiful
okay okay but you got to solve the
problem by the way there's a lot
shortcut notations so you don't have to
have all those all these uh nested
brackets Okay so
yeah so
this so this end this whole end this and
that oh God
if you can remove just one item what
does does it
signify you know if you can just remove
one
item hey Louis Louis from
Germany uh okay so this problems are
okay okay so what am I
doing do I want to do this
yes okay I guess I have to I no
choice
because okay let's call this so if you
can remove one
item is here some
trick so order so most first of all you
got to know it's increasing or
decreasing given a bunch of numbers they
can potentially be
chaotic so there's no
predom you know you cannot say which it
tends to be increasing or decreasing it
could be K you know up and down up and
down so that means there's no shortcut
to say it's this is decreasing or
increasing okay so you got a bunch of so
up and down so their difference is going
to be some positive and some negative so
so if it's all positive so actually you
don't actually need this ordered
function you can just check you know you
just take the difference here and if
it's
all positive but also well you also have
to make sure they are not
um zero so if it's all positive and
doesn't contain any zero then then it's
increasing or decreasing okay uh and uh
uh and uh
then so or positive it's increasing but
you also have to check it whether it's
all negative
okay and no zero so first of all check
the item has no zero then check it's or
positive or or negative okay so that's
one
thing uh maybe maybe I should write out
check the diff list has no
zero then check if it's all positive or
all
negative if
so the row is good
okay so that's the mechanism underneath
this so but now it asks to remove one
item
so can we you know we look at the
mechanism to
[Music]
see so that
means if it's all you know if there's no
zero okay I think I think it'll work
out uh so there
is okay so you know thinking is like 100
times faster than talking so in my mind
I kind of already know what to do but
to to express it in speech will'll take
you know 30 seconds so basically you
check this you know this you know if
this condition met it's good but if this
condition doesn't work then you check if
there's only one
zero okay if there's only one zero
then then
um and uh then you can check the second
condition if it it works then that's
fine but otherwise if
it's if the same position that is zero
is causing one of the negative number or
one of the positive number then then it
Al work because you presume you remove
that
item okay so how do
we express this succinctly succinctly
because
uh Uganda wow in
Uganda Uganda where is Uganda that's in
Africa right
wow uh so
okay so remove one item this pesy
problem you just remove one
item you know actually the easiest
easiest is just brute force it you know
because because at vent of a code they
don't really care about code efficiency
you know there's not nothing you can
show how you
know it it only care for the answer so
if you can do it you know like run the
code in two minutes then that's fine so
the easiest way is actually just root
Force then you don't have to think about
the problem or and then record re recode
the problem you don't have to so you
just Brute Force okay yeah let's just
Brute Force
first check if the row
pass if
not uh if not then you want to
try remove each item so uh
write a function
FF that checks if the row pass okay
now run FF on a
row if no
pass
then then you want to try to remove uh
one item of the row and you know remove
first item remove the second item so you
got the list of you got the list of you
know so suppose that there are three
items in the row then you got a total of
how many possibilities one two three
yeah
uh map
FF
on uh list of rows each one is with one
item
removed okay if any of this
is
pass then it is pass okay that is the
algorithm so how do you generate this
list of rows okay we can try it and you
know let's say one
uh 1 2 3
uh you want generate so if the rows if
if the if the list has four items
then you got four possible uh so you got
2 three4 or 134 or
one two three okay so you
got wait wait one two three
four uh 2 3 4 13
4 1
24 then 2 three 4 I mean then two three
then then one two three okay
so the possible number of rows is the
same as the length of the list okay but
the question is how do you generate this
list without you know brute force uh we
can do
it in a simpler
way we can just do a permutation and
permutation and uh remove yeah let me
let me show you okay
so per
permute uh permute that returns all
possible rearrangement of the
elements no not you know so we want the
permutation
least uh permutation
Matrix represent the permutation Matrix
given by permutation Vector perm a
structure race something uh
maybe what does this
return uh okay that's missing argument
uh permutation
Matrix yeah but that's not what we want
you always got this kind of
problem okay
that's not what you
want
yeah kind of no no that's not what you
want there yeah there's a function okay
so uh permutation least obvious you know
why didn't you think of that yeah
run the
line uh
what returns of permutation least
representation of permutation per
no uh no you
want permutation
Cycles yeah now we we just want the list
of permutations what is the uh related
guide
permutation Cycles cyclic permutation
representation uh per permutation is a
fascinating subject of discrete
mathematics okay if you guys have not
studied it and it is you know
fascinating and easy to understand it
and it's also uh represents group Theory
so if you have if you guys have not
studed stud permutation you can start by
going to Wikipedia permutation okay just
read the article then you know then
you'll find related links to so many so
much others okay so permutation you see
in wam language you got like 20
functions on permutation so it relates
to group Theory and uh combinatorics
probability well you know for example
Lottery you know Lottery
what what are your chances of winning
things factorial you know
factorial
um you know so and and group Theory and
the
matrices okay so so let's go back to the
problem there it is all permutations of
arguments of expression that that's what
we want
yeah
permutations R it
there it
is uh okay that's not you know that's
actual permutation
actually we I think we are digressing
and digressing into different things
uh you know because to do this to
generate this this we can just manually
try to map
and yeah but um but permutation is much
simpler
way one two three four yeah because it
uh
what permutation is not what we
want tpos okay I think I what we need is
tpos all possible tures let's see turos
and generates a list of all possible and
toose of element from the Le that's what
we
want so toose that and uh just three
okay run
it oh okay so but then it uh no well one
that's not what we want
okay but I'm pretty sure
I'm pretty sure there is a single
command
that that returns
um subsets that's what we want
subsets okay check subset three yeah
let's see right
h no that's okay so you need the extra
argument to
specify yeah so you want exactly three
elements okay run
it perfect that's what we want 1 2 3 1 2
4 1 3 4 2 3 4 okay now I have to
memorize this because this this you know
this um permutation topos subset comes
up often especially in this kind of to
problems so now I remember you know you
just remember what they are so you see
this is why wfam language is like very
high level in Python in almost all
languages you have to code
yourself you know most of these
functions are in wam language since
1989 so so you know so over the past 30
years gradually like very gradually
python for example they they added some
some of these in library for example in
Python you you I believe you have like
I'm pretty sure you have
permutations uh I don't know about tpos
or subset but you have some of these you
know like after 20 30 years they started
to add it but many others you just have
to code it yourself and lots of to
problem like in programming industry you
know for beginners or the Nerds like
they the Unix The Bash the
Unix or the python or the disp
they will often compete like how can you
this is the most especially the scheme
dispers you know they they they all do
this like oh every year every all the
time for 30 40 years like you will see
like how what's the most elegant way you
know recursive tail recursion doing like
like they just repeatedly code these
functions over and over
again uh which I did you know I did in
1990s using wolam language uh by that at
that time you don't have uh you don't
have turos okay uh you don't have per
you know you don't have this except some
of these are in the library okay so turo
is turos is added in 2004 Okay so
so yeah okay so toose and subset when
subset
added subset 24 yeah okay so they added
this whole bunch so anyway what is our
problem so so subset is what we want but
um but let's make
sure what if you got 2 two do you still
get the right
answer yeah
I think
so y that's what you want subset so the
length is going to be you know one less
than the
length so that's how you generate all
the other possible okay so
okay I'm digressing so much uh let's I
need to work on the problem so Brute
Force so you so this generates all
possible then then you just apply your
function to it okay let's let's do
it so this is a function now
uh okay so you need write the
function uh
check row okay check row will
be this
function okay so let's change that to
XX that's the body of the
function okay
that is a function check row okay so
let's actually
so
uh it Returns what does it return uh
return true or
false uh and we can try it
on let's say check row what what is the
row
uh
yeah you know that so let's put it here
then
it uh
no okay so got something
wrong oh wait so this is actually
this this is not uh yeah so I know
what's going on so we are actually
working on the whole expression so check
row actually should just
be yeah so not not the count okay
so so we don't need the count
yeah okay so let's try
it there's still something wrong
reverse God
wait okay so
yeah
uh this XX is wrong we got the argument
wrong
what
uh okay this stream is becoming no
good sir your internet is very slow my
monitor is a slow frame rate
uh maybe that is
because no it say
okay
control shift Escape let's see
maybe it's because I'm also recording to
disk uh but the disk says zero activity
so something is
wrong and very
annoying something odd because the dis
says zero
activity um uh but I'm recording to disk
so does that mean my disk is field
no I should have plenty of
space but uh
yeah very annoyed right
now I don't know
internet speed slow why why is
that am I doing good let me know how is
it uh so let's just push on the coding
okay is annoying
so for
map 2
X2
for for
same thing
uh let me stop for a moment let's see
okay am I back is all
good seems
so okay need to fix this
I the is going
on for
fixed okay sounds good uh fantastic
thank you thank you
Hamza uh now we need to fix a
problem oh okay so
so
um so
list list okay so
list and uh
then differences at
X yeah okay so I think I think think
this
is that okay
so okay
so so that and that
function and that difference difference
of the least absolute
okay
then
okay uh and I think that's
it this is a function
okay
it y That's the function that tells me
if a row checks out let's let's rewrite
it I mean let's write it so it's easier
to understand too many of the map thing
okay
so and uh this
all let's just use the shortcut but
now it's much
simpler okay
minute fantastic so now thank you jeel
so we re roll this with the shortcut
notation it's much easier to understand
and in fact this can be further uh SFI
let's do it
okay that's just
that and
uh okay now it's even
simpler uh test it run
it
true okay uh 82 76 73 70 60760
so let's say that it be
false yeah so the function works so
according to our algorithm brot Force
way write a function FF that checks if
the row
pass
then then map FF on a list of rows each
one is the one item removed okay which
we can do subset so let's start to use
subset
so subset you want to apply it to the
input actually X2 okay X2 is our new
input
[Music]
so so actually you want to map okay so
you map you map the
subset you map the subset this is the
input of subset function to to this X2
okay that
generates a list of lists
yeah so okay so what you want to
do
if uh I'm just going to code okay so
if if that
then then it's true okay
otherwise otherwise you're going to
do
this on the subset
thing you want to apply that at uh
you apply that and say
end okay something like
that I'm just trying to finish the
problem okay so I think that's it so if
check row if it's true then return true
okay okay so otherwise
you you find all possible subset okay
so uh here this needs to be yeah the
subset that's the argument okay the
row so you find all the subset okay and
the length of uh minus one okay
so here you will be the
length and
that minus one okay so you generates all
the subsets then you map the row check
row function to each one of
them
then then if if any one of them is true
then it's true okay so the whole thing
can be reduced to uh all operation okay
so let's rewrite the whole thing to one
single o operation
so it's
that uh
or
this
okay so I think that's a entire solution
um so wait so what does this return so
this returns this returns if that row is
true with the possibility of removing
one item
okay but this is not a function so we
need to okay so let's
make let's write the function
okay this function we are named check
row
maybe
remove
one item
okay return true or
false some documentation always helps so
that's a function name
okay
uh and uh and uh the function will be
yeah it will be just
that and uh
yeah this this is the function
okay okay so
yeah let's just um let's just do it this
way
okay okay
so then you just map this
to you you just map this function
to to
X2 then you got a bunch of true and
false then you just count
okay
count count this
thing you want to count the number of
true items okay I think that's
it okay so the whole thing looks like
that now let's try the uh Toy
input so the toy input
God to input is here let's try that
uh so
what so now is
good it was excellent now it's
good um okay let's see so what is the
thanks to the problem damper four
reports are actually save so so the
result should be four on the toy input
okay so we don't need this
anymore yeah that's a comers some
version so we are
doing this is analysis okay so this is
analysis and uh then this is a Brute
Force way
which we are doing and uh
um okay let's run
it please make it work four fantastic
beautiful now we just
try the full input put the full input
here okay now run
it no maybe or take a
minute wait
644 is that right what was the answer
before
uh 66 now 644 Brute Force way
fantastic
okay
submit that's the right answer fantastic
guys we finished
we finished
fantastic okay thank you guys for
watching bye
guys
yeah okay copy that paste it here now we
can do some clean up but that's it okay
so put it back color it showing browser
that's it