hello guys welcome to another episode of
Star Talk show
today we are going to do live coding of
Wolfram language of geometric inversion
we are going to continue yesterday
uh you can see this Graphics is what we
did yesterday so start a Wu fan language
open a new notebook paste it and shift
enter to
your net so you can see this is what we
did yesterday
so today we are going to
continue this and do a
we are going to do a three-dimensional
geometric inversion so you see this is a
two-dimensional version
you start with a grid like that
two-dimensional 2D grid with choose then
you apply the geometric inversion which
is a function then you get this
three-dimensional uh beautiful
uh figure so today we are going to do a
three-dimensional geometric inversion
version so okay so let me show you so if
you have not already watched yesterday's
uh YouTube I mean yeah my you uh my live
stream
two days ago a day you know the previous
one so you can see so here is a 3D
version let's copy the code
copy the code so we are so this one you
are seeing is a geometric inversion
three-dimensional version of
cubes on a grid so you start with a
bunch of Cubes then you apply the
function then you get this beautiful
image
okay and today what we are going to do
is is instead of Cubes we start with a
cage you know three-dimensional grid of
lines with twos then we invert it so
we'll see a beautiful image okay and
today and let me paste the code
uh Ctrl shift n to make it beautiful
like type setting type set mathematics
then
uh shift enter to run it so you can see
so here is the image you can see the
beautiful nested circles pattern okay
so let me tell you uh so I'm using a new
keyboard I did a video about two videos
before last week basically so you can
see I'm using this keyboard I'm using is
glove 80 so I have a so you just search
for
keyboard blog
and you'll see
the glove 80 keyboard that one okay
so I did a review of IT about to be
about last week you can go watch it the
the video is also shown here at the
bottom so it's a fantastic keyboard I
recommend it okay so here's a video two
days ago last week
okay so you know it's great I'm still
not used to it yet and I have not
programmed it yet it's programmable so
for example window space right now I'm
using the windows warang layout
so it might be slower than my usual
coding okay so I'm using emacs
and I'm using subfly keys which is a you
can search it some fly Keys you can find
it's a emacs key binding system
so so that you don't have to press Ctrl
you don't have to press meta or out
every command you can see on the Ping
window that's my command course and
keystroke I'm using a borac keyboard
okay so let's begin
coding this okay so hold on a second
copy that back to emacs open last closed
uh close it and put the link here so
showing browser so this is today's talk
show
and put a link here so people know so
they can come back and see you know what
is the keyboard
okay so geometric inversion fantastic
now yeah Cube and let's begin to code it
if you have questions comments uh post
it okay
so and so begin
a wufan language
mod which allows you to code Wolfram
language in emacs it's also free on
GitHub there's a link okay
okay so now let's start to code it so
you know so first the first thing we
want to do is to create a
grid made of tubes like that but
three-dimensional okay so essentially
the code is almost very similar to what
we did yesterday
so we yeah so why don't we just copy the
code here
copy it back to emacs paste it here
we're gonna modify this code so the
first thing you want to do is
so here is the
function here's a geometric inversion
function uh it basically takes
[Music]
let me paste it so let me magnify
okay so what this function what this
function do is basically
uh you know let me just show you what it
does it just take a point and return a
point that's it point being two numbers
or
in three dimension is three points you
know represent the coordinates of three
of a point in 3D it can be four
dimension or five dimension so for
example let me show you
geometric immersion
so shift I and V so that is our function
and where is my square bracket key
so I'm not too used to this keyboard yet
this is this is maybe not a good idea
where is my
so that's
so I need the square bracket
okay
okay one one of them is there
the other one up okay they're windy okay
so this is
bull rag mapping via Windows on this
uh spatial keyboard so geometric new
version okay so now you need
um
shift
shifts
so for example
shift into
so essentially that's what you that that
is a Formula so if you have you know
given a point a b a vector a b and this
is the read the result okay that's a
geometric inversion that's just a
function that's all there it is so but
you can also have a three-dimensional
vector
uh
shift into so in in a three-dimensional
Vector you just
you know it returns a new Vector so and
it can be four dimensional or higher
Dimension so that's a geometric
inversion now if you want to know more
about it you can just go to the you know
go to you know my website
watch you know I did a video last year
so you can see this video
where I explained we did that one we
explained what is a geometric inversion
here so it's just you know for for for
those of you programmers it's just a
function takes two numbers I mean takes
one number
Returns the number I mean uh I mean two
numbers you know a vector a a point
uh
from a mathematic mathematician
geogeometer point of view it
it inverts
it's kind of like a mirror but it
inverts points inside the circle to
outside and outside circle inside so it
kind of swap like if you have a piece of
paper if you have a piece of paper you
poke a hole in the middle and you kind
of imagine the piece of paper is rubber
you swap it inside out so the outside
edges becomes the whole Edge in the
middle and the middle it becomes outside
you know that's inversion very
interesting concept okay so you can read
about it about it on this page
search for Sardi playing curves
inversion geometric inversion okay so
that is a geometric conversion so that's
essentially just just you know that's
all it does that function so now so this
is a function
by the way if you are wondering what is
this the first part that is that is for
you know the geometric inversion is not
defined at the center of the circle so
so if you you know add orange and 0 0
that point is not defined so
ideally that point goes to infinitely
outside so you know anyway
so that is why in the code you have to
check if that the length of you know you
you you want to check the input numbers
a b or ABC or ABCD they are all zero if
they are all zero then
then it's not defined that's that's why
you have the if statement
okay but this is essentially what it
does okay so this here is the function
geometric inversion then we
now the first thing we want to do is
create a
a three-dimensional cube of
of tubes okay so how do you do that okay
so we did so yesterday
um we explained let me get these two
two so this is the Syntax for the tube
you can see
let me show the documentation for the
cube Wolfram language okay turn on
JavaScript
so this is how you represent a tube you
know you just call the function tube and
give a list of points then it represents
a tube connecting to those points okay
so it's very high level powerful
Wolfram language
so
and so you have so so here is a tube and
what this table do is that it takes any
expression
then it just
iterate it's like python's
um
it generated Nest at least essentially
it's uh it's like pythons
um
how do you call that
any anyone watching so let's go to
python
yeah
p-y-t-h-o-n okay so this is similar in
idea it's like a nested Loop okay nested
Loop but in Python you have a special
method to generate it generate it a
special syntax called
um
least comprehension okay that's very
silly so
least comprehension Haskell also calls
that uses that but that's not good so
but anyway table is just the least
comprehension it allows you to generate
a nested list without using
nested Loop syntax which you know so
this is a functional syntax
so actually so why don't we just show it
for example X
uh let's say X from 1 to
1 2 5 okay and let's do another case in
this case let's say
X and Y
X from one to five and uh y from let's
say negative three two
uh let's say zero in steps of negative
one okay so if I run it you will see
what it does it just generate
a nested Beast okay shift enter to run
it
okay so the first example is one two
three four five the second example we
got something wrong oh yeah this should
be y so let's change it y
and what negative three two zero oh
instead of positive one we've we got the
sign wrong so shift enter so there it is
nested list that's what table does
okay so table so
so we we call table then we put so table
here and here is a tube
you know we want to call a table
and X form let's see let's see where the
X and Y
X from
let's just say
zero two five okay it just say zero to
five and similarly for y
okay and here we want the tube
um
so this is the three dimensional
three-dimensional case so we actually
need also Z
so we want a three-dimensional nested
beast in other words a 3D Matrix okay x
x goes from zero to five white zero two
five Z zero two five okay so and here
you can just say for example let me just
show you uh example let's say f x y z
okay so this expression okay let's show
you what it does
okay shift enter shift enter is that key
okay so you can see
x y z
uh wait why is uh
so what is X did we Define it somewhere
why
Z okay
so table f x y z Oh we forgot a comma
you see we forgot the comma there
so the first argument is the expression
the rest arguments are the iteration you
know so you want X goes from 0 to 5. y
goes from zero to five okay and similar
for Z so now shift enter to run it there
it is okay so you can see the first row
F zero zero zero f zero zero one zero
two and so on and then
um you know we can format it in a better
way
by
by saying uh you want slash slash
table form okay
so that means apply the function table
from to the previous expression that's
what the slash slash operator is that's
a postfix operator
okay now run it shift enter
okay so let's see if it makes sense
okay so you want to make you want to
enlarge the window
okay like that okay that's what nested
you know uh nested Matrix
so anyway so that's a table so here
instead of the f x y z we want two we
want the tube okay
now let me show you as example of tube
okay we so tube
tube takes one argument
at least okay uh and uh each element in
a list is a three-dimensional
Vector so three numbers for the
coordinate let's say zero zero zero okay
and the second number let's say zero
one
zero okay so that's a tube then if you
want to render it as a graphics all you
have to say is you just put graph 3D in
front okay
okay so copy that
back to firm language go to the bottom
paste it
shift enter to run it
uh not graph 3D graphics 3D I always
uh
typo
okay
so
copy it
back to firm language paste it
paste it
shift enter run it so you can see there
is a tube
and the second argument to a tube is the
radius of the tube so you can say one
uh it's
shipped enter
oh this is a long po tube okay that's
too thick
0.1 okay
Ctrl enter and
shift enter yeah so there it is a cube
okay that's the syntax of the tube the
graphics 3D that just render it
so this graphic 3D is similar to print
usually in programming languages when
you say print it print prints text but
if you want to print graphics that's
what this graphics 3D function is so so
here so we got the we got the syntax of
the cube and now we covered the syntax
of the table now we just want to use the
table to generate
a huge amount of tube like
forming a grid three dimensional grid
okay so that's how do you do that let's
see
um so in order to do that let's let's
try to do it here
so first of all and so
so you want so
if it's a square then they then it's
very easy you just start here go here go
here go here and one more point the
first point
now if it's a square
you cannot
Traverse the Q or the edges of the cube
in one shot so you need two cubes
do I make sense hello Benjamin
so
um yeah so
you have to think about how how do you
okay let's try to do this okay x y z the
first point
uh
[Music]
uh how do you how do you want to do this
so a Cube's got six point so the problem
right now is that
is that you are given a point x y z
generated by the table
you know for each iteration you are
given a point x y z you want a cube
you know so from that point you have six
small points because that point
represents a corner of the cube so you
you got six more points okay and what
you want to do is that you want to call
Cube
connecting each
end of
two points foaming forming a cube made
out of tubes Okay so
given a point
okay so let's that's why don't we start
to just write this given the point
what are the six corners of the cube
that's easy let's just uh combination so
how many edges are there
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve
there are 12 edges okay so the first one
is that
let's just do this okay
let's just do
and God
let's do each Edge one by one
okay oops
first where is first uh Plus
that's the key
okay so you need to find my first key
Okay so
plus one okay one
foreign
so that forms one Edge
so actually we we need some kind of we
need to uh draw it because this is going
crazy
huh
here's my tablet pin
oh God
what
oh here so
am I doing good oh we got four people
watching okay so so first of all we do
you know this is getting confusing so
let's draw it
so let's draw it
let me just draw draw it okay
so a cube
and let's say like that that that that
that
okay kind of like that so you got
this is X well this is our engine so you
got let's say a
B
yeah this is pretty cumbersome
c d
he have
G H so you got six corners
what you want to do is that you get you
are given a corner a you want to
generate the rest of the points corners
then you want to for each
you know two corners you want to group
them together to make a tube okay so
that's the problem how do we do it
first time catching a stream just want
to say thank you for inspiring me to
learn emacs
can I see it love you man you are
awesome thank you
uh
Okay so
thank you for inspiring me to learn
emacs over the last couple of weeks
fantastic
okay so yeah so let's get back to work
on this so okay focus
so we want to
do these the thing is okay so we want to
so we are given x y z
what are the other points okay let's
write down the other points first okay
so let's say a
is that okay A B
C let's just name them a b c d
if g h okay now B would be that c would
be
Z Plus One
okay
D would be
uh yeah X plus one okay and E would be
x y
uh wait
X
wait B is not B is wrong so
so how am I drawing I'm using
I'm using Microsoft
snip and sketch in Microsoft Windows
when you do a screenshot your open is in
kind of the drawing type you know this
this application okay so that's how you
can draw a hand type of course I'm using
a tablet you search for Sardi keyboard
blog you can see my review of a bunch of
tablets very useful if you are taking
notes or do mathematics
so anyway let's focus on this so
oh I failed to mention you know if you
want you know we are doing Mathematica
wolf and language you can get it for
free if you just go to my website you
know wufam Language tutorial and
download for free
then you can do what I'm doing
by default you don't get Graphics you
don't get a notebook but you can
download The Notebook from the open
source with um uh Jupiter notepad so you
can integrate them so you also you know
so you can have to what we do we find
language okay search for excited wolfam
Language tutorial you'll find it
okay so but okay so now let's go back to
doing this
okay point B is
X plus one
y doesn't change okay
and Z doesn't change okay yeah Point C
is X plus one yeah actually
and the Y
doesn't change and Z plus one okay and
point D is X
doesn't change
why
X doesn't change y doesn't change Z plus
one okay
and E F G H Point E F G H there Y is o
plus one
E F G H okay so y plus one
okay now e
e x no change y plus 1
Z is zero
now f
is X plus one
you know we can probably do this in a
permutation
kind of fashion to generate this or com
you know this where you should have a
plus one
so F is X plus one
y plus one
Z stay put
G is Z Plus One
G is X plus one
y plus one Z plus one yeah oh if we we
if we think of traversal it's much
easier okay so H is
H is X they put
y plus 1 Z plus one okay so that is the
six points of a cube given one
point x y z
okay so given one point we generate all
these bunch of points uh you know
we don't want this
you know actually so so that's a comment
okay
so actually let's do this let's add a
comment
okay
okay so that's a comment now the whole
thing we want to make it a beast
Okay so
so we got at least
of these points okay and we need the
comma at the end
so since we have a list of numbers okay
and uh
so uh
Corner two Q points so we can write a
function given a point that's a corner
of a cube to all the corners of a cube
okay
so once we have these six points we need
to
kind of connect them okay this is fairly
tedious
you know you cannot just connect
arbitrary points
we could if if we want actually we could
we could then we're gonna generate some
some interesting
um
you know in interesting things that like
for example there would be a cross in
each of these Square
but for now let's not
okay now you need to
um
pair them
okay but anyway once we have this
then it should be easier to pair so
a connects to B
okay so a connects to B
okay so a b b c yeah okay so this is
tedious
as a b
that's b c
and then
CD okay CDs these two
CD
then d a okay then d a
okay
the
hey
okay
you don't need that then
oh God f g
okay f g
e f okay EF is a pair
g h is a pair
okay then we also EF
g h then we have we need h e
g f
okay h e
h e and GF okay so we need g f
she
G if
Okay so
[Laughter]
you know uh chat GPD is very interesting
in fact I got you know some people uh I
asked people they wrote a poem about my
website uh you know it's amazing
uh so I watched so you know if you want
the review of the club 80 watch my
two videos before so I did review on
that
okay so let's focus back on this APS
okay so we got a B
C
d
C D and C A and D A okay so this is this
part is wrong this should be d a
wait what
C D and D A oh okay d a
yeah so d a then
e f we got e f we got g h
g h
e f let's see let's say e f
let's say FG let's go circular
okay f g then g h then we got g h then
we got h e then we got h e now it's
circular okay now we need the you know
those lines there then we need
BF okay
let's split again
B
F okay
then CG okay CG
okay
CG then a e
bfcgae and d h
d h okay
d
h
okay that's a hard work now we need to
add the comma
okay
okay in fact each one of these pair
should be a tube
so
each one of these pairs should be a tube
so why don't we
do it again okay so yeah so copy each
one of these should be a tube
hmm
[Music]
there okay so in fact I can just
there okay that the add sign you are
seeing that's a prefix notation so you
can say add something argument
you know instead of the bracket so you
can use add sign it's equivalent to a
bracket
okay so here is a tube of two points
tube of two points one two three four
five six seven eight nine ten eleven
twelve so
yeah yeah 12 edges of a cube okay so we
got that so that's essentially what we
want so we can actually put here that's
the expression okay let's try it okay
let's just say let's run this code and
see what we get
okay
so from language yeah let's try to put
this here
paste it
remove the comma she shift enter
okay we got
I think we missing a comma or something
uh foreign
missing a comma somewhere
what's going on let's double check
how long we have been doing
oh what close to an hour already
I thought this is
should be fast oh we forgot a comma here
in in indeed okay so now let's do again
now let's
yeah
we forgot a comma okay
paste it
run it
okay oh yeah we got the extra comma we
didn't delete before there
there you
need
it it worked okay now you you have to
say is
graphics 3D
at
Lots tubes
I'm not used to the shift key yet okay
so there
shift enter
fantastic
now we got something wrong you see we
got um
you know there shouldn't be diagonal
lines so we
yeah so we got something wrong
and we have to double check our
so if you're gonna add diagonal lines
how many are there one two three four
you know
diagonal lines are actually interesting
when we do these Graphics because you
have
you know it would be a very interesting
effect
for
you know for the
for the thing we want to generate
you know this
because you know he would be have you he
will have very interesting effect you we
are going to get some kind of spiral
effect but for now let's fix it I guess
um
so we got diagonal lines
okay now let's reduce the number of
iteration let's just say three okay
let's just say two uh okay three
two
run it
run it okay now it's much simpler
here we got two mistakes actually here
and
God
a
H I don't know yeah you know we can fix
it but it's you know it's just tedious
let's just go with this okay let's just
go with that we're gonna apply a
geometric transformation to all these
squid points okay
so now we got lots of tubes and we can
say two Graphics okay so now yeah so now
let's just remove those uh pretty
tedious we got this
is coming that out
and this part is showing
what is this part
so
tube yeah this this part is showing how
tube works okay
yeah a bunch of points so to delete it
we don't need it
so this is an example of a tube deleted
uh
uh wait the common went wrong somehow
hold on a second
yeah the comment
now this is incorrect okay let me do
this comment okay there
uh Wolfram language common can be nested
so you know this is a comment and you
can Nest it
show G so now this tube we don't need
we don't need okay so geometric
conversion function this is the
Prototype of the cube corners and here's
the actual code to generate tens of
cubes with
tube as edges okay then you create a
graphics out of it then you define the
geometric inversion which we defined
here so we don't need
then you just do you show the graphics
then all you have to do here is you do a
transformation replace or replace or in
Wolfram you know Wolfram language is a
term rewriting system
so most half of the time when you do
computation what you do is that you tell
it to do find and replace
so that's what this
replace all function is it it does find
replace of your syntax in other words it
transforms your syntax you know whatever
you typed you know you can consider this
whole thing or this whole data as just a
bunch of data for example let's show the
actual value so
evaluate
you see that's the output you know
there's a bunch of data so you can think
of this whole data as a stream
then the
the term rewriting just means you take
this consider this as a string
you want to find certain pattern and
replace it by some other thing just like
string find replace okay except you are
doing it syntactically
you know it's not just you know it's
these strings are kind of alive you know
so that's the power that's why wufam
language is a symbolic language you can
think of this as a you know at least
macro is a bit like that but it's like
the the the most basic
so anyway so what we want to do is we
now we got this bunch of data we want to
find you know in this data we want to
find any pattern any occurrence of these
three points just three numbers when we
find that we want to apply
this geometric inversion function to
those points okay then then we'll we'll
get our geometric conversion Graphics
okay very easy so all we have to do here
you know is actually find the tube
okay so we can do mean there are many
ways to write it so let's let's do the
way I was talking about
so three numbers X
y z
and you need the underscore
how do you type underscore
[Music]
you know I mean the Microsoft's product
layout with this keyboard where's the
underscore
foreign
[Music]
would normally be Dash okay got it
so shift Dash that's underscore yeah so
you want to find a pattern that's three
numbers
and uh
yeah so at any time you find those
you just say
okay let me write this out so hold on a
second
there okay so every time you see let me
write it this way so it's easier to
understand anytime you find a pattern of
three numbers okay you just you you want
to so this is a pattern to find once you
find it you want to return this
replacement okay which means apply the
geometric inversion to those three
numbers okay so that's what
you know that's what we want we want to
transform you know
I think that's it so okay let's hope it
works it's
uh let me review it one more time
you know we might have Arrow but let's
try it
okay uh copy the whole buffer
okay copy the whole buffer
paste the code
oh we we don't want the underscore there
okay now shift return
to the net
fantastic successful this is the result
indeed that's correct
you see
you see fantastic beautiful oh my God
that's so lovely I I've been very happy
with this
you see why is it corner like that you
know well well that's because remember
our grid
know we started our grid with zero you
know let's remove this uh this huge
thing
huge thing
you know the reason it it's you know
because we started uh
table with you know X
you know at zero so what we want is
starting at uh let's modify it here
so negative five let's see negative five
to five okay
so instead of zero so there
okay and fixed here
okay
copy all
this
so actually let's just put a code here
paste it
okay delete that
delete that
fantastic so now let's run it shift
enter
great
now here is our whole Cube
oh fantastic
let's magnify
okay now you see now the structure
actually the previous Graphics is better
because now it's just two conject
congested you can see but we can take it
apart by
yeah actually the previous is better
because
um
so you can see the inner structure of
this thing
so let's let's try the zero again
shift enter
okay yeah so that
okay I think so we did you know you know
now we we did this for an hour now let's
stop
yeah so you know there are few things we
should fix for example this you know the
diagonal lines we should remove
uh then we should show a graphics of
that it will be very interesting
beautiful then we should try a version
without the orthogonal lines but or just
diagonal lines then you'll just be
another very different effect
Graphics you know then if you want to
show then we should do one where it just
half of the sphere but you see
this this is like a corner of the cube
we want to do half of it so you can see
I don't know if I'm making sense
you know like similar something like
this so you can see half of it the thing
okay but that's it for today thank you
guys for watching
I'm gonna read the comments we're gonna
shut down
in three minutes this is beautiful I
truly love this geometric inversion this
is the beauty of mathematics where you
don't see in school you know when they
teach you math in school it's like
boring formulas but this is a beauty
geometric inversion of a
three-dimensional grid
okay that's what we are seeing
okay comments and anything else
oh let me show you so
so yeah so hey digital Moonlight hey
yeah I'm using uh you know
fantastic you know they they are going
to send me
oh God I have so many things going in my
head multiple things I want to talk
about they want they are going to send
me you know the lighter key switch so
that would be fantastic right now it's
you know chocolate so I want to show you
guys yeah I want to show you chat GPT on
my website and also okay let's put this
code back
tab B wait
tab B why is it undivide oh God
you know I'm not I forgot the keys now
well I mean the the you know I'm not too
familiar with this keyboard layout yet
uh what I want to do now is to pop it
back okay yeah okay let's just Cooks uh
back three okay oh Ctrl B okay now
syntax code the code Ctrl R to show in
browser so this is what we talked about
today and here's a code
fantastic you know just like
three lines of code three lines of code
that gives you these
C and U next coders
how many lines you need
two thousand for this
okay yeah and the chat GPT so let's see
if I can
that's very interesting there's a poem
where Chad GPD showed my
uh you know wrote about me so
so you can search it by
okay let's see if we can find it
chat there
very interesting fantastic I mean
amazing
a poem about xadi.org in iambic
pentameter I'm I'm quite Amazed by this
you know this is a website you know the
the AI generated wrote it this is a
website buildback Sardi a guy who knows
his stuff and wants to share it with you
the site is crammed with info on all
sorts of things from programming to sex
there is something for everyone
so if you are looking for knowledge or
just a good laugh you need to check out
xavi.org the best website around you
know very very fine touch you know you
know or just a good laugh indicating you
know that that indicates that some
people find my website is just not you
know not
you know it'd be like they they want to
make they ridiculous some of my writings
so that that that sense is part of the
poem so you know it means that chat GPT
is aware of that situation quite amazing
and then another poem and then two line
breaks
so one of them says there was a geek
named sa who ran a website with much
Flair he would write code all day and
all night and his side was really
something quite right quite amazing
because all day and all night is one of
the catchphrase I use often in my way on
you know
so it caught that and another lime rig
similar okay so very amazing chat GPT so
those of you coming coming late you know
you know so this keyboard I recommend it
I'm promoting them because they are you
know very nice to me they give it to me
uh and you know and I gave you my true
opinions so if you wanted if you want to
know more about this keyboard watch my
video
about last week so uh the video you know
you can I give you one hour review of it
okay thank you guys if you like my stuff
you know again pay me okay pay is the
best you know if you just thank me I
don't get nothing you know I get median
thanks you know over the past 20 years
but
patreon or Amazon okay
very interesting poem I'm gonna write it
down thank you
bye guys Greg and darkened
digital Moon and bye guys
foreign
just beautiful