good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
Show today is September 7th 6 o'clock
p.m. San Francisco time Saturday and we
are going to talk about programming
styles I got to get my camera right ok
so do something like that programming
styles idioms functional form in sales
ok something like that this logitech
webcam is so bad stupid my Logitech
webcam ok today actually so let's change
you know that's to some change as a side
views yeah this thing
okay
now my head is too small it's not worry
about it okay good morning bathroom you
good morning Daniel and Louise have not
seen you for a while how are you doing
then your language the new language is
in Los Angeles Southern California
somewhere live so what's up so today so
bad from you we are going to talk about
poem in styles functional programming
styles and my program is tiles and
idioms since the stuffs stuffs I have to
say ok shall we begin
good morning Abdo Abdo is from egypt
Carrie Oh fantastic amazing places it
karaoke gypped Egypt is where you have
pyramids mango is 10 your language says
I'm drinking beer ok typing on ball rack
that's good ok so let's talk about
programming styles yeah
begin beginning at the programming
styles ok forum styles so go to Saudi
website Saudi blog then go to this
syntax of semantic noodles good mornings
e-tron crazy [ __ ] on crazy are you
crazy today so we are going to talk
about programming language design and
programming and idioms and styles ok
let's talk about that
so there are few topics I mean I got
lots of tons of topics on these kind of
things and so there is some some of the
articles I'm programming elegance versus
simplicity ok that's a good one
why idioms are bad ok and the nature of
idioms info
in languages okay and hash table versus
hash table switch statement okay now
that is a new fashion in the past few
years you know they people want to use
hash table as a switch statement and
also another topic logic operators
control flow now I discussed this I
discussed this in past videos last week
or something like that logic operators
control flow don't do that okay so so
that's some of the topics we not talked
about and that's about programming yeah
idiom line styles and those I mean those
are just essays I've written but in
general I can tell you about programming
styles you know so first of all there is
Opie there is functional programming
these two are you know the big general
styles in programming of a particular
you know suppose you know they called
multi-paradigm languages such as Python
Ruby JavaScript I don't know about PHP I
don't think you can do that much
functional programming I don't know
about PHP anyway in Python for example
use SoCo so called multi-paradigm but
it's actually it's mostly in Python it's
mostly it does not support functional
programming well so if you are a
functional programmer person you you
wouldn't like Python okay I mean
technically you can you know they code
for multi paradin motor-powered in my
ass technically you can but there are
many aspects about how do you church
whether language supports different
programming styles for example Python
okay technically you can programming a
function a functional style like for
every everything you don't use over P at
all but that does does not fly okay
like in real world you're working a
company or you working a team if you do
for example if you if you use map lambda
you know the typical functional style
map lambda function something there you
know people is gonna question you know
people don't like you I mean he's got
it's not just don't like you you know
you you know when in code review that's
that's gonna be get changed okay they
don't you know they want you to use
least comprehension
you know the idiotic you see and not
just that okay so so what I'm talking
about is in Python you know and also in
Python
they are lambda the pet the lambda in
Python does not is not a true function
it's kind of creeped out function so you
you you know in functional programming
everything is lambda everything is just
a function lambda and now in Python you
cannot do that then you know what's a
you know you can't really say suppose
functional programming so back to my
point in Python
technically it's supposed to be a multi
paradigm language but in practice but
when you judge you know you have to
consider in practice for example in some
languages for reasons that you just you
know you just never do functional
programming in that language Python is
an example because if you actually do go
you know go go out your way to write
functional programming style without
using over P you're gonna run into
problems everywhere you know everywhere
so so what I'm saying is that you have
to consider in in practice and in theory
so yeah so it's like technically in
Python yeah you can do you know it's
multi-paradigm but in practice know you
run into problems social problems people
problems everywhere in the same way Perl
for example it also supposed to be multi
paradin but Perl
it's got problems both ways you know
yeah you know appeal functional
programming either way you know he's got
problems so so that's a point you know
you have to consider what's in practice
now let me point out so I have these
Python sucks why Python sucks Python
language problems actually I did a video
on that let's see sorry
why Python sucks I did a one-hour video
a few months ago and here is a
collection of articles on why Python
sucks you know Python lambda is spoken
gyda because sky dog doesn't doesn't
like functional programming that is why
that is why Python does not really work
well for functional programming because
keidel in every way every aspect he does
not like functional programming okay so
anyway here's the correction of Python
articles and now so so that's about you
know so-called multi-paradigm languages
now let's talk about yeah so we have
JavaScript our notation let's go to
semantic noodle programming idiom styles
and styles okay these are some of the
topics I'm going to cover but also I'm
gonna talk about in general what do I do
for functional programming okay let me
talk about that you know in I never code
any old piece style accepting a walk you
know if I work in a company when you
know the there's already 10,000 lines
you cannot change it you know you have
to follow the flow so but otherwise in
my own projects you know coding for 30
years I never I and I will never use all
of his style so everything is a function
so what what what do you mean by from
I mean you just okay here's the thing he
is my experience conclusion in one or
two sentences okay so first of all never
you know never never do Opie Opie okay
so well in one sentence always
everything you do right are functions in
such a way that there is no side effect
to a function so every function or every
one of your function you wrote there is
no side effect meaning if you can okay
in some cases it's hard because you know
complex situations in you know real
world but if you try every function such
write every function such that it does
not depend on global variables it does
not depends on anything no side effect
meaning the functions behavior the only
purpose of a function is its output so
you a function has input so every you
know input you know all the parameters
or arguments so input and output that is
that is it function that the only
purpose you have functions of functions
is for its output never you know code
functions for its side effect that
basically that is one sentence summary
and the most important once in a summary
of functional programming okay now in
Haskell if you you know you met you
might have heard Oman at all curving or
tail recursion that's that's oh crap
that's all that that's or well those are
functional programming concepts and
techniques but those are secondary okay
secondary or third third theory okay the
only thing when when you think about
functional programming so what is
function for I mean the only thing you
need to be concerned is that every
function has no side effect that meaning
that the function behavior depends on
the input only and the only purpose when
you call a function the only purpose is
to get its output nothing
for example for example when you do a
loop you know for loop in C in Perl in
JavaScript in Python for you know for
loop that's not functional okay so
that's not functional functional
programming okay so don't do for loop
you know for loop you know for I equals
to zero when I is less than 10
well we can we can begin with it okay so
JavaScript okay let's start javascript
for loop okay that's a for loop let's
say so for one print I okay that's a
javascript for loop vennett oh I need to
save it so X X star ja j s okay vennett
syntax
okay so yeah so hi less than 10 Lynette
you see 0 it prints you were to now now
that's not functional programming why
because why it's not a function first of
all it's not function and this print is
a side-effect okay this is a side effect
anyway that's not function so that
reminds me something okay so anyway
first of all so let's talk about its
write down what is function of
programming the one and most important
thing that characterizes functional
programming is this nothing else okay so
what is it it is the only purpose of
calling a function is to get its output
okay return value that is and
function has no side effects meaning the
output depends totally on the input
nothing else
no global bar okay not grove over okay
so that the the meaning of functional
languages now let me say let me say more
things okay in you may have heard of
Haskell and Haskell and Lisp and so on
scheme this for example and they talk
about monad curry curry okay see you are
Y ing tail recursion Co see see
which means call with no just let's just
say Co see see okay
someone add covering in tail recursion
composition it's it's it's really more
composition and all that and immutable
immu tapi arte okay so monad currying
composition tail recursion immutability
co cc or that it's not really important
that that's not a harder functional
programming okay you know it's like it's
drama you know it's like it's like drama
everyone talks about it there for
example Haskell Oh Mona Mona every day
monad more have for breakfast monad for
you know crap as garbage okay that's
[ __ ] that's misleading
misinformation and curry and composition
and tail recursion
now tell recursion is popular you know
he's like deep depending on your
community
Haskell or scheme or some other each one
is their thing you know so if you are in
scheme community every day every day you
will hear oh tell recursion Oh tell
recursion Oh call CC crap garbage and
and and also Marcus okay Marcus closure
those are crap closure
okay so in skin community everyday as
their thing is at their brain every day
is tell tell tell recursion and course
is either ship their brain and in list
its Marcos Marcos Marcos everyday crap
garbage well they are not garbage
actually they are dead they are just
these are kind of concepts and
techniques okay these are concepts and
techniques and programming language
features for functional programming okay
but they are not essential idea of
functional programming okay they are not
essential and at least viewer also have
cons and crap and for example closure
closure and cons those are not closure
and cons in fact they are they are anti
functional programming whenever you have
a closure you know these people and a
lot people are programmers hacker types
you know they love closure they say oh
we need to have closure oh oh we need to
have Marcos those are not functional
programming okay those are actually
destroying functional programming
closure marker and also cause CC okay
kind of it gets complex depending on
your perspective so anyway so these are
not functional programming stuff and and
these cons list cause is the worst crap
so anyway so so the most important is
just function no
scientific input output so you can try
to do that okay you can do this in every
language okay you can do this thing you
could what depends on the language you
to what degree you can do it depends on
a language but you could if you want to
learn from your own experience right
like you you want to learn functional
form in by yourself and suppose you want
to learn all these concepts scurrying
Monad composition immunity mutability
tail recursion core CC you don't want to
you know suppose so what you can do is
that when you program a project let's
see in Python okay you try to write
everything so that it's showing browser
you try to write everything so that
every function no side of it and
everything is a function no oo p no
nothing it just functions Co functions
define functions call them do these two
that that is all you know if you limit
your ho project to be these two define
functions encode them that Enders and
and your functions do not have side
effect that is functional programming
now what I'm going to say is that when
you do this when you you know do this
for a year for two years doesn't matter
what language what project you know you
you just tried to do it when you do this
for one years two years two years then
then the other concept will come to you
not all of them it will come to you okay
the the Monad concept the careering the
function function composition the
immutability tail recursion and so on
and math they will kind of like come to
you because that that is when you learn
something at heart by yourself in a
sense you invented them you would you
discover this concept because this many
most of this concept are they arise
because most of them because of the
function of programming you find that
for example when you have functions
everything is a function
and nothing else no object nothing just
functions function definition call then
you started to they are something that
just happens to you for example you know
immutability will come up you know you
start to get that concept because
naturally naturally you will realize
that you know you don't want to change
variables and in fact you don't want
variables at all you you know even your
function you don't want local variables
no variables that can't comes to you
function composition comes to you okay
because when you have two functions you
want to call one after the other for
example you know you call one after
other for example f co G then whatever
output you want to call F you know then
you see when you do this for five years
you realize you know wouldn't be great
if I can't you know have a syntax or
something that combines name when you
have lots of functions so sequence of
one conscience that is functional
composition ok so what I'm saying is
that all the most of these concepts came
from it you know they are developed as a
either as a technique or concepts or you
know language features from functional
programming not all of them though but
closure for example closure is a
language programming language feature
that came from functional programming
when you want to have lexical scope of
variables yeah when you have okay here's
what how closure the concept of closure
happens okay first of all closure is a
programming language feature now this is
important okay because many of these
concept some are functional programming
concept some are techniques programming
techniques some are programming language
design features part of language
these things are distinct you know they
are very different okay
so closure
closure is not well you can say it's a
premier technique but actually closure
is a programming language feature okay
how did this feature came from I mean
where does the idea came from it came
from when you want a function you know
when you do functional programming you
know every variable of a function is
local then you start to think about
lexical scope why lexico why not dynamic
scope because lexical scope captures the
function you know you remember you doing
functional programming you don't want
side-effects function is like a unit by
itself input-output you don't want you
you know when you run the function you
don't want to oh that variable value
depends on you know some you know
something else that's you know somewhere
else change the value you don't want
that so that's the idea of lexical scope
and you also want nested function
because everything is the function so
why don't you have a function and have
another function defined inside it
because you need it just for this
function so you have nested function now
when you have lexical scope okay hold on
second so you have nested function and
also function programming another
concept comes up is a function that
returns another function or a function
that takes a function as argument you
see so when you have all these three
mixed together this lexical scope nested
definition functions and functions that
returns the function when you have these
three aspects desired aspect you know
you desire these three because you are
doing functional programming so when you
have these three aspects knowing a
language then something strange happened
that is closure because why because
mathematically when you have these three
together then you have an issue you have
a issue that what happens when a
function that returns a function but but
this nested function actually use
uses a variable that's outside of this
function you know that is the summary of
closure when this happens then you have
a question what would that variable be
you know that so eventually what that's
what you got closure but once you have
closure now this is important closure is
anti functional programming when you
have a closure but closure by definition
is a function with side effect and it is
also the arrangin of olp so you don't so
you know you don't want it many you know
many and the hacker types functional
programmers you know they they oh they
want closure they you know they talk
about it all day they want closure
closure it's no good if you are really
into functional programming at least in
my opinion which is also true okay
closure is a function with side effect
you don't want it don't don't you know
don't do that that that is why I don't
like closure because func closure by
definition is a violation of functional
programming it is a function with with a
side-effect okay so you know so we can
actually explain what closure is I I
don't know if you guys already know what
closure is let me read the comments okay
but you know I have a lot articles about
closure
I mean explaining closure so let's go to
jargons
okay joggers now in this page you can
learn many of these jackets Opie Opie
jog jog ins spectacular you learn about
what classes method ok this article this
arco is about how do you explain Opie
concepts such as class methods objects
and static versus instance variables and
constructors expenses
and access specifiers and inheritance
okay so all these jargons of Opie how
can you explain all these in terms of
functional programming in terms of just
functions so this article explains that
then you have the rise of class
hierarchy you know that's typical of
Java you know a Java the the rise of
mutation of in interface the rise of
abstract class in abstract methods as
Java the rise of iterators in
enumerators idiocy that's you know
Python is like that Java Python they
love they love the iterators and
enumerators and generators those are
those are all idiocy
what that's that's actually my biased
opinion okay somewhat biased and and
also JavaScript now has iterators and
generators idiocy you don't want that
okay don't you know what that's my
biased opinion okay but anyway so this
article explains oh okay oh this Opie
concept with examples and showing you
how you can explain them in terms of
functions you know that in terms of
functional programming paradigm so let
me show that Opie jargons and
complexities and you have list
comprehension this comprehension is also
idiocy it's not functional programming
okay
you know like there's a lot
misconception and misinformation out
there all these have caca types and you
know into programming languages they all
say oh yeah yeah yeah with you know this
comprehension you know even Haskell has
list comprehension yeah yes Haskell does
have this comprehension because Haskell
in this aspect is idiotic it's big
that's that's a idiocy of Haskell okay
this comprehension cska you don't want
it because why why is this comprehension
bad because what when you have a list
comprehension comprehension that's a
meanie language is a kind of a mini mini
language in your language and in this
mini language you have non functional
programming that's what happens you have
a little mini than functional
programming syntax in your language
that's that that is what this
comprehension is because you can see the
Audis you know the things okay anyway
these comprehensions so lambda bleep
hold repo is a new jargon that that
means you know the command-line
interface it was popular in the past ten
years or so today I'd always hear it
much in the past three years I don't
hear much but back partly it was popular
very popular big why because it came
from well repo or in the term repo it
eventually came from scheme functional
foreign language scheme beast wide web
hold you know it means something like
repeat evaluation and print loop okay
anyway then then the known function of B
you know for a while like think about 10
years ago from from about 2008 to 2017
it was 2016 functional programming you
know became popular because oh CPU
cannot be faster anymore things like
that so many of the non functional
languages in programmers they picked up
on some of the jargon so it becomes a
fashionable becomes you know popular so
they picked up repo you know everything
Oh rip Oh bleep oh do it this seam
ripper idiocy that those are the jargons
okay so what is repo so how should you
one coop oh you should code command
command line user interface why because
because that's a proper term otherwise
you know like you know repo is like when
you cook
you know like when you cook ha you could
gas combust crank run okay that's how
you caught coal car gas combust crank
run that's how idiotic are these people
calling you know command-line interfaces
ripple you know because it's you know
fashionable in popular anyway that's
that's that's digression repo is not
about functional programming well it's
related because repo came from it came
from you know the scheme this is in
particular the book you know the
structure and interpretation of computer
programs this book and so anyway rapport
crochet okay so if you want to know what
closure is I have article here that
explains in detail you have you know
exclosure example in in JavaScript in
Python 3 in : you know several examples
but ok I'm going to give get let's get
back to the function of programming and
and idioms and all the things that we
cannot talk about and also curve
incurring what is currying in computer
science
oh this is another big topic because in
computer science because there is a
troll this well I don't like the term
troll okay but John harab he's you know
other people call him troll just just as
many of them call me a troll ok john
harab is a very well-known troll on
functional programming languages on this
you know in this community in haskell
community john harab I don't call I
wouldn't call that him otro I'd I would
just call him an aggressive [ __ ] and
and sometimes he's idiotic you know he
he likes to yes
someone like me ok if you you know for
my criticizes you may say it's someone
like me because
in my opinion he said often okay he you
know he's got opinions he tried to push
them but often you know it's just wrong
he's just incorrect and here's an
example and one day you know in his book
you know he has a book teaching you
f sharp no not F sharp okay mo okay okay
mo for scientists and here's a quote you
know let me magnify this you know here's
a quote you know he says what currying
is he says a curried function is a
function which returns a function as its
result wrong okay he also says curried
functions are best introduced as a more
powerful alternative to the conventional
non curried functions provided by
imperative programming languages anyway
his definition of curving a curry a
curried function is a function which
returns a function as its we thought now
that is patently incorrect it's
incorrect so it's it's it's not just you
know nitpicking this is so incorrect
it's it's totally completely incorrect
and misleading okay so he's saying if
you have a function that returns a
function that's a curried function what
I ETS see you know complete idiocy so he
likes to do that he do that you know
then he thought you know he flame you
know with these people with Haskell
people all the time like every day is
idiot in many ways you know obviously
he's a smart guy you know he does he has
projects and you know tutorial things
and so on anyways you know he's you know
currying definition is just completely
wrong curving Karimi is actually the
composition of functions the composition
of functions that has multiple
parameters more than one parameters into
a sequence of functions each with only
one parameter that is what Kareem is
about now a curried function
is a function you know is one of the
function in this curry the sequence you
know it's not about a function returning
a function that's you know that's
completely idiotic because in Lisp in
Mathematica you don't have the current
concept ok currying actually curry ok
Kareem is a decomposition of functions
of multiple variables two functions of
each with just one variable okay when
one argument when parameter that's a
definition of curry now curry being a
programming language as a feature is is
a feature such that it does this
automatically so when you define a
function of multiple variables the the
language has a feature that can
automatically you know decompose the
function into several functions with
just one argument now that that is
currying as a feature of the programming
language what language does that Haskell
does that meta language does that or
camo Oh F sharp those are the same
family okay so those languages does that
has that feature on the other hand
Mathematica Lisp scheme do not have that
feature okay but however Mathematica at
least scheme including JavaScript they
they had have the feature such that a
function can return a function and you
do that all the time well not so much in
this but you do that all the time in
Mathematica in JavaScript everyday okay
every big every every year every you
know 500 lines of code you have that
that a function returns a function that
is not Korean you know that's not
occurring at all that's the idiot of
John Herod okay so this article explains
what is currying okay so so you know so
like I said before all these you know
many of these jargons came from
functional programming this
comprehension came from function you
know
as inheritance it kind of came from the
context of functional programming but
this comprehension itself is actually
anti functional programming you know
don't do that lambda is functional
programming crochet also came from
functional forming but it's not it's
anti functional programming Korean came
from functional programming tail
recursion tail recursion is from scheme
this scheme bees phonetics they are you
know tail recursion every day ok those
are the about you know the jargons from
functional programming and you know
anyway so you know check out that page
if you like to learn about those things
and let's get back to let's get back to
a functional programming style ok I
haven't said we have not begin to talk
about that yet we are what we are
talking about related in that direction
so 30 minutes now so let me have a sip
of my drink and read the comments and
let's continue let's see where I go
where we go next
so let me say so let me read the
comments ok so copy the comments close
that go back to my Emacs magnify open ok
speed above open Anubhava pasted switch
buffer go to diet copy the file path
cross go back to this buffer say type it
and text ok bad is the common and copy
the file path go over here paste the
link link off' i okay showing browser so
we have a link to the other comments ok
so I'm gonna read the comments and so if
you have a comments put my name there
and and you know our answer it like
right now
pyramids in Egypt yes and one in Las
Vegas yes I have a photo did you I did a
talk on Las Vegas so I did a talk on Las
Vegas few months ago pepto thank you can
you give an example of functional
JavaScript oh yeah sure
that's a that's a big topic I like I can
just do an entire one hour on that
actually I could we could do that as you
know it's an actual example because the
example is always good yeah so so so
okay so you can example of JavaScript
function of a whammy okay
maybe we talked about that example of
function programming in JavaScript you
know that's actually a good thing to do
because that actually shows you country
concrete you know concepts and code you
can see what's the difference well
functional or non-functional what does
it mean side-effect you know how do you
do a loop
how do you do map you know you know all
these things or how do you avoid for
example you know many details if we
actually start to code a language so
many joining good morning Justin so
Justin am I wrong to say that has cow
list comprehension in Haskell is kind of
idiotic you know sometimes like you know
when I say opinions like that I have a
solid background okay so it's not
[ __ ] okay so but however depending
on your interpretation you could say
that's not really the right thing to say
you know it's not really so let me put
this way it's not really it's not really
completely correct to say that list
comprehension in Haskell
idiotic well first of all that that
sentence does not have exact meaning you
know what do you mean it does is you
know what he so anyway so it's opinion
so so Justine so you know if you have
opinions on this comprehension he has
called me no because I do not know has
God you know I have never coded coded
Haskell technically sabatham you say is
to be honest I don't have good idea on
functional programming in general okay
so I should I should do more let's yeah
you know you should I you know I'm gonna
do more JavaScript because well that's
what I have to do you know there's a lot
JavaScript topics and all my JavaScript
is almost pure functional programming no
object whatsoever so next time we do it
you can see it oh you know if you yeah
when I do it you know you'll see how it
is different from the non functional
methods I do not I do not do any you
know non functional every everything I
ever wrote in any languages or
functional and I I do it just like I
explained today you know functions
everything is function you could you
define function you call it no side
effect if if if at all possible and that
is all basically oh I focus on and I
don't I don't usually go for you know
for example tail recursion or monad I
don't actually I don't technically
understand monad okay this is a bad
marketing thing to say oh my god that
guy don't even know what is monad but
he's talking about stuff that okay
anyway so so yeah oh these you know the
jargons I mentioned I don't do them I
don't you know least comprehension and I
never use them except if you're working
a you know company you know you have to
make other people happy I never used
them yeah you don't and don't use them
you know those I don't use them okay so
the closure never use closure you know
and what else so anyway so like I said I
thought you know defined functions
functions no side effect that that is it
and you can see when I do JavaScript
project you can see how that works out
you know you can't you can you know as a
concrete example and let's see jargons
you know not not not any of these Korean
Korean again is you know Carini's again
you know many of these are kind of
advanced currying is kind of like it's
nice you know it's fantastic if your
language supported but otherwise no you
know it's not practical you know it's
basically is trying to so what why do
you have Kareem let me explain what why
do you want to you know a function that
has multiple variables for example you
want to add two numbers let's knit knits
to JavaScript concrete the example okay
so let's define a function constant
arrow functions so let's have you know
this is a function let's call it FF and
you want to add two numbers XY okay so
you want to return X plus y okay that's
a function and now you call it call it
FF three and four so it should return
seven okay comment this out so let's run
it seven now now you see this is a
function with two variables we we can
actually do a career right now so this
is a function of two variables okay so
so first of all why why does curving
happen I mean why why I mean where does
a concept come from why do you want it
it came from theoretical computer
science notice the word theoretical
meaning that it has nothing to do with
programming whatsoever
it's about theoretical computer science
is about decidability about lambda
calculus about Turing machines about you
know those kind of things
can you don't never you ever never use
anything from those okay so why does
curry in fact curry happens for math
okay curving the concept happens because
because in theoretical computer science
in formal languages such as lambda
calculus you want to simplify your
syntax you want to avoid many
complexities there so so basically so so
so the basic idea is when you have a
function with variables typically you
don't want variable you know you don't
want the parameters okay when lambda
calculus you know you have you have
lambda calculus okay so I think actually
came from lambda calculus anyway
lambda calculus you have a function with
one variable okay and you can apply a
function basically you just replace that
variable by input and come out another
string all these are formal languages
you know basically you are just doing
stream and emulation that's what lambda
calculus is okay so anyway lambda
calculus you have a function you have
you know one input and come out stream
you know and the the the variable is
typically annoying because it you know
it's you call that parameter dummy
variable it's annoying because because
then you have a problem of when you do
find it replace for example when you do
find replacing Emacs owing any word
processor you like for example when you
are doing refactoring refactoring your
code let's say let's see let's go to
let's go to my code okay
for example list code so I want to
replace for examples let's say this
function okay so let's say some some
variable name let's say X you want to
change the variable you you want to do a
refactor you want to change your
variable named X to Y let's say for
example but you cannot simply do a fine
replace because when you do find replace
find X replace Y then you run into a
bunch of you know all these bunch of
words that's that's not a whole variable
you know you got into this problematic
situation so it would be nice if all
your variable names are unique in the
entire project then when that happens
then you can do find replace okay you
can just do find replace for example
find replace for example you have a
variable named X you know 2 1 2 3 3 you
just you just call for example you just
go for example I copy that find replace
that with Y and you just replace the
whole project the entire directory so
that's about fine replace now fine
replace is the essence in kind of the
essence of lambda calculus or all formal
languages so when you have a line by
calculus when you have a function lambda
with a variable when you apply a
function what do you want to do is you
want to find all the variable name and
replace it by some other stream that
that's what happens and the calculus
that's that's what happens when you call
a function so it becomes a new stream
but now you have a problem you need to
find all those all those variables you
know for example a symbol Y of you know
Y or some other you know symbol so so
that is why variable is kind of a
problem you know and also what happens
if you have nested lambdas you know like
nested functions so then you have
contexts you know the scope concept
comes in you know scope then you don't
know X is like what you know is this
function or you know is when you have a
nested function you don't know you know
what X really is which X to replace
that's a problem so so you so you want
you know you want to reduce you want to
kind of you can
you you you don't you know so very boss
has this problem that's why people
invented Y Combinator and also in this
from across you have hygienic Marco
that's also related concept hygienic
Marco that happens because because when
you are doing Marco basically the
variable names conflict you know they
stamp on each other you know that that's
what happened that's why you want
hygienic Marco you know so the same
problem was the same concept have many
consequences or ideas so anyway let's
get back to the what I'm talking about
so so lambda calculus and find and
replace and those are formal languages
so you don't want variables oh so where
does the Kareem concept happen okay in
lambda calculus in lambda calculus every
function only have one variable lambda
you know lambda just one one a parameter
okay every function has just one
parameter then you might say okay well
that that doesn't represent computing
because some what what if you want to do
you know you write a function that adds
two numbers addition you know two plus
three how can you represent that in
lambda calculus well so that's where the
careening concept came from theoretical
this is all theoretical so you so
mathematician know that you know realize
okay if you have a function with
multiple variables actually you can
decompose it into a sequence of function
cause each function only have one
variable you see so they are totally
equivalent therefore lambda calculus you
don't need a lambda with more than one
parameter you know every lambda is just
one parameter so that's lambda calculus
you know you don't need multiple
variables so that that's the concept
that's our ancient of the concept Kareem
you know from theoretical computer
science it's not about programming
whatsoever and this happens like long
ago 50 years ago sick P you know before
there is you know
memory chips you know CPU like today
before that but but anyway all these
concept eventually they becomes part of
the language you know has cow you know
so has cow okay mo ml meta language you
know they have automatic function
decomposition you know multiple multiple
parameters you know they have currying
the the feature of Corrine so that is
that is about okay so why I forgot yeah
so I was explaining the origin of
Corrine and from theoretical computer
science search as lambda calculus and
also okay so let's just keep that just
let's just leave it that okay and okay
let's answer the more questions so
Bethany say someone what is functional
programming lambda okay so in Python map
view to do work with lambda functions
not so bad no not really
okay Daniel says map theater no you know
why not that's why I say lamb you know
Python is not does not support
functional programming big you know if
you code Daniel if you code you know
Python Europe you know at the company
and you you you you use map and filter
in lambda people will beat you you know
he'll beat you up you get you get fired
I can tell you probably don't code
Python much or you don't coded in a
company environment you know they'll
beat you up you get fired just Oh
alternatively just just try to go to the
Python may be nice you know let's say I
have you know let's go to stack overflow
and try to write something we involving
you know map field walk in lambda
immediately someone will mention no you
shouldn't do that you know to you know
use the the iterators now iterators he
well iterators or the list comprehension
because Kaido hated those and so python
has guide you know in programming
guidance so uh you know so if you keep
using map theater in lambda
people say we all know oh that that
garden you know he's a troll or he is a
idiot he doesn't help you'll get that
you'll come to you I I still refuse I
refuse to use the you know the iterate
you know the best comprehension in stuff
I try to keep using map field
well sometimes you you know I get
changed because you know it's it's not
not a matter of style anymore because
the Python people they hate functional
programming so much so that when you
actually do you know you stamped a few
to map it affects your program your
program becomes slower you rather you
know you rather use the list
comprehension or iterators whatever you
know the generators iterators [ __ ] you
have to you have to do that because
otherwise you have code actually runs
much slower so you see this is beyond
programming Styles
you know so so that that is why also I I
say that Python does not really support
functional programming you just you just
you run into problems all over the place
social problems and you know the
technical detail like you know the speed
problems you run into problems these
problems are not not functional
programming problems it's Python people
problem you know they they create the
language they they they focus on them
functional programming make it run
faster so you know so you
- you are forced in a way to do it that
way - you know Python you know the
Python community so-called pythonic you
have to do it in a Python equate these
jug and idiots hacker types so bathroom
uses is your opinion against or pee your
personal opinion or because of reasons
well both it's my personal opinion for
sure and also because well then you know
you can say you know also because I
think it really you know you die in my
opinion I think almost that the whole
world should not use Opie Opie is just a
mistake it's a bad but but this opinion
it then becomes controversial it depends
on who you ask
I mean essentially when it comes to
programming Styles programming
methodology there is no one answer okay
there's no Universal answer you know
it's not math you know it's it's not
mathematics because why why is it not
math because it's about programming
style right now we don't have tours
formalization to understand the whole
thing because otherwise I can you know I
can just prove here's the proof
functional programming is better than
hope he always you know I write the
proof but we don't have the framework
for this kind of thing yet we don't
there are there are still questions and
the end and as far as style goes you
know they you know for example like
writing Styles writing style writing
English writing style novel writing
style you know you have different styles
and do we have a like do do we have a
academic study that tries to formalize
you know turn these style thing into a
math so that we can say oh this style is
better in some way or not we don't have
that you know the human endeavors you
know we are not at the point where
though everything in every question in
the world is mathematics we don't have
that so
so yeah Opie today for sure okay today
you know on the whole industry all the
programmers considered it is understood
to allowed people at least you know a
lot of people you know they will say
yeah Opie is just no good well
especially the functional programmers
you go ask them or functional
programming academics you know they they
don't think Opie but you know then on
the other hand a lot of people C++ Java
they all say oh oh PC you know this is
the only practical way you know so we
don't have an answer for that Daniel
says reduce the price rolling
computation to sequential Parris this
computation actually works in Python
like these okay 1 2 3 5 7 9 yeah
sabatham you says I heard a lot
beginners say saying they don't
understand monad and use it the wrong
way
Manik you don't don't you don't use it
don't learn it I I know enough to know
what I'm talking about
so when do you use Manik you small Aetna
monad only when you actually programming
Haskell when you program your house cow
well then it's absolutely it's necessary
and it's great that you learn monad and
learn it well and use it ok that is that
is that in Haskell oh similar you know
similar language is kind of you know
Idris or whatever you know you know when
waiting that you are in that situation
yeah you can do it but otherwise don't
you know this is it's one of those
dramatic thing you know that goes viral
monad tail recursion you know Cosi see
like everyone is talking about it in
practice it's you is kind of like
useless okay it's useless
okay so Justine says you need more nanny
has cut it has got to do any kind of
side effect code yes okay I can yeah I
can see that and I I would agree
what about recursion like in JavaScript
in general don't use recursion okay in
general don't use don't use recursion -
neither okay
recursion you know recursion is again
recursion is one of the traumatic thing
recursion recursion is one of the
dramatic thing among the hacker types
you know the who tells you what to do of
you know the language style writing
styles idioms especially yeah especially
from the functional programming people
recursion and also where does recursion
came from it came from theoretical
computer science okay or internally
because you know actually you have a
term code because recursion theory which
is misleading okay recursion theories
actually about computability you know
decidability theory okay that's all
theoretical computer science in other
way like Tareen machines and lambda
calculus they are so abstract and far
away - between average programmers even
ask our programmers they know nothing
zero nothing about it they what they
know it's like to me machine they they
have it in their mouth every day or
something oh this is Turing complete
language oh oh that is curing complete
language idiots okay turning complete
you know your piece stream when you go
to bathroom take a piece your pee stream
is chewing complete like when you when
you talk about some this concept of a
math concept Oh everything you you need
to have a context then you realize why
daddy you know how important that term
is when you don't have the contact on
test you know you just say you don't
know like like children says oh we have
a flying car you know what does the
children do you think flying car is
important how important is a doubt you
know
we have trains we have foodies trains we
have airplanes we have helicopters we
have bus we have bicycles what kind of
communication then we understand what we
need to do transportation then then you
you know you have the context then the
word flying cars comes to your mind you
know oh that's you know you you know
where you know that thing is in the
whole context you know okay that's a you
know you'll be nice to have something
but they say children in five years old
they say they talk about oh I'll give oh
my dad says flying car you know
something what does he know you know
that that's in the same way you know
when when these people are talking about
tail recursion recursion oh the you know
the Monad stuff you know those are
traumatic words so recursion came from
well anyway so recursion you don't do it
in general because recursion it's it's
extremely elegant because it captures it
captures recursion you know it captures
what's going on in kind of in kind of
precise detail that's what recursion
does okay but by the way there's a there
are many meanings to the word recursions
also in theoretical computer science it
means something else you know but for
typical programmers it means you know
coding a function a function that calls
itself that's recursion you know for
average programmers that's what
recursion is and scheme people you know
they love it
please people as well specifically the
scheme people love it but in general
don't do it or the other than scheme
well if you coding scheme yeah do it do
it you know but other in in JavaScript
for example don't do it why because it
makes your code harder to understand
actually yes it makes it actually harder
to understand also typically it's it's
slower okay because it's it's harder to
implement it you know then you have tail
recursion okay
you know and recently you know in
JavaScript es2015 tail recursion became
part of JavaScript okay meaning that if
you write a recursion code and if it's
tail recursion then it's guaranteed to
be fast linear time any way that that's
more details but anyway in general don't
we don't do recursion okay in general
because when you write code that's
iterative that's actually easier much
easier to understand what's what's going
on what the code is doing and also it's
faster simpler things like that and also
when you do recursion when you have a
bug it's it's hard it's hard to get it
right you know you it's hard to get it
right so just in says okay so I'm gonna
read more comments so just in says this
is great advice program simple
functional programming first and you
will start to spot patterns
yeah then learn to advance things so
daniel says small ad Moana don't get
bombarded by penetrate category theory
yeah
similar management sometimes gonna you
know so monad is you know actually I
don't
let's not talk about monad because I
don't really know Haskell
but basically basically nomura is a way
to capture side effect in a in some kind
of a side-effect free way you you
capture you know is kind of like that so
bathroom you says why are iterators bad
that's well first of all iterators okay
first of all iterators when you do
anything with it erasers that's not
functional programming okay so in
today's talk context that's why it's bad
you don't want it because it's not
functional programming in fact
iterators with
came from it came from Opie it kind of
came from all P languages they try to
they try to they try to make the loop
they tried to make improve the for loop
they try to improve the for loop and
because it's all P so they tried to make
improve the whole the for loop in a ob
way then you got iterators okay they try
to abstract it in a all P style so you
got iterators iterators does not exist
in functional programming languages well
today you see some of these things gets
complex because now today in many
functional programming languages
you also have iterators you know then
you become you know so it becomes like
what what does an object me object means
so many things in different languages in
the same way iterator is iterator is
mostly a thing from object-oriented
programming languages you have iterate
iterate errs in Java in Python in
JavaScript okay
but in traditional functional languages
you don't have that at all but I think
today you you might have that in some
functional languages is that true do
they have iterators inch in Haskell
adjusting so how long I've been talking
so okay this is getting too long I guess
okay so we should wrap up and so why is
iterative bad actually I have article if
you want to read it or we can we can
explain it in some other day but let's
go to semantic new dos let's search for
ETA raters okay iterators so here
programming language design iterator not
enumerator abstract abstraction went
wrong
now I wrote this article because I
always I always hated iterators and the
enumerators or these kind of stuff so I
posted on Google+ and one guy you know
he he's a C program expert okay so in
doing our exchange he mentioned you know
in a sense iterator is bad is good
because it actually abstract away the
for loop you know you know P like we
showed before in JavaScript you have for
loop which is kind of ugly you know
there's no structure you know it's just
for I equals to 1 when I is less than 10
you know up to I Inc increment I then
you do something you know that's kind of
no structure kind of you know for loop
so OPP vote improved it so they kind of
abstract it so instead of just syntax
you know for I equals or something they
created a object where the object is a
list of items for example this you know
OB object you have list items inside it
then you have a method you know that
like the iterator enumerator you have a
method that will go through these items
that that is basically what iterators is
about you know they're just doing for
loop being a more kind of OB way
structured OB way so so the question
then here's a question to me you know so
I hate iterator so much well but then
the OB people will say well iterator is
actually just a abstraction you know so
so abstraction is typically good so also
so that seems to counter so what is my
actual hatred for iterators you know how
can can I possibly write them out you
know as a logical reason why do I hate
iterators so here's my answer
basically my answer is it's abstraction
went wrong okay because abstraction you
see the thing about abstraction is
that you can abstract anything in any
way you know I can abstract you know you
have to actually try to do it I mean you
look at the programming language there
are medium ways you can abstract medium
ways you know of a programming language
you can do it like almost arbitrary and
so you can create a result that is just
basically pure garbage incomprehensible
garbage by by abstraction you know that
you can do that so so my logical reason
again is iterator the logical reason is
they are simply just bad abstraction
okay you shouldn't that that's why
anyway so that's my reason about that
let me just focus on the comments
addressed to me then for hope he was a
mistake but by the way that's not
controversial at all because a lot of
people I mean if you you know if you
follow programming languages that's not
controversial at all you will hear a lot
actually a lot articles even from 1980s
for example let me show you some you
know articles from old school people
these these programmers for example
let's go to semantic noodle iterators
okay so I explained my reasons but there
is a much older guy
see this Arco iterators science of
weakness in object-oriented languages
this is written in 1992 by Henry G Baker
now Henry G Baker is a famous Lisp
programmer he's a computer science ok I
think he you can look him up
I think he's got a article I mean
Wikipedia is a entry of him so you can
kind of you know look so he wrote Alko
back in 1992
that's criticizing iterators you know
you can read that and let me go back to
Oh P jargons explaining functional
concepts okay so this article had a very
button you have you have this guy let's
let's open jaws scoff Ali he wrote an
article in 2016 he wrote a blog
goodbye object-oriented programming and
in my opinion is pretty good so this is
his criticism of Opie and apparently he
is Opie guy you know he bought into Opie
for ten years and and any in this blog
he he take you know he decomposes all
these Opie myth you know that's supposed
to be good the interns are actually
doesn't work out inheritance for example
inheritance and the diamond problem the
crass problem the base class problem you
know anyway the base class problem the
hierarchy problem encapsulation the myth
of encapsulation in capitalization is
crap you know get a degree you know
anyway so that's his take you know I I
explained my take here so you can read
his you know it's so today among
especially among a lot functional for me
you know function of Hermes becoming
very popular you have that in JavaScript
you have that enclosure in Haskell you
know Haskell is using Facebook you know
okay mo is also using Facebook f-sharp
Microsoft invented F sharp which is a
okay more derivative you know so all
those are functional programming so
functional programming today it's not a
niche anymore it's rather it's a kind of
still minority I would say but it's
pretty big so the criticism of all P is
actually mainstream is not
it's not a you know crazy idea anymore
so so oh if he is a mistake that's
actually you know minority view but but
pretty pretty mainstream now so anything
else I think I'm going to end it now
like let's say one more minutes or two
more minutes something like that so any
new comments posted okay
and actually I need to go to I need to
go as well so so let me read the
comments so another rise or not hang
window windowing
attach - good morning from good morning
to chilly can you talk about two J's
write a English - Brielle converter yes
we can do that not today let's do that
next time okay so next time let's maybe
we do that tomorrow
and we can explain that but you know you
you know come to my you know yeah you
you come you know it would be great if
you come you know early then you say
that we can do that because otherwise
other people we cover other topics
change yours I copied the bad one I mean
talk about this for understand
JavaScript object in depth okay so yeah
JavaScript object in depth so we can
talk about about that next next time yes
react.js Abdo yes in Web Audio API and
Dre so and Ray you talk you talking
about that avi all the time are you are
you did you write that API or something
like looks like you are trying to sell
that apip five dollar JJ s like you
talked about that few times and I don't
know nothing about it
you know and I I talked about why it's a
problem
so are you like are you are you
marketing are you marketing for that
team or something what's your
interesting that you know type it why
are you doing that where are you
interesting that
so yeah such you know I don't want to
such a I mean yeah we did it last time
you were here
p5.js logarithmic frequency stroke
spectrum yeah so and Ray say it like
answer you know why are you interested
in that you know would a logarithm
I don't like logarithms you know
logarithm is the math function ID
I don't like logarithms
so anything else that's it for today so
a spinal spinal champ says can use
samples from your streams in music yes
of course yes feel free you know make
derivative work of Sally talk shocks are
touchy okay make ensued and make a mean
make a mean spam the other chance you
should you should read window function
on Wikipedia what are you talking about
and Ray what window functions okay
analysis good float what okay so that's
it for today I think that's it for today
so spinal champ spinal champ I forgot
you from where you from
so are you like what are you trying to
make
Spano champ what are you trying to make
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching thank you bathroom you and
g-tron crazy great to see you here and
adjusting and oh you guys are you people
that's it for today and I go to take a
piss and I go to eat or whatever and you
guys go do whatever it is that you guys
do in different countries so bathroom
you you're gonna wake up you're gonna do
work or whatever and Abdo by right by