hello guys
we are here today to go through the
difficult problem
of coding emacs leads welcome to another
episode of talk show
we have some technical difficulties
before earlier on
and but you guys are here and we start
over
so today is 2020 september 5th
uh 11 o'clock in the morning san
francisco
time and we are going to code emac lisp
dearly beloved so what we are going to
do
let me announce what we're going to do
to do okay so you can see
i'm going to um i'm going to insert
a hr horizontal break so you see there's
a horizontal break and showing browser
and you can see there is a horizontal
break let's
you know let's put two two of them you
can see two of them
now but in the buffer i want that i want
to show them
as a line you know as a line like uh
like these okay you see display them as
a line
so that is what we are going to do today
okay and let's start to code emacs lisp
so far so good everyone uh good morning
bot
and good morning reaper
okay let me double check one more time
are we
am i doing good i'm doing good video
check audio check okay
so let's start to code emac this
so we want to show this as a line so
what we do first of all you go to
search for xrd emax tutorial
text properties so the way we are going
to do it is using text properties
now in the past two videos or three i
have
we done several coding uh using text
properties
so what they are is basically in in
emacs
every text in a in a buffer
you can attach a property list
to the text any region of the text you
can attach a property list
and this list is basically a list of key
value pairs
so you you could you could attach for
example these
these a few words you get you can say
you attach your text property and you
say you want the face to be read
key value pairs then when emacs display
this buffer it will show it
as red that this is how syntax coloring
is done for example this red
uh for example this blue that's syntax
coloring okay
so text properties so that that is how
we gonna do so let's
start a new buffer and let's uh
let's define a function and let's call
this function
uh let's say uh show
hr as line so that's a
that's a command name by the way so
yesterday i learned a trick
from jeff the host of
emacs sf meetup if you search
you know search the web emacs sf meetup
you'll find it uh it's a emac san
francisco group
and we are doing uh you know he's doing
uh online meetup now about every two
weeks
so yesterday i learned a tip from him
where how you can use text properties to
display
to make emacs show some certain text as
a line or something else or even a
picture
entirely so that is a fantastic feature
and i'm going to explore it today i
haven't done this before so you are
going to
look at me struggle struggle about so
anyway
so back to the code so you can see we
started
a um you know we start we started a
template
uh function show hr as line
and dark string or the old important
doctrine okay
display now i always
my habit is always to write the
specification before i
begin to code that is my habit now
different programmers often i think most
programmers they
they just start to code but
documentation is all important and
that's what i do so i write the spec
before i
even before i go so so this doc string
will say
display hr tag as a line
in current buffer okay then give it a
version
and give it today's date my convention
okay let's begin the code so
so how do we begin to do it well first
of all
you need in order to attach text
properties you need to find the
beginning and end position of something
okay let's go back to so this is uh this
is my talk show page you can see showing
browser
magnify magnify so back to the elise
code so we need to find
you know we need to find the beginning
and end position of that
of all these hr in the buffer okay
so back to here so
uh begin let's begin go to character
point amendment point minimum is the
beginning of buffer that's so that's
that
point minimum returns the position
of the of the minimum uh
position which is usually one okay so go
to the beginning of buffer
then search forward we are going to
search for this
hr stream you know we want to find the
position
okay so optional bound
neo no error true count we don't care
so now once it's you know search for
move the cursor
once emacs found it it will place it
you know at the end so how do we so
right now our problem is to find the
position of this
you know beginning and end position of
these this string
so there's a way uh
match data okay uh wait
match data i believe
oh match beginning there it is match
beginning
uh yeah match end yeah so match
beginning and match end is what we want
so which let's introduce two um
variables p1 and p2 that's position one
and position two
and here set p1 equals to
uh match beginning now match beginning
one
okay match beginning beginning zero so
what does that mean so you can look up
the documentation for match beginning
you call describe function and there's
you'll see the
uh the documentation for the match
beginning function so match beginning
zero zero basically means the
entire matched string okay so that's the
beginning
so that returns the beginning position
uh basically
here you know the beginning location of
the hr
so similarly we want to set point two
to the match end zero okay
so now we got point prettify the code
okay so now we got so far so good
yes okay now we got beginning and end
position now we
want to add a text properties to
to this region good morning but
sometimes the spec evolves during
development yeah
right um well yeah you you can always
rewrite your uh spec good morning
contest good morning jetwa
okay so let's continue uh our code so we
got the beginning and end position of
this hr string in a buffer
then what to do next next what to do
next is we want to add a text property
so attach
a key value pair to this region of text
so how do you do that you say put
text properties i think no
okay so
i don't remember so let's look at uh put
text properties yeah so that's the thing
you want to add
okay copy it go back to the buffer go
back to the lisp code
list code so
wait uh
yeah so that's the code put text
property that we
so then you give it the first two
argument is the beginning position
and end position you tell emacs that
between this position
the text you want to add some some uh
text properties
so the key will be found log face okay
uh let's just say face uh the key will
be face
you tell emacs uh the face and the value
will be
the value will be
that's this is interesting part okay so
let's for now let's just say red
foreground red okay
let's say background red just just to
make it some interesting
background red okay so you can see
background red okay prettify the code
uh so is that all
i think that's all so evaluate the
buffer
now go back to the html
okay go back to html we are going to
call the code
after we call the code this hr should be
read
okay let's what's the code name what's
the command name
show hr as line okay meta x
show hr as line do it
okay error symbols values variable is
void
p1 okay so we got the error so
symbols value as variable is void of
course
because because we are calling
p1 p2 here but however
the let the block for the variable p1 p2
you know it's outside of it so we we
need to move this
line inside of it
inside this let block
okay there predefine the code
evolve the buffer back to the html
call the command it hr is line do it
did not work did it work no it did not
work
why is that i don't know let's go to the
messages buffer is there any error it
doesn't say
the message buffer is mum
okay so in that case let's go back to
the list code
maybe the background is wrong
let's let's you know let's not
foreground let's just try foreground
because that's the code for my website
and uh that should be correct so
you know maybe for the background you
have some other names that you know
that's why it doesn't work so
so okay so let's see is that good
eval the code back to the html code
call the command show hdr as line
it did not work okay
why is that something is wrong
okay maybe maybe it should be font lock
face the key
should be found lock face not face
because i you know i was changing it on
a whim
maybe i shouldn't do that by the way
face
should also be valid you know but maybe
i forgot something or something
uh so okay this this part should be
font lock face okay evolve the buffer
go back to the html call the command
do it red fantastic now it's red
okay now that's not what we want you see
we are just doing this to show that
show to show that our code actually
works you know we
we added a text property to this region
but what we really want is to have this
hr
showing us you know a bunch of lines
so we can do that easily so you see here
when we add a text property we are
adding
we are saying you know use the keyframe
log face
and the value will be you know
foreground red or this
expression instead of that
what we should do actually is uh let me
show you here okay what we should do
is
let's let's uh what we should do hold on
a second
let's predefine the code uh
okay what should what what we should do
is we
not not font lock face we should say
display okay
display that's a key so when you add a
text property to a region
now remember text property is a bunch of
key value pairs
now some of the key the keys can be
arbitrary
for example you can the key can be a
honey can be a b
can be anything you know you add to the
text property and
then you can you know get those
property names and do something about it
but however
certain property names have spilled in
meaning in emacs in imagbeast
for example so you go to my text you
know you go to my tutorial just search
for exactly
uh emaclis text properties then you
scroll down you can see
you can see some of these keys are
meaning
meaningful to emacs font log face face
syntax table key maps okay i'm not going
to explain them
well you know found lock face and face
is for when you want to change the
appearance of some text
that's what you do syntax table is for
if you want to change the cursor
movement behavior
you know for example comments or end of
word
you know you can use that key map is for
for example if your cursor is on a link
in some mod for example you press enter
it will open the link in the browser
how does that work usually it's because
of a keymap text property
you know when you press because when you
press enter
when your cursor is on a url
and emax you know is
the mod we are may have you know it
added
added a key map to that region so
so emacs will check that key map and and
and do whatever that key key says you
know it
might say if you press enter open the
file you
you know open the link in the browser so
that's
that's what key map is for so you see
text properties
is key value pairs and some of the keys
has has
meaning has building meaning in emacs
in emacs so you can see the official
documentation there's a bunch more
so you then you know you have category
you have face
here's the official emacs list manual
you know category
face front lock face mouse phase
quantified display
request quite there are quite a few
what we are what what we want to do is
to
to show that hr as a extra text as a
line
or even a picture so in order to do that
what we want to use is this display
uh property okay so you know the this
display key so you know it says this
property activates various features that
change the way text is displayed
for example it can make text appear
taller or shorter
higher or lower wider or narrow or
replace
with an image that's what we need okay
let's look at a detail
text properties you know emacs this
documentation is 900 pages so so you
have a lot to read
i have a lot to read okay the display
properties that's what we're going to
use
so back to our code emacs list code
we are going to add a display
property here so you can see now what
shall the value be
uh wait uh wait so
what should the value be let's let's
check the documentation
okay let's look at the comments any
comments comments
alain and alan and daniel
and is easel weasel
hi guys okay questions and comments just
post it okay i'll read it periodically
okay so what are we going to um
add to the you know what do we
how do we make this work so we need to
add the display property so i have to
read okay
now last time some of my last time in
two or three episodes ago i there are
some these
experts in my in my group
you know they suggest me things that's
fantastic
so if you guys know the answer just tell
me okay
so we we so so let's look at let's read
the display property okay
the display text property or overlay
property is used to insert images
into text and to control other aspects
of how text
displays okay the value of the display
property
should be a display specification
okay or a list of vector containing
several display specifications
okay display specifications in the
in the same display property value
generally apply in parallel to the text
they cover okay if several sources
overlay
and or text properties specify values
for the display property
only one of the values takes effect okay
following the value following the rules
of get
chart properties so that's a older kind
of priority
okay they are talking about priority if
you have overlap
you know uh properties like one part
says red
the other part says blue so anyway the
rest of this section describes
several kinds of display specifications
and what they mean
okay i think i i glanced at this a
little bit
yesterday the one we want to use
to to make it display as a line is the
other display spec
specs display on image adjusting the
height
spacing and other properties of text
okay i think that's what we need
so let's look at string okay i think
that's what we
want string display string instead of
the text
that has this property that's what we
want
recursive recursive display
specifications are not supported okay
so anyway strings what we want let's
let's try it
let's be uh interactive and let's try it
so we want to say uh wait how does it
say
what okay so so the value should be a
string
oh the value is should oh it should be
easy it's just a string
okay add a string let's say let's add a
bunch of string
let's say that okay eval buffer
now back to the html close it
we open it magnify magnify
you can see here's the hr
then we're gonna call the code once we
call the code
it should be a line let's see if it
works
do it yeah
fantastic success
successful okay so it turns out pretty
easy we are successful now
this is not done yet because for example
let's say
if we have another hr you see it doesn't
display you see
let's add another hr you see they are
not showing us a line because
why because because in our code
remember we searched for it
then you know we searched for it then we
showed them as a line
but however it stops right there you
know
it doesn't check the the next occurrence
so what we need is actually a loop
okay let's add a loop
while loop okay
while well we are
while we search for word you know search
for word
if it's found it will return i think it
returns a position so
position it's a true so while this is
found
then we're gonna do something we're
gonna do something here okay
then we're gonna do this is what we're
gonna do
grab those block of code put it here
prettify the code that's what that's
what we're gonna do
that's pretty fine
that's what we're gonna do so we have a
while loop here
while search for it
and if if if it's found we
set point p1 p2 and
actually that's yeah this will work i'm
sure
uh let's just run it okay run it back to
the html
call the command so remember you see we
have two hr
call the command do it
oh it moved it moved the cruiser to the
bottom that's no good
so we we need to fix that but let's
scroll up
there it is you see we got three we got
several lines so it's success
okay now let's continue to fix the code
we don't want to move the cruiser to the
bottom okay so
in order to do that you want to
save excursion so save excursion will
save the cruiser position you know
where they are once the command is done
it will return the cursor to
to where they are okay so let's see
uh
so we need to put this block of code
inside there
okay and also
we don't need the p1 and p2 anymore
do we um
okay it doesn't hurt to have them there
so anyway so we want
okay so we want we don't want uh we
don't need this red anymore let's just
display a line we don't want it red okay
and
let's make these lines let's make 50 of
them
okay so how do you insert 50 lines you
press ctrl u
you press ctrl u and
and type 50 and
press the character whatever character
you want so
in this case we are we are going to type
underscore there it is okay
even the buffer go back to html code
close it save it yes reopen it
magnify for a few times and page down
you can see our hdr here now
so we call the command show hdr is line
do it fantastic
so actually we are done actually this is
fantastic so
so okay so you see so this is the code
so what you do is that you know you put
this code
in your emacs init then every time you
open
html you call the code you know you
you call the command then you'll display
that yeah but we
but this is tedious we want it automatic
so in order to do that you can add a mod
i mean you can add a hook
for example let's add a hook okay so for
example
ad hook okay ad hook
so so what is a hook you know you just
search for xrd
emax hook you'll find my tutorial about
it
but basically a hook in
e-max is kind of an event okay in other
programming in javascript for example in
other environments it's usually called
event a hook is kind of a event handler
so so so what we want to do is that
whenever this mod x htm
html mod is activated
you want to run
this command this function so the event
is whenever html mod is activated
the event handler is this function so in
emacs the way you do that
is first of all you find out what's a
hook name
hook name is kind of like the event name
so the event name is going to be
um by convention it's a mod name
appended with a hook for example the mod
name the mod name for this
mod let me tell you okay
i can tell you directly uh the
the hook will be xr dash html dash
mod dash hook that's the hook name
which is kind of like the event event
then the function the function is just
uh
our function show hr a slide so what
this means is that whenever
html mod is run then it will run this
this function okay so
evaluate the buffer go to html close it
do i want to save yes reopen it
no it works you see they already show us
a lie because
because the hook ran you know the hook
just ran
okay fantastic i think that's um
that is about it today i mean how long
have i been talking let's see
we can now we i mean so the main thing
actually is
done 20 28 minutes fantastic
so i think maybe we shut down uh or you
guys have any questions
any we can chat random for 10 minutes
um so basically yeah let's
you know so post your comments or
questions okay
so basically this is the code it's
already done
now since you see i'm you see
i have my own so so if you want this to
work
in your emacs you can add a hook uh what
you can do
is you can do this
you know just add it to html mod hook
actually uh actually
you want to add a mhtml mod
hook you know in emacs there are
several there are there are two at least
two html mod building
if you are using emacs 27 or 20
uh 27 or 26 the the the default mod
when you open the file ending.html
is the mhtml mod
okay for example let's go back to my mod
okay
let's go back to my html file here i
made my html file
i can call the command i can say mhtml
mod okay enter so that's
mhtmlmr that's that's the um
that's the uh that's the default emacs
mod
hold on a second close it reopen it
okay magnify wait
uh hold on a second let's make let's go
to fundamental mod
meta x fundamental mod
okay i um what i'm trying to show you
is that you see
all these are still showing us a line
because
i guess because our code already added
this property
so the property is not removed so even
if you switch to some other mod
you still see them as a line because the
the text property is already there it's
not it's not being removed
so let's remove the hook okay so let's
remove the hook
um okay
okay quit emacs quit save
save let's restart emacs
so we are already done we are about done
informatic
uh today is pretty good i think uh
learning about emac bisp so
[Music]
about adding showing hr as a line
so we are backing our code open a new
window called
start command log mod so in this window
you'll see all my commands
as i move cursor or whatever commands
and keys
and now we open another buffer
go to console talk show html go to
today's talk show
uh html now it's opening fundamental mod
why is that
close it open it again okay
so now it's open right inside html mod
so you can see the hr there
now go back to the list so if you
so if you want this to work in your html
so what you do is you
so so yeah so you you add this line okay
so for example you can call describe
variable
and type mhtml mod hook
and it will come up the documentation
you see
mhtml mod hook is a variable defined in
mhtml mod its value is new because
you know we haven't added anything to it
yet
so here comment this out so
mhtml mod that's a new mod since
building in
emacs 26 beginning emacs 26
so what what's new in that mod that mod
the mhtml mod
allows you to have a mixed code of
css javascript and html
in one single file you know this is very
common today
so emacs actually the emacs dev
struggled for like five five or ten
years to come up with this
multi you know multi syntax mod
so that's a mhtml mod okay that's so
that's new so use it it's good
so if you want this code you know if you
want the hdr displayed as a line
here's what you do so first of all let's
try let's try this in
html mode so let's call it
mhtml mod okay you see it doesn't
it doesn't display hr as a lot as a line
but now now we run this code
then it will okay run the code back to
html
let's call mhtml mod again
call it you see now it's lines
okay so that's that's what you do that's
how you can have this code work for you
just put this in your e emacs init file
now for me i use xsi html mod
which i wrote from scratch myself
so in order for my code to work for me i
don't need
i don't need a hook you know what i
really should do is i
should put this code inside uh
html mod
okay so so we can do that easy you know
just copy it uh
copy it okay
copy it and describe key space space
space
h that's my key for for activating
um size html mod here
so now tab to the link go to it so we
are at
my site html source code
so all we have to do magnify all we have
to do is copy the code here
wait go back to the code
copy this code copy back to the
site html mod and basically
paste it in make a backup
then in the main body of the code
we just call the command we just call
the command
somewhere here okay let's say
uh let's say here let's call it
you see that should work okay
close emacs quit emacs save it
save it save restart emacs and that's it
for today
we run that we start emacs again if that
works
uh fantastic thank you guys for watching
if you like my tutorials
go buy it okay support me
so now let's go back to the html mod
let's go to the talk show open the talk
show you see
those are showing signs okay thank you
guys for watching
bye guys
you