welcome to another episode of our talk
show today's 2019 November 6 Wednesday
10 o clock 40 40 minutes after 10 San
Francisco time and we are approaching
awesome welcome all welcome but I'm
alive indeed and welcome Coover school
and panels and you know Bernie Sanders
and and Emily and sing - I scream you
scream we scream ok so Oh
discord yes you guys spot we miss you we
have a lot fun here so join us you know
we're gonna talk about Emily's setup
Emily's kick she's got hands she's got
her hands on thousands computers and
this computer has got 96 CPUs 96 course
okay we're gonna have you know have a
look at that that's interesting and good
morning Alan good morning all and
discord yes discord so for those of you
guys who have not joined this code so
here is some fan club
so to speak I saw discord okay so it's
fun yeah so okay so what we're gonna do
we have several topics so I've been
walking so I I I started to call eMac
B's you know I haven't really done for a
while so yesterday two days ago I so I
did a lot aMAG disp and I'm gonna show
you what's going on so stop this video
okay
so let's do that
what waiting for your comments
yeah thank you guys and for some reason
I have audiences that's fantastic and
emily is a Emax list coder oh my god she
her screen is like one huge giant screen
and it's all emag list code and she's
doing she's using Emacs list for work
apparently so so actually that's
beginning with the let's start talking
about Emily's setup so she's got let me
show you guys okay she a lot of messages
I missed did I miss
oh this one is cute let's see this one
Wow
this code Wow okay full screen this code
this one is cute so what is this Emily
could have a list that list
oh that list that list sounds like
common list applications function filter
ASP LSP filter flatten define flatten a
least common list has flattened right I
think flattened rest I extract get file
be oats dropped CSV iteration so device
years okay so there is no dark stream so
maybe this is I think doc string is
optionally McVie's so difference CSV
iteration name function functions
optional return member CST you know I'm
checking if there is I'm checking to see
if this is common list or what lease
fees
concat stream okay concoct stream maybe
this is this is not emag this right so I
think that Lisp is common this I have
encoded comedies and and this girl this
anime girl cute in to decode filled
something something for something what
code is is let's see see Malik okay well
that must be see I don't have encoded
any see but to realize that Malik would
which is one of the that that what that
function is the drama
the dramatic function of see you know in
scheme dis its tail recursion or Co CC
in Common Lisp is def mark World divine
markers in in Haskell its monad
okay so s PCL SPC our common lisp random
code okay so so we have here Emery's you
know yeah yesterday she she nothing she
happened to show us her computer setup
and that turned out amazing and it's ty
now
oh no second so let's get them big
screen let's get them big screen let me
get the pictures first and these these
servers got 96 CPUs and is in Emily's
hands all the CPUs are max out is this
this is just now 90 this is this is
Linux edge tops that shows these
graphics and oh my god oh these CPUs are
max out so what what is this is a server
right but what what servers are you guys
running is a web server or what let's go
back here and so let me show you the the
earliest pictures Wolfram language
that's great okay so this is yesterday's
talk and okay let's see the pictures
let's show the pictures and and I want
to show you some of the emag B's I did
yesterday let me find the pictures I
should have should have prepared you
know you know Lena's Tova's he is making
10 million a year so basically like 1
million a month Lena's tobots
he doesn't he doesn't really code these
days but that's how much he is making
and he is introducing code of conduct to
to Lena to Linux code of conduct
okay so this is Emily's CPU from
yesterday at the server CPU but she's
got some screenshot of her keyboard and
she is using happy hacking keyboard the
keyboard the keyboard I despise but
she's got a great set up you know very a
lot of do-it-yourself stuff so one more
picture that's it right yeah yeah that's
it
well there's some others well okay so so
here is her set up and let's see so this
is her set up and this this this giant
three monitors first this one four
monitors you know giant monitors and all
these are emag beast code and she told
us that all these are she's writing
she's using emag beasts to do something
at work you know for for the company for
her company and she's using happy
hugging keyboard and note this one is a
Japanese version now the Japanese
versions got several extra keys the
Japanese version is a good version
because it has arrow keys but but she
she customized and swapped all the key
caps I think she still got the Japanese
letter key caps is that I think she
could yeah I think I'm pretty sure she
this is customized key caps because in
Japan keyboards you don't have you know
giant Japanese characters hiragana
katakana like that is that right
this is young your own custom key caps
right anyway happy having keyboard if
you like it get the Japanese version
because then it's called arrow keys and
it's got a whole bunch of thumb keys but
she customized it she customized hers
out of shape you know the arrow keys
now here and she's got Kensington
trackball and
fuoco that's a vehicle not vehicle
that's what's the name you know one one
of the expensive brand name keep
keyboard makers so she's got this
mechanical keypad I think in another key
keypad so that's her keyboard setup but
also her happy hugging keyboard is got
custom firmware so she she swapped her
custom firmware so she can program the
keyboard the keys and she's got this to
it yourself device sort of USB dongle so
that when you connect you you you you
connect your keyboard to it and that
connects to the computer so any key code
is gets translated so essentially
becomes a physical you know it can make
any key keyboard become programmable
keybo keyboard so but so in Emily do you
have the details she she gave some
details in her discord you know you
might check it out here somewhere or
Emily posted okay so that that is her
keyboard setup you know these fancy
things fantastic and she's got this
classic compiler book now this is an old
version of the you know this we you know
we call a dragon book the red dragon
book it's got fantastic cover design the
red dragon book fantastic cover design
however this is this is from 1990s I
think 1999 the edition somewhere there
the later versions today it's still
dragon but they changed it it's no good
so anyway so so that's her CPU night
six CPUs it's a Cisco server Cisco blade
you know right rack-mounted server you
know and her other machines her personal
machines to connect to the server and
stuff and that's the that's the classic
good old Microsoft ago 4000 keyboard
this keyboard are useful like five years
it's got the the spacebar is very steep
to the point that it causes you problems
so it costs me problems and I try to fix
it I took took it apart and you know
remove the stabilizers and stuff didn't
work so he ventured a I threw it away
let's see so 96 CPUs all maxed out
amazing
oh yeah so here is a better picture of
her happy hacking keyboard so anything
special about about your keymaps
Emery Rio force yeah the name of this
keypad is real real force okay this is
high-quality picture great Thank You
Emily and I'm gonna put this picture in
my keyboard block and another picture of
her scream
okay so that's Emily's setup Rio force
that's right Rio force customer that's
custom keycaps okay but on it belongs in
every office oh I've found all the
additional keys as well to stuff like
escape past backspace enter and it's the
OG one what is oh gee ma so go is my
backup keyboard okay
Pecos is somewhere like subway because
of you yeah the Kibo layer is one that I
have designed over many years
oh that's interesting it's all custom Oh
G Dragon book oh you called OG o
original okay wait no that that cover is
not the first you know I I know I have
like
post a picture publishing date in this
code oh okay
and see discord you are viewing okay I
have to scroll all the way down let's
see let me my spin wheel Mouse spinning
spinning wheel walk okay so you see
today's application they load only part
of your window they kind of so this is a
dragon book library Library of Congress
1986 okay so I actually collected
actually I haven't I don't think I have
collected all the versions of that
book's cover let's see if I have that I
don't think so
Parsa notes okay dragon book table of
contents so I've been trying to read
this book I read like half of it about
three years ago I should continue but I
didn't but you know this is one of the
things I need to do compilers techniques
principles and tools by these three guys
and you know when you read them you know
I look at when I read books I also look
up the authors so and you learned
something I think if I remember
correctly one of them okay
Alfred aho I think he's a guy who began
oak oh oh did I get confused sorry
anyway and I can't find it anyway yeah
well let me show it then let's let's
show it so let's go to syntax soup or
semantic noodle and we want to search
for scheme okay we want to search for
UNIX philosophy no we want to go to okay
I know where to go to you want to go to
white Python sucks okay and the number
one top item why Python lambda is broken
and can't be fixed okay and okay it was
it's not this one we want to go to we
want to go to syntax OOP semantics
noodles we want we we want to find
alcohol while UNIX pipes sucks UNIX pipe
dot notation prefix notation okay
ontology ontology of Pacific's fix
notation method cheney and unix pipe
this is a great topic to talk about
typing and function composition
equivalence unix Pipers functional
language there it is
so this one indeed that's this guy so
Alfred aho he is a guy who invented oak
you know in Unix
and he's he is telling us here you know
history he is an interview of you know
of him and he's telling us oak he's
actually and and UNIX pipe originally it
is powered from functional programming
concept you know when you have UNIX you
pipe you know cat file name pipe grab
something things like that in UNIX pipe
so oak the language for basically text
processing it's outdated today you know
it's replaced by Perl bit and today pers
replaced by Python Ruby or any other
languages but anyway thirty years ago
awk
so he created awk and he is one of the
author and of the dragon book and the
another author is one of the famous a
cryptographic hash function or
cryptographic system I think but anyway
so so that is the you know this is not a
first version I think I think there is a
version before that I don't have a
picture of it oh there it is
it is the older version
the older version let's see Amazon is a
bigger picture
no no bigger picture so that so yeah so
they're you know the older I think this
version is the best I like I like that
one the modern one it's no good they
become 3d and they try to be funny I
don't find it funny and they introduced
another author Monika Aslam Monika Aslam
I think if I remember correctly she's at
Stanford University which is down here I
don't remember what else she has done I
think she's teaching compilers you know
one thing about book writing and book
publishing is that they try to keep the
names of the famous people like so
people know these guys wrote it so even
let's say some of these guys may you
know may pass away but they usually try
to keep the original name author's name
even though they you know it's it's you
know the arrangement of what I didn't
write it I mean even even even though
you know the entire content of the book
may have been changed Rita but you know
because because due to the recognition
so book publishers they usually keep the
original name okay that's about
compilers book that's about Emily set up
let's go to let's go through I think how
long I've been talking for 20 minutes I
think 22 okay so let's go to compare the
book very interesting okay yeah so you
guys go by it compiled a book okay so
actually I have
I want to demo a lot of things okay so
this is you need to magnify make
copy switch back here and I need to get
back to compiling good morning weenie
come on in Freddie PDF layout
development in the discourse so guys
join the discord okay so she's got Emily
Scott more information keyboard
development history oh my god she's
she's got his keyboard development
history okay so you have to download it
wait wait I don't have to we can show it
in the browser so let me get that right
click copy link opening copy link go to
Chrome now why it you know why is the
Trey browser start to download because
it's it starts to download anyway okay I
guess it's because yeah this code makes
you download it so her keyboard history
Commack japan Commack th white wide
keyboard angle mod miscellaneous okay
you guys can check it out I have to read
later
okay so let's see Emily Emilie's Emily's
setup saw start command log mod so that
for you Emacs fans you can see all my
commands on the Left window here and so
Emacs tutorial update so we're going to
talk about Emacs updates let's see if we
can okay so we may not you know let's
let's do some interesting things first
okay
let me quickly mention so on Twitter I
was chatting you know I was posting
about keyboard layout stuff and there is
this guy who has interesting stuff he
apparently he also created created his
own layout this guy Tony Aldon and
apparently he's a mathematician so he
created this very very weird layout is
this one so I think this one he is this
one more weird than yours
Emily very weird and I asked him he so
so you know where does you know where
does this letter layout came from and he
tells me it's because let's go to we
have to go to Twitter here so let's go
to Twitter view in open linking brave
okay and open link in brave so you have
to turn on JavaScript
yeah Tom JavaScript that's going on
turn on JavaScript
you know I was talking about escape key
because I I was thinking escape keys
kind of disappearing in mainstream you
know I'm trying to see if there's a
trend that the Escape key is disappear
disappearing in the mainstream for
example Apple's laptop keyboards they
made a scale they they don't have Escape
key a physical Escape key anymore they
made it into you know one of the LCD
display touched keys and also on the
ultimate hacking keyboard this one I
have they also don't have Escape key by
default let me let me show you quickly
the ultimate hacking keyboard let's plug
it in so you can see the lights
so you see so this is the automat
hacking keyboard and this is currently
QWERTY I want I don't want Kody I want
to switch to X X X okay and they don't
have you see they don't have physical
escape Keys now by default but you can
see there it is escape so if you want to
press escape by default you have to hold
on mod and press that you know hold on
mod and press that so that's the
ultimate hacking keyboard you know so I
was thinking perhaps there's a trend you
know because I try to observe these kind
of things perhaps there's a trend in
mainstream that removes the escapes key
you know these kind of things happen and
you know then you have to you have to
you know see why you know - like the
question I ask is - do people actually
use use Escape key
I mean non-programmers like average
people so I think most people for those
who are not computer professionals they
probably don't use Escape key because
today because of the iPhone you know
phone apps interface influence that you
know the phone app has a great influence
on UI that's spreading to all desktop
for example you know responsive design
or that because you might have noticed
that you know desktop
you know many websites their font
becomes bigger you know and much more
spacing between lines things like that
that came from phone you know although
on a phone you know it's a different
system but however because the
technology they are also using CSS and
all that so apparently the designers the
programmers you know the coders made it
so that both are using the same kind of
system so anyway and another another
good example is that you
we started to see a lot website has this
3 bar menu 3 bar menu you click on that
to show the menu that that design came
from phone so so so the the phone had a
lot UI you know the phones to you I had
a lot influence on you know everywhere
else it's spreading out product so one
of the thing about phone is that you
started to see your design like this
pop-up like if you click anywhere else
it goes away you see so it's not
actually a window
it's rather it's like because CSS layer
that that pop-up let's see if ice can
still go back yeah so you see there is
no let's see Escape key walks if I press
escape it does work ok so but that but
that but that's a thing so you know the
phone UI design influenced that became
spread over to other places anyway so I
was talking about my you know the escape
you know a lot of people answered and he
showed his layout and apparently he
created this on his own
and he gave reasons let's see yeah
hamburger menu yes that that's that's
the name
III don't like that hello so he's got a
gate website I showed I showed here and
you can go to and he's so he said so he
said he begin with the peephole layout
people is a layout optimized for German
language and he is French
then he pays the tab backspace returned
him he moved them to the middle and then
he removed those exit accented letters
because those can be done with more
general mechanism called dead accent
dead keys and then he he added previous
next backward forward and X on one side
control keys on one side and he added
autograph key middle then he grouped
punctuation and stuff then
so that's very very customized key setup
what a deep rabbit hole keyboard
customization yeah yeah I tried to avoid
that well actually I do a lie - I do a
lot of that in Emacs 404 Emacs
keybinding but not for the late letter
layout for the letter layout I usually
try to avoid that anyway so that's about
his layout so let's close close all
these windows to save memory so dragon
book contents
so this is spots forum but is walking on
it
but are you still working on this so
let's ok let's save let's save this so
let's save e-e-e-e this is my e to save
close save III save close save EE for
save close they don't need to be they
either need to be e or TT so TG 1 save
close because EE the letter E and T are
on borax index finger first by these
fingers so ye and TT because if the file
name started with EE or TT then I can t
default let's say for example so it's
all saved and go back to this code and
go here and what can't what I can do is
let me show you
I call this command now watch the left
window you'll see the command name and
watch over here on the right window you
will see the what it does so I call the
command San talk show and I say I type a
directory name ok directory I for images
and you ask me a file name I'll just say
ok the default name so use you show in
browser you see I got the photo here so
when you save an image in browser you
know suppose you are a blogger or
something you save the image what's
what's the crap 4 4 4 are you talking
about your so so what what's up with
this what were you doing with this so so
so what so what this in makes Emacs
command does is that
when you if you are a blogger you read a
lot there are some images you want to
grab on the web so you save it to your
desktop all you have to do is you name
it you you named the starting name with
EE or TT then you can call Emacs command
and it will automatically move to your
blog directory you know and you know
basically is with the image tag or setup
you'll move the file and you can also
name it you know at the time so for
example let me do it again in a
directory and default name
okay then repeat last command okay
repeat repeat repeat so we got four of
them to go whenever it's a PNG file it
will also automatically try to PNG crush
to optimize the image so this is very
convenient okay so I think that's it
showing browser so we got all M emily's
images so I can you know I can pick some
to blog it and and you know so that's
that's about the Emacs command so that
command is called what is a command
repeat complex command some move image
files so that's that's the one cuz I
move image file I don't think it's on my
website because it's on my github though
oh there it is some of the image file so
if you are
Emacs user you can use that okay so I
did a lot a max so so where are we going
so I need to I need to I need to get a
drink so we've been talking for and this
is Emily's PDF so let's save it I'm
gonna read it later so close close to
save memory 17 people watching 40
minutes ok so we we have we we don't
have time to go do something wrong
save memory and Dragon book so Emacs
tutorial update so let's talk about okay
so I'm gonna talk about Emacs and
PowerShell maybe a demo of powershell
and and great math stuff let's let's get
over with the math stuff because because
okay so open linking brave because Emacs
stuff we can talk about everyday you
know because that's my thing
so this so yeah close to save in memory
so this is fantastic math application
this this thing is called train kwatak I
don't I don't understand it but but on
this page it's a collection of visual
very interesting visual stuff good
morning
Finch Fitch how do you how do you say
your first name Fitch
which stitch in dem ash is that a
fictional name or is that a real name so
this page is a collection of visual math
software so every even if you don't
understand it but it's fun because it's
just visual I have a plum juice here
today so if you go to you know this guy
you open it and you turn on JavaScript
of course you need JavaScript this is
modern society modern society you need
JavaScript on so that corporations can
track you you have to help them help
them track you so here is the
application you hold the mouse now you
click and it just moves like that it's
fantastic math you know then you have to
then you have to start to you know learn
this stuff you know this this math
visualization are very interesting you
know it gets you interested this can be
used for decoration for building a house
you know many stadiums things like that
they are built based on math geometry
principles things like this like sports
stadiums especially the modern ones and
and then okay so let's see what is is
let's see Oh so you can actually wow you
can do a Veroni diagram on this
hyperbolic space you know I think this
is hyperbolic space but this is a
hyperbolic geometry
so but you can do what Roni
well Rono a diagram you guys know Baroni
diagram if you don't look that up okay
that's very interesting so the here's
award Verona a diagram you can see it
right yeah yeah exactly
you know just Google Google there's
Google that would there are many
interactive applications for that and if
you are a programmer I bet you would be
very interested its first of all it's a
visually fantastic there's a Wikipedia
Arco as well but you know but anyway
it's if you're a programmer you'll find
this interesting and you might exercise
you might to write the application doing
that there are many interactive
JavaScript applications that you can see
on on the web basically you you give a
random dots any any dots on a plane in a
plane like you know then it can be
random or it can be regular doesn't
matter then you see the lines or these
lines is either it divides the plane it
partitions the plane into many regions
the way the lines are created you know
is the way the lines are generated are
each point on the line you know the
between the regions they are equidistant
between any neighbor points so for
example at this point in this point you
know you draw a line between them and
there is a midpoint between them so that
midpoint is part of this of the boundary
between these two points and what about
the other points on a line they are also
equidistant like if you draw circles of
the same same radius one centered on one
point and the other circle Center on the
other point and you increase the circle
size they were the circle
your intersect and all the intersections
of the circle will become the boundary
of the value Inori diagram so basically
this is a way to partition the space so
that each neighbor has kind of kind of
the kind of a fair way to divide a space
between points so this and this this can
be generated in real time and you can
track the point around there are many
interactive application on the web you
can track the point around and you can
see them changing real time so this is a
Veroni diagram okay very interesting you
might try to implement it I I always
wanted to but I never did you know one
of the things to do and this is part of
this is part of the subject called
computational geometry
you know when I'm studying game
programming like 3d graphics I thought
you know I'm very interested in this
kind of thing so this is computational
geometry okay so what I'm doing you know
what I'm trying to when I see books
about computer graphics I thought you
know I'm going to read about these
things but actually know when you study
computer graphics that you know like for
the gaming game 3d engines and so on all
the books you go in a bookstore out
there you look at them they are nothing
about this at all maybe one section you
know a little bit computational geometry
but but like nineteen ninety-eight
percent of the poke of the content is
not about these things it's about it's a
you know the OpenGL
idiocy OpenGL and pipes you know
pipelines you know incredible idiotic
thing that's a computer that's a
programmer stuff you know programmers
created that situation they love that
anyway that's that's digression Saburo
need of a Voronoi diagram very
interesting and apparently
so these guys doing it on a hyperbolic
space same principle so very interesting
so anyway I just want to show that and
let's go back to Emacs so let's read the
comments then let's read the comments
there is some Emacs I want to I want to
say though ok 4045 minutes
Emacs tutorial update so Emacs tutorial
yes curling demo okay so for example so
we are left with E max some talk about
Emacs in some demo powershell maybe so
let's read the comments
magnify
so winter is coming
how so
so but and Emily do you guys have photos
of UK and Germany and any of you who for
school posted
so Emily says SPC spcer that's steel
bank commonly that's an interesting name
you know SP CEO is a open source
implementation of Common Lisp but they
have a interesting name
they name their software steel Bank
Common Lisp
just some random code that maps function
calls so I'm okay so I can visualize the
program structure okay
so wow that's interesting but do you
show it in I mean the final output is
the image some kind of graph structure
just random code that map's
function calls yeah map function calls I
imagine that would be hard to write a
program you know so it's it's that
basically is a either static analysis
right that's part of static analysis you
have to draw a graph of function calls
okay maybe it's not that hard
I'm not saying so this moisture is very
example okay yeah it's amazing - it's
amazing true - no you guys because I
didn't expect someone who wrote a lot
this is gonna follow following me and
watch my videos via force okay so so if
you have a comment post okay post right
now
dragon book
okay so Emily says Emily says the final
output is a CSV oh okay commas comma
separated value CSV that I can import
into something like Gaffey okay pasta
Germany in diffs discord
okay Germany in this code
not that man I know where Germany is
thank you photo of your you know streets
like something you know photo of your
house your phone yard your street so
glue Bernie Sanders says elite new Emacs
user and I mean I'm not interested in
compilers currently why should I read it
and what use will it have compilers well
if you are not in you are you if you are
not interested in compilers there's no
use I mean compilers is you know it's
it's kind of fundamental but in real
life vast majority of programmers you
will never need to code anything close
to it you don't need to know that's
that's compilers
how about snapshot of security cam in my
bedroom
there will be entertaining ok let's
let's let's talk about Emacs then so I
did a lot in Magnus so I'm gonna show
you let's go to my Emacs tutorial so am
accident openings run open external now
works in Windows okay so great tips okay
one of the great first thing is I found
this fantastic
so Emacs Emacs creative via autosave
inspired by V s code so I got this
inspiration from Visual Studio code so
for example you see my oops okay so let
me let me split a window create a new
buffer type something so you see do you
see to you see these two asterisks here
that means this fire is not saved if I
save it you know the asterisks will be
gone for example
save it okay save it you have to type a
name
okay so you see the asterisk is good so
if I type something you see the asterisk
is there again so it's not saved but huh
and in same thing on the left window you
can see so this is not saved but now if
I switch out of Emacs then all unsaved
files in Emacs will be saved
let me show you okay so I'm going to
switch out of Emacs you see the
asterisks is gone because it's all saved
now switch back to Emacs you see now
it's saved so so this is automatic save
and you know when when window is out of
focus it's it does a save I got this
inspired platform vs code before I was
doing when whenever I switch to command
mod it does so save but that's not so
good because it's kind of annoying
because sometimes you don't want to save
you just want to switch to command mode
and insert mod back and forth you don't
you don't necessarily want to say so so
this is much better because I was
looking at you know via visual studio
code you know since few days ago and so
Microsoft you know this is quite
interesting many things going on with
Microsoft and they also adopted many
UNIX and Mac Mac conventions because
traditionally you see in a Windows
application you have options you know
like on a Mac the tradition is called
preferences you know you have these menu
preferences and command coma is a short
key shortcut key to you know to open the
Preferences panel on Windows by windows
convention it's usually called options
and options usually it's one in one of
the other menus but in vs code
apparently
they they did the Mac way because some
windows you see the same thing you know
they're co-ed preferences you know and
the the the shortcut key is also control
coma so so they adopted the Mac way and
you know so this is interesting you know
in a sense of user interface design
changes history evolution yeah so I
noticed that that's interesting so I was
looking at visual studio preferences and
you have for example you you have
autosave option and you can choose
between after delay or you can choose it
on focus change you know which means you
know when you switch out a visual studio
then it does save so when I was seeing
this you know I thought wow that's a
great thing so I did that in Emacs as
well so if you are Emacs user then I
recommend you know if you like it you
can use that so the code is here it's
very simple so here just you know it's
just seven lines you know you go to my
Emacs tutorial and you will see it and
I'm using it right now it's fantastic so
that's about let's close that so that's
about the Emacs Emacs vo autosave you
know why the Emacs itself has a autosave
but it's not like the Emacs autosave so
let me show you Emacs autosave okay so
let me talk about Emacs autosave Emacs
has a autosave option since like 30
years ago but it's pain yes
and it's rather it's a diss feature it's
a you you know you don't want to turn it
on fire okay so you go to so you go to
my Emacs tutorial you go to in each
setup this is all brand new you know I
rewrote it I kind of redid it
you know I spent two days we reorganize
the whole thing so it's been you this
entire index section all the pages are
brand new so you go to this page and you
click on so this is all about Emacs
customization then you go to the file
section you have autosave so here's how
you do all automatic save however Emacs
has its own it caused it autosave okay
autosave mod but it's not it's not what
you think you know in modern sense
rather it's it's kind of a backups
system so it the proper name would be
the proper name would be automatic save
in case of crash okay so basically what
Emacs does is that after some time every
you know periodically Emacs will create
like a backup copy of the current file
you are editing and name it you know
name it with a pound sign in front he'll
make a copy in the same directory then
when you actually save your buffer then
that file disappears you know it then
Emacs TD that file and it you know in
case there's a power failure then you
you will have some of these autosave
files in your directory then when you
open you know the the file again Emacs
will detect that you have this autosave
then Emacs will ask you do you you know
Emacs Emacs we will say there's a
autosave file do you want to revert to
that so this is a mechanism to basically
for power failures things
like that and it's a pain yes because
because it creates these files and those
files are problem wherever you do sink
or whenever you have a some automated
script automated script that traverse
your directory it run into this file
sometimes these files points to
non-existent links so you you know it
chokes your autom automated script very
annoying and you my team I you know I
turned off in the first ten years of
using Emacs oh I didn't turn it off
but I almost never find it useful like
there's you know one time or two I have
a crash I want to recover but it's not
he autosave so I find this annoying so
that's that's the confusing part of
Emacs autosave basically I turn it off
you just you want to use this you know
this code instead the code I just gave
today so that's about Emacs autosave so
let's see so the init file so I did a
lot work on Emacs and of ensue okay and
a lot I spent whole day two days ago
yesterday on coding windows making some
of the command commands working windows
that is let me show you that
so these commands now they have proper
version when you are in Windows so the
commands are showing desktop open in vs
code open in terminal and opening
external app so showing desktop just
show the kind of current file the
current directory in desktop for example
let me show you you see you see so I'm
showing it on the Mac you know you know
desktop of the current directory the
file is in so that's that
so on Windows there's a
bug now it's fixed and opening vs code
now this this we did few days ago in a
video we coded in real time so let's
call it so saw open vs code opening vs
code so you just open the current file
in Visual Studio code wow this is
fantastic let's have a look
Visual Studio it's pretty good you know
my impression I plan to dig into detail
and you have this navigation map that's
interesting you know Emacs has this too
you can you can install a package but I
would not trust Emacs features like that
in Emacs because for features like that
typically involves something Emacs is
not good at you know like this minimaps
thing okay so this is this is today's
some talks your way so actually close
that shrink let's go back let's go to my
Emacs tutorial and open EVS code so this
works in in Windows too and also on
Linux yes so if you have vs code
installed you can use it look look at
this mini-map on the right this is a
very long document so they have the
mini-map now I wonder okay so this
mini-map I don't think it's actual it's
not a image file I don't think so wait
is it an image file what what happens if
I have a image in my okay I don't think
it's an image file it's just a shrink
text file
okay so in that case like I guess the
Emacs version would also work okay good
morning Scott hello and good morning
hello beautiful people
good I have to know
ha so you have a Visual Studio C press
first macro to open the same file with
kusa position in Emacs so that I can
edit it in a real added after coding
some years to do debugging yeah okay so
yeah so you know this is the commands
like this is nice because you need to
because sometimes your editor doesn't do
something well so you can you know
switch okay let's see what's the next
Emacs stuff and how long I've been
talking I think we're gonna end
and pretty soon yeah so okay so any
questions guys type comments and
questions so basa is how about snapshot
of security cam in my bedroom okay we
talked about that
okay so Emacs let's see what else you
need setup
yeah so go check it out
Emacs open run in external yeah so let
me show you that so there is still few
comments I show you
so opening desktop okay opening vs code
open in terminal so let's do that open
in terminal so on a Mac it's gonna open
in terminal so here is the terminal with
with the the current directory this
buffer is in this file is in and on
Windows on Windows it's going to open in
PowerShell you know that's what I did I
walked on so and the commands are here
you can get them okay so that's about
that let's see what what's the next
Emacs stuff stuff like he's okay so
ficus is got a new version so here is
the source code go to the top and go to
the URL and then your language his poor
request has not been processed yet so
you know because there's a lot work I
tried it it you know I need to fix
something so anyway so so there's a new
version of Sophocles closer closer
okay powershell let me let me take five
minutes to demo powershell and i'll be
here today so we're gonna shut down in
i'm gonna shut down in five minutes
so power showers you know it's available
on the Mac today and also on Linux
PowerShell is becoming very popular
because you know it's it's it's it's
natural because PowerShell is the
replacement is a new generation of the
command prompt and much more powerful
basically if you work in Windows if you
use Windows technology then or even if
you use Windows as your own desktop and
if you are programmer then PowerShell is
the appropriate shell you want to know
you know because the command prompt is
really lousy he doesn't cut it and
you're the UNIX bash is not suitable for
Windows and all the reason let me show
you okay so let's open a terminal wait
not open the terminal and it's open well
yeah open terminal yes so open terminal
so let's put this here let's magnify a
bit magnify and let's put this in a like
that so you can go to power shout let's
go to PowerShell
so I have a tutorial check it out I have
a tutorial here its covers basics but
I'm gonna I'm gonna show you I'm gonna
demo the basics so you feel you know
it's not so scary to dive through and
you can start to learn you know the
details actually the PowerShell so
PowerShell has a lot building help
features so you don't actually even need
to read a tutorial you can start just to
start to use it and whenever you don't
know how some command works you can just
type help everything you it has
expensive like man pages basically but
much more better written it's actually
you can read them so PowerShell once you
install it then you what's the thing
okay so you it's very easy to install
just you know download it on Mac Linux
or Windows it's building on Windows so
you aren't on a map you started with
pssh but on Linux and Windows you start
with PowerShell the full name so I mean
PowerShell and you can you can for
example CD ok I can I can type all the
UNIX patch commands like CD to previous
directory actually in a case of Mac when
you do CD I think it's actually it may
be using the bash version of CD because
English you know in shells like this
when you call command if he's not part
of PowerShell it would and if that I
mean first if that command exists in
your system it will just call that
command I think that's the case but
anyway on Windows or Linux you can you
know on Windows for example you can CD
you can make let's say xx feet three
four okay so CD X 3 4 so I mean that
directory OS you can do LS there's no
file
yeah in this case when when I caught
actually so Wakko these commands they
are actually coding a Mac version I
think you know the bash the Magus
building version the UNIX version but my
point is that power these commands also
work in PowerShell on Windows even if
you don't have CD and make the things
like that because PowerShell has spewed
in aliases for example for example on
the left you see the full name of the
PowerShell command they call it camlet
command lit so the full name is for
example you have the you have a command
called get help get - help but it has
areas of help or men so you can you know
if you are on UNIX you are used to type
man something like to get a main page
that will walk so for example you can
say men make the yeah this will just
called a UNIX UNIX version because I'm
on a Mac you know those command exists
but anyway but if you are on Windows for
example you can also say ma'am actor and
that will actually I'll tell you what
that will show that will show you this
help make
why is that about filesystem provider
okay so you have to actually let's
shrink the window let's do it again
okay so you can say help about okay so
they do have help about fire so that
this is part of the Power Cells
extensive documentation but anyway what
I'm trying to do is I want to for
example I want to find out what make the
what areas what is a full command name
of mikta okay so according to my
tutorial it should be
where is mikta it should be this one
wait make directory hope our shell
doesn't have anyway I'm trying to you
see what I'm trying to do is I'm trying
to see if there is a alias
what does the command of the if if make
the weight is mcdo is actually I haven't
used that command for a long time yes so
let's see I want to see if there is a
command of mikta so no there's no alias
to make those so when I use maker it's
actually the UNIX command but okay I see
what's going on but on Windows if you
are gonna empower char on Windows then
then the command maker is an alias of
this wait where is it match it is not so
good well I'm trying to I'm talking
about we moved okay let's try to move
this so CD CD up remove the x34 okay so
now that directory is good now I want to
find what's real command fold we move to
the full name so I type GL removed
okay so no okay yeah so I know what's
going on because if you do these on
Windows it will walk it does not work on
the Mac because there's actually no
alias to make to remove to or make that
because you already have that command on
a Mac so the the Mac version of
PowerShell does not have those aliases
well anyway on Windows then you can you
you can type okay for example let me
show you this Gao Gao you see when I
type GL
that's actually an alias for the Foo
name Kate get alias and this skit alias
command what it does is that it will
given an idea so it will tell you the
full name of that command so let's for
example we can do help gee al so you see
it this is the documentation for the
gate get alias candid you can also do
help get alias see that works so if you
if you know an alias you want to know
the full name then you can say gee al
you know that then the alias name so Gao
Gao will return get alias or you can say
get areas using the full name Gao that
will also work so so the point here is
that power sha has all these aliases
building so it makes it convenient if
you know command prompt or if you know
bash you can already use it right away
you know CD two directories make the
remove file move file things like that
and wherever you need to know the
command name of something I mean you
need help just type help help
seedy okay so CD is actually an alias so
it's not using okay yeah you see when
you talk about shell things get
complicated for example if you use in
UNIX on a Linux box if you type CD
something you know there's a question
whether that CD is part of bash or if
that CD is part of the you know is a
command utility outside of bash you know
for CD it's obvious it's part of bash
but for example the key or command that
events because I find we call correctly
bash the key or command is part of bash
however the Linux or UNIX system also
have a kill command utility so you do
want to know so there's a question you
know just which key are you coding so
that means that's the question that you
have this issue you know when you call a
command in a shell whether that's part
of the shell or actually your system
utility so so this issue is showing up
here you know showing up you know in the
past 10 minutes 10 minutes we've been
talking so when we call CD like I called
CD here I don't know where does the CD
came from is it using is it using my
bash to do it or what so apparently not
because CD is part of bash there is no
separate command CD in unix's so so in
the case of the macro version of
PowerShell you don't have it actually
has an alias to CD so in PowerShell CD
is an alias to the full command name
code let's say GL GL
it is a language GA LCD so CDs the areas
to the full command set location the
full names say location so you can type
help say location or help CD and then
you tell you what it does he said it's
kind of a generalized version of CD ok
so let me so so that's kind of some
introduction to PowerShell and you also
have piping just like UNIX and you also
PowerShell vs smash wait when we
PowerShell was a smash so you have all
these familiar commands in bash you can
do touch cat tell and I show you the
PowerShell version so why wait you know
one interesting thing is why did why did
Microsoft invented PowerShell so I was
reading Wikipedia and the guy the
inventor of power sha said that you know
like ten years ago when he began to
manage you know Windows systems he just
bash you know he just run the UNIX patch
but however that doesn't work because in
UNIX is everything is a file
you know by design you the UNIX
operating system everything is just a
stream it's just a file so you can use
text processing tools you know then
things to work out but on Windows most
things are not files you know you have
everything is the API with object so so
bash in the UNIX way doesn't work on
Windows that's how that's why he created
PowerShell so when power shall return
something often it's an object you know
it's an object but however it's
represented to you as a text but it's
actually object when you pipe something
in PowerShell it's actually typing the
whole object that way you kind of have
more structured control
okay next meeting okay so I think that's
it for today does power sha has object
yes that's what it does join the I do
Club join the I do club so what I do so
mastering Emacs the thing I book that I
can get used to his helm and I prefer I
learned Emacs the inversions 18 and so
scott is reading that mastering Emacs
book that's interesting I think that's
it for today guys
okay we shut down in one minutes
anything anything interesting hello
beautiful people
steal Bank common least
PowerShell basics yeah power shall very
interesting PowerShell help CD quit help
man you don't have men because man is
not an alias on Mac because an American
man is a tool by itself therefore you
don't have a alias to it but on UNIX you
can do man man you know so um you know
man is interesting on Emacs you have a
command called women these stupid nerds
inventing these stupid jargons so why
women first of all we can let's so I
mean Emacs right I can show you a main
page so you just M x-men okay then you
need to type a topic so man man okay so
now we see the main page the UNIX main
page in Emacs now the the Emacs man
command when you do am x-men that
actually cause the UNIX man command then
it takes to you the its output then
formatted shows in Emacs that's the man
command now there is a man utility
written in Emacs Lisp entirely and that
command in Emacs that command is called
women woman okay these nerds you know
they they try to use these jargons you
know they they love it this this we are
talking about 1990s so 1980s hackers you
know these type of people typically the
UNIX philosophy the UNIX loving people
so let me show you the women the woman
command okay let's open a new let's open
a new window new new window okay so I'm
gonna call MX woman okay there you have
it now I need to type a topic so I say
me woman man oh there it is
you know it's basically the same thing
you know but but the woman utility is
written entirely in Emacs Lisp
you know that's the difference okay
that's it bye guys thank you for
watching yes the full name is without
men yeah that that that is that is the
you know like you know that's that's
that's so they always have backward
justification back Oh names you know for
example the new you know guru is not
UNIX the back on them you know recursive
recursive acronym the the word recursive
acronym is a back corner okay because
they they the these nuts they eat good
money in Rome and love you so this nerds
they create a jargon and they create
justification afterwards like post the
fact typically that's a case for example
PHP the programming language was pretty
homepage okay my pretty homepage because
it's a teenager who wants to create his
poem page based on Perl you know
basically is a Perl script pretty
homepage they became popular then after
ten years it's some something kind kind
of what's a full acronym for PHP like
like fantastic hypertext processor you
know for those crap this it's kind of
verging on lying you know on erasing
history and also another story is the
naming of Apache you know the Apache web
server the naming of Apache web server
where is it Co Apache because originally
it's just a patch you know patch like
code patch lots of patch you got you
find a bug someone patch it you know so
patch patch patch Pachi Pachi Apache
Apache Apache server that's what Apache
web server name came from a patch
Apache web server but now it's like oh
you know if you go to with their website
with their FAQ now it's like oh we
respect we respect Native Americans we
want to pay honor you know to them so
that's why we named our server as Apache
him and they backed in like in a 19
you know in 1999 also the Native
Americans they actually they actually
fought the domain name with Apache
people the Apache people you know don't
don't give a you know they did they
with Native American people they
don't give a they want the domain
name that is a history of Apache you
know so I have this article Apache write
rewrites history why is it named Apache
so they have a FAQ from 1997 he says why
is the name Apache he says a cute name
we which stuck Apache is a patchy server
it was based on some existing code and a
series of patch files okay but now in
2013 the FAQ says why is that why the
name Apache says the name Apache was
chosen from respect for the Native
American Indian tribe of Apache
limb you know this this is lie this is
this is open source guys this is open
source you guys are born into this this
is this is malicious malicious this is
criminal act like this type of thing
context but that's it for today thank
you guys for watching bye