Hello everyone, welcome to another
another episode of talk show. We are
going to code emac this today as again
and eag this and wam language. So we're
going to continue yesterday uh fantastic
emac this yesterday uh we started to
write a JSON tutorial.
So I did a my last live stream two or
three live stream ago. We started to do
this and we talked about something else
which is quite interesting. If you go to
S talk show uh uh EMAC this Jason
serialization
idiocy and crimes of Google Chrome and
Microsoft Edge. So that was yesterday.
Fantastic. Uh but so today we're gonna
continue right my tutorial. I I like
finished most of it. I'm just going to
explain and we are going to uh start to
do wra so you can see the
comparative linguistics
of emac lisp and wuam language. Okay,
fascinating subject. So I'm just going
to work on it. I think nobody nobody's
here. Oh hello Tomid. How hello. So if
you are watching this offline, play at
1.5 speed because I ramble. If you are
watching it here, say hi. Love to see
your comments. Okay, let's begin
quickly. So Jason emac this Jason so
let's start to write it. So uh so JSON
pass string so let me tell you
uh so if you are a EMAC list coder there
is uh four new functions now it's native
in Emacs it's written in C
uh so they began so you scroll down you
know you scroll down you can see a
history page history so these four
functions JSON par string and JSON
serialize and JSON pass buffer and JSON
insert they um they begin in 2020 Emacs
27 but however they require the C
library JSON okay then in EMAC version
uh the lip JSON library is no longer
necessary so it became native uh
building function and they are written
in lisp I mean they are uh I'm sorry
they are written in D. Okay. So,
actually there's something uh I need to
change. So, JSON pass string which is
reading a JSON file or JSON string. Um
so, JSON serialize
is is exporting to JSON. So serialize is
eaglist
object to JSON such as EMAC list hasht
uh list association list and JSON insert
is
uh so wait pass string pass buffer
anyway so that's we what we going to do
okay so so they are part of Emacs
fantastic however there's old JSON
library since 200 2016
and uh you know they are just written in
lisp someone wrote it. So this is kind
of old. So if you are eager you should
use a new one. They should be like five
or 10 times faster. But the old library
uh seems to be still useful because they
have some pretty print functions
allows you to format JSON. But actually
you don't need that because for JSON you
can format by uh using Deno like I
previous talk show last week also we
talked about formatting JavaScript,
Python, HTML, CSS uh and that the demo
will also format JSON files also HTML.
Hello Hank Chuk Chung. Thank you Hank. I
see you are working hard. I'm between
split shifts.
Are you still working at that place?
Split shifts. I just read about
composers and it sounds like a squash of
I have no idea what though those are,
but I know you read a lot uh kind of
like mathematics actually. So uh my
disco friend. So you you know I have a
discord discord discord. You can find my
discord on my website. So let me quickly
look up what what what is uh compos of.
So let's search for the web
compos of state of the union Alexander
Gnome. some Gnome [ __ ] like you know
Gnome the organization is entirely
corrupted deep state thing today since
about you know I don't know since about
how many years ago that's from you know
that's for you Linux people so Gnome is
a desktop they they are like now
foundation you know the like um anyway
they are very very corrupt
like they you know any anyway so I can't
believe it's more than a year since
composer block. So much has changed.
Finally things starting. So yeah, I
don't know what the [ __ ] that is. So
that's a Windows composition. Is that
what what that is?
The reliability of disk images. The
flexibility of files. Oh,
the reliability of disk images. The
flexibility of files. So let me explain
this one. You know if you are young you
may not know. So you have this thing
called disk images.
So like when you have a file or
directory
you can you know like right now there's
a directory lots of files. You can
actually save them as like disk images.
For example this is my Emacs directory.
There are like a thousand files. Okay.
So you can save them as disk images. So
when you do that they the the they they
are saved into a binary format very uh
uh uh they they are saved into a blob.
So I'm not sure it's more compressed or
not but anyway it's uh so the advantage
is that it provides a 100% replica of
the folder. actually it's not even a
folder but anyway so that that's kind of
what it means disk image um then
flexibility of files you know you know
what is a file right so so so composer
is supposed to be the combination the
composer project combines several
underlying Linux features to provide a
very flexible mechanism to support read
only read only mountable file system
tree Okay. Stacking on top of an
underlying lower Linux file system.
Okay. Some esoteric Linux tech geeking
[ __ ]
That's technically that's what it is.
Okay. What do you got? What about
scratch? Uh oh, wait. Compose FS. That
means compose file system kind of. Uh,
okay. So, scratch FS. Uh, let's see.
Squash FS
is a compressed readonly file system.
Okay. Yeah, I don't care about those.
Uh, good for you.
Sounds like a worst scratch file system.
Oh, okay. So, you think that compose FS
is worse than file uh scratch FS? Okay.
Yeah, I I don't know anything about it.
uh you know I yeah I don't know anything
about those but okay so let's uh
continue let's this is the thing we
talked about let's just write it there
okay so let's continue to uh JSON okay
JSON
uh yeah so so we're going to do this uh
let's try to do this okay so let me just
show you uh import JSON okay so
so import JSON JSON uh if you don't know
what is a JSON JSON is JavaScript
based format okay what what is it uh the
full name JSON JavaScript
object notation that's what it stand for
or originally JavaScript object notation
so essentially what it is is just a
JavaScript syntax so in JavaScript you
have something called object which is
like a Python diction dictionary or Java
map or it's like emac this hasht pearls
hasht
you know it's a basically a collection
of pairs okay and in JavaScript you also
have array which is basically a sequence
of items so you can nest them
arbitrarily you know you can have array
and each item is a number string or it
can be array again or each item can be a
a dictionary you know what Python would
called dictionary or you can have a
dictionary then so dictionary is a list
of key and values. So so each key are
always a string and the value can be a
array or another dictionary. So things
like that. So you can nest them
arbitrarily that is effective
effectively what JSON JavaScript object
notation is
uh in in JavaScript syntax. Okay. So
it's a data structure representing
nested list or nested uh hash hash table
or dictionary mixed in any way in
JavaScript syntax that that is what JSON
is. But however, however there's slight
differences you see if you are a
beginner you you might think that but
but actually if you know the detail if
you work with a JSON there's some
warning you know you need you need to
know because in JavaScript
you don't have to quote the key you know
like for example here is the syntax for
hash table of one key and one value the
key is the string H
but in JavaScript you don't have to
quote that but however in JSON you have
to okay so and also the only allowed
quotation mark is the quotation mark not
apostrophe in JavaScript you can use
apostrophe but not in JSON so that's one
difference another diff difference is
that in JavaScript you can have trailing
commas but not in JSON okay so JSON
basically basically cleaned up made it
more strict
and in JavaScript you can have uh what
is this uh semicolon you know semicolon
this kind of actually necessary
sometimes you need a semicolon at the
end of the hash table the object value
or the array value but in JSON not
allowed okay and also in JavaScript you
have this this type called undefined
and But in JSON that's not allowed.
Okay. But in but in JavaScript you also
have this new data data type and that's
allowed in JSON. Okay. And JSON in
JavaScript you can comment things out
you know. So if you have array in
multiple lines you can comment you know
slash slash some elements out. But in
JSON that's not allowed. Okay, that's a
major uh like a major crack,
you know, major um what's the word?
Major traps you might uh need to think,
you know, need to know if if you came
from JavaScript, you know, if you are a
master of JavaScript. So JSON is, you
know, so so why JSON? JSON, you know, so
essentially it's a string. It's a text
textual representation of a data
structure. Okay. And uh it is used today
is you know very it's the number one
most popular. It's used for data
exchange between different programming
languages or between different programs.
So if you code Python you might export
to JSON. Uh then then the server or the
client or the JavaScript or the browser
may may read the JSON you know.
Similarly, the browser JavaScript can
output JSON then your server written in
Python, Golan or whatever wam language
you can read it. So it's it serves as a
interchange format.
Okay, that which which uh which
supplanted the previous vision of XML.
So before JSON that the vision for
interchange format is XML the universal
extensible markup language but but that
kind of failed. So Jason JSON is created
by this guy. Um okay I'm digressing
again. At this rate I'll never
demonstrate this.
So you guys tell me your opinions what
you want to hear. Okay. You want me to
like focus technicality?
you know the the the the master of
JavaScript and the master of uh whatever
what what is the language emac this you
know you want to learn about that or you
want me to tell you stories like your
grandfather would
so anyway before JSON is XML is is is
the interchange format but JSON turn
won't JSON was created by this uh qual
Uh
uh Kali info search uh
uh c wait uh JavaScript the good parts.
What
what uh oh god I'm about as good as
dead. That that was 2012. Okay. Uh,
Crawford CR A W.
Okay. Well, JavaScript books. Let's just
search that. Wait, what happened to my
something wrong with my um
what? Why is JavaScript
book?
No, I have several pages about
JavaScript book. What happened to my
info search? Am I searching the right
right place
review
pattern of software 1996? Richard
Gabriel which is one of the founder uh
he's the founder of Lucid which is the
creator of XEMAC which became XEMAX.
Richard P. Gabriel is one of the uh top
expert of lisp.
Okay. Okay. There it is. Okay.
JavaScript books books review. There
they are. So why so when I search for
book?
Okay. Because I typed JS. JS [ __ ] it
up. Okay. It should be JavaScript. Yeah.
So anyway, the the guy
um JavaScript definitive guide 2020,
there's a new version. Okay. The cost of
complex languages. Uh Rand Ryan D, the
creator of Deno and N.JS there. And uh
what I need to find the book JavaScript
book review 2023. Okay. I read these two
books. JavaScript the good parts that is
by
this guy. Okay. Quarkford. Oh, okay.
Douglas Quarkford, right? He's the top
expert of Java JavaScript. I talked
about him several times. So he's famous
for he's famous for making making
JavaScript popular as a as a good
functional programming language in the
year 2000s. Okay. He created he wrote
the book JavaScript the good parts which
introduced JavaScript to the masses
about the good parts about how it is a
functional programming language.
Okay. So, Douglas Quford,
I I've seen quite a lot of his videos.
Very I highly respect that guy. Okay.
So, Douglas Quford, he created Jason.
Okay. Jason is his product.
Okay. We are far away. So, what do you
guys want? Uh,
stories are fun. Okay. But technical is
probably still useful for some people.
Okay. That's ambivalent vote.
When you vote, you need to like vote on
one thing
GPS. Good morning, good evening, GPS.
Okay, let's let's do this JSON. So So
here's the JSON. This is emacisp. So you
run it and put the output here. So you
see this is uh emac this array. So out
output is that
uh wait
I took it take it back. So JSON pass
string this is reading a JSON. So this
this thing this is a JavaScript array.
So that's JSON. Now it's a string. So
when you run it and put output here that
becomes a list I mean list vector. Okay.
This is emac this vector. Okay. Now if
you read this thing, this is a
JavaScript object which is a dictionary
uh collection of uh pairs. Okay, key
value key value. Okay, that's JSON. Now
you say JSON pass string turn it into a
eag object. Okay,
run it. So what you get is this. Now
what is this? This is a hash table.
Okay, this is emac this hash table. In
this syntax, this syntax is the uh read
syntax for hash table. In other words,
it's called literal expression for hash
table. So effectively, it reads a string
of JSON and uh and let's see.
Okay, so it well anyway. So it so here
this is a JSON and now it becomes a hash
table. Okay. Uh for example I can demo.
So for example set this to xx. Okay. So
let's set the output there. Okay. Now
run it. Success. You can see my commands
on the ping window.
Now you want to say xx. So let's say get
hash. Okay. Get hash. That's a syntax in
eac list to get a key from hash table.
Okay. Uh key. What key do you want?
Let's say name. Okay. Key is a string.
So I want the name and table. What what
what table? XX optional. What if the key
cannot be found? What do you want the
default value? We don't care. Just use
Neo. Okay. So if you run this,
oh so the key the value for the key name
in this hash table is Mary. You can see
so it verifies.
So it proves
that this read pass JSON is correct.
Okay. Now continue. Uh so that's you
know demo of other you know examples.
It's a tricky part. Now you see in JSON
you got this true you know any of the
item the so-called atoms
atoms in the expression. Do you guys
know what's an atom in uh expression?
Atoms means like you know if you have a
list or array or hash table you know the
like numbers are atoms strings are
atoms. So atoms in general means the
smallest expression in a programming
language typically inside a string array
collection uh map dictionary hash table
that kind of thing atom the concept of
atom is particularly defined in lisp
programming languages including wam
language you know so I can show you lisp
manual okay search manual atom
Okay, it says predicates unleash. Now,
now, now let's highlight the word atom.
Okay. Bam. Bam. Bam. Atom. Yellow. Yes.
No. You see? So, the following
predicates test whether a list object is
an atom, whether it is a conale or is or
something something function atom
objects, you know, something something.
So you see the atom the word atom is
defined here and and talked about show
in browser you know I have a fantastic
command to view uh info documentation in
browser in my own website this is
kali.info info emac so you can see atom
you know so there's this atom function
so that is about showing you how atom
the concept is defined in lisp and
similarly it is defined in wuam language
okay so
so for example let's start a new and uh
switch to kasaw wufam mod you can see at
the bottom kasawa wuam mod now I I want
to type atom Q. Okay. Completion there.
Okay. So, atom Q. Let's say three. Uh,
wait. Three. Run it. And paste the
result here. Uh, wait. Not that. Okay.
So, I press the wrong key. Press press.
Okay. It'll take two seconds for it to
start wam language. True. You see what?
So, this function in Wuam language. But
let's look up the documentation. Okay.
Press press
turn on JavaScript. It's already on and
magnify to 1,000°.
Okay. So you see atom a function
expression argument yields true if
expression is an expression which cannot
be divided into sub expressions and
yields false otherwise. So in other
words, this function atom Q test if an
expression is the is an atomic thing.
Okay. So atom includes numbers, strings
uh or symbols symbols such as atom
itself you know symbol. So woofam
language is you know in you know it's a
it's a lisp
and this atom Q by the way what Q stand
for? Q stand for question that's a
convention in wam language it means any
function that ends in capital Q always
either return true or false not any
other value so always return true or
false okay it's called predicate in list
languages or in functional languages it
was called predicate but today's zuma
generation know nothing you know today
they don't know but classically they are
called predicate functions
What's a predicate? Functions means a
function either always return true or
false return a boolean type. Okay,
that's called predicate.
So uh so in lisp you have this atom
function does exactly the same thing.
Okay, atom.
Okay, that's kind of a little
digression. We were talking about this.
Um, okay. So, uh, so let's cut that and
go to talk show. Let's put that to here.
So, that means we talked about that
thing. Okay. So, wra language code.
Paste it there. Syntax code show in
browser. There it is. And now go back to
uh, close that. Go back to this. So, we
so we were talking about this. So in
JSON in JavaScript the language
specifically in a subset of JavaScript
called JSON you have the the special
value of true false and no these are
atoms okay special atoms
so there's a issue when you import JSON
you know doesn't matter you are using
Python or JavaScript or I mean
language or any or Please you know when
you import this true false no from JSON
what do you want them to become because
your language may not have this concept
of true or no you know that's the case
with emac this and this in general
including common dispo
is supposed to mean force anything
otherwise is supposed to be tr mean
true. So you need to specify how when
you encounter these true false or new
how do you want them to be translated
into um emacisp your language or python
or wuam language whatever or goland okay
so by default true just become t okay
let's run this okay run it you see by
default true the atom true becomes just
t in this false became this special you
know Now this this this special thing uh
not well known in this. So force becomes
a symbol. This actually this is a
symbol. Whenever you have a symbol that
became with two dot that means a symbol
and that means kind of like a temporary
temporary symbol. Okay. And then new
JavaScript JSON new becomes eag symbol
new. So, Emac this by default they don't
have this thing but you know they just
create that those symbols for for for
JSON. Okay. So, this is important
when you import JSON to lisp. So put the
code back syntax code showing browser
back to our JSON uh emac list tutorial
that's about reading JSON
and uh so
so for example you can add so if you are
doing in Python oh I have an article on
that so scroll down so JSON
uh JSON Python read write JSON so this
is Python's version
you know so in Python you encount
encounter new what does Python you know
Python in Python it became
uh JSON to Python object it became none
okay Python doesn't have no new but
Python has this special none okay
this
special things okay
and in wam language you have the similar
issue when you import JSON. Okay. So
anyway, are you guys is this is is this
interesting? I already talked for 30
minutes. Okay. So, so we we barely begin
to cover this emac this. So, we we you
know we kind of covered reading import
JSON and oh then then there's more
complexity. So, this is for those of you
who are eag coders.
uh some you know uh technical detail
because
remember JSON is a data structure of
JavaScript syntax. Okay. So what what is
a data structure? Well, it's a nested uh
nested array or nested dictionary in
JavaScript. Okay. Can be mixed nested in
any way.
So but in in lisp in eac lisp when you
want to represent a sequence of key
value pairs you actually have three
choices.
Those choices are
association list
property list let's open and hash table
hash table. So actually you have three
different data structures to represent
key value pairs. Okay. So here's a hash
table in EMAC list. Here's association
list in EMAC list. Here's property list
in EMAC list. They have different
syntax. They have different behaviors.
Okay.
So question when you import JavaScript
hasht you know the the JavaScript JSON
um
like this name Mary uh you know like
like this name marry age 24 what in you
know when you import that should should
it become hash table or should it become
uh
you know association list or property
list you know so
the most fitting Main choice is actually
hasht. So by default it they become hash
table. But if you want it to become
association list or property list you
can you just have to specify you know
this you know. So here's the example. So
by default array becomes array but you
can also say array becomes a list. Uh
and what is the hash table example here?
So hash table. So here is a hash table
very simple one a dictionary. So you can
say by default you you know you u by
default they become hasht okay like that
but you can say you want it to become
association list like that or you can
specify here to become a property list.
Okay. So that is kind of you know the
technical detail for Emac beast.
So far so good. So so far so good.
Matlab should open source as well. It
would be cool if we found open source.
Uh well that is frequently asked
question. You know there's a quandere
you see if you you know wam language you
know it's fantastic. You know it cost
you few thousand dollars. Um you know
you can you can get a you know right now
it's free uh for personal use.
So let me let me let me well let yeah
well why don't I you know wam language
wuam they donate to me. Okay so let me
tell you how good they are you know I've
been coding them wam language since 1990
uh 19 1993.
Okay. So, Wuham language, you know, you
can download it for free. They became
free like free to use for personal use
since about seven years ago. Okay.
Download it. But you can also pay for a
student version like uh $200 something a
year, $300 a year stu student version.
It's I mean if you are a student then
you can do that but the version is just
the full. So, wuam doesn't have crippled
version like the every wam you know does
it's the same okay so you pay like 250
something you know check their website
you know a year then you get you know
wam desktop or Android version or
whatever they have you know so many
uh but the it's always the full version
it's never like some like it used to be
you know before some software you have
this concept of crypaware here like like
some student version would don't have
this feature that or or something like
that that does not happen with Wuam
language okay Mathematica
I bought it when I was a student in 1992
or 1993 I bought it I spent few hundred
uh you know I I bought the student
version I still have the disc CD you
know
actually I I you know it be at that time
it's not CD CD is not out yet. You got
these floppy discs you know five or 10
floppy discs.
Okay. It's a wuam language you know it
began since 1987
199 1988
and before that Stephan wuam is another
software which became wam ma mathematica
okay but the the thing is you know so
today people want you know why don't you
you know they want open source right
because open source became
long story you know I'm not going to you
know I I talked so much about open
source But the question is people want u
language to become open source. You got
a problem
because once you it became open source
nobody pays and it became just become
[ __ ] It become [ __ ] within one year or
two just like the Gnome Foundation you
know they it became deep state [ __ ] It
it gets into your pants, you know. It it
it check what you're doing and send it
to CIA,
send to the it and you want to do this
it oh [ __ ] crashed. Oh, go let's go to
Stack Overflow, you know. Let's Why do I
crash when I'm I'm doing this? You know,
it became [ __ ] just like Linux.
But you'll love it. You'll love it. You
You'll love it. you every day you'll
spend, you know, one hour to check, you
know, how to how to fix this thing.
Tomorrow you spend another hour to fix
that thing, how to fix fix that thing.
Nothing works out of the box
open source, but it's open source.
So that's a question, you know, that's
people being demanded, you know, I know
that's what you think.
and Matlab that's another sad story okay
mat lab is also a victim of open source
you see I know mat lab since like 1990s
okay uh they they got the same problem
because the open-source invasion you
know the open source fanatics they
demand you know they they demand you you
should be open source you know I'm not
going to pay [ __ ]
so open source has collapsed many prop
proprietary uh uh companies including
many
companies that creates lisp you know
France Lisp mini okay France uh this is
old history you know starting around
year 2000 you know all these companies
become basically bankrupt because nobody
is going to buy anymore because commonly
Oh, we got you know we got several
version of open source they by these
open source fanatics.
So and the B O B operating system you
know you guys know B operating system
you know many of you don't but you know
so basically it just killed a lot um
small
software companies. Okay because no you
know these [ __ ] demand things to be
free. They say they demand morality you
know because they want you know moral on
based on moral principles. They don't
you know and also we need to we need the
source code because how do I know you
are not like looking into my pens
looking into my files so therefore I
demand source code but actually they
just want things free
these student young [ __ ]
just just like communism just like
exactly the the reason communism the
idea spread let's share you know if you
don't share you are evil
that's what open source are you know the
essence okay
so um
[Music]
so it seems but but it became a huge
movement just like communism you know so
year 2000 they became you know they
demand so a lot so you know so what does
the corporation do you know what what
did Google do Google is Google uh open
source well not really you know like is
Google Chrome browser open source? No.
Well, your part of it is, but the
important part, no. Is Google, you know,
search open source? No.
Is Microsoft Windows open source? No.
Although this they sponsor open source
today, you know, the thenet is all open
source. But why is Windows not open
source? You see, is is Amazon open
source? No. Is Facebook open source? No.
But they are known for open source you
know they they are the donors of open
source they they support they are the
heartbeat actually today of open source.
So they are not but they are not exactly
open source. So what they do you know oh
so you demand open source. Oh so you
demand open source. You are so loud and
so so so powerful. So many of you. Oh,
what am I going to do? If I go open
source, you know, then then anyone can
sell my software, then I'm going to be I
going to be dead, right? Hm. We must
think of some something. All right,
cloud.
Let's go to the cloud and let's make it
a service.
So, we are Google. We actually do search
engine as a service. No, we don't we
don't we don't write software. We we
just have the service you are paying for
the service
cloud you know we we will you know make
it convenient so you can doesn't matter
what device you are will store it on the
cloud you know this is adv advanced
computing cutting edge computation it's
called cloud computing
you know so store your you know photo
your bedroom photos where you are you
know where you go we all store it on our
computer, you know. So that's
that's that's that's what the [ __ ]
open source [ __ ] did. Okay.
Everything become becomes cloud. There's
nothing you can do because you open
source [ __ ] You demand things to
be free for selfish reasons. Okay? You
don't actually care about morality.
Nothing. You just [ __ ] pretend you
do. You just want things to be free.
So you know you when you punch someone's
going to punch back. So when you demand
this you know these people the masses
the mob you know making demand this you
know Google you should be this or that.
Okay they created the cloud computation.
Now everything you ever have is like
stored in their computer. It be and
became normal.
That's what opensource did.
Okay. So, uh that became a rant. Okay.
So, uh the [ __ ] open source,
you know, I was actually I was a big
supporter of Richard Stman for like 10
years, you know. I was like I I was, you
know, I was a young guy just like you
guys. I was a big
fanatic
supporter of Richard Stoman's Free
Software Foundation.
Uh, that's too bad.
Okay. So, what else you guys um probably
been asked many time, how did you get
your Windows cursor to look like that?
Yes, that has been answered. So, all you
have to do is you
go to control panel. Oh, let me show
you. Okay, just go to um Windows
preferences, go to devices, then go to
mouse, then go to adjust mouse and
cursor size there. Okay, there you can
make it huge.
You can make jingle bell huge, mega
mouse cruiser. Okay, and you want to
trail. Okay, then you click on
additional mouse settings. Click. Then
you then very complex. Then you go to
adjust mouse additional mouse options.
Okay. Click. Then you got this ancient
20 years [ __ ] old mouse properties.
Okay. Then use, you know, tiny. You
cannot see the font, you know, tiny
[ __ ] Windows. [ __ ] Windows. Windows
10, Windows 11. [ __ ] You know they
supposed Oh, we we we we created Windows
10 a revolution. No, we created Windows
11 advanced technology.
Yeah. But got you got you you got this,
you know, tiny font impossible to read
and this claustrophobic window, you
know, you like my window now the screen
is, you know, 30 inches, but you know
this unlargeable [ __ ] So you got this.
Then you go to pointer options. Okay.
Then you you say uh display pointer
trails not load trails. Okay. Uh pointer
trails not trails. Okay. So that's how
you do it.
Okay. Uh
IMS is still based even is uh even if
he's wrong.
[Music]
Well, what do you mean by based? You
mean he says things freely? Yeah, that
is that would be true. Uh so the you
know
you know in the past 10 years USA became
so bad because of the deep state uh and
you know then you got code of conduct
you know
you know kind of like the offshoot from
the open source [ __ ]
you know uh and then
extremely evil. Okay, this code of
conduct.
So Richard Sman is like against that. So
he, you know, he's still good for that
in that sense.
Anyway, so
okay. So I didn't want to go into a
rant. So let's go back to this. Uh I
think that's it for today. We just
So we didn't did we get to the code wam
language, you know. Not not yet. Let me
demo a little bit. Okay, let's go to
Wufam language. Okay, so um
you know importing and exporting JSON is
not really interesting. Now this this
mouse is too big. Okay, let's put it
back. So um
system settings
devices
mouse
additional mouse options
then you pointer options then oh wait
the size okay so the size cruiser speed
wait what
uh just mouse and cruiser size okay So
okay let's leave it like that
uh you know import export JSON is not
really interesting so let's skip it you
know because it's kind of boring you
know you just import data so
okay so hello AOP
are you Greek because looks like you are
using Greek no is that Greek or is that
Not. It looks like Greek. No, it's like
like kind of mixed. Heroki, sorry for
asking this. I know you've talked about
Oh, but why windows? Jesus, I talked
about a thousand times. So, just look
at, you know, Yeah, you know, I
literally talked about it for like five
more than five times. Okay. So, you go
to talk show, just go to search. Okay.
Windows
Okay, then let's say you know so you got
we got 156 results. Let's also type Mac.
Uh then you got uh so let's say type
Linux, Windows and Linux.
Uh okay. So
let's say talk show. Okay. So let's say
talk show Windows
most efficient way to switch Windows app
on Linux Mac Windows uh knob keyboard
joystick uh bash probies something
something efficiency Richard Storman
resign free software foundation
something something 2019
uh UI pip show window that that's what
we just demonstrated astron astronomy me
the palades.
Why tech sucks? Rage comics Pepe talk
show window tiling white tiling window
manager sucks window key setup free soft
for your foundation you know one thing
annoying about windows is that
everything you know it's a common word
so
there it is talk show 2023 February 6
China YouTube
windows versus Mac versus Linux. Okay,
that's one of the time I address that
but I addressed that many times. Okay,
for example, this article why I'm
switching from Mac to Windows. Actually,
I just talked about it this week.
Okay, so I'm not going to talk about,
you know, this week I talked about it.
uh you've been thinking about dropping
Linux and maybe going back to Windows,
I wouldn't recommend that. Okay, Windows
sucks very bad. So, if you are already
on Linux, I would say stay with it. You
know, Windows very bad, very bad in deep
state. Okay, if you already familiar
with Linux, stay with it. If you really
want to switch, switch to Mac. Okay. Mac
OS. That's my recommendation.
A Mexican. Okay. Why do you want to drop
Linux? Okay.
I don't know. Okay. I think that's it.
Should that that that should that be it?
I think that's it.
Okay. So, we we did did we talk about uh
JSON? Yes, we did talk something about
JSON move language close. Uh so my check
out you know my eac list tutorial
in JSON is almost complete. Not not
exactly though because when you import
JSON wait
yeah when you export to JSON uh
there is something I still need to work
out you know. So and also the old JSON
library I need to like write a full like
coverage.
Okay. So anyway but this but you know
there it is. So,
so and there is JavaScript, you know,
JavaScript JSON object, you know, how do
you do that?
Import JSON or export JSON in
JavaScript. It's all here.
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching. Donate to me. Okay,
so just go to you can buy my tutorial.
You can buy my Emacs tutorial. You know,
there's a big button there. by pay me,
you know, PayPal
$100,
you know, it's that's that's like a
donation. Okay, just donate to me
because the the or you know or you can
Amazon gift card me $100. Why $100?
Because the entire thing is on the web.
You know, today people don't like like
download the zip file. You know, you
have internet 24 hours at all times
anywhere on the phone on, you know, so
the entire content
of my EMAC list is on the web
since like since like 2006. Okay?
You know, when I ask for donation, you
get like for example, you get maybe $100
at most a month.
Okay? It's very sad situation of the
open source [ __ ]
when you ask donation like I used to you
know it's been you know my Emac tutorial
on the web it's been 20 years so I've
tried many things for 20 years
experience I know how things are so you
know for many years I have a link about
donate on every page something
so if you ask for donation you get at
most
$100 $100 a month. Okay, basically. But
if you put ads like you you you know for
for many years I have Google ads. You
get 300 a month.
Okay, that's the difference. You don't
have to beg. You don't have to beg. Oh,
please donate whatever. You just put
ads. $300 month. And typically when you
ask for donation, 100 is maximum. You
know, maybe you got lucky in one month,
but usually it's like $30 a month,
you know, $50 a month if you are lucky
in that month. Okay.
If you ask for donation, you know, all
the all these by now what what 600
pages, you know,
my most popular, you know, for Emac this
my my tutorial tutorial is most popular.
you get $30 a month, $50 a month if you
are lucky that month. But if you put
Google ads, very annoying, nasty. You
know, Google, they they they
plaster ads all over and and and over
the years to the degree you cannot
control. You say minimum, they still
plaster all over. Very annoying. So they
become deep state very much. So that
that's why I removed all of that. But
anyway, so if I have Google ads, it be,
you know, $300 a month.
So that's a sad thing. You know, these
opensource [ __ ] Opensource
[ __ ] They they being abused
by these deep state Google, you know,
who is promoting open source? Is it
Richard Storman? No, it's by Google and
Facebook and uh all these big
corporations.
So, so that if you are a programmer,
they made sure
that you can never be interdependent.
The only way you make money is to work
for them.
If you dare to say, you know, men, oh, I
think men are and women are not the
same. Goodbye. You are cancelled. Okay?
You won't be making money anywhere.
doesn't matter you know if if you are a
great software writer you know you
that's why that's Google Google Facebook
you know and and now Microsoft in the
past 10 years they became
and Linux you know they they they are
the sponsor of the open source you know
they made sure you if you are a coder
you can make money any by any other way
just except you listen you became a
cockwhe a pong on under them. Okay,
that's what they are. That's what open
source is.
H it's very sad to talk about is this
you know so so but you know like in the
past month I've been asking for
donation. Do I get donation? No. Do you
guys want to know how much I get?
$10 a month. Maybe not something. Well,
thanks to um actually Hank,
he's donating me every time I do a
video. So 50 $50 a month, something like
that.
Except there are few good people, you
know, there are a couple of people, two
or three who donated
a big amount to me. Okay.
Uh, that's it. Okay. It's [ __ ] sad to
talk about this.
Bye, guys.
Thank you, Nastia.