test I wonder he find my life starting
code okay so Oh
I'm live wow this is unexpected
okay so I'm live and welcome to another
episode of Santos show today September
6th Friday
6:50 a.m. in the morning San Francisco
time and so I'm starting 10 minutes
early so let's start command log mod and
on this window you can see all my Emacs
commands such as forward backward and so
on and let's see how do I find out how
many people are watching now and I'm not
sure I can it's seeing the Live
dashboard stream status bad what the
heck
no data
- heck no data
like bad primary stream we are not
receiving video data at fast enough rate
he is not receiving data at fast enough
rate 720 stream okay let's go to
settings and stream okay general
now it's in the morning 7 o'clock so I
cannot talk very loud and video it's
check video ok
it should be right but YouTube says
YouTube says no no it's good
what the is going on with this
morning hey good morning Cathy great to
see you again
what's up Cathy so today we don't have a
topic so you pick a topic so Cathy pick
a topic like do you do you like to do
you like to hear about Emacs JavaScript
Golan or anything else
random otherwise I'm just gonna start to
talk random I guess and okay so you know
yesterday well too few days ago I did
this interactive application
this is inverted Unicode so let me show
you here so I'm gonna copy the file path
go through the Google Chrome hope a new
window Pacey
enter so this is done in JavaScript so
Cathy you are a programmer right oh you
are a logician I get a sense you are
audition a regular expression in the
eby's okay let's do that
so you see okay let me show you this
first okay so I wrote this JavaScript
application few days ago you see as you
can see it shows the text inverted
inverted so these Unicode characters you
can see for example I copy these well
they are just you know inverted Unicode
characters each one of these is a
character you know Unicode is
interesting this is something
interesting about this you know some of
these characters their name is enemies
let me show you
let me see let's see inverted
okay yeah let's see you see they you see
this character inverted Y the Unicode
name is turned sans-serif capital y so
in unicode you have several characters
that's turned for example this one
inverted V is called Latin capital
letter turned V you know apparently when
you know in the old days when you print
you know you use the metal and you know
you met you you have several metal
blocks each one is a letter you arrange
them together that's how you print and
apparently sometimes you invert too late
the letter for example there is for
example this one latin small letter
turned e now this character is used also
used in phonetics
it's pronounces that pronounced like
Berto it's like ah it's kind of like and
the reason we have a character like that
is because you know it's very easy just
turn just to turn around you know the
printing block to create a new letter so
people did that you know because
otherwise if you are going to create a
new character such as you know whatever
character let's see for example this
sharp Shavian alphabet you know if you
are going to create a new character such
as these you are going to need to cast a
new metal and that's that is a very
expensive process you know this is like
200 years ago or something like that
very except expensive so when people
wanted a new character what they do is
they just invert it so that's why you
have these inverted many of them many of
the characters you have them you know
just English characters inverted but
however some of them do not exist
like you have to for example let's see
inverted a b c hope and d e reverse t
turn death turned g okay those are
capital you know in there are some of
them that does not have a inverted
version so you just try to find it in
russian or some other languages so
that's about inverted characters and
they also have inverted coma for example
you see this we're here in inverted coma
and of course you have inverted inverted
exclamation sign and you have in
inverted question mark those are used in
spanish you put that in the beginning of
a sentence and you have also inverted
period so let's copy that go to Emacs so
you are a Emacs user right
yeah obviously regular expression in
Emacs so open a new buffer face it
magnify then we can let's copy this part
copy it copy back to Emacs
paste it here and the you core describe
cha so you see this is an inverted
question mark and let's call describe
cha on the period okay so that character
is start above so Kathy says I always
wondered how people did that hand
especially why okay I guess the reason
why is you know Koch did this this ad on
Twitter coca-cola
they did this ad on Twitter so it's
easier to read it if you just let see
the mission let me show show that you
know it's it's dramatic that's why I
guess
that's why people so here is a picture
let's back up that's got tired go too
tired so this is a file let's rename it
rename it with - okay okay open it open
in preview and you can see here preview
now we rotate it rotated about there it
is so he says think you got what it
takes you know so that's that's an ad
for from coke Coca Cola hold on second
so let me delete that file so this is a
fire TV the file close it close it okay
so so we are done with that
okay so regular expressions in v's so
are you you are coding eMac B's clothes
that don't save go to Emacs blog open it
then eMac Lisp and there is a section on
regular expressions such high a GE X Y a
regular expression Hema crisp so Kathy
says I'm a PhD doing machine learning
research almost to minimum programming
compared with other code okay cause
normally what make thing walking is just
a few lines of mathematical functions
machine learning research okay that's
that's a deep subject so yeah so that's
mostly mathematics statistics I think I
haven't really I haven't actually got
into study machine learning machine
learning so I suppose you are I mean I'm
thinking mostly they are doing neural
networks they are using neural networks
or some kind of data mining and
statistics so what languages do you use
to do those machine learning so Kathy
says but I'm thinking doing something
more practical for for natural language
analysis with web scraping scraping
regular expressions is underrated in Oh
academic study huh let's see I see yeah
it's it's heavily used in industry
statistics okay so regular expression oh
you are using oh yeah I don't know any
other I barely even have ever looked at
our code but from what I hear it's not
you know and it's not that good
programming language you know from from
the from the people who are into
programming language
but I suppose it's a usable language and
okay so we are going to do talk about
eMac this eMac regular expression in a
matrix but do you code eMac this I mean
so regular expression in Emacs there are
there are kind of two aspects one is
that you use it too in Emacs for example
I want to search something I can use
regular expression to find all patterns
in the current directory you know all
kind of for example let's try
I want to such has I want to search any
words beginning with H then three
characters then ending with L let's see
if we can find that so do that
so in this directory such or HTML files
okay not let's try it again
oh wait that that is not regular
expression I need to call soft find some
find some find texts rejects okay H dot
dot dot L okay so that's finding replace
let me try it again
soft find text rejects okay H dot r dot
L in this directory Oh HTML files fixed
case search yes with context string yes
okay so okay so these are all the
occurrences you know that's how you use
regular expression so regular expression
one aspect is that you simply use it you
know when you use Emacs
the other aspect is when you are using
it with emag in with image based code
for example let me copy this line it's
let's go okay so let's open this file so
this is my Emacs blog so now I paste
this now this is a regular expression
this is the Emacs function research
forward which stand for rejects you know
such forward using regular expressions
so we can we can try it oh my god
there's a spider here on my wall so we
can try it using a regular expression
pattern let's say a let's say space a
dot T space so this way you find all
your fine words like end okay so now
what we do is we give our last
expression we want to evaluate this
course so we do it so I'm gonna call it
look at the left window so call it you
found it found it you see right here you
see you just move the cursor to that
place okay now now so so that is calling
regular expression in Emacs Lisp so you
know so this is you know kind of two
aspect to it
okay so yeah you know okay so you know
what I'm talking about yeah so so I
guess you could email list them because
you know otherwise you wouldn't ask that
because I wasn't sure you know because
most people do not need you know they
are not doing an emag piece
okay so eMac beats also regular
expression so yeah so let me go back to
the regular expression topic so regular
expression you know first of all I mean
if you are he max user you I mean even
if you called eMac miss you should be
familiar with regular expression you
know using regular expression in Emacs I
mean such rejects so there is a regular
expression tutorial you know we we
talked about this before and this is
just an introduction because regular
expression in Emacs is a little bit
different from typically all the other
languages Python Java JavaScript Ruby
they are used or pretty much the same
regular expression but Emacs the the one
in Emacs is a little bit different minor
differences but still it's different
from the others while the others are
pretty much all the same so once you
know regular expression you know once
you are you got familiar with for
example calling beasts matching lines so
let's go let let me go a little bit
beast naturalized and then let me move
this here so lease maximize space a dot
T space okay enter so you you you see so
here are the all the results that
contains space dot T space how the lines
and basically they are or just end word
yeah they're all end okay so once you
have familiar with Emacs regular
expression syntax
you know which characters stands for
what once you know that then it's pretty
much trivial to to use it in email is
the only difference is that you need you
just need to add a lot back slashes
right so you know that so with that said
do you have any like do you have any
specific questions you are wondering
like okay so where where do you add the
back slashes let's still get my tutorial
so so Emacs regular expression so you
know if you have any specific questions
or directions just posted okay so so
that way it's better so so Emacs regular
expression you need to if you use it in
email is you need to add back slashes so
let me close this let me explain what
what is it that you need to do okay so
so first of all in Emacs when you have
when you have a stream this is the only
syntax for stream that is with double
quotes you know ASCII double quote
something something else Etobicoke
that's a stream now in Emacs this there
is no special syntax for regular
expression for example for example in
Python for example in JavaScript okay in
JavaScript you can a dot T okay so in
JavaScript this is a regular expression
you can you know it starts with a slash
ends with a slash it's not a string so
when you see when you well you can also
use a string for example for example in
JavaScript you could use a string and if
you use a string in a regular expression
function that you know it's an argument
depending on a function often you will
just
automatically change it into a regular
expression object or alternatively you
can use this slash syntax directly you
know that that just becomes a regular
expression object so this this is in
JavaScript
similarly in Perl and you know similarly
this is true in Perl you have different
syntaxes to represent regular expression
specifically but in Emacs Lisp there is
no such thing the only way I mean every
regular expression function they are
just going to take a string you know as
a regular expression pattern so you can
forget about all these you know special
syntax okay so so why is this important
well this is important because because
that is why that is why when you need
all the back slashes you know in a sense
is simple because now you you don't have
to worry about anything you only your
only concern is stream and how to escape
things in stream okay so that's one
thing the next thing we gonna talk about
is what what characters you need to add
a backslash good morning Derrick mone
so today is a moaning one so Kathy says
yeah okay so so let me just continue on
about yeah okay so let me just continue
on what about what characters you need
to add a backslash in front you know
this is actually not so good because
then you you need a lot back slashes you
know it's almost even simple regular
expression becomes unreadable such as
this one for example you look at this
image let me show you an Emmy magnify
so typically in other languages you have
something like the first line this one
but but when eMac eMac this he looks
like that there's no way around it this
is this is an actual you know the the
full syntax you have to type there's no
other way well there is a another way
but that's not standard
you should I do not recommend using it I
mean let me just mention that okay so in
Emacs there's a package called there's
in Emacs there's a package code which
rejects something I don't I don't
remember you we can find it but anyway
the purpose so if you use that package
the purpose of that package is that for
regular expressions you have a Auton
alternative way to represent all these
different syntaxes so basically it
becomes like a disk code
everything is for instances you know you
have lots of nested parentheses in some
way that's better because in you know
because it's just it looks like a list
code let me show you
okay so here is some example of Lisp
code so in some way it's better because
everything looks like this Lisp code but
in other way it's not better because
because typically you are familiar with
the regular expression syntax you know
that's everywhere in different languages
but now you have a completely complete
new thing so let me show you what that
package is let's try to search it so
hold on second they meet before we do
that close that let me write down what
we are doing today so create a new code
block for that here and this is in
JavaScript okay
in JavaScript and other in JavaScript
you have different delimiters for
regular expression for example you can
use a string or use use sash to
represent rejects object directly okay
that that's that's JavaScript and this
is true for other languages him in many
languages so could that face it here and
so there is JavaScript now here is an
example of eMac this showing browser
okay so here is an example of a regular
expression in eMac B's okay so what so
let's let's show
there is a Chili's package that uses
special Lisp style rejects syntax okay
and now let's find out it's such what
that package is I don't use it and I
don't recommend it
email is rejects package so good morning
Derrick and the Kathy okay and Kathy
says exactly normally I look at rejects
we can understand what it matches at
glance but in Emacs I got lost pretty
quickly in counting slashes yeah it's
very you know I have a lot experience
but now I'm getting better
I can I can know right away I can't I
can write it directly but it takes many
years and okay let me let me talk about
what exactly you know which character
you need to add a backslash
but we also want to find out what is the
regular expression package because I
mean there is an eMac this pack that
there is a eMac this package that
changes the entire regular expression
syntax to list style
okay so green deck
good morning green deck good morning to
Russia Kathy says but Emacs have to know
how to write customized configurations
what do you mean Emacs us have to know
how to write customize what what do you
mean for what okay so so right now two
two sub two topics
what is the eMac this package for
regular expression let's let's call this
packages maybe we'll find it here so
it's such for rejects okay okay
let's this matching eyes rejects okay so
we have several packages there I think
this one hold on a second
I think it's this one available good new
so XR I think is this one
open it
he asked me to install I don't really
want to install it but I just want to
show you there exists this package email
is rx rejects okay so let's go to
rebuild know the Builder is not what we
want
okay so rebuilder is another thing okay
this guy this guy mastering Emacs he's a
very popular Mike he Peterson so he has
a tutorial on rebuild me let me talk
about what is rebuild
the backslash madness indeed further
readings oh my god okay way anyway so
let me let me let's get on with this on
a second it's put it here so
okay so so we need to find the name of
that package but I don't know what it is
right now so let's go to emac wiki
so regular expression they are talking
about regular expression regular
expression syntax
okay so Emacs wiki has a tutorial
idiosyncrasies of Emacs regular
expressions yes indeed some rejects
examples oh my god they are stealing
they're stealing my my readership
rejects Marco okay so rejects Marco is
spearing Emacs okay
o X Marco yes that that is the one I'm
trying to find let's see in Co X yeah so
you see you write it like that we I'm
not going to show that but I'm just
going to tell you what it's like then
you can look into so for example this
okay so so there's a this package that
use special distinct tax for rejects and
the package is called rx yeah so the
Markov is it's technically a macro so
macro IX provides user-friendly syntax
for regular expression it's not exactly
user-friendly for example it says this
okay so you see this this code now this
code is similar to yeah so it did that
cost and for this one you know so which
one you actually like you know depends
on you
so it okay so see we see our X okay so
here is a link to Hayek's package now
this one is building okay yeah so
apparently it's building so if it is
let's see let's see if it's building we
can try it
so eMac this so speed wind well okay
speed a window then let's say require
require rx let's see if that works when
it yes it works now let's try this X 1
or more let's run it okay run it no it
works let me show it run it okay so so
this this thing returns that so meaning
that you know so okay so this is kind of
a I mean if you are learning regular
expression syntax you could use this to
learn it actually I don't recommend it
yeah it's like intermediate step you
know it's like middleman I wouldn't
recommend it so anyway there it is
that's the that's the rx package is
building in Emacs this returns please
okay so cut it out put it here make it
that and let's
showing browser okay so there is that
package I X and now now there is another
thing interactive we build a regular
expression builder I actually do not
recommend that one neither I don't
recommend it
you see I like things you know I like to
study things directly you know use the
raw whatever building you know I don't
use those intermediate steps but I'm
going to show you rebuild you know in a
moment
you know I'll show you what it is about
I actually never used it I mean so my
recommendation is that if you want to
use learn you know to build up
experience with Emacs regular expression
just use it directly you know just try
it you know many times it's the other
ways are simply learning as well you
know you might as well don't regular
expression directly the advantage is
that you know because it's a real
everywhere almost the same in other
languages so anyway let's let's go back
to the regular expression in eMac B's
what you know where do you need to add
back slashes so first of all I recommend
you just use you just be very familiar
with the Emacs regulation commands such
as query replace rejects and least
matching lines especially in
particularly smashing lines just go
ahead you know like when you are
learning regular expression you just
create a buffer type something you want
to match then just call then just call
this matching eyes like right now this
matching line space eight dot the space
okay you know that you know if it turns
out no answer but you expect something
then you know your rejects is wrong you
can try it again
you know just try this matching lines
again
you know so this is a very fast way to
to get the right regular expression
syntax so I had a high D you know highly
recommend it this is important when you
cook even if you could Americus because
sometimes you get okay so wait so yeah I
recommend you know least Matt you know
as well now let me tell you about where
do you need to add okay hold on a second
so let me go back okay so this matching
nice okay just use it okay here is a
trick so I call this matching lines
right let me do it again
this matching lines space 8rt space do
it and I find out this you know result
now suppose I want to turn whatever the
regular expression I just searched I
want to use it in eMac B's that is I
want to use it in this you know some
eMac this function you know I want a
string there now in this case it's very
simply see exactly the same you know no
backslash shows - but there is a easy
way that you can convert whatever the
interactive regular expression to the
illest it is string syntax with all the
backslash is added for you three thing
the way you do that is this okay let me
try it again
this matching is space a tardy space
enter okay you just call that now you
want to call the command we repeat let
me just do it because I remember the
keys I don't remember the command okay
here it is we do you see in the mini
puff in a mini buffer you see that let
me copy and copy okay and paste here you
see when you call the command we do okay
what is that man I just caught its
see here is a command oh yeah we repeat
Kody's command call this this okay to
convert a rejects in interactive call
such as this matching lines okay what
you do is this
cawww
first call is madness first to do to
what you want to do what you want then
immediately call whip repeat complex
command then a mini buffer it will show
the Lisp syntax of the rejects
expression you just used okay
that is the thing okay so so let's try
it
so let first of all so let's see let's
search for something that requires a lot
backslash or something let's just try
something okay so this matching noise
let's say I want on an ASCII characters
we wait and let's just try something
simple first okay so did that you know
let's let's say I want to find all links
like that which involves the quote you
see I want to find things like like that
like that pattern so so I do I call this
matching noise for the hold on second mu
first copy comments okay guys comments
so I call this matching lines then I
typed this whatever bracket inside and
here I want to say I want to say
anything that is not a double cross okay
and one or more okay so that is my
pattern enter there it is
let's magnify so you can see so you see
if it finds all the links okay let's try
it again this matching line is that
pattern enter okay now I want to know
how to write that pattern in eMac beasts
you know so I call repeat complex
command I have a key for it so I just
press it you see in a mini buffer it
shows that so let me copy it copy it
cancel paste it here so let's do it
again so so you see this this this line
now becomes becomes these you see so
that's super convenient so this is a
simple way you know to convert the
interactive regular expressions syntax
to the this string you see now it has
many back slashes it this is the easy
way because it machine the machine Emacs
figures it out for you so Kathy says I
agree no intermediate if possible I do
want to hear your experience about which
to add backward slash okay so okay so
yeah so this is this is first of all
this is a simple way to convert Dana I'm
gonna show you I'm gonna tell you which
one which character to backslash
so first of all let's make a lisp copy
copy paste it there this I don't need
quoted now the syntax coloring is
screwed up so this is what I have to do
anyway so show in browser
okay so this is very useful so you know
very very useful to convert rejects to
the list syntax the kerning is not so
great by anyway okay so so as far as
what characters you have to you have to
escape I you know the in alkali die
hi
double backslash okay so first of which
characters you need to escape let me
think about how to explain
okay so let me explain which character
you need to escape foot foot
first of all that backslash T and C
backslash t means tab okay so actually
yeah okay so backslash T is tab and
backslash in his new line okay you do
not need to escape them and and
backslash quote so these three with back
slashes you don't need to escape
backslash T so it's just single
backslash that means tab and backslash n
means new line and if you want a double
quote you need to have one backslash
that's that is it now the next thing is
that in email is regular expression many
of many of many of the things you need a
backslash a character for example
suppose you want to search suppose you
want to find a group you
I mean you want to group a patterns such
that you can refer to it later how you
do that you use parentheses but you need
the backs you need to use backlash
parentheses so this is even for
interactive regular expression this is
what you need to do so in it is then in
Eve is everything with a backslash you
need the backslash or game so so in it
is let me show you what is in it is so
in the EE Mac this is going to be that
okay so for example I say some okay
let's say ABC so this is the this is the
interactive code if you want to capture
the pattern you know ABC you want to
capture that doesn't make sense so let's
use the a dot B space okay let's say
that's a pattern you want to capture
but in eMac this code this is the code
you want so let's let's do an example
let's do an example okay let's open a
new buffer good morning Amane amny come
on e so let's show an example so we want
a hand and okay so hold on so hands some
and that this and that so we have a line
this and that now we want to replace
anything this end I did say
had three okay let's say these and that
add three that's a sentence now we want
to replace anything with space a dot B
space to something else okay let's say
replace them with x-axis let's say X
okay so let's do it do it okay so I'm
going to call query replace rejects on
the Left window you can see there and
now I'm going to type the pattern okay
hold on a second I mean just do this
okay
query rejects we query we paste rejects
now type the pattern so I want to
backslash parentheses space a dot D
space backslash parentheses you need the
backslash because you want to capture if
you just use parentheses that is literal
parentheses okay this is a difference
between a Mac this regular expression
versus other languages okay let's do
that so enter replace with X okay enter
so it found it you see he asked me
whether I want to replace that one so
yes yes okay so so that worked you see
now remember what I said before the
technique to automatically convert so we
can do that so we call we call repeat
complex command and copy copy whatever
in is in the mini buffer paste you see
so so Emacs showed us you know this is
the actual regular expression pattern
you can see now it has two backslashes
okay so let's go back to our notes
yeah so it's just like what we showed
here so this yeah so does that make
sense so okay so I know it's this is
sofa it's probably very confusing and
there's nothing you can do about it it
is true it is very confusing there is
actually there's no simple way to
explain it the only way I can explain is
that first of all remember first of all
remember that backslash T backslash n is
tab a new line there are few others okay
there are a few others but rarely used
and then if you want to have a literal
double quote then you need to have a
backslash in so all these by the way so
let me just actually put it correctly so
all these needs to have wait they are
strings you know they are inside streams
okay first of all first of all remember
they are these three okay now the next
thing first of all remember these okay
okay so actually let me make it more
fancy
this means apps Detroit the velcro okay
first of all remember these three things
then then then then any backslash in
this rejects needs to be double
backslash okay
for example that becomes that okay so
show in browser yeah so you know first
first of all remember these three then
then any backslash in eMac this regular
expression needs to have a backslash in
front of it double backslash basically
now why so what what things in eMac this
regular expression has a backslash they
are quite a few yeah so it's very
confusing you just have to try you know
you know I you know after many years you
know then you get you'll know it well
why did they do these spaces oh yeah
because my replay okay yes the previous
example that's because my replace string
do not have space that is why so for
example let's do it again you know let's
do this again let's redo and do okay so
let's do it again okay
what we are doing we are doing credibly
plays rejects okay and pattern is this
okay and replace pattern is X now if you
need space let's just put space X space
okay enter yes yes then you got space
okay now let's let's call repeat complex
command so you know mini buffer we got
that cancel it paste you see yeah so so
by the way it so this command we place
this command
what's repeat complex command is quite
useful I use it a lot what what it does
is that it will call the previous
command that involved some option like
sometimes when you when you do meta X
some commands you need to give it option
I mean you we will prompt you okay what
file name what directory things like
that or what stream you know when you
want to repeat those commands you can
just call repeat complex command when
you call that you just put out the whole
actual eMac this code you know so so you
see once I have this okay let me show
you this trick okay
read and do and do and do and do okay
now I paste it here now I can just
evaluate this expression and you just do
the whole thing for example without any
matrix for example without calling any
minarets for example let's try I'm just
going on I'm going to call Eva last sex
okay call it you see it's it's already
calling so I just press enter enter
instant you see and do and do evaluate
you see so so this command
leap leap leap a repeat complex command
is very useful it it repeats the last
command you caught that involved options
you know without you having to enter
optional options again because you just
you just prompt the whole list code then
you just press ENTER and just you know
just coy so so Kathy says I didn't know
there was a query replace rejects pod oh
that is very useful that is fundamental
yeah it's very useful so so okay so in
Emacs you know Emacs regular expression
is used in many commands let's see where
he max blocks so okay so practical Emacs
then you go down fun topic rectangle
topic show topic which rejects is
somewhere I forgot where and it's just
such Foley checks
okay so Emacs find we paste topic yeah
so the all these articles are about
find/replace of the current buffer or
all files in a directory or or you
simply want to highlight certain you
know sentences lines or words you know
they are always very expression so yeah
so mastering regular expression is
rather very useful analysis its curse
that
let me just put this for the moon from
the moment so yeah so so the first thing
you want to know is what are all the
commands that use regular expression
there are many you know such texting but
I search for word that that that uses
regular expression
no yet that doesn't actually but you
can't you there's a regular expression
version for example and now I'm not
going to talk about that anyway so so
you have hi such coin world I such
whitespace rejects okay so anyway okay
so you have least matching lines
extremely useful that use regular
expression you also have highlight lines
matching rejects you have DVD matching
lines you have devide non matching lines
I used all these very often almost every
day for sure at least every day some of
them but this matching lines I almost
used every hour you know so this takes a
regular expression which also means when
you when you want to code eMac B's using
regular expression or these are useful
you know oh this I can can actually
recording email is to you know after all
yeah there are this in there are also
these commands so anyway so I go to the
regular expression tutorial so these two
are the most useful query replace
rejects and this match realize okay so
in summary I would recommend you know
use you use them often that way is of is
the best way to get familiar with you
know trial and error you know to debug
your regular expression then you use the
you know reap repeats complex complex
repeat complex command technique
to convert it to the actual Lisp rejects
string syntax so anyway so this tutorial
is about regular expression how to use
it then go to the bottom rejects in eMac
this code this is about you know once
you are familiar with the Emacs version
of rejects then you need to know about
how to code you know how to escape stuff
and related issues and this article will
help okay yeah so another way to test
regular expression is by this way for
example let's open a new buffer taste
here and let's do the same example like
we did before this and that had three so
here we just space a that a dot t space
okay then just evaluate this part okay
cool but like I call evil as command
okay if you see the cursor moved it
worked
if the kusa didn't move we do some work
let's try it again
okay evil ask says evil last six okay he
walked now let's copy this space let's
try something else okay even last six he
says debugger entered we such failed you
see so this is another quick way to test
your rejects then then you can just
modify let's say let's try dot dot okay
devour it it worked
actually dot dot oh yeah data you you
know you know we are searching for space
any character any character any
character space that is why it jumps to
here because anyway so that's that's how
you one wait you know this I do this all
the time this is
this is how I test regular expression
now let's try some another example then
MIT then then you know any any other
questions type it let's see how long
we've been talking
46 minutes yeah so if you have any other
questions type it so so what I want to
do is I want to show first of all
showing this in browser so this is my
Emacs blog I want to show all the
Unicode characters such as this one
emoji you know I have in this buffer so
let's do that this matching lines
Unicode characters so I'm going to use
these rejects I know
non ASCII okay this is a this is a
syntax particular to Emacs rejects not
in other languages you it's not like
that but this this works in Emacs so I'm
just going to do that so enter that's
incorrect okay so let's see what's wrong
let's do it again
oh okay so okay this is wrong so
actually I need to do it like that
okay I need let's do it again this night
Reno is I need to I need to turbo the
square bracket enter now actually that's
incorrect
and Stuart again
okay any anyway I forgot so let's look
up the Emacs info for regular expression
H cause such such index I forgot what's
a command name so let's do let's call
apropos control H a rejects let's say
such okay now Emacs shows me all
commands that involves the name such and
I want to okay I remember the name
contains the word index so let me such
okay there it is
index here you see this command Emacs
index search this command will search
words in the Emacs Emacs Lisp menu so
let's call that command I have a key
you okay
okay so let's do it so I'm gonna search
the command I'm going to search for
rejects in Emacs manual enter there it
is you see right now we are in the info
Emacs info talk are you guys familiar
with that info dog is the Emacs manual
in Emacs so on this page it shows me all
the special characters in regular
expression
I mean basically it's explaining the
regular expression syntax so I go up
actually I go up and go up a section so
this is the manual of Emacs in a regular
expression you will need to read it so
you know I have a tutorial like I
explained before you know I have this
tutorial I show all the basic syntax but
you know after you have some experience
you will need to read the Emacs this
menu of a regular expression you will
need you will need to read it because I
don't I didn't cover all so anyway we
are on this page and what I want to do
is go to the character classes open and
there it is you can see the character
class I want is this oh so my mistake
was with a - I had a - I should not have
the - ok so I you know we know what I
want so close that let's try it again
least naturalize such fun an ASCII
without a - there it is
wait it's wrong
so maybe I need to double oh they're
okay finally finally so here are the
occurrences or the non non ASCII
characters you see Cody called Cody
single quote arrow emoji bail you know
that's just the example so let's try it
again
let's go through top let's go to where I
was let's go to top mikesblog okay now
this matching lines search for that
enter and now let's call repeat complex
command copy control chief or cancel now
go here and paste you see here is this
code this matching line is and that okay
that's that's I think that's about that
for regular expression any questions so
Kathy says yeah I think listening much
noise with rejects is important in daily
walk yeah green deck says does commonly
have any practical use today I'm reading
a book about it right now very
interesting because I don't know
anything about this I read that closure
is very similar to this yeah I have a
lot to say to about that now if you want
to if you if your goal is to have a job
okay coding this you basically the most
popular is closure you want to go with
closure
okay now ever close I have a closure
tutorial so let me just show it
Sarki board blog know some programming
blog opening browser so language
tutorials crochet okay I have you know I
have my closure tutorial is not complete
but you know you can read it especially
if you are beginner so anyway if you
want to work in industry closure is the
way to go unless if you PhD students you
know you know if you are going to do
postdoc in some research then you can
don't scheme or racket let me write it
down let me write it down okay so which
lists Petula okay that is the question
if looking for a job closure
okay if in academia ACA
ACA DMA then racket scheme giving a
cliff in academia or language research
then racket or scheme okay
now common list I don't like common this
so item so my opinion is biased probably
a little bit yeah I try not to you know
web I am answering questions but anyway
so Common Lisp is not really used okay
well it's using like let's say ten
companies in the world something like
that well you know not many not not you
wouldn't find a job in Common Lisp okay
so I would not recommend comedies also
because come commonly is the well I'd at
least in my opinion is a worst and it's
not it's not that controversial opinion
because for example let me show you
sun-lee comedies okay because many
famous programmers have you know they
don't like common this famous
programmers on how commonly sucks you
know we have guy style guys osteo who
invented scheme thirty years ago we have
Rodney Brook I don't know who he is
Richard Gabriel is the guy who started
lucid Inc which eventually gave us X
Emacs you know this is like in 1990s you
know Richard P Gabriel he you know back
then artificial intelligence is done
with Lisp and you know Richard Gabriel
he Richard Gabriel is also most famous
for having written worse is better you
know the worst is better the kind of you
know hacker have you guys did you guys
know that I'll call very famous okay you
should read it was was his pets like was
is better okay
goes such okay what what was this better
is one chapter of a book he wrote
Richard Blake about the UNIX
philosophy versus the disp philosophy on
design how you know when you have a
decision there are you know there are
certain principles of Lisbeth versus the
UNIX people I mean oh this is kind of a
law okay they are not scientific but
anyway what's this better is you know
you probably heard of it anyway you can
go read it so in this of course this
program which is popular for Yahoo store
who you know he coded comedies he wrote
uh gusto and so to Yahoo for some
hundred millions or something and he
doesn't like common list you know he so
that's why he created arc uglies which
which which went nowhere nobody
uses except y combinator uglies
yes they are using our face right Y
Combinator is retaining that is the the
comments you know the hacker news hacker
news is using uglies
as far as I know it's going nowhere very
few people use it and there is Daniel
Weinreb who is one of the founder
co-founder of the list machine Inc I
think you know one of the these
companies you know in the 80s you know
and he doesn't like yeah comedies you
know many people doesn't like common is
you know why because I studied this
history so you know in the 60s this was
invented then in 70s and 80s there are
many different disp you know it's like
lunch language war you know I like my
list you like your version at least you
have I don't remember the names there
are several different discs so
eventually people decided okay we let's
just let's merge them all together we
want one unified Lisp and the result is
Common Lisp but why do many people hate
it because because there's a committee
committee okay you know I have so many
stories to explain because this this is
gonna be another hour but I'm not sure
I'm gonna it's not maybe we should not
do that anyway what ended up happening
is that you have a committee that
created common list basically every you
know every sector of lease they say oh
we must need I need this feature in it
because this is my B's I'm used to it I
you must have this feature and that
group says no we must use that have you
know another feature to so you end up
with this extremely bloated you know
commonly lots of problems you know so so
I don't like it that's my opinion of
course today you ask
whispers they are you know us fans of
comedies that they are a lot fanatics
you know they'd they were saying they
say you should use companies saying yeah
but but they still commonly speak today
you don't have no industrial use okay
very little it's kind of dying you know
it's being no you know the standard is
like 20 or 30 2030 no really no progress
okay and and here you until you ask some
communist fanatics I know I know several
you know because I mean that group for
10 years they are they'll tell you a
different story but you know go ask them
there's you know see what they say
so I would say study closure if you are
thinking of finding a job one day
I mean coding for living in this but
even that you know that's you know don't
go don't do this if if your goal is to
find a job you know this you don't go
anywhere
but closure is the best chance you have
if in academia or for your own pleasure
hobby racket scheme you know you can do
that then yeah so I thought I'd I
wouldn't recommend this well you can do
email list of course which is kind of
practical okay Kathy I don't know why
are you using you make this you know for
research because you know it's actually
not you know it's only used for Emacs so
let me read the comments so I hope MIT
green deck does that answer your
question
yeah let me know what you think you know
let me give me feedback so gfx can
initiate GFX Kathy says you know I think
with this math you know so there was a
question I am excellent the meet up how
to manage visualize many textbook files
with tree structure
how to manage visualize okay
especially those tech stock files that
are not belong to any tree branches
what do you mean they do not belong to
any branches because if you have a whole
file everything is under a tree unless
you know config headers so Cathy Tay
Cathy says I think searching with
rejects can solve the management
problems visualization is difficult if
you have thousands things files ok so
Cathy are you still here maybe we should
we lend you know it's one hour so yeah
maybe that's it for today but I can
explain something about the
visualization because you can turn it
into a image with you know a graph
directed directed graph that's what they
call so let me show you some of that
well maybe I should I can show you or
maybe not but let me search for graph ok
search for graph because I have written
about this let's see what we find
ok not paragraph
okay lots of these are paragraph let's
go to practical Emacs let's go down
there's a section of oak mod okay o
clock Hoch mod markup cheat sheet oak
mark tutorial source code mark hooked
mod for to do hope mark hog
customization in Passau mod okay
there there there is some packages
actually I have written code that turns
a oak mod into a tree graph like you
actually generate a graph showing you
know an image file so I can I can find
that so you if you go to my Emacs blog
go to archive go through 2018 open them
I think you'll find it okay there's a
lot to search let me just search for
this space viz because
okay the hell done it's not it's such
for visualization search for such for
space square
there there it is here's the article so
what date is 2019 January
case
mind such for mind there it is
so there is this package anyway look
let's look at my yeah here so there are
packages that turns oak mud into this
you know images not mind map Oh gunshot
Oh graphs like that so I don't know if
that's useful to you and so if if that's
what you mean or not so what you have to
do is you have to write code to turn you
know the input is the oak mark fire and
you turn out a different different
format using the dart language you know
you output is a Thai language file then
there's a tool that takes the dart
language and render it like that so you
could actually see you know if you have
old file with lots of trees you can
actually see it visually that's what
this this is about so anyway let me post
this and if it's useful to some people
and this also by the way there's also
packages on the on the way up you know
mail part that helps doing that I have
written one but it's not public it's
I've written for this professor it's not
public so but you can try some of the
others okay so
Oh alignment yeah right oak mud oak
Mahad was the descendant of our line mod
because as far as I know the guy he say
astronomy well you know he's a he he was
a student of astronomy so he needs to
take notes you know in class so he take
notes and and he used the are dime odd
you know but online mod has lots of
problems with the keys key bindings is
very convoluted so anyway so he started
to improve it and improve it and even
yeah and then it became Oakmont and and
after by now it's like after 15 years
now he is a professor this guy the
Oakmont you know let's just see what's
his name why you know you can you know
you can you can find his name but anyway
so he is now professor but anyway that's
how achma begin so anyway so that's it
for today I guess that's it so any more
questions otherwise then that's it you
know 30 seconds then I'm gonna cross
time I guess so Green Tech says you know
I'm learning it just for fun not for a
job so I should probably switch to
scheme yes we just switch to scheme but
don't use no no Kyle because I've heard
I mean if you are just interested in
this don't don't do group no Kyle
use racket okay racket scheme you know
just search for racket you'll find it
racket racket is actually kind of a
broader scheme but anyway just you know
do do racket lookup bracket actually I
have some kind of tutorial
I don't actually have a tutorial for
racket but
but I did some I I you know I I did
somebody's home work with racket someone
paid me to do homework so this is about
five years ago so I learned the racket
you know you know so there's a racket
mod which is fantastic in Emacs you can
just Eva
it's like eMac this you know you can
give up things you know part of the
expressions just like eMac B's so
there's the you know racket using Emacs
rocket racket mod I have a tutorial here
and this is this is back in 2015
yeah that's that's basically when I did
the homework then there is the okay
racket okay so this is about this is
kind of a introduction to racket you
know the like what what commands are
there you know the the the terminal UNIX
shell commands how to started things
like that racket has its own editor dr.
racket racket you know it has its own
editor but I use it I use it in Emacs
but if you are interested you could use
this its own editor now racket is kind
of focused on racket is mostly focused
as a you know for tutorial world for
programming students in Rice University
and elsewhere and and they also focus on
language research so so racket racket is
a super set of scheme with the language
okay it's a superset and racket language
has the feature such that you can easily
change some semantics of the scheme you
know you can so it for example you can
have lazy evaluation you can have I
don't know as you know language feature
features like closure or what if you you
know the Intel recursion and you know
the Co Co with call/cc
if things like that you know language
research that's useful anyway it's using
academia ok racket then okay thank you
guys for watching see you next time bye