good morning my friends
today is 2020 uh august
10th 1 50 p.m san francisco time
and welcome to the talk show today we
are going to do emacs
emac list and braille this fantastic
unicode thing
and uh possibly some javascript
coding okay now what i want i want you
to do
let's look at my talk show page okay
talk show go to
uh magnify on the right window you can
see
all my emacs command as i if i press a
key you can see the command there and
also my keystrokes
i'm using vorack keyboard let's go to
talk show i'm using voila keyboard and
soft light keys
rack layout okay now show in browser
so this is my today's talk show page
and we so we're gonna talk about emacs
so
uh here is the thing okay hold on a
second let me do this
let's change it to ul
let's change it to ol uh number
older at least okay and let's do this
okay i don't have a number
um so i want you to pick a topic okay
let me do this okay so
let me you can meanwhile you can see my
emacs workflow
okay remove those bullets and
i want to call command rectangle number
lines
okay undo you need to select
the part you want then rectangle
number lines so you can see one two
three four we got numbered items
so uh copy that and go back to the
stream
and i'm going to post here so you guys
pick a topic okay what we're gonna talk
about today
uh oops that didn't go well but anyway
one two three four four topics
uh good morning scott so scott is a uh
c and c plus plus expert and working on
cpu and gpu stuff
uh being for 20 years right
so scott says funny i was just looking
at the braille unicode earlier today
because something is used for cheap
graphing on the terminal for cheap
graphing on a terminal oh
that's interesting what's
what is cheap graphing so speaking of
unicode let me show you okay so you go
to
visali unicode
so let me show you this unicode app this
is fantastic
and fun hold on a second let me modify
this
so wait let's magnify okay so you can
see better
uh and uh okay so i i want to remove the
list
here so i call command
key or rectangle removes those numbers
and showing browser
that's what i want i don't want the
numbers so you guys pick a topic okay
now we search for study unicode so
unicode this is my page i love unicode
unicode and symbology symbols and
functional programming
and mathematics you see it's all related
and
linguistics and um
well stuff like that so anyway here is
the braille
uh you go there and here
is one of the fantastic things do you
know do you know about
roth 13 you know that's one of the
cryptography
uh for example let me show you okay
uh something
in the water so you have that and in
e-max you call meta x
root 13 region okay
and that becomes that you become
skippish you know why because there is a
uh cryptograph okay let me explain
so am i doing okay so guys pick a topic
okay how many people
we have eight people come in say hi and
pick topic pick topic in the
uh chat box good morning allen
so let me explain about uh
cryptography the very basics if you
don't know okay
so okay graph okay so let me show you
um the crypto
uh crypto how do you call that crypto
analysis
cryptology
let's just say crypto analysis
so i have a tutorial on the basics
of
jesus how do you spell crypto cryptology
okay cryptology
no that's not oh cr why
wait here well here's my article
public key cryptography for beginner
okay
go read it uh
public key cryptography for beginner so
um so why is public key cryptography
so confusing well is it confusing yes
because you have all these
abbreviations for example pkg
ssh ssl tls
rsa d e s triple d s blowfish
aes rcs then you have more you have
like um md5 shot one
and stuff you know if you are a
programmer you hear that all that
so here so this article is a basic
introduction
but let me tell you the most basic
cryptography
uh from like 3000 years ago is called
uh it's called substitution cipher okay
basically for example you look at this
uh here okay so you replace
so rod 13 rot 13
rot 13 which stands for rotation 13
which means rotate 13 places okay so
what is what
wrote 13 that is a method of
encryption so you are given a text you
want to encrypt it so other people
cannot
understand it so so wrote 13 is a method
of the encryption and how do you do it
what is the method the method is by you
take the english alphabet you know 26
letters
and you change a to n b two o
c two p and so on for every letter
so that's what you got uh so for example
you know we have
let's do it again so you see we have
something in water
and you apply rod 13 it becomes
becomes that so basically if you have a
b
c d e f g okay you apply rod 13
then it becomes n o p q r s t
so so why is road 13 because you
you move you you sw because you change
a to n and n is the 13th letter
right i think so something like that but
anyway you can have root one for example
a becomes b b com becomes c
c becomes d that also works
so so this type of cipher is called
substitution cipher
and one particular one you rotate the
letters to 13
13th place is called rot13
and you have a command in emacs
that has it built in okay so
you know so we just tried several times
so that's
route 13 and that's crypt uh
you know that's one of the basic uh
cipher
uh so you might check out my article
it's an introduction to public key
uh uh
public key um cryptography okay
now why am i talking about that because
this unicode
is interesting because for example let
me magnify okay
magnify so i type something delete
you type something and it
be becomes braille
fantastic you see that that becomes
braille and now you can copy the braille
copy it go back here select all paste it
and say to english you see that's
decipherment
decipherment of the cypher
so you can convert both ways i just uh
completed this
javascript a few days ago very
interesting have so
have you guys picked a topic yet
guys i said you know pick a topic you
know one two three four
the topic above pick a topic okay so
then we're gonna talk about that
so scott says here's an example of
graphing with braille unicode all these
okay so we cannot
see your url link uh scott
because i don't know if you know
we cannot you know when you paste link
google sends us sends us it
so so randy holier hello
cortes good afternoon paul edward says
lately last couple of months have been
interested in topic related to full
emacs workflow oh okay so you guys want
to see emacs workflow okay let's do that
and happy friend says javascript okay
uh we can do javascript if i do you know
the javascript let me show you the
simple javascript first so okay go to my
unicode page
hold on a second so go to my unicode
page
local page and go to the
unicode bail so this is my local page
copy the url back to emacs
open the link and magnify
okay so you can see
here is the javascript you see so
let's open it it opens actually
typescript
uh because i do typescript let me
magnify okay so you see
here is the typescript here is the
javascript type
you know all right typescript
then javascript type yeah okay so
you open the typescript so typescript is
a superset of javascript so if you
so so typescript what does it add to
javascript basically it adds types
you know like static types like c int
float
uh array you know those things
in hope that it reduces programming
error that's what
you know they they want types for and
also it increases
uh you know you reduce type error that's
the primary thing
but in languages like c it is c or c
so java it also increases the uh
the code speed because
well because you you um because then
when you translate it to machine code it
runs faster because it knows well
because computers they are all binary
digits
they don't use i mean they are not
integers and floating numbers you have
to
it's all binary numbers on the chip so
when you have an integer but on a chip
it's actually binary number so you have
to
kind of do some kind of uh translation
or conversion
on the fly when you run a program so
those static
statically typed languages c or c plus
plus
and now scott and many of you probably
know better than me
correct me okay so so when you run c
c or c plus plus they have types
you know they tell the computer what
what is the type instead of trying to
find out
on the fly every time when you have an
integer so in general the typed
languages
you know cc plus plus they are faster
and high score is a different story
anyway let's go back let's go
to the typescript so typescript added
types to javascript
so you are looking at you are looking at
actually just plain javascript so
here's the code for my uh for my
converting braille to and
back and forth and
and uh it's not too many code but
the code is fantastic okay let me tell
you because it
involves nested maps it's
fairly elegant i would say okay
but anyway so let's go back to our topic
so uh
i guess uh workflow let's do some emacs
workflow
so let's see how are you by the way so
i'm drinking
by the way the the usual energy drink
okay so this is sugar-free
always drink sugar-free energy drink
plus
apple cider you know it's funny they use
the word cider they should just say
apple juice i'm not sure what's the
etymology
but typically only apple juice they call
it
cider they don't call grape juice grape
cider i don't think so
for example
so scott says google coin coin
top okay so let's do that maybe it's
something interesting coin top
uh according top okay that's not a
coin top terminal based application for
tracking what the
let's look at uh that
tracking your crypto on linux is that
simple
with cointop tracking your crypto on
linux okay
what they mean coin top
view on github a fast and lightweight
uh wait uh what a fast and lightweight
interactive terminal based ui
application for tracking
cryptocurrencies
oh okay so it's a it's just a terminal
app
for for showing the up and downs of of
bitcoin okay so that that is
uh understandable uh but
i want to see
so this is this is uh useful guys you
know
my followers you you guys might be
interested in this
thank you scott for that so let's let's
see
okay so cryptocurrency there are now
thousands
1 000 of them bitcoin ethereum
repo bitcoin cash eos okay
okay anyway so what is this chart
it's going up and down going up and down
and going up right now
this is what this is uh
days or what anyway so
coin top oh no that's good okay
market cap
okay that's interesting um now
cryptocurrency
so thomas ward says i enjoy programming
more in dynamic languages these days
okay
now i need some ammunit munition
ammunition
you know crease crease of the day what
is the difference between munition
and ammunition okay now that's for you
uh what were debuffs
to find out today i'm not going to look
into
what is the difference between
ammunition and munition
so emax workflow let's see let's look at
let's look at emacs workflow okay so
i'm doing emacs right now and you are
see looking at my emac
workflow i'm just i just closed several
windows so move the cursor here
uh wait you see i want to delete this
paragraph
i just move it somewhere in the
paragraph hit one single key
and it's good you see that single key is
i here on the vowel keyboard with
stuff like keys so that's my workflow
but
showing browser one single key again
showing browser
magnify so what is the workflow emacs
workflow
put elise command because html insert
br tag into a html page okay
let's do that so let me quickly do that
first okay let's see how long i've been
talking and commenting questions
posted okay and
maybe you know since we already started
random today we've been talking random
for 18 minutes
maybe i'll show you this my new mouse
i have a review of it on my page
this fantastic one two three four five
six
six buttons on the side and two more
buttons on top
uh six seven eight nine ten eleven
twelve thirteen
so fourteen total is like fourteen
buttons this is
also bluetooth
you go by it okay now emacs workflow i
want to go to
let me show you my emacs workflow
the top the the workflow i'm supposed to
do is this one
which is put a emacs list command i
wrote into my emac beats blog
so that involves uh
quite a few things you know get the
source code
create a new page html page all the
templates
paste it there you know and prettify and
put it upload to my website but
it's not much different than what i'm
doing now so i might as well just show
you what i'm doing now
so that's this is my emacs workflow so
this is my workflow you know right now
i'm working on a mac
i let me show you some some of the
interesting things about my workflow i
have 1 000
articles about that so first of all
let's go to my keyboard blog
okay how you do you use bookmark you
know
um there are 10 000
branching off points let's just start to
do it okay i press a few key key
uh it goes to my keyboard blog and
showing browser
here is my page up here is my keyboard
blog so what
what did i just do basically you know uh
emacs bookmark let's go to my emacs blog
okay
showing browser so here's my emacs blog
go to my emacs tutorial search for
bookmark it's
a book mark so you can see
i have a tutorial on emacs bookmark it
looks like that
i can show you i don't want to show you
because my bookmark
contains uh
files that's private i guess so i don't
want to show you real time
so basically here's emacs bookmark but
but i have a special command that
opens a any specific bookmark
without the need to actually open the
bookmark
okay so that command is let me show you
that command is what i used to go to my
uh keyboard blog and emacs blog and any
other website
so let that command is called um
let's see okay so
emacs bookmark let's see where is it
up up
uh open the bookmark where is it i
should have it linked somewhere
god i don't have a link here i should i
used to have links here
uh oh
here it is you see this one open file
fast
yeah so that's a one so that's the
command i used
for example let me show you again okay i
want to go to my javascript block okay
i press a key that calls
open file fast then i just type um
jb so you see it pops a uh
you know in in a mini buffer whatever i
type
it will match by regular expression well
by
you know it's the first imaging so i
just type jb and
hit enter i open my javascript block
okay
now show in browser you see my web dev
blog
now back to emacs uh call that command
again
again cuz i open file fast let's this
time type
eb eb is for emacs block okay
enter show in browser by emacs blog
so this way you know in my bookmark i
have like
maybe 100 items you know all my files
and whatever
and i press you know two keys basically
uh
uh uh
three keys i i press three keys that
invokes star open file fast
okay then i type you know one or two
characters you know for example i type
py
that goes to python i press enter i
arrived at my python tutorial
showing browser you see my python
tutorial so when i want to work on
python i
quickly i can quickly open the file so
this is uh
emacs bookmark
uh with uh plus plus the
command because i open file fast you
know because open file fast is
is just a command a wrapper that allows
you to
type a few keys to open your bookmark
so anyway that's so that is not my
bookmark now let's go to keyboard okay
so go to keyboard and let's just quickly
do it and
go so on my keyboard blog you go to the
mouse
section page down
and this is the mouse i'm talking about
i was going to
you know i might do a review later on
today well i mean
maybe maybe you know let's just
let us do the emacs um
workflow first
so okay so so this this i mean this
mouse okay you can go there and buy it
so
let me copy so what emacs workflow right
let me copy
so press the key to copy the url back to
emacs
close it close it start talk show right
cause
talk show go down paste it here add a
few paragraph
make a link show in browser so i have
you see so
it's linked there so i have a list of
uh wait whoops close it okay
go back show in browser again
so you can see it's uh
linked there so i can put into uh
youtube
so so close it
uh topic show notes close it uh
crypt up cryptography close it
um braille okay copy the link
go back here go to the top paste it
linkify showing browser
i have it open it
close it close the python tutorial well
actually i don't want to close it reopen
one single key to your plan copy it back
to emacs
uh let's put the python tutorial here
as an advertisement you know python is
becoming very popular today because of
google
i talked about python several times and
python
the python is a language i don't like
okay it sucks
and why does it sucks because the
inventor
geido okay kaido van gaalson i did one
hour
rant on about guido van gaalson several
months ago half
half a year ago probably
uh and that i think that would be
interesting you t
uh youtube you might you know some of
you
might be interested so braille close it
let's go back to my uh talk show let's
see what you guys are talking
uh bulk sod drink indeed
so paul edwards says cider is ferment
fermented apples oh fermented apples
okay
usually alcoholic very good and popular
with
ladies up there in canada
okay but my side my apple cider is not
alcoholic okay but anyway so that's the
that's the meaning of cider i guess uh
paul edward hey paul edward are you luna
lunarius
loneliners
so because uh scott says have you
contrasted python with ruby
uh yes or no well i have quite a few
articles about
python and ruby okay let's talk about
that a little bit okay
so let's see you know right now i want
to go to my ruby blog
so let me show you the command to open
file fast again
so press three keys then type ruby
enter that's my ruby blog show in
browser
this is my ruby tutorial learn ruby in
one hour
okay so so you have this page that's a
basic
introduction uh to ruby page down page
down you know
i don't actually know ruby well so i
learned ruby for
three months about five years ago 2015
or so
because i was trying to get a job um but
anyway so i
so ruby in my opinion is a is a much
better language than python ruby is more
clean
simple elegant and equally powerful ruby
and python and pearl
they are basically all the same class
okay it doesn't matter how you
which which one you like they are but
they are the same they are kind of they
are they are almost the same
in their efficiency in their uh
specialist you know specialization the
type of tasks they do
in their um high levelness they you know
ruby python pearl
it's a they are the same but
but of course you can compare the syntax
compare the the community the
communities are a bit different okay
you can compare the syntax you can
compare
the semantics you know you can say you
can compare the documentation quality
you can compare the um
the the the complexity of the language
you know their model you know each
language have a model they build on
so for example lisp haskell see
they have very fundamentally different
models of computation
you know you can almost call it a
virtual machine
you know for python java c or or haskell
very different model and this so
so you can also talk about that between
ruby and python and
uh pearl uh and i would say so ruby
is comes out uh the winner in every way
than python in my opinion
i'm certain of that okay of course
it's somewhat subjective because
uh every person have different ideas
about what um
you know which language they like and
the biases
in their preferences about syntax and so
on
but in my opinion okay here's the
important part
here's a class video important in my
opinion
it is true that languages you know
each person have biases and preferences
you could say
there is no objective um qualification
objective
comparison but actually in my opinion
there is
you know all things considered you look
at computer science
you you look at human animals history
entire humanity
suppose you are god suppose you are
omniscient
you know everything about computer
science you know everything about
mathematics
you know the entirety of human history
suppose
you know suppose you are that then you
can you
if you ask god you know so okay so in
your opinion which one is better ruby or
python
there you or whatever language see there
is
absolutely there is the answer okay this
is my opinion
so in other words there is
uh objectivity in judging a programming
language
even in a general sense you know without
precise definition what do you mean by
better
you know what what do you mean by better
you know some
some people compare by speed some people
are compared by how you
how fast you can prototype it in general
higher like higher level languages are
faster
you know you can code things faster than
c or c plus
there are so many ways to judge you can
compare speed you can compare
the simplicity you can compare compare
the utility of the language for example
c python is
is much more general purpose than c for
example
because c is very tedious you know you
have to do all these code to do
you know python is much more general and
you know general purpose even
for some things it's much slower than c
and not suitable
for example so there are so many ways to
compare languages but
but all things considered i believe
there is uh
you you usually you could say
one is better than the other okay
uh anyway that's i'm getting a bit far
but anyway ruby and python
i like ruby much better
but right now today i don't you know
pearl so ruby and pearl
ruby and pearl they share much more
similarities
because ruby
by design ruby by design is a derivative
of pearl and lisp okay
i have so many articles let me show you
okay
okay open a new page uh uh emacs
workflow okay
sardi magnify magnufact saudi so
uh xrd
ruby maths okay search
you know press a key to search uh on the
web
so that command is called lookup web
it's a package on map you can you can
get okay
so now back to browser so here is
um i have several articles about um
you know these some of these are 10
years old or
interesting articles okay
about programming languages uh okay i
didn't find the one i want
let's do it again go um
okay i'll go emacs ruby matt such that
there it is so ruby creator maths on how
emacs changed my life so
this guy ruby creator maths he did a
talk in 2012
2012 at libra
planet okay at at
mit university of massachusetts where
richard stoneman
is at the gnu so he actually won
a word from gnu so anyway he he
he talked about the history of ruby why
he created
how he invented invented it okay
so actually he's a programmer on this
calculator his first language
basic on this sharp calculator
okay go back to emax close that don't
save
magnify learn ruby in our show in
browser
back to emacs close it show in browser
talk show that's right go back to emacs
paste it here make a list okay so we
have
you know that topic there so close that
also copy ruby back to emacs
paste it so learn ruby in one hour so
that's a tutorial and python by example
so close that let me talk about learn
ruby okay learn ruby in one hour so
so ruby the language is basically uh
improvement of pearl you know he saw
this guy so
pearl and he is very impressive by it
however
the syntax of pearl is crap okay he
he doesn't follow the pearl coat you
know pearl is a coat
so he wanted to create something as
powerful as
you know very useful like pearl back
then
1990s very useful but he wants to
change the syntax to something better
and he's also
a big fan of emacs uh you know
this guy lives in emacs you know so he
started to study emac
lisp and look at the code how emac this
is implement implemented so
then he created ruby you know just by
himself
he is his his history i mean this one
the sun micro systems this is one this
is his first computer
he owned like that one so so he created
ruby
and you know he wants to create a pearl
but better syntax
and the implementation is all from lisp
okay he learned from e-magnesis
not just companies was scheming he
learned from
emacs list source code to create ruby so
in fact
you can see so he also likes lisp but
but he doesn't like the list parenthesis
okay he
he doesn't like the parentheses so he
created ruby so ruby
is a improved a much clean version of
perl
with many features of lisp in fact
the implementation of ruby is like a
copy of emac lisp
you can see you know if for example in
ruby you can see some of the
uh similarities for example in ruby in
a early version of ruby the number
types uh
the the the the character there is no
character type in ruby back then
uh maybe not i'm not sure today i don't
know
ruby that much but anyway in ruby
there's no character type or there is
but anyway the character types
shares the same type as an integer for
example in emacs let me show you okay
so in emacs i open a new buffer so look
at my command okay let's do
it again close don't save uh new buffer
type of parenthesis now look at the pink
window to see all the commands i'm
calling okay
magnify magnify magnify okay first
uh plus one two okay move the cursor to
the right
evaluate it okay about last six
now look at the bottom okay uh now look
at the bottom
okay so let's go to the message buffer
now look at the bottom you see emacs
shows that
emac shows three then emacs shows this
bunch of things
uh this this part okay let me copy it
put it here
uh wait let's go let's make it this
side emacs list mod okay so
and paste it here comment it out so this
is the output
so the output is three but why does it
show
what is this o3 x3 uh let me
explain okay so this is octal notation
actual notation for three
uh in imacbs this is for example emax
this you can
also for example you could you could say
it'll come out the same okay evaluate it
you see it comes out the same let's try
again so
i want to evaluate this code this is
actually
octal notation for number one which is
just one
in decimal this is two okay so one plus
two equals three let's evaluate
so you can see the same result three
but why does it print that because okay
it shows you octal notation
it shows you the hexadecimal notation
but then
there is this one now that's interesting
that
notation in emac this indicates
the character i mean that indicates a
key stroke
control c okay why control c
because control c is in part of the
ascii code
it has a code number called point three
okay
so let me show you something else okay
let's say 90 plus two uh
let's say 90 let's do it again okay
90 plus three okay let's run that
well let's not uh let's say 90 plus six
okay
let's run it you can see the result at
the bottom
okay uh wait
let's not do 96 let's do 90 plus seven
okay
run it you can see the result at bottom
so let me copy the result and put it
here comment it out
uh let's let's put it here okay
let's clean up okay so 90 plus
7 returns this thing which is 97
so then you have the octal notation
uh octal notation then you have the hex
notation
and then what is that that is character
a
a as in apple because in sc code a
is 97 so but
but the result is 97 integer why are you
showing
where where are you showing your
character this this is the syntax for a
character in emacs by the way why are
you showing a
because in emac list there is no
distinction between a integer and a
character
okay a character is an integer an
integer is also a character at the same
time
so which one it is depends on how it
depends on how you want to use it
for example let's do we we can do for
example let me show you okay
char to int okay wait char to
int and okay char
to uh string okay
char to string uh and he asked me for a
character as a argument let's just type
that
okay question mark a that's a syntax for
character
so you i evaluate it you see it says a
you can see can you see it you see here
that's the result
a string a wait
uh
you see so he imag this character and
integer is the same thing
indistinguishable now in ruby
uh at least like five years ago or ten
years ago
it's the same way because ruby copied
from emaclis
but however this property i mean it's
not good to have a language where the
character and integers are the same
it's stupid actually it's a mistake
so so ruby inherited that you know you
have to learn you have to begin
somewhere so
ruby inherited that mistake but i
believe they changed it in ruby three
also so anyway that's my that's kind of
my
some uh segway
a word i learned a segue into
digressions about this
uh let me show you this okay create a
elise
code paste it here shown in browser
okay we have today's sample emac list
code
and press the key to syntax color it
back to browser show it syntax colored
fantastic back to emacs then you can see
here is the command i just called
to syntax cloud so actually that's a lot
of digression and so let's go back to
ruby versus perl
i wrote a lot
history of programming languages in one
sentence okay that's kind of
which language to learn pearl python
ruby java php
magnifice okay so this one is written in
2013 i tell you
i give you my reasons but ruby
you know ruby is the antithesis of
python
as far as you know in the history of
their of these programming languages
ruby uh you know ruby
well well not on t i'm sorry antithesis
is a pearl actually
well python in pearl python is the
antithesis
antithesis is a pearl uh
yeah not ruby anyway so here's a funny
picture of the guy
uh let me show you the guy the
creator of ruby wearing a python shirt
and here's a my friend thomas
he's a entrepreneur in china
he created git cafe
which is kind of like github you know
you could say a github
clone but for use in china
so this is back in 2013 also
so you have mats and him and his team
you know
my friend's team git cafe uh they were
using ruby
and here's git cafe logo but he sold the
company
a few years ago three or four four or
five years ago
you know so he's a entrepreneur this guy
thomas
so that's some i i have interesting
things about ruby okay let's go back to
the chat
chat let's see
how long have i been talking
comments questions
45 minutes okay
uh let's see
let's see the comments let me go back to
the comments
uh braille workflow okay let me show you
okay have you ever programmed in cv shop
no
cider okay so it shows the graph using
braille
oh yeah we forgot about that
wait let's see
okay i oh wait here
oh okay so this is this graph is in
braille jesus
[Laughter]
this ascii hack these people using ascii
hack unicode hack you know
they are using braille to emulate
a graph a chart a stock chart
and this it's a hack i do not approve
because if you want to use ascii or
characters or unicode characters to
emulate a graph
uh i don't think you should use spare i
mean yeah you could but
it's a hack it's not designed to do so
it's
it's it's i do not approve
uh this these crazy people
i suppose there's i mean
well it's just like ascii art you know
yeah yeah it has you know it's useful
but it's a hack and you know
so so braille yeah so let's see if i
have
links to braille here
so braille you know braille is very
interesting let's magnify okay so
braille is kinda
interesting because
why is it interesting because
it is just a bunch of
dots very appealing
to mathematicians why because it's a
it's a it's kind of a combinatorial
thing you know for example you can ask
the question how many possible
arrangements you can have
for three dots in in earth in
a three by two grid how many possible
arrangements
can you have you know that's a math
question you know
combinatorial and you know programmers
also like it find it appealing because
because it's you know it looks like you
know you you have seen the matrix you
know code right so it's
interesting
and by the way there's also a dot
version of braille
it's some kind of extension but when i
studied braille let me tell you braille
is the way they are created the way they
represent
letters for example here's the you know
abcd
uh is not it's not
elegant it's it's not systematic it's
not consistent
it is almost like random okay random
issue
uh and my impression of that of
of this is that it just happened that
way because i believe someone
in in france uh you know i you can go to
wikipedia to read the details but anyway
someone just
created it without without
a solid mathematical foundation or
theory
you know which one should represent what
there's no such
it just happened to uh be
invented i think originally it's
supposed to be military code or
something
but eventually it becomes braille for
the blind
so yeah so and also they have this weird
uh you know braille it's just a
it's just a bunch of dots right in a
grid so
theoretically you you might think that
it's very
it has the potential to be extremely
consistent
on how or either that you know
it's like keyboard layout you know why
why should you have you know q
w e r t y on the top row there are so
many
there are billions of ways to arrange
letters why are we using
the way we use and the reason we know
today is just history okay it's
not for any any specially designed
reason it just happened so that
it happened to be that way i think it's
the same
same reason i mean same thing applies to
braille it's not consistent
so so theoretically braille could be a
much more
consistent system and also another way
to
to create braille is that you have to
judge
you have to create create these symbols
just
based on based on
perception you know human tactile
tactile
sensation for example if you are a
scientist you are a statistician and
scientist
and you study human perception
with the tactile sensation you know you
can
for example for example let me ask the
concrete question
of all the braille characters which one
is most
recognizable now we
are not blind so we haven't actually
tried rail but for the blind people they
probably can tell you
oh they can most easily recognize
certain
you know thought patterns
and so you you can create a braille
system based on that you know which
letter are used most frequently
which letter is most easy to perceive
then
create a braille you know translation
based on that
but i don't think that's the way our
braille is
and of course it's impossible to fix
it's too late
so anyway that's that's braille so um
random chat anything else anything else
common okay
and maybe that's about it today random
things let's see how long i've been
talking
52 minutes okay so we have discord
sally discord you can find my discord on
my website
sally.info so go join discord we have a
lot of people
tons of people diverse diversity
are fairly diverse okay i would say but
most of
most of us here are still nerds in one
way or another
for example we don't have uh we don't
have
uh lawyers in our group we don't have
english majors you know well we have we
have allen who is
linguist linguist and we have
we have frenzy frenzy who is also a
linguist
i mean but in general we are still nuts
uh overall
and we talk about things so so join okay
join the
star discord but also i like to say if
you join
it's preferred you use your real name
okay don't
it's this is not this is not another
reddit
or fortune or another hacker news okay i
hate
i despise those this is not another
random
website you go to and fought your fart
and you can change your nickname you
know be anonymous and
around and tomorrow and go off you
know
that's this is not a place like that i
want
you know i well my i created it of
course
so i i prefer it to be a place
you actually meet people you know you
know you you get to know other people
we know each other you know aaron i mean
here's some of the
us regulars alan ripper everyone
super you know we sometimes we go on
live stream
and chat chat about things and cortez
and smoking code many you know
you know all these people actually i met
at least online face to face
uh many many of them you know so
so join okay join it's fun and uh
you can be anonymous if you want to but
try not to be
you know you you go here meet other
interesting people
make a difference in real life so you
might meet them in real life
and help each other out things like that
that
that's better instead of the
twitter
you know the reddit hacker hacker news
you know the
hot the facebook you know the the heart
you know star
you you go there to get the stars and
and drama the
it becomes uh what was it was
all
for chan 4chan and 8chan whatever
chan
okay so that's that let's see what else
e wheel so i'm going to read the
comments and that
maybe that's it for today uh
so so okay s
so scott agrees that ruby is better than
python
and scott is disappointed that raspberry
pi
projects are python based instead of
ruby yeah
you know because of the kaido the guide
of rossum
you know kaido van rossum the guy who
created python you know he's a great guy
yeah you know he's a good person a great
guy and he created python and now it's
used everywhere
very popular because of google okay i
talked about this a few times
in the past i have one video that i
talked about uh guido van rossum and
white python is not good
uh for one hour so go watch that
about half a year ago so he
you know in python python you know the
the
guido van rossum guy he doesn't like
functional programming okay he doesn't
he's not fan of it and in fact he
doesn't understand much about
functional programming he but however he
is this
sort of um sort of uh of
of uh you know he think of his design he
you know he thinks he's designed the
best in you know
even though he doesn't say that but
implicitly his behavior he's the way he
write things
you know implies that he thinks he's you
know his design is better
oh you know python crap python
and he you know he has this idea
that he want the python he want python
to be
the the number one agent educational
language you know he has he has tried
tried to push that for a long time for
for for 10 years the first 10 years when
he created python
he want everyone every school to
education institution
to begin with python this guy is idiot
okay
python python the language first of all
it's inelegant it's not
elegant in any way you know ruby
scheme are both more elegant than python
ruby came later okay
ruby python pro they came all about the
same time
well per first then python then ruby
okay
uh the the difference in year about two
pearl is created in 1986
or 1989 something like that then after a
year
or two python then then you have pearl i
mean then you have ruby okay
but you know python python the language
is not
it's not really elegant it's not really
orthogonal like scheme
it's not it's not that great okay it's
not really that great and it's also
it's not it's absolutely not a easy to
learn
language okay it's not like like one of
the logo for example logo
is you know logo um quite a few
scheme including skin logo scheme and
and quite a few other languages are
basic you know basic the most popular
and pascal
you know they are designed to be simple
to learn they are designed to be
educational programming languages
but if you compare python it's really
not python the language you do
you look at it it's not it's not a easy
to learn language
but this kind of idiot he he really
wants to paint on to be
like the oh i created python it's the
most easy symbol to then it's not
it's not at all by any judgement okay
except the python phonetics the python
phonetics every day they are talking
about python
they don't know nothing but if you try
to ask all people objectively about
you know people who know different
languages not average programmers who've
been in programming for 10 years that
doesn't count
you want actually people who have done
education or study
human posses human psychology perception
you know learning uh or having has been
a teacher
teaching programming languages in of
different programming languages
at different levels you ask those people
python is not a easy to learn language
at all compared to
uh basic scheme and you know uh
and and and logo and and and and so and
so on
quite a few now there's some graphics
languages but
but but this bit but this guy does
awesome guy he
he just think that oh he's the best so
he pushed python
to be the number one educational
language and he failed
basically yeah he failed completely
but why is python so popular let's speak
not because of geido van rossum at all
because of google i said as i talked
about this twice
two or three times in my past video
because of google the first time is in
around 2000 year 2000
google picked python to be their
choice of language scripting language at
google
the other is you know google's choice of
languages python
c c plus plus and java mostly
java python c
plus plus and c usually more or less in
that order
because google becomes very big in year
2000 so
everyone is like oh google is using
python this is the first time
google made python popular python it
wasn't
known you know it was back then you have
pearl no other choice
google made python google uh
gave a big giant helping hand made
python popular
okay then in 2000s ruby
on rails came up ruby becomes everywhere
everywhere then
python is falling behind actually
falling behind around
you know year 2010 then google
again gave a huge helping hand
that brought python up to popular
popularity why
because of the machine learning you
know
you know we are into machine learning
age so google every day is like
oh machine learning this and that oh we
have a
library in python do machine learning so
that that is why
python becomes even far more popular it
becomes you know it's
you know it's falling apart then google
and machine learning craze
uh drove the popularity of python
and ruby kind of said ruby is kind of
just falling behind
you know so anyway so i i guess that's
it for today
um
so jason yeah so uh jason uh i've only
ever used python but i i like to be open
to giving ruby a go so yeah you might
try my tutorial that's good thank you
if you like my tutorials buy them okay i
have my emacs tutorial for sale
you just go to my emacs website you'll
find it okay
uh you know my emacs tutorial
and actually the tutorial that i'm most
proud of is my javascript in depth
okay let me mention that uh
i talked about this several times
javascript in depth
now you know i've been coding emac this
for 20
for for 15 years almost every day emac
lisp and i have my emac this
tutorial on the website it's most
popular the most
uh uh you know it's almost the only one
on the web
in terms of quality and quantity you
know
but so i spent 15 years
in emac base and you know i have a lot
more experience in emac display than
java but however
in javascript i spent
full time two years to write this
javascript script in depth
so actually i know javascript the
language far more
actually far more than i know emac lisp
i mean the technical details of the
language just
well you know i spent two years to write
this javascript in depth
i read for example you know the
specifications the extreme complex
javascript specific specifications the
most lousy
written and javascript language really
sucks
in so many ways so i wrote this
javascript in depth
i i i've also read quite a few
books for javascript you know
uh anyways i i have too much to say
about javascript but anyway i want to
sell tell you my javascript in-depth is
really
the one i'm i'm most proud of and i
think
it's better than than than any tutorial
in english language okay that's my claim
and i say that with confidence okay my
javascript tutorial is better
better than any javascript tutorial
that exists either online or in book
form in printed form
in english language except two okay
qualification except two two or three
books
which i think may be better than my
tutorial
okay i've talked about this many times
actually i have an article that compares
the different javascript
tutorials anyway i just want to say that
judge by yourself just
judge it yourself and check out my
javascript tutorial if you like it buy
it
okay so let's see
comments and we are about done today
we are about done today that's uh that's
what
one hour and five minutes okay
beth hello mew good morning i haven't
seen you for a while but
says look at pascal look at oberon or
what it was called nobody knows this yet
it has big influences on modern
languages okay
uh but
it says okay boss says uh the kids are
taking drugs and
my and being my grandparents even often
accept
things okay
censored by youtube but
your comments are censored by youtube
don't use words like
uh yeah three of your
comments are censored by youtube and
alan says
uh drama the hoe okay
okay i'm gonna skip i'm gonna scan the
comments and uh
and that's it for today thank you guys
for coming
thomas wall says steph uh okay something
something
something ruby parallels how i think
okay small talk as well okay
in ruby all types are classes or
operators are methods
yeah i like that because you see i like
those kind of things you know systematic
you know we you know when you learn a
new language for example list
list syntax you only have to learn one
or two things you know the lisp syntax
at least you know you just learn okay
parenthesis that's it
applies everywhere applies to the entire
language no exceptions
on the other hand languages like python
c
or perl every line every command every
function name every method or you know
you have function or you met you have
method or you have directives
or you might you might have commands you
know you have a bunch of different
things
and each one have a different syntax
then you have the
the the the most extremely idiotic
uh
list how do you call that
you know i forgot the terms
now let's go to my computer tutorial
okay let's show
showing browser programming tutorial
i mean programming language blog and you
go to the language tutorial section
wait not that you go to the primary
language
proving complaint perving section
you go to wait let's go to
why python sucks okay
uh wait not what a python thing sucks
you go to
the jargons of software industry
yeah there it is least comprehension the
most
idiotic and it's it's loved by
python by guido van rossum these
idiots you know at least complication
because you
you have a specialized syntax within
that
line that's what python and c is like
while loop
for loop print statement especially
print you know the
sprint you know the format you have like
you have
within each line you have a specialized
syntax specialized thing
idiot what language should
be what i mean you know there are
different opinions but
in my opinion i prefer languages that
are
just a few simple rules that applies to
the entire language
this is kind of like that okay for
example the syntax is all parenthesis
mostly then the semantics is also very
simple a function
arguments that's it you know that's it
that's all you have to learn about the
language that's it
then you code whatever you do
mathematica
for example is even more extreme simple
consistent
okay i actually i have quite a few
articles on that but that's another day
about about this idea of of
constructed um uh
regularity of the syntax okay
this code is written in ruby it is not
it is written in javascript
okay so that's it that's it exactly um
seems to be trend of using braille for
console
based you know those are hacks you know
this this using braille to graph
you know this this is one of the thing
that
attracts the nerds you know the idiotic
nuts you see let me show you
let's go back to this you see when a
programmer
of the unix philosophy type or the nerd
type
when they see this they get excited oh
man
they they're gonna use this for sure
because when they say
oh my god fantastic no you oh oh oh they
you know they realize it's spread out to
char you know
it creates a coat this this type of
thing it
you know it's part of the
part of the attraction of the hackers
you know they they look they just
this little thing things like that you
know they
they attract these nerd types
uh of course i'm not talking about you
scott right you know i don't think
you i well i don't think
scott is not um
too much of that type of person but
anyway
you know i'm just talking about
different type of person you know these
hacker types of programmers they are
fine person too
but i just i don't like that their ideas
they are
you know pearl unix or these hacks
they you know to them they don't think
it's hacked to them they think this is
smart you know it's a different thinking
they think it's smart
and also the c programmers you know they
they like little tricks
little techniques little tricks pearl
golf for example
vim you know vim golf perk of crap
i don't like any of those i want science
okay i'm a scientist
not a hacker i'm a you know i study math
i'm a mathematician
not the the chicken this and that the
unix philosophy
crap
you know
so i have a hard time catching up with
the comments
um so let me just skip a few
and that's actually that's it for today
um
okay scott uh gonna go okay so uh looks
like he's trying to be modest he has no
reason to be modest he's done so many
things
okay uh m.c reid in speaking german
okay i'm gonna skip the comments and
uh no question to me any questions to me
uh
yeah too many comments anyway that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
have a good day bye i'm gonna close in
two minutes okay
two minutes close down
uh i need to get my fan oh forget it
let me get my fan we closed down in two
minutes two minutes
bye guys
history of software bikes are by thomas
wall where are you from thomas
join this code okay bart says their
products are crap
yet every school buys their products
shows that
superior engineering doesn't win