hello everyone today I'm going to show
you how to write grip in Emacs Lisp so
this is another spontaneous recording
and yes how to write grabbing Emacs Lisp
so let's start okay first of all I
remembered let's do this quickly now I
know how to to which is to turn along my
key log so command LACMA yes that's one
yes and it's a global command lock mark
yes and
okay good so now you see this on this
screen it's showing the command I'm
using so you know I get questions like
what did you do to do this what command
did you call so now you can see it there
so first of all right its tongue sorry
Emacs me smart you see it's right there
okay so let's try to grab grab means
find text in your directory I have
written these like tens of times over
the past 10 years because that's what I
need to do and so okay so that's
different
let's let's begin defend let's just name
X X because it's easier to type for this
one no bar so okay you want to write a
grip let's start with documentation
that's what I do always so X X will find
prompt for directory and okay prompt for
let's see prompt for text to find and
prompt for directory and then print
result something like that okay so let's
begin so prompt text to find prompt for
directory from results okay so okay I am
this to be like 15 minutes but now I'm
starting to code it I don't think I can
finish in 15 minutes it might be up to
20 minutes or 30 minutes okay now it's
5:01 let's see how let me let me try to
be as fat as you know quick and not you
know be verbose in stuff okay so you
need Tom okay well let's save the file
xx start yeah let's just say that
and I don't want to overwrite execs it's
not yeah so he max let's go to my Emacs
blog because this is my Emacs tutorial
and actually I use it myself because I
don't remember things actually I have
written in detail how to write a grave
somewhere here like that's probably
scripty script examples
yeah I've have written that detailed
tutorial before well it's not look at
that because it's no fun to not the
interactive I mean in real time that's
the point of videos so okay prompt for
text to find yeah let's see how do you
get prompt e command example Emacs Lisp
how do you get prompt from user get
buffer string get user input that's
that's the one you want rich stream so
that's what we want
restream no okay I don't have pay I
don't have a shortcut for that that's no
good because I need anything I'd you
know so the way I usually walk is
because I'm using its open a new frame I
think know what I'm talking to people my
faculties is looking at 50% the other
half needs to be concerned about how to
talk to people
okay what's the command to open a new
frame okay traditionally Emacs is
control x5 I think okay canto X 5 Wow
let's see control X 5 control H find new
frame let's see where is it other frame
we frame anyway so inks a ficus you can
do shift control and so there make frame
command and he's found a cx-5 - that's a
traditional key and and ink supply keys
is space and I like what I did I am
space and hi there it is a new frame III
call this command everyday but you know
I just forgot so a new frame so what are
we gonna do yeah
Reed string yeah so I was saying I
opened a new frame and let's go to Emacs
Lee smart
jump to the file and jump to the file
you see because the way I woke out my
mods he makes this stuff packages is
that whenever I try to do something you
see obviously here I need let's try this
okay I need a brief to expand to the
that template so let's do that
I may not be able to finish you know
writing a graph is key because it's
already five minutes but you know I'm
just going to show you my workflow
anyway so great so yeah you see all
these are our briefs now we want to
letter please make a copy and let's say
how s and okay split let's find
tweed string okay there it is already so
copy that
come back here copy paste they need Eve
above him safe did we just involve our
yes we didn't even save so now that will
work but it won't because you need to
reopen it close yes the open you see
that is good that's what I want so now
you know now I can go back here and
commit
like I would say oops hunting I do okay
yeah so actually so is and usually I
need to sort this so now my ass is like
sorted you know so did with the others
and I go to the top inserted a state I
want in this format and delete the
earlier one and now I can do a mess
which is magic magic mod magic status
you can see here it makes okay it's wait
how when you coca man it doesn't list I
guess so it's just keys oh there's
another thing I want to actually let me
do that
yeah so I'm trying to write a regret
grab but you know I did and what's the
word distracted I get yeah there's the
thing I want to turn on okay I mean
let's try that and do I want to show my
stuff
kick up kick ass
yeah it's it's yeah there is a Mac
utility that shows the keys I'm typing
so let's try that extensions
I believe it's extensions and security
actions photos no sanctions no it's the
accessibility this is okay anyway let's
not talk about things so much
diction diction again use well anyway so
it's not what is it
let's let me show you this key cast okay
he cast he cast is so utility for Mac
that shows your keys what what this is
some kind of the spam website yeah this
is the one we want
maybe it's the same thing maybe it's not
okay so this is the utility you can use
to
[Music]
what his
key cast okay key see a STR not cast
okay apparently they are quite a few of
them
yeah and I hesitate in turning out get
home because you know it's open source
but I haven't looked at the source code
but I even I did even if I did I don't
understand it because I think it's C
code the C language C language sucks
security and privacy okay there it is
security and privacy and it's wholly
important accessibility and I know okay
and it's just tired on because it's
probably trustworthy you know like fear
that once I turn on you know it's
sending my keystrokes to the FBI I don't
know if I'm gonna be censored for this
you don't even want to mention the name
so anyway so key cast app so I have to
find the app let's try right had one to
see even why is it grayed out because I
have to do this all and now then it's
man I don't want to do it now
so let's skip sorry about that forget
about the whole thing then well just
just just use okay so you know just look
at this window it's good enough so check
for changes
so I added more well I didn't wanna
breathe okay this is becoming no good
because I'm talking too much let's get
back to the restraint okay type fine
string let's see if I can still do this
five twelve his job mean it's already
option initially input and it's skip the
whole thing set Q mine strain that's
just use short short words yeah yeah and
find the directory so pump pump for
directory name read directory name read
directory name okay that's good
the to search okay let's say skip that
set Q yeah the to search yes the okay
the dou X so I'm using these names so
that it's easier to find you see and
feed of that and
okay fine strange that let's just say
that let's just say that with temp of
with temp of yes okay now you need to
traverse directory in order to do that
you use directory recursively something
okay
you see you see I'm using my Emacs Lisp
tutorial myself to find things but if
you are not used to that of course there
are so many other ways to find the
functions you want for example I don't I
don't remember the file name actually
the file name I want is directory files
recursively
but I just remember recursively so you
can do this actually you need to control
you then do that on purpose
basically that that's a that's the
apropos command directory you see it
shows here such so that that's what you
want so that X rejects rejects is going
to be okay actually you need another
prompt file name rejects let's do that
read read stream
restream file name rejects Naomi checks
regular expression okay so that's good
fine every checks and write V file
directory recursively let's see
alright the hex reject is gonna be that
you don't need that so now you have that
now before we do anything let's just
message see if we got a right find
stream the X
file name rejects I don't like that name
is too long okay and evaluate the puffle
now let's just call the function X X and
find string let's say TTT directly to
such yes file name rejects let's say
HTML dollar sign and let's go to a
message both yes I got so the program is
running that's good you know just make
sure show up before we do anything else
make sure it's the structure is good
with temp buffer okay
5:16 almost an almost with ten buffer
okay you need to walk directory yeah so
what directory directory because really
that's going to return a list file is
let's just say that so and of course you
need this to be here as well
well I already know he's walking so fire
list now with now what you need to do is
that so it returns a fire list of file
paths so for each one you want to open
it and such it and if it's there print
it and close it so now you would need to
walk directory directory fabrica yeah so
what you do is map car and well map see
some app see you need to give a function
here and the sequence is going to be
fire list so that's going to go through
it you don't need that anymore
so let's into some map car so X X is
going to be the file path and the body
is let's say that X let's do that
IVA and run it yes fine strain TT that
that rejects that okay so you see it's
it's printing all this path so that's
also working and now so you see we are
dissecting the problem into each
components you know and in each step we
make sure it's working so so X is a file
and now you want to open it yeah with
temper temper and with temper for insert
contents insert file contents that's
right
is that what we want no that's not what
we want
well I was going to look up my older
code but didn't let's not do that now so
so let's see here's the file contents in
the content of file file name after
point returns to these service returns
list of absolute file name and number of
characters inserted but yeah that's I'm
pretty sure that's what I want
so insert the file content hex that's
right you don't need that and go to go
to char but beginning of buffer this we
want to go to beneath beginning of we
can just say 1 because 1 is the painting
I was going to do point mean but one is
ok ok now we the way we open usually do
is you can use finite file but that's
not what you want because fine file has
you know it has lots of side effects for
example when you find file which is open
the file it will load the mod oder
automatically you know in Emacs this
model HTML mod and that usually is very
slow because it's going to do syntax
highlighting and stuff lots of stuff for
example it's going to also run for
example let's say hook because you can
look at that hook for our hook and you
see these are the values so each value
is a function so if you use fine file it
opens the file then it runs a bunch of
functions like you know tens of
functions from each minor mod of major
mod because that you know that that
makes Emacs convenient I actually don't
use many packages but for you if you
describe variable on this you probably
gonna see a few times more than me so
you don't want if you writing script you
know I can run this in patch so you
don't want to use fine fire in general
so what do you do
you use with temper for instead with ten
buffer then instead of fire content it's
much faster it doesn't and also it
doesn't have undue because when you're
writing a script you don't need you know
you don't want undo so go to cha one
then now we want to search the text okay
how do you such tanks such for what
that's the that's a thing
so such forward find stream bound bound
we don't want bound and kneel because if
you don't say weight bound you know but
Borneo is a position if you say bound
ten years only such after the tenth
character so you don't want a bound and
you want no arrow true and you don't
want women to have count you want to not
know arrow because otherwise if you
cannot find it it'll stop your program
you you know with an arrow
so such forward so so that's it so if
such forward if it's find you we return
true so if it's true then let's just say
print it print print let's
yeah well print see okay it's just you
want to print let's say from the
beginning of line to end of line line
okay so print buffer substring no
properties beginning of line my
beginning position yeah my in position
that's right that's what you want to do
so if I'll do that if it's not found do
nothing new you can just say new you
know you can
well in this case you know instead of
doing that you can just say when when
it's like if but without the else part
so so you don't need the new anymore so
you see match match yes so Eve out the
buffer so we are I think okay so instead
of file go to the beginning wins when
such forward find string neo T then
you've true then printed so let's try
that okay and and now let's try to do
that okay call xx find string let's do
that you know we can actually use
rejects find find string yeah rejects
because script by default is rejects so
let's do that
so it's rejects you want instead for
such forward you want such forward
research forward yeah so that's what you
want that's good eval buffer okay let's
try go that rejects what me check shall
we say let's say a scowl because well
it's not it's just fantasy
it's try that first so this directory
yes in filename rejects that okay please
please make it work who hate didn't work
yes okay so wait so did it work
yes now because I know it's spinning to
message which is actually a bad idea
let's copy it close it new puffer paste
you see and it's printing like a string
we
which we don't want we want to just
without printing this quote so let's say
such for a scar okay you see so you'd
find in the other Emacs directory my
Emacs directory all the lines containing
a scowl and okay so that's basically it
and okay 26 minutes okay if I have half
half an hour that's too long so but we
need to refine this program you see when
you print it out you also want to print
let's see where is it print you also
want to print file name print file name
but actually yeah you want to print file
name and print that then you also want
to you know this lots refinement you
want to do you also want to make it so
that ad buffered text properties to the
printed output so that user can press
ENTER and jump to that occurrence right
away so yeah so so so anyway so that's
the basics of I'm you know the time is
up so that's the basic I have ever have
written the package you can use actually
are I recently did a demo of it so find
package you know it does all these you
know nicely so for example let's try
that some fine text you know so I let's
say fine text okay let's go yes I wanted
directory that okay you see now it's
good you see it shows you and I can
press ENTER and jump to the location
okay that's it thank you for watching
and I've been wanting to do more videos
and if you like you know hit me up you
know like comment on the YouTube and I
would like to I'm thinking you know but
you know I don't want to say I'm
planning it because every time I plan
something it's just you know I have
pressure like you know it needs to be
good it does come out usually this way I
was a so I like to do maybe interviews
like Sasha has done like with Emacs
people so you can you know we can do
like I interview you and you can talk
about your experiences you know let's
focus on some topic like and also I have
some questions I would like to get
answered for example use a use a package
that's a great package by the Emacs
maintain current maintainer
John Wiggly he's a great guy and he's
you know he's a he's a a Maglis expert
of course he's expert know and he's also
expert at Haskell that's quite
interesting and he's also you know C
compiler expert because I think that's
his job for like 10 or 20 20 years so
that would be interesting and and also
there's a lot other people I like to
talk to I recently Howard Howard what's
his name Howard Adams you know and shift
row I've met Jeff Joe is a guy who runs
Emacs meet up San Francisco
it's a great guy but anyway I'm I want
to mention you know talking about people
they would say Sasha yeah Sasha is busy
with her and well not not this person
but Sasha she's busy
Howard Abrams so yes it would be great
to have them you know you know in video
Jong Wiggly or Howard Adams Jeff Shaw
and there's a lot of people you know I
can't just you know right now go of list
him this a lot Emacs developers I know
you know but it has 10 20 years like
Stefan what's his last name he was the
previous maintainer
and I actually never seen him on video
oh I you know no top talk to him life I
never met him in your life and a lot of
people so you know if you are interested
check you know chapter me you know the
email me or Twitter otherwise so let's
see if we can get it going you know it
would be great to have that okay let's
say for for today thank you for watching
and to thumpa thumbs up please thank you
thank you bye