e e
audio oh
okay there is no audio [ __ ] so anyway my
keyboards glove 80 ultimate hacking
keyboard and the other one the yellow
thing is SW board okay so this is s v a
l b o a r d small board for each one of
them I have a review on my website and
today we're going to code um so am I
good now Angelo today we're going to
code emac LP so pure emac lisp coding so
if you have questions about emac or lisp
ask me I'll get to it otherwise let's
begin so let's just
begin so video check audio check audio
audio audio audio audio check I'm alive
so let's begin coding so let me show you
what I want to do so pure emac
this fantastic thank you so let me just
write it what's going
on
okay emac this coding ask
questions about emac or this okay uh
let's begin coding so what I want to do
is I have this command in soft FL keys
by the way in the pink in the pink
window you can see all my command Calles
as I uh as I type any key for example I
want to delete this H1 header press a
key it's going press a key remove all
empty spaces press key the entire main
section is gun so showing browser you
see it's gun go back undo undo and undo
undo undo undo okay weo so start now
yeah so show in browser so there we have
it so yeah so let's um so I'm using so
Pink Key you know the pink window shows
all my command C you can see undo there
and keystroke on the left and I'm using
a vak keyboard layout and uh I'm using
Sly Keys okay cly Keys like that just
search it you'll find it so there's a
website it is the most efficient key
binding system for
emac uh so you don't have to press
control keys or command keys or meta or
alt so saves you hand
pen for repetitive string injury for
those of you heavy coders emx users so
okay so what I want to do today is I
want to code a function
uh why is there no treea emx yeah I'm
not using Tre sea at the moment I mean I
haven't tree Seer is a kind of a passer
editor helper so for example for syntax
highlighting for example the coloring of
the string and
for you know it's related to syntax to
help you to help the editor so you can
um you know get all the list of function
names or things like that so treea is
new in emac about two years ago uh I
think it's very interesting but I just
haven't had time to use it so oh I so
I'm not using
Tre okay so what I want to do today is
there's a function you see I press the
key F1 here can you see the key uh no
it's on the left side so you cannot so
anyway I
press the key one so so you see It'll
move closer to um to the
previous the previous quote character
double quote you see I can move backward
or I can move forward forward is two so
you can see in the pink windowa backward
punctuation forward punctuation you can
change the characters to search for so
right now I set it to the quotation mark
so you can see see forward forward
forward forward forward forward forward
or backward okay so but one of the issue
I have is that every time you press it
you know you have to press twice because
obviously the quotation delimeters comes
in pairs um so I want to
make I want to
modify modify the command so that when I
press the key it simply get me to the
previous you know the previous string so
this is a string right so I just press
one key press one key it gets me to the
maybe the beginning of the stream so I
don't have to like manually Navigate
Okay so let's try um you know let's see
how it goes so let me show you the
command so you see here's a
documentation for the command backward
punctuation jump to the file open it so
here is the source
code very simple okay s backward
punctuation so what it does is you just
uh if you want by the way so if you want
the code just go to this website showing
browser so you can copy it and you'll
have
it so you can use it okay so um let me
make a copy of that go to my emac blog
new section paste link linky make a list
showing browser so you know so that's a
page now I'm about to make modification
to this code so that's why I'm putting
there so I'm going to change it and blog
it when it's done remove the to-do push
it to my server and put it to the uh RS
web
feed so anyway so that's the command so
what so you you can see the code is very
simple all you have to do is C the
regular expression search backward and
uh search backward you know by a regular
expression and Neo means don't report
any error if you cannot find it and t
means if you do not find a character you
are looking
for uh just move the cruiser as as much
as backward as possible you know
so very simple command Okay so so this
is backward punctuation then there is
also forward punctuation so you can see
this is a forward punctuation or you
what the the difference is just search
forward and versus search backward and
uh what is my punctuation regular
expression that's this line okay so
right now it's basically one single
character the
um you know the the that is the name for
that character in unic code is quotation
mark okay so you can press describe
character so you go here so you can see
the name is quotation mark That's a unic
code name for that
character okay
so so I want to make it that instead of
searching just a
character
um you know in instead of just moving by
a character or any punctuation I wanted
to make a dedicated command that simply
jump to the
previous
string okay so go to previous string
previous string or next string so let's
actually code it let's begin to code it
so instead of using that let's code it
code it
okay so create a new emac block p is the
code here and uh pop it out so we're
going to code it and we're going to
change this
uh instead of punctuation let's change
it to
string uh wait uh forward
string no yes yes no okay
and uh these two we don't need okay so
so there it is forward string move
closer to the next occurrence of string
syntax okay remove that remove that
date
okay and uh let's delete that okay so
actually it's Del that as well so
okay so forward string so
um yeah juang I know what Trea
is so Diego says why do your variable
name start with X that's my convention
is that the pattern you know that's just
my convention okay so one of the
advantage of this convention is that for
example let's create that so if you have
something so whenever a variable that
start with x then it'll be colored so
this is a kind of a hack way to have a
easy coloring of all variable names
without an actual parer like Tre sea
okay
I'm I'm assuming Juan is using Tre C and
he's played it with it I haven't yet it
would I think it's very interesting but
I just I didn't have time to play with
that yet you know since uh even I like
wanted to since two years ago um because
for me the way I work on things is very
uh
fastidious
systematic uh and usually through
usually deeper than you know so I
so if I want to start to uh use Tre Seer
I'm going to take several hours just to
read stuff and you know it's going to
take many days many days and days and
weeks because then I'm going to start to
create my own package interface to the
Tre Seer I'm not going to just use you
know GitHub you know GitHub or or MAA
download some other and stuff like that
CH Ching Crystal long time no see happy
New
Year please explain uhar insert Ruby r t
most sufficient this key
strokes
uh didn't we explain that before I think
I I
did yeah so you're talking about so okay
so let me quickly address that yeah so
because there's a pay this is customer
okay so let me answer that okay okay so
let me so there's a question about Ruby
um stuff so let me show you guys what
that is about and let me answer the
question so you go to web dev blog
HTML then then basic syntax so this is a
complete tutorial for HTML so search for
Ruby there it is click it so Ruby is a
new um Ruby is a markup in HTML
uh which is pretty new started in uh 20
2010 well by now it's 15 years God I'm
getting old you know so anyway Ruby is
um the Ruby markup is to allow you is
basically designed for Asian languages
in particular Chinese and Japanese so it
is designed to allow you to have
annotations at the top of the line okay
so for example you see the green that's
Chinese characters the red are
annotations those are pronunciation
symbols okay because Chinese is not
alphabet system so you have to learn how
each one is
pronounced you know usually so so for
especially for students like
kindergarten or great school children
they need to start to know you know
learn about how each character is
pronounced because the character
itself usually doesn't tell you you know
you have no idea how it's pronounced
because it's not alphabets therefore you
have this uh this so-call Ruby markup
okay I think that's that's a name from
Japanese Ruby markup so hold on a second
I got a call
uh so Ruby mockup so okay so the way you
do it so basically very simple so um so
for example here you have a English
version uh you can you know it's it's
not just for Chinese text you can also
do it on English for example this p is a
English word it's came from French I
think so you can add
a uh IP a symbol International Phonetic
Alphabet in on top of it to show you
that this is
um how is that pronounced I I thought
it's p oh but according to that it's
Pasa anyway so the way you do it just ru
be the whole thing then put the
pronunciation inside the RT markup okay
so cryistal has a question about you
know so basically so how do you do that
so so let me show you okay so
um
uh
some uh let's see something okay so I
means
so uh so you put a markup you see a
markup on Ruby and you want to um let's
say SSS okay so you put a markup RT okay
put a paragraph showing
browser okay so you can
see you know it doesn't because you
don't have you know CSS so right now by
default it shows like that can you
see so so all you have to do is add some
CSS here okay so let's add
it
uh okay so so style Ruby whenever you
see Ruby let's say uh
color red okay and uh
RT
color blue okay and uh and and make this
uh font
size okay press the button by the way
that's a fantastic command Kar CSS
format buffer you can also find it on
search for Kar emac blog okay so anyway
we added some CSS cascading style sheet
put it back here and show in browser now
you see that's you see control zero to
put the size back so you see that's Ruby
okay so that's called Ruby
annotation now I had a emac
command that you know because it's
tedious to add the
tag each time you want to do that so I
had a command I believe uh let's see if
I can find it I believe I
deleted oh there it is Ruby markup okay
tab uu uh wait
tap uu okay so let's go to yeah so there
is a
command HTML Mark of Ruby so it it wrap
HTML Ruby annotation tag on current line
or selection CHS inside par are wrapped
with rt okay so let me show you how to
use
it let's say uh how okay let's find some
word
okay example how do you pronounce it
let's say
example let's say that okay so now you
just tap uu there it is now put uh
paragraph showing browser there it is
fantastic and for IPA by the way for IPA
you could um wait where are we so you
know like by tradition IPA has this
slash slash there you
go okay so that is the command so let me
let me show the command here okay so
um and you can find there is a you know
if you like the
code the code is there so you can go
there grab it and you have it it doesn't
require anything else
okay so okay so that I guess that answer
your question
yeah okay so let me Demo it
again you know you got a code so I think
yeah your question is about this emac
this command okay so let me Demo it
again
um extra okay how do you pronounce
extra
xra okay you pronounce it like that okay
so now just callar Ruby markup
press enter there you have it and the
option you know you add a paragraph
showing browser there it is okay so why
is
it you know so so so you know so instead
of you know writing add each tag and you
just put the parenthesis for the
pronunciation and press a key and you
are good to
go fantastic thank you thank you so yeah
yeah Japanese is a very complex language
you know very very
complex now I don't know about the
Japanese uh grammar but the Japanese
writing system is very very complex
because it in involve like involves like
2,000 to 3,000 Chinese characters then
you got about 48 or 80 yeah actually 80
phonetic symbols for
Japanese then yeah then whenever you
have a Chinese character they have they
have like like two or three four
different ways to pronounce that Chinese
character depending on uh I I'm not sure
exactly depend you know there are many
you know several ways to pronounce a CH
Chinese
character uh yeah so Japanese writing
system is extremely complex but you
know primarily because you know let me
just talk random so because Japanese the
Japanese language is very different it
doesn't share anything with the Chinese
language so Chinese and Japanese are
independent languages okay however the
writing
system the writing system of Japanese is
basically entirely borrowed from
Chinese about like a thousand years ago
so so Japanese take the Chinese they
don't have a writing system you know so
they you know they are we are close so
they they got the you know they travel
you know they so they took the Chinese
characters then adopt the Chinese
characters to the for the Japanese
language we which is kind of you know
it's not very complex you know because
they the two languages doesn't really
share
anything yeah so and plus the Chinese
characters is not alphabet so it happens
to be just you know this 3,000 to 10,000
characters you know each one is just by
itself so
anyway let's go back to the function so
let's go back so now I want to write
this function forward string so let's do
it quickly now okay so all we have to do
is um yeah we explain about the um
variable why do I start with X so that
you can highlight all variables without
passing the text so it's kind of a
hack uh that is Ina emac this mod
okay now you guys have to pay me okay
okay because I talked a lot for years
and uh I get you know like I get no
money
so uh I still enjoy doing talk show but
if you like my stuff you really you know
you should pay me cly keys and uh for
example right now we are talking about
um let me show you okay uh wait
there saw emac this mod okay so that's
what I'm using when I code EAC dis so
that's how why every time you see you
know a symbol start with X they become
black so you can
see
um you know basically that's uh by this
line you know
anyway and also if you have
Capital
anything Capital it becomes red okay so
anyway let's focus back on this so
search
forward uh actually let's search
backward
okay uh What uh regular expression you
want to search so now you need to look
for regular expression emac okay go to
emac block go to uh list
Basics then go to string functions
regular expression in emac disp then you
want to go to regular expression
syntax so we want to
search by the way this feature is unique
in emac you will not find it in par
regular expression in Python in Java in
rubby in goand in
C++ not anywhere this regular expression
feature is unique in emac it allows you
to
search search a um pattern that
is according to the emac lisps syntax
table so in iMac L you can Des designate
group certain characters to be uh to be
a string or to be
a bracket
without actually searching for you know
the character but anyway let let me just
try Okay so regular expression syntax
you want to search for
string
uh yeah so go back so repetition uh so
you know this regular expression is very
complex captured
patterns I know it's at the bottom
grouping alternatives
character classes okay we are
close then character classes of emac
syntax table that's what we want okay so
there is a there okay so match any
character whose syntax class is that
okay that's what we want so here's
example check if the next character is a
string delimiter
that okay close that okay so search
backward uh search backward basically we
just want this this thing okay so this
means it will search any
character that's designated as a string
delimeter
okay according to the current
major mods syntax table so it can varies
so if you have you know in one
mod for example in Python both the
double quote and single quote they are
both considered string delimiters so
this command will jump to either one of
them uh but it's kind of okay anyways
you know this is not you know it's kind
of complex because it's it's very hard
to deal with syntax table because if you
want to write a major mod you need to
you
know kind of Define your syntax table
and syntax table is uh very kind of very
complex you can read my tutorial you
know you can just click syntax table you
can learn everything about
it so what I'm saying is that usually
it's not this is not too useful because
if you want to jump between you know
either single quote or double quote you
can simply uh use a regular expression
like that okay so let me show you okay
so single
quote
or vertical bar means or but you need
two slashes before it because of because
emag is string so all double quote so
you all uh all double quote okay so
actually and you need a back slash for
that before that so it becomes so this
is kind of equ equivalent to that if
that if that mod defines the quote the
limiter as either single or
double so but in let's say in some
programming language you can define a
string quote by let's say parent or
square bracket or even a unical
character or Smiley you can do that then
this will find it you know you you'll
find it without you manually you know
hard code what characters you are
looking for so that's you know so that's
a regular expression
feature of emac only you know where you
can give a syntax to search for a
particular uh gr uh set of characters
that's defined by the syntax table okay
so you can so essentially you can
arbitrarily Define some group of class
of
characters so in this
case back slash S
then then a double quote that means find
all the double quote find all the string
delimiters it could be anything okay so
let me just run let me just run it okay
so let me just
okay let's see F6
undefined
F7 F7 is
f8 f8 start a new emx
okay I want to have hold on a second
okay F5 F5 is undefined
okay let's use F5 okay so let's say this
backward
uh
okay so this is backward and this is
forward okay so this one is
forward am I still
good okay so forward string backward
string and let's set them give them some
keys
okay key map Global set so you want to
set to this command and what key uh the
key will
be F6 F5
okay so actually F5 should be backward
okay
so and here F6 okay so
now eval buffer we got it now let's
press
F6 do it fantastic do it do it do it
fantastic it works now
F5 it works you see so so now we did it
now this is but
functionally it's no different from what
we had uh let's go back
to uh let me show you the
other you see functionally it's not very
different from this you know in this
case you see we are just search forward
for this regular expression
and that regular expression is just a
single double quote but here we are
using
this special regular
expression to
search any character that's defined to
be string
delimeter and in emac this major mod it
happens to be also double quote so they
have the same
function functionality right now so what
I want is but they still have the
problem because every time you do it you
know it it it doesn't jump just jump to
stram it you know you have to do it
twice uh let's go
back yeah so you see it basically just
search for the double
quote so what I want to so that's not
good by the way you can search it twice
for example you can for example you can
add it so that you think it will solve
it
um I did this before like several years
ago uh let's try it again okay so now F5
F5 yeah it's such uh yeah it jump you
see it it jumped twice okay so let me
show you
some okay F5 you see F5 F5 F6 F6
F6 yeah maybe I should just do
a
twice uh yeah I guess this is a simpler
solution you know we can just just just
score it twice you
know uh but you know we so it becomes
into gets into some minor very like very
Minor Details because I did this before
I've been using this jump twice uh like
even 10 years ago uh I've been using it
for for a long time half a year or
more but eventually I stopped because
some like some issues uh and I can't
exactly remember
what yeah okay so I guess I think the
issue is sometimes you know like you
have one odd quote there so if you
always jump
twice let's see jump twice jump twice
jump twice jump
twice wait jump
forward back forward
yeah okay I I'll just do this thing okay
I think
that's that's what I want okay to solve
a practical issue now there is another
solution you know it turns out I think I
I'm going to try this for a while and
see how it goes there's another solution
I was thinking of doing is that instead
of searching forward
by a character or by a syntax
class you search forward by
a
um by text property okay so in emac this
so this is a bit advanced emac disp in
emac disp you have this text property
thing so for example why is this part
red why is this purple why is that blue
how does it work I mean what is is a
mechanism well it's because in each text
in a buffer
actually every character you can attach
a stream uh text property okay so
here actually there's a text property
that says color blue that is why it's
green okay not blue green so it's text
properties
it's kind of invisible but that's how
you know you got the
colors uh so okay so let me show you so
you can read about it emac this create a
major mod and there it is text
properties so you can learn about it
it's it's fairly simple you know you can
you can create a link click
link uh or
coling uh or if if you are on a link you
press return you'll open it in the
browser how does that work because when
you press
return that text has a happens to have a
text property that
says that bounce the return key to a
command that opens the link so this all
by text properties so this is how the
way emac do it for example in some other
editor you know if you have a link uh
you know like if you have a link HTTP
something you can press enter or jump to
it how does it work I don't know how
does it work in other text editors but
in emx that's text properties every text
in a buffer you can attach properties
and there are many properties you can be
coloring can be some action something
okay so I was thinking to make you know
to jump to jump to the next text
property that has the string
syntax anyway yeah so I'm but I'm not
going to do that I think I'll just try
this okay I think that's it for today
anything
else okay that's it for today so let me
say again you like my stuff pay me okay
you can buy my emac
tutorial uh this is most complete emac
tutorial and emac dis uh
fantastic you know pay pay here PayPal
or Amazon gift card and there's a
Chinese guy who asked me about it in
China I'm going to send you a copy today
okay so pay me and uh you can also buy
one of my
packages
uh s emac m s packages you know the
things you see me doing it's all
basically all my
packages uh and I also have a JavaScript
tutorial you can buy that's one of the
best of all JavaScript resources online
including printed books I consider mine
to be even better than them you know I
you know I talked about this
for a few times okay JavaScript in
depth and uh all in general actually
just donate to me okay go to s. info and
go to all the way to the bottom patreon
me or gift card or PayPal
okay thank you guys so for now this put
it back
syntax Cate showing
browser there it is okay that's it bye
guys