good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Santos
show today's 2019 November 20th I think
or 21st I live without without knowing
what they did is so today's November
20th 3 o clock p.m. Wednesday San
Francisco time and today we are going to
go technical we are going to do
miscellaneous live coding of Emacs Lisp
and JavaScript first SVG scalable vector
graphics coding a live rotation of
platonic solids so this is live coding
plus tutorial so I'm going to do live
coding plus I'm going to explain how it
is done good morning Edward Oh Eduardo
and Kathy and Helen and Paul so we're
gonna do technical talk today so no
rambling and stuff so let's shall we
begin let's begin begin at the beginning
which is Emacs Lisp
so what emag B's am I going to do I
don't know so let's look I have several
things I wanted to do for a while so
Emacs topic brain remember to show
aliefs code on how to learn not yes oh
yes indeed
ok so let's do that
Emacs is coding and how to win not ok so
let's so this is my topic brain so well
the first question so on the left window
you can see all my Emacs command I call
such as moving cursor and so on so if
you don't know what I'm doing I mean if
you found something interesting you can
look up the web by the command name
usually it's on my website so we go
to do okay first of all how do you start
how do you learn not jazz in McGee's so
let me show you so we're gonna create a
new buffer let's hold on a second let's
magnify my font so that means we go to
settings my Emacs bookmark then I can
open settings then I want to increase
font so search for font and I'm on a Mac
so this is this line and we want to
so let's why don't we just copy this
line out copy this code go to saw Emacs
Lee smart magnify this is the code for
setting up the found for every buffer so
it says on a Mac many men love 14 okay
let's save 15 okay and evaluate the code
okay so that's there we have it so new
buffer did we do that actually I think
we did so anyway
close that don't save close that yeah I
think yep so what we're gonna do your
topic brain so email is yeah so so first
of all how do you jannat j/s in Emacs
okay so let's go to talk show how to run
not in Emacs very simple so let's open a
new buffer and let's just go to such of
a script mod then for example
console.log 3 okay i want to print 3 and
just run it press a key i need to save
the file first okay save the file XX dot
j s run it and you see the result three
beautiful so how do you do that i'm so
this is I'm learning not yes
so basically Emacs is calling not yes
that's how you do it but how what is the
code so the code so you can see
the left panel this is a command sorry
on current files so let's select that
and search for it on the web and you can
see that's a page so you just copy this
page copy this code 20 lines of code put
in your email in it and you are good to
go
of course you need to eat install not
jeaious or it takes so this code Soglin
current quadrant wait sorry on current
fire on cassava and can go fire wait
ok here here is the code cuz I he is a
command cuz I learned current fire it
will run any of emag B's PHP Perl Python
Ruby JavaScript typescript : bash Oh
camo and notice so oh it requires is
that you aren't on your terminal you
have clear clear input ok on your
terminal you have for example I typed
which not you know or it takes is that
the NARC man chosen your path that's
that's all you need to do so which
Python which Python 3 which pearl which
ruby which or camel you see I have all
that installed so this code we all walk
or any of these programming languages
that's how you do it ok so so that's how
do you run not in JavaScript ok so and
we go into copy this and go back to
Emacs and put this here so that we have
a record of the things that's how you do
it so email is random coding so what
what what is the coding we are going to
do let's see JavaScript : san talk show
top explain Emacs Lisp I have several
things I want to do
so these are kind of my to-do list let
me show you so so eMac be smart effects
on your page to add a title okay we can
do that select random page okay so there
is some codings you see I need to do
that one is already done actually few
weeks ago demo sati leaked on fire
okay demo create a new Unicode page okay
Sally's demo extends copy HTML by link
to a presentation of HTML mod covering
basics features any comments keep the
comments going coming okay guys
night people so we are going to do eMac
list so okay so what what is the one we
want to do okay let me think
mother page to add a title okay
let's do that
okay so eMac B's let's see how long
we've been talking that's eMac this may
be 20 minutes if no comments you know
then then we start to do JavaScript so
let's do 15 minutes let's see okay so
email gives this so I have a command
that that lets me create a new file so
something oh I remember I had this
problem before okay hold on a second so
for example I typed something here well
for example yeah suppose you know
suppose I go to my programming block
okay so this is my programming block I
want to create a new entry and and you
know so show in browser so you can see
2019 eleven twenty that's a new entry
and something switch to browser reload
but I want to create a new HTML file so
what you usually what you do is you
create a new buffer then switch to HTML
mod then you start a template you know
blah blah blah title something then you
add a header header something okay then
you start to write so it's tedious
I want a command where I can let's say
let's say new keyboard okay I want
command that that I want to press a key
and you will create the entire HTML file
for you with that title so I already
have that command but it's not it
doesn't add the title so we are going to
try to do that so for example let me
show the command so Sanyal keyboard so
i'm going to press a key then I'm gonna
cooks our new page so there it is the
command so I press enter you see it
creates a link HTML link for you and the
file is also created because if I press
ENTER to open that file showing browser
that's a new file with templates
everything custom customized for my own
website so for you if you are going to
do this you probably want to have a
different template but if that's easy to
do so so I'm going to show you this code
and but there is a problem because if
you open this page and show in browser
oh there is no problem actually you know
because before I thought the title is
not changed that's why I need to add a
feature so that the title will come from
the file name remember we we begin with
a file name remember we begin with just
these words so then it creates a file
new keyboard HTML then then the file
name I mean the title of the HTML page
came from the
name but apparently is all coded so so
we don't have to do that anymore okay so
now here's a question should we go ahead
and look at this how this code works or
should we do something else I think we
should do something else because I
talked about these few videos back and
Alan you don't you don't use Emacs right
so if that's a case let's see how many
people are interesting Emacs otherwise
we we begin to do JavaScript but Kathy
uses Emacs so what topics Kathy or
anyone interesting Emacs what should we
do something else in Emacs and and let's
see so Eduardo says did you start
learning in maximum efficiency alongside
learning programming or it was later
thing it was a later thing so I this is
about my history Oh Alan to use Emacs
okay oh you are you evil user evil how
evil you are so well about my computing
history from 1992 you know basically
through our 1990s AI programming in
Mathematica I just learned it you know
you read the Mathematica manuals you
just then you start to code it but in
1998 I started to look into the UNIX
thing fascinating UNIX in Emacs what
they are strange names you know UNIX
said okay great grep you know so so I
started to do UNIX seasoning and Perl
coding and that's also about the time I
started to learn Emacs so that is 1998
so I did programming for seven years
before I started to use Emacs then in
2000 you know basically are living in
max since 1999 everyday you know
everything Emacs
but in 2006 I began to do
to learn in Ag Lisp so that is short
history okay so so this new command this
cuz i'll create a new command i you know
we discussed that before so let's not
I'm not sure it's too interesting to you
guys so so delete that page okay so
actually I want to show you delete a
page didn't you know let's just show
something you know okay so I already
delete the page so let's do it again
let's say I want a new page ABC okay I
call the command cuz our new page so
it's created open the file showing
browser now it's ABC brand-new back to
Emacs okay now I decided it's a mistake
I don't I want I want to delete the file
that's in a current buffer so I press a
key pad is deleted so that command is
this one sorry Deacon file it's also on
my website so you can go and grab it it
will just delete the current buffer the
file you know current buffer so now I
press ENTER it says doesn't exist do you
want to create you see it's deleted
because it's deleted and you can also
see in the messages buffer you see it
says you know delete it and also backup
created everytime it deletes it creates
a backup so that's about that so we
don't need this anymore so we don't
actually need this anymore so showing
browser that's my blog programming block
blog back to the original state so close
it okay so that's about Emacs what it
refresh it's gone
refresh it's gone that's about Emacs
ruin current file what else let's see do
we have Rouen confiar here yes we do
okay
okay so let me show you another page
hello beautiful people welcome thank you
for coming so we can do JavaScript in a
bit so so now we let me show you another
UMAX command okay
so often because i do my you know i do
website a lot I write tons of blogs so
often what I want is I want to open this
current file that's shown in browser I
want to open in my Emacs so this this
this is a local URL so yeah you know
this is fun this is pearl pearl pearl
mangas you know the language they are
into this kind of thing okay so then
anyone with something okay so pearl
mangas yeah so I work in HTML so I
usually I want to open a browser
slinking Emacs for example this page how
do I do that
here's up what I do okay so I control l2
to move the cursor to the URL field then
I copy it back to Emacs and you can see
if I paste it
he let's see you know that's path file
path and now notice it has this file
schema the file colon slash slash slash
but the problem is I want to open that
file so how do you do that so you can do
normally in Emacs you can call a fine
file at point so a meta X fine file at
point usually there's ideas so you can
you know let's type the full name find a
file at point okay you call that an
Emacs will ask you oh do you want to
open is this ask you for confirmation
which is very annoying so you say yes
then it opens it okay so you can see
that
then it opened and said here is a JPEG
image you opened that that's you know so
you can so I know I'm me in the right
file so close it so remembered so you
you go to a page you copy the URL you
know like control L then control C you
know on Windows copy the URL switch to
back to Emacs and then paste the URL
then you say then you say five hour at
point then press ENTER to confirm
that's how you do it but that's too too
much too tedious so what I want what I
want is after I copy that URL and after
when I mean Emacs I want just to press
one key you'll just open the file
without having to paste the link here
first you know I don't want to paste the
link first I just want to press the key
and just open so big okay so how you do
that so let me show you so let's say I
want to open this page so copy the URL
go back to Emacs and just press a key to
open it so I press the key that's it
this is a file so so that command is
this one cuz I'll open file from click
clipboard okay so let's see if we have
it on a website so close this file
just just search it
okay it shows several link but those are
not it let me see if I have this on my
website so oh this this file is actually
not on my website so this code is not on
my website although it's in my github
yeah so if you want that code you can go
to Emacs github under miscellaneous I
think under the miscellaneous fire some
open file from Creek clipboard okay so
that's that is the that is the let's
look at the code okay what I think it's
not um it's not on my website because
this code is somewhat personal yeah
that's true because I need to because
given a local URL you need to you know
know most people you don't have blogs
basically given a local file URL file
you know you are path you need to find
your web root on your disk you know the
web root path so yeah so this is a bit
personal so that's why it's not on you
know it's not on the web so I don't know
if this is useful to you guys maybe not
okay so let's read the comments then if
no more Emacs let's go on to JavaScript
20 minutes okay so I seem to use running
Emacs for everything apart from
programming I seem to learn and use
Emacs for everything so in programming
you don't use emacs org-mode rules them
all hello beautiful people hello
beautiful people you also use Emacs or
not Kathy says
a lot that's where I disagree with saw I
think oak oh yeah so oh c'mon uses yeah
he disagree with me
Oh Marty is fine ain't nothing wrong
with it oh yeah oh god you know yeah so
oh nice so you math or science okay so
let's do JavaScript maybe
we don't see bot today way spot but I
use Emacs pretty much every day okay so
we are all Emacs people great so shall
we continue to JavaScript or more Emacs
probably we should continue to do
JavaScript because that's what promised
today in the YouTube description okay so
we have we have let's close that sub
open file from clipboard okay so click
so close that email is live coding
miscellaneous stuff okay so we didn't do
much of that oh well so so JavaScript oh
by the way so I should also mention so
hello beautiful people he he is going to
have a live stream demonstration and
question and answers about this chemo
keyboard key mouse this thing okay so
he's going to do a YouTube live stream
on this device so if you are interested
mark your calendar okay so so this
interesting device especially Kathy so
you should you know you asked asked
about it so this you know here he this
is his photo so the YouTube so you go to
youtube you go to this link okay so you
go to that links okay okay so let me
post post link let's just copy the post
so you go there so it's scheduled on
November wait my date I got my date
wrong
okay wait did I oh my god I got my date
one so came out so let's open Chrome
yeah I got my date wrong open Chrome
browser go to the YouTube
November 26th okay so November 26 six I
need to fix
okay let's knit let me just fix that in
real time so I need to fix in several
places so November 26 11 o'clock so
November
yeah so first of all let me copy it here
and then it's you know it's to demo of
Emax operation so November 26 so copy
dad so let me show you another command
okay so right now I can copy this line
so let me show you so right now I can
copy this line and use bookmark go
through my keyboard block okay okay
bookmark is another interesting thing
you know all this is on my Emacs website
so you know if you go to my Emacs
website practical Emacs all the details
in code is over here so you can read
that you know take you know read them
one page a day you learn a lot of things
so my Emacs block okay and so what I'm
going to show is another command so I'm
going to I'm going to go to my keyboard
block okay showing browser so this is my
keyboard block so I need to fix this
date now now fix this date so I can so
go back to my previous buffer which
which buffer is this wait
showing browser so that's Emacs blog I
need to fix that close
showing browser so like a keyboard block
okay I need to fix that close so showing
browser this is the talk show so here we
got the correct date so let's copy it
okay open keyboard blog copy it paste it
there and the date is all wrong okay
copy that paste here so showing browser
so November 11th 26 that's correct so
that is fixed in my keyboard block but
also there is the keyboard XML page so
open that
then then fix that date then fix that
date that's good
then call saw Adam update time stamp saw
update Adam entry date that will update
this line okay so don't close it yes
save showing browser that's correct
close it now go through my Emacs blog
showing browser now we need to fix that
paste okay
paste showing browser again that's
correct date and we now we need to also
show we need to also fix the XML file so
open the XML file paste it the date
paste it so it's good call update atom
entry date so this state is updated so
is that good yes that's good close it
save yes
close the block now go to ECL & Co saw a
brief saw interactive a brief now this
what is this command for this is this
command is for when you have hundreds of
briefs
you forgot which one exists you forgot
what's a brief name so you can code you
can call this interactive a brief so you
can see that those are Maya briefs some
I don't use often so I don't remember
they are there but once in a while in a
month or two I use it so I can you know
choose one and we will it solves a
problem where you have hundreds of
briefs and you forgot what what's the
brief name so it pops up at least so
that command is so interactive a brief
okay so you can he's on my
if you want that you can use it so now I
call that command and I want to a sink a
brief enter and that up slows to my
website a sink to my server so you can
see your other changed file so so that's
updated that's that's good yes and by
the way they are they are easier ways
because to to fix that so because when
you have when I have some text that I
need to fix in several places I can do a
global Find and Replace on all my
websites so instead of going into each
blog keyboard blog Emacs block open them
edited save it and open the XML versions
instead of that I can just call command
that that does that oh but anyway we
already fixed that so let's see let's
see what live stream damn demo yeah so
that Tuesday 11 o'clock so I think we
there so Motty mean consider considering
invest investing time and effort into
Emacs bash I can see the benefits
pulling back the veil of illusion that
you I impose on the user but I have
doubts about the whole venture nice
content you have doubts about the
venture well it depends on you you know
if you are you know you know my hand you
can just use vs called visual studio
whatever sign you know that get things
done Emacs is its own world and you if
you want to eat to Emacs then you have
then you are going to learn
it's like Linux ok you're going to spend
a lot of time drinking stuff learn
instead of learning and drinking stuff
almost every day and
it becomes a lifestyle I mean and the
benefit is that you well it gets you
interested in computation in programming
that that's why some people say Emacs
users usually they know stuff because
that means you know when you dive into
Emacs that means you are really really
interested in programming in technology
so it's almost like these kind of people
they they they try to learn Emacs
meanwhile some many programmers
significant number of programmers they
are in yet just you know just to get on
with life they are not really not
interested in programming so they
wouldn't you know look into Emacs so
that's why Emacs people you have certain
thin certain you know like like it elite
status attached based on you know pace
important fact that's that is true
so jorik there you are here we see each
other again so article about jean
keyboard thanks are for sore sold
another one today now you have to pay me
advertisement fee so so jorik so i don't
know if we are going to do a javascript
you know yeah today you know because if
you have interest we you know like type
it doesn't you know so anyway so jorik
so so there is this you know keyboard
for keyboard nerds so we have a lot
varieties let me show you it just in
general so you can see we have a lot
varieties of keyboard
ergonomic keyboards people made and and
there is new one this one is pretty new
so i put them together kind of because
they are similar so anyway all these are
do-it-yourself keyboards right now i
arranged named by a number of keys so
ergo docks is
seventy-six keys then you know then 70
keys 68 so so so this one actually they
are like two or three of them so one of
them is gogo keyboard the both of these
are new I think this year am i right
something like that so they they they
don't have many keys like they focus on
you know some people like that I don't
like that but you know 50 keys 42 keys
they are similar similar in shape but I
think they are based from different
previous technology you know these to it
yourself I think Kong and John are based
on based on pivot based on this one
helix which is originally from Japan you
know the Japanese hackers they created
that am i right so anyway so you have
these two keyboards like look somewhat
similar but I think they are based on
different you know different how do you
call that
different different set up the the the
the CPU whatever the PCB board and stuff
beautiful people
so I'm thinking maybe we should do
JavaScript now so can we do that
mmm Oh would that be it for today so
what do you guys think you know today is
gonna be short
oh we we start to do JavaScript let's
see yeah type type it please type type
comments
emacs bug crows polyhedron let's do
let's do one feature okay of JavaScript
since I you know stop I mean okay so
let's do a JavaScript so I'm going to
open this thing Chrome open okay hold on
a second
so Chrome we are going to open linking
home okay so there is your JavaScript oh
this one doesn't have live rotation you
have to press keys I want the one with
live rotation so let's go to I have
another version okay so maybe this one
okay open in Chrome browser by the way
that's another Emacs command we talked
about a few days ago so if you want that
command you can it doesn't show there
okay so let's let me show you hope and
chromium browser okay so the code is
here that's so that's here that here's a
URL the code is here I talked about this
a few a few days ago so you can you can
open fire in external app such as PDF
such as image files very convenient for
example and let me just show you some
okay so let me show you so we got lots
of image files so I want to show this
directory of these all images over in
desktop okay there you there we have it
this works in Windows Mac and also Linux
okay open in desktop then we have open
in desktop ok open so for example I'm
showing this I can I don't want to open
in desktop now I want to open in
whatever the application for images so I
call opening external app oh wait wrong
key do it up gets to it again opening
external app then it shows on a Mac it's
preview on Windows or Linux is whatever
your image app and also work for PDF so
very convenient then let's say I want I
want to open this this file location in
terminal so I call open in terminal
woohoo there it is
this here is a terminal you see with the
correct directory path so that's the
directory this buffer is in you know
sometimes in Emacs you want to you need
to do something in terminal so you can
call this command anywhere even when you
are in issue for example what right now
I mean issue LS there is my files I can
call open in terminal then you see is
switch me to terminal he opens a
terminal with that directory okay close
that close that close that back to Emacs
close that opening in terminal and also
when you are in Windows here is
interesting when you are in Windows it
will open in PowerShell fantastic power
show and for Emacs uses some of you for
those of you new to Emacs you might be
wondering Emacs has quite a few shares
you know for example let me show you
Emacs shares so I want to share okay so
I'm going to so this is a show so let's
split okay so and this is special well
it's not called bash but you see
so now I have split windows so on the
top you are seeing Asia so what's a Xiao
Yao is a she's a shell that's written
entirely in Emacs Lisp pure Emacs Lee's
you know so it works on Windows some on
Windows you know where you don't have
the typical UNIX tools but it can it
works
so that's easier and and it has its own
features okay then you have the bottom
is the traditional shell command in
Emacs which basically is a interface to
bash ok so so so a shell is kind of new
Wow yup by now is like 10 years old but
for the first 10 years of my Emacs I'm
using you know these shell commands but
since about three or four or five four
years ago I started to use hashanah
which one is really it's up to you they
so in this article I have some
explanation what what are the
differences which one to use you know
that's a question people wants to know
so you can read it you know you can find
out you can find out but you know you
can try it for yourself and you see
which one you like and by the way in
Emacs you also have besides these two oh
they are building
you also have by the way when you run
the shell command MX shell it will if
you are on Windows it will call it will
call the by default I think I'm not sure
what it costs today I think possibly
PowerShell or possibly I think
traditionally it cause the command dot
exe so on Windows that's the case so
anyway beside these two shell commands a
shell or the shell command in Emacs you
also have third term and Ann Seton okay
I can again demo I can show you okay so
let's create a new window let's say
okay and they I'm going to call my ex
turn okay then it's gonna ask me what
what shell to run okay bash okay enter
so now we are in so this is turn so the
Emacs term command you know MX term what
is it it's it's also a interface to
shell just like the shell command here
at the bottom but the difference is that
it tries to actually emulate it tries to
be a terminal emulator so in other words
when you call the terminal commands
everything it behaves like a terminal
okay so all your Emacs keystrokes
doesn't work anymore
like the typical Emacs keys for moving
cruiser they don't they stop walking
because Emacs is now pretending to be a
terminal so it sticks to whatever the
terminals keys that is that is a major
difference okay and typically I don't
use this at all I'd never use this the
reason the reason you want to use the
use this term command is when when in
some shell commands they they are kind
of incompatible when you are running
them in Asia or in this shell command
because like you may see the display
like all the lines become one line with
a you know caret M something like that
that that that is what happens you know
let me show you let me run some commands
so you can see you know LS lots of files
there iOS and the initial iOS you know
you see they behave a bit different so
initial it's got its own coloring in the
shell command it's not so much color but
I have the might
and my prompt color but in this turn
it's all just spread I'm not sure we can
color it may be but it's flame because
the when you run the term command it
tries to be the more most strict you
know I don't know if I can show you any
difference okay so here's the difference
like initial for example if I type Emacs
okay oh if I type in that will not walk
you know you gonna get garbled screen
I'm pretty sure and similarly for when
you are in the shell terminal but but
you can do that in term when you are in
turn I said you can do that let's
demonstrate let's show that see what
happens
could you talk a bit about Mouse versus
trackball okay let's do that let's do
that right after this yeah that's a good
topic so what what else are people
saying John Kehoe thanks car do you ever
look at Emacs source code for horses do
you ever look at Emacs or C code or
atleast code
I look at Emacs source codes it you know
I don't code in C so I not I'm not too
interested in that but if you have wait
why is it here hold on a second
so if you my mom on the Mac right now
I'm a Mac so I don't have you know and I
installed a Mac from binary so I don't
have the source code however you can
also compile Emacs on the Mac I haven't
done it before but I was doing it on
Linux so when you are on when you have a
Emacs installation that with the source
code then whenever you code the square
function let's just try it okay describe
key let's say describe key that command
okay so we have a command write cha
which moves the character to the right
and then you can see there's a link you
enter you go you go there and cricket it
shows the source code now in this case
it's a list file but sometimes it's C
code because some of the co commands are
written in C for example this forward
child so let's call this pipe function
on the for watch ah okay describe
function oops not there describe
function for watch okay enter so you can
see here he says for char is
something-something building functions
in here C source code now if I press
ENTER he asked me to type the path for
the source code of that since I don't
have it on on the Mac so I don't have it
so I press cancel but if you compare our
Emacs on the Mac or Linux you press
Enter or go to the source code so when I
was on lean oxide you know I have that
you then you can look at C source code
it doesn't interest me too much because
I don't code in C so that you know that
this just doesn't do anything for you
for me but that's that's that's the
thing that's that's what this is about
assha is lovely yes good morning Emily
Faust P P says what what what is that
two garnishes what what language German
okay ma TC says don't care about you
need status would settle for competence
so I have useful computation information
data analysis skills in the academic
world where I live
seen these women Emacs used comedy you
know I don't think you know these days
it's not necessarily to learn Emacs
ahead yeah I'm sorry too Emacs fans you
know this is kind of unconventional
opinion at least some and Emacs people
but outside of Emacs people you know if
you look at computer scientist prominent
computer scientists researchers
academics in artificial intelligence
field vast majority of them are not
using Emacs you don't know nothing about
Emacs okay that that's a fact so you
don't have to know Emacs to you know -
oh I need to you know what you don't
need to you know you can use Visual
Studio code so mouse versus oh my god
yeah you know I'm under pressure to
continue to get on to the topic let's
see what ok close that no no JavaScript
today then how long I've been talking 50
minutes the night is young we have 10
more minutes we're gonna okay we're
gonna do we gonna not not do it like 20
hours today we cannot get on that pretty
soon so hold on a second let me show you
what apps I wanna show you here the
window but
let's go back to shell so I'm here
showing actually I'm showing what way is
like did I close it shell ok shell okay
there so we got my three shells here a
shell on top shell at bottom you know
it's funny
Emacs called inferior shell I never
figured out exactly what it exactly
means you know I've read it about I read
read about it for 20 years but never
stick the Emacs cos Emacs like inferior
shells it doesn't really have you know
technical solid technical definition
anyway that's that's kind of the culture
of Emacs of you know 1980s in 1990 90s
anyway I have three shells here let's
try to run VIN let's see what happens
okay first of all let's try to do it in
a shell then you see it's it looks like
that
I think it's screwed okay let's try J
you know the hjkl let's move the cursor
okay it works well HJ k yeah so I'm a
ball rack wait I'm envoy Iraq wait wait
I'm among sucked fried cheese which is
modo so everything is totally screwed up
you know because I'm a flat I'm using
sawfly keys which is a modal key binding
Emacs then they they are me vim which is
moto2 so I'll be extremely confused
which one is actually working now okay
this is sapphire keys though okay I need
to switch to insert mode then now I mean
him okay now
JK okay Jay okay I guess I mean so MA
right now actually is doing stuff like
he's in Selma so anyway so here's V
indicia so let's please let me kill it
did it work
no okay I guess I'm stuck here forever
yeah I don't think I can get out because
I mean so Frankie's I don't you know if
I press escape my escape key is remapped
to control G so it's not actually I
don't even have a scape key to properly
exit in Samadhi in vim so oh I have to
know all right so I can do just kill the
buffer queue it yes okay that's it
so now in in shell that's to VIN well
that's probably something any because I
to properly demonstrate this I need to
start Emacs from scratch you know
without my sapphire key stuff so Emacs
Emacs then no Q okay so no Knox are in
it so in this window we can we can
demonstrate the name vim in shell but
anyway my point is I was going just
going to say if you want to run them or
Emacs inside a shell in Emacs you can do
that in in the term command but you
cannot do that in Asia or the shell
command that's that's what I want to say
cured yes and kill the terminal yes
close the window and close the buffer we
don't need it and copy the path go back
to talk show sometime sure what is that
sorry max open up TD that excit ml mod
okay good good back to adoption
and let's talk about mouse versus mouse
versus trackball well what about it so
so I've been using trackball for like
five years now actually I don't write
use it right now but I have used it for
four years I so
oh yeah control and control that is also
escape but however I don't think you
walk because once you remap Escape key
it will also be map that you see because
it's a long story
you know for example let me try it let
me show you okay my Escape key so I'm
going to let me turn on this key I don't
know sometimes it doesn't work so you
can see my key on the Lord lower left
window well you don't see it because my
video is hiding it yeah
okay so now you can see it okay so ctrl
n for example so if I press escape okay
so if I press escape okay there it is I
press escape but however in Emacs you
are actually you see it's actually ctrl
G let me do it again okay so I'm gonna
press escape escape you see it says ctrl
G meanwhile you can see the actual key I
type this escape because because I'm
using carabiner and well in this case is
because Emacs I have in Emacs the escape
is remap to control G okay now now let's
press
let's press control left square bracket
let's see what happens okay
I mean while I watch the left window
let's see so control left
kid I'm Canisius keyboard so it's gonna
be weird so let's see so I press it you
can see on the lower left corner I
pressed it oh okay so it's escaped it
still works okay so you see on the mini
buffer at the bottom you can see escape
okay so let's so mouse mouse versus
trackball so what about so the first
question is you know which one is better
so every you know everyone wants to know
that it depends okay so but in general
without any color you know without any
qualifications I would say Mouse is just
better in general okay okay so I about
this topic you know I need to send my
mood to talk about this topic because
like what to what to talk about any like
okay any specific any specific questions
like here's your life raft Alan what we
studio has both Emacs Winky bunny know
was gone for a couple of minutes why I
saw him about
ha studio okay ha studio I guess so I
hope utiful people any specific
questions about tracker vs. Mouse you
know hey I need to set my mood to talk
about this that's why because I need to
some kind of lead so anyway I've been
using trackball for four years I wanted
to use trackball for like 20 years since
1992 when I first have my eyes set on
track ball so you can see here is a
bunch of track balls and I really want
to they are fascinating because I think
I like them better
I always think so here's yeah so here's
a story of what I think I always thought
that trackball is better because because
it's more intuitive and it's small I
believed it's more efficient okay I
believe this more efficient and so so I
always wanted a trackball
since 1992 but you know I've tried in
stores but I have actually never really
have one to to have real life you know
true experience until until about six
years ago 2004 so so in 2004 so let me
show you my trackball history so until I
have so I got I got track boss I got you
know I you know I I I got this one it's
like $30 cheap so I got this one it's
pretty good okay it's pretty good
but today don't buy this one today it's
no good you know you go to my tracker
website just such folks sorry trackball
my name then you will find my
recommendations okay
my record at work because what does my
record you know how do I know which is
good which is bad if I don't have them
well because I read all reviews on each
one of them how
rates of reviews I that's that's what I
do I go to Amazon read all reviews of
for example of a trackball I want to
write about and then I go through the
read a trackball with it has a trackball
forum okay our trackball so you can see
you know those people notes they are
trackball phonetics talking about it so
I read you know terms of review says
that's why that's how I get my opinions
so anyway so my trackball I had this one
and I also had this one actually this is
my first one I still have them okay I
don't use them right now and if you are
going to buy one don't buy it
neither one of these two okay bye you
know I have my recommendations but you
know if you want big posed by this three
one one of these or if you prefer small
balls or thumb balls by you know one of
these four if you want the cheapest one
just get this one okay Kensington orbit
now for trackball unlike much you know
track board design are there's many
varieties there's no for example for
Mouse is pretty much every Mouse are the
same you know they have three buttons
you know two buttons on top then you
have some buttons pretty much every
master same but the trackball the design
is very lady for significant country so
there is no universal agreement as to
which is the best trackball okay like
I'd read all the reviews of the past at
least 15 year or 20 years you could say
I read more than more than 20 years I
read trackball reviews since 1992 back
then you don't have Wikipedia you don't
have internet you go you there's a Mac
world magazine
Mac Word and Mac user magazine I was a
Mac user back then so I bet every every
issue every month issues I read almost
every page Mac Mac uses Mac and Mac word
those are magazines you can search for
we Wikipedia Mac what Mac user
you can see magazines okay so you need
to type magazine actually you need to go
to a browser with JavaScript on so you
can actually those are magazines okay of
course they don't have printed version
anymore
but and you have Wikipedia articles so
you know you can see actually you want
to show covers so anyway I read you know
so this is the example I had actually
covers okay so I read all of them so I
read about trackball review since since
1992 so anyway so what you want is so
what we'll be talking about we were
talking about okay hold on a second so
yeah there's no universal agreement
about which is the best trackball you
but basically these are you know people
these are best ones and also okay for
track balls okay I'm jumping around very
many different topics let me go back to
mother histories
how I use oh so so I started to
use one about five years ago and I use
it everyday and so now I have good idea
whether it's better or worse and their
Mouse it depends on you for example if
you want typically trackball users are
those people who wants to avoid
repetitive strain injury but that's not
a whole street story because for four
miles you have word minimum vertical
mouse today and even if you don't you
know you have many vertical mouse and
even if you don't use vertical mouse the
reason you have problem with mouse
possibly
because your posture I mean the way you
use Mouse is not correct things like
that for example my recommendation is
not you know don't always hold your
mouse like just nudge it you know try
not to touch it at all
use finger use crow you know use
fingertip grabbing the mouse
okay I'm rambling nowhere so any
comments let's see the comments because
I'm remembering over I'm not sure what
to go I mean the question is which ones
so most people use trap trap or because
they are trying to avoid RSI however
they are also people who use trackball
and they got RSI so it's a complex issue
there's no easy answer okay and also the
the the the problem I find with
trackball is that you do have to clean
them even like once a month I mean even
it doesn't take much you just pop out
the ball so it takes you know 10 seconds
to create you pop up pop out the ball
you just rub it with toilet paper or
some tissue then you have to do that
kind of every month otherwise the ball
won't won't go as smoothly you know it
you know it won't go as smoothly so
that's the thing on the mouse you never
especially like today laser mouse or
optical mouse you never have to do that
so that is actually a considerable
advantage of mouse because I mean even
you only have to do it once once a month
it's I mean in modern society in you
know first word this is a first world
problem you know oh my god it's a pain
it's a pain I can't find a parking lot
same thing with the trackball even you
only need to create once a month but
still you think rather I'd rather not I
don't want to so so anyway so and and
also there's a question like gamers okay
for example if you play first-person
shooter the
mouse is absolutely better okay for that
purpose first-person-shooter Mouse is
absolutely more efficient meaning it's
faster to get where you want to faster
to turn fastening everything anyway
that's that's another big black hole
topic because when it comes through
cameras then they talk about
acceleration like oh you need to turn
off acceleration and so that's another
topic I can talk for 30 minutes and most
most of the gameís beliefs such as
turning off acceleration is crap okay
they are the they don't know what they
talking about you know some of the
cameras they are their programmers and
they are real nerds
they have written driver software to for
their Mouse such that you know on
YouTube you can you can watch it such
that you know they created created a
mouse driver such that they try to Excel
accelerating in a linear way you know it
gets very kind of complicated but anyway
if you ask my opinion is that if you are
playing first-person shooter games just
use a mouse so a mouse is more efficient
of course there are some different
opinions they are certain let me show
you some interesting pictures there are
certain trackball users who insist that
chapo is superior their Mouse for
first-person shooter games for example
let me show you some of the you know
there here is some of the device and
this one is still coming okay this one
this one is in Kickstarter for like
three four years and is still coming so
you have trackball controllers this one
exists apple peeping like 20 years ago
it failed in the market and the other
ones are people custom made you know
these custom made devices okay they try
to kick-start I think it also failed
okay
and this one is do-it-yourself this guy
so if you want to do it you can do it
and this one this one is something you
can buy it's on the market you can buy
I'm not I'm not sure it's still made but
you can buy I think currently
unavailable okay yeah it's dead and this
one I forgot what's a story in 2006 okay
I forgot what's the story of this one
and this one is a prototype from the
steam valve they also failed so they
don't end up with this okay touch fat
they end up with this as the final
product which you can buy by the way bye
bye phone my website ok bye bye phone my
website so let me copy the website and
show it what's okay
and so ain't any way I rambled a lot
over the place
let me read the comments then so many
hello beautiful people and M x11 can cut
and paste with mouse what is that a
question or what's your favorite track
ball so if I am going to buy a new one I
know what I want okay it's not huge Eric
it'll come huge it's not consent an
expert it's not slime Brett played they
all have problems okay if I'm going to
buy your mouse it's probably a trap oh
it's probably gonna be this one this
came out two years ago it's either this
one a simple Logitech MX ago or this one
ever come deft pro okay okay either that
one so logic Logitech MX or oh go deft
pro or the previous version of deft Pro
which is previous version of that is
here this one so if I'm going to blow up
our trap I think I you know I'm easy to
buy a trackball because I'm obsessive
you know I read about it about this
everyday yeah you know so I so yeah if
I'm gonna buy a new ones I think
probably Logitech MX because it's you
know I like I can tell you which what
are the problems for each one of them
the the Ella come deft pro the problem
is the function keys you see this here F
1 F 2 and F no not way which one left
click right click wait but anyway they
they you know the problem with the deft
pro they are made they're from Japan
they are made in Japan ok so they came
from Japan the
have custom driver so if you don't
install the custom driver some of your
button you will not walk okay and so
that's the thing that's the main thing
about this I forgot what's this
which button exactly this one this
anyway some of them custom buttons will
be dead so this is a particular problem
if you are going to use this on Linux
because typically their driver I'm not
sure for this one yeah like I forgot you
can check maybe I have information here
like if so on Linux if they don't have
Drive typically they don't have driver
for Linux so so if you buy this then
you're gonna have three dead buttons
that's no good you know and so that's a
problem with the error come death row
now Logitech they are round about they
are in general pretty good so works on
Mac on Windows on Linux and Wireless and
all the buttons work out of the box at
least with the default features for
example these two will be forward
backward in browser and and this one
yeah you know it's just it's what
workout works you know it's just your
generic pretty good ones and wireless
and rechargeable I think and for example
the problem with the Kensington big
memory has this one you know I have a
quick question for him Emily for this
one the there's a well-known problem is
that the wheel is very scratchy like if
you try to learn it makes ugly very
annoying sound I don't remember I have a
video here somewhere but you know if you
go to the track Boehner's website there
are people trying to fix it they take it
apart I show you how to do it you know
it makes this very
scratchy noise like you know these kind
of things like if you never heard of it
you you may not notice but once you know
if you have this device every time you
use it it gets into your bread it's like
the Cherry MX brown key switch I'm using
okay cherry I'm extra like before I know
about the details about the keyboard
hackers they talk about key you know key
switches I don't notice okay it's just
mechanical keyboard okay it's just good
but now I read a lot you know so you
know I know the Cherry MX brown every
time I press the key I can feel the
Scratchy
you know knowing that it's like
scratching my heart so you don't want to
know too much about these details so I
don't think it's fixed Emily yeah am i
right and the slim blade also I have a
problem you know when you buy a prop as
trackball you want one with a some kind
of a mechanism physical mechanism to as
a mask wheel okay so you want either the
wheel like that the best wheel on a on a
chapeau is this one okay this one you
want the best wheel anywhere then get
this one okay that's a that wheel is
like mouse wheel you you you treat you
twist it okay and and in these days
almost all trackball cartwheels you know
like the mouse wheel this one for
example on the side so the slim blade
the profile and everything is good you
only got four buttons which is not much
but you know trackballs usually don't
come with too many buttons but but then
it's got a problem of no way oh no no
mouse wheel instead you what you do is
you roll the ball so they have the
mechanism that you twist the ball like
that then it's it's it's like mosquée or
score
now okay and that's no good I don't want
to do these special hack thing that's in
general no good okay then you have you
know trackball phonetics for example
they are using this one they tell you to
program the trackball so that you hold
this button down then the trackball
becomes mouse wheel that's no good you
don't you don't want to do anything with
holding code then you know that that's
the idiocy okay that that's that's if
you have repetitive strain injury that's
what you're trying to avoid never hold
any control option okay never do
that and and and people are trying to
now they are like evolving into the
trackball you like you hold this one
this is you hold this one and they hold
that one then you rotate the ball
idiocy you know some nerd do
that like Linux people have seen that a
lot of them they tell you oh I just buy
this one oh if you want to swirl then
you just install this you know Linux
code and then you hold this and hold
that they do this this this is idiocy
and so similarly this twisting is no
good okay you don't want you don't want
that twisting and anyway that continual
comments so I think that's it for today
I talked too long now one hour and
twenty minutes okay what's what led to
the into intuition that trackballs are
more efficient I am Not sure I don't
know most people you know over the past
30 years who insists on trackball
typically there are people who do CAD or
Photoshop yeah especially in the 1990s
mostly it's awful this one okay let me
show you the history of Kensington do I
have history of canceling here history
history of Kensington
okay so it's not here you need to go to
track bow history at the bottom then you
can see the wondrous history of track
boss okay so then the Kensington is one
of the it's a most famous one of the
earliest most famous track ball it looks
like that it's the elite device for Mac
uses like if you are you using a Mac you
already elite but then if you are using
this you are the elite of the elite okay
this this is the the has the elite
status for from 1990s to up to I would
say 2005 this one it looks like that
Kensington expert Mouse so its own Mac
user and Mac word magazine every every
every month advertisement and also
reduced you know it's considered the
best okay and it's all stip eclis used
by Photoshop users you know in this is
the beginning of desktop publishing
where you you print newspapers or
magazines from your Mac you edit you
know the you have croc Express you have
Photoshop you have free hand you have
illustrator to do all the design layout
then you print them you know Mac users
Mac what data you know desktop
publishing then you have laser printers
it didn't come to PC and you know Mac is
the pioneer for everything especially in
the 1990s usually after 5 years or 10
years then it comes to pc if becomes a
popular pc so anyway so this is the
granddaddy of the elite trackball and
most people are using you know so on the
mac usually it's especially in the 1990s
its artistic people creative people
using Mac so Photoshop Illustrator
freehand it all Street the trader and
free hand they are vector graphics they
are like of you Linux people would call
Inkscape
okay those are there so and you have
quite a lot others on the Mac you know
you have Mathematica for example
originally first version is on the Mac
you have Mac version first then Windows
and this applies to photoshop or all the
other software in fact then you have
painter you have fractal which today
becomes you know this is quite long
history but anyway or basically all
drawing software and CAD software almost
so they begin on a Mac they thrive on
the Mac in the 1990s early nineteen like
I would say 1990 to 1995 at least at
least then eventually today they all
moved to the their home is Windows they
have wind windows their primary platform
they have window version first the the
movement began in let's say 2000 okay by
2000 slots of these they're the primary
platform easel or Windows by then so
anyway creative people yeah and another
lots of use of choco is cat uses you
know AutoCAD you know creating 3d ads
and you know things like that
digital creative artist you know today
you have lots of those people would edit
videos who create memes and stuff and
also for advertisement so anyway so wait
am I going so let's read the comments
yeah so I guess those people who who who
drove the idea that trackball is more
precise because when you want to rotate
3d art object then track boys better
okay so I remember cuz I a special
setting for Mouse it auto click once
detecting Kusa yeah right now you know I
have auto quick as usual oh look Auto
quick is fantastic okay because I don't
click I use the mouse anywhere it does a
quick for me
so this is also grant this is how I use
the mouse okay this is now this
advertisement is fantastic okay let's
see you see I don't click okay so this
this advertisement is fantastic I
remember seeing this in 1992 also
Logitech they created this mouse and
they are marking this one
what which one is this I think it's
Kensington X but I they are marking this
one I forgot what's the name wait
they are marking anyway they are they I
think this is a name you know they are
marking this one so that's a trackball
history so I think that's it for today
so Kathy says yeah this so I have auto
auto click if you want that you go
through my keyboard block you go to the
software then you can see Linux how to
do that and Mac how to do that such
folks are the Hoover click oh sorry auto
click you'll find it okay so why is it
efficient so so so what is better for
you on trackball compared to month's
track tranquil what is you know I since
I use auto click track bow is great for
that
I wish I have trampled to plug-in but I
kind of put them away because they've
been sitting here for long for 2 years
and I thought I'm just gonna choose for
the name away because you see I want so
I so because the trackball I have don't
buy this ok this this is designed this
is 20 years old for some reason this one
is tremendously popular so they still
make it so they still sell it but it's
it's no good because it's you know it's
very slow on a Mac you have exact super
slow and you know today you have lots of
better ones
so that's the two I have and you know
it's no good and another thing with
track before you for example this one
this one is got the touch ring
okay no good touch ring so you move your
you know touch sensitive ring you put
your fingers there you rotate it they it
function as a scroll wheel it's not good
okay so just listen to me by what I
recommend don't buy it don't buy
whatever I don't recommend you'll save
money and time okay no guarantee though
I don't guarantee nothing
so Mouse versus trackball I will Co use
both yes you know either one but if you
force me to pick just one not the other
then it will be trap oh I mean it would
be Mouse okay another thing with trap
whoa is that you don't have much choices
like Mouse you have thousands gaming
choices with different buttons you know
features with trackball you are stuck
you can't you have quite a few now but
you very much stuck because you don't
have much but as you know if you like
this one big you know good one you only
have four buttons four buttons this one
this one got more buttons but three of
them three of them don't work if you
don't install their driver then the
others are on the side you know I don't
want this I don't I prefer you know the
top so your choices are limited that's a
problem you know and this one I really
like but you only got two buttons you
know that we always fantastic but you
only got two buttons so that's so you
limited choice is a problem with the
trackball so if you forced me to make a
choice I I'll go with the mouse you know
I yeah what are the properties you are
appreciate on a trap or how you would
choose the new one okay yeah I thought I
talked about that many before so the
other thing is
what for let me show you one more thing
okay and that's it for today one more
thing is when you want a trackball
you want that you want one that can spin
okay I need to go to a browser that can
show JavaScript
sorry trackball you want one that can
spin I want I love that but most of them
don't so you go to my trackball page
then you go to economic mouse trackball
versus Mouse
yeah you can read that page in detail so
I talked about details of how to look
for a trackball things like that but I
want to show you one of the property I
want very much is trackball such that
the ball can spin like you can just
press it it will spin forever but very
few trap or does that so that page is
this you can actually see a video they
have this prototype that spins forever
but never made never became reality
okay anyways I think that's it so you
you know you go to the my website and
you watch so there it is that's means
and also these spins okay this this one
spins so this page you can see all the
videos of oops go back on this page you
can see all the videos of where I show
how much they spin you know someone has
put video so this one spins but this one
is hard to buy and it's like $300 this
one also spins I think because they have
ball bearings so you have a video that
shows the spinning of that thing then
then this one also spins I think
somewhat this guy showed it not too
clearly but but basically at least don't
spin but you know anyway that's it for
today so that's it let me just read a
comment we shut down one minute so it
ends up by talking a lot about track
balls track point track point I don't I
don't like it all because yeah well
that's a loan that's gonna be your loan
story because track point
track track both track ball and mouse
they have this poverty this poverty is I
would call that I'm not sure there is a
proper name but I would call it
instantaneous variable axilla variable
speed acceleration instantaneous
velocity change which is a same reason
you know if you ask Emma's you know
first-person shooter scammers they can
tell you they want they want a they
don't want joystick they want the mouse
because mouse you have instantly you you
can control your speed at every moment
in time meanwhile with the joystick you
cannot because you you know you we don't
have that property so in the same reason
for the same reason I don't like the the
TrackPoint at all I can send video if
some tomorrow you want to hear it oh
yeah we are Emily so yeah send us make a
video of that it's that weird the
Kensington mouse trackball but bye guys
do you have to I still have the mag
magazine no your Apple track trackball
track pad apples track pant I think
that's interesting but I don't think I
like to rub my fingers on the thing I
think I prefer mouse and trackball then
trackpad
okay bye good bye guys