good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
today we are going to do
live comparison of different programming
languages
python
perl
powershell
wufram language and emaclis and golan
battle royale
to see which language is the fastest in
doing find and replace of
of 2000 files in your directory
okay so we compare image lisp wolfram
language
golan power xiao pythong
and pearl
uh yes yeah so um
so today's talk show so let's just get
to it okay let's begin the technical
session today is purely technical okay
good morning david dude and luis
alright so
so i have the link so i have link
prepared here so let me open them and
show you okay
so um
powershell and wufang language so i have
written them before like i you know i
did several videos about find replays
it's my obsession so
here is find replace code in a directory
for python and here is using regular
expression here's a code which i use
actually every week for the past 10
years
then here's golan golan version find
replace and each one of them each one of
this code is written in the most
efficient way by the expert
by me
so go land and then
go line find replace script wait he said
okay so one version is just find grep
you know unique script the other version
is find and replace
so then you have the pearl which is my
earliest version written in 2000 year
2000 okay so year so there's a date year
2000 february
this is a pro version and
then you have emac this version find
replace okay emac so you know you can
you can find each one of these you can
use the code you know it's all on my
website free and
and the most important
oh then then there's powershell friendly
place okay powershell the most fantastic
wonderful shell is going to replace
splash
in five years or ten
and then there's wufam language the
the mathematics oriented language
shortest code by the way shortest code
the most powerful the most expressive
language by a magnitude of them all
wufang language so we wrote we actually
coded this uh two days ago or something
this week in my video i talked about so
let's so first of all let's create let's
create a directory with you know about 2
000 files so for that you go to emac
this my emac list
website
the emacs menu open it
so you can see emac this menu
uh there are you can see
1000 files okay turn on global highlight
mod so you can see my cursor where my
cursor is so 1000 files for the emac
list manual then for emacs manual there
are
750 files okay so we are going to copy
these directories so that we can um
uh you know do find replace uh using
these files so let's see where i want to
go so
okay go to cassardi info
and
okay
move
not move copy
okay copy recursively yes
okay copy done
so
and by the way on the pink window is all
my emacs keystrokes in command course
the command name and keystroke you can
see as i type okay so here we copy it we
want to rename it let's rename it xx
okay xx is my convention for
files or directories that's temporary
you know short so now we got the
directory now close it copy the file
path three key strokes you can see
the keystrokes is that dd keys right
here thumb key dd ci
three key strokes to copy file path
that's my command
okay copy file path close it close it
close it close it
now uh what is this emax block close it
back to emacs close it
now let's put
uh the directory up here okay and let's
put the directory here show in browser
so we have the directory here so okay
let's begin so
so we need to time it okay so let's
begin the journey
we are going to run the script in each
one of these on this directory do some
find replace and we need to time it so
how do we begin this um
let's see
okay should we do
just find first or find and replace
together
[Music]
okay because if you do find replays then
that means
uh um let's
okay this is just to find together okay
that's i mean i i i want to i don't want
to be stuck thinking about things you
know because i'm doing live video
so
hola so comments and questions okay post
it comments and questions so let's do
uh so
so let's go to um
let's go to this directory so this is
our
directory of files
okay
so
open it
okay those are the bunch of files we
want to find replace
then we okay so
do we are we going to do grep
or
uh find and replace because when you do
find and replace that also involves
writing to file
let's let's do uh
okay let's go to yeah let's do just
scrap okay let's just do grab first
let's see which language is the fastest
okay so first of all i want to go to
my golan script okay so you are looking
at my golan script this script is 250
lines of code you know
it's spacey you know golan and you know
many of these languages they are called
their standard code formatting is spacey
you know spaced out you know for example
this this gotta be on online by itself
then this gotta be online on itself
instead
you know instead of for example make a
backup instead of let me show you
uh if you put a semicolon then you can
compact these lines you know then
instead of one line like that
you know so you got more lines of code
you know this project is one million
lines of a code
but if you actually reformat it in a
functional programming way
it's just ten thousand
lines of code you know reduce reduction
by ten if you and if you use wufam
language it's one lines of code
something like that okay so anyway so
this is scolan
okay so let's let's begin to code it
copy the file path wait um
wait copy the file path here actually
this one
okay so this is uh this is the
goal line version for grep okay so input
directory that okay
then
then the file name extension okay we
want or html files do you have any
special directories you want to skip no
okay well except git okay we don't have
git there so then
then do you want a special list of files
you want to grab not just whole
directory no we don't have a special
list okay so now
now the graph string okay now what so
what do you want to grab here okay so
let's see
we want to find some
um
you know we want to find a word that's
somewhat common okay
so let me just call my emacs command
emac this right now you are saying emac
this find and replace okay there's the
result so you have all these occurrences
uh
occurrences what string shrink okay
expand
right you cannot see the window so well
so let's move it here
so you just move the cursor you can see
all the occurrences okay let's let's
let's use the word command let's see how
many
uh occurrences are there
okay there is a lot of
um
occurrences for the word command
okay so what if you say comments
okay let's try that word uh let's i mean
let's not use let's let's try to find
okay now let's back to golan now the
the word the string you want to
grab is these commands okay and no
regular expression so this is you know
you
this is this quotes out regular
expression so you just want to find the
plain text command okay
so and all these are garbage actually
you know all these are garbage
you know this is uh these are my past
find and replace so let's remove it
uh
let's just
remove them okay i don't need them
so anyway so this is my golan script you
can see
this is the find string then this is
about number let me just run it okay let
me show it run it
and we need to time it okay that's [ __ ]
we need to time time it okay you know i
have rsi repetitive strain injury like
right now right here it hurts okay it's
done
so
it's done and now let's
turn them into
sci-fi mods so you have the syntax
highlighting and you can jump to you
know you can jump to any one of these
and press enter it will open
the file you can see that word you know
the that's the occurrence
so
how do we do this we actually need to
time it
but before we time it let's just run
let's just see how fast um
let's just see let's just get a sense
okay join it
done okay now this is go land now let's
go to emacs
emax
okay
run it
okay so so emac this okay right now i'm
going to try to do
uh grep
using the emac list okay so it's already
a command so i don't have to go to the
script
well you can you can look at the script
by
let me show you the source code so
here's a package cause i
dot el you open it
and here is the command you see xr find
text that's uh you know lisp
so it does exactly the same thing go
through the directories and find the
file so let me just run it okay so close
that so
right
search string commands yes in this
directory yes
now uh what what's the file extension
okay dot html yes okay it's also
instantaneous you can see
wait
wait do they have
so
the output is 23 000 lines
okay
so let's write let's go back to the
golan version run it
the output is
um
15 000 lines and the last one is
that let's compare okay you see they
match
so the last file is
emacs index.html
then the file before is
yes or no prompts okay let's not let's
go back to the goal line version you see
yes or no prompts
okay same result but um
but they print slightly differently
because
um
[Music]
so why is the emax much more number of
lines uh
you know so
right
so you see this file xref
commands
has six occurrences you can see there
now let's go to the golan version
uh
where is it
okay xref let's see
xref search for it
okay there it is
ah there's a incompatibility
you see this file
emacs xref commands
according to golan there are three
occurrences
three occurrences and they are here
here here
now according to the
e-mag this version this same file
let's see
one two three four oh i see the
difference so you see the e-max version
actually
uh case insensitive
you see that's why the imax version has
lots of results so let's do the e-max
again with case sensitivity turned on
okay search for commands in this
directory file path okay so let's do it
again ctrl u
then press the key
then search for commands in this
directory file path
fixed case search
no
print surrounding text yes
okay now
now let's search for x
ref dash commands
what
wait it's still
it's still returning the capital letters
yeah what it's a bug
there is a bug okay
wait okay so let's go to the goal line
version okay we got we got the
big screw up let's
i'm doing things you don't know what i'm
doing but
god this this is
so painful
this matching lines
and this file does this does not even
occur what's going on okay
now i'm introducing doubt to my scripts
i was going to show something else
comparing the speeds but now i'm kind of
stuck in the
president berg you know i'm pretty sure
there's no bug okay i mean
well there's probably a book about the
capital case version but it shouldn't
um but what are we doing okay so we kind
of um
german says do you have used parallelism
function with wufam language no actually
i haven't used it
my guess is scotland is probably the
fastest okay that's the most common word
okay so
ah this is a bad beginning so our goal
is actually to benchmark but right now
we run into this issue of case
sensitivity and it appears in the e-max
version we have
a minor bug
okay case sensitivity is
ignored okay let's let me okay so let me
call this command okay so this command
is called repeat complex command what it
will do is that it will call the last
emac emax command you code
but however without answering all the
prompts okay let me show you okay so
let's let's do that so you can see
uh let's do that so you can see in a in
the mini buffer let me let me go to it
okay this one okay so you can see
suffering text okay let's copy it
now let's open a new buffer wait let's
open a new buffer split the window and
paste it here so you can see
um
and let's make it multiple lines so you
can see
this is the command the emac this
version we just called find command so
you want to find the word commands
and and in this directory and this is
the file name extension filter and neo
means
not case sensitive okay so
actually so let's look at the code okay
it's what's going on
uh
so describe function okay then jump to
the source code okay here's the source
code
software text search directory
input directory search string info
directory path regular expression
fixed case okay so
so let's narrow to
this function and search for the fixed
case
why is it not
respecting my fixed case search
okay so actually
okay so fixed
fist
let's see
fixed case search
so
if it's true
then
case fault search should be set to false
okay
then let's look at this block okay maybe
maybe i just
you know i typed it wrong let's try
again okay
so let's try
all right who is the
where is the directory
yeah
okay
where is the directory let's go to talk
show okay let's open this directory
again
let's
do the find again show the pink window
do the find
okay
we want to search for commands
in this directory html files okay wait
you need to
get emacs to ask
parameters so you press ctrl u first
then call the command okay
search for commands in this directory
html files
fixed case in search
yes
print surrounding text yes
okay
now go to the bottom so you have 13 000
lines of output
uh
okay then there it is that's the file
yes
oh that seems correct so
do we have any
so if you see any occurrence of commands
that's capitalized that means it's wrong
so
these matching lines
let's type let's these matching lines to
see if there's any occurrence of command
let's wait
copy that list matching lines
capitalize commands
okay i know what's going on you see
uh you see
yeah it didn't it didn't you see all
these occurrences there's no capitalized
version but however the context you see
some of the
you know the before and after
of the occurrence
those parts com contains the capital
commands
because let's let's do this again okay
so let me show you what's going on so
you know it's a bunch of emac these tips
so i copy the whole buffer copy the
whole buffer
new buffer
paste it okay now
now
now let's go to you see any occurrences
will have this this uh bracket around it
you can see
that bracket is called
left square bracket with under bar so
you can see that's a unicode magic okay
so any occurrences will have that
bracket around it so now all we have to
do is now we
copy that part and
find and replace
that bracket
by
space i mean a new line then that
bracket do it
everything okay so now you see now
shrink you can see
any such bracket occurrences will have
let's let me show you we'll have a you
will buy a line by itself okay you see
now let's do the same let's do the same
add a new line to the end of bracket
okay to the top
find and replace that
that that
everything okay so now you can see
every occurrences of the command the
found the occurred word is by the by a
line itself now all you have to do is
delete the matching lines okay
so
so delete
keep lines containing okay delete
everything that's not just that line do
it
so you can see
now the whole buffer is just now i
scroll down the whole buffer is just the
occurrences the words okay
and now all we have to do is sort it
let's sort the whole thing
okay select all sort
now it's sorted
now the first line and the last line is
the same thing that means
the whole buffer is just that
the whole occurrences is just that so
there's no occurrences of capital
you know command so that means it's good
there's no bug the
emac this
fight
package is fantastic
okay
so now
so another way to do this is now you can
remove duplicate so okay so that command
the key is let me show you okay
[Music]
let's see
uh clear rectangle remove duplicate i
forgot rick
uh
i forgot what's the keystroke or command
names but the command name contains the
word duplicate so let's search for it
d-u-p-d-u-p-d-d
[Music]
duplicate lines okay so in stuff like
keys for our keyboard let's
delete t y okay let's do it delete i
mean space t y
okay
well because
let's do the from the beginning space t
y okay
so that means okay now close it
now we have confirmed all the currencies
uh without capital letters another way
to do it is for example let's
close it let's do it again so ctrl u
for universal argument you can see it in
a ping window here universal argument
you see
so that's when you want to call emacs
command and you want to
give it uh options when if if the
command supports it so let's do it again
control u
then press the key to call casa fine
okay
do it okay what what string you want to
find the string i want to find is
command okay commands
okay in this directory yes
and the file path regular expression.h
yes
fixed case in search yes
print surrounding text
no
fantastic
now you can see we don't have the
garbage so it shows you know the all the
files
it occurs and how many occurrences for
example on this file it's three now
let's search for
now in this window you see this window
is go lens result so let's search for
the
for this file xref commands okay so
let's search for x
ref
there it is three occurrences
three occurrences they agree they concur
fantastic now let's go land
okay now close it okay this is scolan
go land versus
versus emac this okay wait
versus this emac this package now expand
uh wait
get out of the narrow to region so now
you can see the whole file so this is
the emax version you know the emax file
is
700 lines because it it contains several
different commands grab
you know find and find replace and and
few others that's why it's 700 lines but
just for find replace that would be
so this command copy new buffer paste
okay 30 40 lines of code 40 let's go to
xa emac be smart
okay so 40
lines of code you know
compared to the golan
192. it's you know it's not comparable
that way because then in emac this then
you have also have
kind of the documentation and some of
the you know predefined variables and
stuff uh not here but
here for example the prefix the brackets
and so on
so anyway we kind of digressed
so we have looked at the golan code for
find a string in in a directory and we
also looked at this and looks like their
speech
and you know so we look at their source
code but however what we need to do is
to
benchmark
now how do you do that um
well you can for example in the emac
this case
let's let me show let me let me try to
do it okay
so if you want to benchmark the emac
this code all you have to do is just run
this code right
you see if i run it
you know it here's the result close it
run it again you see result you see i
just call the command
evaluates you know this is one of the
way to run this code you know instead of
instead of you know
instead of you know calling a command
and answering each prompt again i can
just
do it you see so now
if i want to benchmark this um
[Music]
there's a timing you know this is
so to benchmark each of the programming
language there are several ways to do it
one way is you is that you add the
timing code in each of the language for
example in emac this
do we have a um wait let's go to emac
this mod
sorry might be smart then try completion
do you have some kind of timing function
um
i don't think so building
maybe there is i don't know
so you can
so the point is that you can add a
timing function in each one of your
languages or
another way is that you dive into shell
and
in bash for example you have
time function
that will show you how long does the
script
take to run something
i believe that that is called time i i
forgot but
but in the but in powershell actually i
don't know
wait this this is uh this is a microsoft
terminal bug
okay so
tim
i m
yeah so in microsoft powershell i'm not
sure what is the command to measure
timing
but even that doesn't apply to me
because
because my script is designed
to not be running a terminal because i
don't like it you know
like typically when you have a find
replace for example grip okay well not
well for example
i don't have grab here gcm get command
grip
you know i don't have the unix script
installed because on windows since i
started to
you know i thought i need grip and all
that but actually i don't since i
learned powershell you don't need the
unix crap
so
i don't have grep installed so
okay but my point here is that typically
when you write a find replay script you
know most people they write a terminal
command command line for example like
sub find
then
something
you know that's what you do you give
option okay like
find string okay something like that
that i don't like that because there's
lots of problems with this user
interface this unix idiocy
why because suppose suppose you want to
find this block of code
multiple lines
how you gonna do it this way it's very
hard so rather the more efficient ways
you just open up a editor for example
let's close it okay so so now let's say
i want to do fine replace so watch what
i do okay show the pink window so
i want to
do find replays by calling the
golan
script okay so i press a key
then type
then type f i n there it is
so that's five key strokes five key
strokes i got this
go script open
compared to
compared to casa find string that's more
than five key strokes you know
the terminal version way of running
things then
if i want to
find some multiple lines let's let's see
okay let's do it this way so i i want to
find in the directory
of this block of text okay now i can
just copy it go to the go land script
and
put it right here there it is
there it is now i can run this code okay
you'll have no result because
you know because that you know so if you
have a
so that is one one of the advantage of
having a
full editor interface instead of the
command line
crap the command line idiocy the unix
idiocy the linux idiocy
okay so so for ex so
that's the so you are looking at the
golan script now what if i want the
pythons you know what if i want a python
script okay same thing i i press a key
but right now i don't have a bookmark
but the python code is right here you
see
python3 this is the script
go to go to the bottom 60 lines of code
uh of fine let's run this okay
so actually we haven't um we need to do
benchmark okay but let's run this um
python script okay first of all let's
copy the directory
so go to the python script
okay let's magnets let's turn this okay
so you can see better remove the backup
python 3
i have python 3 version of course i had
python 2 version as well so
here is the input directory so there
then find string is
commands
okay
so file list ignore find string commands
input directory that
directory level recursion level okay 129
is good enough okay let's learn it
python version okay
done what the what the [ __ ]
uh
done in nothing found what is this
fine dot p y three what
print file name when no change force
okay
uh find string commands what
so run it
done that means no change
what
no change in the so what's going on so
wait i haven't used this
python version for a long time so what
uh
so am i actually running python3 let's
check okay so
so i i think i'm running on three okay
so what
got another problem
[Applause]
measuring time in powershell measure
command oh okay fantastic thank you i'm
gonna try that we haven't done
powershell we haven't got into
powershell yet so that's oh but
but you can also do okay
okay i i'll have to try that so
another problem what's going on with my
find python script
uh
find python 3
so replace
what's what's going on with my
python fine script
so you guys python experts can you debug
on the flight tell me where did i
where is my
i haven't used
i haven't used this code for a long time
for like 10 years because
you know because usually you know the
wait
why did i move
what's going on
uh we have a problem
what
wait we we have some kind of problem
this um
this window becomes a ghost something
what's going on
close it
uh e-max bug then you got into an e-max
book i'm not sure what what book that is
so because
i haven't been using this code for a
long time okay so let's
why why is this not running
okay i don't know so let's
let's try the find and replace version
python3 okay
okay let's try that
so
copy the directory
yeah maybe the directory path is
incorrect
the windows file path that yeah that's
probably why
uh and python doesn't
you know python doesn't okay so let's do
slash to backslash
okay maybe that
it's
it's a python problem
not my problem let's run it let's try it
do it
okay syntax arrow eol right yeah so you
need double backslash
okay let's do
slash to double
backslash
okay
run it
yeah
what's going on what
let's look at the directory oh recursive
right
let's try this directory
run it
input is not defined okay so wait you
need to
run it
why is it
not printing anything
yeah what an embarrassment
you run the command and uh it's not
working
so okay so so okay so let's let's
let's copy it let's try the python find
replace command okay the
python find and replace this one should
work because i actually use this
so the other one is probably bit rot
okay so this one
so level one to level four directory
level and you want to find
find
the word commands
and replace it by the word commands okay
so you actually don't
change anything
so
it's
okay backup file name do backup true
uh
so let's go to the top find and replace
multiple pairs home page version 2019
this is actually written
in
2008 or something
uh input directory okay that
the directory level one two four that's
good enough html extension regular
expression filter dot html that's fine
print file name when no change force
backed backup name
and
directory to skip
okay directory to skip
okay let's just run it
find stream
commands replace string commands uh one
two three four then arrow the god python
error python unicode error that this
happens often python unicode error
probably so
unicode encoder error charm
char map codec can encode yeah
problem
uh
you know python is a headache you know
the python unicode thing and it's a
headache
what does the no change option mean
so i mean
so if you are talking about this line
that means if there's no change do you
want to print the file name
uh
no okay so anyway we run it and it's
running into an encoding arrow
of what function so so this file active
key map
this emax file
okay let's open it this emax file what
wait this emacs file is
no [ __ ] python
python [ __ ] it up you see this emax
file was 730
bytes okay now python made it into zero
python deleted
because it's running into a encoding
yeah before you know python is trying to
write to it
so this file contains the word you know
we want to find but python you know it's
a find and replace script so it's trying
to write to it but however it run into
error so it made it to be content zero
so the
the error is
so apparently this file
it contains some characters that's not
in
it's not correctly encoded by utf-8 that
shouldn't be the case
so in position
so here's the characters
u 2 1 d 2 the unicode point in
hexadecimal in position six eight nine
two okay let's jump to the position
let's see if we can
go to char
position six eight nine two
i don't know what's uh what's going on
with python god this this this maybe
maybe it's that character that's a
non-breaking space
okay so what we do is now we copy the
entire buffer
open a new buffer let's show the pink
window
[Music]
copy the entire buffer
and
[Music]
okay this is getting boring this is
copy the entire buffer paste it
now in this buffer
call
find
and replace by regular expression okay
this is the emax tip
so this is spilled in so you give a this
regular expression
ascii
plus
so you want to find osc characters okay
replace it by empty okay now do it on
for the whole thing so you got that
so this is a bunch of non-ascii
characters in that file
and all these characters seems normal to
me so this this one is breaking space
you you can see number king space this
one is
single co uh right single quotation mark
okay
and this is uh
right words double arrow and this is the
breaking space again
so that file contains these
these
non-ascii characters
that shouldn't cause any problem
so i don't know why python is like stuck
line one one one okay what no that's the
module the python
sucks donkey s
output right so when it's trying to
write file it encountered this problem
and some python you know it gives you
the python
you know the python unicode handling is
really sucky
you know in python 2 and python 3. i
always always had this problem like 10
years ago in python 2 it's a headache in
python 3 you know you think
python 3 made it much better but
you know because all the languages i've
used you know in in in in this case
pearl
python golan emax powershell wufang
language none of them have this problem
just python
unicode problem
and it's giving these arrows like what
what the [ __ ]
so okay let's so it's
so what do we do now so you know
i was going okay let's do it again so
copy okay hold on a second
paste
remove
all these okay and let's see which
character is the python error okay
i mean it's let's see which is the
character causing python error so it
says
u21 d2 so let's look at them one atom at
the time
u2 and d2 so not this one
describe char
so this one is u21192019
and this one is that that's the problem
2 1 d2 so you can see
here
so
that
oh you are correct young so how did you
find out okay so you are right yeah
so that character is this character is
causing this
choked python [ __ ] python
so let's
let's this um
describe matching lines okay there it is
so why is this character
causing python python is the most
popular programming language how dare
say you bad things about it yeah that's
right
so how
how is the
python error so let's see where is the
python error let's get back to python
here
did i just
so anyway so
so python choked on this
line
so let's run it again okay let's see
what happens okay
uh you can run it again because this
file is now empty
[ __ ] python
so let's see where's the python error
messages can did i did i delete it
okay maybe i okay here cause i'm an
output yeah
so it says
unicode in code error char map codec
can't encode character that
imposition that
character map to undefined what the
[ __ ] what the [ __ ] is the problem
with the python [ __ ] it
you know it cannot deal with this
character i don't think so
something is wrong something is wrong i
don't know where you know exactly but
something
let's copy it and put it here so we
don't
you know close it by mistakes so let's
shrink
so you see that's output that's the
error so
no idea what's uh
you know basically essentially it's
because this
double arrow character causing the
problem python says it cannot encode
this character
what
let's go back to the python code okay
so in case someone is gonna blame me my
lousy python code
so this is the code that does find and
replace
now where does it says
so input file encoding is utf-8
output file right path okay maybe
so what is the output
default output
file encoding because i didn't specify i
thought it's utf-8 you know maybe
because i screwed up
what the [ __ ]
so if we add that would that save would
that make it work
i don't know but you know the other
option is to look up python
documentation which is the circus
possible
so let's search for open file for python
open file for writing python
documentation is the worst possible
you see
you know
one one of the way to tell which
documentation which official
documentation of the language sucks
is that when you search
and if it doesn't
if the top results are a bunch of you
know these
blood sucking ads spamming websites like
tutorial point you know or this python
tech i don't know pat on tech.com i
don't know what that is
if if the top results are all this
you know random website that means your
documentation your official
documentation sucks donkey ass
and python is that such a case you see
all these results guru 99 guru 99 python
file handling
and this free code camp you know the
yeah the coding camp the [ __ ] idiocy
python central dot io
ah god jesus
and w3 schools learn python you know
python documentation the [ __ ] worst
[ __ ]
let's search for python doc you know i
want to look at the official
documentation i don't want the random
[ __ ]
so
people you know let's see the open you
know
major problem i have 10 000 articles on
why python documentation sucks
so
so i already talked for an hour already
okay uh so much for the benchmark
now i have back pain sitting here too
long
so python open documentation okay so
it's it's um let's
let's do it okay so
you know the extremely bad organization
so what is this uh we need to find right
so find is in a library i believe
i mean open file open file is in um
was it
like it said a is a is it a
object or is it a function
uh
i haven't looked at python documentation
for a long time for 10 years
so
like uh either library reference or
language reference yeah language
reference is usually
uh not useful language reference because
they talks about the like formal syntax
and so on lexical analysis analysis
there as
lexical analysis data model
was the writing possible
so it's it's gonna be in the standard
library okay
then yeah so you have building types
building functions so building functions
one of them is open that yeah it's very
this is a one of the sour point of
python you know some of it is function
some of it is like an object
idiotic python so open is right here
so you
so you see open file and return a
corresponding file object
okay
so
so do you have encoding yes so you have
encoding there so what is the default
encoding
um
python documentation is the worst
possible
so where is
do you want does any one of you know you
python experts are there
it's it's truly a pen in the ass i can
imagine we stuck on the python thing
so i have three versions so i have a
fine version in python so
so for example
so i have
a
find version in python then we have a
uh
replace find and replace version and we
have a find replace using regular
expressions
um but
the fine version got a problem now the
replace version got a problem
yeah this is pretty bad
let's just run it again
okay so except that file the python
version runs so now you can see
except that file i don't know what's
going on with that file so so you can
see here's the result the python version
you know the python version is a
a bit lacking features you know i
haven't put much
as much energy as in my golan version
and emac these and others so it doesn't
print the context but here's a result
okay let's do it again run it
ah god you run it again then it's got
problems
file exists error cannot create a file
when that file already exists oh god
when you make a backup
okay
okay i don't like python okay let's just
close python
let's skip python because we got lots of
others um
[Music]
yeah [ __ ]
so what am i doing so
power version let's try perversion okay
so but before we do we need to refresh
um
we need to refresh the copy of the file
okay
so
you need to go to the file
so let's open the golan version so here
is the directory
deleted delete yes because python
already screwed it
so now
emacs manual
copy them over
yes recursively
okay now we have a fresh version
okay so python let's do perl okay so
pearl
there it is okay pearl there's also a
replace version
so here's the pro version
so the directory uh we got the directory
would be
the directory would be that okay
then
backup directory path okay yeah
now the direct the pro version actually
backs up into a separate directory so
uh
so okay
okay so let's just
say some
then find and replace string so
the find string is commands
the replay string is the same thing
just one pair
okay
now
use regular expression zero that's good
now file size limit
i mean if the file size is more than
that many bytes we skip it so this uh
that's the feature of the power version
okay so let's do it
let's just run it okay
run it
okay the pro version prints lots of
things
a total of 593 file changed processing
too much you know
so the pro version is the oldest
you know let's run again
you know when when you have a script
that writes to file that makes it
significantly slower so you cannot
compare this with the
with the golan and emacs we did before
uh so today today's talk show is a fail
because we we we want to do the
benchmark but
but we we don't even have a mechanism
set up to do that
but anyway so we demonstrated python we
demonstrated
golan we demonstrated perl
and we demonstrated emacs e-max is the
most versatile so for example let's open
that
just do it just do it like that
you want to find commands
you know the emax is the best
then
then there's powershell then there's
wufam language let's let's try wolfham
language okay
so we end up
just kind of doing demo
without actually benchmark
but so far it appears that at least the
golan version and
the emac this version they are they are
the same speed like you don't see any
perceivable difference
so anyway here's the wolfram language
version so let's let's
you know let's at least demo it okay so
delete that so we want to copy the
directory
so the directory will be here
okay that's the directory
and
the
find replace okay again here's a find
replace so we want commands
and replace it by
same thing and it has it allows you
allows you to have multiple pairs we
don't care
um
so just one single pair okay
and we can run this
internet
oh
uh before we do this we need to start up
the kernel yet yeah you know because
otherwise it's you know it takes the
time to start up the kernel so let's do
it again
[Music]
okay that's a problem
wait why is it taking this long
[Music]
let's see what's going on let's open the
file
and it's making backup so
the wolfram version let's do it again
now that's taking too long okay
the woofing version is right now the
slowest
and i think there's something wrong i
mean it shouldn't be this long at all
uh
for example the printing takes long time
so let's suppress the printing of the
output
yeah still this it's got a problem
something is not
not
optimal here shouldn't take this long
[Music]
so let's see
okay so that's it i think
[Music]
yeah so
yeah this is pretty bad today
you know we did
is it pretty bad because
we want to
benchmark but we failed in doing that
and
so what am i doing now so what
so what do we want to do
now
yeah where's
my even where's my talk show page
okay let's
we shut down okay we shut down in five
minutes meanwhile let me think about
what we're gonna do so
so let's let's try let's get a sense of
speed at least you know the golem so
let's go back to the golan version find
go okay here so let's run it
wait why is there so many oh god the
wufang language screwed it up
the wolfram language
i think it actually
yeah it actually in double triple you
know it
yeah the wolfram language
screwed it up
there's a bug
what it did
is that it actually made
i think each of this file
double
or three times
so if we look at this example this is 80
kilobytes you know this file is usually
usually just eight eight by eight
kilobyte but now it's 80 kilobytes 10
times small
so if we run the wolfram language again
you'll see it'll probably become larger
so now you look
now right now it's 80 kilobyte okay
refresh
it doubled
okay now it's 162 kilobytes oh jesus
this this such a failure okay
what's going on today
process file module backup
yeah it's a failure today okay so
okay so that's it for today i guess we
wanted to
yeah this this is pretty bad so
and we haven't demonstrated the
powershell version yet it's a powershot
version it's okay let's show the
powershot version is pretty simple okay
so the powershell
i don't have a script ready
but it's something like this okay so
let's
let's uh hold on hold on a second let's
let's go to talk show
today's talk show open new buffer pasted
savers
xx
date
ps1 okay psy is a powershell extension
now look you are looking at the
powershell
now let's write this on the fly okay
so powershell find replace let's say
find
replace okay
so so documentation
something replace accept a pipe object
your
ear
to find
replace
a given string
well what i'm what am i talking about
you know in powershell if you just want
to find something that's very easy okay
so what all you have to do is
ah
all you have to do is
the
recurse
file
include
html
then pipe it to
so do that include private to
i don't remember
so go to my powershell i have a example
right here search text
select string that's right simple match
no we don't want we want okay sim simple
match okay
so that's all you have to do
by the way the sls the sls stands for
select string so you can see now it
expand to select string okay so copy it
now let's
do it
that's how you do grep in powershell
what abc oh what do you want to find is
a command not abc commands okay
what so many okay clear screen
paste it
do it
oh yeah there's so many because of the
wufam language code screwed it up
it
duplicated each file's content like 20
times
so
okay that's it thank you guys
bye
so
so yeah so we demonstrated
finding replays in several of these
languages which i did so many times
before
what i really want to do is
myself actually what i want what i
really want to know is actually the
speed of python and golan and emac lisp
you know
because i had that question for 10 years
i want really to know
how fast is emac this you know because i
think it's five times slower than slower
than python in general and gola and
python is five times slower slower than
golden in general
but
you know so i want to really find out so
but yeah but we are in so bad the state
what we're gonna do now um
close that so we
the journey is more fun than the
destination yeah that okay
yeah okay yeah that's it that's it i'm
gonna
that's it for today you know over wow 70
minutes kind of long
have a good day guys enjoy the new year
let's look forward to year 2022
bye
measure command yeah that
yeah i'll look into you know that's uh
that's uh
wait
that's definitely i will have to look
into it because i haven't used it before
uh
and if i do on in real time you know i'm
probably gonna like spend 20 minutes
just reading about it