good morning good morning welcome to
another episode of Zatoichi Oh
today is May 11th Saturday 2019 and so
is sheis
there is a five-second lag here so today
we're gonna talk about
century random things okay we're gonna
talk about we might talk about noose
website went to clicker website how to
church sites quality you know what
weather is fake new so you can something
you can trust or how I how I go about on
these kind of things where do I get the
information so that's one thing or maybe
we can talk about Lisp programming
language syntax problems you know the
nested parentheses what are the issues
you know things like that and we talked
about these markers and pattern matching
now in the case of these markers and
pattern matching I'm going to give you
my opinion I'm gonna tell you what they
are in the great context of things you
know the programming language design
syntax kind of things in that background
oh I'm gonna we can talk about you know
I go to my Twitter and there are tons of
subjects so basically there are two type
of subjects you know for the show
technical topics like you know
programming languages programming
related state stuff this is energy drink
this is powered water power I've been
addicted to this thing for like I've
been drinking this for like four years
five years actually everyday so in a
sense I'm actually addicted to it which
is no good I used to drink the sugared
ones the ones with sugar never do that
they do bad things to your body you know
in my life I never drink sugared stuff
such as Coke Pepsi you know sprite 7up I
never drink any of those never drink I
never drink anything that you know in
your drink with sugar unit you know you
dope
but however because of the energy
drink I started to drink the sugared
ones about five years ago and I did that
for three or four years and they are bad
they do things to your body they do
things to your skin for example you know
cellulite you know when you have your
ass you know women usually like your
legs you know you have this ugly skin
cellulite whatever they call it and I
noticed I started to have that you know
when you drink sugared water you drink
that a lot every day you know every day
so I stopped drinking sugared ones and
and and now I'm drinking the sugar-free
ones
energy drink still yeah I don't think
it's not really a good thing but by the
way don't but don't also don't go to the
other stream thinking that it is you
know terrible you know it's it is it's
you know it's it's it's essentially it's
caffeine you know they have caffeine and
stuff bunch of it's stuck
Londyn good morning just found your
channel thank you so what is it how did
you find my channel how what is it that
attracts you so are you a programmer are
you in my channel too because for
programming topics or other random
things so let's see how am i doing I am
Alive yes indeed so this is OBS software
you know when you do videos you have to
streaming and you have to use this
software this this is the open source
one okay let's get back to all for
watching fantastic number four is the
Fantastic Four the number four
represents the superhero group Fantastic
Four okay so and also where are you from
like what country are you watching for
so what topic guys let's take a topic so
first of all is it gonna be technical
talk do you like to see today technical
talk Oh non-technical technical meaning
programming related least you know
anything you can ask me Emacs and Python
Perl stuff or non-technical would be
anything goes linguistics society so I'm
thinking maybe we do yeah so yeah dude
so guys so since we have for people
watching let me know what technical and
non-technical like type it let me know
so got killed in for tonight by a player
with a name XA hyt so I looked up the
name wow that's strange
okay so oh you are in Japan that's
amazing so so so you are not typical not
a typical follower you know my audience
you see I'm a nerd I'm a programmer
programming nerd so I don't know if you
would be much interested in my talk show
because I usually talk about programming
stuff I love cami but I haven't been you
know I'm kind of old
I haven't been gaming for you know for
like ten years
but I think you know I'm a gamer you
know what you call since I was a team
that is 1980s you know you have arcade
video games and though you know I'm one
of the I'm you know I'm a very serious
you know gave me addict not like today's
because today's you have different games
but back then since 1980s when I was a
teenager 13 you know 10 11 up to you
know age 40s so whenever I play a game I
have to like complete the whole thing
you know I play a non-stop not eating
you know not stop for 10 hours and wake
up and do it again it's like that so
I've been doing that you know much of my
for much of my life
but then the last game like today's kind
of game social you know in what's called
massive online network to get you know I
say that I the one I played is a second
life you have you may have heard of it
heard of it you may not have slowly
second life that's quite different from
these fortnight or other team fortress
or whatever so second life but but it is
a you know online virtual world so at
any moment you have a hundred thousand
people you know online doing all sort of
things including gun fighting like this
I you know these are furry furries this
the creativity is amazing in this
virtual world so it's it's actually far
more creative in Thimphu for night I I
never sing for night actually I just
read you know I know that it is like the
most popular game today you know young
people play but anyway second life
because Second Life is filled by people
so the creativity is far greater than
the four night kind of things so all
these people you know these are furries
okay these are so in second life we have
there are all sort of communities you
know there are sex they are you know
first person shooters there's adventure
there's you know role-playing or you're
playing all sort of things
westerns you know why Wild West or
historical you know all kind of you know
what kind of errors and you know but one
of the community is is is first-person
shooter where you have team you know
shooting you know all kind of the
different types for example you can have
you have one versus one or team versus
team but there is
I'm not sure there is a one where you
take the enemy's fortress so like like
anyway so all these are created people
by people so in this first-person
shooter games you have different groups
you know what what different armies you
know or you know so what well this army
is this
what's your name this team anyway they
and also in this you know you have lots
of furries you know furries good morning
Isaak so yeah I in Japan so that's great
oh you live in America
so the next question is were you born in
America or how young did you came to
America because that's a huge difference
cultural bringing cultural difference so
you saw white key okay I don't know you
know that my name XH that is that is
name I created for myself and it is also
my real ID my you know my driver's
license California ID but and that is
rather rare but so sometimes people use
my name so I don't know if this is okay
so it's just a random guy because online
I'm you know let's see
okay so so let's let's go back to get
the topic because that for people and
I'm going to talk about Isaac so eyes
like what represent death so Isaac
should it be technical topical and
technical otherwise I'm just going to go
random okay so B so these are my four
number four number four as in let's see
who is it
how about a topic on how I can become
smarter smarter one two three four oh my
Twitter so where's the traitor you are
thinking let's go to Twitter then how to
be smarter you can't you know I don't
think you can I mean not like as far as
IQ goes you know that the intelligence
you know the intelligence has become
controversial topic some people say it
doesn't exist I think I think it's
absolutely exist you know although they
are you know colorful takes exactly what
you mean but you know intelligence such
as what so what does that mean Cajuns it
basically just means how good you can do
math okay that's basically what it means
how good you can do math in a natural
way for example there are many math
quizzes that does not require you to
know calculus but just you know math
question how you can analyze such you
know situation and you know that's
intelligence and it's and it obviously
exists okay so it exists so much such
that everyone understand
you know there are people you know there
are people who are you know who are
called I think it's called morons
technically no no what's the word
imbecile okay like the medical you know
technique or name I think
imbecile that means that means people
with very low IQ you know you know and
some people are born like that they are
disabled you know so Quartus about some
sometimes they also have motile function
disabilities like they they you know
they cannot you know talk or we have
difficulty control their most muscles
you know but anyway so you know as you
know that the exist you know you cannot
say oh they are the heck you know they
are smart they you know it's obviously
and different people like when you talk
about programming to you know go out
talkin you know see us people on the
street you try to talk about programming
with them you will see the the meaning
of intelligence okay so you know so like
some people like I live with you know I
know you know I work in restaurants you
know I've been washing dishes you know
you talk to those people you know they
they don't have the concept you know
they use their phone to like today you
know just like everyone everyone it's
the phone and some of them actually use
iPhone you know the expensive ones you
talk to them many of them okay did you
try to tell them teach them what is copy
and paste and for a lot of them they
will never get it how it's like almost
doesn't matter how many hours you try to
teach him because I had roommates like
10 years ago like people are like that
you know you copy and paste they just
they we are not the concept is just they
were they don't get it after you know
our stays after day you know mom they do
not get the concept of copy paste they
cannot do it you know that's reality so
there's a so that is the why the so
actually exists
okay the Socialists justice cans they
are just [ __ ] heads they are just they
are they are today you know they are
like criminals they are intentionally
this and it's getting worse okay they
are creating a situation they are you
know cooking frying on the race on sex
on issues you know they did that that is
a technique attacked tactic to
intentionally create disruption in
society because some of these issues
such as IQ sex race that can never be
solved that's part of humanity that that
is how we live about how society forms
how we thrive how we live okay that can
never be solved you know I'm not going
to go to into details like you know like
some of the typical white people's style
they would you know start to maybe cite
things yeah you know that thing and you
know intent intelligence free or
rationally discuss what you know what IQ
means or what what you know the
definition or sometimes why it's good or
how it relates to you know that's
typical white main style of talking okay
I'm borrowing the social justice can of
using the phrase white people okay yeah
they are white people oh this anyway
typically yeah that's the western style
okay of thinking of talking you know but
but anyway you know intelligence it's
obvious video okay so the social justice
can of course they don't like this idea
now as far as the okay they don't like
that bad idea so I'm not going to go too
deep too much into this because I'm
putting some restraints on self
censorship because it's good at Google
is going to ban me you know if I talk
too much about this anybody anyway the
issues like sex race the social justice
can you know what they are doing that's
you know because I have studied I study
marketing brainwashing you know coat you
know thought control
propaganda they are all related topics
you know I've been having you know I
have a say civ interesting these topics
throughout my life for thirty years now
you know because when I was a when I was
19 I when I was 20 or 21 I actually went
to work for Scientology I didn't know
because but I went to Scientology
because they began with a psychology
test you know personality test you know
person this personality personality test
things like that they are one of the
attraction to get you into things that's
you know very popular and also vote you
know vote online like you can select
what who you know that's one of the also
popular tactics to attract your
attention
but anyways Saudi scie and he orgy why
okay so you can read this article so I
happen to work for Scientology you know
because you know I need a job
you know it began with the personality
test and I always loved that so I have
several articles on Scientology you can
read and this article discussed my
experience you know so in 1990 1991 or
1992 went to work for Scientology and
it's not actually working but yeah
actually they just cheated my money they
just you know I worked for them almost
like free and anyway I have details on
this page and there are several other
pages about Scientology about you know
so I have obsession about study these
all these subjects coats propaganda
brainwashing marketing techniques how to
influence people all these are related
how they are they related they are
related by they are all about changing
opinions other people's opinion okay
for example marketing is changing all
the people's
opinion to try to get them to buy things
to buy your book to buy your TV products
or whatever okay that's marketing so
they are focused on changing other
people's thoughts about giving you money
basically that's marketing so so Apple
does it you know the greatest success of
Apple's
makhani is the 1984 you know where you
have a girl smashing the giant screen
and also think different you know
remember that slogan around 2004 think
different that's grammatically incorrect
phrase but it's a it's a huge success
you know it's a celebrated marketing
incident you know Malkina is a big giant
billion-dollar business you know Google
Facebook base they spend millions
studying the subject so anyway that's
what's marking propaganda is related
proper economies influence people
typically your enemy okay influence
people in a massive scale
that's what propaganda means okay
usually with the connotation of force
force or fake things like you you want
your enemies in a massive scale you want
to change their mind so that they
believe something that usually is not
true
that's what propaganda means so it's
also about changing people's mind
marketing in propaganda influence people
psychology influence people influence
people and also being politicians when
you negotiate when you talk about a deal
when you have a co-ed being smooth being
tact you know so that's also part of it
so what does that mean that that means
you know negotiation is a common
situation in life you know in business
in politics in anything in you know when
you go for a job when you work for
company there's an interview then you
have to talk about salary how much you
get paid that's a negotiation okay by
the way how much you
get paid really has nothing to do with
how good you are
it mostly has to do with how you
negotiate how you are able to talk me
you know it's all about that that's
that's why it's so important so
negotiation so what it is about it is it
is also how it relates to changing other
people's view negotiation for example I
want to sell you something my used
computer okay I have a used computer I
want to sell to you Oh keyboard okay and
you want to buy it but how much well you
know that's of to negotiation so I I
want to talk to you so you wanted sheep
I want to sell the experience you know I
want to sell you $150 let's say you
wanted to be like they say hundred but
there's no really price tag like there's
no card actually say this is this this
is 150 you know in real life there's
nothing like that all prices are just
kind of neat any price diamonds cause
anything on Amazon they they are all
kind of just not official okay there's
no one with set price this knows you
know any anyway that's that's about
Martin you know demand you know supply
and demand that's usually that's a
theory how how much something cost you
know why some why your time and cost a
million dollars wow it's basically
almost useless to you and why you know
anyway you know there's some keyboards
you know Amazon that's like 10 years old
I mean heaven being made for 10 years
but it's very expensive five hundred
dollars that was that's also why some
paintings they cost millions of dollars
but they are with literally useless but
they you know anyways negotiation
negotiation is part of the it's about
influencing you know I want to you I
want to make you think you know you know
something I want to sell is what is
worth 150 buddy but you on the other
hand you want to make it you know make
me think that it's actually not worth it
so if I
you want to make me think that if you if
I can just sell you a hundred it's
actually good for me because you know by
whatever means that's a negotiation
maybe you'll say it's good for
friendship you know come on we I know
you for ten years you know things like
that that's so it's that's all about
negotiation so that's also about
changing other people's thought you know
so propaganda marketing negotiation and
negotiate new negotiation happens
everywhere and also there's he polemics
or the the skills to lecture when you
talk to a huge great audience or how
politicians how they rise you know so
all these you know I'm interested in
these subjects all my life and let's see
and so so back to the topic so so yeah
so what I'm saying so what was the topic
before IQs
I forgot what was what was the reason I
went in to talk about why how I have a
interest in the marketing propaganda
kind of stuff I forgot what's the topic
before that anyway back to intelligence
okay so that's exists for sure now the
social justice can they deny it and you
know it began it began this day our
denial of in IQ okay it began like in
1990s basically the root of the that is
the post-modernism philosophy in
academia okay
the postmodern modernism is is kind of
that the mo yeah so it's kind of the
most destructive thing in fact now I
don't know the actual history of how
that philosophy how that movement came
up you know for that question you you
you you go watch Jordan Pederson stocks
or Camille Paglia
and Camille Paglia YouTube you know
Camille Paglia she calls herself a
feminist she's the first you know that
like you know the thirty years ago that
generation of feminists so she hold that
title steadfast not like today's
feminist so today's fantasy feminist is
you know the opposite of her so anyway
if you want to know the history of
post-modernism you know there's
something you go watch Jordan Jordan
Peterson Oh Camille Paglia but so what
I'm saying here about post-modernism it
began you know I've seen it you know
began in 1990s and the word you know so
what what it is is it basically that
they are a destructive you know here's
how I describe it okay let let me put it
my
my specific way to about what
post-modernism is okay my likes are
style
okay so post-modernism it is a it's like
suppose we are at war okay you know
suppose you are me our enemies or
suppose we are in competition you know
we are in competition to see who is the
greatest programmer or who is the
greatest orator you know you know
ability to talk or who is the better
leader okay let's say Oh anything you
know in competition let's say you know
we are in competition fierce competition
or we are in a in war you know like
enemies like violence you know or we are
in you know boxing fight whatever you
know well not physical let's say not
physical just we are we are in company
we are enemies okay now the the first
question of concern to you or me is that
how do I win how do I get you off you
know you can play by the rules so you
can you know you know like in real life
there are there are no rules okay when
you play your chess when we play a chess
there's a rules you know you certain
things you cannot do but that's
artificial you can kind of good you can
always you know because there's no like
God that says once if you do not follow
a rule you get a shock electric shock or
something that doesn't exist so in real
life you can do all sort of things for
example we play chess I came first for
example I can do psychological tactics
and you know I noticed you get annoyed
when people are late or you you start to
have you know anxiety or something so
I'm going to be late for 10 minutes you
know that's a tactic you know even
though technically I did not violate the
rules of the chess but you know I pray
these psychology you know I'm late for
10 minutes and I also I studied you I
noticed you maybe you find it annoying
if people have certain habits let's say
you know since and strange habit so I
just I you know I studied that I noticed
and I do that when I play chess you know
maybe I start to you know shake or
something you know that gets you annoyed
you maybe you you know your
concentration face off then you lose so
that those are tactics kind of outside
of the rule but however not technically
so you know championship I can still win
but you know doing these tactics so
that's about Lewis so so when we are if
we are enemy in anything I you know
that's the question to me is how do I
win you know I'm not you know there are
certain rules or more or lose but I
don't have to follow it it depends on
you you know depending on you how much
you wanna break the you know so code but
you know how weird how
what kind of tactic do you want to use
so so post-modernism okay so so we are
talking about tactics of winning
something anything in competition or
wipe out your enemies in you know in
friendly crash or in you know severe you
want to totally entirely wipe out your
enemy so when doing that when there's a
conflict the the first concern is
tactics you know strategy strategies
don't a tactic tactic tactics means
shorten you know how do you wing it
now post-modernism is essentially is
kind of a philosophy of tactics or
strategy tactics okay the sole goal is
is is is is to wipe out your enemy that
is possible that that is basically when
one essential aspect of post-modernism
okay and that that is what this social
justice can there are theories and
whatever they do there joggins it's all
came from this post-modernism it's it's
essentially it's just just a tactic
so whatever they say whatever you know
they create whatever you know whatever
they do basically they are you know they
are a group you know maybe students or
professors you know left-wing professors
so they want to think of a way so that
whatever they say they we are wing like
political opinion they say it they want
to make sure whatever you know opinion
that is they will win so how do you do
that oh you know so how do you do that
you follow the you know the the the
philosophy of post-modernism that's how
you do it okay so they are they are they
are opinions about politics or their
their what they say about feminism or
whatever it's it's never about reason
okay like like that's that's why we can
see so many of them they don't like to
argue they don't you know they don't
follow stuff because because the soul
you know the SoCo the soul essence of
post-modernism is too flat your enemy to
win okay so so that that is a thing
that's a very interesting thing so in a
sense it is post-modernism is you know
you look like I talked about you know
how to influence people propaganda you
have probably Conda you have
brainwashing you have marketing you have
tact you know how to talk smoothly you
have negotiation skills you look at all
these okay you want you want you know
maybe as a philosopher you want to think
of a way like that extract them all
create a philosophy such that it
contains the kind of the alternate
destruction like the ultimate tactics so
that doesn't matter what you're doing
what area it just wipe out your enemy
that that is the essence of
post-modernism okay okay that's that's
that's about that okay so back to
intelligence so anyway obviously is
something that you exist
and what were we talking about
intelligence for oh yeah so how do be
smarter now IQ is born you know people
are born with IQ by the way IQ is also
this so many things about IQ it's not
you know I have a let's say related
above average higher IQ okay and look at
my life okay I am I'm Emily you know I'm
living in poverty this shirt this
t-shirt is like 20 years you know I'm
gonna throw it away after today then I'm
gonna take a shower this this [ __ ] it's
20 years old you know so high IQ doesn't
really you know it's not like oh you
have a higher IQ you know the little
intro this a joke okay like there's a
rich man and who who you know who met
this actually that's I think that's a
real story of some strange architect
okay who made this Archie Tech well
known you know designer a cheetah Club
of buildings so the richer man says you
know like well why aren't you reach yet
and the the architect shot back no well
why don't you know and then he asked the
the the the billionaire okay why aren't
you smart yet so so that exchange that
can't that illustrates how IQ is not you
know it's not like you have IQ you know
suppose the high IQ then you become
you'll be rich or you'll be good it but
in general it helps just like money you
know in general money doesn't make you
happy but it does help in so many ways
in so many ways okay it doesn't really
you know [ __ ] you know because if you
have you don't have money first of all
you hungry you know you don't have food
hungry or you have more nutrition
that you won't be happy with that then
you get sick you know but if you have
some money you know just you know enough
to survive that that's you know that's
money that is how money you know that's
one instance of where having money
helped you prevented you from being
unhappy you know example
so anyway high IQ is not something you
know you just oh you know you just wish
you have high IQ and things through a
piece things will be good no you know
and also but it helps you know it's a
good thing to have and also most people
you know we you know you know today you
know today the social justice can they
make IQ I don't you know I don't feel
too comfortable talking about IQ thing
because I think you know because then
obviously people think oh I think I have
a high IQ Avenue it's not good thing to
talk about that anyway it doesn't do you
you know it's not a magic okay also also
I think if this is true statistically
okay you have you you know you have IQ
it says you know from let's say from 0
to 10 okay let's just say that scale so
most people are around five you know and
so if you are you know statistically
speaking you know if you're above
average with IQ then then you tend to be
better off you know in your life in your
career you tend to it make more money
okay but this here's an interesting
thing when your IQ is like eight or nine
this is something maybe it's something
just I believe okay well when your IQ is
like a bit higher you know night let's
say then statistically I think there's a
study about that you know so you know
it's the teached by statistics when your
hike IQ is high you you don't you start
to not do well and and suicide rate also
also becomes higher
yeah that's okay that's that's my life
story so I I've seen this I've seen this
report I haven't really actually studied
it but but you know despite any possible
bias bias I I might have you know I
might want to believe that but I think
that's you know with consideration of
that I think that's a true story you
know you might have to look up and do
research on that and I I believe that's
also a point children Peterson mentioned
on this about this study of high IQ you
know in general higher IQ is good but
once once you go a bit higher you know
you don't do well also let me also
mention high high high IQ does not do
you you know don't it's not a magic
trick okay a lot you know for example if
you look at all the greatest
mathematicians in history okay how many
people I have watching oh okay people
are going away if you look at the
history of the great mathematicians okay
they they are not high IQ okay they are
just like you know a above average for
sure you know but they are not high IQ
on the other hand you know all the
greatest mathematicians accomplished you
know they have contributed you know
incredible theories you know they solved
problems
that's unsolved for hundreds of years
you know those mathematicians you know
the greatest mathematicians in history
the IQ is not like you know it's it's
not super high okay like like you can
you can know from you know studying the
their biography you know so this like
you know this it's not like they all
have super high IQ on the other hand
when you look at when you look at you
know like since fifty years ago we start
to have IQ test so we we do know who the
people who have really high IQs like you
know in a top zero 10.1%
you look at those people those people in
their life there's no typically there's
no accomplishment I mean I mean they are
not you know they're not good you know
this is you know they did need to not
become you know greatest mathematician
so they do not become the you know beast
great you know a great businessman such
as Bill Gates or Steve Jobs and they do
not become that and I don't know for
sure but I think most of them they just
live a normal life so anyway IQ doesn't
do you know do you much and also yeah
and also and also it's not IQ is not
something like concrete you know it's
not like you know it's not like
something that can be very precise you
know so you know if you are programmer
you have a you have higher IQ okay you
have we have the same IQ basically you
know like above average average you know
dude but you cannot measure like you
cannot you cannot measure oh I have
higher IQ than you that doesn't make
sense unless there's a huge gap when
there's a huge gap in an IQ then you can
see it without actually you know testing
for IQ you can just you talk to people
you know you know they they they feel
you are smart or you feel they are you
know you know they are you know some
people are not smart you know you'll see
it you don't need the IQ test so
I I don't I don't I think I had IQ test
when I was maybe 15 16 in Montreal so me
you know I don't remember but I did you
know my SAT which is like you know the
SAT score I have a have obsession about
studying SAT so I got you know I got you
know like top 10 percent scores in SAT
that's you know so so back then in 1990s
you know there's this there's this
min-suk meets IQ good
so one of the qualification is that is
if you're i SAT score is in the top 10
percentile then you qualify so i
qualified and I think I applied for
membership I don't remember
something yeah but oh yeah you have to
pay the package so in 1991 or 1992 you
have to pay like I don't know $30 or was
a $50 back then so I was a Mensa member
for a year after that then I didn't I
didn't pay so I found a member but then
when you are a member they send you
these newsletters I know is it's kind of
silly
so how to pick up become smarter you
cannot and also you don't necessarily
you know you it's not something you want
to it's it's like how do you become more
beautiful okay I want to be you know I
and how do I become younger you know I
don't want I don't want to lose hair you
know you cannot so many things you
cannot just do it but and also the
question you know that you might say
that is the wrong question you know
because there are so many good wrong
questions in life you know program I got
the wrong question about which language
to learn or which one is the most
arrogant language you know so many so
many wrong questions you know you have
drawn questions because you have lots of
misconception and misinformation and
also you know the pop you know the
everything every day the pop news TV
they feed you bad information in
incorrect or misleading information so
or you have bad friends for example if
you are if you are young and your
neighbors you know your friends are
gangsters so then you have bad questions
you know like what should I do
you know it's you know so you get back
so instead so if you want to I suppose
the better question is how to you know
maybe how to become you know successful
and usually that's just you just work
hard on it study work hard and you know
yeah I mean there are there are lots of
books and you know talking about that
stuff work hard is the work hard is is
fundamental it's it's necessary it's
absolutely necessary okay
like I don't believing any tricks okay
you know like if you want to lose fat to
exercise and you know it's don't eat
junk food you know eat healthy and
exercise you can lose fat if you know if
that's what you know if that's you know
what you want to do you know if you are
you know really fat
and but but don't you know there's a lot
of tricks you know each this fruit
strange fruit and you lose fat you know
especially women because that's their
main concern you know is every day
there's ads about how to lose fat that's
all [ __ ] you know so I don't buy
those tricks
same thing with programming you know you
or studying math or anything you just
study spend time to study it so what
heart that's one thing also don't work
yourself to death okay I'm like working
myself to death for nothing okay that is
my fault
you know because you cannot just like
close the doors and and study something
for ten years that gets you nowhere you
have to you know you have to be smart
you know as they say you know you work
hard but also you want to you know do
you know normal things you know like
talk to people get people you know that
can you know help you or you know know
know people talk to them things like
that and when you have a job negotiate
you know don't be like no you know don't
be like a nerd like you know I'm not you
know I can just do programming what do
you think you should pay me just do that
that's kind of nerd you know I'm like
that and that's most people are not like
that and unless you are severe not yeah
okay so like how much you get paid is is
almost 90 percent of it it depends on
your skill of your ability to talk not
just talking I mean what I'm saying is
that it does not depends on what you are
was actual worth because what you
actually are worth there's no there's no
price tag there is everything how much
you get paid is this know is I mean like
there's no god that says you are worth
you know ten thousand dollars or years
something like that there's no such
thing so all the things about how much
you get paid is like it depends on when
you your
to talk how you look how you make other
people think and depending on the
situations maybe you are unlucky today
things like that so you know a practical
tip what I'm saying is that I mean I
don't know you I don't know you guys
each person is so different I don't know
what you guys situation are and I don't
know you know how old you guys are not
just you guys but all the people who
might watch me after you know after
today so what am I so so but this a
practical tip is that when you I forgot
what's what is that
well anyway just just be smart and
negotiate so as an older person how did
you become involved in technology and
coding I have always been interested in
math since I was young you know like it
since I was 10 so I'm interested in kind
of math and but I didn't you know I
didn't go to high school so I was in
Montreal and so I started kind of late
so I only started to actually start to
learn things when I was 20 yeah
essentially I essentially start to age
okay you know education like stuff
starting from high school education when
I was 20 you know but I just I love
computers very much I love math in
computers so I just dive into it in the
beginning so in 1996 mostly I study math
you know I want to be a mathematician No
so normal says Oh Landon okay
yeah London so Landon so what's what so
you play full night
can you show us some screenshots I love
to see that
Norman cinoman says being persistent and
working hard can get a lot harder can
get a lot farther than a high IQ yeah
absolutely
yeah IQ is just you know IQ is like you
know one of the dramatic subject you
know you know and the very the very name
IQ the jargon you know intelligence in
the IQ you just by the name itself it's
a traumatic subject because just the
name people want to talk about it all
the time because it it's it's it's it's
like a quality you know of a person it's
part of just like how good you look you
know how beautiful you are or you know
how you know it's part of your natural
product the person
and I studied you know I have been
studying about the issue of physical
appearance that actually influenced
people a lot I mean it's amazing that it
you know not just for girls you know of
course we love beautiful girls also
there's a topic of why we love beautiful
girls you know from you know from the
evolutionary biology perspective but
anyway in general not not just for girls
not just for you know men men picking up
girls but in general it applies to males
as well males or female okay when you
look good okay when you are pretty or
handsome it has significant influence
adventurous to you it's it that is
actually true you know I didn't know
this you know but I've studied you know
I've looked at articles and you know
that that is actually any true and it's
quite significant and also there's
amazing also for women if you have big
tits okay if you have huge breasts that
is also sick need Vantage's to you not
just for two men but to other females as
well they they they treat you
differently you know because you know
there's this let's say this is this
debunker what they call it on YouTube
there's a myth post myth myth buster
they have done experiment breast size
you know so they have this girl working
in a yeah here to do larger breasts
Conor larger tips you know they did an
experiment and that is actually true
this YouTube video it's try to amazing I
mean but it's it's just it's not men
giving them you know bigger tits girl
more money but but we
as well especially I think especially
women so that's kind of so that's a very
interesting thing you have this video
you can watch so yeah so you know being
beautiful and being happy you know those
those are social somehow they those are
good social signals for some reason they
are actually how we are you know we we
promote and we help we promote those
people who have good looks for some
reason okay for the reason about males
picking you know who you know make for
males you know liking beautiful women
the reason for that is pretty simple
because usually what basically you are
just just looking for youth you know
pretty girls you know in general the
younger you are the prettier you are you
know look you know when you are older
you have pulled hair you know you don't
look so good when you are younger you
know young people the skin everything is
new
you know things new things look better
than other things
same thing with you know animals so
younger people they you know they look
better so white but why do men wants you
know younger girls because this biology
you know when you are older you know
women you cannot have babies so those
those guys you know who prefer younger
you know who likes younger girls tends
to have more children because you know
if you [ __ ] you know fifty years women
you are not going to have children so
after a few generations the guys who
prefer older women dice off you know you
don't have children you you don't pass
your genes you die off so we got you
know you just got males who prefer could
really want younger you know girls the
younger the better because you know 2200
years ago we don't have
today's technology you know you know so
when you have a baby you can die you
know the woman you know you know the
woman can die when you have a baby but
the younger the girl is you know you the
more survival you know the the older is
more chance for you know dying that is
why you know eventually you other guys
wants younger girls prefer you know
younger girls but why it's all on the
other hand women when they choose mate
you know when they look for guys they do
not care that much about how guide you
know look so how how old is a guy why
because that can also be explained
simply because because for guys you know
you don't get pregnant you don't have
this age issue you know I'm 50
I can still have babies you know you can
you know some people's 60 70 even 70
years old you can still have babies you
know but your your chances are less you
know of course but unlike you know
females you know for females when you
are 40 you are you know your chance for
baby is almost zero especially like 200
years ago you have to be you know 200
years ago girls they get married when
when they are 13 you know when they are
18 that's so they it's almost like they
are almost like you know meet that's the
middle age you know that yeah and those
you know 200 years ago people died you
know when you are 30 you know so so you
know that's the situation saga Neha so
what about what else so let's see what
else I want to say about this so so yeah
so this is about so this is why about
white guys like younger girls why our
girls they don't you know they don't
have that much preference for the age of
the guy
you know but however they what they are
looking for what they really want is how
powerful how wealthy you are that's
because that is how they can have higher
chances for their survival of their
children because no more powerful the
guy is the more [ __ ] you know yeah
that's that's why girls you know women
they like [ __ ] they like strong male
you know they like just you know
[ __ ] like you know like the football
players because that signifies those
kind of people guy you know [ __ ] it's
like you know I don't care about you
know I just do what I I want and and I
can you know nothing you can do with
girls like that those type of guys
because those guys have power you know
they you know that's an indication or
characteristics of power and wealth you
know they they have you know they have
no problem in survival so girls like
them because then they have children
their children is more likely to survive
because you have these powerful dad you
know who can do things provide money or
whatever you know so they're the the
girls you know children survives on the
other hand if you have a girl who prefer
you know who don't care for the [ __ ]
guys who prefer you know the nerd earth
types or the weak you know guys chances
are they're children you know does does
not survive like maybe there's a storm
you know the you know the guy cannot be
or the house or you know maybe there's a
tiger you know lion you know Oh war
between you know so so your children
does that don't survive so these kind of
girls who who like you know weak you
know guys they die off you know so he
so girls Lee they want the you know they
like the [ __ ] that that is the
evolutionary biology so but the thing I
don't know is that why why in general
the good appearance
Kieran's you know he's good
so anyway sug
so what else so I think maybe that's it
for today let's see how how many six six
fever so guys say something say
something in the chat or I think maybe
then maybe we are done
fake yeah type type something you have
like 10 seconds ok nice you actually yep
nuts what nut
so let's see what else so I'm in UT so
what what do you mean that anthem pant
and Manton
Tim for Tim Foofa is a great guy okay
if you want to read news fair news you
know not fake news you want to follow a
team pool let me talk to about 10 more
minutes about what websites to read okay
now today there are a lot of websites
you know like this the popular website
CNN New York Times Washington Post Vox
you know vice you know all kind of
website you most of them are fake news
this cooperation corporate fake sites
new sites today are all fake news I mean
they are all blatantly fake usually when
I read the website even you know why I
got read a website I don't I don't I
never click you know on Twitter or
anywhere I don't click unless I actually
know what what that website unless you
know I have studied the background of
that website so for example New York
Times that that is a big name so I you
know I know it's a you know big giant
corporate site and many there are so
many websites today so usually you know
they almost they are all fake so the the
the major fake site fake news web site
today CNN New York Times Washington Post
vise purse BuzzFeed
The Verge Gizmodo I think also including
the crunch you know yeah they are like
they are actually just like they are not
just borderline fake they are actually
churning out blatantly false information
every day because they can do that
because then people don't check because
people don't have you know spend time to
actually check what is the
[Music]
you know what these I'm gonna answer the
question people don't check that's that
is why so these are fake news and fox
news of course Fox News is oriented is
it's small white right-wing conservative
it's very biased biased to Fox News and
but also this fixed-size are kind of
dying except the giant was New York New
York Times but most the others are dying
by the way you know just if you want to
check if you you know it's good things
to follow this guy came for he he is an
independent journalist so he always give
you kind of balanced view so whatever
news every day there's drama every day
you you know now and then check up on
teams you know what he say he he gets
repetitive you know and he's today these
days he's like making five videos per
day so it's very time-consuming you know
these days I only you know I just look
at the first two minutes of his video he
always repeats things you know he he
keeps saying he's a saint centrist and
you know he's a idiot
not exactly a idiot but he also he's not
you know scholar academic you know he
doesn't have much knowledge anyway he's
good at because that's his job he look
at all the news and he tell you a
summary of you know and he exposes many
fake news so he's a good reporter or
journalist I would say I don't like the
word journalism because all those words
are just jog and fake fake words what I
say is just reporter you know he's a
good reporter okay and he just does he
does videos and he actually has wrong
awards about his coverage of packing ten
years ago the Wall Street riot or
whatever you know so I recommend
following him so question about what
time do you tend to go live stream
actually I don't know
right like people have been asking
asking me that I don't have a schedule
that is the issue so forth because and I
don't have a regular sleep in psycho -
neither so sometimes I sleep in the
daytime sometimes at night and it's been
like that all my life you know I'm 50
years old so it's been like oh my like
that all my life is you know this cycle
it changes it switches about few hours
every month and sometimes sweet you know
is so I don't have a schedule so I do
plan you know I might announce a
schedule like for this week you know 2
o'clock p.m. or something like that I am
planning on that because because I
noticed the problem without a schedule
is that people don't know where I'm
going to come out so went but so when I
come on there are no people here you
know and also my topics changes
drastically sometimes it's very
technical for programmers sometimes it's
for you know random things like today
there's no fixed topic so that so but
some people only wants to watch my Emacs
stuff you know so that creates a problem
so I don't know I I'm thinking of you
know coming up a schedule we'll see oh
you know I'll talk about it or I will
try to announce it what time zone I mean
I'm in California Mountain View sunny
California I've been here for like for
like 30 years
or basically all my life
so another problem with my schedule is
that when I do a live show you know you
know the first minute the first first 30
minutes nope nobody is here you know
three four but after like after an hour
maybe six people then after 90 minutes
you know after an hour then I have maybe
five eight people but I'm all like I'm
done
you know I'm I've been talking for for
70 minutes I'm kind of done oh you are
in Australia so how did you follow me
like did you know me for my programming
stuff for my Emacs or other things so
Anton Anton Patton Menon Anton's had to
Manton so wait how do you hear about me
I like to know that found you from sorry
dolly info okay so I guess it's mostly
for my programming and math stuff so are
you a programmer and are you are you
like young people or are you in your 30
so are you still in school or you are or
you are like a programmer for four
decades so you know I if you have a
question oh you have 15 Wow amazing
yes oh you are young so are you like you
want to go into programming then 15
young people is great because 15 years
oh good I can teach you stuff if I can
teach you so much so many things oh
Unicode okay yeah Unicode is amazing so
year probably what do you mean year
probably so are you so so are you a
gamer are you a are you trying to learn
programming or maybe all you already
does for me
Oh like what what what do you do now
do you go to school
so anyway so I think that's about it
today so you guys if you have so I don't
know I have no idea who who guys who you
guys are so you know just keep comment
you know type comments you know you know
you can ask questions or typed your
opinions anything goes you go to school
so don't really play many video games oh
okay but I'm just interested in
computers in general and music and stuff
no cool
yeah so III so I'm very interested in
computers since I was a teen but I start
really late you know basically I started
my high school education when I was 21 I
didn't go to high school high school I
tricked actually but I passed you know
the GED exam in USA USA you have this
GED exam which stands for general
education development I think that's an
exam if you pass may give you a
certificate which means high school high
school graduate you know high school
equivalent then you can go to you know
so so you know I passed GED when I was
like 21 or 22 I think I still have the
photo of that certificate somewhere yeah
so so when I was 21 so I then I I went
to Community College over here for here
college but mostly I just you know
mostly I studied on my own computers you
know I know programming and stuff so
yeah programming is a good thing to get
into I think I'm pretty sure
okay programming I mean depending on you
okay your personality who you are your
dad your mom you know your your
environment where you grew up you know
so it kind of depends on you but for me
and for a lot my followers you know
they are programmers hi Daniel you know
and we you know I think so programming
is great oh great to get into because
that's that gives you a good stable job
you know programming and for the future
because you know as technology we are in
this AI age edge no I don't use corty I
used Warwick I showed my keyboard many
times so this is the keyboard I'm using
so you can see that's my mouse that's my
Canisius keyboard you can just search my
name solid keyboard and I have lots of
reviews and I'm drinking this is tea
yeah I don't use corty I've been uh I
was a QWERTY typist back in 1987 but I
switched I learned back in 1994
to study computer science you Muslim
binary systems yes
oh you use Walkman layout okay so you
are advanced you are a advanced keyboard
enthusiast yeah welcome in layout is one
of the alternative layout and it's great
so let's go to excel keyboard so
keyboard layout alternative keyboard
layout so the squatty is for AK and
there is Walkman Commack is very popular
so this so this is Commack and there is
Walkman Walkman welcome end is a
supposedly a improvement over Commack so
can ask you how did you decide you want
to use Walkman layout so have you tried
Commack and work
oh so you use modified walkman
ah si at the age of 15 oh my god
how did you get that so so you are doing
a lot with computers but you don't
pretty much game so so you are doing
programming you already a programmer
okay yeah
so Daniel says I started with Morag a
few weeks ago and can can go 35 to 40
one per minute I'm right at the point of
going cold turkey with it cool so you
began vorak cool
Danielle you are right yeah so yeah
that's great
letting corty right now oh so you are
trying to do both no that's no good
well I mean well it's not no good but it
is it's not it's usually if you want to
learn a new layout it's it's the
recommendation is usually to go cold
turkey because if you you know try to
still do both that you become there
slows down your learning process
it's significantly so so much so you
know like three times four times because
you don't need to not be out the muscle
memory you know because your muscles are
trying to learn both ways so how rich
smaller says I actually haven't tried
anything outside of Corti and walkman i
jumped directly to walkman since quote
he was really uncomfortable and it's
good enough for me so that i haven't
given any thing else a try
oh so you also walk use walkman amazing
so he'll rich moolah so we have new
people here amazing keyboard layouts I
sometimes have to use other computers
what yeah
silent quote he again yeah that's a
problem you know that that is the
problem so let's talk about keyboard for
maybe lay out for him ten minutes then
we are done for today so the the the the
problem with the quote II you know if
you don't know the subject the problem
with a quote is that the arrangement of
the letters are not efficient I mean
they the history of it of the QWERTY why
the letters are keyboard are arranged
the way they are and and that
arrangement is called QWERTY
you know the reason but why is it
arranged that way the history is kind of
complicated complicated but basically
basically it's to prevent key jams on a
mechanical typewriter you know back back
to years 200 years ago but anyway so but
that arrangement stuck you know we we
learned that habit and so you know even
today we have that arrangement but it's
inefficient
you know so a efficient alternative is
vorak where for example on the wall
right layout all the older vowels are
are on the left hand home row you know
AOE UI and the most frequently used
consonant letters on the red hand home
row so so that means that you do not
when you type you don't have to move
your fingers much you know up town so
most know the most frequently used
letters are on a home row you know so
that's more AK and over the years many
people have created many different new
layouts so people have created new
layouts that are also efficient you know
people create new layout because they
believe you know you know they they
don't think work is the most optimal so
they create actual
they are all pretty much the same the
newer ones okay Borak komak walkman all
these new layout they are you know
pretty much equivalent okay there is
actually no you cannot say one is better
than the other you know there are so
many ways to measure which one is better
but it depends on how exactly you
measured you know how how exactly you
measure it and and the difference you
know the efficiency the result comes out
the score they differ in minor details
because if you change the input you know
you if you change what programming
languages you use or if you change
different input text they the score
becomes different you know so in one
instance of measurement you know Walkman
is better than say Morocco Commack if
you change the input and Commack is
better you know things like that so they
are kind of all different oh pretty much
pretty pretty much similar so you have
all these modern new variations now let
me let me talk about the RSI problem in
the the repetitive strain injury that
actually do not have much to do with
keyboard layout actually if you have RSI
the most important thing is to get a
economic keyboard with mechanical key
switch that is the most important thing
there there is no proof that keyboard
layout foot such as Morocco the Commack
will actually reduce RSI it you know it
logically it helps because it reduce
finger movements but there is no
scientific proof also there is not much
stories from people that actually says
that however there are a lot lot of
stories about using
ergonomic keyboard that actually do help
in reducing eyesight repetitive strain
injury so that is about that then why do
people want to use or why do you want to
learn more a core this well that's
because it actually is more comfortable
for your fingers so that's the thing and
but there are also some other issues for
example there are inconveniences for
example if you go to a library or if you
are working with your co-workers or your
family your members may not be able to
type on your keyboard like every time
you go to a library or any anywhere
public you you cannot touch type because
you know they are using QWERTY then you
have a problem whether you want to learn
you know corty again or you know there
are these kind of inconveniences so
let's read some comments and and I'll be
it for today
yep have you ever tried something like
Provo or any form of stenotype
no and I don't recommend it but I talked
about these two days ago like for a
whole hour about that now don't I don't
recommend Provo at all in fact it's it's
going to make it's it's the fastest way
to get repetitive repetitive strain
injury okay I talked about like an hour
two days ago
check out check out my early videos so I
don't like you know Provo is just a bad
thing it's extremely bad if you want to
do anything like that
I recommend let's see let's go to my
articles I recommend you actually pick
up a steno type machine like that okay
don't use the you don't use computer PC
keyboard to type you know to type the
steno system that that's really bad
okay I think that's about it for today
so you know let's see the
where is the article about keyboards
yeah last week something somewhere here
you know I talked about that a lot
you have to just search it on YouTube
anyway I'm getting tired so that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
great to meet some of you new guys and
Landon from Japan so bye see you guys