good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa show I'm your host
Solly and today we are late I'm late for
six minutes so let's begin and today I'm
planning to talk about JavaScript I'm
going to give you a comprehensive
introduction to JavaScript and depending
on who is here you know and we might we
might switch topics you know if people
if you are here and you are asking a
question you know whoever is here first
so so let's okay today's 21st I think
it's an talk show on you first and let's
go to our talk show showing browser and
we're gonna talk about JavaScript so
talk show 21st that's right and we
cannot talk about JavaScript okay
so JavaScript okay I'm Vic I'm going to
give you a comprehensive introduction to
JavaScript okay you just go to you go to
my JavaScript tutorial this is
JavaScript in-depth okay you just go to
web and search for JavaScript in-depth
saw John J as in-depth and you'll find
my website
let me get my apple juice and energy
drink ready so this is my website
javascript in depth and I spent two
years writing it and it's very good it's
the best out there online opened it you
you won't find any other that's better
they are actually two two resources that
that I would consider as good but you
know if you search for sorry JavaScript
book review you'll find my review of all
the JavaScript resources in English you
know personally its printed or or online
I'll give you a review of them also but
anyway you know try my JavaScript
in-depth and also buy it okay so you can
buy it here it's twenty twenty nine
bucks okay JavaScript in-depth buy it
and you what you get is the entire
JavaScript website in HTML and you can
read you know mostly it's a commitment
you know once you decided you know
JavaScript is the most popular language
used today one one of the top five let's
say and so it's a commitment if you
decide to learn JavaScript then you buy
my tutorial and you can my tutorial is
also reference let's see
it's also you can it's also a reference
so you have you know JavaScript in-depth
coverage and miscellaneous and
JavaScript object references so you find
or you know or or building functions you
can you can use it as a reference so I
think I'm going to give you an
introduction to JavaScript and if you
are here say hi good morning green deck
so so green deck and any others okay if
you have a question ask early okay
because I think okay we're going let's
talk about Java swing in depth I think
I'm gonna talk about for 30 minutes on a
second so um Chavez came in depth now
first of all the you know you when you
learn JavaScript you want to know the
basic syntax and stuff so that's the
JavaScript basics and as for JavaScript
basics you can there you know there are
a lot websites that teaches you the
basic of JavaScript script you know this
there's 3 w 3 w3c there's a Mozilla you
know Mozilla and there's also Microsoft
but actually you you need to be careful
when you read JavaScript tutorials
because javascript is a very complicated
language okay there's lots of watts and
potholes so you don't want to get into
the wrong direction
many JavaScript tutorials online are
misleading to say the least okay
especially true this is especially true
for Mozilla JavaScript tutorial like you
know it's very extremely misleading okay
let's see JavaScript tutorial
so JavaScript tutorial w3c w3 school is
a wast you know you don't want to read
that and the modern JavaScript tutorial
I don't know which one is that so W is
three C's tutorial is very bad
misleading and all and errors you know
it's totally just incorrect even though
it's easy to read but you know if you
want to easy easy easy to read you can
just read my tutorial it's easy to read
so tutorial point is another lame pop
popular JavaScript tutorial then you
have more zeros this code Academy and
there's there's a whole bunch of others
this one is more serious most of them
are there because they want to make
money that's it they don't care about
anything else
they they just want to become the most
popular so that they run ads so they
make money for those who don't know any
programming you know those people who
never not technical people but they they
thought they heard that oh programming
makes money so they want to learn
JavaScript the content is garbage and
you see we have this JavaScript info you
see this see this is idiotic I don't
know you know I don't know I haven't
seen this one this one must be new this
javascript start info but apparently of
course this one is here just to make
money let's see CSS animations you know
I feel
part 3 part 2 gentleman's promise ok
anyway so I don't know about this one I
don't know I haven't seen this one
before this must be new I think ok
anyway so in Mozilla is JavaScript you
know they have like a it's also no good
code Academy
code Academy as far as I know they are a
commercial website I mean they are like
professionally run commercial website
mostly they have videos I if I recall
correctly
code Academy yeah let's take a take a
look
join you see they they want your money
30 time to complete 30 hours join
numbers why don't you escape take away
skills up next field games now filled
with black application with lunch a mess
well yeah I don't have much that and I
don't really have opinions on codecademy
but but first follows I know this these
kind of joints they I guess if you are
learning from you know first of all I
don't know the quality okay I suppose
it's okay because I heard code Academy
and they are very hyper commercialized
you know company they are like companies
I know from firsthand experience that
you can go in knowing zero nothing and
just get a grasp on everything else you
goes that now but let's see who is yeah
I wouldn't you know you know so I I do
not know if code Academy's JavaScript
tutorial is me the misleading or not you
know because many of these are
misleading so but I do not know that for
the code Academy however from what I see
here you can see it's you know it's it's
it's it's written to attract those
people who never have any concept of
programming I mean that the the it's
designed to attract people who don't
know coding at all for example you can
see their quotes you know from this girl
from you know from firsthand experience
that you can go of me knowing zero
nothing and just get a grasp on
everything as you go and start building
right away yeah the does are crap you
know they they want to cash in on people
who don't know nothing and you know
attract them so that they can think oh
they can start to build applications now
you know heck but you know learning the
first language and building applications
right away so they they do not teach
anything in depth you know what happens
is that when you are supposed to if you
are new even if you or if you have some
experience in programming you try to
learn this kind of tutorials which are
designed catered to you know the
population you know trying to make money
fast it's kind of like you know make
money fast scheme so you read their
tutorial okay even though even if you
are experienced programmer but you don't
know JavaScript so you learned from code
Academy or the others you know to learn
the JavaScript language what do you get
okay what what is the result the result
even if their tutor tutorial is not
misleading but the result after really
near to tutorial for let's say three
months okay doing all the homework and
stuff what do you what what you have is
a is basically it says it's a skill that
gets you nowhere like you cannot really
build applications you know are you
kidding me you know those professional
Google whatever you know writing
applications that takes years of
experience so if you have this something
you know here you you learn for a month
and you can build applications that
application is more or less like hello
word you know yeah so I wouldn't
recommend it at all because most of you
you know whoever followed me are you
know you are programmers or you want to
learn stuff you know seriously good
morning web dog no no no mmm DN is the
worst okay a man Chama script tutorials
empty and from the Mozilla is one of the
worst JavaScript tutorial in existence
okay but however the the MD and Mozilla
Weber reference for JavaScript is very
good it's very good to the
point that sometimes it's the only
information you can find I'm talking
about the JavaScript reference I mean
some esoteric things you can you can
find some of that in especially like new
things like JavaScript every year they
have new things so for those kind of
things youyou already have five years of
the experience in JavaScript then mdn is
useful as it's useful in mostly for the
new stuff like every year they have new
stuff you know you you will not find out
the information in any books because you
know books they were already printed so
he owned in that respect and basically
only that respect the MDM reference for
JavaScript the reference part is good
okay the tutorial is one of the worst
because because it's it's misleading and
it's error-prone now when you read a
tutorial especially on some subjects
okay such as certain math topics or
certain complicated programming language
okay on certain topics you want to begin
with a tutorial that's good that's not
misleading that when you read it you
know the reading style gives you a
pattern of thought you know in the right
direction you know you don't want to
read you know another you know that you
want together yeah so makes a good
tutorial makes a difference for certain
subjects on the other hand you know
suppose if you have lots of time you
know you you don't care you just read a
lot then everything works you know you
can read any tutorial just keep reading
you know just like reading a novel you
know but the thing is you don't have all
the time in the world right usually you
want to spend you know you want to be
efficient you know spend X amount of
time and you learn you know good
information so
now ACMA's script standard is also the
worst it's impossible to read even if
you have ten years 20 years of
programming okay so I guess you know
from the questions I see most people
don't know what the app so there's a lot
misinformation out there that's true
yeah a lot of these tutorials also teach
you a framework you know like since ten
years ago all the tutorial tutorials
becomes like that like you don't really
actually learn anything about JavaScript
rather you just learn you know copy
paste this code MPM something something
and you just rent it and you know then
you do follow in the next you didn't
follow the next step is like this step
by step instruction you don't really get
anything out of it so anyway on the
other hand you know if you might if you
learn my tutorial you learn the core
JavaScript the language is defined by
the JavaScript specification you know
I've read several versions of them they
are the worst SPECT among languages so
anyway so you know you know check out my
tutorial buy it
okay so JavaScript basics you know
JavaScript basics so here is you know
you can you know you can follow these
basics you know assignments rhythmic
arithmetic operators how to run
JavaScript and so on okay so I'm not
sure where I'm going now should I
continue should I continue to give you
an introduction to JavaScript or
something else
so Norman says some tutorial yeah so
let's see how long I've been talking so
I already spent 17 it's talking okay so
let me just let's just let's just go
ahead and give a brief introduction to
JavaScript so JavaScript basics you know
you rendered in browser you can learn in
browser in any browser usually you have
you have these inspect elements that see
where all tools web tools so you go to
web tools and develop developer tools on
the Mac is its command option I okay and
you got these consoles and lots of other
things for example elements consoles
they you know the browsers has become a
JavaScript IDE and you know sources it's
actually you know JavaScript and web
applications are extremely complicated
and the browser is on javascript is a
JavaScript web web dev you know
application IDE you can think of that
think of it as that in fact it's
actually I would say it's actually even
more advanced as an IDE it's more
advanced then you know then most other
IDs because JavaScript you know the web
applications you have resources you have
HTTP you need you know you need to find
you know the memory usage and all you
know very complicated and JavaScript
often it's also compiled from other
languages such as typescript so when you
actually do web dev you know you have
all these things you need debugging and
so on so anyway that in in in browser
you can go to you can go to this panel
by just right click like go to any page
in right click and you will see a
inspect elements here inspect okay in
Safari in any browser your cities then
you click on console console is where
you
type your javascript code you can for
example one plus two and you get three
and you can say you can say let x equals
two array okay so three four five so
that's a race so array you get array so
let me um Oh actually you guys cannot
see it sorry about that okay this is
scanning this is going bad okay so yeah
so you right-click and you go to inspect
and you can see the web console and
click on the console then you get a
JavaScript console and you can type
three plus two you get five you can let
X equal two array four two two five nine
so that's array yeah X has already been
been defined so let's say Y okay so why
is an array now so this is how you
evaluate a javascript code you can start
with that
and okay so this is kind of tight
another way is that another way is is
that you download you go to not J's calm
you go to not jazz and you download it
then you can run the not jazz in command
in shell for example let's write nod so
3 + 5 3 plus 4 is 7 and let X equal 2 3
4 2 so that's an array and X is array
and array is array you can try that so
so this is another way to run JavaScript
you download not which is you know
either way it's I would recommend you
download not you know browser is very
convenient but as a program are usually
you working or edited you know either
way is actually fine but however with
not you can actually run as a script for
example Q it open a new file let's say 3
plus 4 let's say console.log ok so save
the file is X X dot J's ok then let's
say console.log 3 first 4 and run it you
see concept so this is a file X X dot
J's that's a file then we go to shell
then used you can say not xx star J's
and that runs the program and up 47 you
see so this is this is convenient if you
are from if you are if you want to use
an text editor to run JavaScript code
but however there's some differences
between nodding and web browser because
okay because javascript is so-called a
hosted language that means in practice
that means the global object in not J's
is global and while in browser is window
for example for example let's see so we
are back in browser you can type window
ok window is actually a object it's a
global object you can you can see window
is actually object with huge number
properties like like over a thousand
number of properties so so that's how
you see it
and but in not jsut don't have the
windows object for example let's see
you know console out window vennett you
see it says reference arrow window is
not defined but however it has a global
object you can run it and you can see
output it's it tries to print the global
the there's an object name called global
and it tries to print all its properties
and stuff so that so that's not not just
you know you can run it in editor if you
are you know oh you can run JavaScript
code in browser now mostly I'm going to
run it in Emacs which is in you know
editor so JavaScript basics so you want
to learn the basic now you can actually
just read the basics on this page
because it shows you how to print the
basic format for string you know you
know string length substring joint
string string methods and with metrics
like plus minus multiply the division
and assignments you know the basic
syntax then you have variables you know
the basic syntax for variables let x
equals to 3 and so on then you have data
types yeah actually I'm a bit lost so I
am am i doing good
we are gonna do a JavaScript
should I continue so so JavaScript
basics yeah so then you have
if-then-else statements so green deck
says what do you think about people who
use emacs SOS like for browser email act
do you use for something other than text
editing okay so maybe we should maybe we
stop talking about javascript then okay
Emacs as an OS I actually don't do that
these states you know back in year 2000
I use Emacs 4 for email for browser as
well you know occasionally in general I
don't do any of that today I use Emacs
purely only for tasks that's text
editing you know for for text files um
be I do not use Emacs to play music I do
not use Emacs to browse the web not for
email not for anything not for anything
that's not text editing okay because
it's it's almost you it's almost all
that always that the dedicated
application is much better for example
the the great the greatest example is
browsers in Emacs you know you cannot
it's it sucks so badly that you know
this you know there's no comparison at
all for example let's just show you
example let's still go to w3 you okay
eat a butyl you is a browser in Emacs so
I'm calling you right now and let's go
to sorry that info okay and you can see
this is how it shows in Emacs okay it
takes a long time then some images shows
up so it looks like this okay
it looks pretty bad you know why because
first of all Emacs does not support SVG
images and then it does not support CSS
you know the CSS for changing a width
what happens going on and and now this
page is completely blank and it's also
dislike five times slower you know like
in a real browser if you go to sorry dot
info so you see you see this that's how
it should look then you have all these
programming tutorials you know all these
SVG images and stuff but in Emacs it
just doesn't work you know so that's a
major you know it's like there's no
comparison
Emacs browser is just for it's useful
fun it's just for certain websites
that's that's text only it's useful in
that way ok such a for example as an
English dictionary
you know dictionary website even that
it's like it's very slow and but the
convenience is that you can you know
everything is in Emacs you can operate
copy paste text and so on so that's an
example of browser and and also email
using email email in Emacs is a
perpetual pain like because email
technology they changes every year you
know back in 2000 so I you know around
2000 1999 to 2001 ok I have used all all
there it is Emacs email clients or I
have used them all for like a year or
two and I also I have also used several
basically all UNIX email clients in in
terminal you know it's hard even to
remember the names but for example in
Emacs you have mail mail is the most
it's the earliest ok there's a command
code mail
okay that's sending an email but our
mail okay the command name is our mail
command name he's all male okay I don't
have you know I it shows nothing because
I'm not connected to a email account
but anyway so eMac in Emacs you have our
mail you have one thing called VC I
think this is from originally from X
Emacs then you have then you have you
have several you know I've tried like
three or four of them I use each one of
them for you know I used a lot you know
I tried them all and also several email
programs that run runs in terminal
including mud
for example mud is one of the later ones
but anyway the email running emails in
terminal in Emacs is always a problem
it's like perpetual problem every
because email technology they changes
every year for example today the most
popular is Google right so if you want
to set up email to connect to Google
from Emacs it's a lot of pain you have
to spend hours you know do it then it
doesn't support lost a lot of features
in email for example back then the
feature the new feature in email you
know back in 1900 1900 1990s email is
basically just plain text then we
started to have attachments and we
started to have HTML email you know with
formatting bold and italics and color
and stuff and then also we begin to have
image files like embedded images or
attachments so when that began as new
you don't have that in your Emacs so you
know people you know everyone is using
it because this features are essential
but you don't have to
well you could have because then you
spend you know ten hours every day to
try to get it to work you know
same thing with HTML and so on okay but
that's back in 2000 then you know
there's new features added in email than
this basically they add things you know
what I would I think that you know once
we have attachments that should be it
you know then we are good to go we can
use Linux or whatever no it turns out
it's not true those applications changes
every every three years I would say so
so every three years Linux or Emacs or
lags behind so basically it's like
permanent lagging behind what everyone
you know no more people is using lagging
lagging behind in features for five
years permanently you know over the
years then you have Unicode then you
have you know lots of things so you max
recent supports so and and you know you
you you really have to spend huge amount
of time to get it to work
but the thing is you know if everyone
who if all your contacts are nerds
you know then that seems to be fine
because all we do is send text mails I
mean we are very careful about what we
send you know like we are you know
technicality conscious you know we we
know the difference between give between
video formats and different video
formats different sound formats
different you know or HTML file versus
versus enriched text versus plain text
you know we are conscious you know about
all these things so we usually choose
the most efficient you know for example
we never embed an image file into a PDF
you know but a lot of people they send
send our PDF but I actually that's the
whole PDF file is just an image file
it's kind of stupid you know like a JPEG
or PNG file in a PDF so anyway so if all
your friends you know contacts are
nerds then you can use emacs
you know email in emacs that works fine
but however almost the most important
contact in your life are not nerds you
know your boss your you know HR
department your company you know what
whatever payment Department banks they
are not nerds okay so they send you
whatever is is the current technology of
email attachments or you know whatever
you know your friends you know
non-technical friends you know you're no
more daily friends or your girlfriend or
boyfriend okay
so they they sent you all the stuff you
cannot read oh you have trouble reading
it all you have to launch
you know PDF video or whatever you know
you have to launch
external file so it's like extreme
inconvenience you know that you you have
that extreme inconvenience and you know
and some of it you can try to fix if you
you you spend you know hours try to get
it to work it's just not worth worth it
so I only used Emacs for purely text
stuff today for IRC I might use you know
Emacs is you know I sometimes I haven't
been using IRC for over ten years but if
I'm going to use I see then I imagine
possibly I could use email but I mean I
could use IRC in Emacs but likely not
because about fifteen years ago I
actually tried I compared running IRC in
Emacs pure text okay versus on the Mac
there's a a RC client one of the popular
ones I forgot which one a DM I think
it's a diem I compare them actually the
ad which is a graphical application okay
learning you know at for IRC the idiom
actually uses less memory more features
and faster than the plain text version
that is true it's so sad you know is
it's it's actually true because and it's
logically true too because you know eMac
eMac based language is very slow so you
know these situations it annoys me to no
end that we hear about from Emacs
community for example reddit Emacs and
all the Nerds you know they say oh you
max is great this or that or you should
run emails in my castle Oh you
know patently untrue crap you know so
that you know so it pains me every time
I see those kind of things because the
way it became its that way because it's
a code you cannot like you cannot say
anything you cannot tell the truth like
if someone on rated Emacs they say ok oh
I love many emails in emails for example
then suppose I try to point out you know
oh but you got these problems then you
got an army of people shutting you down
like shouting you down oh yeah but but
the Emacs can do this or that but but
this that that you know that's the
situation and you got voted down so you
know they wrap the it's like that it's
because it's a code because because
there's a code situation going on
because everyone is like you want to
this is the right thinking you cannot
think other than this way you know Emacs
is the best of everything in a world
that that's the correct way you know if
you go outside outside of that people
don't like you you know that that's
that's what happens and in turn that
makes Emacs worse and worse no progress
you know because if you think about it
you know this is my big Emacs flame okay
Emacs is such a great editor you know it
is it is I mean it is true I I still use
him of course I use Emacs I am a master
of emag list master of Emacs
have the most efficient system then any
editor because you know you can
customize to the way you want so it's
great but why is that nobody use it uses
it I mean in reality actually very few
people use use it you know most people
use you know they even you know for text
editors they use Adam or Microsoft you
know code and stuff so what you know
it's it's a insult it's almost like a
insult you know so you have like such a
great editor but nobody use it why is
that in the same way it's true for Linux
you know you have a great operating
system Linux and it's free and Microsoft
and apples they cost $100 $200 and you
know the other things so why should you
you know it should know you know
everyone should be using Linux already
but that's not happening why is that
it's really truly because Linux and
Emacs in comparison all things
considered truly sucks so badly it's
like the worse they are the worst
possible okay they waste your time they
just no good okay but it needs not to be
that way actually week we you know we'd
nerds together we can actually we can
really makes new Macs better than
anything and and it's still free and
used by everyone okay like like a month
program like for example I'm a
professional programmers today how many
percent people people use Emacs like
less than 0.001 percent using Emacs
now that's an insult you know that
doesn't you know so you know to us Emacs
is such a great editor why does that
happen
then most Emacs people will say you know
in an Emacs mmunity will say oh because
most people are stupid
oh because they don't appreciate they
don't understand no the real reason is
because you
you know you Emacs code fans you know do
not believe reality you cook up these
fancy things you know you're extremely
idiotic keybinding unreadable
documentation with 10,000 jargons that
is why that is why nobody is switching
to Yuma Emacs but these things are can
be easily fixed you know but you'd put
but why can't I fix it I mean why can't
we change it because it's a code okay
but there are many of us are reasonable
people we can maybe we can spray the
information so stop the code mentality
and made and maybe Emacs becomes you
know widely popular but that's not easy
because the reason is that because it's
a politic political situation it's a
power struggle which is why code remains
a code most of the time because they are
there's a power play going on they are
control for example emails Emacs Emacs
is controlled by Richard Stallman and
he's got you know it's a political
situation there's a power going on it's
not just oh let's think rationally and
you know and fix whatever and remove the
code situation no because it's a power
they have to remain in power because
once you well anyway so so that's my
reason so first of all Emacs is you know
not that popular because because we are
in reality Emacs all things considered
okay important this is important all
consider everything Emacs is not a bit
good because it's really just bad it's a
bad editor okay bad everything else okay
all things considered cut you know for
all professional programmers not just to
you and me you know a few handful elite
nerds you know who do nothing except
staying at home and you make stuff so
it's the product is bad so why is it
remain bad for like so long why can't we
change because it's a code there's a
code mentality
same thing happens with Linux you know
UNIX philosophy and all this crap okay
that's why but why why why won't the
coat go away because there's a power in
involved it's a political situation and
it's controlled by Richard Stallman and
you know some of the Emacs dev and
whoever some of the Emacs devs because
that is why basically
yeah take a look marty is great yeah oh
c'mon he's great okay I'm kind of lost
you know I was going to this is a talk
show you know I was going to talk about
JavaScript comprehensive introduction
but I guess that's kind of went away but
you know the problem is that I don't
have a fixed schedule like you know you
would be great if I say okay today like
like you know set out the plan for the
next ten days you know and set out the
time so you know at 1 o'clock p.m. we're
gonna talk about JavaScript you know
next day and after tomorrow we cannot
talk about Emacs and after that we're
gonna talk about code situation of
programmers you know if I do that I
think it will be better but you know I
so that's the issue you know so I wasn't
I wasn't sure about fixing a plan so
what else guys anything else interesting
what comments comments or questions or
no anything you disagree okay you know
feel free to say it so yeah we have the
Emacs code situation we have JavaScript
so yeah so back to the question about
using Emacs as a OS I don't do it and
because it's it's not practical but the
other thing is you know Emacs is so
called single threaded so if I run you
know I've done you know I've done them
on and off you know using Emacs to play
music using Emacs to do everything you
know have I been there
the problem is you know you know usually
Y you know when you use Emacs you know
that you are using it to program right
which is important but if you run a
bunch of other things and the other
things may crash Emacs like when you
start to run IRC or whatever image you
know music you know or whatever they may
crash and they will bring down your
whole Emacs so that's a major problem
you know when your Emacs crashing you
are you know you might be programming
something you know in the middle of it
so so that's also why I avoid using
Emacs for anything else other than you
know just edit just text editing also
when you run a shell in Emacs doesn't
matter it's Alicia or you know bash in
so-called inferior Xiao Jing Emacs
usually if you know that you are going
to run a long shell job such as
compiling something big ok you don't
want to run it in Emacs as well because
the you know Hugh thousands of lines
they parked down Emacs also also is it's
prone to crashing max you know so once
it crashes then you lost all your you
know the output in shell so yeah so for
any serious shell task I always go to
you know the Rio terminal instead
yeah Joe Armstrong passed away I
mentioned about that yesterday yeah Adam
looks good you know the thing about Adam
you see the thing about Emax is that I
always thought that the idea the idea
the the co idea of Emax is not very
difficult to replicate I mean the
essential idea Emacs is that you have
this basically you have a this
interpreter okay that's a core of
everything you know so it's a this much
it's a it's a list machine all this list
in my environment but basically the
essence the bottom line the heart is a
lisp interpreter that is the whole
engine and that's dynamic so so you have
this so the idea of having this you know
listening a language interpreter that
builds everything I think that's the
essence of Emacs
okay and I thought that's not difficult
to replicate today either in a lisp
language or in another language you know
it may be in ragged skin base or maybe
in Ruby Python even you know Python or
JavaScript I think we can do that not
too difficult we we just need some you
know some ultra program I'm not capable
of that okay but we I know that they are
quite a lot people who are capable of
that I know a few for example in Emacs
community the one guy named Danielle you
know who wrote the essay about butterfly
about you know it's about Emacs
windowing system but anyway so there are
few people who are capable of doing that
you know you typically those are people
who
who knows see well like they they know
low-level programming well but anyway so
I thought it's actually easy to
replicate the Emacs the essence of Emacs
system and I thought that Adam was one
of them but it I haven't really looked
into Adam but it seems actually not
because I know other programmers Emacs
users for example David Capital I think
he looked into Adam and he says that
basically nah it's not like it does not
have the essential like the essence of
Emacs it's not like Emacs okay even
though I mean it's written in JavaScript
and JavaScript is the scripting language
so in a sense you have the the Adam
editor has embedded language you know
JavaScript and it's also written in
JavaScript but however it does not have
as far as I know it does not have the
nature of the Emacs where you can just
you know in real time then dynamic
dynamically change your things by by
using javascript yeah so that's for some
reason that's that's the case you know I
haven't looked into but I always wanted
to but but I just don't you know didn't
get the time to do that but from what I
hear from other people is it doesn't
seems to capture the essence of Emacs
do you know what color scheme is best
for eyes like white text on black
background in vice versa
or maybe gray or something I think I
think the best is actually going on
black horse near Seon on black holes or
orange on black basically you want a
black background that's that is the best
if you are using some kind of
illuminance illuminance technology like
your screen shines you know light then
you want a black background okay I think
that's actually the best for the eye but
however it's not practical because every
website they have white background so so
it's not good if you you know I don't
think it's good you constant two
constants we switch from a black
background and then to a white
background you know that's just a fact
you know that's just how things are
because most website you know using
white background so that that is why I
don't use you know black background much
in Emacs I you know I only have it in
terminal but other than other than that
my background is kind of it's called
it's called honey drew let's see
keyboard yeah okay let's go to my Emacs
settings
who's this page
okay so here is my Emacs settings and if
we go to it's on github as well if you
if we go to basics okay
where's basics settings
okay this file wait let me delete the
backup file so this file
Emacs settings so that's that is my
background background color honey true
and everything else is default I don't
use special colors because I prefer
simplicity I want I don't want no frills
no nothing any fields I don't like okay
any any kind of fancy look so anything I
want the most raw basic and functional
note it's important I want to be
functional not just raw or basic I want
it to be the most functional possible
not as opposed to the more the most raw
or the most primitive or the most you
know UNIX philosophy my ass kind of
thing I know a lot MX people they are
you they are interesting for example
they want to turn off the scroll bar you
see the scrub on the right they want to
turn that off they they want to turn off
and they want to turn off of menu and
all that no that's no good okay because
the score bar is actually the most
efficient visual feedback for for where
your cursor is relative to the whole
fire scuba okay not not you know the ten
percent the bottom ten percent at the
so-called Mart line this line Emacs is
called mod line okay
you know you see that 22 percent that's
actually your kusa position let's see so
you can see that
so that means I'm at 37% of the page yet
that's that's good if you
in terminal but anyway the score by ism
is is the most effective visual feedback
for week where your Kusa
are but you can see sorry Emax
background so all my settings and tricks
are on my website so let's see you max
let's just go to Emacs
then you can find what is this page
practically max tutorial huh eh let's
search for color it's not there
oh it's in it's in in each setup so here
you can see this page set color theme so
that's a tutorial about color themes and
I also show you how to set up your
background color without using color
themes I don't like you know I don't use
color themes at all and it's kind of
funny it's also you know color this page
is actually the most one of the most
popular page in my MX tutorial and also
on reddit you know everyday you know
color theme is one of the most frequent
topics like everyone wants to know you
know wants to know about color thing or
what what color theme you use you know
what it yeah you know they like to talk
about that you know I think it's like
back it's like a bike shade situation
you know where the most brainless things
you know everyone wants to talk about
because you know it's color you can see
it you know color how do you adjust your
color so you know everyone can see it
everyone everyone can understand it
everyone can play with it and you know
it seems like you are doing something
you know with your you max settings so
so every month you know already you know
it'll be a discussion about color themes
yeah I don't use it at all
I only set the background to - honey
drew color so as to not make it white
you know because it's pure
white I think it's less you know pure
white is less easy on your eyes
oh the syntax coloring DD so so Norman
says Rob Pike is in famous for saying
syntax coloring is childish did he did
he actually say that do you have a
reference I would like to see that you
know in the early days like in 1900
1990s there are some programmers who do
not like syntax colouring and one of
them is Eric naggin who is known who is
well known as the most famous troll
among these communities so Eric nagging
he died in 2009 oh wow it's ten years
now so he's a famous Common Lisp
programmer and he has written an essay
about I think it's him yeah I'm pretty
sure yeah I'm pretty sure he did he does
not use syntax coloring he don't he do
not think it's good so back in 1990s
they are quite a number of programmers
who say that but I did I don't think
that's I disagree with their idea I
think they are actually wrong because
because syntax coloring actually help
you identify the locations of your code
you know any specific location more
efficiently and I think it's it can be
proven scientifically to you know just
by you know you can do statistics you
can you know test people's comprehension
you know of syntax coloring
versus no syntax going for example for
example this is my image in a file okay
so you got a bunch of list code now if I
turn everything to you know if I turn
off syntax : let's say font log mod okay
means you don't have color anymore it's
not as readable because color lets you
you know spots you know different parts
you know because Steven part of the code
on a long page they they have different
colors so you can easily identify you
know which section you know are where
you know so doesn't matter how it is
syntax colored as long as you have just
a little bit syntax coloring it helps a
lot and I think that's a scientific
truth so those for those people who
think scene syntax coloring is for
children
I doubt they are you know I kind of
question their judgment so Rob Pike says
syntax highlighting his juvenile when I
was a child I was taught arithmetic
using colors rod coloured rods I grew up
in today I use monochromatic números now
it is it true that he still do not use
syntax coloring I would be curious to
know yeah because you know people might
change you know the other thing okay let
me let me make a guess okay the other
thing about this kind of issue is that
it has a lot to do with habit okay
a lot has to do with her habit like like
if I start to code with our syntax
colouring for a few weeks then I will
get to you and we will get used to it
then I will be fine with our syntax
coloring seriously I mean if you try it
I'm pretty sure you'll get the same
conclusion you know try for one week
without any syntax coloring you know for
the first few days you'll be painful but
after two weeks let's say two weeks you
you will get to use it used to it okay
then you will have no problem then when
you then if you turn syntax coloring
again you will find it jari you know
it's habit you know that this is kind of
like that's what habit is doing to us so
so I think what happens with Rob Pike
and some other people is that you know
they just get to use it you I mean they
just get used to it and and they never
tried to change you know back in those
days when when you know Rob Pike is one
of the old guys you know gray beard I'm
not sure he's got gray beard but anyway
he's you know that class programmers but
anyway so he grew up without syntax
coloring because syntax coloring was not
introduced around say 1995 awesome maybe
a bit before there was no saint syntax
coloring before in fact in fact Emacs do
not support syntax coloring in for a
while in even up to 1999
I think but X Emacs does so if you can
see sorry
Emacs versus X Emacs
so I have a documentation I wrote that
documents my experience of Emacs versus
X Emacs you know back then X Emacs is
better than Emacs in every way
so I documented some
the issues I remember you know so this
is returning in 2007 by anyway yeah
thanks for that Rob Pike said
okay so Norman says coloring Emacs font
lock mod was added by jwz in lucid X
Emacs if I remember correctly yeah
that's probably true so you are old you
are an OB yeah you know jwz is one of
the colorful character in programming
community I've you know I have exchanged
exchanged email with him a few times
since since year 2000 or something so
but a few year ago I stopped you know he
turned he turned me off because you know
has to do with politics anyway he's one
of those guys who talk a lot you know
like among programmers some some
programmers you have you know a handful
you know of a small percentage of
programmers who talk or beaver me for
example
JW z is one example ESR is another
example eric s Raymond and you know who
wrote the bazaar and cathedral in bazaar
and other things you know yeah so there
are few performers you know who talks a
lot all the time
so jwz so a man also Olli Lina's yeah
leanest Robert he's one of the guy who
talks and also typically dramatically
none stop so anyway III admire jwz you
know for like 20 years and here and here
in 2016
I think it's 2016 he he he he he banned
me on Twitter for political reasons I
don't think it's reasonable because you
know because he he he want
to vote for Hillary Clinton okay okay
that's that's fine with me but anyway
but I criticized I mean I anyway I
didn't even criticize him anything about
politics
one day I post something about Pearl but
because our previous issues about
politics he banned me so that kind of
turned me off very very much about him
so anyway I think that's it for today
yeah anything else
he so he was always on the left I act
yeah okay you you are probably right but
I don't know anything about it you know
I'm not into politics on the left you
know
like throughout 1990s and 2000's and I
mean up to okay up to 2016 up to the
Trump situation okay I was always I mean
III my oh my hotel life I live in
California which is you know in in in
the heart of Silicon Valley so
everything I read you know I'm you know
on the left of course I do not like the
Conservatives I do not believe in God
you know I in fact back then you know
when the Conservatives are in the power
you know they want to they want to send
some home okay they want to you know you
have to dress you know in your suit like
they have they are family men okay they
they are more moral people you know you
cannot do this you cannot do that we
must you know like you know they are
conservatives you know a family or
whatever you know you I'm so I'm you
know especially like believing in God
okay I don't believe in God you you know
but but they but they want to control
you that like Jesus like you have to
come you have to believe in God oh you
know you you know you know you know for
example you know on the US dollar bill
you have in God We Trust and you know
things like that so I didn't you know
I'm always I'm a suddenly or liberal I'm
actually more of a like a libertarian
you know as far as each ideology goes
you know I got anyway but since 2016 the
social justice can rose that so that
turned me freed me flipped me my
political views completely so so so you
know it's like
I actually I believe pretty much the
same but today's Democrat you know it's
not it's not a liberal is the the
meaning of liberal changed you know they
become something else they become this
social justice cat extremely evil these
scumbags ten times more worse than then
then the Conservatives okay this today's
social justice can these people end that
that is why when I have this you know
situation with jwz that pissed me off
and he was you know back like he wrote
an article back in 2016
he wrote article you know kind of like a
hint keyboard you know you can go to wit
his website you'll find an article
basically the article is about the
engine of the Mozilla logo you know that
dinosaur that dinosaur
you know the Mozilla has this logo they
actually changed yeah this you see this
tent dinosaur okay they actually changed
it today you know me I mean so but
anyway so it's like that you know but
back then it's not it's actually it it's
not like that it's a bit different but
anyway he discussed you know jwz
discussed the origin of this something
similar to that
yeah and even you know III can find the
original logo but it'll take a while so
let's see
but anyway so jwz wrote an article about
about the arrangement of the Mozilla
logo and the name okay essentially
basically he comes down to he says that
he because he want to push communism I
mean the idea is it's it's borrowed from
communism the logo the thing you know
red color and you know because back back
then the open source just speaking this
is around 1999 you know the open source
just began and Mozilla is the first
company that because Netscape failed you
know Netscape lost to the browser war to
Microsoft and Sony Escape is no longer
commercially commercially valuable you
know then they put it to open source you
know when when you don't have anything
you put it to open source so that's
basically the first major open source
project you know besides Linux you know
Mozilla was commercial software that
became open source okay the first anyway
so happy easter pace
so today's easter you know it's easter
is the american holiday i don't even
know i heard about easter so that's
today uh yeah I didn't know so I'm
supposed to hunt eggs somewhere so
anyway what else I think we've talked
long enough
our fourteen anything else so no man no
man I think JW was okay yeah so jwz but
I don't know what's his political views
so anyway but anyway anyway yeah so he
wrote the article you know basically
basically he is hinting he wants people
he is telling people that oh we must
vote hallory because
this is so critical you know he's trying
to express that but I think I made a
comment I made a comment saying that
both of them are bad okay both of them
are bad something like that I made a
kind of a tongue-in-cheek common in in
the same kind of style like he's doing
like he's telling people okay please go
vote for Hillary but he does not say it
you know he's the type of a guy you know
who is kind of you know playing around
with words you know he doesn't often you
know he doesn't say exactly what he
means he want to you know play around
with words
you know maybe many of you think you
know I'm I think I get an impression
that many people think I'm the same way
you know because well anyway anyway so
he's kind of like that so I responded I
think I'm Twitter you know I I responded
in the same kind of fashion you know
basically I'm saying you know both of
them are bad you know whatever you think
oh we must vote for Harry it's actually
that's that's just your opinion it's not
you know valid so I made some comment
like that and he and by the way it's not
insulting he's not in Saudi him or
anything you know I just made kind of a
tongue-in-cheek comment you know because
he posts a comment I have a you know
then I have opinions I post my you know
kind of you know let's see who can you
know who can write you know poetry
better you know so what did he do I
he replied okay anyway we can actually
find it let's see
Saudi jwz Twitter okay I think we can
find the I hope we can't find it then he
blocked me not for that okay he didn't
block me okay that's fine okay so I made
a comment and he replied okay then then
then that you know then nothing happens
okay but next day he
was posting something about pearl okay
then I'd retreated his pose with my own
opinion and my opinion is like oh my god
he is people still using pearl you know
you should dinosaurs you know something
like that something to that effect then
he banned me oh yeah he was asking a
question about pearl I think you know
he's the one of the old guy who doesn't
learn you know who don't learn he's just
sticking to technologies from 1990's
last time I heard that he is still using
X Emacs you know like I think he's wrote
an article about how he see no reason to
change you know for the past 10 years
whatever Emacs improvement he see no
reason to change its using e XE Mac's
compiled from 2000 year 2000 something
like that so anyway so next day he made
a comment he asked the question about
pearl eye I'd be treated note I'd
retreated not reply to his twin okay I
retreated he's he's post about pearl
with my own comment on top then he
blocked me you know that I considered
that turned off you know that turned me
off then I can see that that's that's
not a good person's behavior because
okay you have your political opinions I
have my okay you made a post about it
I replied you know it's a public forum
you know and I didn't insult you you
know you know I post my opinion okay we
disagree that's fine then you post your
opinion you post something about pearl
I'd be treated and I posted my opinion
about Pro and also I did not insult it's
not like I'm in so doing him nothing
like that
you know but but it's not like it's not
like ass-kissing you know way you know
I'm not kissing his ass and I'm just
making my own opinions about because I
despise pearl okay I hate pearl so I
make my opinions rather negative but not
you
anyway you know insulting to him or any
anyone I make my opinions about pearl
you know rent you know a little one
sentence read you know something like
people still using power then he brought
me so that to me that's it's like no
good it's not the serious thing okay you
know we had some disagreement you know
this is some grew up you know some
friction about political opinions then
he says something I say something then
he blocked me yes you know it's no big
deal
so I wasn't you know I was not like oh
you know this guy is a bad guy nothing
like that you know it's just I'm just
mentioning it mentioning it you know I
say you know a story so but because of
he because he did that so I didn't you
know I don't think that's a good thing
you know one should do you know so he's
a bit negative and I stopped I stopped
you know he blocked me so I stopped you
know because before like almost every
every few years I have articles
discussing you know issues programming
and that often mentions him you know and
links to his website so you see you see
the thing about that is even i mean
before all these we had several
exchanges over the past twenty years
like fifteen years we have you know you
you know some
nothing bad exchanges you know before
example this one in 2016 earlier we were
talking about keyboard and mouse but
anyway twitter makes it hard to find but
if i'm very sure you can find the trait
in question where we kind of qward
dear oh my god Dion you are so late I'm
actually I'm gonna curse down so because
I've been talking for like you know 19
90 minutes so why do I use OSX well only
because a professor gave me a Mac Mini
two years ago that is why because I
don't have money to buy Mac you know
computers so but anyway so I got it free
so you know that is the main reason I'm
on the Mac alright I talked about my
history of using Mac or Windows and
Linux in you know a month or two ago
like for a long time but anyway so and
Mac is good you know it's just you don't
have to worry about things because
otherwise on Linux it's like every two
days I mean literally statistically
every week you spend about three hours
teetering you know just you know didn't
Linux stuff like how do why something
doesn't work or tricking the user
interface you know window management you
know window managers in you know x11 and
all these you spend you spend few hours
every day you know yeah all those kind
of things you know for some reason and
something doesn't work why doesn't this
install oh I cannot get my audio to play
when I'm streaming or something you know
it's like like that like that Linux it's
extreme pain in the ass that's a
situation I really hope not to be the
case but just the Linux people you know
as I said before it's a the problem is
with a code you know the ideology that's
hurting it the open source ideology and
the code mentality because we really
should Linux really should be you know
should have already wiped out Microsoft
at least you know it's a free system and
you know could add
but then you have the open-source
ideology and basically then the Linux
people of course everyone is open-source
but actually everyone fights internally
you know fights for power you know you
have you know your distribution my
distribution you know I create a new
window you know manager and things like
that you know power struggle that that's
what happens to communism you know
that's what happens to communism because
on the surface you know everyone abides
to the ideology you know we all peaceful
we share everything there's no private
properties okay but in reality you you
suck you you have lots of problems then
you have power struggle but you cannot
do it in a way that that's explicit it
becomes in internal you know it becomes
run about in other ways you fight for
power in you know for stuff and nobody
wants to do anything because you know
you don't get nothing you don't get
benefits you know everything is supposed
to be shared and actually there's a
people you know there's a lot of open
source communities and there are people
who study communes you know the this
kind of ideology like for example
communism is you you know the government
niche national scale okay war scale then
you have free software which is kind of
a among programming you know community
is kind of a thing or open-source that's
another you know faction but there are
also lots of other you know kind of
hippie or this of ideology of you know
commune communities like there's no
private property there's no you know
ranking you know like you know company
you have ranks you have your you're the
CEO you know you have your you know your
boss you know so but anyway a lot of
people didn't you know they disbelievers
you know imagine there's no countries
idiotic believers they so they have this
kind
Mews they start to build you know in
some small town and there are people who
studied these communes you go there and
study them they all fail failures in
fact this all ugly very ugly things
going inside and horrible things
so anyway actually let me show you the
article let's see if I can find an
article that's a great article because
this guy actually spent a lot of time to
visit you know all the words
you know this basically the idea of
communism
you know the different groups of commune
communes typically they have one guru
which is their leader for example in in
free software foundation we have Richard
Stallman you know he's sitting there
every day we will be like you know we
were you know Emacs Church of Emacs
and you know whatever
singing his songs and he get money of
course because he's ahead he doesn't
have to worry about food even though
it's not like wealthy it's not a you
know medium airs living but he you know
he he get to live free you know he he
got donations but not everyone else join
you icon you he great let's see how do
you I okay the easiest ways actually go
to my go through my Emacs block and then
search the directory for comm you and
okay search it
okay that's too many that's such again
comm you and II
let's search for ideology
okay
let's search for site okay here here's
our ago y utopian communities fail okay
I'll leave it at that you know you guys
you know if you like you can read that
page and that's it for today let's wait
for this page to run yeah
y utopian communities fail you know it's
a it's a big article that he surveyed
you know other communes and and write
down their problems okay so thank you
guys I mean bye I'll see you next time