Hello, good morning. Good morning
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
Sad Talk Show. We are going to code Emac
Lisp today. Nothing but Emac Lisp. So,
let me introduce my keyboards. This is
glove 80. Fantastic. I have a review on
each one of them on YouTube. This is
ultimate hacking keyboard. Fantastic.
This is new trackboard. Fantastic. And
this thing is called board. S V A L B O
A R D. There are two parts. And this is
magnetic switch. Uh, fantastic. But I
haven't got to use uh I haven't used it
yet. I promised each video until I use
it every day. Each video I'll, you know,
shout out do a shout out. SV A L B O A R
D. Okay. I have an intro, but you can
watch other people's uh review on
YouTube. You'll find. Um, so let's do
Emacs. lisp. So it's pure emac bisp
coding. Hello talmid.
Pure emac this coding. We're just going
to focus on that. Okay. Uh stream bit is
my stream alive and well. So tell me.
Okay. So immac coding. So uh if you are
watching this offline play at 1.5 speed
or higher because I ramble just like Joe
Rogan monkey.
And now so now let's focus on this. So
there's a command we live streamed uh uh
about two month few month ago. So let's
let me show you. Okay. So for example I
have a number
okay so you see uh can you see let's see
check the uh check check. Okay 168. Now
I want to increase number. So normally
let's say I want to it be 189.
So you delete it then type 189 89 that's
tedious. Okay like usually so what I can
do let me show you press a key and I can
scroll the mouse wheel to increase or
decrease. You see fantastic or I can use
this mouse the other mouse you cannot
see but it's got a spin wheel. So it
just increase
this magnify. Okay. So for example the
command. Okay. So the command you can
see in the pink window increment number
on the right hand side and on the left
hand side is a keystrokes I used to type
that backspace is right here under my
left hand thumb right here. Uh and so
that command fantastic I can just uh
press a key to begin it. I can score the
mouse wheel up or down or I can press
the arrow key up up arrow or down arrow.
So we live streamed coding this um few
months ago. Let's see if we can find it.
Kasar talk show homepage. Okay on.infos
on my website without https no s. Okay.
So search for increment. Okay. Search
for there it is. Uh talk show 2025
January 23rd episode 69. Emac be coding
increment digit. Okay.
So uh increment so
but there's a issue we're going to fix.
Okay. So if you have a date, you know
let's you know today's date. So I want
to change it to tomorrow 9th. Okay. So
start the command it become you know it
dropped the zero padding.
So usually you know so that's annoying
undo. So we want to modify the command
so that it so whatever how many zeros in
front padding will be kept. Okay.
Okay. Let's do that.
So far so good. Hope you are well. Hi
audio. Hi qu. Uh, hi my goat. Uh, hi
audio. Okay, let's So, let's do Yeah.
Okay. So, let's do uh wait uh let's go
back. So, there's a command. So, let's
go to the source code. Uh let's see if
the source code is available online so
you can use it. No, it's not. Uh because
otherwise you'll have a URL. So, why
don't we make this command available
online? publish on my website so you
guys can grab it. Let's do that.
Uh as far as coding you you know you can
watch last you know the the video. So
we've done so let's just let's just
quickly create a URL for I mean put it
on my website. Okay.info
Emacs blog. Search for Emacs blog.
You'll find everything you want to know
about Emacs. There are like uh 700 pages
uh most comprehensive tutorial on Emacs
and Emacs in it on Emacs keys and Emacs
uh
and Emac list the language and uh uh you
know the EMAC list the language and how
to write the major mod everything. Okay,
that's the most popular Emacs and EMAC
list tutorial on the web. So let's see
uh Emacs block. So okay so let's write a
command. Where do you want that command
to be? So
uh so actually let's go faster. Okay. So
let's go faster. Let's just quickly put
the code on my website. So first of all
uh let me go to so that's part of the
Emacs commands. Okay. So you know so
there are all these EMAC command you can
copy. Okay. So copy that. So let me just
do it quickly. Okay. So what is this
page? Emacs blog. Okay. Create a new
section. Paste uh link. Okay. Then go
here and say clone file in link. Okay.
Then cut it and put it here. And here is
a new page and rename it. Uh ren rename
the link. So this is will be increment
number. Okay. So what is the command
name? Uh there it is. Kasa increment
number. Copy. Go back here. So the
command name is that. Okay. So rename
the file path uh emac increment number.
Okay. Let's just uh let's just say that
change change to underscore in uni code
name. That's called low line which is a
better name than the underscore. Okay.
So wait enter. Yeah. So wait I don't
want um well. Okay. So I don't want
hyphen. Um I want underscore. Okay. Now
there is something going on. Why is it
slow?
Something is not right.
Wait.
Okay. So anyway then title title is
going to be uh increment number. Okay.
Um
sac command actually.
Wait. Uh, actually I copied the wrong
page. Yeah, I don't want that page.
Okay, so actually let's do this all over
again. Open it. Delete the file. Uh,
then go to one of one of these command.
Go to the top general purpose command
buffer. Copy file path. Close. Close.
Okay. Put it here. Linkify it. Then go
here and clone file in link. So now
cut that link. Make a list. make a list.
Okay. And then rename this increment
number. Okay. So, rename the file path
uh emac. Okay. Uh increment number.
Delete delete that. Change change to
underscore increment number. Yes. Okay.
Then delete that. So this command name
will be called increment number. Okay.
So paste previous. There it is. Then
make them space and capitalize each
word.
Okay. Cuz I increment number. Okay. So
delete that. Open that and go back. Go
here. Paste it there. That's a command
we're going to uh do. And now and you
need to change the file title. So go
back here. So copy the
that uh inner text. Okay. D copy. Okay.
Now open it. Now rename the title and uh
rename the
rename the title and the H1. Okay. So
you there is a command like that. Then
you just say that. Okay. So that
fantastic. Can you see? Okay. Showing
browser. So this is a copy a clone of
the previous file. So we don't need the
previous section. So okay. But first of
all, change modify the updated date.
Okay, done. And you don't need uh the
other parts.
Uh
okay, because this is fresh file. And
then okay and actually the actually we
need that. Okay, then the section delete
section delete showing browser.
Fantastic and beautiful. Go back to
Emacs. Now copy the file path. Close.
Now,
rename this. Make sure it's correct.
Wait. Um,
what?
Okay. So,
yeah. So, showing browser. This is my
Emacs. That's a new file. Fantastic. And
this old one, this is a clone from we
don't need. Okay. So, open that. Copy
the file path. Now, go back to the
source code there. So you need to say a
URL.
URL is this file path. We need to turn
it into a qualified domain URL. So press
press.
It becomes casi.info. Fantastic.
Capitalize the URL and press press.
That's the special syntax in Emacs
inline documentation.
You see? So that's so that you need the
back tick and then you need a straight
apostrophe.
Okay?
Because when you have that when you have
this this is a markup. So when you have
this then then let's say uh let's change
the version date. Okay. Uh okay then
evaluate the buffer. Fantastic. And now
if you do copy that if you do describe
function sign increment number and
here's a documentation and you can see
it you know there's a link you can click
and jump to. So that is why you need
this uh markup. So if you search for
Emacs inline documentation markup um
in my my EMAC tutorial
uh doc markup so you can see emac do
dark string markup so it tells you all
the conventions you need to do you can
have a clickable link that's what this
is for okay so so you got the code so
you got the code uh I mean you got the
URL okay so now we need to copy the code
this code and put it to uh this talk
show close that uh let's copy the code
and put it to this page okay so normally
I just do it manually let's say close
that okay wait reopen
normally I just do it manually but let
me show you something okay so uh add a
emac list this code and uh and cut that
put here and remove that show in
browser. So right now it's a dummy. So
normally I just go to the source code,
go to the source code, copy this, you
know, block of text and go to the file
and uh then insert here and uh syntax
correct. But now
few weeks ago we did this live. So I can
it's automated. So let me show you. You
just go to wherever the source code is.
Let's suppose you made some update then
press press
then it automatically find the file via
that URL and in fact update the page now
showing browser
fantastic so now this is public you can
copy and grab for your own use now did I
call any commands that's not here no so
it's all plain new emacs
the power of Emacs and emac is the most
efficient editor. Okay. And that command
is update code to website.
Uh that's what uh you know few weeks ago
we did the live stream which I didn't
finish the coding but uh I did it
offline. So anyway so here's a code. So
now our job is to modify the code so
that it keeps the padding. Okay. So
showing browser back to Emacs close. Uh
so let's go to what is this page? Uh
talk show. Uh actually so since we added
that uh let's uh what is this page? Talk
show. So we can add a link here. So
there there it is. There it is. We can
actually directly link to um the file we
just created. Okay. Now but um
okay fantastic.
Fantastic. So now what is the job? The
the the now the job is to modify this
code. Okay. So you want to keep the
padding. Okay. So let's demo again. Co
you see increase 13 14 6 19 25 19
5 4 3 2 1 11 10 and ban. It missed the
digit. You see we want to keep the
padding. Okay. So uh so we let's undo.
So what is this? Uh what's original?
[ __ ] I forgot what's original. Undo.
Undo. Undo. Undo. Oh, wait. What? Okay.
So original is that. So uh here today's
date. Um yeah. So let's make it today's
date. Okay. So we need to keep the
padding. What to do? So we now we need
to think um well
have some red wine. This is 100 ml or
150 ml red wine to sooththe my soul.
Why do you need to sooth your soul?
Because when you read politics today on
Twitter, it's
uh very painful and ugly things.
Uh and here is my uh here is my uh you
know uh my discord. If you haven't been
there, you can join.
Hello, Hank. Ching. Thank you, Hank.
Okay, Hank says, "I'm going to stream
after you are finished. I just got a G
game working for someone else."
A game working for someone else. Nice.
Am I doing well? Say hi. How do you like
it so far? Is it is it is this
comprehensible? Okay. Now we need to
think about this uh you know thinking is
the hard part. So so beginning position
end position that's uh integers. Let's
uh mark the beginning position of a
number. Okay. So you search backward uh
of all digits. Then that's a beginning
set it to the beginning position point
is the current cursor position. Okay.
Then you skip char forward to the end of
the digit. Then you set to the end. So
far so good. Do I understand it? Yes.
Now xnum is you grab the two positions
beginning and end and that grabs a
string. That's xnum. Okay. So let's uh
so let's can you know let's highlight
it. Okay. Xnum.
Now, so Xnum
if so what are we doing string match uh
so if it matches this regular expression
then delete region okay then you need to
know how many characters are there okay
we started to code we we are you know we
are talking
okay so string match If it's all digits
now obviously this will match. Why? Why
do you have to match?
If match delete the region then insert
insert string to number then plus one
then number to string and insert it.
Right? Correct. Uh otherwise insert
zero. Oh I see. So right. So when you
skip backward and forward to grab the
digit it might be possible we that you
are not on any digit.
So that's why you need to check string
match if it match your digit because if
it does not then all you do is just
insert zero. Okay. Uh let me
demonstrate. Okay. So you call this
command call. You see it just enter
zero. Now if you call it again then
you'll just start to incre increase. You
see now you can use the mouse wheel up
or down. Okay. So let's make it larger.
Okay. So the beauty of the font. So you
can see um so okay. So now you
this checks if there's actually some a
digit in the c under the cursor. Then
you need to know how many characters.
Okay.
Uh
how how do you do it? Because let's say
if you have zero or nine, you can
increase to zero or 10.
So if you have 09, let me do you do you
guys understand you know if you have
like 09 okay so you call the command
then it becomes 10, right?
And so far you can find out yeah there
are two digits you know so you want to
always keep it two digits. Okay. But now
what happens if you keep increasing then
it becomes 100.
So you have to check if the two digit if
the current value if the new value
the number of digits in the new value.
If the number of digits in the new value
after increment or decrement is
smaller than the number of digits before
then you want to keep the digit. Okay?
But if it's larger
then you don't want to you know you
don't want to drop you know you want to
increase. Is that right?
Now let let's make it simple. Let's just
always remain the same number of digits.
Okay. So so let's add a new variable num
of digits.
Okay. Something like that. Okay. Let's
for now let's uh well we can make it
like that.
No digit
count. What about that? The art of
naming variables supposedly the most
difficult part. Okay. Digit count. Okay.
So, let's just say chart count.
Okay. Um, then you want to
do you do where do you do it? Okay,
let's just do it. Let's keep like let's
keep typing. Okay, so child count equals
to length uh length. No, not let length
the length of um
match string one. Okay. And uh what?
Okay. So the string the xnum
xnum is a string. Okay. So so that's why
so you need to say xnum here. So this
means grab the capture. Okay. So
actually you need to capture. Well, zero
means the whole match. Okay.
So you
So what is that? That's the beginning of
string regular expression.
You see we need that because now it's
getting tricky. The situation is what if
you have let's say xxx
then 9 you see so what if xaxs let's say
88 okay what do you if you have this
situation you know so when you if you
call this command it becomes 89 because
but however it grabbed um
it the code grabbed the two digits It's
right. Okay. So,
so but so you don't need this, you know,
this back tick. That's a specific emac
regular expression for either beginning
of line or beginning of string. Okay.
Uh so I don't I don't think you need it,
you know. So
yeah because you are already you know
you are always always grabbing the
digits anyway.
So anyway so child count length match
string uh
yeah match stream uh xnum. Okay nobody
is here. Okay so char count. So let me
just code it then. Uh char count
char count uh match string. So grab that
and uh then find the length that's the
char count. Okay. And now you can just
for now x chart count. Uh you can kind
of print it for debugging purposes.
Okay. Then let's evalide the region and
uh let's do it. Okay. So call it CH
count two. Now 91 92 3 4 5 6 7 8 99 8 99
and the 100 CH count. Okay.
Yeah. So char count is the original CH
count.
Okay. So, let's go back to the code.
Okay. So,
okay. This is beginning to become boring
chan. So, okay. Let's quickly let's
don't worry about many edge cases. Let's
just finish this for the simple case.
So,
so then after increment uh okay then you
need to say a new number. Okay. Uh
x new num. Okay. Something like new num.
X new num
uh will be
set X new num equals to something like
this. Okay. Um
string to number plus one X new num x
new num is turn it to string. Okay.
Then xnum let's rename it. Rename the
xnum to xnum string.
Okay. Then okay you need to deal with
decrement number two. Okay. Jesus.
Ah
Jesus.
Uh go to child to other buffer. No.
Okay. So yeah. So let's make a backup.
Compile it. Yes, it works. No error.
That's good. Okay. Now go back to our
code.
Okay. So then you have to deal with
decrement number. Then you see this uh
but the body is pretty much the same.
Then you need to do refactoring to make
them one function. Um okay, getting
complex. Okay. So purify the code. So
you got
num string that's original then new num
that's a new number then you delete
region then you insert number two
string. Yes. Yeah. But before we you do
that if you want to know the padding.
Okay. Oh god.
If
length
of
new num you need to turn that to a
string. So none to string.
So if that new number the length of that
is less than
less than the x chart count
then you want to okay wait so this is
increment oh god you see this line only
makes sense if it's in decrement oh god
uh okay but Let's keep keep going. So if
the length num to string
is greater okay so let's just say
greater so um wait so
wait greater than okay
so the length if it's greater than you
then you basically just want to drop a
number
that's you know so the you are getting
into a kind of new behavior now uh
getting complex okay
hey Hank you can you know you can start
your video um thank you for you know
checking though but you can start your
video
Okay.
Okay. I need to finish this. Oh god. 40
minutes already.
So if length is number two string then
chunk. If it's greater then
oh god what you what to do if it's
greater?
Do you just inc increase the number or
do you uh you do you want to drop it
Matio? Uh what's so great about Lisp?
Uh
well I can say about Emac Lisp okay Emac
Lisp is the greatest programming
language for text processing. So if your
task is about text processing especially
small files like let's say less than 1
megabyte and you need to process it in a
flexible way or you know or make a
report then EMAC this is the best
language better than pearl python
whatever
text text processing and also
in addition
when if you want it to be interactive
Okay. Like like like what you know what
we are doing today. You cannot do this
in Python, JavaScript,
Pearl or whatever you know especially if
you want it interactive.
Uh you cannot do this in VS Code in Neo
Vim in VI in Vim you know whatever [ __ ]
Okay. Best programming language for text
processing especially
if you need it to be interactive. Okay,
that's emac disp. Now, what about lisp
in general such as common disp
um
well in that case I like them because
they are functional programming. I don't
like common lisp. Common lisp is this
bloated crap bloated
um
common lisp
happened because back in like 20 years
ago 30 years ago they need to merge all
the different families of lisp because
so in the 1980s there's many factions of
lisp mag lisp and you know zeta lisp
civil you know they are slightly
incompatible
So common lisp was created as a vision
to unify all the lisps.
Uh but it turned out it be becomes crap.
It becomes like the huge you know
humongous baggage of all the little
features each faction wants. So it
became like so we are compatible to all
these factions you know to please
everyone. So common list is the greatest
word what
in programming language you know it's a
huge you know the doc the documentation
is like over you know 10,000 pages or
something common list so in a sense a
lot
this experts said that common list
killed lisp okay uh but so what what is
good about lisp well there are several
um
reasons but mostly for myself I like
lisp because it is functional
programming. Okay. And and also because
of the syntax the syntax correspond to
semantics because everything is
parenthesis. So you can you know you can
edit uh uh wait undo redo you can edit
or for example I can ed you know kill
this whole semantic unit by just
pressing a key. How can it does do that?
Because this you know because of the
regular let because of the regularity of
the syntax. So it allows you to
trivially manipulate
expressions and because expressions the
syntact the syntax the syntactical
expressions corresponds to the semantics
semantic unit of the programming
language. Okay.
So that is the a good property of the
lisp syntax.
Um, and for example, I can let me show
you another one. For example, select the
unit under the cruiser. Press a key
again. Select the outer unit. Press a
key again. Select the outer unit. Okay?
So, extend selection. You cannot do this
in C, in JavaScript, in Python, all
these languages fetuned with
irregularity of the syntax. Like oh in
this case if you are doing while loop
the syntax is this one with semicolon.
If you are doing loop for loop then
there are you know this special ad hoc
syntax you know [ __ ] the C and C++
and Java and JavaScript basically all
languages came out of it. Okay. because
of the Unix
virus, the Unix [ __ ] and the C
[ __ ] they damaged the programming
industry for like 30 years.
Okay. Are there other syntaxes that's
like not parenthesized but
but have good qualities? Yes. APL, Wuam
language and few others. Okay. So I'm
not saying like you know list syntax is
the only way but the point is that you
have to anyway that's a programming
language syntax issue okay there are a
lot of issues about that
anyway let let's go back to the code so
can I you know so now right now we are
distracted can we finish the code so
let's finish the code
who is watching
so you guys are quiet my people. So, you
know, you guys need to say something.
Okay, say something like you want to
meet uh me to keep coding or whatnot.
Thanks for the insight. Thank you. So, I
did a lot of videos in the past, you
know, I have like by now five years of
videos. So, I did quite a lot videos
talking about the Lisp programming
language and which language to learn.
So, you can search for it if you want
to.
Okay. So let's back to so back to this
uh you know one thing particular again
about emacisp is that it's the greatest
language for text processing because why
because you can control you have the
buffer data type and you can have you
know you you can get the cursor position
you can move it forward you can move it
backward you can do a rejects on the
current buffer text you can you know
rejects save it save the current
position or what or rejects regular
expression again or whatever or delete
characters, delete a section, you know.
So everything I do manually it can be uh
you know uh done programmatically that
in fact that's what this code is about
you know it's in increment of numbers.
So that's why it's the best text
processing language. It has the buffer
data type which is what you see in the
whole whole buffer right now like you
know uh and buffer data type what what
what is it? Well, it's basically a glor
glorified
string
data type you know in a typical language
like Pearl, Python, Ruby, JavaScript you
know when you have a string it's just a
string it's it's dead you know there's
nothing you can do to it. Maybe you can
change the nth character or maybe you
can do find replace. That's it. Every
time you do it, usually in these
languages, doesn't matter it's um
Python, Ruby, uh JavaScript and and on
and on, the strings are immutable. So
every time you make a change, it it has
to create a whole string. So if you have
a buffer, you know, of 10,000 characters
or one megabyte, whatever, it very slow,
you know, it has to recreate the entire
string. You cannot like and you cannot
save the position inside the string like
the index right. So suppose you got a
string you want to delete the index
let's say 10 to 100
you cannot do that you delete basically
recreates a string uh so it's very slow
but
you know comes in emac buffer data data
type which is comes into bas so so it is
like a string but you got cursor
position you you can you know you can
move forward backward you can save
cursive position position and so on. You
can delete part of it and it's still it
basically is a string. You know this
whole thing is a you know you don't call
it a string. You call it a buffer or in
other words it's a text. Okay.
In addition to this buffer then you then
you do have the normal string concept
which is like you can turn this uh you
know this part of text into a string and
so on. So that is the buffer data type
in EMAC. is and that is why let's go
let's jump uh let's undo undo undo
whatever I did before uh uh so that you
know the buffer data type is like a
glorified string very like much more
enhanced string data type very rich that
makes eaglist the most powerful
programming language for doing the task
of text processing Okay. Now if you go
beyond text processing, Emac this is not
good because Emac this is very kind of
niche only works runs in EMACs. Okay.
So if you want to do huge amount of text
processing like processing gigabyte
tetra like Google or whatever or
processing you know language translation
then you know you move to Python or
whatever go
okay that's a huge digression
God we need to finish the code So
let's just do it now. Okay, then I'm
going to code it offline. So if the
length is greater than the number of
characters, then you you want to drop
the first character.
Uh okay. So,
so x new
number
uh you want to turn it string, you want
to turn that number into a string, then
you want to d drop the first uh few
characters. God, it's going to getting
tedious.
Um,
uh, then you need a new variable to
insert. Okay. So,
uh, and now I'm half drunk. [ __ ]
Okay. So,
okay, let's concentrate and uh do I want
to finish this? Yes, let's finish it.
Okay, let's just code something so it's
it works.
So, um
so the new number okay string uh number
to string actually you can use format.
Okay. Format will allow uh will allow
you to drop numbers. Let's test. Okay.
1 2 3 4 5. Okay. Then you say uh number.
Okay. I need to check the documentation
for format and uh for integer. So
integer is d. So go back here. Go back.
Go back here. So integer is d. And how
do you change the um
I mean how do you specify how many
digits
search for digit? Okay. Uh
I don't remember you know this this this
sprint f you know this format string is
one of the grave crimes from the Unix
and C [ __ ] Okay,
you know that that percentage D, percent
o, percent X, you know, whatever, you
know, this this is so-called a mini
language, a language within a language.
And it came from C and then it spread to
Pearl, spread to JavaScript, swept to
Python, script to spread to Python,
JavaScript, Goland, basically every
language there. C and Unix [ __ ]
created this. Okay, it's
incomprehensible [ __ ]
Okay, so how do you want to So right now
I want to Okay, so here so field let's
see field flags width and precision and
character very confusing.
Um
I don't know. So let's just try trial
and error. Okay, something like two do
it. Okay, uh wait. So, you got to put
the two in front. Okay. Do it. No, it
didn't work. Um, what?
Okay. So, let's go to eag this blog. So,
let's go to saw eag this tutorial. Do I
have it like easy to read
uh solution here? Format. Okay. Format
integer uh padding. There it is. Oh,
padding decimal four digits. Okay,
that's padding decimal. If you that's
okay, that's a good solution. Padding
decimal four digits.
Zero means you want to pad with the zero
and then four then d. Okay, so the first
character is the character you want to
use for padding
and adding sign. We don't care. So,
okay. So, okay. So [ __ ] idiotic. The
[ __ ] the Unix and [ __ ] the C.
Okay. Something like that. Okay. So
wait, is that true? No. Yeah, I think
so. So let's do it again.
Uh,
no. Let's say nine.
Okay. So if you know, so so the padding
must be greater than the number. But how
how can we drop it, you know? I don't
want that many.
Oh god.
Decimal. Hexad decimal.
Uh number to decimal. Okay.
So it seems like is it even possible?
Okay. So if you can can you use floating
number? Okay. So let's see.
So instead of D, use F. Then do that.
Then you got the [ __ ] zero zero at
the end, you know. [ __ ] [ __ ] the C. [ __ ]
the Unix and C, you know, because I'm
right now I'm running into this problem.
Who to blame? C and Unix [ __ ] They
did it this they did this to the coding
industry.
Um,
so anyway, so I just want to have two.
Okay, let's try it. No, that doesn't
work. So, you know, [ __ ] it.
Um,
can we just use S will the S S work? Uh,
let's see.
No.
Uh so you so so now it means you have to
read this carefully.
Number two exponential notation or
decimal point notation. Number two
exponential notation. What the [ __ ] is
that? [ __ ] it.
Let's say G. Okay.
No. So what we want to
uh go. So wait,
you know, so we we want
[ __ ] it.
We want just two digits. How do you How
do you do it? If it's more, if there's
more, then drop them. Okay. Okay. So you
you really need to read the
documentation carefully. Okay. So let's
go back to read the documentation.
Yeah.
Produce a sign number in decimal. Okay.
Sign number. Okay. That's what we want.
Okay. So it's going to be percent D
then
and possibly also percent F. Okay.
Um
and C means produce a number as a single
character. Okay, that's a unic code
point.
Okay, S capital S means produce any
object as X s
S S S S S S S S S S S S S S S S S S S S
expression symbolic expression that just
means this syntax. Okay. The argument
used for D, O and so on must be a
number. Okay. Yeah. And uh
and uh and that that treat argument as
unsigned if binary as unsigned is true.
[ __ ] complex [ __ ]
Uh use percent to put a single percent
into output. Okay. A percent sequence
other than percent may contain optional
field number. Okay. Then you got flag
width and precision. Okay. So you got
field flag width position.
Okay. Field flags with position. Okay.
Field is 0 to9 followed by a literal
dollar sign.
Oh, what the you see one of the problem
with EMAC list um documentation is that
they don't have much examples. Uh well,
so search EMAC list manual for format.
Let's see if we can find so let's read
the full
EMAC manual for this format instead of
just the inline documentation. Okay,
close that.
So, um,
so we got this format format function
and, uh, where is it? So, here it
describes the full documentation for
this.
Okay. So then you got
okay
God. Okay. I'm currently half drunk and
uh at this rate we are not going
anywhere.
Uh
the flag zero. Okay. So let's see cause
any padding inserted by the width if
specified to be inserted on the right
rather than left. Okay. The flag zero
ensures that padding consists of zero
characters instead of space. Okay. Uh
what is the Okay. So the flag pound sign
specifies an alternative form which
depends on the format used. Okay.
So plus means add a plus sign
field number. Okay. So after the percent
sign any field number you can put
certain flag characters.
Okay.
So flag is zero. I think we
where is it? So flag is zero for sure.
Um,
Mr. Lee, I was trying to install fly
keys on Doom, but I could I could
not get it to work on my for my blog.
Yes, true. It's true. On my blog, it's
outdated.
But my recommendation is that if you
want to use Doom, just go with Doom,
okay? because you know Doom is another
guy who is a great emac coder he's great
you know so but
he's him I'm me so but you know he's not
going to like promote Safly keys and so
if you're going to use Doom just go with
Doom if you want to try keys I would
recommend just go with Safly keys okay
and don't don't use Doom just playing
Groom Emacs and Kafly keys Okay, that's
my recommendation. I I don't think it
works well together with Doom because
Doom, the core foundation of Doom, the
philosophy is designed to be Vim like.
So, it has like last time, you know, two
years ago, I tried to install it live
stream. It has like 1,000 packages.
Um,
you know, but it's it's very popular.
It's very good. uh but it's like
you know it's focused on vim.
So if you're going to use safely keys
you don't need all the things in in
doom. Okay just so just use safly keys.
Okay so let's see let's read the
comment. You know I'm I'm kind of like
going nowhere here. So let me read the
comments and maybe that's it for today.
It's already one hour.
Uh so M Leah so another dark page
mentions this the new variable float
output format controls how this prints
floating numbers its value should be new
or string okay
uh
yeah
okay so I think that's that's it for
today you know just random talk this is
something I want to do but Um
you know so usually I code it offline.
Coding offline is much faster like at
least three times four times faster
faster than live stream because in live
stream you need to explain what's going
on then you know basically you are doing
a show that's what I'm doing a show you
then you know at this occasion I need to
flame the sea and Unix [ __ ] I need
to talk about it history like where does
this format came
How did we get this this you know this
percent 00002
as cryptic [ __ ] that's history of
computing and that came from the C and
Unix [ __ ] Okay.
But if we if I'm coding offline you know
it's just me you just need to get it to
work then I won't be you know talking
about these elaborate things. Um, so
anyway,
should we finish this now? Well, I don't
you know,
you know, so right now I'm like like so
so the question is should we like finish
reading you know doing coding this?
Well, we need to go through this format
and or alternatively you know just don't
use this format then you know you know
then just use like code it manually. So
instead of using format all you have to
do is just extract substring actually
it'll be simple
uh substring.
So substring you need to look at the
documentation substring option from two.
Okay. So, so the substring is going to
be the string is x new num. In fact, we
need to tie it to num to string. Okay.
uh number two string x new number then
from
from starting from uh so actually we
need to drop the first you know we we
want we we we want the total number of
digits to be char count so we need to
get the length of that
okay so this is like like what you have
to Okay. Length
length
uh god then you then you need to cut you
know so the length of that
two okay so the two is to the end length
which is optional so that means you
don't need it okay but the front from
the beginning index would be the length
minus So uh so it would be minus
length minus the padding right. So when
it's greater right so uh yeah so length
minus x chart
count let's make sure is this correct
so number two string
uh number two string minus the char
count.
Oh wait, we need to wait. We need to
take the beginning or end. We need to
take from the end. Okay. So,
yeah. So,
so let's say number let's say there are
five digits. Let's say the char count is
two.
Okay. So you need to begin basically
uh basically 012 at three something like
that.
So this will actually be
okay. I'm half drunk. Okay.
[ __ ] it.
Okay. I think that's it for today,
right?
Okay. So, what what else was I going to
do? I was going to write something else.
Reformat lines that one and then another
ones, but we didn't even finish this one
for an hour. Okay.
Uh yeah, that's it for Okay, let's Well,
let's continue. Let's continue coding.
Let's finish this.
Okay, substring
substring of this string and uh begin.
So let me think about it.
Uh let's say you have let's say the
current number the current the the new
number is 10 digits. Okay, 10 of them.
Then let's say the char count is two.
You only allow two digits. Okay.
So that means you want to begin at
something like eight.
Yeah. So so that minus ch would be it.
Do you need to add one?
Uh that's always always uh annoying. So
we can try it. Okay. So for example,
let's say string let's say
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 okay then
let's say the char count is two so we
want to just get a two so
uh 7 minus two
uh two right so what do we at
uh wait so 7 to
67. So that's is correct. Okay. So
substring
then that string then length
of
number two string and then length. Oh
god, this is [ __ ]
length and ch count. Okay, then purify
the code and we don't need format
anymore. So it's just substring
and then you and then we just remove all
these uh code. Okay, so we kind of
remove that all that that testing code.
Okay.
So you just insert
insert that
otherwise
insert that. Okay. Purify the code. I
don't know if this works, but let's try.
Okay. Uh, let's just try it.
So, we can at least say something
worked. 70. Okay. Increase now. 72 76.
Increase increase.
92 95 6 96 97 98 99.
If you're going to do it again, it's
going to be 0 0. Not one zero. Okay? If
it's zero, that means we did it
correctly. Okay, do it again. One more.
Oh, wrong argument. Type sequence
sequence P1
[Music]
[ __ ] Okay, so our code is incorrect.
Uh incorrect incorrect somewhere here.
Let's see. Wrong. What? What is the
error?
wrong type of argument. It expect a
sequence and it got one instead.
Uh what?
Oh, wait. This is this shouldn't be
number two string. Okay. Uh what? Wait.
This should be number two string.
Wait. number to string
then length then minus char
and it's a number. Okay, so this this is
not a length. Okay, that eval the code
let's not worry about anything just
eval. Okay, so let's try it again. Uh
let's say 98 98. Okay, do it. 99 and
increase 98. Okay, decrease increase 99
and increase again 0.
Fantastic. Oh,
correct. Okay. So, we got it to work,
but we didn't work on the the other
case. So, what is the other case? The
the other case is
if it's less than
wait well the less than is because the
then you need to work on the decrement
number.
Actually, we need to refactor to combine
them into one. So we don't repeat, you
know, we don't repeat this um
this whole code. Okay, that's it. Thank
you guys for watching. Bye guys.
God.