good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sound talk show today's topic
is going to be random you ask me
questions and I answer okay so now you
have questions type in the chat
and pay me don't forget okay PayPal me
super chat if you use PayPal say you
paid answer your question in depth
uh okay so today's topic is random I'm
gonna just go over it's been a month I
haven't been doing any live stream so
it's been a while and uh
uh I'm gonna show you what I have been
up to and uh updates on my various blogs
on keyboards on emacs on programming
uh on Unicode you know uh miscellaneous
things okay voice check video check okay
first of all I'm gonna show you my
keyboard I'm using this is glove 80
keyboard just search for Sally keyboard
you will find my full review and video
review Club 80 fantastic now it's my
current main keyboard and here is the
ultimate hacking keyboard it's also
superb it's a highest quality design
thought went into both of them in
different ways okay so these two I
really highly recommend and you know and
they gave me they gave it to me
free it was a gift so I can do full
reviews and use you know and help them
sell and I really love those these two
these are you know the best okay so
gravity and the glove 80 and ottoman
hacking keyboard version two okay that's
the current version
okay now that's my keyboard and also
yeah so we did um we talked we uh we we
talked about I mean I did a unboxing of
the of the Kinesis Kinesis 360 keyboard
okay now let me switch to my screen post
your questions now okay
so
all right so let me show you my keyboard
so keyboard blog uh yes so there's some
news about keyboard I'm gonna tell you
but first of all let me tell you about
the status of Kinesis sweet 360 okay
let's just search it
okay so we I did a unboxing of the
Kinesis 360 keyboard uh about two months
ago okay so
um you know the so it's but I haven't
used it much
part of the reason you know when they
give me a keyboard I need to use it for
long term like one year two years so I
can help them sell it
this one I'm pretty sure I like I like
it you know there's pros and cons in
comparison to the ultimate hack to the
glove 80. okay but anyway the one they
sent me is brown switch okay because I
have repetitive strain injury uh for
many years so Brown switch is too heavy
for me I cannot
use it as my main so I've been asking
them if they want to send me you know
the you know lighter switch they say
they said they can't right now uh so
anyway so I cannot use this as my main
keyboard so
so there's no point I'm going to return
it to them
so but I decided I'm going to finish the
review so I'm gonna try to use it for a
month and just complete my review okay
so that's a status of kinesis 360.
okay let's see the questions so we uh
there's a question about GitHub but you
know ask me a question when I'm on okay
don't ask me offline
because I don't want a bunch of people
you know they are not really concerned
about anything they just ask whatever
questions
when did you get your haircut last
haircut about two months ago something
so right now it's back to this is uh
back to the
the
here
so is there any comment on the Ocean
Gate incident it seems to be Frontline
headline news on Google search engine
yeah so
okay so I mean yeah so let me start to
answer questions random okay so today's
topic is anyway random so I wanted to
talk about keyboards and uh you know the
lots of things on my blog
okay yeah so there is the Ocean Gate so
basically there let me tell you the
story first of all I recommend you go to
Twitter okay Twitter now even by Ella
musk is one of the best thing Twitter
you know lots of uh lots of angry you
know you see lots of the ugliness of
humanity you can see it at all you can
see it all non-stop on Twitter
you know beating you know High School
people being people Injustice everything
you know and war war mongering the
corrupt politicians everything okay so
anyway I'm mentioning that so Twitter is
a good I recommend it now you know in
fact I've been spending like five hours
per day for the past month on Twitter
reading and writing uh
yeah and and I'm also on Discord so you
can join my Discord which is kind of a
smaller crowd we have about 2 000 people
but one thousand or two thousand but
only maybe 50 people active so start
Discord or Twitter you know follow me on
Twitter so Twitter is the place where
you want to get the latest dirt of
corrupt politicians or latest news you
want to find the truth you don't want to
follow the mainstream the vast majority
of mainstream news are all fake news
since since past 10 years in USA so New
York Times Washington Post
the Atlantic these are the three major
mainstream
fake news basically funded by U.S
government okay corrupt part of the US
government
and they you know they focus on you know
high level political war issues you know
it's all fake news for example the
Ukraine war so you want you want to know
the real news what's going on Twitter
okay you can start by following what I
say I have some recommendations on
different variety of subjects on war on
the social justice scan you know the
lgbtq and you know and so on and on you
know so I recommend trade Twitter now
I'm mentioning that because Ocean Gate
of course is the latest news so let me
tell you the story so the you know there
was the Titanic which is one of the most
biggest
um
vocational ship you know how they call
that you know ship to take vacation or
you know transatlantic anyway it's the
biggest ship okay ocean liner uh and
it's sunk about 100 years ago 1890 1890
something okay about 100 years ago
almost exactly so and uh
a lot rich people are on it so it's a
big news because that that ship is
supposed to be supposed to be Unsinkable
okay but it sunk it it hit a Iceberg uh
and sunk so
about a thousand people died you know
most like uh I think 60 of people on the
ship died there were 2 000 people on the
ship
okay so that's a big news so it sunk and
and since then people has uh tried to
find the wreckage and it's not easy
because it's at that place it's very
deep in the ocean uh I think 200
kilometers down so
at that depth there's tremendous
pressure you know you can even nuclear
submarines I don't think you know
like War submarines cannot go that deep
you know you go that deep you pressure
you know what what does pressure means
undersea the deeper you go basically the
easy way to understand it understand it
is that you know the all the water below
you are weight you know like wait one
kilogram two kilograms so the deeper
basically wherever you are in Ocean all
the water above you are weight on you so
so you're gonna be kind of like that
okay so you're gonna be crushed to death
you know instantaneously
so people has been trying to find the
wreckage of Titanic and it was
discovered in 1985. how do I know
because I was just reading it you know
for for the nth time yesterday
so the wreckage was discovered in 1985
and today you go to YouTube there's a
lot of videos of it you know the
wreckage all the detail or the build the
Titanic what's inside in this Wikipedia
full of details you know actually I read
the Wikipedia yesterday I think for the
second time uh it's complete detail yeah
very very well written okay
uh so
the wreckage is found in 1985 and the
wreckage is in international water that
means actually it's not
some somewhat so there's no
one single law that says this belongs to
you know you United Kingdom or USA so
anyway it's International water so a lot
of explorers and went into you know take
footage study or scientists you know
there's a rust you know
bacteria are eating the iron frame of
the Titanic okay so anyway
so
1985 okay the wreckage was discovered go
to YouTube you can see hours and hours
of it
and now so the so this this guy uh
explorer who created a uh submersible
you know called Ocean Gate Ocean Gate is
the company name something like that so
he invited people to have a tool of
Titanic go in the you know beneath the
water and look at the Titanic inside
this submersible and for 25 hundred
thousand dollars each so five people
went including the guy himself so four
people each one paid 250 000 dollars
a quarter of a million and the ship is
is kind of non-standard so it basically
collapsed uh it has some problems with
the Hole uh and it just
um
collapsed so all the people died so
that's basically the story
okay there's also conspiracy theories
but I'm not too into that
so if you yeah so if you you know
on Twitter you'll see uh of course on
Twitter there's also lots of fake news
like conspiracy spin stories idiotics
EDR idiots
hello Christos Christopher Smith
immortality hello that are you
immortality Are you a
are you uh
are you the the no the
um
and Juan hello
and Rio engine Titanic is unsingable
yeah so there's also apparently there is
a video you know they use in real region
on real engine the game engine
that gives you a tool of Titanic so I
found that yesterday so you can see it
you might start Discord uh I believe
it's no so yeah so here is the yeah so
here is a good article posted by
uh
now the name is just okay
okay so you know here's a story you just
crushed okay this is what it looks like
anything else so yeah I've been talking
on this for too long so
this is not too interesting you know
it's just some
accident
uh
is there a Perpetual link state to
Wolfram engine once it is installed what
do you what do you mean by link State
okay so Wolfram engine is stored on your
directory
uh let me answer that question so you
know first of all go through my Saudi
Wolfram Language tutorial website then
you'll see download free uh file name oh
by the way I haven't been doing Wolfram
language for a while because there's
some issues there you know they are
donating to me so but I'm going to start
to do Wolfram language again soon maybe
starting next few days or next week okay
and also tomorrow I'm going to start to
do a emag display coding writing a
writing a HTML validator or an XML
validator so I can in emacs I can press
a button and it you'll tell me if I have
a you know mismatched tag or on closed
tag such as like that
so tomorrow okay tomorrow
uh I think tomorrow noon one hour
earlier than today so tomorrow no we I'm
going to do that
emac basis coding writing a HTML
validator so you can call it right there
right in emacs okay so tomorrow
and uh after tomorrow I think I'm gonna
do a random possibly political talking
about politics because USA
is in the brink of collapsing you know
it's already collapsed it's already
collapsing pretty bad
and uh you know the
yeah it's it's very very very bad Okay
so
if this continue in five years you know
we're gonna
Our Lives you know those of you
Americans we gonna have a bit very bad
bad life like third countries you know
you know there's criminals there's
corruption you can't do nothing there's
no law you your your streets become
dirty like right now San Francisco full
of [ __ ] on the street and drug users you
know that's happening in USA right now
and there's you know the uh you know why
because higher level corrupt politicians
so it's very critical moments right now
so I'm thinking doing a live stream
about it
after tomorrow
and that will happen on
Odyssey okay so if you don't know yet I
have an odyssey account you just search
for artistic Sally so I might try to
stream there because YouTube will censor
you part of the corruption you know
very bad
okay so that's about that so back to the
Wolfram language yeah so your question
so in fact I believe I have article on
that
the location so once you install Wolfram
engine there's a path uh
pre-configured path okay so let's look
at where I have that
so let's try search okay
move fam uh path
okay file path functions load path so
yeah there it is
so here I believe here answers your
question
language you can find this is a constant
variable that holds the installation
directory file path and this constant
variable user base directory that tells
you the user's Library location and
here's a load path
uh returns a list of directory to
directories to search for library or
file you know typically like in Python
you have export
path you know import path things like
that so you know
that answers your question I believe is
that correct am I correct so if I
answered your question
give it say so okay uh
so I get a feedback you know uh
so next question I think the next
Titanic okay is there a Perpetual link
uh vadamus says big hello from Balkans
hello Serbia hello we have people all
around the world that's a good thing you
know that's
my
my followers tends to be Global or in a
classic sense of the word Cosmopolitan
okay like people
uh it kind of you know learned you know
educated people around the world tends
to be
in contrast to most American YouTubers
you know they they they tend to gather
just
um American you know readers
so why do I have kind of international
kind of more International audience well
because my face you know I don't I'm not
a white person
can you talk about your keyboard keys
are they Cherry MX red so that one says
okay so Cherry MX red so
first of all you need you should get a
mechanical key switch right now okay if
you don't if you have a normal keyboard
and that's not mechanical key switch
and you do have some hand pain you
started to feel hand discomfort the
first thing you do like right now is to
buy a cheap mechanical key switch
keyboard they cost about forty dollars
forty dollars USD okay so that's the
most important you know don't don't
worry about oh which one I'm gonna
choose whether should you choose
ergonomic or not just go buy a
mechanical switch keyboard like right
now if you don't have one yet okay then
you you then you use it then you can
think about you know whether you're
gonna get worse or what other other
things you need to fix okay so that's
the most important mechanical key switch
okay you might hear people say oh that's
not too important oh Robert don't oh
this is like a mechanical that's all
crap okay get a mechanical key switch
keyboard there are many mechanical
switch makers the most popular famous is
Cherry the company
from Germany it's called Cherry that's
just a company name okay they make
Cherry MX key switches then there's a
bunch of them from China Kyle
uh you know I have articles on my
website you will find lots of my
you know just go to kusadi keyboard and
here you go to design
then you have design flaws then why are
keyboard keys not aligned vertically
then here's a key switch you can learn
from this article keyboard key switch
mechanisms everything you need to know
about mechanical key switches what do
they mean
what types are there uh you know what is
Cherry MX and who makes them you know so
everything you want to know what's the
low profile or mechanical key switch and
you know so on so that's the first thing
you want to do now there are many
different type of mechanical key
switches one of the most important thing
is how heavy how much resistance there
is okay
so for me because I I it turns out I
like light switches now you know 10
years ago when I first got into
mechanical keyboard key switches I
thought oh those people are Elite you
know Fabs they you know they say oh they
get into lots of details about these
switches I think it's silly I thought
because it's it's all the same you know
it should it's just all the same to me
but actually now after 10 years I
realized not really not really because
for example the Cherry MX Brown
a so-called tactile Cherry MX Brown
switch okay which is uh here so you can
see Cherry MX Cherry by the company
Cherry one of the switch they make is MX
switches one of the type of switch and
they are color coded by color Okay so
the color indicate what kind what type
of
resistance you know is for each one so
one of them very popular the most
popular is brown so it's so called
tactile so
and so you know
uh and it this one turns out it's not
that good comparatively to all the
others okay this one is got scratchy and
and for me it's too heavy I cannot
I can still use it but you know because
when you because not if I type you know
five hours a day that will give me
likely more likely to get me into hand
pain so I today these days I prefer very
light switch such as Cherry MX red or
silent red and I prefer linear switch
this I don't want any tactile sensation
like click or a fee or bump I want them
to be linear
you know so this is a this is a detailed
interesting issue because you know again
in the beginning I just like everyone
the common
the common wisdom is that you know if
you are a gamer you would prefer linear
switch if you are a typist then clicky
is probably better for you and then
there's a mid you know mid middle of the
ground the brown switch
actually I think that's still that's not
that's so that's just that's all
[ __ ] okay that's there's no
scientific data about these things
there's no scientific study that
actually says typists prefer
a tactile okay no such thing
yeah I mean not not strictly okay so but
anyway I started to realize in the past
few years I you know after so much study
and writing about them I realized and
that
the best switch is linear
why because there is no natural
mechanism there's no natural way
there's no engineering to create a
natural bump okay because when you have
a blue switch for example blue seeds let
me show you a picture of it
blue or brown you see they have this
pump on the on the on the stump okay so
that's what makes it
the tactile sensation you feel a
resistance like the resistance goes up
for a while so do I have a blue one so
you can see here's a blue one
there's a bump but that is not that's
that's unnatural that bump has nothing
to do with the activation of the key
switch in other words
when the key switch in other words
if you use a blue or brown switch you
can try to press it very slowly your it
will activate without any bump at all
something like that okay so in other
words there's no natural way there's no
engineering so far that makes a switch
where the activation Force corresponds
with the bump okay there's no way so the
bump is kind of kind of like a
decorative
hack
to make you feel like you press the key
you know you know but actually and also
there's no scientific study that really
says
you have that that when you have the
bumps you feel you get the better sense
of when the key actually activated
there's no such scientific study in fact
if you really want that you can have a
sound activation for example on Kinesis
keyboard
which is this one
it has a you can by default there's a
sound Activation so when you press the
key here you have a tiny beep sound you
know
so anyway so that's my preference so I
prefer low light very light switches
today uh 35 grams of activation Force
also another detail is that the
activation Force you know if you go to
each spec they'll say you know how many
Force sometimes by Newtons sometimes by
Gram but actually they are not
comparable across different makers okay
so that's another important issue
the bottom line is that you have to feel
it you have to like buy the switch Tesla
in field okay let's move on so
that's sad about that topic
so I've been talking for 30 minutes
already Okay so
so did I answer your question okay so
Cherry mxo I recommend
so if you are new to key switch I would
recommend Cherry MX red silent that's
one of them I recommend because there
are so many I cannot tell you so so
but you can read my articles I have some
articles that details which one I
recommend this you know search for Sally
Sally switch okay sorry for example
uh
well can you go switch Mouse mechanical
switch no
this article I compare red switches but
anyway anyway just you can find it on my
website okay
Rudolph says if you spend too much time
on social networks such as Twitter do
you still have enough time to read books
papers and the like of course no
obviously no
so Twitter
is kind of
[Music]
um
strictly speaking I would not recommend
Twitter No any other so among social
networks including Reddit Hacker News
Twitter Facebook Instagram
telegram Telegraph you know whatever
there's quite a lot now
of all of them
I think Twitter now is the best okay led
by Ella musk Elon Musk is in my opinion
is Our Hope For Better America Elon Musk
he started to
to to save America from collapsing okay
so among all social networks Twitter is
the one I recommend and I'm on Twitter
as I and I intend to keep spending at
least one hour on Twitter every day okay
so that's one opinion now
now if you are a young young person you
you know you started to do whatever your
career I recommend so you want to study
mathematics or programming or whatever
your field or chemistry or engineering
uh all the social network they they are
really they just waste your time
and even if you have unless you have
tremendous amount of self-control
which I do in some way because I'm a I'm
a big nerd you know I have tight control
about or aspect of what I read so unless
you are like me very very rare okay
that's not not that's not common so
likely when you go to a social network
you'll likely become you'll fall into it
you started to be you know you you
started to read lots of [ __ ] this is
so kind of [ __ ] on Twitter on any Social
Network on on troll
scams scams current politicians FBI
agents CIA agent or China agent
spreading fake news then you have
conspiracy idiots they they tell you if
they talk about F UFO like Joe Rogan
idiot then there's there's a there's
there's a agents or idiots like Lex
Freeman Lex Friedman who talks about AI
you know idiots
pure idiots these are okay so I don't
even recommend Twitter because that's
you know even though Twitter in my
opinion is the best of them
however there's one great use of Twitter
nowhere else that exists okay if you
want to dig the dirt of politicians
corrupt politicians if you want real
journalism that is exposing corruption
exposing bribes and Crimes by the top
politicians that that is what journalism
means
traditionally not today because in the
past years they've been all corrupt the
today's mainstream journalists you know
New York Times Atlantic they are just
lying lying for the government they are
pro-government so they are the opposite
of Journalism
so who is the real journalism for
example Julian Assange who is now in UK
jail okay
very sad story so
so there's one good use of Twitter and
and only on Twitter
okay that is if you want to dig the real
news in corrupt politicians their dirt
and if you want to know real news
uh world news so U.S USA domestic news
or international news Twitter
okay Twitter is is actually provide you
that gives you the real news from the
real people that have seen it you know
you know who or
um you know so-called citizen journalism
in some sense okay but there's also but
you have to know who to follow okay
because if you don't know you just
follow randomly you're for apart you'll
fall into the lies you know the fake
news the agents the trolls the BART
Farms the the AI Bart Farms fake you
know just tremendous millions of them
in giant giant scammers it's very
complex because on many political issues
anyways anyway I should talk about that
another day on Odyssey okay so watch for
my announcement if I'm gonna do that
uh the band provides feedback there may
be no studies messaging and
uh
[Music]
so let's see what's the next question uh
what spoken language do I know okay I
grew up with Chinese
[Music]
and then I learned English starting at
age if 14 so I've been speaking English
for most of my adult life
then around 14 I also lived in Montreal
Canada and Paraguay in South America so
I learned a bit Spanish back then
and and some familiarity with French but
I never uh kept them
[Music]
do they replace Hardware at the variable
data centers available in the United
States of America what do you mean
have you been using the kinesics 360. I
talked about that already I saw don't
you use Mac anymore I do but right now
my main my main computer is a gaming
machine you can just search for Sally
uh gaming machine or something like that
you'll find on my website
so
I do have a MacBook
with Emma and Chip the first generation
but it's a hassle to switch because you
know my desktop is already set up if I
switch to Mac M1 I'm not sure it will be
faster it might be you know maybe not
because the M1 the one I have only have
make eight megabytes of RAM and put on
my Windows desktop I have 16. so
I also have a large drive and so on so
if I'm gonna switch I need to also buy
you know the bunch of dongles you know
expensive 200 300 then you have to do a
lot of research on which one is good for
your monitor and so on
but I would say the Mac would be much
better than Windows I talked about that
many times before
[Music]
ah
okay so Wikileaks do you heard of have
you heard of WikiLeaks
why do you post so rare what
uh thank you you answer my question okay
uh okay so why do you don't shoot like
keyboard layers the one thing that you
just need to press one wants to access
keyboard layers okay
keyboard layers that's not good so I
have an article on that okay
[Music]
pan key codes okay so there's article
you can go read you should go read
uh because keyboard layers such as the
shift key and also old and Ctrl key they
are they are they are modifier keys so
they are you know when you use them you
know you call them key codes or key
combination they are no good because
they require
extra key press you know because
normally it's just one single key press
now you have to press two keys and you
have to press them in your in a
particular order like hold down this key
press that key release that key then
release the first key
any other way it doesn't work you can
just try to place them together just
doesn't work okay so that's key code and
the origin of key chords is historical
because of the shift key from mechanical
typewriters because when you press the
shift key
you know mechanical typewriters 200
years ago that actually shift gears so
there's a
literally Shifting the gears underneath
so you have to hold it so when the so
the gear are shifted then you press on
the key so they strike different letters
so that's shift key shifting gears okay
then when computer got invented you know
in
1960s 19 you know 70s and The Habit
stuck you know because of the typewriter
shift key so we started to invent so we
start we invented the shift key
such that you have to hold it down first
then press the yellow key then release
the other key then release the shift
that's the Habit from mechanical
typewriters okay
but the computer keyboard that's like
idiotic [ __ ] okay this is extremely
idiotic but anyway we don't know because
we we go by habit that's how we learn
that's how we evolve you know the Habit
you know it's obvious to us
the shift you know holding it down first
is the most natural then we then we
started to have control key by the same
method of a key chord you know then then
we started to have the
super high super key that eventually
became that eventually became today's
Mac command key or the window key okay
that's how things evolved so I have a
detailed keyboard history if you want to
know the history of each Keys okay
so anyway that's where key code came
from okay historically from the shift
mechanism of mechanical typewriters okay
so why is it bad so is it good or bad
it's not good because if you study
ergonomics
now normally you press one key now you
have to press two key but you have to
press them in a particular order very
complex but also because the location of
the modifier is usually on the side you
know it's difficult to press with your
pinky so it [ __ ] up your hands okay I
despise these stupid people who never
thought about things you know and they
promote emacs users for example emacs
users and many of the
40 keyboard do it yourself idiots okay
they don't they don't they don't think
about things they don't know
so anyway so
that's why they are bad complex
difficult to press and also using your
typically using your pinky so
and you cannot do them fast okay
so there's a lot of details and many
other articles about this issue on my
website okay so that's bad key key code
not good now in the past 10 years of the
do-it-yourself keyboard community
community of course they created a
keyboard like right now I'm using
gravity you have lots of thumb keys so
thumb Keys allow you to use thumb to
press the modifier so that improved the
situation a lot so for example I can
hold
you know control here and press F to
start to search or control you know hold
Ctrl with my left thumb and press in to
start a new window right or press Ctrl
you know and press W to close that
window okay
so thumb piece that's a huge Improvement
but in comparison that's still good no
good because for example if I want to
open look okay look how I operate if I
want to open a new window Ctrl n
normally now I just press one key okay
uh not that one actually I don't have a
let's see a new tab okay
you see one single finger
new tab you see now if I want to close
it one single finger close it okay new
close new close new close can you see
that
new close
as opposed to
Ctrl t for new
then Ctrl W to close okay
so you can see the efficiency aspect of
it
so you want a single key
now however you cannot just get rid of
the code key because the single key you
know you don't have enough Keys normally
a single keyboard you know you have F
Keys you can I I can also close you know
I can also do that for example
Ctrl t for new tab to close it I just
press this one single key can you see it
okay you it's it's this key you cannot
see it over there but I have to move the
camera but anyway
you know if I want to press you know
just this single key so that's a
situation so
and we have lots of tradition you know
Windows and Mac and Linux stick or out
of the box come up come you know they
have a bunch of code keys so
you can buy a new macro keyboard like me
but that's not practical I mean that's
you know you have to spend extra money
you know that
okay [ __ ] this guy pen
okay don't post [ __ ] okay
so that's about key key code okay so in
general it's not good so you want to
avoid it you you want to get rid of it
as much as possible
but you cannot you know unless you like
me you buy a dedicated keypad otherwise
it's hard to do because you have to
program your keys a lot so
uh so you can there are some solutions
you can turn on sticky key and others
uh uh you know you can turn you know I
have many articles here okay so just
read them
I talked about this a lot in lots of my
videos so it tends to be like just
repetitions all the time I think maybe
that's it for today
so I don't like the people the announce
you know who don't care about nothing
um
what's your opinion about veeam you know
what what kind of question is that
idiotic question or team question
uh
so there's a question you know there's
argument so to hit your new tab key you
have to move your hand quite far which
takes a lot longer that's true
but but idiotic opinion persistent
because I have I have written 10 000
articles on the details of each of these
questions okay so right now I have one
article addressing exactly your question
which is very common repeated by these
people by people don't think that you
know they don't really think okay
so for example F key uh
uh versus code so for example there
function key versus key code which is
healthier which is faster okay that
article is written
2017 okay to address that question
exactly you know most of these people
will say oh but the F key is far away
you know blah blah blah okay that's true
what they said is true because you know
obviously you have to move your hands up
to type the F key on a if otherwise if
you use chord you can just you know you
don't have to shift your whole hand to
do it that's a valid point
but that's not that that's not that like
the end of it that's just like oh so
therefore chord is better [ __ ]
idiotic facts this this brainless you
know on Hacker News on 4chan this
typical programmers fashion following
you know gets into onto my nerves
because I've I've I I wrote about this
you know over for 20 years lots of
details so anyway
even so anyway there's here's article so
that's one aspect that's true okay then
but
I won't go into detail because you know
you know those of you just you should
read the article okay so basically there
are several things you want to consider
first of all what exactly what keyboard
are you talking about exactly
are you talking about for example my
glove 80 right now I'm using okay that's
for example so you can compare
on this keyboard exactly so we are
talking about this keyboard we are going
to talk about this issue scientifically
with brain okay so on this keyboard the
function keys are here the code keys are
here so you can compare you know you can
do comparison on this specific keyboard
that's one
one of the issues you have to consider
is which keyboard are you talking about
now most of them are talking about this
normal normal-ish PC keyboard okay okay
on this keyboard you can also do the
analysis okay so on this keyboard you
know the function keys are on top and
the the code keys on the button
okay so first issue you want to dive
deep is which keyboard are you talking
about exactly okay
consider this for yourself because you
are going to maybe you are going to you
just started you know college you're
gonna be programming for the next 10
years so which which one should you do
should you use should you stick to the
conventional code or you should you like
me started to you know use the function
keys to program markers you know you
have to think about it you know for
yourself for your for the good of
yourself so first of all which keyboard
and and on on the question of which
keyboard you know whether are we talking
about this keyboard or on laptop
keyboard which is entirely a different
story okay in terms of how fast the
speed or the handheld long term in 10
years for example maybe on this keyboard
you know one way is easier but if you
use the laptop and use that way you're
gonna have hand pain you're gonna become
a [ __ ] after five years so have you
thought about that [ __ ] idiot
then are we what about this keyboard you
know because Microsoft ergonomic
keyboard is very popular and common so
on this keyboard the analysis will be
different story okay so one of the issue
is which keyboard are we talking about
then given a keyboard let's say let's
say the standard one let's now let's say
this one okay normal PC keyboard now we
can think about okay which weather is
more efficient you know whether the
function key is better or the code key
on what aspect okay for example
long term let's say five years you're
gonna type three hours a day let's save
you're gonna you know you're a
programmer or writer you're gonna use a
keyboard or photoshop or a video creator
editor you know like a YouTuber you're
gonna use a computer three hours a day
for next five years in five years which
way will
we'll we'll we are likely to have uh
give you hand pain
okay so that's one thing to consider
which one is which way is healthier
now the other aspect is which way is
faster
okay that's you know that's typically
what you guys are saying which way is
faster
okay
but but
yeah maybe maybe the code key is faster
on this keyboard maybe okay but even so
even so do you think that that that is
more important than hand hand health I
don't know you have to think about it
that's that's the thing okay but the
vast majority on the on the internet
talking about this they don't know they
don't know they don't even mention these
issues they are just they they us you
know I despise especially this this 40
the key code or the emacs idiots okay
okay that's what I have said to say
about that one
you know I get pissed you know there are
several reasons I get pissed and angry
because the good information people
don't follow and uh also personally
because I
study a lot of things on programming
languages on keyboard in depth and uh
I don't get I don't get you know I don't
get much reward you know meanwhile the
scums and scams the corrupt you know in
corrupt politician and also a lot of
people in programming Community they
become rich and past prosperous so
that's why
are many of these issues I'm um I get
angry about that
okay so so one shot layers that's a good
thing too
um you know so you know
so anyway yeah so let me give you my
personal opinion my personal opinion is
that I just don't don't use any cold
Keys okay and you buy if you you know
it's pretty you can yeah you can buy a
keyboard marker 40 you know extra
external keyboard Marco so you don't you
know so you can
so
so that will be best for your hand
health and uh it's it's also
tremendously easy to use because you
don't have to remember key chord you
know it's it's much better than key code
okay key code now if you are young uh
and if you don't want to have extra
elaborate equipment uh you know then key
code is good but you know just but think
about especially you know try not to use
a laptop keyboard in any circumstances
don't use a laptop keyboard
if you use a laptop keyboard and if you
use key code on laptop you're gonna
you're gonna have isi very fast okay
that's what happened to me
in 2005 that's my first the beginning of
RSI okay so there are there are so many
other considerations so you are saying
you know you are saying about the one
shot you know
a toggle key to turn on layer yeah
that's that's another solution okay but
then we get into lots of other Solutions
you know lots of others alternative
Solutions
um so so for example what you are saying
is a toggle key that that turns on a mod
then you know for example you press a
key then the right hand side becomes
number Keys becomes a number pad and you
press that key to toggle it back okay
that's one that's a good thing you know
not bad but however
you you do have disadvantages
for example what what you have now is
gonna you you are having mods now your
keyboard now become model
now every time you sit down you have to
know which mod it is seeing otherwise
you make a mistake
okay so so that has complex
uh put uh
issues
Pro inside cars so you have to consider
all kind of things
also if you want to do that that means
you have to spend a lot of time you have
to buy a programmable keyboard or do it
yourself you know you have to program it
typically you know I'm probably I'm I
can probably guess who who you are you
know in a do-it-yourself keyboard
Community which is very nerdy you know
no more people cannot do it you know
that's not the you know like
so I'm talking like to a small very
small niche of people you know they they
are thinking about that thing
yeah but that means you have to spend a
lot of time to create that thing you
have to spend a few hundred dollars to
buy a programmable keyboard or you have
to spend you know days to study various
ways to
um actually you can't even you you know
under the vast majority of software
keyboard software does not support that
feature Okay so
of of you know toggle layers okay so
that's that's what that's what you are
getting into okay so let me so to you to
those of you who are in to do it
yourself this Niche very very Niche
idiots okay let me just call them idiots
even for you
the toggle layout may not be optimal
because think about this let me give you
a practical example because if you buy a
do-it-yourself keyboard or gravity you
chances are you are probably
gonna still use a laptop keyboard at
least sometimes
you know because you have to go to work
sometimes at your friend house a library
so you are likely you cannot avoid using
a normal average standard keyboard
so that means so that means now you have
to have two two habits of pressing keys
because on this keyboard it's this way
to turn on number keys to turn on the
layers this and that very complex and if
you have multiple keyboard eventually
you will if you are the do-it-yourself
type of people then each keyboard how do
you to use them is different because
after a month or two you haven't used
one particular keyboard you forget what
that keyboard how that keyboard is
programmed
that keyboard basically become a break
to you because you forgot what how you
programmed it so every keyboard you have
different ways on this keywords model
that keyboard the the modifier is here
and here and this one you have special
numpad you know hell okay that's one of
the Practical issues for you do it
yourself kind of people okay so you have
to remember that
okay I think that's it that's it for
today
um started to get into a rant about
keyboard
uh you know a keyboard I talked about so
many times uh these issues
so many so many in my 300 videos in the
past
uh what else I think that's it for today
uh I don't feel so good thank you thank
you of famio for the five
five dollars donation you know you know
I started to rent so much I don't feel
so good because
all the questions because all those
questions are questions I answered a
thousand times before
um
yeah
okay so that's it so is there anything
else uh anything else important I want
to cover
oh is there one more question
uh
yeah I was going to so there's news
about glove 80 so they have a light
switch keyboard key switch available now
so you should buy
okay so I think that's it huh let's see
yeah that's it so tomorrow tomorrow San
Francisco San Francisco time noon we are
going to do emac Beast live coding on
um writing a
HTML and XML valid data in email please
tomorrow okay thank you Don Juan
thank you thank you guys
okay that's it bye guys thank you guys
for watching oh let me mention those of
you donated to me so I want to mention
some important big donors to me so Dion
has donated to me over 2 000. US dollars
in the past two to three years so Dion I
really want to thank Dion
and also I want to thank Alan Alan is
now soible Warrior Alan who also donated
donated to me two thousand dollars so
these are big donors you know I only
only two of them and also I'd like to
thank
um
Andrew who donated 500 so these are the
big ones you know I also appreciate you
know the small donuts as well so thank
you guys very much
bye guys