good morning good morning good morning
guys
today is 2021st this is sun talk show
and you are welcome to it and we are
going to do wufang language mathematica
coding
today and uh yeah just that topic i
think
uh you know uh post your comments and
questions
i think i'm just going to focus on that
topic
because it's better to focus on one
topic and
uh then next video we're going to do
imagine
coding or keywords uh it's better that
way it's better that way because
long term wise people can you know
who watch my videos offline can focus on
that so today's 2021st
august 1st well today's august now
august 1st
so today's talk show okay so i'm going
to uh let me tell you what
are we going to code today welcome back
good morning bot and we are going to do
three
fantastic subjects in geometry and we
are going to code it with wolfram
language okay wufang language
so we are going to code uh fantastic
buffalo language with it
and i'm going to show what to do so
uh greetings called bamboo so we are
going to so this is
the topic is geometric inversion now
that's
um that's kind of that's a process in
mathematics okay let me tell you what
what that is first of all uh so
here you can see some first of all you
see some pretty pictures
now this is circle inversion geometric
inversion of many circles
in recursively nested geometric
versions of circles so basically you
begin
with this image on the left you see
seven circles
then you you invert each circle with
respect to all each other circle
and you do that uh you do that about
three times three or four times then you
got this picture
isn't that beautiful fantastic now
here's another inversion so you begin
with these
six circles arranged like that then you
got that
so and similarly you start with this
image
uh five circles then you invert
each one every one each and every one
with respect to every other one
uh four times also you got this picture
and similarly and so on
and then in this picture you invert a
bunch of lines with respect to a circle
in the middle
okay a grid and in this picture you re
you invert a bunch of uh lines arranged
in a
kind of pentagonal way and you invert
all these lines with respect to a circle
in the middle
and you got this picture now this photo
and this one is an inversion of a grid
rectangular grid
with respect to a circle in the middle
then you get this uh
image on the right so this is called
geometric inversion
okay alternatively if you know
mathematics
alternatively it is the image of the
complex function one over z
yeah the base yeah one over z uh
or is it conjugate one over conjugate z
z
anyway it's it's uh it's the same it's
except it's flipped
it's mirror flipped okay but anyway if
you
know what i'm talking about you know
that already okay but if you don't know
what i'm talking about let me explain
okay so
this is geometric inversion so geometric
inversion is a process in math okay
so let me show you let me tell you what
that is what what is this
process okay so okay so here is a
picture
actually there's a live version
let me show you okay this slide version
so we need to turn on javascript
turn it on and uh refresh
and let's start this video here and good
morning
ndd those are pretty patent pictures so
how did you cam
come across this topic of geometric
inversion
well yeah well if you are if you are you
know
obsessive about mathematics which i was
in
in when i was you know around my 20s
in the 1990s i was obsessive i want to
be i want to become the greatest
mathematician
so you read a lot then you know a lot of
topic just like programming you you get
into
all sort of uh topics so
you know you can just search for
geometric inversion
there's a wikipedia article uh you know
of course i did this in the night
you see all these pictures i did them in
1990s
mostly 1990s 1996
to 1999 okay all these pictures so
you can see they are not anti-aliased
you know they
took by by today's standards it's kind
of lousy
and today in fact you should have
dynamic you know you should move your
mouse and
drag the circle around and see them
change dynamically
with javascript which i'm getting old i
intended
i i wanted to do that like five years
ago i still haven't done so
so and but anyway today we are going to
use mathematica
to code this uh so all these are done in
wufang language
uh back in 1990s 1997 1998
uh and today you know you go to uh
okay so let's go to wikipedia
but mostly i'm just going to show you
how do you code these okay so
the circle in circle inversive geometry
okay
it's kind of called inversive geometry
not but i'm not sure that's a good term
so they explained here it's a wikipedia
they explain the process how you do it
i'm going to do i i'm going to explain
okay and
and and this is also a fantastic idea
okay by the way
actually we we actually i might be able
you know i might show you how to code
this
so given a hyperboloid we talked about a
few days ago
this shape if you invert it
with respect to a sphere in three
dimension you know
then you get this this surface called
cycloid
very uh fascinating okay so geometric
inversion is a
it's it's kind of a general concept uh
you know if if you study math especially
if you are a geometer
you know you is this one of the things
you must know
but let me also mention this is not in
the standard curriculum
let's say you have a let's say you have
a
let's say you studied calculus for two
years one abc you know
all the calculus for two years in high
school or in college
but you may not know this concept
because
i mean if you have a math degree you
know bachelor's degree
let me close the door
you still may not know this concept
because
that's another topic because math just
like you know
math is big okay so but this is uh
but if okay so if you are uh
if you have a math degree you may not
still
know this concept you probably will but
not maybe not much however if you are a
good mathematician then you know this
con
concept for for sure okay geometric
inversion
especially for geometers now let me
uh let me explain what it is okay so you
uh so let's begin
with this um so geometric inversion is a
process okay it's a it's a it's it's
like a function okay
a function where uh
the parameters so so first of all let me
explain it geometrically
so it requires so it requires a circle
okay so it's a function first of all
and uh and uh
yeah okay forget about requiring a
circle so it's a function
in the plane let's say the
two-dimensional case in the plane so
given any point you apply the geometric
inversion
you get another point somewhere else
okay
so first of all understand it it's a
it's a function it's a mapping
from a plane to a plane okay so how how
so given so if
if i have a point p where does it map to
let me explain okay so you so in a
cartesian coordinate so this circle
this is a circle of radius one at the
origin
so given any point on the plane you
draw a line from the origin to the point
then then you um
then you uh actually i explained here uh
but
let me think if i can remember it
without you know you can actually read
it
equals to r squared
yeah okay i got it so this circle has a
radius of one okay
so what is given a point p what's the
what's the
output what's the point q so the point q
is
so so basically the distance from origin
to p
times the distance from o2 q equals to 1
or r squared whatever is the radius the
radius here is r
so you can see from the picture if q is
far away
the new point is inside the circle if q
is
close to a circle the new point is uh
close to the
circumference if the p is inside
then the the result point is outside the
circle so that's
that's a geometric inversion
so this concept so so you can see why
it's called inversion so basically
every every point outside the circle
becomes inside the circle every point
inside the circle goes outside the
circle
any point on the circle uh doesn't
change
remains the same okay so it kind of
swaps
the the plane inside out so you'll
notice
you know in another sense this is kind
of mirror so
every point outside the circle got
mirrored inside the circle you will see
you'll see that in a moment okay so this
is called inversion and it's
of course like i said before it's
related to the inversion
like 1 over x especially in the complex
plane it's like
you know so you can see you can also see
that from the definition okay so
let me go back here so if you read this
page you know just
search for geometric inversion sorry
you'll find uh you know step by step
explanation what it is okay
so now geometric inversion is a function
on the plane let's limit to the
plane case but it also works in
three-dimensional euclidean space or
four-dimensional
or higher dimensional euclidean space
okay but let's
just talk about the plane case
uh so so if so first of all it's a
function okay
it's it's a it's a function that maps
any point on the plane to another point
so once you got that idea you can see
what happens
if you draw any shape like a circle
whatever shape
on the plane and you try to invert it
what is the result
okay so there's some theories any line
inverts to a circle
and any circle inverts to a line by
itself
i mean okay so in
in other words if you have a circle you
know and you
invert every point on the circle what is
the result
usually it's another circle okay smaller
you know smaller or bigger if the circle
is outside that
center circle then then becomes a
smaller circle inside the circle
so anyway basically the theory is that
circles and lines invert to themselves
circle becomes circle lines becomes
uh lines become circle circle become
uh circle or lines okay so
the you know so here are the four
abcd four different cases limiting cases
so you can see so here is a uh animation
you can see
uh here is the animation you can see now
now this yellow
um open image in a new tab okay
you there's a yellow circle on the
origin
that is the inversion circle you cannot
see the dotted circle are the
other circle you want to invert then the
the other red one is the result okay so
that's kind of the
animation so whoops
yeah close the browser by mistake okay
we open
we open last page go back okay cannot go
back
and you will see geometry so let's go
to uh
so it relates the geometric inversion
relates to
uh in you know inversion or
in inverse multiplication or especially
in the complex plane complex numbers
okay so let me so let me start to call
wufang language okay
that's an explanation about this page
about what inversion is
so if you begin with you know a bunch of
grid lines like that you invert them
the here is a result okay so all these
lines become circles
it it this is kind of very interesting
because it swaps the plane
like inside out you know so
you know you know as outside comes to
inside inside comes out
around the circle so this is what
happens so you might wonder why is there
a hole
in the middle because you see we begin
with this squid
if this grid if all these lines extend
to infinity
then then there will be no hole
you you are seeing the hole because the
this
this kind of a club shaped hole
is actually the boundary the boundary of
the square
you see but if your square if your grid
is infinite in size
there will be no holes you know it forms
a hole because
things outside comes inside you know so
that's why you see that
so it's fascinating and then then
there's many um
for example this linkage we talked about
highly important in
robotics uh today and in the past
so this is this linkage is based on the
idea of geometric inversion uh basically
so it converts linear vector linear
motion to a circular motion okay so how
do you
how do you do that let's see
how do you uh
okay so you can see the red line is a
rotational motion
uh um and the blue line is a
linear motion so if you are doing
mechanics robotics you need
some kind of this conversion linear
motion to a rotational motion
now how do i show this as a good example
um
yeah okay so this is anyway this this
linkage is called porcelain
posterior posterior linkage you can see
it
on wikipedia by the way
okay so enough talking okay so let's
let's do let's uh code wu from language
let's how do you like how do you
actually
create this image let me show you okay
so let's start coding with
language so uh so first of all what is
the
thing we want to code any any questions
i'm getting into math starting with
algebra and trigonometry that's great
so we want to start to code okay let's
see what i want to code so i want to
code this one okay
so uh yeah so let's write start to write
code
so how do you um let me let me think
okay
um
uh square okay
first of all let me see if there's a
square function in
from language
magnify so square
okay so this is not
uh
okay so that's not what we want
first of all we want a graphics
primitive so
we want some some function to represent
a
uh square okay so let's say polygon
let's go to talk show let's go to
today's talk show
let's start some wolfram language uh
and let's start to code some polygon
okay
polygon and the polygon
so four points okay so this is a plane
zero one
zero one start with
zero zero zero zero two zero one
two one one two zero
yeah so okay zero zero two one zero one
one
two zero one then back to zero zero okay
so that's our polygon okay
so and that's graphics 3d
okay uh
okay that shows a square now let's say
x is true
uh okay there's no
way there's no axis
oh yeah so i i play this is wrong
yeah so now axis
okay so now you can see that the axis we
have so we have a square
of
of a side length one okay but
let's see
let's see cube cube represents a
rectangular cube centered or engine
and unit length okay cube is 3d i want a
2d
square it doesn't seems there is a
square function
let's do this okay
anyway so let's say polygon yeah what am
i what are we doing so we wanted to
generate this
so the idea is that begin with a one
square
then you create lots of unit
squares from your grid then you apply
the
inversion to them all okay so let me
just quick
code it quickly
so first of all table okay table
x y
x from 1 to negative 5
to 5 y
from negative 5 to 5.
so we got a matrix okay a bunch of
coordinate
values uh then
let's name these grid points
okay great points bunch of
values then
so then we want to map this uh
let's do a 3d case okay let's maybe
let's do a 3d case
cube cube uh let's see cube
q represent the cube with h length uh
cube centered at that
rotate it by an angle with respect okay
cube represent the cube centered it okay
let's
let's try the 3d case let me generally
just code it
so so if we do a 3d case let's see
then
z 0 5 to 5
okay x y z so now we have a
three dimensional matrix now actually
table okay so cut it so we want a cube
with these points and
length one okay so we got bunch of cubes
now graphics three
d okay
great points okay show it
okay so we got a bunch of cubes
you know i'm trying to do a
three-dimensional case here instead of
you know i can do two but you know this
uh
the the way i i called it just happens
that
perhaps we let's try the 3d case first
okay so um so we got a bunch of cubes
now
we want to shrink each one um a little
bit so we don't want
uh wait
oh yeah so wait
okay so we got a bunch of points let's
see let's
let's say smaller let's say six okay so
we got
lots of uh grids now let's define our
inversion okay so inversion with respect
to
let's let's define a inversion
inversion function okay
now is there a uh there's no i don't
think there's a building inversion but
it's it's so trivial that is why they
don't have a building
so let me just define it myself okay
x y z those are the
input and the output is going to be
okay what is the formula for geometric
inversion
okay here so you can see here is the
formula
kind of paste it uh
let's that's pretty fine pretty fine
okay
so r is
let's say ah okay i is the radius
now so this is a 2d case
now we want a 3d case ap
so what is the a and b so inversion of x
y b is reached
centered at a b okay so yeah
okay so let's do circle
a b so a and b
is the center of the circles this is a
2d case okay a and b
is the center of the circle i is the
radius
now normally in in the normal case we
assume a
a and b is 0 0 okay so
n i is uh what
and x y is the input so this will return
this thing will return the um you know
the new point
of the geometric inversion 2d let's say
2d okay so
yeah so that is the case
okay so let's try
let's let's try
one and one okay so what happens to the
point one
and one if we invert it with respect
to a circle at origin and radius one
okay now what if we give it a um
symbolic result so here is a symbolic
result very simple
so that's a three that's a 2d case let's
write the 3d case okay
let's write a 3d case now the 3d case
is z
3d so so a and b
and c
so this is a circle now in 3d you have
one more coordinate
you have one more coordinate c
and so here will be
z minus b abc
abc all right
first
i think that's that's it can we do that
yeah so this is the 3d case now let's
is that double check okay let's double
check
um let's double check okay so that's
x y z abc is the center of the circle r
is the radius
so x y z is the input point so x minus
a y minus b z minus c
okay then times r squared divided by
that
uh plus abc okay i think that's right
so so now let's call it
okay let's just copy that copy
paste so in general what happens if you
invert it okay to a circle
uh yeah three d three
okay so here is what happens
in general okay
okay we okay so fine fine so let's now
let's try to invert this cube okay so
so that's a bunch of we have a bunch of
cubes
so cubes now
we have a bunch of cubes we want to
apply these
two the bunch of cubes
what is a bunch of cubes
let's see
i want to see what is the uh
i want to see what is the um
what is the uh
what is a structure
okay so let's see so cubes so anything
cubes apply inversion okay got it
so that i'm trying to see the structure
of this cube's expression
so now i know the structure i can do
transformation on it
so cubes so any cube
cube has a radius okay so radius
will become
geometric inversion 3d
apply the point of the cube
and apply this okay
copy it let's just copy it
and here is just p
okay so this is what we want
yep you see we have applied
the geometric inversion 3d to the center
of the cube so this is a result so we
can actually show the result
let's hope it works
cubes cube oh okay so wait what
what what is the error
cube is not a graphics 3d primitive why
is it not
i thought it is
cube is not a graphics 3d primitive or
directive it is what are you talking
about
you see cube cam you see cube can be
used in graphics 3d
uh
let's try again okay so let's
close that
don't save okay what's going on
oh we forgot the
x y z did we forgot the
oh we forgot the z yeah so you see the z
is not evaluated to a number
so why is the z not evaluated to a
number
so cube geometric inversion p
so let's try that again oh yeah so we
yeah we we
uh yeah so we need to evaluate this
do it okay then
show it
okay now we got the actual cubes
now now we
do this infinity okay forget it's
you know you got infinity when a cube is
centered on zero or zero you know
you cannot you see you cannot invert
when a point is at uh at the same as the
inversion circle okay so anyway
it but anyway it should work okay so
let's show the previous
this better show my friends
okay oh okay so i know what's going on
so we got this
okay one more thing to do let's see um
oh yeah so uh yeah so we got um
one more thing to do so we we got this
error because
we need to dis discretize the cubes
essentially so that's right um
okay
okay so
so we got a cube geometric inversion
we need to apply the inversion to the um
to the um
we need to apply the geometric inversion
to the
coordinate coordinates of the cube not
the center of the cube okay that's a
problem
you see we are applying the geometric
inversion to all the centers of the cube
and
um
let's see what happens let's see let's
see 0.1
okay let's just give it some
okay so now you got this kind of thing
um
okay i have to think i have to i have to
think about this
so
so you so our formula
so our formula geometric inversion 3d
takes a point and the circle
oriented i mean center of the circle
here abc
then the radius then the result is that
okay so for example for example
at this point the result is that okay so
this
is a geometric inversion of a point
in 3d okay so this function
transforms a point and returns another
point
in euclidean uh r3
space and so now
now we got a bunch of cubes
uh
okay let's i know what to do discrete
discretized
cubes you see we are applying the
transformation to each cube
and the cube is specified by a center
and a rate and the length of the cube
like that
so but that's not what we want to do
you see what we are actually doing is
just moving the cube
around it doesn't change anything we are
just
applying the geometric uh trans you know
the inversion to
the center of the cube we just move the
cubes around
but what we actually want is uh let me
show you okay
discretize uh circle okay
so um so i can show you
what we want to do we want to consider
the cube
not just a you know atomic thing
we want to consider
we want to consider each you know a cube
is formed by
several lines right several lines for me
or cube we want to
right right now we are just considered a
cube as one single point
that's not good what we actually want is
to consider the cube
as us let's say one two three four five
six seven eight the eight corners of the
cube
and uh transform those corners corner
points
okay then we we will get a better result
but actually what we really want is to
consider all the points in the line
that makes up the cube transform all
that points
so in order to do that we can do a disc
uh i believe this is the function
discretize graphics this
discretize a 3d or 3d graphics into
a mesh region okay so let's try that
okay i'm not sure this works
i'm you know i'm doing this for the
first time
since like 20 years ago so
this is new function wolfram language
has lots of
uh new functions okay so let's
discretize graphics
let's see what happens to when we do a
cube
okay okay so
so what is the um
[Music]
so what is the actual structure of that
graphics
full form okay
let's see okay so you got
mesh region
okay so you got the mesh region
yeah okay okay now you got tetrahedron
okay tetrahedron
so you got uh what is this mesh region
list list you got two lists
mesh region list
list so a bunch of lists
and then
i'm not sure
okay that's not what we want
not not the mesh region okay
we want actually i know what we want so
we want
uh actually you see the mesh region
this the discretized graphics basically
breaks the graphics down to
lots of bunch of points so you see a
circle
becomes lots of points that that is
the essentially what we want but but in
our case
in our case
geometry computation so what are we
doing so
yeah this is annoying cube okay polygon
yeah i think i know what now
what i'm doing i we want canada
canada canalized polygon something like
that
so polyhedron so we want to turn the
cube into
okay here
canaanite collides polygon gives a
canonical representation of the polygon
poly
with shared coordinates okay so let's
try that so
so what happens if you do that 2 cube
and that doesn't
what
okay so polygon
[Music]
so i actually not polygon we want
polyhedron
okay
and you don't have
god we stuck this is gonna
this is taking longer than what is it
supposed to
yeah okay there it is
yeah there it is so
yeah that's what we want
so let's see what is this
so we got a polyhedron so we got a
polyhedron
um
and see what is a structure
why is it uh fully hatred and why is it
bunch of lists
okay we you know i can do this but
my explanation of how it works will not
um you know it
you know i i i can just start to code it
and in 20 minutes it will be done but
i i uh
i don't think i can explain all the way
to
to it uh
so so we have
so yeah so we have to
so let's see so we got um
we got cubes we turned them into
polyhedrons
uh and polyhedron is also new around
2006 i believe
oh 2019 so it's very new two years ago
three years ago
so and what exactly is the structure of
polyhedron
it uh fairly complex okay
so polyhedron polyhedron boundary phases
okay polyhedron
okay this is more complex than i thought
why don't i just go my way
just to the way i would um
so we begin with 2d and now we mentioned
ventured into 3d now in either case
you know this is not a huge jump because
it works similarly either in 2d or 3d
so we can continue on with the 3d case
no problem
and with for the 3d case you'll see more
spectacular graphics
which is good for you know doing v uh
youtube you'll see you know i'm gonna
show you spectacular graphics which i
actually never done before
even in the 1990s uh geometric inversion
of three-dimensional objects
so that's what i i'm trying to do now uh
and so let's continue with 3d because
you know it does not add much complexity
at all the work they work in the same
way
so but the problem right now i have is
okay
let me just talk over so like talking to
myself
and and you'll be better as well
so let me have a drink
so we're gonna push on with the 3d case
we want to do geometric inversion of a
bunch of cubes or a grid a rectangular
grid in three-dimensional space we want
to invert it with respect
to a sphere in this in the center of the
coordinate
okay so and of uh and and
we have our function here so
this this function is defined that way
it's it's good
so it's correct definition geometric
version of 3d given a point
and uh and a circle and radius it
returns a new point that's good
so now but we want to see the graphics
we want to see what happens to this
bunch of cubes
when you apply uh
uh
okay so i i i think i know what to do so
okay so
hold on a second so so a cube
given a cube with its center
yeah i know i know what to do okay so
even given a cube
we are going to write you know the the
result actually will be one single line
like no more than 200 characters i mean
the whole code will be no more than 200
characters
i'm just stuck in the process okay but i
can finish
maybe in 20 minutes so here is the what
we want to do okay so
cube so we have a cube
and radius we so we want to transform it
we want to transform it into uh each
cube let's see
let's let's do it the silly way okay let
me do
it the kind of the primitive way so
i mean the focus is just to get it to
work then
we worry about the you know
elegance of the code or stuff so cube
so p is the point so
so we want to turn a cube into a polygon
and did we succeed
we want to turn a cube into a polygon
so discrete discretized graphics
[Music]
uh
but what is the
i want to show the actual data mesh
themes no i don't want mesh
pretty okay
so you got the mesh
so what kind of uh
but what is the structure of this thing
decorate a mesh what the what the
is this
view options
print so
so we got a mesh here embedded dimension
geometric dimension 3
but i want to see the actual code i mean
what
what e like this okay so
actually so like that
okay so
actually i can see the code yeah so here
is a better
mesh region a bunch of so mesh region
then tetrahedron oh okay so
okay so here mesh region the way mesh
region works is that the first argument
is a bunch of
coordinate points okay data points
points in
in three in 3d in this case each point
is three coordinates
then you have a tetrahedron and each
of its arguments the number refers to
the index
so for example here you have a
tetrahedron
with points with the with the
you know the corner point seven six one
five
that means the seventh points in the
data here
then the sixth then the first then five
that forms the tetrahedron okay
so so how did we get this so
yeah so we turn a cube discrete
discretize graphics we turn a cube
into a bunch of tetrahedron
we we turn a cube into a bunch of
tetrahedron
into like uh you know like one
two three four how many one two three
four
one two three four one two three
four five six six tetrahedrons
wait how is that
okay so six tetrahedrons
we turn a cube into six tetrahedrons
and uh
why this why is there no option to show
transparency what the
okay so we turn a cube into six six
tetrahedrons
and the structure of them is in this
that's the structure of the expression
okay
once you have tetrahedron then you
um
okay so let's do this so okay i know
what you
to do
so cube so change cube
into um
do
okay we are turning each cube into
a into a
into a discrete graphics okay
then then we
turn each each tetrahedron
when then we turn each mesh
region
okay then we turn each mesh region
we then we turn each mesh region
okay mesh region
so mesh region has got length two right
this is
actually um
you know the code is not so great but
yeah so mesh region got two arguments
okay
so mesh region
so mesh region got two arguments
then
the first argument is
the first argument is a list of points
okay
so data points
okay graphics
okay
okay so measure region we patent match
mesh region match their arguments
then we
we turn them into
okay so i think
so this needs to be a function
so you don't know what i'm doing but
i know what i'm doing okay because
you know the mathematical syntax what
what is this ampersand and what is slash
at you don't know what i'm doing but i
know what i'm doing okay
so
data points so we
so we want to map them
yeah so we want to map that okay so
double
zero
and then this is no good
let's just evaluate and see what happens
oh god this is gonna take a long time
this is incorrect i'm pretty sure
all right
okay i'm gonna finish this for sure
as this turns out too much
yeah this is no good why is it showing
this bunch of things
idiotic you know thousands of them
okay
that's not what we want
so
yeah this is this is not good i have to
think okay so
so
okay so
let's reduce the number of
that's a lot of cubes
and three
let's see
reduced number of cubes okay there's
still a lot
five times five times five okay
so but let's say let's see three
okay
one two three okay let's see
okay so now it's much less number of
cubes great points
wait what is this cubes
okay so now it's much less
so now
a cube so a cube center
let's see can we plus one
one two three one two three four five
six seven eight so you got eight points
okay let's look at the documentation for
cube
okay so cube is centered at origin
okay so this output is no good
and we want to see what's going on with
these
okay so
so that and
[Music]
and and that gives you
that gives you a bunch of tetrahedrons
tetra tetrahedrons so mesh
region so a cube
a cube returns a you know you
discretize graphics a cube
what what if you have some bunch of
other
numbers three four five
let's say radius two okay same thing i
suppose
yeah so so this is uh
same thing basically
yeah so so discrete
discretized graphics of a cube
returns a bunch of uh
returns a mesh region and and the mesh
region is
the structure of it is two arguments
the first part is data points the second
part is tetrahedron
so
so mesh region
we can transform mesh region
map yes we can map
so this should work
we can turn a mesh region
so can we actually plot that
let me try
yeah we can fantastic okay so
now we are back to our transformation
process
uh which is here
so we are transforming a cube
to
[Music]
any cube becomes discrete
graphics
okay any cube becomes
discrete graphics then
for each match mesh region
we map to
then for each one we map it
why is it not
yeah we got a bunch of
okay so what
so we do that the image region
how becomes that okay
that do it man
yeah okay so
so okay so we got we got
that okay so let's see
let's say that okay result
x then graphics 3d
result x fees
what happens to our inversion didn't we
just apply the inversion to the points
our inversion did not apply we
did it
not not what the coordinates given at
position 1
in mesh region pdsg
are not at least the real valued points
in the same
dimension okay you got up
somewhere
open
so mesh region so it's just at least the
mesh regions that's correct
okay that's a structure of this
of this expression of this expression
so it's a at least the
uh mesh region okay
now but why is it uh
let's try it again so mesh region
each one is three numbers that's right
so mesh region each one is three numbers
okay then
then cubes um
okay let's let's do that
so what is the result
okay don't know what's going on
z so zero so so
so cube you don't want to have a cube
beginning at the region
so let's modify
so you got infinity 1 over 0
encountered that is because when you
apply geometric inversion 3d
to something on the way to to
to a point on our engine then you got
that
that's right so if x y z equals to zero
then okay so we can modify the
expression
let's try to modify this expression
uh if
let's try this okay
let's say
three four five equals to
three four five point zero
force okay but
true okay so that works so that's one
way so you can check
so if
x y z equals to that
then
then just that okay otherwise
otherwise that
actually this is stupid okay let's do it
so let's rewrite that
let's rewrite that as
let's redefine that as that now
what
oh this is we got we we got it wrong
it should be over here
and this should be over here yeah
we evaluate that
do that yeah okay we got we need to
redefine them so clear
okay so now
that's right so now we got this
definition back
now let's save it save this
okay then
then let's try to do this
no we don't have the we got rid of the
infinite
you know division by zero uh
problem which which may be a problem
because when you have that
then you do graphics then you may run
into uh problems
uh i don't know if that's our problem
but possibly okay
so now we got the so now we got what we
want let's see
cubes okay so okay
now let's let's see what
we
[Music]
now what uh show stack trace
what
now i want to understand what exactly is
the
is the structure of mesh regions
so mesh region is always
true arguments
so why does it say the coordinates given
a position
1 position one image regions
are not
what the i don't understand
i don't understand
what what
do
okay that is why
yeah but
why are you giving that era
so we've been coding this for an hour
and let's say 2
30 for 90 minutes already
and we haven't done nothing we failed
yeah miss region that you know so
menstruation is new i know
you know i know a better way to i mean
not been you know the
classic way i you know if i just do it
my own way i should be able to do it
but but miss region is definitely
something
i should use because it is you know now
new part of ufam language
so what normally what i can do normally
is that okay save the uh
so cubes you know so we got a bunch of
cubes
then we uh we plot it okay so we got a
bunch of cubes
then we uh we define our inversion
okay that's a 2d case then we define our
3d case by this formula which is correct
okay then you know and we test it that's
correct
then we uh let's let's see what happens
yeah kind of
yeah okay
yeah there's a translation okay so
basically this is about translation okay
so anyway
so this formula is correct uh definition
of
geometric inversion 3d uh
then our problem is
now actually generating the graphics
the formula is correct so cube
and see how many face one two one two
one two three four five
six so you you need a sixth phase of
uh of uh of a
cube okay let's do it
our own way shall we so anyway
i i need to turn a cube to a bunch of
polygon
now i don't understand you know so how
do i turn the
cube into polygon back to the question
i mean i can do it manually but i want
to be able to use
wolfen language
what
canonical
canonicalized polyhedron this should
work but what does it return exactly
yeah i could read them a bunch of
rational
okay so so it returns a bunch of uh
it's so it's a polygon
that stupid standard form
so it returns it returns a
so cube becomes a polyhedron okay
a cube becomes a polyhedron
yeah this is okay so i should use
connect
canonicalize canonicalized polyhedron
instead of
discrete discretized graphics
because this is a better okay so so cube
becomes a polyhedron and polyhedron
has two arguments okay so let me show
you so polyhedron has two arguments the
first part
yeah you know the first part is a bunch
of
points okay the second part is
a bunch of polygons they specify how
yeah okay so yeah so let's do that
okay so let's instead of uh
instead of discretized graphics
let's turn that to
yeah so this is what we want okay so
input form
that's right so this is uh you know so
it becomes a bunch of polygon
okay a cube becomes a bunch of uh
general polygon
and the polygon is has two arguments the
first part is data points
a bunch of at least of points the second
part is the
indexes that forms each face
a polygon okay
so you know each one of these group of
numbers is a
polygon that forms the face of the
polyhedron okay so
now so we turn a cube into a bunch of
polyhedron okay then
then we okay so then we
okay so then we um
so cube so a bunch of cubes becomes
okay so copy that
let's let's do that
okay so
yeah yeah
okay so that's what we want then
then
[Music]
anyway so that's what we want then so we
got result x
then result x becomes
let's see polyhedron
so polyhedron the first part is bunch of
points
then
okay then we're gonna map our function
to
it
okay so map our function
zero vector now
let's do it fantastic
i think we i think that's it
okay now we got our result two
save it
let's let's see
show it no
result x no nothing changed
what the
what
what happened to our transformation
why is it not transformation not
applied
first argument second argument did we
did we make a kind of a cd
um
did we make a silly
syntactical error
oh now it becomes what now because
it becomes one single cube
what uh okay
i think the problem is me have not been
coded mathematica for a long time i i
might have
made some
very simple error
what is result too
so result two is a bunch of polyhedron
okay so if we can if we
make this into a standard form
yeah so polyhedron
oh you see you see now you see each one
of them have a different
shape yeah so that's what we want
exactly so our transformation worked
you see each one of these cubes become
kind of funky
exactly because we applied our geometric
inversion
on the corner points
okay so it worked
you see especially you know look at this
one dimension type polyhedron
did we spell something something wrong
so so result
2 worked okay
but when we show result 2 in graphics 3d
why is it not showing funky nothing why
is it just showing one single cube
code bamboo you are still here
son can you talk more about your 20s in
aspiration
to being the best mathematician i'm in
my 20s and have similar aspirations
about programming
oh yeah this it's simple it's trivial
now um
you know i became what i became is
because you know that's a
great great side track okay so
so i got excused to talk about something
else
but actually you know we should i should
finish this because we are
so very close you know this is just me
working
i'm surprised you're still here so
so okay so yeah
so i wanted to be a great you know i
wanted to be
a great i actually i did you know i was
kind of a weird guy
very ambitious i wanted to be one of the
greatest mathematician okay like
he's you know like top 10 in history
that was i i wanted to become and
and i failed very badly you know i'm not
even a
professional mathematician
well that is my personal life story uh
and there are several there are few
you know there are some reasons for that
well
you could say you know put it simply one
reason is that because i procrastinate i
have a problem
yeah um you know you know maybe
or you could say i didn't work uh you
know anyway
for some 10 years i didn't work for
various reasons so i
become very poor i live in you know
poverty below poverty and then
anyway i just didn't you know become so
because i didn't work and that's not
good
you don't have money and when you don't
have money you don't have food and when
you don't have food you you
you cannot do anything uh so
that is my personal problem okay
and you know my my problem my story
uh you know but if you are a programmer
you know it's
unless you are very very extreme you you
happen to be like me
but there's something wrong okay you'll
be fine
you know you you do programming after
two years
heavy study code every day you know code
ten five hours a day and you know don't
push yourself you know five hours is
good enough
persistently on average statistically if
you go five hours a day
for two years you can essentially work
for any
big giant corporation you want now
coding is just very vast you know coding
is you know there are so many different
fields
there's gaming there's operating
operating systems there's
networking there's kernel
yeah well operating system there's low
level well low level then there's
you know there's a scientific coding
like we are you know
and there's educational what i'm doing
right now coding this thing is kind of
kind of a
educational thing or all part of
scientific
coding which you need to do if you are a
mathematician or if you work for
nasa for example or if you research
ai for example these states are very
popular
very common and very highly required
you know needed skill so yeah so
i mean today mathematician there's a lot
need for mathematicians now uh you know
especially with the aih so yeah
uh statistician also so anyway so you
you know if you wanna you know
study math or programming especially
programming after
two years you have you'll be good to go
um
and you'll have bread for life just like
me
it you know so i was fairly doing fairly
well but for
it's hard to say you know when your life
why why it happened you know
i just became uh kind of
maybe maybe partly because i'm too
ambiguous
ambitious okay i you know i despise
lots of things you know google like
google sent me
you know back in 2005 google's you know
send me a
request you know oh we like you you know
maybe you are
uh like to work for google and i
i you know i didn't i
kind of ignored ignored it
so anyway so yeah so so that's my
problem okay
for many reasons how to say
uh so anyway so let's continue i want to
finish i want to continue what's going
on you know exploration of
the uh wufam language which i haven't
coded for 20 years
so what is going so let's come back
actually i'm also getting tired
what what so what is our problem so do
you uh does that sounds good
i already have 10 plus years experience
start at 14
okay so what so so um
so so what is your like what
what question what do you have any
specific question or specific
aspect you want to ask me or something
yeah because i don't know you know it's
because there are so many different
people
in a world you know i have especially
for me my followers tends to be
not the normal american okay it tends to
be over the
world in russia in middle east in africa
in you know in in south america
all over the place in england and europe
in germany in
in japan in hong kong and also in china
so i don't know what's your background i
haven't
i don't know you i don't know if you are
on my discord
and you especially with you guys you
know anonymous name so anyway
i don't know what kind of person or what
kind of you know this is very diverse
like i cannot imagine
you know like you see me you kind of
know me because you see
my face that tells you already a lot of
things
but online you don't know who they are
you know so i don't know what's your
uh specific questions or what you want
to ask me about
okay so but yeah so i hope you do good
you know
i i love programming and i love math and
especially i always
i still have the opinion they are the
greatest thing
um you know of course for many people
they cannot do it it's not suitable for
them you know oh i'm not good at math
oh you know well even i don't i don't
know anything about computers a lot of
people are like that
so for them maybe they go to leadership
they go
become politicians or they become
businessmen
yeah okay fine but if
for many of my followers you know we are
into
you know we are nurse we are into
programming we are into computers very
much
so it's a very great uh job and you know
profession
profession and you don't actually need
to go to university so i'm
i'm basically self-taught uh
so yeah you can do that i'm bored of
the web dev yeah then what is worth
going to programming wise i want to make
what you call
permanent work okay so now
that's a different question because now
you are picky you are tired of
web dev uh
um and you want to
yeah so i don't know you know that you
have to
i mean you have to you have to find out
yourself and you know there are so many
i don't know
i don't know you know systeming or
whatever game dev you know
i i don't think there's you know
i don't think it's gonna be
ideal you know what you know because
when you go into another field you'll
find oh it becomes boring also depends
on the company so
so i want to get some coffee actually
so i'm kind of um
uh anyway i'm tired let me get back to
this
so what's the other celtic orthodox
okay math social
uh youtube lots of good books okay
okay so we kind of failed to do this and
i'm getting tired
but we are close um because
the result will be spectacular okay the
results
i'm not going to show you some wikipedia
but anyway i
i'm very close okay um but
i want i want to finish this so
we are so very close so so why is it
so yeah so we got the result so
so result 2
which is result 2 is showing one single
cube
that's definitely up
what
and what is this so we have so many
so many polyhedron
but why is it when you show
in graphics it just uh one of them
i mean this is
okay that's it for today i guess i'm i'm
tired i can you know i'm gonna
so i talked for uh 90 minutes
um
and kind of failed that's that's that's
a pity because
i'm so certain that i can do this
um
shut down or not yeah and it's shut down
it's
i've i work this offline i'm gonna maybe
i'm gonna delete this
live stream i walk this offline so i get
a better sense then maybe
i'll do another one tomorrow or
sometimes later so i can show you again
you know
instead of you watching me you know
fumbling around
i'll just show you know in 10 minutes
explain everything
and show the spectacular results of
of inversion okay so so that's what we
are talking about
uh inversion we were we were going to
code this
and i i thought why not let's just do 3d
case because
it shouldn't be more difficult but it
turns out didn't we didn't finish okay
okay thank you guys for watching bye
guys
okay so i'm gonna shut down in two
minutes
there's something truly weird here
hey but but you still here see you next
time but thanks
for coming by
okay i'm gonna
i cannot believe this is not okay so
now it shows okay hold on a second
guys i think i got it
there it is okay let me show hold on a
second guys
don't go yet we we did it
yeah
what hold on a second okay we almost did
it
we almost haven't had it
so what the what the with
the graphics 3d
so something
yeah so so you know if i show just part
of it
you see so you can see we we got you
know we got a bunch of cube
inverted geometric inversion but however
right now the problem is that for some
reason the graphics
is not showing them all you know it's
just showing one of them i don't
understand
you know probably something trivial
because i'm getting tired here
um you know so if we see the result too
you know the structure is that it's just
a bunch of polygons
okay so they are you know they are you
know let's say dimension okay
so four four four you know it's a nested
matrix it's a list of four items each
one is another four items each one
is another four items okay so
so why is the list of um
a polygon not
okay so let's try this okay i know what
to do
okay hold on a second
okay
so why is it why does this works then
i don't understand
so we got a total of 64 of them
but why what but but why is that
if you put in a graphics it does not
show
do
okay i don't know give up hey
ze trunk crazy what's up
okay okay okay
okay let me sit let me why don't i
figure this out
because this this is very strange
so now the problem you see now the
result
actually contains the correct graphics
okay
so here's our result too that's actually
correct
contains the correct graphics it is a
nested
list of four items then another each one
contains four items and four items okay
so dimension is four four four
a at least but the problem is that
the problem is that if you show it in
graphics it doesn't
it doesn't show the thing it
just shows one cube
but however if you show you know part of
the
you know the list you know if you
extract
the result then then it shows you see
so i do not understand
i do not understand what's going on with
these
primitives okay
so i do not understand what is going on
with this
okay let's uh quit kernel and let's
start over
maybe that will fix things
because this is pretty odd okay let's
start from the beginning
first of all save the buffer
computes three plus
three okay delete that
okay then points we don't need anymore
then we start to compute so cubes
okay so we do cubes okay
then we
show cubes okay that's good then we
we define our function
geometric inversion 3d okay then we
test it correct then we
transform our cubes
okay wait this is not what we want we
transform
we we transform our cube's expression
which is these
you know this bunch of cubes we
transform them by
replace each cube by
canaanite uh canon
colise polyhedron okay
we do that okay then
here's a result essentially
uh there is essentially a list of
input form okay
so so essentially it's a list of um
polyhedrons okay
so result x is a list of polyhedrons now
let's try to show result x
to see if that works okay so
yeah that works okay because we haven't
we haven't converted we haven't applied
the geometric transformation yet
so you know let's show it
for example wait what
all right so but now
result 2 equals to result x
we transform it into a
we do that
okay so we got at least a bunch of
polyhedron again
that's result two then
show the input form that's good
okay this is too long
then show the dimension that's good
result to show it
same problem but now if we show
part of it
oh i know what's going on i know what
is going on you know the reason you are
seeing this
whole thing in one like one cube
is because all the rest is inside it
because remember the inversion
yeah the inversion inverted inside
becomes outside
outside becomes inside so on the outside
you have the one giant
cube
is that right yes they
they all be i think so i'm pretty sure
okay so now
you let's let's do some uh transparency
opacity point five okay let's do it
okay so wait uh okay so these two needs
to be in
the same together okay
there you have it fantastic my friends
finally
okay so this is going this is
spectacular okay
so you are just only you are seeing just
part of it okay
uh you see but now let's
let now let's let's uh let's let's make
the whole thing
okay now let's clean up the whole thing
and let's make it
truly spectacular okay so
so this video i can say after two hours
i did it
[Laughter]
okay so cubes uh cubes we don't need so
let's make this clean
okay cube yeah we need cubes okay so but
this but instead of
from 0 to 3 let's say negative
as 3 2 negative 3 to negative three two
three okay
so now we got massive number of cubes
okay
so now you show it
what okay zero two three we forgot the
negative sign
yeah so now we got massive number of uh
number of cubes do it then
show it fantastic okay
now wait a minute now let's i want some
transparency okay
so opacity
0.5 then cubes okay
do it okay so now we got a
you know massive number of
semi-transparent cubes okay
now save it now the 2d case we don't
need and let's clean up our code so
the 2d case delete delete
delete so now we define our
three-dimensional case
geometric inversion okay and
test works okay now we
now now we we actually let me
truncate this let me just show you the
one single result
you know instead of me fumbling before
let me show you the proper way
because i made a miss you know it's a
silly mistake so let's review
what what is a mistake i because i
forgot
i i forgot that geometric inversion
you know it it it covers your cubes
that's why you don't see it of course i
don't see it because the outer cube
covers the whole thing
so i do about nothing for about
40 minutes idiotic
okay i i i you know i i wonder why does
this work
not work i know it should work but it's
not working
so i you know i do about nothing for 40
minutes about
so anyway so our function works
geometric
inversion 3d then the expression here
will be this
okay so let's so now i'm i know what i'm
doing
this should be that okay we don't even
need the result too okay so delete that
so
so let's see so do it okay
now you got you you're gonna have
massive uh what
you're gonna have massive number of
polyhedrons okay
uh okay i want to hide the output
just don't show the output output takes
a long time okay
so that okay so
that
so that okay so now
opacity result two way not result to not
result x okay
we up somewhere along the we
up
again what geometric inversion 3d
do it and uh result x
right cube
oh yeah becomes uh
what
we up along the way
yeah okay so it's better split this okay
then
okay so result x is that
okay then result two what the
i click mistake i click some feedback
thing
so now result 2 equals to apply the
polygon
then let's do it oh i forgot actually
this
actually this should be that yeah
so now
what the oh yeah x result
x result 2 wait okay
okay now we have better graphics okay so
now
i'm going to show you we need to
we we need to remove the outer uh
box okay so now you
you kind of see
we we need to remove the the the
the back the outer box let's do that
okay we remove the one in the middle
because the one because when we begin
you see we have this
bunch of cubes we have one in the origin
and that one after revert inversion
becomes that
giant cube so so let's uh
delete cases okay let's so let's
so cubes
um dd cases
okay wait cubes equals to
cubes uh remove one of them okay
to do it do it
it okay
so here's the result
then do it do we still see the one in
the middle
yes you see it's good you see it should
be there
but it's not there anymore so
okay so now we
do it do it
do it fantastic
okay now we want now we want
a viewpoint okay
front range
wait so becomes zero zero
zero one
do
okay
let's say 9.
okay that's it that's a result of
today's
thing
um i'm getting tired and this
is you know okay not bad okay let's say
not bad
so this is a result of a geometric
inversion
of a bunch of cubes in the plane
i mean in in 3d in ukrainian
space r3 this is
uh that's so you can see how it is
similar in the two-dimensional case
okay so so finally that's it today
so i'm gonna let this image
sit for a while so that youtube will
pick it up
yeah that's it i'm gonna shut down shut
down for real
this time shut down for real
in in a minute
um
let's go into it dive in let's see what
happens
so we are diving in
we are diving into the inside of it
it should be more spectacular
yeah so so
[Music]
so let's say not opaque let's see what
is the effect
you trial and error
okay so actually we can there's
something more fun we can do
okay so so okay so let's
so now
we are just showing now we just have uh
this many
okay
in fact this formula will go to the top
okay and now
okay we are cleaning up the notebook
no
yay fantastic
okay so let's try that
bye