good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of our talk show today is August
14th 2019 hey guys now we have the
YouTube set up and this is great and
hold on a second I'm in my online it
should be really on time wait it still
says offline so are you guys saying are
you going to see are you guys seeing me
because it says offline here
are you guys seeing my video in my life
okay so you are seeing me but for some
reason this you should always schedule
your streams easier yeah okay I'm live
but for some reason this this stupid
YouTube it's not showing online okay so
guys so what are the topics so and
thanks to John Lewis for you know prompt
prompting me to set up this YouTube no
sketch
well not scheduled but you know the URL
so that people know where to go which is
much better because okay so what what's
going to be the topics so let me so
Johnny says you shaken me with the point
about programming language elites okay
we can talk about that a little bit and
battle of mu says if it isn't okay and
everyone else three or four are my
choices okay number three okay so number
three is random chat okay and four is
Emacs tired tips okay so it looks like
we're gonna do random chatting and and
maybe you max tired so so type whatever
you like to see okay if you haven't been
I gotta fix this one second why is this
this refresh
and yes don't do anything crazy okay
okay show that I'm in for random chat
okay so let's do let them chat then okay
yeah now finally this is working good
okay let's duel and Amjad random today's
topic is random okay random lets you
know let's start off with this one you
know I was reading my ink woody blog
English woody blog so now for this one
you have to look carefully now there's a
poem here you see that poem now read it
you know my friend you know you you
don't know English okay so look at this
poem it says draw a breath for progress
tread a breast a head fight against old
spelling better read then head spread
the words at breakfast measure them in
bed dream of wealth and treasure better
dead than dead so that's you know if
normally if you see this if you are a
native English speaker you know American
or Britain you'll get offended you know
all those grandma grandma Nazis you know
because you see this in the you know all
the words are spelled wrong but actually
this is a spelling reform this this is a
spelling reform of a specific one called
sr1
so in fact you know so and this is the
example of a poem using the new spelling
basically the premise you know the
principle is that you want to make the
spelling regular you know based on
pronunciation and by the way the
property you know in English sticks
there is a property where when when
you're written form is is is the same as
pronunciation as much as possible
knowledge irregularities such as Spanish
Spanish is kind of
like that English is not so there's a
name to that property but does anyone
know what's the name for that I mean
there's a name I mean we're a language
where the spelling is exactly the same
as how it's written there's a name for
that
I forgot anyway so this is the one of
the spelling reform because English is
is very bad extremely bad about how a
word is spelled in how it is pronounced
and you know there are lots of English
spelling reforms in history actually so
we have this Wikipedia article and they
show you many you know 16th century 17th
century in 19th century 20th century but
usually they don't succeed you know like
for a while you know maybe some famous
guy famous writer or some supreme some
educator you know it becomes a movement
for a while then basically just dies out
why does that happen
I mean why does why is it's not
successful because I think mostly
because you know people well first of
all people don't like to change ok
people are am I still alive people are
you know people don't want to change you
know that you don't want to change your
habit for example you you already know
English you don't want get on with the
new program you know change your the
spelling although it's easier for new
people for example Chinese version you
know you know other countries when they
learn English they they will find you
know it great you know the spelling
reform so everything is more regular but
you know for native speakers you don't
want the first you know because you
don't want to change the habit I think
that is actually the primary reason all
these spelling reforms are never
successful I think that is a primary
reason so this is about English
straining reform but there are a lot of
them you can look into them it's very
interesting you know like there's so
much
so spamming reform is one thing there is
also reform of the alphabet actually
there is also reform of the alphabet for
example there is one called oh yeah I
know Lois bong I have a tutorial on that
okay let me show you okay now second
okay since we are not talking about
Emacs let's move these maybe up here so
let me show you loss bang
Sawadee English okay so what the English
is my English blog then you know yeah I
have several things here but let's go to
loss bong lachemann is a language based
on logic based on the mathematical idea
of logic okay and why is it okay what
are these those are supposed to be ads I
guess anyway so I have kind of a
tutorial here and it turns out you know
these comics x k CD also have an episode
about laws one large one is a language
based on logic the idea is that okay
this is quite interesting because there
is a there is a theory called safer wolf
theory let's see if I mentioned here and
I don't remember if I mentioned here but
there is this theory called say let's
let's we are getting off into lots of
topics but let me yes I'm alive I'm
still alive yes indeed
that's why spelling bees are such a big
hit
excuse me yes spelling bees is the worst
in the universe you know you know
you have these spelling bees that's the
worst it's incredible yeah it has no
merit you know yeah it's quite an
achievement to master English spelling
you know one there are a few of my you
know like restaurant how do you spell
restaurant IES ta ra u and T I think
that is no that is incorrect
yes ta you are a UNT no that's incorrect
okay so we so the ink the correct one is
this IES tau R a and T and that's that's
not clear the word you know too bad a
word you should say eatery EA ter why
okay Oh eat house or eat sharp something
like that each make it logical you know
with like when someone you know you all
know about problems in English when you
when you ask someone who do not speak
English you know Chinese Russian
Japanese for example in a similar way I
mean most of you are native English
speakers but if you are learning Chinese
okay try it you know you you know when
you are trying to learn Chinese you
realized oh my god all these big
irregularities like totally
incomprehensible illogical and stupid
you know you you you know this the words
to be stupid comes to your turn because
truly that that is what it is you know
it's just stupid really you know where
you rather have a logical way but but in
fact that's the same thing happens in
English it's just that if you are the
native speaker you don't realize it
because you were born with it in the
same way you know I was wrong you know I
was born in Taiwan I was I was a native
Chinese speaker I didn't learn English
until I was 40 15 to 14 years old okay
why I moved out to
first in Paraguay in South America then
then in Central America
then finally in Canada I was in Canada I
was 16
so basically when I was 16 well 15 or 16
I started to learn English for real you
know because you have to learn it you
know you talk to people you have to
because you are not longer no longer in
Taiwan so when you so I was you know
Chinese speaker so I'm learning English
you you you know I find lots of problems
you know the regularities and why is
that and and and and get this most of
the questions you ask to English
speakers they do not know the answer you
guys okay
you know like right now I'm you know I
mean I mean this is like 30 years ago so
I know English well today and I forgot
all the questions I had you know it's
like long ago 30 years ago I don't
remember what the questions but for
someone new to English you know they
they have asked questions you know what
why is this way this way you know like
it's totally illogical they ask you and
most you know you will not be able to
answer you know you just say oh just say
that way just say it just do it that way
you know so you know natural languages
obeys I think oh all that natural
languages are like that French you know
Russian because they are developed you
know throughout history they are evolved
you know like in a beginning from a you
know anthropological point of view you
could say like there's no Khmer ian's
you know there's no there's no like
correct way to say something there is no
such thing you know you meet another
animal you know over there you just you
know you use you you utter whatever you
communicate there's no grammar or things
like that it's later on people started
to you know do those things grammar and
then stuff and spelling and standards
especially French language you know they
they are very
they are very firm about you know they
want to keep French
a very strict standard you know this you
have to follow this is the right way so
anyway we we were talking about natural
languages she write right out like what
we were talking about like list of a
topic because usually that way gives
people a sense what's you know we've
been talking but usually that's good if
you are doing programming languages but
since today we are random let's see
yo Chico irregularity of natural
languages okay that's one thing we
talked about and we are going to talk
about supper wolf theorem okay okay it's
called linguistic relativity now okay so
it's s a PIR WH o F saberwolf hypothesis
okay this super bowl of hypothesis
basically it says you know it's a
hypothesis that language you know
controls your thought to certain degree
or hundred degree you know it depends so
this is so okay now they change the name
you know I've been reading Wikipedia
like every year or so like it you know I
have like I have like seven thousand
links to keep Vidya for my website
sorry what is being water what being
water I got my okay I got an e I
have to read the okay it's not the wiki
pedia okay so hold on a second
okay so sorry old
okay so there it is you know I have a
you know I have this page shows this
page is generated last time in 2016 and
I have 7,000 links to Wikipedia you know
each one of these is a link to my page
and on that page I have a link to
Wikipedia page so you know I'm looking
video I check it off and so on on this
you used to be a safer wolf hypothesis
so I guess now they changed the name to
linguistic relativity I don't know what
for what reason sometimes it's political
you know they change things for
political reasons like current current
fashion of thinking and Louis Poong okay
Laurent is the logical language so let's
get back to the zipper wolf hypothesis
basically you can read it basically it
says you know language controls your
thoughts for example I speak Chinese you
speak English you know perhaps Chinese
is perhaps English is more logical you
know therefore people who you know
native languages English we all have
logical more logical thought you know
that is the hypothesis you know your
language actually controls your thought
which in turn controls your behavior you
know your your ideas you know things
like that so that's idea you know a
sabre wolf hypothesis and solow-swan
lost upon is language based on logic you
know it's it's absolute regular spelling
and pronunciation I mean everything is
regular it's like mathematics you know
and it's very simple and but the main
point is that the semantics you know how
hard language makes meaning is also
logical because you know this language
is originally is it's called Lockland
arrow Zhi LAN Jie
Lachlan like logical language but the
guy who invented Lachlan went into a
patent dispute you know he patented
Lachlan language then the community got
unhappy with him so they went to court
you know there's a fight and it turns
out he lost you know the court decided
oh the group the community can actually
use it but anyway the community decided
to create a new language low spunk
so it's called aerogel pnpn okay Laura
oh these are on Wikipedia you can look
up Lachlan okay so this group created
laws from but you know internally it's
Lachlan but however they are different
because all the vocabularies are
different but however the principle is
the same these two languages are based
on logic you know strict logic so the
main point about Lachlan is that
everything is regular you know the
spelling the writing system is as
regular as possible hundred-percent
regularity but also the main point about
them as opposed to other natural
languages or artificial languages is
that Lachlan the the semantics the
meaning is based on logic so that you
know like lot like mathematical logic
you know predicate logic first-order
logic so that the authorities that since
you have this extremely you know
mathematical language so perhaps if for
people who speak this language you could
remove limitations from your thought you
know that that's limited by by that that
the language you speak you know such as
English or Chinese so that is you know
the the the arrangement the purpose the
principle of law swung or Lachlan okay
Hoglund
okay so so what's so what am I going to
say it's a large part so yeah so I
studied this for a while for several
years
you know and I wrote several tutorials
you know studying in 2004 and the
tutorial includes pronunciation you know
pectin
for example let's see Huck G so hoc she
means hungry okay I don't know if you
guys can hear it can you guys hear it
you know one second no do you guys get
echoes do you guys get echoes right now
okay so let me get to a stop then let me
read the comments let me finish the
thought here so anyway I got the
recording you can hawk G is means hungry
and what is is okay it's not and this
one is Chinese I you know I am
pronouncing Chinese so hug XI so this is
the definition of hakushi in logic bomb
okay so let me show you what what what
it is like okay so you have this this is
a sentence so the definition is x1
hungers for x2 okay so that's one
definition the second one is X 1 needs
or wants food fuel x2 ok so let's just
focus on the first part so x1 hunger for
x2 that's a definition for the world hug
G so the X 1 and X 2 are variables you
can replace them you know with other
things for example X 1 can be me you
know so so i hunger for something so X 2
can be banana for example then you know
it means I want a banana
oh I'm hungry for a banana so you see
every word in launched run well every
verb in la Japan is defined like that so
you have you know these variables then
you have a kind of meaning so so yeah so
to say I'm hungry for banana used you
would say
you would say x1 Hoshi x2 so hug she is
the world hunger here so x1 you can
replace it with you know you me he or
name you know and x2 can be a food or
can be a car you know it so if you say
x1 hunger for car that means you want
the car you really you know you really
love to have a car so so this is Lois
bum okay let's let me put links here you
know just just just get you know visit
my websites so that's not wrong and we
talked about super wolf hypothesis so if
this is true you know a simple wolf
hypothesis if it is true then Lauren
would be great to be powerful you know
when you studied law swung there is lots
of details you get into because you know
it's basically you getting into
linguistics use you start to discover
lots of the issues in linguistics lots
of semantic problems you know not not
just you know the spelling or the
irregular verbs
you know the tense is not just that but
you actually get cut into many the
logical issues of the semantics say like
what does it mean you know you you you
can see that if you actually start to
learn Louis Bob Solow Swan has say this
is the aspect kind of that I copy I copy
it from you know they respect it's open
source you know so you know you can read
it you know it's it's long you know it's
it's many chapters it's like it's a book
Louis bomb so I started to learn it and
back and also the simple hypothesis you
know for programming languages this is
absolutely true you know for example you
know many of you will probably agree
like if you if you could see then if you
called Python
it needs not be Python you know it could
be Python Ruby gold Nicola and
JavaScript you are realized if you coded
in C and never anything else as opposed
to someone coding in Python you will see
that you know the Python guy we are no
allowed constructs that never occurs to
the C guy you know in the same way for
Lisp you know for Haskell functional
languages it it you know as far as
programming language is concerned the
language is matters it actually does
change you know how you think about
algorithms change changes your
perception and what you do but we don't
know for sure it is actually true for
you know natural languages and by the
way I have heard I but not verified and
I don't know if it's true that there are
people babies who are born who whose
first language is it launched bang or or
Esperanto I think it's I'm not sure it's
true for lojban I think I've heard that
there were people babies you know who
were born so the baby's first language
is so strong you know that's incredible
that's something incredible but I don't
know if that's true I think I heard I
heard somewhere I forgot long ago but I
think it's definitely true that they are
baby you know there are people whose
first language is Esperanto you know
esperando is another artificial language
you co-construct constructed language
you know which you know meaning that
human just made it up you know so it's
it shares many things with Laura it's
regular for example so it's extremely
easy to learn Esperanto so that that's
the let me show it so Louis well as for
wrong though okay hold on a second let
me copy my website copy it
switch back link of Phi and lodge Val
go to Wikipedia Lachlan okay Seoul
Oakland and they have a website you know
I I have been I have fought you know how
cute with some of these people or maybe
they are computer nerds okay they are
just like the UNIX philosophy and nerds
meaning that they are prone to argue and
attack other people antagonistic you
know if you do not agree on something
they you know you get into a fight and
fight with them and you know they also
just just like list communities /
communities just like programmers they
want to uphold their community like
Emacs okay but if you say anything even
reasonable rational but but you know it
doesn't look so good on the community
they attack you they attack you this is
a scums for example one time I
criticized the logo this is the idiotic
the most idiotic local okay in a
universe and of course they disagree oh
you are a true and so on and you know
but you look at them you look at what
they say they have no idea they have
like zero idea what is logo design you
know what is supposed to be the purpose
of a log they don't know so but you know
it's part of the community thing you
know tribalism so let me mention that
logo design
okay let's search for that because
there's a website I want to show ok
purpose of logo and principle of logo
design I wrote this page in back in 2007
originally because I have so many fight
with the programmers or nerds about
logos it happens on the lowest bound we
mentioned before it also happened and
Lisp communities you know I tell them we
need a logo they say oh no and so and so
on you know that's of you know then it
also happened with Python communities
stupid pythons comes you know Python
okay well okay we digressed a lot you
know we have so many things to talk
about and we haven't get into the
comments so many comments it's so busy
you know so what one of the thing about
logo you know one of the Nerds they'd
like to say this happened with my
argument with the Python people back in
2006 or so and also happen with the
least people I have actually a lisp logo
tool lambda logo tool list needs a logo
so okay so this page collected all the
lambda logos you can see I think they
are beautiful you know yeah I love the
member logos okay so this is the article
let me I need to post a link on string
so that
okay so let's post link here lambda logo
tool and there is another one and this
this Arco is about Lisp needs a logo
this this is when back then I was you
know turning these people we need a logo
but they say oh no and so long you know
we we have a fight you know they call me
a troll then you know so this this so
this is the article about some of that
you know this book so let me talk about
Python logo for a bit so with these
people okay what typically what happened
is that they lambda logo to Livan
tutorial
this needs logo hold on second Emmy
needs another one logo design okay there
are some principles about logo you know
we talked about the purpose of a logo
then piece of principles of a logo
design what makes a good logo what makes
a Glock logo bad for example all these
are bad because they are generic they
don't you know there are many reasons
you can read the details
okay so let me post that that here maybe
so and we're gonna get back to the back
to the languages and so on there's so
many things I want to get back to I
haven't started to talk about them yet
but we get sidetracked sank chat site
attracted to a logo but let me say
something about logo then we'll be done
with that
so I argue with the Python people and
you know Python used to not have a logo
back in 2006 up to antio
let me tell you when did Python start to
have a logo okay until 2005 okay so I
was arguing before that with Python
people before 2005 2004 2003 okay until
you know so before this official logo it
used to be you know unofficial you have
this this this this this you know this
Python logos okay so I was telling them
you know we need a logo and the typical
here's the thing I want to say the
typical response for nerds is that you
know from this program as UNIX
philosophy is so this bunch of
the typical response is that oh no we
don't need need a logo because you know
we are we don't need you know dressing
you know programmers typical programmers
they don't they don't you know they
think everything else is a fluff you
know like the web page you know don't
need to be pretty
you know grandmas they argue you don't
need the look we don't need the logo tee
and you know when so when do they become
to start to have a logo when the groove
actually becomes speak okay I'm thinking
man who made this back when a group
becomes speak in a society any community
when you actually become speak you start
to have lot people then the Nerds you
know stupid nerds they started to see
you know actually you know you you start
to have salesmen you know you know
designers artists you know also the
people instead of just nuts then you you
know they decided that because you need
a logo because in modern society
everything is a logo you know that's a
fact of life
a logo so what does a logo do it's like
it's like a person's name okay a person
you have a name you know you don't say
oh I don't need a new you know I'm just
me you know I don't need name but logo
is say you know it's a pictorial version
of a name so Python is a name but you
can also have a logo that's a pictorial
representation of your thing of you know
the language so that people can see they
can recognize it and also imagery you
know pictures are the primary
communication of human animals not text
you know text written Triton's writing
system is invented much later and also
writing systems begin by pictures you
know pictograph if Egypt Egyptians you
know the you know Egyptian has that in
Chinese has that they begin with
pictures so pictures is the visual is a
primary you know the the more primitive
communication therefore logos you know
logo you don't have to have it okay but
in modern society we you know it you
know you don't say you know you know do
we need a card no you don't need a car
but you you have a car probably you know
especially in USA you know you drive you
know so logo is it's you know it has
critical functions in modern society
that's what logo is for and similarly
when you talk to these people you know
these nuts
these nuts you know they are
they they did they say oh you are a true
you know they they start to they start
to do nasty things to me you know like
all sort of name-calling or whatever and
you know plunk you know this programmers
I go that just you know qfi ox Valley
you know he's a troll you know this so I
so I had 10 years you know more than 10
years are
humans with his programmers and you know
so even you know so I wrote this article
in 2007 like I want to tell the world
you know finally I want to like write a
one coherent article about the whole
issues anyway so we so that that that's
about logos but we were talking about
languages there are so many things we
irregularities of natural languages
super Whorf hypothesis ok so you know
it's meaningful for programming
languages that makes a difference for
sure but we don't know for we don't know
if that's the case for natural languages
so we talked about Laval Esperanto we
talked about logos yeah so let's so let
let me be the comments and then we then
then we then then we say let's see what
what's the next thing
Louis wrong yeah okay I think there's so
many comments I got so many comments
although I've been talking Live
dashboard 14 people well that's a lot
people for me you know I look at other
youtubers when they go like this like
the the comments just fly by 10 comments
for second yeah they have thousands
people watching I'm doing so for a year
so let's see the comments ok I'm gonna
I'm not going to read everything and my
eyes is getting bad so Louis wow that's
like spelling Louis wrong yeah it's very
large one is regular you should index
your pages with title categories in open
web pages straight from Emacs now well I
did that's that's easier said than done
okay for some reason eat house sounds
very Chinese to me yeah I yeah I mean
stick I'm taking notes with writing
stick what's a writing stick Oh pain
okay that makes sense
yeah that's illogical you see being
logically there is this advantage
because you don't need to know the words
I know you know if I don't know why
looking at writing stick I know what it
means being water indeed being water you
need the units which you didn't specify
the plant you know so yeah coffee plant
water that we could such example of
reminding me of Trump spelling it Kovac
of FA so she always say sucks I don't
get it distracted you continue he just
drinks being water okay same as my
ritual bath and likes to digress
so since to digress digress digress for
the digressive reasons nested aggression
recursion degress recursively that's
great yeah you know one of the story
about a great but about recursive
digression like stories within a story
I've talked about this before that is
the Arabian Nights the story of 1001
nights
nothing like Disney ok if you are
thinking Disney whatever you know about
Arabian Nights is completely wrong it's
like not not even close ok
I really annoys you you guys should
check it out ok it's just such for Saudi
Arabian Nights Arabian Nights is kind of
like is it's classified
it used to be classified as pornography
ok so and when you read that you won't
read by this guy's Sir Richard Burton
you know he's a great scholar is
fantastic guy an Arabian the you know
the book of 1000 N one
I find it his translation okay you must
read his because there are so many
versions like some are written you know
like for children and most of the
existing translations they are alighted
you know censored you know they just
censor everything out and Disney is
entirely a different thing that's not
Arabian Nights
you know Disney you think of genie or
what whatever it's yeah the basically
the whatever Disney versions you know
they could punch a Fanta Oh Mulan
whatever they are they are like fast
foods like Americanized other culture
okay they remove everything about over
the other culture except the colorful
hats you know you still have that or the
Chinese eyes you know you still have
that so what remains is the colour
Foghat and America you know the skin
color everything is American you know
that's Disney's version when they when
they comes to other cultures like Disney
many Disney movies well anyway Arabian
Nights okay so this you wanna read this
this one okay by Richard Burton okay and
let me give you one example okay and
also this is a great book you can buy it
from let me explain what that book is
about
okay so Arabian Nights let me post it
here link and buy from with my website
you know this is partial out of them
heisman just Amazon buy it from my
website so Arabian Arabian Nights if you
want to read the real true Arabian
Nights without censorship and without
you know diluted or water down or
Americanized things there are two
options one read the ones by which Sir
Richard Burton or
now this one is translated in 1800s he
is a great scholar you know he's
like a polyglot he's a polyglot okay
multi-talented you know expert in many
things in language he's also a
linguistic he speaks like 10 10 20
something languages master a bit
Sir Richard Burton okay he is also an
expert fencer you know swordsman
finished finsih so he has a translation
in 1800 so that's the one you can read
the other one is the modern by this guy
whose son had away okay so you can get
these two versions these are you know
the Rio Arabian Nights
now the the Sir Richard Burton's version
is very archaic and elaborate meaning
it's difficult to read for example you
know I actually take took me several
years I annotated you know I read them I
annotated this Arabian Nights you know
you can you can then I add a JavaScript
you know all these difficult words you
know tide waves load loaded leashes
height you know many I so I took it took
me like I took two years to annotate
them so the problem with the Burton's
version is that he tried to write it in
a archaic and poetic way so it's it's
almost like you reading Shakespeare so
you know it's harder to understand you
know you know so so that is why you
might try to read this modern guy this
this version
I haven't read I haven't read it you
know I don't have it you know so you
know it's that's why you might want to
get this version but however Sir Richard
Burton's version I like the way he did
exactly I like those difficult words
like it's the begin it begins with two
brothers okay this is a first story
story of King Shara and his father two
brothers in the name of Allah the
compassionate in the compassionate
that's his style of translation and
praise praise be to Allah the beneficent
King the creator of the universe Lord of
three wards who set up the firmament
firmament without pillars in its stead
you know him
and so on anyway and there's lots of
poetry is there you know intermix there
look at this picture okay this this
picture you know it may be shocking to
you you may be what you know this is
representative of the entire Arabian
Nights
this guy cutting the other two couple
you know they cut a mean have that that
is representative of the entire Arabian
Nights anyway so that's the story and
you know Arabian Nights and I this is
one of the most enjoyable I like you
know the literature I've read you know I
like it very much
this and Shakespeare I you know this one
but you know I really love Shakespeare
stuff you know like before when I read
no I heard sometimes programmers talk
you know mention Shakespeare before I
knew it I thought you know what
you know the facts figure what is that
you know who cares but after I started
to know my first exposure to Shakespeare
is actually in college in 1991 Community
College 1992 or so but then after you
know I really love Shakespeare stuff you
know the way he uses language okay
that's I think that's a break now let's
see let's go back so when how did we oh
yeah
so we were talking about Arabian Nights
because Arabian Nights is one of the
first Oh classic story where they
feature nested you know nested stories
stories within a story so you know you
know as you know the Sahara something
you know the girl who tells the story
oh yeah let that begin with the first
one so you have this story and and in
the end you know the daughter you know
is married to the king you know then she
tells another story but actually we
haven't reached to that yet I think you
know anyway so then you have the someone
you know in a story this guy is telling
another story that is the tale of the
poor and the ass okay the tale of the
blue and yes then they start to tell
another story so it's all nested story
it's not actually where nested no so
it's like a tree so you might think okay
it's a tree you know its own but
actually it's not it's just not totally
coherent but you know so anyway yeah so
this is fantastic story so that's so
let's see how long I've been talking and
let's get back to read the comments how
many people 13 people
okay so comments in the Q and a session
so apart from you digress Cassandra is
the hypothesis is wrong English is not
so developed language just rent I've
never heard of this liuchuan thing okay
now you have you should look into if you
ever fail to be strained by the language
you are mainly using to explain things
to other humans in although Schwalm so
lost wrong is all outlined it's a
logical language right but however
I think there are issues you know is it
because first of all it will never
become popular it's like all these
artificial constructed languages nobody
will nobody will learn it you know the
only person the only people who are
interested or need are logicians you
know mathematicians or programmers let's
see that's it no no other people who are
not nerds you know they are not
interested and also among logicians you
know one thing I think with the issue of
loss bond is that okay so
solow-swan is this logical language
hungry physiological but however once if
it gets popular you know if let's say
let's say you know a country or you know
let's say 1 million people speak it then
I believe ok this is my thought you know
I believe it we are no longer we remain
logical the language will evolve into
illogicality just like other natural
languages and you it will happen in such
I mean it's it's I think it's something
it's unavoidable like you know suppose
you know suppose Lodge one becomes
popular you know suppose there are 1
million people speaking and very soon I
mean as you know the more people you
speak it if we are more likely to become
illogical it would just evolve into
totally illogical again that's my
thought so so this opinion is kind of I
you know I talked to the like if you
talk to the lowest one community they
are owners they don't they don't know
nothing okay surely they are not like
thinking about I mean a lot you are
interested true but I mean the nuts but
in anyway so I think that so you have
evolved into illogicality and I don't
know if this is
you know I haven't seen people discuss
it like oftentimes when you have some
ideas you discuss to these nuts and
anyway so I'm pretty sure that you know
there are linguistics who will be able
to discuss this issue fruitfully but you
have to like find find you have to find
a group usually it's hard to find such
people know a co okay so let me see so
Louis Wong and Esperanto is another very
interesting language is Esperanto is
much more popular yes
Esperanto is particularly popular in
China because in middle in mid-1990 you
know 1940 1930 or 1950s the China
they-they-they you know it's a long
history but they wanted to replace
Chinese characters they want to
modernize the you know Chinese China was
in big trouble because other countries
hit in China and any'ing war so they
were you know the leaders they want to
this movement lasting for several
decades to eradicate the Chinese
language the the writing system at least
so anyway so so Esperanto for a while
has become very popular in China because
because you know the Esperanto is a very
you know it's a constructed language
very regular and easy to learn so
there's a thought you know Chinese will
start to use Esperanto instead you know
it happens it's a period of time in
China so and there are also as far as I
know there were Chinese radio stations
that use Esperanto you know
yeah so if you learn launch bung or log
land you will you will you will notice a
lot of the semantics you know geological
issues and Express ability you know the
power of expression things like that
like you know it's like you can like
yeah okay so so a lot wrong
it's so bad for my bathroom uses where a
large phone is it's to be expected the
more complicated topic oh you had a
recordings great okay so so is it worth
learning that that really just depending
on you yeah because you know if as far
as learning materials is mathematics you
know that's a black hole then computer
science itself is a black hole
theoretical computer science well that's
part of math and the practical
programming that's also you know too
much stuff to learn in a person's
lifetime you know you have JavaScript
your front-end you have game dev you
know networking dev you know protocol
networking protocols you know and then
you have Bitcoin you have this you know
the the you know the the what's the
technology behind Bitcoin that's the
hash tag you know the basically hash
change blockchain you know so this
infinite things through and so whether
rush bond is worth learning that's
really up to you
in general no okay because it's it's
useless
you gonna you're not gonna find anyone
using dodgeball and but if you are
interesting in linguistics and logics
it's worthwhile because you know if
that's your interest because you learn
you learn things about semantics what
you know really things like that
and but also by the way no University is
teaching it if you go into a university
linguistic program they have nothing to
do with lachemann you know that when you
know one thing interesting is about
University you know you think no
normally you think Oh University is the
center of Education therefore you know
if you study linguistics you know the
linguistic department they must you know
have something about large large one but
actually not big
why not not because those around it
doesn't teach not because logical reason
but part mostly because you know
universities they are funded by
governments they are fashionable to
funded by fashion you know Shabbat
nobody speaks if you on the other hand
if you teach French oh yeah a lot of
people you know want to study French if
you teach Chinese especially today
because Chinese becomes powerful you
know the China becomes powerful yeah oh
yeah I want to you know I want to go to
you know Stanford University I want to
go to Europe and West University I want
to pay I want to apply so I can study
Chinese you know University part of the
function is to make money for themselves
that's you know that's why so bathroom
you curiosity is what makes human move
forward it is first step advance to the
second okay so said open source we need
another unix/linux wrench know oh Dan
visas for foreign languages I absolutely
agree
it definitely modes the way you think
yeah genre says but I am fahren speaker
solo chuan Eickhoff Farina's English
me love you me hungry me sleeping
totally logical tech way says there is a
kid who learned King Kong as his first
language oh is that true
that's interesting
bethenny says yes he mentioned UNIX
philosophy running coming and keep you
ahead downloads those projects a good
old KDE wizard what what KDE wizard
oh the I don't think I have a KD logo
logo should be made by professional
designers yeah I also don't like I also
don't understand how so many folks just
named upstream name - of strain m3 okay
what do you mean hang on a second let me
see how many more comments
okay we almost Stern with the comments
let's see let's see how many folks so if
you have questions posted okay so battle
Mew says it is always the same not
practiced at all and makes maybe sense
for sleeper members not for normal human
being
Sun Microsystems logo is absolutely
fantastic yes I agree I'm going to make
a logo for me Dec ways okay forget my
name remember me by my logo yeah you
need the logo on your face so I won't
recognize you human face is also generic
so no creativity that's true
where were the designers when faces were
created but the thing about funeral face
yeah it's so generate generic you know
it's interesting because for example I'm
Chinese so when I look at white people I
cannot tell well I can now because I
mean us for so long you for example if
you look at Asians you know you probably
cannot tell the difference between
Japanese Chinese Korean Vietnamese but I
can you know we can tell like we pretty
much you know 90% accurate you know we
can tell and also within China within
China they are different you know people
in different regions you can also
recognize you know differences like oh
you can tell he's from the north is one
of the south so but to outsiders you
cannot because you know human face all
it's like if you look at monkeys can you
tell which monkey is different from on
the face no you cannot but I guess the
monkeys can because we developed you
know particular sensitivities yeah we
are extremely sensitive you know we can
recognize recognize all the emotions
like you know I've read you know human
face you have like thousands of muscles
that controls your face and you can tell
this is why you can tell a genuine smile
from a fake one you know if you you know
say hi you know you smile that's there's
a difference we could this I mean it's
not just psychological there's actual
difference from a you know from a smile
you try to smile from a genuine smile
that you know someone made you Kiko or
something the the MIRR so that they are
different
okay so MA Marco Avila says between
expose and truly Obama economic keyboard
which one you think is better expo is
better absolutely yeah
I'm not going to go into that well let's
look at I think that's about it yet so
let's let me show you the keyboard okay
between expose and let me show you what
they are so this is the Expo keyboard
and helps on a second so what's going on
okay so Expo keyboard and history kewal
history and ergonomic evil history and
you have these truly organ homage so
this is a truly organ ami keyboard
that's their name that's the brand name
I I have it you know I've been using it
for like three three or four years they
stopped making it now but they have a
new version they have a new version
anyway so this is the old version so and
then you have this expose expose this
better okay now both of them are flat if
you really type a lot you you want
actually tended but flat is you know for
most people you know you try this good
anyway so I think Expo yeah definitely
go for Expos but but I should mention
truly ergonomic they have a new version
okay I mean let me show that okay so let
me go to keyboard
okay so yeah they have this new version
yeah this is their new version now I
haven't I haven't I don't have this I'm
not sure they are it's already out or
not you can go to their website to check
and I have not actually analyzed the
design so so if you are thinking between
these and no seconds so between these
and the expo I'm not sure which one is
better okay so yeah but but the expo is
Steph definitely better than the old
truly ergonomic design make sense so
Mike who is sad
Margeaux Marco Marco Marco Vela so
that's C that's my answer is it
religious book the Arabian Nights no
it's not religious in fact it's
sacrilegious you know the as far as I
know I learned from the you know the
Middle East people you know and also I
read from Wikipedia they don't care
about Arabian Nights that book yeah it's
not Regis review no it's so religious
books by definition of entertainment and
no it's not his is Islam a book so
basically my sense is that it's not
religious okay the Arabian Nights okay
if you ask people in Middle East I think
the devout is is Islam believers they
don't like it they act they don't like
it okay but the non-believers I don't
think they care for it much neither yeah
it but however the book is full of Allah
because that's I think that's that's the
culture of the Middle East culture like
it's full of you know Allah you know the
great the greatest you know let me also
show you some Unicode okay let's let's
let's go to Unicode because let's see if
I can find my website without typing my
name okay so that page is not popular
yet so saw Unicode Arabic okay there it
is
so that's a rebek and you know they are
from they are written from right to left
and you have or these are lick lick you
you have you know lots of things like
this for example this this one ligature
is a real big picture yay with hamza
above you final like often these
lectures they laugh you know they have
names of God you know a left or
something like for example there is the
most popular one is this one let me show
you this one a really big ligature
bismillah bismillah ham him something
like that okay be some abysmal eyes God
and also this one you know they have
like you know anyway so that's part of
Middle East culture it's kind of you
have that who over here asada is about
to die by that man so she is speaking
him stories to avoid the death yes
because the king he got his he got
cheated by his wife so he killed his
wife then he did he and then he hates
all women okay he decided you know I'm
going to have a new wife every day you
know and by the morning next morning I'm
gonna cut her head off so that's what
the king is doing then you have this
visor you know the one of the you know
you know what one of the how do you call
that one of the the keys
you know advisor you know give king of
devices so he started offered to to be
the King's wife you know and the the
visor says are you crazy
you know no yeah that's a very
interesting story okay here okay the the
first story the story of a king Shara
and his brother okay then at the bottom
the the the daughter says to his dad you
know she wants to go you know she what's
the girl and of course the dad says no
but then the daughter says something is
only I don't remember okay so here let's
meet when the vibe when when the vasa
vasorum kind of official around the King
you know give the King advices so when
the vasa heard from his daughter these
words he related to her from first to
last or that had happened between him
and the king okay so anyway they begin
it begins a little bit before but anyway
so he started offered to go then he says
no and I think he started to tell a
story like
he started to tell a story a story we
think so that's why it's a story within
a story so he began to tell the story so
the the daughter heard that then a
daughter will be pride by telling
another story so that's yeah so that's
like that
you know if you want to you know this is
so long read let me show you one one
passage okay one short story by the way
I don't have the whole story here by the
Sir Richard you know sir Sir Richard
Burton because it's like several volumes
you know it's like you know so I only
have like 16 17 likes 15 of them by the
way the Aladdin that's not actually part
of the Arabian Nights Aladdin and 40
thieves
you know those famous popular stories
you've seen from Disneyland from Disney
that's actually not the core Arabian
Nights and I read you know I also really
Richard Richard Burton's translation of
the Aladdin in comparison it's not good
you know yeah you have the genie and but
in comparison it pales in comparison to
the the others so anyway let me show you
this yeah so this Leo the all the ones
I've annotated that's fantastic
spectacular you know not just a story
but then you have then you then it comes
through the monsters you know the genies
the monsters or the different monsters
okay but if you want just be you know
spin if you want you know if you are a
modern man you're looking at your iPhone
or whatever phone all the time you don't
have time to study stuff you can just
read this spend five minutes
you know like today you have blogs I
says this this post is five minutes
reading this is three minutes reading so
this was is is five minutes reading then
you'll get a picture of what part of the
you know the the Arabian Nights is like
from beaches I kept wanting to say
Richard Stallman from Richard Burton
okay
I think that's about that's it today
that I think that I've been talking okay
yeah that's I've been talking for 17
minutes
so what else let's see I'm gonna answer
questions for one minute out a few more
minutes and see so let's see me cover my
eyes since you say that Ultron community
is full of nerds I think that might be
one reason for why this language exists
for so long and at all costs no no no
more people yeah I mean nobody wants to
study logical language like for example
how many people wants to study logic you
know the math mathematics symbolic logic
you know predicate logic proof theory
you find very very few and not just
logic and even mathematicians by the way
let me just say you know logic you know
so logic to theory you know math
foundations you know say theory that's
you know that's a giant branch of
mathematics but however among
mathematicians that's kind of fringe
okay what not fringe but you know that's
kind of nobody nobody study yet
mathematicians like very few like less
than 10% even less less than 5% that's
even less than that
among all mathematicians you know maybe
2% you know less than let's say less
than 5% actually study set theory proof
theory logic you know symbolic logic
first-order logic
those kind of thing you know less than
5% less even less much less than that
most mathematicians they study so what
did what they study they study
differential equations you know
differential geometry analysis complex
analysis you know algebra you know many
branches of algebra geometry you know
geometry though those are the mainstream
because why because those actually are
practical that they solve problems like
especially
differential equations differential
geometry differential and hey you know
anything with differential and integral
and did you know that's part of calculus
calculus is the beginning cause of that
so why are they used because they they
use for they apply to physics you know
you you send people to the moon
that's all calculus you know
differential you you understood study
you know check you know you want to go
beyond the speed of sound
you know differential equations and
everything is differential equation lots
of that is and and for computer graphics
you know linear algebra so very few
people actually study the set theory you
know and logic you know improve this
system that's kind of like fringe okay
it's almost like among programmers
Haskell is that's a fringe okay nobody
actually do that most people they do
ZBrush worse you know game game gaming
sleepers first JavaScript front-end web
design you know wait you know it's kind
of like that I think that's that's it
for today let's see better the mandarine
he could talk with us finished yesterday
I forgot my lotion i forgot most of it
you know freaky people who are smart and
do crazy crazy
yeah I'm using a go keyboard I show this
almost in every of my video I've been
showing this because every time people
ask I show it
so this is my keyboard and this is my
hand and if you turn this camera around
slowly you see me you see so you know
that I'm using Kinesis keyboard you know
goes to my website and buy it okay so I
think that's it for today so let's see
[Music]
set theory we learned in first grade
elementary school oh that's interesting
no my mouse is not economic my mouse is
is this Logitech I forgot the number but
it's I can show you my mouse is let's
see okay so let's see keyboard mouse how
to choose the mouse and so logitech g502
okay so and this is got the infinite
spin wheel for example again again okay
so that if if we go to my blog for
example you see let me show you the
infinite scroll you see you see if I do
it fast you scroll all the way like even
you know it's fantastic it's it's one of
the feature it's necessary it's almost
like necessary for me especially if you
use Linux because on Linux you do not
have accelerated school and that's
painful because if you don't have
accelerate school you're gonna do like
this you know like like this yeah that's
what happens in Linux you know yet you
have people saying oh Linux is fantastic
you know the Linux is got problems
everywhere you know so this is what
happens in you know it's except moving
Chrome or Firefox because the
sab has you know did in other words the
in in Enochs there is no global general
way to have accelerated school on the
Mac you can because I'm not going to
show it I think that's it for today yeah
it's a very popular mouse among gamers
so actually let me show you let me show
you actually let's post a link so in
case people want to buy it
trackball mouse so that so that's it for
today thank you guys for watching yeah I
mean glue on Linux come kernel usually
you should not say Linux it's good know
Linux richest oh man thank you guys for
watching great great this is you guys so
many people hope to see you next time
bye