good morning guys Merry Christmas oh
Merry holiday oh happy holidays
2024 the ending of the
year and uh today's uh what can you see
me yes I'm going to do drink coding
drunk coding okay this is half red wine
have orange juice oh I should put more I
should put some more so today we are
going to code what shall we code Advent
of code day three I'm going to finish it
that
sucker so how are you today newbie hello
newbie who else is here nobody for
concurrent users what the
[ __ ] okay
so uh let's just shall we just C Advent
of code then did you vote for some topic
newb sh shall I just get on Advent of
code hi so you see nobody is here you
know you do a poll and some people says
they want to see Advent of code Advent
of code and we got nobody okay anyway so
let me just finish Advent of code number
three let me explain so drunk
coding okay let's
begin new have you been uh LC is nice Q
in 10th great uh so newbie new newbie
have you been following my Advent of
code so there is a problem day three
okay I began a week or two ago and stuck
on a trivial problem because I was
trying to do the shortest code not just
among all languages but I was trying to
be the shortest among wolfan language uh
but uh so there's a problem let me let
me explain the problem okay so you are
given this input a text file and suppose
okay so this is uh for example this is a
big input you know a text file and in
this text file you see your numbers you
see your
numbers and uh some numbers they have
adjacent to the numbers you have a
symbol so the period doesn't count as a
symbol so for example 973 point2 oh they
have a decimal number so that is a
number so they have they have symbols
you know as risk and slash adjacent uh
to it so that counts as a number so if a
number does not have a a a symbol
adjacent to it that doesn't count for
example uh let's let's see a example
uh okay so you need a a number that has
a symbol adjacent to it but also if it's
the symbol is above it also count so for
example let's see and also diagonal
countes for for example 440 there that
number doesn't count
because surrounding this number there's
no symbol okay and this 165 count
because there's a slash adj a diagonal
to it so around the neighbor of the
number there's a symbol so that number
counts so the problem is given this text
file you want to find all the numbers
that count uh and
uh and you want
[Music]
to uh you and and yeah so find all the
numbers that count and sum them up and
that is your solution okay so this
problem so this problem let me let me
tell you about this problem okay so this
problem is very interesting
because the easiest solution is first of
all you use regular expression to get
all the numbers to catch capture all the
numbers then you
to capture all the numbers along
together with their position the
beginning position and end position of
the number in the line in each line or
with respect to the whole string okay so
you
capture each of the number with their
beginning and end position then you then
you uh for each number you go through
the string find the beginning position
you check if you know the character
before it is a symbol and you check a
character after it is a symbol and you
also check the previous line in the
about the same position to see if
there's a symbol there and also check
the next line below it to see if this
symbol so so that way you do this for
every number so you can capture uh the
numbers that has a adjacent symbol
around it then you just sum sum it up
summ it up so use the regular expression
to capture all the numbers along with
their beginning and end position so you
got a list of these items then you go
through each one of them check you know
use a position information to see if
they have adjacent number to it okay
that is the most common I believe that's
vast majority 99% of code solution is
doing that okay so I was trying to be
smart you know so so is it is so the
question is it's possible to not use any
positional information you just use a
regular expression you know like one
single expression in some way because
this looks like a regular expression
problem you know it's a textual kind of
so you purely use regular expression to
solve a problem without checking any
position or getting any substring you
know that's like so you want a pure
regular expression that turns out is
turns out to be practically
impossible okay uh there are subtleties
okay so one solution is to see if you
can do Sol this problem with regular
expression without any positional
information in one shot in other words
you use one single regular
expression okay just one time you call a
function that does regular expression
matching just one time not allowed to do
it a second time so one time you capture
all the numbers that has a you know a a
symbol around
it that turns out that turns out to be
practically impossible however it's
theoretically possible why is it
theoretic um okay we need to explain why
in each case
why is it theoretically possible that
information I I I was talking about this
problem with uh with with this guy this
this this guy okay oh my God you
know it turns out when when Discord when
you are doing a live stream in Discord
they hide the name but anyway this guy
zelfa okay that's an anonymous name but
he so
he
suggested he told me that you know so
it's possible theoretically to do this
problem by using just regular expression
uh the way you do that is you basically
you generate one huge regular expression
with alternative or so possibly you have
thousands or millions of alternative
regular expression cases so I think that
makes sense that that made me believe
that this problem is theoretically
possible but it's not practical you know
you you just generate like
1,000 uh all expressions in one single
regular expression okay that's um that's
hard but why is this problem practically
practically impossible well that's
because you want to you know you want to
capture so first of all you need to get
the number of characters per line then
you want to capture before each number
so you use a regular expression right I
can show you a regular expression
somewhere
here uh where's a regular expression uh
to capture the digit and that's easy uh
you know it's just a
bracket 029
okay so where's a okay so let me see
okay so let me let me do this
okay
uh ah
[ __ ] you cannot see the r uh screen
[ __ ] I did how much I I wasted 13
minutes thank you
Thiago [ __ ] up
[ __ ] okay shall we go shall we do it
again okay anyway ad Advent of code day
three okay so you guys can see the
screen now yeah so you are giving let me
let me repeat quickly so you are giving
a text input like that uh the text input
got a bunch of numbers so this is a toy
input let's magnify okay so you got the
real input so you know lot you know like
hundreds of lines so you got this bunch
of numbers you want to capture all the
numbers such that the number has a
adjacent symbol to it now period doesn't
count okay so for example this 409
counts because there is a asterisk on
the
southwest corner of this number so that
number counts okay this 44 Z doesn't
count because there's no there's no
symbol occurring adjacent to the number
so adjacent means in the front of it
after it or above it or below it
including diagonal Okay so this 165
counts because there is a slash on the
south
southwest corner okay so you want to get
all the numbers that has a adjacent
symbol around it then you sum up all
those numbers that is a solution okay so
I was saying you know so normally one
approach the normal common approach is
that you go you you use a regular
expression uh capture all the numbers
along with their beginning and end
position uh so such as uh such as let me
show
you uh
okay okay let's
show
uh okay so for
example so you can can you see that
expression regular expression that's a
regular expression s syntax in wolam
language you see this square
bracket then inside back SLB SL D that
means all digits and this correct sence
means not any of the digit so I'm doing
something else here but anyway the
simply solution is you simply capture
all the numbers first all the numbers
along with their beginning and end
position then for each number you go
through each line and you
take a subring and you check if there's
a symbol before the number after number
or in the previous line like that okay
on or in the next line you you do a you
know substring you know you grab a
substring you can find which index to
grab by first of all you count the
number of characters per line then you
just add that number of characters that
gets you to the next line so the
beginning position of a number plus the
number of characters of each line that
gets you to the next line right below
the number then you minus one so you get
this you know you get the
diagonal and you do the same thing to
the end position of the number so you
can take us you so you got the beginning
and end index of the next line so you
all you have to do is is you check this
subring to see if there's any symbol
character in it you do same thing
similarly for the line before it okay
that's a problem now there's some issues
like the first line the first line it
doesn't have a line before it so if you
try to subtract a
substring it doesn't work because you
get out of boundary so you have to do
some special Edge case checking you know
if this is the first line
then you don't do the you don't do the
check before you know the previous sline
and if the number the first the
beginning position of a number occurs in
the beginning of the input you also have
to make sure that you don't check the
character before the number because
that's out of bound okay that's one way
to do it you have to do
extra uh case of edge Ed uh Edge case
checking but I figure I figured out a
trick a smarter way so whenever you have
a case like that what you can do is you
can pad the input string so in other
words you add a empty line to the
beginning and add a empty line to the
end where each character in the lines
all dots so and and you know in the
beginning and and the end and also on
the side so you add one dot to beginning
of every line you add one dot to the end
of every line you pad them so all
together you have like one surrounding
periods around your input so if you do
that you know it's simple to Pat them so
if you do that you don't have to worry
about the edge case cases because every
line has you know every number has a
beginning line and end of line and so on
so anyway I was trying to do this
problem by uh by one single pure
expression so it turns out that's
basically practically impossible but so
I spend a total maybe 10 hours 10 hours
trying to trying to trying to come out
with the like a shocking solution that
You' never seen okay but that failed
that failed um so one so regular
expression like one single so there's a
issue if you are trying to solve this
problem with without any substring
position information at all so you
purely rely on regular expression there
are still two two kind of levels one is
that is that you do it in one single
regular expression code not two you know
just not not once you got some pattern
then for each number you do another
regular expression no you do it in one
shot one single regular expression you
capture all the numbers you want
okay that turns out so I spent most of
time on that uh so you can see my code
you know wolam language you know wolam
language supports regular expression
like that like like so but it also
supports a
alternative which is called string
expression I I explained before but um
uh I explained before when I was do
doing you know I explained you know this
month or in my live stream uh you can
just go to my wam language uh let me
show you because meanwhile I want to
promote my stuff so Kasa wolam Language
tutorial this tutorial is teaching you
wolam language from the ground up
assuming you are already a programmer
you know python you know C or maybe you
know Java Java or
JavaScript however it's different from W
frames tutorial because I teach you the
I make you understand how the wolam
language works okay wolam language is a
term rewriting system you have never
seen before not in Java not in hascal
not in closure lisp not in any of the
lisp a term rewriting
system sometimes it's called P pattern
matching but in hascal in okamo in F
this functional languages they have
pattern matching but but they are their
pattern matching is not the same because
wolf language pattern magine is symbolic
pattern magine so symbolic just like
this okay so anyway there it is wam
language okay so uh I talked a lot I
don't know if I'm going to do any code
at all patri or German Lopez so any
feedback guys you tell me where I'm
going going on okay if you get tired of
me just talking philosophical you know
computer theoretical computer science
just tell me CU I what I like to see
code code okay then I'll start to
code I need to get more okay in a bit so
we spent we are 22 minutes in it who's
watching eight
okay so yeah so back to so yeah so so I
was saying wolfan language has a regular
expression uh maybe it's faster to do do
it to do it than just talking so for
example let me demonstrate the power of
regular expression in wam
language
uh string
cases okay string cases uh is kind of a
regular expression function that returns
all patterns captured patterns okay Hi
how are you some number and
my email is
cad.org
okay and something something something
something uh I don't want to evaluate
actually
uh actually how do I oh yeah so you just
do that happy to 2020 24 okay so first
argument is a string then the second
argument is a pattern okay let's do a
pattern so you can
say
regular expression that's what we want
and what do you want to capture you want
to capture let's say all digits
okay uh 0 to9 okay one or more one or
more okay let's run it there it is is
you got 3
827 and 20 24 you see that's regular
expression string cases okay fantastic
now wam language
supports a alternative to regular
expression is which is called string
Expressions okay let's so let's try the
string
Expressions string
expression okay there it is so now we
want to express a pattern that's just
digits okay
easy
uh digit character you see this symbol
digit character
means a sequence of digits okay let's
run
it oh it works however you got it wrong
because that's digit character is just
just one of them so you need to fix that
Let's do let's
magnify okay so digit character let's F
we now we want one or more how do you do
one or more in this weird string string
expression okay
easy dot dot okay that means one or more
there it
is fantastic okay now back to the Advent
of code day three
so you see so I got lots of code so I
was so I was first of all trying to do
the solve the problem by regular
expression uh by one single regular
expression that failed but theoretically
that is possible but it's like you have
to
generate I don't know thousands I
thousands of all Expressions okay so
anyway um so that failed so what I'm
thinking it okay
so the
first
um dramatic solution is trying to do
solve this by regular expression only
okay that kind of failed
I yeah I spend like 10 hours on it uh
I'm like
99% sure it
fails you know it because you know but
it's interesting whether it's actually
you
know even if I even if I have to to to
generate thousands of all expressions
for regular expression and some of this
problem I think that would still be
spectacular yeah so anyway I'm
99% sure I failed okay but I haven't
tried the like the theortical you know
because each approach each one of these
traumatic solution you want to approach
you're going to spend few hours thinking
about it and lots of coding so
anyway one of the dramatic solution is
regular expression okay no positional
checking at all and I failed I failed at
that the other
solution which I've been thinking a lot
is that you see this
problem uh you see this problem
you see this input is kind of a
pattern right you can you know regular
expression is a is basically a pattern
finder
okay but regular expression allows you
to find sequential
information in the data basically a
string a text okay but
sequentially that is why you have
problems with this with you know trying
to do this with pure regular expression
because in this
case you want some kind of like
two-dimensional pattern you know
obviously this is a pattern because you
want all the numbers that has a symbol
surrounding it right so is it possible
you know consider this input as some
kind of Matrix right a two-dimensional
Matrix okay so is it possible to have
some kind of pattern that just you know
that just you can specify the pattern
you'll just find the number where it has
symbol NE neighbors right that is what
I'm trying to do uh so that's another
dramatic approach I don't have a code
sorry so so guys say something okay am I
does that is this my high level
explanation making sense
or do you think you know should I just
code is do you think oh that's just too
much philosophical talk just start to
code you know maybe you want to learn
actual wolam coding or stuff let me know
okay so anyway the alternative solution
I mean dramatic solution is
to turn this into a two-dimensional
Matrix which you can easily do in wam
language okay two-dimensional so it's a
two-dimensional Matrix where each
element is a single character okay so
wolam language is a language of term
rewriting system so it has a lot 7,000
functions by default out of the box you
do not even have to load a library like
7,000 functions are available to you
without you having to say you know uh uh
import something something no no import
7,000 functions right there and Wen
language is a term rewriting system so
it has a lot facilities far more
powerful than regular expression to
match patterns okay so that is enticing
that makes me think that I want to solve
this problem
by uh Rob Rob pack on go language very
interesting okay uh we had an argument
on the S Discord about robik about where
is where is sis code about Rob Pik about
the original intention of of go
land I tell them I tell them what it
is very interesting so Steve are you
here
Steve so Thiago says using regular
expression for this seems a bit tricky
exactly I always get a bit uh what I
always get a bit lost with syntax of
complex regular expression patterns yeah
that's very common for all of us so
anyway so uh R pack okay so let's go
back to the problem
so so we can if we can turn this into a
2d Matrix we I mean we can do that easy
then we can you know the key is to find
some kind of mask you know in
programming especially C you have the
concept of bit mask so bit mask means
you know you when you have a binary
number
which is made out of zeros and one let's
say 0 one one 0 0 one one one something
you can apply socalled a bit mask so
another string another string made out
of zero and one and zero zero means pass
through one means hide it so you kind of
just stamp The Mask into this Matrix you
know imagine there's some kind of mask
you know you just stamp on it to it onto
it and all the numbers you want came out
all the other things you know the the
you know the the symbols the dot or the
numbers that doesn't count will be
hidden so if if is there some kind of
like like pattern you so you need to
generate that mask okay that's so this
is the second approach that I have
been uh thinking a little bit you know
like 1 hour or twoo I've been trying it
um I mean spending like 3 hours uh
and I haven't found it I haven't found
the solution okay so in this idea is
that you consider this a some kind for
example let me give you another way of
seeing this okay so for let me let me
show you okay so keyboard now we need to
go show keyboard and uh layout okay
layout and uh you can see uh ergonomic
keyboard layout okay so you see this is
this is the heat map of the keys in
English so e is used most frequently
then after that t then after that um you
know which one is bigger a a then H you
know so this is a frequency of the
letters you can by the way you can
change to vorak
comac so anyway this is a heat map okay
so in this Advent of code day three you
can think of this you know you do the
same thing you generate a heat
map that's the idea okay that that's a
kind of fuzzy so but that's an idea you
know either you you create some kind of
mask map so you basically all you want
is that you don't want to like
individually check each number you just
simply want a pattern that that in one
function call it you get the numbers you
want
okay that's an idea so but I have uh
have not been successful on that so this
is so far is just all talk all talk no
actual code
okay so what I'm thinking today I'm just
going to finish this day three part one
problem by by a normal solution okay but
before we do that let me show you the
the kind of Graphics thing okay let's
just go to wolam
language go let's go to their
documentation
let's turn on
JavaScript uh find answer by product
what I
want release notes okay let's go to
release notes I want to go to the
documentation uh wolf ma Mathematica
reference 13.1 that's what I'm
using there it is the documentation so
you want let me show you some of the
visualiz ation thing
okay turn on
JavaScript love my content thank
you okay let me know what's going on
okay guys talk uh data visualization let
me let me show you some okay so you can
you you you get idea for example there
is this uh density plot so you kind of
like like I was talking about heat map
right so in wam language you can uh do
density plot so for example
this this given input uh you know a
bunch of numbers with that you know this
given input consider it as a 2d Matrix
so we got a 2d array then you can do the
density plot you
see let me show you okay so since since
this
um
do do I get that copied uh there it is
okay let's just run it so you see what
I'm talking about
so so you see this density plot you
FedEd this function okay so that means
it's not even function it's just a 2d
array okay so
let's table
form okay so you see you just got a 2d
array just like just like uh
numbers you see now now you can now with
this 2D array you can plot it so what
does it density mean so density
means the higher the number the the
higher the color okay so you can change
the color to you know to Rainbow or
to gray to Red you know Bas you know
it's kind of like a heat map so anyway
this is what
so this is least density plot okay so
one of
them okay so at this rate I don't think
we going to start to code because I'm
just you know I'm just starting to show
you some of the interesting things about
wolam language okay so you got density
plot then if you don't
have you see right now we the input to
the density plot is a bunch of numbers
2D Matrix okay a 2d array but if you
don't have a array you can
um there are so many ways okay let me
just show you another
one
uh uh what what is uh surface data
surface appearance appearance surface
area we want uh what we what is it we
want oh there's also array plot okay so
array plot let me show you so you do the
same thing now instead of uh instead of
density plot you say array PL they are
kind of similar okay so you
see in this case uh yeah so again higher
number
becomes uh more dark okay so you you so
you know we are starting to get idea
right
so
so so back to the problem so that's what
I'm thinking
so you know i' thinking of a way so that
we can
somehow it's not trivial though I don't
know if this will actually work how
somehow turn this into kind of 2D Matrix
and consider each of these number like
somehow condense them to a single number
and we
can you know make this you know you you
simply plot it and you know which color
is the right number and you know in
order to get the adjacent you know a
number if it doesn't have symbol
characters around it it doesn't count
right but if it does then it counts so
what you have to do is uh for
example let's see txt okay so this is
keyboard block we don't
want uh what is this WF Language
tutorial close it uh yeah here text okay
so we open uh
what we open that file so here is the
input so you see this is see in emx you
can do this
uh
you see in emac you can highlight you
know re rectangular highlight you see
now you can see the surrounding numbers
for this now let's magnify okay uh the
window is not big enough so anyway so
you can see this um oh they got a
negative numbers
tricky
uh you see this 103 NE
-73 so in this case does so does it does
that negative count or not It's Tricky
it's it's trying to [ __ ] you up this
advant of
code so I actually I don't know if that
negative count
as oh it doesn't count I think it's all
just positive integers okay so that
negative sign counts as a symbol
adjacent to the number seven
703 so what you have to so the neighbor
is actually this not one more column
before the negative sign okay so anyway
this number counts because there's a
negative there's a you know negative
sign is a
symbol so I wanted to kind of turn that
into somehow turn that into this idea so
that you don't have to manually like go
check every number you just somehow
apply a pattern or some kind of mask and
you get it okay do I make sense Thiago
do I make
sense those of you watching you know Q
intent is that some kind of idea that
you know so I don't have a solution so
it's just uh so far it's just empty
talk uh anyway so maybe that's enough
for showing the some of the graphics
let's okay here's the thing I'm going
going
to hi you a n okay so I'm going to now
to start to code this problem in the
simplest way possible forgot forget
about the fancy things I'm trying to do
okay just do it simple way uh I can
finish it in 20 minutes okay before I do
that let's get a
drink
for
trying out a mask seems like a good idea
yeah that's uh not easy though I mean
you know you got I got this you know you
got this fancy idea but actually the
thing is
about uh it's not trivial to think about
how can it actually be
done Che this is red
wine red
wine and
uh orange
juice sliding window
approach oh what does that mean that
seems
interesting sliding window yeah that
seems interesting but I have to think
about cheers unan
unan okay turn the screen back so we
don't
forget and show the fancy thing amazing
so you guys download Ram language okay
okay it is my job selling you guys wolam
language okay so you go to is you can
download it for
free okay just you know just just go to
wam tutorial you will find my link you
know or just search You Know download
wam engine for free so you can try it
but actually I recommend you just buy it
okay you know if it cost you $10,000 is
worth worth it okay you know you stick
it uh for your life like I like I did
you know since
1993 why why should you there are so
many languages there are so many
programming free programming languages
fancy ones like hascal or camel FSH all
all those are functional you you also
have AGA you also have [ __ ] C OG G proof
systems you also have you know uh a
closure you know if you are into you
know then you have racket scheme this
all these are free why should why do you
want to pay or or get the wolfen
language well that's
because all these things you
know you know it just let you do things
let you you know you can you can kind of
consider wolam language is one giant
calculator A system that has everything
you possibly want that possibly could
could be put into one system so you you
have not just you know the you have like
20 plotting functions including plotting
graph okay imagine you know if you want
to you know Peterson graph okay if you
want to PL this in go in in Python okay
you have to download NP or something
then like download you know you have
first of all you have to ask just go to
stack flow overflow which one should I
download I need to PL plot the graph you
know which
one then you got one gigabyte you know
10 libraries n Pi s pi stuff and it
doesn't you know sometime it doesn't
work and and then the documentation
sucks you have to stack Overflow then
you know but in wolam language it's one
integrate single hole that allows you to
solve equations symbolically
symbolically differential
equations linear algebra equations like
inverting matrices or Matrix Matrix
equations or tensor equations or you
know differential equations and integral
equation any equation possible that is
in the entire field of mathematics if
there's some idea that has been captured
before wam language try at least tries
to have it okay in number Theory and in
number theory in in analysis calculus in
algebra you know group Theory or whatnot
and in graph Theory you know you are
witnessing graph theory for example this
one this one shows you you know it's
automatic arrangement in in graph Theory
when you want to PL something usually
you have a problem of arranging how do
you arrange the knots so that it
displays nicely for example this
Peterson graph actually I don't know
this Peterson graph
but you see and you
can magnify it and if it's a 2d graph a
3D graph you can rotate it okay so it's
kind of too
big you can import export it to PDF to
to anything any possible uh you know
Graphics system format out there
literally literally any possible graphic
system that exist just for a simple
graphic example so you can plot um graph
Theory you know it's just not not just
plot you can do you know the entire the
world's entire possible graph Theory
related functions and algorithm
algorithms about graph that is known is
in W language okay that is just graph
Theory then you have number Theory you
have have analysis you have topology
things you have differential geometry
that one of my favorite
subject okay then you say oh yeah that's
interesting but I'm not a mathematician
those things are not useful to
[Laughter]
me then then what about programming oh
you don't know things
man what about programming let me show
you okay so programming you are
interested in list manipulation you know
like you know so and what about AI what
about neural networks you are if you are
a neural network researcher so let me
show you neural network and sound and
audio God it's endless it generates
sounds okay it
generates let's let's see let me show
you one okay actually I showed this
before uh simple as simple as that so
you want to plot you have a you have
a sound wave defined by sign okay first
of all let me show you what this sound
wave looks
like okay there's a documentation I
don't need to know the documentation of
sign I know what sign is okay let's just
plot sign
okay so P sign 440 that is uh that is
called uh standard a in music if you are
music that you know that that frequency
440 is the middle a that's on a piano
right below the middle key see about two
two white notes below it okay A B C A so
this this is um so let's plot
it uh T goes from let's say 0 to 4
Pi okay so it's
like anyway you can play it okay let's
run
it
okay oh my God that's a pure pure tone
can you like hear it let's
see yeah you can hear it it it's very um
it'll make you crazy pure T so but let's
see you you know this a uh let's see
let's try something interesting okay so
this
one uh go back to wfam language okay now
I'm BEC now I'm a Salesman for wolam
language okay let's play this
one yeah that's not so interesting what
what is
this I want something uh let's do some
more okay I want something
more V uh not pure turn but variations
okay
uh no that's not
good let's try this one
tangent n not so interesting I want
something
more sample
rate oh this one okay it's more
interesting this
one got oh this one is nice can you hear
it yeah this one is
nice so Anon says the reason I never
went over to Mathematica is because it
really isn't that referenced in
engineering analysis in my career mat
lab however is always being asked
for yeah well that's because because
matlb is you
see let me just tell you okay my opinion
mat lab there's no way this is like it's
not comparable it's a it's not
comparable at all Matt lab is mostly a
numerical system so mat lab cannot solve
you know wfam language is a symbolic
system so everything you do you can by
default it's symbolic so you it gives
you close from symbolic solutions to any
equation differential equations or
matrices if your input is symbolic okay
now matlb and most vast majority of
other systems they are numerical
Solutions so if you are engineer usually
you don't need symbolic Solutions I mean
if you are an engineer typically
typically okay if you are engineer you
know Building Bridges or car designing
engines or whatever rocket
usually usually okay often you don't
want you don't need
symbolic Solutions you just need
numerical so that that's mostly what
math lab do mat lab is I think in
particularly focused on uh linear
algebra so actually let's try uh today's
AI B okay so today is like I'm starting
to ramble a on other things let me let's
ask AI bot what is Matt lab good
for you know I know these things because
I've been nering about them since
1993 okay because I you know 1993
there's really no internet yet but what
people do you know you can this's like
newset internet not like today you don't
you don't have really have websites you
know but you go to you can ask other
people other Engineers mathematicians or
physics you know what's the best uh
what's the best software to do
engineering and solve equation and you
know and they can tell you and and and
many of them came and went okay Matt lab
is one of them that last
it uh so let's see what is matlb good
for so matlb is a high level programming
language and software environment
primarily used for mathematical
computation tasks here are some of its
main uses Matrix operation you see
that's a that's a primary thing data
analysis okay numerical Computing again
that's what I said that's the primary
thing of mat lab okay numerical
Computing then scientific Computing of
course machine learning and AI right
that's all all numerical okay rapid
application development okay you can add
that uh and education right
but it you know it when it comes to
symbolic which is very important for
mathematicians especially mathematicians
and physics okay
mathematicians you know mathematicians
usually they don't care about numerical
results
okay numerical results that's for
engineers you know we want exact result
we you know find this theory of things
not numerical okay so let's ask
can uh math lab do symbolic
computation Matt lab right did I spell
it correctly Matt
lab oh not lab but
B yes mat lab can perform symbolic
computation through its symbolic math
tool box this tool box allow you to
perform symbolic mathematics incl
including algebraic operations calculus
solving equations simplification
arbitrary Precision arithmetics
mathematical functions okay Pol nomials
okay that's kind of
limited uh so symbolic math toolbox what
is that is either add on or
what okay let's keep
asking what is
symbolic math
toolbox the Sy symbolic math toolbox is
a mat lab tool box that extend that's
there is that extends mat lab's
numerical computation
capabilities to include symbolic
computation so that means mat lab cannot
do symbolic computation you have to add
this plugin okay so anyway there's a lot
um systems you know in the past 30 years
I've seen them came and go so M lab most
of them are numerical focused which is
very useful and practical for
engineers and right so Maple is one of
the main comp competitors of uh of wolam
language you know so-called computer
arbra system okay I digressed so much uh
at this rate I'm not going to code the
you know uh let's go back I should
really you know I
should you know I should code
this I should code this day three
problem
okay
so did you start programming in the 93
yes and in 95 I loved wam language so
much I read you know the 1,000 page
books cover to
cover more than three times in over 10
years in different years and so I I went
to wam research for half a
year uh in Illinois and yeah that's a
long story and yeah
anyway Maple yeah so it's a module you
have to pay extra yeah so you know that
so that's not you know that's what if
you want s symbolic computation mat lab
is not the main thing you know you
rather go with
Maple uh and and the wolam language you
know and if you ask me wolam language is
far superior because do you know
why because it's got you know because
wolfan language got this stepan wolfan
character in it okay stepen wolam is
this this very
odd and outstanding character you know
he's got theories about about the
universe about s automata about
you know
the modeling of the universe not you
know the current phys his wolam physics
project you know so he's got a lot
Visions so that is
why uh wam language
is I would say okay I never really tried
Maple you know even 30 years ago but I
would say WF language is far
superior uh and uh and I can um I can
you know
other other systems you know usually
many of these packages are
written uh not on topic but why so many
keyboards okay that's a long story but
anyways that's a long story anyway let
me finish what my thought okay so many
of these computer Lang uh computer
algebra system packages they began their
life by a math student you know like you
guys you know you were a math student at
college right you studied it and you you
can code you find it fun to code so you
wrote a program that solves something
integration or whatever D then you it be
you are very good then becomes popular
then you thought of selling a package
that's a lot of these mathematic
packages life
began
um Maino and and most of them most of
them began like that or if you are a
professor you know like the S um s math
so anyway so but what usually happens is
that just like uh many situations in
open source you know you begin at it's
very popular for five years but usually
after five years you know you started
company selling M math lab or
whatever after five years you got tired
of it you are no longer a college
student you you got married you have a
wife you are not really no longer
interested in these mathematical things
anymore maybe you know you you you now
you are the boss of the company you have
a lot money your company went public you
know uh you quit you sell the company
you know once you go public the the
company is no longer yours so the
company becomes owned by St owners so
they they have their own
life then you you start being a c CEO
you know you got you got your money you
got millions of dollars you you you went
on with your life right mat lab is one
of the story okay the original Founders
is no longer long time ago has nothing
to do with mad lab
anymore right so it's a public company
it got traded it got sold you know by
this money money over oriented
people
so that also means the quality of the
software degrades significant
significantly like Google Google is a
great example 20 years ago it's one of
the best everything Google does is the
greatest software in design in you know
tight code everything is the best about
Google today it's the most evil company
it's and the Google search is [ __ ] not
just [ __ ] but censorship and also and
YouTube you know
imagine YouTube They removed you know
your ability to thumb down and hide it
they don't actually remove it they want
to keep it but hide it so you can if you
and huge amount you know it becomes [ __ ]
censorship and becomes total [ __ ] that's
what happens to public companies you
know what happened to these sergy bring
and you know these two guys from
Stanford College you know they have a
vision they want to save the world you
know they want to save Africa they want
to help the world you know what happened
to them I don't know they they become
billionairs you know they they own their
own
Island what do they care about this how
this is this corrupt you know things
going on in Google and YouTube you
know I'm not sure they care you know
they they they you know the life change
so anyway that's the story so that is
why I think I'm telling you wolam
language is truly the best thing because
because this Stefan wolam character you
know he could
have sold the company you know open
stocks you know so it's public but he
doesn't want to he's a type you know
he's still after all the this years he's
maybe 60 something all these years he he
want to control he he's got a vision
this is my software I want this way he
control every aspect
okay he's got vision and he runs you
know cellular school wolam summer school
wolam physics project he's got a vision
okay he's got he believe you know this
he that's his passion okay when you have
a passion someone and you have a very
capable man you know that you got this
wolam
language okay that is that is my kind
of so what are you guys
saying will you upgrade to Windows 11
someday okay that's off topic probably
not Windows getting worse and worse the
next time I upgrade will be Linux back
to Linux again actually Mac
actually so the question about keyboard
let's talk about that another day okay
because uh not uh but because mostly
today we're talking about math and
stuff and Matt lab is one those features
they want me to be selling to them
selling to them as an
employee you know one of the thing is
that I heard mat lab got Rewritten in
Java like five or 10 years ago you
know kind of City knowledge of mat lab
makes me money oh okay that's good I
guess if I was the boss I could use
Mathematica anyways uh there Wasing any
special food for new years no well my
wife cook me uh good things
okay my wife cooked me great meals
she's she'll be back
tonight anyway let let me let me try to
uh do some coding okay uh it's already
70 minutes let me try to do some coding
or let's see what
else
should I do some coding or because
um Steve where is Steve Steve are you
here so let's see how many people
10 okay let me let
me okay I'm going to code for 15 15
minutes if I failed then I failed I'm
going to close down if I succeed that
great that's great uh I'm going to try
to finish this uh day three problem
okay so okay so let's see so
um
okay so let's so here's a code wam
language um and
uh yeah so lots of fun today so this
problem so
um so we got lots of code here uh oh
God so
actually
okay I'm going to do that here so you
got you got a list this list of numbers
you want
to you want to uh Cho a line so you got
choer line
so so what is this padded
input so you want to get each number
okay so you want to get each
so I'm going to do the easy way so first
step is just grab all the numbers by a
regular expression or a uh string
expression okay and uh also get their
position okay so yeah let's ignore the
rest let's just quickly do this Cher
line we don't care so we want
to string positions
okay okay stream positions is the
function we want that just give us all
the positions so so takes two arguments
the input is the you know the first
argument is the input string the second
argument is a pattern okay so in this
pattern we will
be string expressions and digit
characters and uh digit
characters
one or more okay so let's run
it okay so
let's Okay so let's see let's see let's
run that so there it is that's a
beginning and end positions of every
each and every of sequence of Digit
characters okay so once you got that
what else you want to do
so yeah so let's just do the most CD way
uh so once you got so 24 24 is the
position of this one you want to check
the so you first of all you need to know
how many characters per line you need to
know that so that you can go up a line
and you know and check okay so you need
to know how many characters per line so
characters per line is done by this I
already have the code there so it's
really character apply zero what what
the
[ __ ] stream position input and
uh what what uh why is my character
here
stream positions input
pattern oh yeah pattern so that then
gives that and uh so let's see what is
this okay I'm going to trying to finish
it instead of like
uh
wait why is
that oh yeah so we got it wrong because
we added this you know extra new line to
the beginning that City so if we remove
this extra new line
evaluate then we try our stream position
code 10
okay that tells you the character line
this is kind of annoying you know this
the beginning of line because if you put
a new line there it's it it's aligned it
it's more visually understandable but
you shouldn't really have it so anyway
so character per line This is a
character per line we need let's put it
here okay that's a number of characters
per line
and and we need to know because for
example this number you need to go up
that character per line number of
characters to go to that position and uh
then uh minus one uh and
uh character
Pine uh character Pine then uh then we
want
to
uh okay I decided we I'm going to pad
I'm going to pad the whole input meaning
that I'm going to add the empty line in
the beginning a line of dots and uh a
line at the bottom dots and also add
dots to the to the side okay so padded
input let's see if we have that already
written
uh
let's so so maybe this code will do
let's see padded input equals to what is
this string repeat character per line so
character per line is a uh thing we
defined plus two because we need to add
also two columns at the beginning and
end okay so character per line plus that
and
that and that is y y then then and why
why that this means stream join and
stream replace
[Music]
um God what is
this happy New Year Anon thank
you
so I forgot what it is let's just run
it okay so what is this string repeat
um so string repeat the first line the y
y gives us that then what is this
XX that gives us
this let's see string replace so what
does this do oh y y so you add y y to
the beginning which is
the a line of dots that and then you
string
replace so this means join okay so let's
see if we can do this
more no it doesn't help anyway
so a DOT plus the
input plus a
DOT
then rep replace
a replace the line new line by dot dot
we replace each new line by two dots
because instead of the new line
that that is an
obstacle we replace the new line
character by two dots so the first dot
is like the left padding the second dot
is the right padding
okay so re replace the new line by two
dots character
then then what is
this string replace to takes two
arguments so replace new line by two
dots then
replace regular
expression uh
any not digit so we replace all n digit
by
T So this mean means instead instead of
dealing with different symbol characters
we replace all symbol characters by the
character t Okay so actually by
character X would make sense okay
then let right it okay let me show
you okay so the first part the y y is
the is just a a bunch of dots okay one
line the second part
XX is the whole
input padded by dots including in the
side and but with new line replaced so
we kick out the new line and replace by
a DOT so this does not looks like a
matrix it doesn't look like a 2d Matrix
however it is like it represents you
know so visually this is not good but
for coding this is
good so then what is the third
one
so the third one what does this XT do so
add
[Music]
TTT string
repeat
dot by character line minus
4 and
join TTT so you are adding a TTT in
front and
uh
I don't know what this do [ __ ] I forgot
what's the code I wrote
here uh
but so XX is our new
input let's change the name okay uh
change YY
to
line of dots
okay and change XX
to we got it something here let's
see okay
so
so that should be more clear line of
dots so let's
see and
uh yeah God I'm on a I'm on a burner
so paded input let's see
how many characters are there string
length so 144 does that make
sense so orally it's 109 okay
so oh
god let's grab this part and put there
somewhere
okay let's save it let's say sound
play 2024 in Brazil I'm from the future
now
hey Thiago from Brazil wow are you the
are you the emx guy from braz Brazil
because I remember this you know there's
a bunch of you young people in Brazil
but you are one of the emac user
right like you you guys joined my
Discord
before so okay so that's the sound play
so so this is a problem and we solve
this okay and uh then string characters
is
10 character
line
that you don't need okay character per
line okay so this part we don't
need control shift d
to character per line we don't
[Music]
need control sh shift d to break the
cells into two then line of
dots okay
then then this
is okay
then we want to know input how many
lines let's
see
line count
okay so this is find line
count stream
position string count okay input and we
just want to count number lines so do
that that's line count okay so this
needs to plus one because you count the
number of new line characters then plus
one right because you know if you want
to know the how many lines of count so
this is
the how you get line count okay let's
copy
that
God drunk coding okay so this is line
count then once you get line count you
don't need
um oh you still need that okay so you
got line C you got CH
line you got line count you got CH line
10 is that also is that right 1 2 3 4 5
6 7 8 9 10 oh you got 10 lines but you
also got 10 characters per line 1 2 3 4
5 6 7 8 9 10 oh okay so it's a square
Matrix okay and uh line of dots this is
you this is what you
generate
repeat CH line + two because you padded
okay so this is padded line of
dots uh and uh yeah so then like uh
so
replace okay we rename them so we got
padded line of dots then we so the
padded
input so let's do this padded line of
dots so now there's a two 12 characters
of
them am I doing good
guys 12 you see I'm correct now now
padded input so padded input let's try
it first uh you know that's this thing
how many characters are there well so
you have 10 by
10 now you add one so 10 20 30 40 41 42
43 44
right can you see me 10 20 30 40 and and
four more on each corner so
42 so let's see the length of padded
input
perfect now you see we padded we padded
the whole string and then also we
replace any symbol by just the symbol T
so it makes uh instead of T let's use x
okay let's use x so it's makes sense it
makes better
sense so this this is actually our
padded input so we don't have to check
the edge cases of boundary condition
okay so so far so good and what is this
thing
TTT string repeat string connect minus 4
TDC I forgot what is that for let's
forget
it okay so now string positions okay now
string positions now let's check padded
input okay this is a bunch of occurrence
of the beginning and in positions of
each occurrence of sequence of digits
okay now uh what's next so for each of
these number occurrence you go through
the input string you take the
substring then you
that's right so you go through it you
take the substring so what you do you
map
uh okay map take takes two arguments the
second argument is paded input the first
argument is
um uh the first argument is a function
okay so let's write the
function uh and this function you want
to
so this function will be
fed wait so you want to go
through uh what do you want to go
through uh you want to go to stream
positions
okay non positions equals to you want to
set that okay let's do that so now we
got a weet it n position so it's a list
of beginning and positions now you map
this function to that non positions so
the non positions is two
numbers okay uh let's let's let's be
clear
clarification we
prefer full names instead of like the C
style of short
names am I still good are you guys
watching n people are still watching
okay I need to get up I need to go to
the bathroom but anyway so you map this
function the ma the function takes two
arguments you map to this you know a
bunch of beginning and end positions
okay so your function takes those in
position positions then what you do
you you take a
substring okay in wolam language you
don't have names like substring you know
that's not wolam language style so how
do you call a substring you know you
want a function that takes a substring
by index beginning and end okay so wolam
language calls it um string Parts okay
so I can show you okay
string part okay okay that's how you
take a substring substring okay let's
say something in
water okay that's a string second second
element is a
list okay so let's
say first first position to third
position let's say to Fourth position we
should get
some oh okay so we this is um we got SE
so
let's see the
documentation yeah so you if you say n
that's the N character so if you say
that it's a each of these character so
you have to say that okay
so so what you do is you want to one
semicolon semicolon 4
evaluate oh wait okay so but I don't
want I don't want them each character
per element I want them just
subring
uh list of the N character okay list of
the character so
it so I want just
the I want the subring I want sub I
don't want sub characters
okay a string take string take is a
function you want okay string take
okay so string
take so that's uh like similar to
subring and here I believe it's like I
familiar with this one two 4 there it is
Sun okay so string take is what you want
so here back
here string take function okay string
take the function
from pad input and
uh and the position is just a beginning
and position okay but not exactly let me
show you okay first of all let's run
that oh okay so wait what did I do wrong
string take a
function
uh function number positions so put a
do we have a seen we
got map this
function to number positions okay too
many par parameters in beginning end oh
okay so I know what you're going on so
when you map
you okay
so so instead of that you say positions
okay let me just code fast say hi guys
say hi okay
so
one two okay so that is how you do it
there so you map it to number positions
so here here is your input position pair
because each element is a pair beginning
and end then here you take them apart
the first part is a beginning the second
part is end okay let's run it there it
is so this is a bunch of numbers you
extract it from this
thing uh but why is there five let's
see why is there a single number five oh
that's because it does repetition you
see you got a number 35 and five why
because it it considers overlap okay so
what you want is you don't want overlap
okay
so let's look at the documentation for
string positions you don't want
overlap so overlap Force okay so that's
what you
want
so there's some
complications okay
there that's your begin and positions of
the padded string okay then that is
there it is now you you no longer have
these single digits there so you see
these are the all the digits you
extracted
from the original input okay oh God I'm
just talking myself at this point 10
people watching say gu say hi guys am I
doing good so okay so now you we but we
are making a lot progress I'm not like
stuck in the past few days okay so now
but I need to go to the bathroom so so
now we got this so what's the next thing
so you so now you are able to extract
the
substring but that's not what you want
because you want to extract not just the
substring but you also want to extract
up to the
previous line up to this numbers you
know diagonal corner and also the next
line so what you have to do is uh is
instead of this map you let let's clean
up the code so it's easier to
read
okay it's kind of you know wam language
is on nested so let's so stream position
pair here you want to
add choer line
okay then you want to oh not add but
minus minus so you want to go to the
previous line and also minus one because
you want to count the diagonal
okay and uh similar here so let's make
it easier to
read similarly here you want to get the
next line so you say plus X Char per
line and plus one okay let's grab that
and let's
see syntax zero what the
back H we we we place this in the wrong
place okay so this is here
yeah beautiful isn't that beautiful my
friend so let's do this again this time
so percentage sign means the last
output slash slash is a postfix notation
and we want to apply table forms the
function table Foams so we got a
beautiful look I need to go to to the
bathroom Okay so I'll be back so you
guys seven people
watching
for
now more
drink
are you guys enjoying the drunk coding
even
drunk we can Cod a
river is a video am I still alive
yes okay a
break
what is the best position this
way so I've been live streaming
for 100 minutes
now
peanuts you know I was just reading
about the about the Mr Beast guy what
what a
Zuma what a Zuma
[ __ ] you know you know th those people
their goal is just to to get to become
the most popular you know I'm going to
count to 100,000 one two 3 you know it
it take me a whole day 24 hours but I'm
going to do it that way I get YouTube
views
oh my God amazing world record this guy
counts to 100,000 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
11 12 13 14 15 16
17 the [ __ ] the Mr
Beast this kind of people you know I
don't think he did anything illegal or
anything wrong but however this type of
people this Zuma type of people they you
know they don't have any
um Beauty you know they don't have any
beauty beauty of the world they are just
concerned make money cope memes you know
I'm going to just I'm going to just
let's see you know I'm just going to sit
here like that for 100
hours and I'm going to going to be the
most popular you know on YouTube
because [ __ ] [ __ ] these people
yeah that is true you know Mr Beast he's
right now the most popular people on
YouTube with you know five million
subscribers or something and then he do
you know tricks like like you know he's
so rich each video is like he makes is
cost him him million dollars you know of
course he has like thousands of millions
you know I think I think Wikipedia says
he's like worth 500 million so million
is peanuts you know he but he like he do
things to you know to the video like
idiotic things these
people zoomas Zuma generation [ __ ] the
zumers Q in 10 where are you where you
from are you in
USA so let's get back so I'm back to the
code uh so this so so far we are so good
you see we we doing so great with
this so we you see we got this padded
input uh fantastic and now all we have
to do is for each this number we
check if the we check if the beginning
three character is X okay and we check
the ending three character is X and we
also check the character in between you
know to the left and to the right of
this middle thing
is X okay if it is X then that means
this number is jackpot is part of the
number we want you know so easy okay so
next step so once you map
um so I'm I'm going to go with elaborate
L names so this this would be potential
jackpot
okay uh where do I put this oh yeah it's
you know potential jackpot here and uh
let's say table
form okay so that way it's easier uh
what
wait what ah f i sced
somewhere there okay
actually
actually yeah what uh okay let's just do
it this way okay then table
form
okay beautiful so this is potential
jackpot which is
a you know in look at the middle line
okay that's the number we are looking at
okay so potential jackpot and the next
step is we want to map to each of these
line of strings okay so
map okay and map to potential
jackpot okay and the first argument is
going to be a function again
okay okay a function so you map to each
of these line and you want to
check string match okay so the function
is so that tells you if if a whole
string matches Okay so the stream match
is going to
[Music]
be oh string again
[ __ ] oh [ __ ]
[ __ ] thank you Q he makes me angry
too okay so anyway so we got this
beautiful um you know potential
jackpot which is a list of lines
each one you look at the middle of the
middle column okay each one of the
middle column numbers is a potential
number we want all we have to do is we
check the first three characters
is uh let's say check the oh actually
check more than
wait we uh oh okay so it's a bit tricky
let's look see so if the digit if you
have three characters you want to
check 3 + 1 characters so if you have
two digits you want to
check uh 2 + 1 + 1 okay so the number of
Digit if let's say that's n then you
want to check the line begins with n n +
2 if they are
X if if so then that that's uh that's a
number we want and
similarly the okay I don't know if you
guys are following what I'm
saying but let me just do it if you paid
attention so far you should know what
I'm doing
okay uh so stream match so let's see
wait we actually need to know
ah [ __ ] there's another there's one more
problem we need to know the number of
digits for example
66633 we actually need to
know that's three digigit number huh
okay
so yeah we do do need to know how many
digit number how many digits is in a
number so we can do that by adding that
information to the
potential
jackpot okay
s
uh
okay let's add a s
okay because we we do need to know do I
make sense to you guys am I like are you
guys following my
logic because that's the point of
watching my video if you are just uh
watching for entertainment that's still
good but anyway so you need to know the
number of digits
okay so you need to know the number of
digits let's
see position so we can know the number
of digits because we have the position
beginning and position end so position
end minus the position
beginning
is and plus one is a number of
digits okay so we got number of digits
so
okay let's double check this is tricky
so let's say suppose this
number
what what's going on
what
h
what is going on
[ __ ] okay now so for example let's
magnify okay now for example this
58 so you go up one
column so for example 58 you go up one
column and you move one to the left
and
[Music]
um so in this case of 58 you need to
check this four
characters let's look at the user input
okay so in the case
of
166 you need to look
up four characters okay now in the case
of
of three numbers three numbers
what oh in the case of
29 you need to look up four
characters in the case
of
657 you need to look up five characters
so you need to look up two more
characters than the number of charact
digits okay let's make
sure so if any of these character is a
symbol then that
um then that then the number is what we
want
okay
okay okay you know my goal is to finish
this job okay so coding problem right so
we got the position beginning position
end and
uh now we are at the part of trying to
reject smatch the whole
thing now did we subtract did we extract
the
subring so
potential jackpots is not a good name a
better name
is
surround substring something like
that because we want the number is we
want but we have the surrounding
substring so let's say neighbor
substring okay so actually beta name
is Okay naming of things very critical
for maintain maintainability of
code okay you guys are good okay am I
good okay I'm still a little bit to
[Music]
go drunk
coding fantastic it's like drunk Kung
Fu okay so we got the we got the naming
correct so now now think about solving
the
problem so doesn't matter you see it
doesn't matter how many digits you
got you still have to get the
previous you know the previous line
including a
diagonal by the number of characters per
line minus one right is that correct
yes
but however once you got these lines
like we
did now you have to there's a question
about how many characters you need to
check if it contains X in the beginning
of each
line that depends on the number of
characters in your string I mean in your
number so if you have three digits then
you need to check if the first 3 + two
digits
let's see one two 3 4 5 is a
x okay got that yes I think so
[Music]
so so okay so actually so neighbor
string
uh so we we want number
positions neighbor string we don't need
this
part num positions let's let's include
something else num positions so you got
you start with padded input you grab the
digit
characters then overlap
force that returns you a list of
positions each element is the beginning
and end of the number like that
okay but we also need to know the number
of characters that's easy because you
just end the position minus beginning
position plus one okay so you do not
need to change this part so
neighbor neighbor put
subring oh God but the problem is you
need to know number of characters in a
digit in the in a number
so so you extract neighbor
string you extract neighbor
string and
uh
that's good but then you need to stream
match this is when you need to know the
number of digits okay so is
so okay so instead so I know what to do
okay so you want to map
index map indexed what it does is that
it's like map but except your function
takes two arguments the second argument
is the index of the element okay
so let's say I I okay
so index element is let's see neighbor
subring
okays let me just code it instead of you
know you guys are not responding so I'm
just going to code it and uh talk to
myself okay so n I'm just just going to
code it and so I can finish the prop
instead of you know code and
explain so we so let's do this in one
shot NE
subring so actually we don't even need
that so we number positions this is what
you want so you
map each one you get the neighor
subring and you do a regular expression
match okay
so like that okay so wait these two are
the same thing
okay so map
index num positions okay
so okay and the function you got number
of positions number positions
okay uh
[Music]
so position
pair and
uh so you need to
take okay so you need to do a lot of
things
okay
module okay
so uh so position
pair
begin position end position Char count
okay so let me show you what these do so
begin position equals
to position
pair first one and end position equals
to
and uh then CH count equals to begin
position minus end
position
plus one
okay and instead of the com instead of
the comma you need semicolon because
that's compound
expression my my wife is
back my wife is back Savor Savor I
haven't finished this I don't know if
you guys are interested six people you
guys gotta say something guys okay I'm
gonna go or else I'm gonna quit I'm
almost done
I'm almost I'm in my
like
uh I'm in my uh what is the word God I'm
drink
drunk
uh I'm in
my
trans you know getting this code is
almost done but now my wife is back but
you guys are quiet it's like what am I
doing like are you are you enjoying
watching me or are you just like turning
it in the background or what I don't
know but I'm almost done but let me talk
to my wife for a bit cuz she's back uh
but I'm almost done
here this module so let me make it so
that you can actually
um you know actually if I paste it in
wam language you'll be clear but
otherwise this is kind of you know this
current situation okay let me be back in
a
moment check audio input
yeah
voice check video check fantastic guys
inter interm
break go can you see me
no
n
chcken almost done
back to
code
okay let's see who who is in the
Discord you bunch of
people oh Steve is watching hey Steve
which one are you Q
intent
708 well that is that was an hour
ago real
life see what's this in real life George
and uh
Ripper okay so let's go back to the
coding okay let's get it
finished and
uh let's get it finished okay almost
done so map index so so okay
so we want to get a this done okay not
like the past few days okay
so so we
got so what time is it 8:09 so 20
minutes
okay so begin position that's that end
position that's that of course we can
shorten this all this going to be within
200 characters okay the entire problem
is going to be solved within 200
character characters can guarantee you
okay but I'm just doing you know a live
coding so I have to explain I have to
write things in the ways uh that's
easier for people to
understand
uh okay my wife is talking
[ __ ]
uh okay so no no uh no question from you
guys so anyway so let's finish this okay
so where are we so map index okay map
index takes two arguments so the
position pair and index
okay so it takes two arguments
so why do you want to map index you know
you don't want to map index let's
see so hold on a second my wife is
talking
keep going okay let's keep going fact I
finish
this so let's yeah so what is this map
index do we need to map index what are
we mapping we are mapping to number
positions okay that's a pair of values
beginning and end okay we map into that
now why do we need the
index the question is do we m need do we
need map index or
not no I don't think we
need uh map
indexed let's
see okay
so oh [ __ ] my wife is talking is your
way no this this microphone is like open
so there's no way
uh okay
okay let's try let's try this I'm just
going to be quiet so I'm just quiet so
you're gonna Focus your attention on
just watching me instead let's see how
that goes
okay
e
is the video
back what the [ __ ] my wife is talking
via the phone video conference to her
friend so so my live stream got
[ __ ] seeet
so I'm trying to quit because this is
hurting my
throat now uh back to live stream let's
see how many four okay I'm going to
finish the
code finish finish my cigarette and uh
I'm trying to quit let's see the New
Year's
resolution American thing you know Allan
was asking if that concept exists in
China I don't think so I don't remember
this like new year's resolution I don't
think so that's a western
concept okay I'm going to put out a
cigarette and uh back to code
okay
okay back to
code back to code got to finish this
thing
okay
so got to finish this thing so
neighborhood string equals to that uh
and we are right now on this which am I
on so those I don't care those are old
code yeah unique characters so
neighborhood
string yeah we are on this code okay
on this we are going to do it in one
shot so this this part will get get us
the numbers we want okay
so previous neighbor
string uh count and
uh
if so
if
or
yeah
what if
or
that string match not string match we
want string con
contains
Q okay if it
contains if that
contains if that contains X
or if the next
line contains X
all
or okay let's go
elaborate previous
Char
one one
so actually you need to add that
there previous chart next chart okay pre
previous
chart my head hurts only looking
at
programming
yeah uh if you love it you're gonna like
love the hurting it's like
the
sadism the masochism in sadle masochism
you
know that's not a good way to put it but
you know if if the subject is what you
love you love it so I love the subject
okay previous
CH and uh next
CH so if string contains so now let's
look at the documentation for string
contains you can have a list of strings
so in other
words this block of code is equivalent
to we can just put the list
here okay previous line neighor next
line neighbor previous
CH next chart okay so we this whole
thing becomes one single line the power
of wam
language so if it contains X so we don't
need this so and uh we don't so now we
don't even need all
anymore so what is this string
contains yeah we don't need all anymore
so if string
contains okay let's just put it in like
that if string contains X in any of
these then what do you
do so if strings contains let's see
let's go back so our code you know if
the string previous line next line and
neighing characters if it contains that
then you grab that number so that number
will
be begin position end position so you
has have to
take string take string take uh what is
the documentation for string
take m2n okay
so true input two index so string T
begin
position end
position okay so if it contains any of a
symbols then you just take the string
and uh then you apply two
expression that turns the string to a
number okay now if it does
not if it does not then just return
nothing nothing is a element that in a
inside the list you'll just become
deleted you'll just be gun
okay uh let's see no for now okay
so so let's double check if this works
so if it contains the then then the
substring uh
wait wait
so num
positions so this actually this should
be padded
input yeah paded
input okay
so so if that contains those
characters okay then
[Music]
you oh then you need to apply all
actually okay then if any of those is
true then you string
take then you string take
um paded input beginning position end
position that's right you take the
number if otherwise you return zero okay
that's right so I believe this
is what you want okay I believe we are
almost done
let's try it please make it work
[ __ ] part specification position pair
one is longer than depth of
subject uh part specification position
pair one
so position
pair function so this is the function we
map to number
positions so number positions is this
okay so
it so we ma into that so one two one two
one to why is it
uh why is
it part part specification position pair
one is longer than the
depth
where where does that came
from and Sh stock TR
Trace expression does not have an
element in a specified position yeah
what part
specification sequence
specification okay something is wrong n
[ __ ] uh string
pair okay begin position end
position begin position position pair
the first one then position pair the
second one I don't understand what what
what is uh your problem uh CH count
begin position end position oh chart
count that's right chart count begin
position minus end position plus one
that should be
right okay so string take padded
input oh we we you see naming problem
instead of position pair it's p pair
okay let's let's change it to position
pair let's change it to the long
name yeah let's change it to a long long
name okay let's try that
again hope that fix it run it
no something wrong if force force force
okay so there is something
wrong yeah so this
all all we have to do is put that double
at that means apply okay so delete that
actually copy
that paste it here run
it the output is fine but that is a
wrong answer because this output means
only 35
count yeah but uh wait is that actually
correct no it's not correct 467 should
also
count
okay so it's not correct it's only give
you us for 35 and 633 should also count
617 is also so correct so we are like
totally wrong we only get 35
God uh God this is not going so
smooth now you got supposed to be shorty
solution now you got this long ass
[ __ ] and uh by the
simplest method and is still wrong
God now we need to think a something is
wrong some some logic okay some little
Minor error must be
so string you take the string from
padded input
the so line numbers CH count perine so
you see CH per line is wrong so where
does the CH line came from okay let's
re-evaluate because we have so many
intermediate steps we might have [ __ ]
up
something
so okay so let's copy or paste run it
okay so we have line count we have choer
line padded line of
dots choer
line so choer line the padded line of
dots then then we have padded input so
in the padded input remember we pad we
paded with the extra line in the
beginning and extra line in the end we
also padded two extra columns so chop
Line is now Cho line plus two Okay so
so this choer line is actually choer
line +
two okay so you need
that kind of and let's hope this is
correct okay so then you got number of
positions okay so this is number of
positions this this is sharper line what
is that
zero H
what hello I'm glad someone is saying
hello so wait so L count is
11 oh God line count is 11 Cher
line what is CH
line zero that's obviously wrong how can
[Music]
you
what uh we got our input wrong again we
need to do that so let's do that
again that's good
okay line count is 10 CH lines 10 and
this is our padded input this is a
padded Line This is a padded input then
this is the position for each uh then we
need uh this part let's see if
that 467 and
592 now it's better but it's still
incorrect
uh God this annoying so 467 is part of
it correct
because because it has
a because it has a Aster risk okay now
the other result we got is
592 592 is here that is also correct
because because Plus on the upper right
corner that's correct but
however 35 also should be part of it 633
should also be
617 should also be because there's a
character so why so let's see
617 there's a character so why did we
miss that so let's fix that
problem uh so stream
take oh yeah so wait stream
take stream take take no this is wrong
okay so string
take oh yeah string T should be a yeah
so this is wrong and it string T should
be oh this string take is all wrong
string T takes two arguments
so yeah so this is wrong so it should be
two items CH count plus
two uh it should
[Music]
be negative Chon + 2 to and up
to wait wait where do you take the
string string take so what is
uh string take is including the previous
neighbor
string take padded input then you got
two
positions so the first position is
position pair
beginning so that's begin position why
are you doing this idiotic
thing and uh this is in
position
beginning
minus charper
line + two so this should be one thing
minus Cher line +
two then minus one that's
correct uh and the N
position CH line + 2 + one that's right
so xtrem is the
neighboring and also the neighboring
lines
okay
God okay you don't need this so let's
see Xtreme this extreme is is what you
don't
want
yeah so instead of you want
to choper line plus two okay I know what
you want so what I want is previous line
neighbors paded input then take two
string previous line neighbors so
beginning at
beginning at this thing
okay
so take from the chart paded input you
got you need the two numbers here index
and index okay so you start by that
index then you end position is
the
beginning
P minus
one okay that's a previous neighbor
beginning position minus
one God this we are very close an early
happy New Year to you thank you
gash and hello
[Music]
shanu okay we close Okay
so previous line neighbor and next line
neighbor is should be similar
okay uh next line neighbor okay next
line neighbor incl in should be padded
input and
uh
okay two oh yeah so this n position
minus
one okay so the next line neighbor
should be end position + one not minus
one it's
always in
position + one to n position plus
line number characters plus two + one
plus one because of the diagonal okay
so previous neighbor and neighbor then
then you
got then you got next line uh so we
don't need this line then you got
previous
chart CH neighbor so instead of previous
CH let let's just do this
this I don't know what you understand
or previous CH next chart so all you
need to do is to
find okay so previous CH next ch chart
remove okay so instead you just chart
neighbors okay previous chart next CH
remove okay and but you have
uh CH neighbors okay
so previous line neighbor actually we
can
better
so this padded input so beginning
position so from the beginning
position minus CH
line +
2 that's a padded Shar
line okay then minus one because you
want diagonal then actually this
number this
number
plus the number of characters in the the
number of digits so the number of Digit
would be Char count okay Char
count okay that seems to
be what you
want and Char line next line neighbor
will be in position
okay so this is similar so you
want you want so suppose that is correct
then
that okay then you uh that minus
4 uh not minus 4 minus Char count
okay so you get wa
so so in the so because this is tricky
you have to think about it you want to
get a neighbors hello George oh George
you are three hours late you missed all
the fun you missed all the fun you
missed my drunk coding and lots of talk
about wolam
language glad you are here okay
listen to that you know you you missed
my great
marketing of wuf
language uh and lots of other things but
anyway let's back to code I want to
finish this this this day three this
problem get it done
okay uh so that hot dog will not say oh
is just a
thinker shut shut the [ __ ] up Hot
Dog Okay so let's get back to you know
getting
complicated
uh oh by the way oh aren't you wolf uh
George aren't you at the you know on in
the desert so you have you have a cell
phone connection and all that internet
anyway let me finish the
code so previous neighbor uh previous
neighbor previous neighbor is you want
to extract the substring so from the
beginning position minus CH line
the paded chart in minus one yeah and
two two basically that number
Plus
so this you don't want minus one you
want
God CH count plus two
[Music]
so e one + two becomes
three three two is a Char count let's
say so one +
two then plus then plus one so you
want that
position that position plus Char count
Plus two actually so God this is what's
such an annoying tedious
problem so day three you are back okay
so so George you got to do Advent of
code day three you know in this video I
talked about the fancy Solutions one
single regular expression and I talked
about
um you know very fancy Advanced you know
so you have graph Theory there but
anyway Advanced you know heat map and
density plot and bit map bit bit mask
kind of solution so very fancy so you
miss that in the beginning one hour so
anyway but now I'm just like going
through the basic algorithm the most
basic approach to solve this problem
because I want to get the Sol instead of
like because usually I talk a lot of
Advanced Computer theoretical computer
science stuff and people think K can you
actually
code can you do actually can you do one
regular expression so I want to if you
know you know I this I I want to um
actually finish this
problem uh okay so so so uh and is
always have the best JavaScript solution
you know very Advanced so
anyway Advent of code day three okay
George do the Advent of code day three
problem number one and try to yeah did
you do it did you do it I don't think
you did day three okay prob part one try
to do it so anyway so I want to get back
to the code okay so so this and then
you okay so suppose then you then you uh
that do that
okay okay so
now you need to double check we are
almost correct almost done so then next
neighbor uh you
want next neighbor you want to see if
you extract you take a substring from
padded input and
uh and then
you you want to get in position plus CH
count plus
two and position plus CH count that plus
two that gets you to the next line okay
that gets you like to there then plus
one because you want to get the diagonal
and
then and then that's a beginning index
you want to grab
then wait in in position so in position
then not minus ch I
can't uh
okay oh wait
so in position yeah so you want
to so for example this end position you
get to this
point okay you want to minus the CH huh
n minus one
okay yeah suppose the number is
633 then you want to
minus you want to grab starting you you
know you want to grab these five
characters so the position of them
is oh
[Music]
actually you can you can do the
beginning
position
plus name minus two
oh okay that's
simpler
then
wait God this is not so tedious now wait
so next like got to
focus beginning position plus Char plus
two that gets you here then minus
one minus 2 okay now you take now where
do you want to end you want to end with
end
position then you take the end position
plus Charon plus two that gets you here
here then plus
one CH on plus two then plus then just
plus
one
seems so let's double check previous
line beginning
position beginning position position
minus Char + 2 that gets you
there and minus one that's correct then
this part you take the end
position end POS minus Chon plus
two then actually + one so actually +
one and you don't need this CH plus two
so that seems to be please let that
B so but why is
this uh this should be
end end
position minus CH
2 okay so maybe that's it
so this xtram you don't need
anymore so extreme is totally
wrong so neighbors stream take padded
input string take padded input so what
do you take so again two indexes
beginning and end and uh then begin
position minus one and position +
one okay it's Char neighbors that is
that's a character just right is right
to the left or right of the number okay
then if then if or apply to string
contains previous Neighbor Next
neighbor and CH neighbors contain X then
if it does then string take paded input
begin position end position and two
expression okay otherwise zero so let's
hope that's
it okay so you need to so this whole
thing maybe let's
see did we get the answer this is what 4
hours 3 hours a deal [ __ ] [ __ ] the
Advent of code let's see if we got it
right so
467 should be there correct double check
over here 114 is not so 35 it should be
there yes because of
that 617 should be there yes because of
that but 633 should be there because of
that uh that pound sign that number sign
but we don't have
633 we got a bug so this bug happens in
the next line of the number so remember
that something somewhere in the next
next line neighbor is
incorrect oh yeah of course we can fix
it right
away in position plus CH line plus one
okay who told you to plus
two what wait next line
neighbor begin position plus
CH line plus two gets you to the next
line and uh minus one okay should be
minus one my
friend okay and here end
position
beginning position plus the CH comp line
plus 2 minus one you got you need the
diagonal okay then end position plus CH
per line plus two that gets you to the
next line then plus one because you need
the diagonal okay so maybe that will fix
it I'm H I'm kind of tired so but we are
almost done so let's double check again
467 check because of the as risk 35
check because of the as risk
633 check because of
the number
sign 617 check because of the as risk
right to the right of it
592 check because of the plus sign on
the upper right
755 check because of the
asterisk on the lower left
58 is not part of it correct because
there's no symbol neighbors
592 check because of the plus sign on
the upper
right 755 check
664 check because the dollar sign above
it
598 check because of the aster above it
fantastic now let's check the Advent of
code okay we are in day five we need to
go to day
three stupid of then code let's see what
does it say oh it needs it want the sum
okay s it want the stupid sum okay let's
let's let's give it a
sum fantastic our code is one single
line but I just haven't done it yet uh
total okay I'm going to make this code
single line just five minutes I mean
three minut three minutes I can make it
single line okay here is a solution
let's see to
correct okay now it wants the what's
your personal input okay so now let's
just say personal input now let's run
the hole
again okay and now let's clean up first
of all we don't need this confusing
things this is our intermediate
code uh neighborhood stren we don't need
it remove it and whatever this that
remove the whole [ __ ] okay copy so
select all paste this is our entire
input
code run it
4361 okay now all we have to do is we
use our own input okay copy all go here
select all p
run
it okay long input let's see what is the
problem what is the five
53235 are you sure I'm sure you idiotic
[ __ ] that's the right answer of
course okay I finished the problem
that's a fantastic finally after 10
hours struggle to you know to have like
one single regular expression or these
fancy Solutions I spent about 10 10
hours failed uh but now we got it right
okay and now we clean up the code let's
see you see now the code is just it's
just this right it looks long because I
have Long Function let's make it
short you know let's let's make it short
let's okay let's make it short to sting
hot dog
okay Advent of code 2023 day three part
one single
short
shortest Solution on Earth
to thing hot dog okay hot dog is this
guy C coder
now make it one single line shortest
solution
to sting hot dog okay now that's the
what we are going to do so let's copy
that paste it here it's so now we're
going to make this one single line of
code should this solution we don't need
uh let's see how we're going to do I'm
going to show you okay so first of all
you don't need all this uh padded
input okay lots of
uh actually I I can just turn each
variable to a very short variable and
that would be it uh there's a lot to
shorten
then
uh
and meanwhile I wanted to keep it um you
know I can show you how
many lines of code is there okay
so I mean if we count tokens let's see
if we can do
it
hold okay let's let's see if that works
let's see do it do it okay that is the
symbolic expression now let's last
output last output show tree form okay
show it in a tree form so you can
see it shows our solution as a
tree can you see that
beautiful
uh okay so we can actually shrink
it let's copy
it then you know let's put it on Discord
so people get
impressed tree form this you see this is
a
tree uh of uh abstract syntax tree you
know when you mention this phrase all
the all the industrial coders gets
excited you know abstract syntax
tree you know idiotic so now you got so
you see it's a tree form and you
can let me show you okay and you can
count the number of nods in it okay
so
de count okay
uh de de count
okay 159 tokens so basically we our
solution is 159 tokens meaning that uh
actually that's just leave that doesn't
count knots but we can uh we have not
counts do we let's
see uh let's
see
argument count atom count atom count is
what we want okay so let's show you so
we're going to count how many atoms in
this tree I mean how many nods in this
tree so you can just
do uh that's not what we want so output
one0 so output
one0 now atom
count uh
what output one zero argument hold that
that that
that is not a valid molecule oh okay we
don't want atom atom that's is doing
chemistry
so argument count so there's
uh how do you call vertex count Edge
count leave count I forgot so let's
check Leaf count so you go to the
documentation Leaf count gives the total
number of indivisible sub Expressions oh
that indivisible sub Expressions does
that does that include the noots I
forgot but we you know we can try
it you know we can try to see if it
includes sub expression let be C okay
leave count three so that actually
counts the NS because faab for example
we can let me show
you so this expression faab in tree form
is just that very simple so how many NDS
are there three and if you do leaf count
it actually give you three but that's a
bit confusing because Leaf count usually
means you know you don't count
the
you don't count the knots but uh anyway
it's trying
to yeah Leaf count gives the measure of
the total size of an
expression but it also but I mean it
seems confusing
to to say Le because Leaf usually means
it doesn't include
the you know the the nods of a tree but
only the leaves anyway there must be
some way to make sense anyway so our
code is basically
159 tokens okay now I can so if you
rename all these characters to Single
Character variables you got
159 hello uh good way to start a year
with wam hey thank you oh jman oh you
missed the whole show today with we
finish the problem so this is day three
event of code 2023 day three problem one
okay so this is a solution and right now
we are trying to shorten it you know
here is a whole solution so we are
trying to shorten it yeah that will take
10 minutes and uh actually it's very fun
to do but now I've been doing this video
for three three hours already I'm kind
of tired
so to shorten the code the first
brainless thing to do is you just
replace each long variable Name by one
or two characters okay that's like
idiotic but but that doesn't reduce your
Leaf count you
see that doesn't really actually reduce
the actual uh let's remove this error
you see 159 leave count that's kind of
your token number of tokens in your code
so but there are a way there's a lot way
to shorten this code let me show you a
example quickly okay so for example um I
can
is well there's
a you can you can do a syntactical
transform but that doesn't
um so let's for
example so example for example let's
replace the position Pair by just
that okay and
uh and you don't need that
anymore
and okay module so you get this whole
module you don't want the function
anymore you just put
a okay let's see so this will also give
you the
solution for example we already
shortened it we removed
the where is
it
what oh we didn't I thought I created a
new let's undo
okay so we create a new pad let's put it
in wam language so here's a new version
here's the old version the old version
got the function word here and
actually yeah God emx and do you went
back you want to go back back back back
back there so this is
original we kind of shortened it and uh
let's check if it still
works close leave count back to F
language curse
Discord and
uh back here and
uh paste that here same result you see
it works now does this new solution
reduce the leave count let's see
okay so let's copy the whole
thing so before we
have uh what's the Lea count 159 okay so
now let's see
hold paste it here and now let's
do leave
count
what
167 what hey wait we copy the wrong code
[ __ ]
yeah let's try
again no it doesn't change the leave
count yeah so it doesn't so Leaf count
is very smart it
doesn't if you reduce the
expression by changing them to a to the
equivalent syntactical shortcuts that
does not actually change the leaf count
even though your number of characters
has reduced but it still doesn't change
the leaf count very smart this wolam
language thing very smart
so to truly shorten the code code you
actually you want to remove variables
let's let's just do it oh God this is
uh so where is line count used line
count is not even
used line count is not used
what
oh yeah so we don't need line count
anymore so choer
line there so we don't need that and uh
padded line of
dots yeah so it occurs twice here and
here you can remove it of
course
uh there's a lot wait are you so are you
are people still interested I finished
the problem so six people do you guys
like me
to finish the shortening of this whole
thing I can shorten it
to to I can reduce at least 50 token
okay uh wait 50 are you sure
yeah so I can reduce it to less than 200
characters okay the whole thing it it
can but are you guys interested
otherwise um that's it for
today say it okay say it in one
minute meanwhile let me just
try because usually you see
when you want to reduce the number of
characters so the number of it will be
nice oh
okay you're giving me more work but let
me
explain so doesn't matter in what
language okay once you WR the solution
or coding some
problem and uh you see the number of
lines of account is usually not your
concern or you know the shortest number
of uh the shortest code is not your
concern
because instead of shortest code the
criteria is
maintainability efficiency of the
algorithm efficiency of the code and
maintainability and readability of the
code okay that is your criteria in
general and the tness of the code is
usually not not a good criteria for for
real life coding okay but however in a
competition or in Advent of a code you
know the shortest number of lines or
shortest number of characters you know
that is a dramatic dramatic winning
point
so but the problem is that if you do
that now if I you know right now I'm my
code is reasonably maintainable you know
it's it's pretty good it's a bit
redundant somewhere but it's pretty good
okay but if I now try to make it
shorter you know I'm trying to I'm going
to get my you know I'm going start
to uh use
my expertise of wolam language and make
it shorter you know like code
go what I will achieve is the winning
point of drama right because Advent of
code you know I post on Twitter look
this is the shortest code in the world
by number of characters or by number of
uh tokens right people will impressed
but the result is usually not good you
know after after a few months I look at
the code it's
like uh it will be less readable so my
point I mean the the point I'm trying to
explain uh is that the shortest of a
code thing is usually is not a good
thing unless you know you are in some
code uh code Golf and Such Thing usually
I uh don't like it so
anyway let's get on okay let's you know
again I'm starting to talk a lot so
let's get this code to be the shortest
number of tokens or shortest number
leave count because that is the most
important not the character count
because character count I can simply
change it to two variable you know
shorten the variable names and so on so
that's not good also syntactical change
in wol language you have this
syntactical equivalence like I did here
so I reduce like 10 characters here but
the token count the Lea count is exactly
the same because wam language knows you
are just changing the syntax but but
your code is actually exactly the same
it doesn't change so it wins a point to
people who don't know wam language
but not to people who actually you know
actually measure your um expression
tness but anyway so let's let's try to
um get
this so CH count actually we don't need
do we ever need CH count actually you
see we don't need this variable so CH
count it's not used so delete CH count
deleted so we shorten that select
all select
all so remember before it's
169 now let's
see
hold
paste uh it's it's kind of getting late
I so now leave
count 144 you see I you see we have
redundant variables there so now it's
144 saved
like uh 20 also almost 30 charact count
uh knots okay let's see next position
pair
uh
you can also shorten it because for
example let me show you these two lines
would be equivalent to uh let me show
you okay beginning position so you
assign them in parallel
okay
so these two lines now you can do like
that let's see if that
works I'm pretty sure it
does
it's
okay are you telling okay you're missing
a semi
colon yeah it works you see that works
and in fact you don't have to assign
variables here you can just assign them
here so let's do
that equals to
that and position equals to that so you
don't need that
anymore okay and the previous neighor
characters you can
also so we can shorten this a lot by a
lot
actually uh CH
line CH line came from is a global
variable uh plus two you know we can we
can simplify the arithmetics here plus 2
minus one
um previous
neighbor so where is previous neighbor
used okay next neighbor okay for now
let's just let's
just jman ch thank you how much is that
worth what kind of money is that1
,000 oh my God that's a big one but what
kind of what is that is it Japanese Yen
or what how big is
that
uh close okay we are very close so let's
see where do I want to put this let's
put that
here so we can Define them you know
assign the value in line instead of in
the body of the module you see the
module thing is like
um the module thing you see this
module thing is like is like Lis slet
okay it allows you to define local
variables so module takes two
expressions one is the list of variables
and their value
possibly and uh
uh cop what what is
dollar I have to find
out so uh so this previous live line
neighbor yeah we don't need that
anymore and the next line neighbor this
is just one single
line next line neighbor we don't need it
anymore and put this whole
thing equals to that you
see then Char neighbors we can also
assign to the whole assignment
here okay so now if we copy this and
paste it
here ah we got something wrong
[ __ ] oh
God uh when you get something wrong it's
headache
because uh what stream take sequence
specification because then you got
[ __ ] up
because
so how did we [ __ ]
up why is
this yeah God I hate
that previous line neighbor next line
neighbor begin
position end position previous line
Neighbor Next sign
neighbor okay and uh Char neighbors
equals
to paded input begin position end
position oh yeah because I know what's
going on
because because in wolam language it
does not
allow when you use module which which is
like Lis SL you know you have a bunch of
variables
the each value of the variable if you
give it a value it doesn't know the
value of previous one so in here because
the near the Char neighbors it
uses begin position which is defined
here but it doesn't know what is the
value of the begin position
position
uh because you know you have to in so
instead you have to Define it in the
body but in this case let me let me do a
trick okay so in this case because the
beginning position and end
position we only actually use it once so
we don't actually we use it more than
one time
okay
okay so we use it more than one time
okay so let's let's move it outside then
okay
so there okay so copy that and uh select
that paste run
it what
the
what's
wrong
what oh again you see we are using
beginning position and end
position you see that is a problem okay
so
well so what we can do is that we okay
so this
is
annoying
yeah
okay uh so what are you going to do so
you know the problem is that you see
this beginning
position is used here is used here so
you cannot in the same lead block
because the latter variables doesn't
know the previous variables value so so
what you can do is you have to move this
line outside you know into the
body uh yeah we can do that but our goal
right now is to shorten the code so what
are
the some of the ways to uh shorten more
of the code actually there's a
lot
oh
see convert this this demo this wolf
from language let's see if that
works
$2 okay not not too bad uh not to that
what what kind of dollar is
cop is
that is that somewhere in
Africa okay so
we so okay so we you know we so how do
you shorten this small okay so I mean
I'm kind of tired so I'm kind of tired
so because right now I'm just I'm not
really thinking there's so many other
ways to show
yeah I think that you know I I that that
should be it we how how long has it
been six
people started at 6:00 it's almost 4
hours okay thank you guys thank you
jman uh and who else is still here thank
you guys for watching this is a long one
so you
can maybe watch offline thank you guys
bye guys yeah my wife needs to come back
uh she she's you know in the living room
she needs to come back in sleep