Good morning. Good morning everyone. Uh
welcome to another episode of talk show.
We are going to uh do miscellaneous
programming language design issues on
string and unic code.
String and unic code. And uh if you are
watching this offline, play at speed
too. If you are here, say hi in the
comments. Okay. So we talk we're going
to talk about unic code and programming
language design involving strings. Uh
for example some programming language
they are string is bytes some of them
are
code units some of them are uni code
characters also known as code point. So
very interesting issues. So first of all
let me introduce my keyboard. So this is
ultimate hacking keyboard. UHK80.
This is Nia Trackable. Fantastic. My
favorite mouse. China cheapo. And this
is Logitech uh classic Logitech G502.
Okay, let's go to my uh my screen. So,
[clears throat]
search for XR keyboard blog. You will
find my keyboard review. So there it is.
Ultimate hacking keyboard 80 on my
website kasardi.info.
http no s. And uh there's a YouTube uh
video review unboxing and a review. Each
one is one hour.
And uh you can see on my keyboard blog
there is lots of huge amount of
ergonomic keyboards. Uh each one has a
video review. Glove 80, Kinesis 360,
Kinesis Advantage 2. Uh each one of
these I've been using for almost three
years. So Kinesis Advantage 2 I've you
I've been using for five years every day
on live stream. Glove 80 in past three
years every day. Uh Kinesis 360 I
haven't used regularly, but there's a
review I did one hour long. And uh also
uh expose night fantastic I've been uh
used for several months I think live or
a year. Um so these are fantastic
keyboard reviews. Okay. Just search for
Kasali keyboard.
You will find my website kasali keyboard
guide. Okay. There are like 1,000
articles. And for the mouse, you go down
track ball. So here are the best track
balls. Track balls are better than mouse
most of the time.
Excuse me. I got a cold over uh
Christmas days. Then I smoke too much.
So, I'm quitting smoking
now. Uh, so anyway, back to track ball.
So, these are the best track balls. And
the one I'm currently using is this this
one, Nia M505,
China cheapo. One one of the China
cheapo since like 10 years ago, China
keyboards and mouse and track balls,
they are taking over. They are in
general. For example, these are the best
track balls. Okay, Nia. This is another
one from Nullia. Okay, so if you buy
Logitech or other well-known brands, for
example, this uh Kensington expert or
the
or the uh sling blade also from
Kensington, they are like $100 or $90.
Okay. All the Japanese brand Elicon. Uh
I forgot how much is sacon but anyway
but for if you buy the Chinese ones
usually like they don't have a brand
name like the brand name changes like
they they are several exactly the same
thing but different brands. Okay. So
anyway, Nulia ch I call them China
cheapo.
They are half the half the price of the
comparable
uh
named brand name ones. Half the price
and they are good. good enough. In fact,
so uh China cheapo, they've been taking
over not just not just on uh trackboard
but uh keyboards for example keyboards
lots of these uh Apple maker that's from
China I believe or Taiwan.
Key move is from China. Apple maker name
plum is from China. Uh H
HHKB happy hacking keyboard that's from
Japan. That's a classic base one. Now,
Kron is a USA brand. Bloody is from uh
uh Taiwan or China. I forgot which.
So, anyway, so that's digression into
keyboard and mouse.
So, but let's go back to our main topic.
Okay, the main topic I want to talk
about is about programming language uh
and unic code. Okay, so close that. Uh
yeah, let's talk about that now. Uh am I
live? Yes. So if you are here, say hi.
Okay, I got six people watching. So
we're going to talk about Unicode. So
it's all programming stuff. Now when um
every half an hour, my alarm clock
beeps. Hold on a second.
So, it's a good thing to set your alarm
clock to beep every 30 minutes because
every 30 minutes you should get up and
walk. If you are a heavy computer coder
like me, okay? Doesn't matter what you
do. every 30 minutes just get up for 1
minute just go to uh the bathroom uh get
your coffee whatever.
Okay. So if you are younger you can set
it to one hour but you know you you need
to get up. So every time so every every
hour or two I get up and take walk
around with my iPad.
So I take notes. So these are the
changes I need to do. So uh you know I
take screenshots and notes. Okay. Oh, I
forgot to introduce my uh my tablet. You
see this is fantastic device. Okay.
Tablet. You can use it as a mouse. And
you can see if you want to know about
tablet there is also here. So my
keyboard block keyboard block. You go
down there's a track ball mouse pen
input. So all kind of pen input devices.
The one I have is this one
H640P.
Okay. It works great. Fantastic.
Okay. So, so, so I take notes. So, I'm
just going to work on my notes. Let me
tell you as I work on them, you will
learn about Unicode. You about You'll
learn about um Unicode. What is code
point? What is UTF8
encoding? What is UTF16 encoding? What
are code unit? Uh fairly complex. Okay.
So let's see. Let's go to the beginning
summary. So what I want to do here Julia
and Okay. So let's skip that for now.
This is very interesting. So let me tell
you about this. So let's um JavaScript.
Okay. This can you can see in
JavaScript.
So these are all my programming articles
about JavaScript um UTF8. So in coding
you can learn if you are impatient don't
watch this video just learn everything
on just search for unic code. So let's
begin let me show you this kasali unic
code search
kasar unic code search you'll find my
website. Okay that one. Now you go there
and you can type
f i r e. As you type the character shows
up like f i r e. So these are all unic
codes whose name contains the word fire.
And you can make it show
the character name. You see this is
triagram for fire. That's one of the
China triang ba or tai kind of the
inyang symbols in Chinese and this is
Chinese uh character radical for fire
and this is Chinese character for fire
and and Chinese character for fire in
parenthesis usually that's used by Japan
[ __ ] Japan Japanese Japanese also use
Chinese characters so you can see then
there's a fire character Chinese in a
circle that's usually used in Japan
Then you got fireworks, you got hexog.
So before you have triagram, then uh now
you have hexog. Hexog is um
interesting. So you got six bars. Each
bar can either be a whole line or break
broken into two lines or sometimes
three. So you got comb notorial
um issue. Okay. So anyway, these are all
characters. Uh then there's a fire
emoji. There's a fire engine truck.
There is uh oncoming fire engine.
There's a alchemy symbol for fire. Oh,
that's interesting. The fire cracker,
cracker, and the fire exting
extinguisher. Okay, so unic code names.
Each character has a name. Unicode is a
standard for all the words, symbols, and
characters for all human languages. You
can, for example, the most well-known
today is emoji. starting from past 15
years but it contains all
characters the writing symbols of all
human history
[clears throat]
including dead languages. Okay. So for
example we looking at ar Arabic writing
system which is used in Arabic uh
languages and also Persian and uh you
know and also it was used for Spanish
um very interesting okay so then you got
of course you got Chinese characters
then you also got let me show you some
interesting ones okay there's a hero
herogly from Egypt
Okay. So, very interesting. And uh one
thing I want to show I I talk about this
many times. You know, they have like
characters for breasts, tits, and they
also have characters for penis, but
Microsoft censored it. They don't
provide a font, but it shows if you are
using a Mac. Uh and I'm not sure about
the Google's font whether they censor
these these characters. Okay. So, you
can see a picture of it uh if you scroll
down. So you e Egyptian characters they
are, you know, very interesting. If you
go all the way down,
you can see a picture of those censored
characters there. You see penises. Okay.
So you got Egyptian, then you got of
course you got uh lots of um Egyptians
uh Tamil, which is uh po uh language
used in South Asia.
Indonesia, Malaysia, Singapore kind of
like that and also in India, Sri Lanka
very interesting unic code. Okay. So all
entire human animals writing system
symbols
including historical ones and you got
also got uh very interesting ones such
as for example let me show you some the
earliest one. So ancient ones. So you
got Hero Gly life from Egypt. Then you
got um Rome from about year 500 to
uh year 100 uh
uh 1500.
So western white men are obsessed with
this wrong character. You often see
nerds, you know, on their keyboard key
caps that you can buy actually run key
caps. Do I have a photo of it? Uh, let's
see here. So,
so this is Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 60.
I [snorts] also have a review and I
think I believe I live streamed with it
for several months or maybe a year. I
forgot. Oh. Oh, for for actually five or
seven years because I use it as a key
mark uh keypad. Okay. So, that's
Ultimate Hacking 60.
So you see they put wrong characters key
caps on it because uh you know this is
the wrong characters are associated with
a history of western Europe kind of like
kind of like the white men German people
and United Kingdom English people it's
part of their history
um run characters okay I didn't know
before because I thought where are They
you know you know I I live in USA so
mostly I'm in contact with the white men
my co-workers or whatever I'm in
California but so often I often I see
you know where are they like often talk
about run or show for example another
interesting thing we're going to talk
about today for example Goland
[clears throat] so you look at my go
language tutorial which is one of the
best programming language Okay, don't
use C. Don't use C++. Now, if you are a
young person, you have if you are study
programming programming languages, don't
do C, C++. Don't just like don't even
learn them if you are begin beginning
beginning your career. Okay? Pick
something and stick. So, because you're
going to move on, you're going to in the
p in the next 10 20 years. Okay? Don't
follow you know whatever on 4chan those
idiots saying that you got to use you
know like the industrial standard like
the most common game programming C++ or
C for Linux kernel whatever don't do
that learn Golan okay Golan is far
better for the like and also Golan is
very popular extremely popular in fact
like like basically as popular as C C++
in the same category of popularity.
Okay.
In fact, I think it's even more popular
than Rust. Rust is another like very
fashionable today. So, Goland. So,
Goland, you can see Goland actually they
have a character type. So, you go to
string. So, character type they but but
they don't call it a character type.
They call it run. You see it's funny.
the Goland people, Rob Pike and others,
you know, most famous famously known as
uh as the created by Rob Pike. Actually,
there are two or three guys who
co-created it, but Rob Pike is one of
the most famous character who um who
also created UTF8,
the
[clears throat]
encoding system UTF8. Okay, we're going
to talk about today. So go language they
have a character type but they don't
call it character type they they just
call it run okay very funny what is run
run it's just a unic code character type
character okay but they call it run so
that's a type so so so that um so that's
why I'm saying that this you know the
white people so-called you know the
phrase is very popular in USA since
about 2015
rise of the social justice warrior
movement, you know, they they talk about
white men, white men all the time. So
the white man basically it technic
technically it means took me a long time
to actually learn. It doesn't mean white
people with white skin, okay? Like the
Russian the Russian or the Bellarus or
the Ukraine, they are the whitest white.
Okay, the white girls, they are the most
beautiful. But when you say white man
that actually not them. Okay. Very
interesting. Took me like I learned it
the hard way. So like white men this
kind of so it's kind of like usually
actually the core of the like the phrase
white men actually means Germanic
people. German people from Germany and
UK because German people moved to UK
back then like 500,000 years ago.
So they are both Germanic like according
to their blur line to their DNA. So as
far as I personally understand those are
the white men. Okay. British people,
English people and the German Germanic
people which by the way are the most
white people in USA because their
ancestry if you take you know you can
look at the USA census USA by the USA
government the white people the or
white-kinned people their ancestry in
USA are mostly from Germany
or the uh England. Okay. So, so the
white man today is like the USA, you
know. So, anyway that, so, so I was
talking about the run. So, that's uh
kind of part part of the white man
history. So, you can also see that by
for example, there is this very popular
novel uh loved by nerds. The toolken,
okay, Tokyen, the trilogy, the two
towers, the ring, you know, the ring,
one ring to ru rule them all. Okay. I
actually never liked it that that movie.
No, the I I really wanted to like it
because that's you know the nerds will
talk about it. For example, let me give
you two characters very famous
characters in programming industry who
loves the Tokyian trilogy.
One of them is Eric Eric Raymond. Okay.
E uh E R I C K. Wait, E R I C or E R I E
R I C. Okay.
Eric S. Raymond, very famous guy. He
wrote the bazaar and the cathedral. You
know, he's one of the guy who pushed who
found co-ounded open source. Okay. He's
so well known. You know, he pushes for
Unix, Unix philosophy. He wrote several
books and pushes for open source and so
on. Okay. He's kind of like very
questionable
person, a very questionable man in my
opinion. But he he's a great coder.
Okay. And so he's one of the he so he
loves the run the
so the he loves the uh the
that that trilogy token. Okay. So, let
me type it out since I'm I'm I'm
starting to like ramble over. Okay, we
haven't talked about Unicode yet. So,
Tolkien um you know the Tokian
Jr. RR Tolken he is a ling ling linguist
as well. So, Lord of the Rings the
people you know these people love it.
So, when I was younger like 20 30 years
ago I really tried to read it that
didn't really like it. Okay. And also
there's a movie, you know, about about
this.
But however, by the way, I love token.
So I but I love a similar
uh long novel that's called um Game of
the Thrones.
Okay. So uh actually, so let me just
show you let me show you my my web page.
Okay. So we talked about Golan and we
talked about let's go to search. Uh
actually you can search there. Okay. So
actually
game of the
uh t h r o n e. That's king's chair.
Do I have it? Does it find my page? No,
it doesn't because it's um Yeah, let's
not show it. Okay. King of the throne.
Okay. So,
uh, Game of the Thrones. Oh, I mean, I
forgot. Game of the Thrones. Okay. Not
King.
Uh. [laughter]
[clears throat]
So, what uh what guys you are saying? Do
Unicode support man languages like
Klingong? No. Unfortunately, Klingang is
another
so-called constructed language or
artificial language, but a lot nerds
love. But Unicode do not have special
characters for cling. That's one of the
kind of uh people complain but uh it's
not there. But however, people has made
font for cleaning that you can download
that maps to the special use area of
Unicode. Okay. So, you can you you
search it, you'll find it. Okay. Now,
Kasali Game of Life, they Game of
Thrones. Okay. I I wrote some blogs
about it. This I love Game of Thrones.
Okay.
I never watched the TV show, you know,
because I don't have money to, but I
watched all the clips like hundreds of
clips of Game of Thrones and also the
fan website. So fan website usually they
have detail like the story which
character you know what he did uh the
the full story of the series and maps of
the places you know different worlds
different islands different kingdoms you
know Game of Thrones I love this this
this uh this novel this show and also
the the the TV program is fantastic.
So, Game of Thrones, they have dragons.
They have kind of these monsters. They
have dro They do they have dwars? Um,
well, this guy is a dwarf. Okay. But,
but I was thinking about a dwarf race.
But anyway, they have dragons, they have
kings, they have swords, fights, they
have knights, they have queens, they
have, you know, incest, they have, you
know, and lots of fights, knights, uh,
and the sorcerers and these kind of
monster, the ice, the ice dragon, you
know, the kind of monster race and, uh,
fairy tales and giants. They have
giants. They have this is a sorcerer
great story. Okay, they got dragons.
They got this queen and mythical powers,
you know, she can she she can, you know,
stand in fire.
Uh, so fantastic story, okay, in swords
fight. [cough and clears throat]
Love it. Now, but the the Lord of Rings
trilogy. Okay. So, let's look at some
movie stuff. Lord of the Rings.
Okay. So, let's look at images.
So you also got monsters and dwarf race
and elves race and this ring the magical
powers and that that but I don't like
it. I like I I find I find it I don't
like it. I you know this this this
dro I mean this kind of like cute
village character. What's their name? I
forgot. It turns me off. Okay. And
especially the movie, the guy, you know,
this guy, I look at him, this bunch of
like he got some brothers or friends
like idiots. And this ring, idiotic
ring, and you got this ring, you know,
the the monster that what's the name?
You know, grabbing the ring. It's like
ugly, [ __ ] offensive. And then you
got this like sorcerer, like two
sorcerer sorcerers fighting each other.
One of one of them, the good guys is
called um uh
you know the the the good guys the
uh at uh DAFF something. Wait, so you
guys help me. Okay. What what's the
what's the good sorcer you know? And you
know then you got this elf race, you got
dro race, then you got the ugly monster
race. You um Gandalf. Yeah, Gandalf is
the is the uh the good sorcerer on the
good side. Okay, Gandalf, I think. So,
and and that's like stereotypical story
like [ __ ] boring [ __ ] idiots.
Okay, I don't like this and the eyes of
the Sauron. They're [ __ ] [ __ ]
You see, both of them are like meth like
kind of f fantasy stories. But I I truly
I love the Game of Thrones. But when but
but this Lord of the Rings I I find
myself I can't I don't I don't like it
at all, you know. Then then you got this
of course you got this uh wait
uh uh images game of the Lord of the
Rings. Okay. Oh, do they have a new
movie in theaters 2026?
So look at the images. Okay. So you got
this uh then you got this um
idiotic. Okay. I don't like it at all.
So that's interesting. So
you know even though both of them are
like about uh like fantasy uh kind of
genre.
Okay.
So I digressed over. We we can't finish
this talk. It take another one hour.
Okay. So, let me go back to like the
programming and unic code stuff. Okay.
Are we done about Yeah. So, I was intro
so go back to Unicode. So, I was like
introducing to you guys some of the
Unicode characters. Okay. So, we talked
about run which is a thousand years ago.
But Phoenician this is what this is like
the earliest alphabet. this Phoician
from uh 3,000 years ago is where the
English alphabet came from. So English
back to Latin and Latin back to Greek
and Greek back to Phoenician. Okay. So
that's this character set in Unicode.
Okay. Uh then you got Cooney form. This
is even earlier but this is not like the
origin source of English alphabet. This
is like 5,000 years ago. Kuniform. Okay.
5,000 years ago. It's, you know, so this
is like the origin of human writing
system. The earliest
uh is this absolutely the earliest? I I
think so. Wait. Yeah.
Okay. So, they are etched in stone. I
love these. Okay. So, these are unic
code of course. And you got linear B.
Linear B is uh about uh 2,500 years ago.
Okay, linear B.
And part of it, linear A uh part of it
is undeciphered. Okay, like we don't
know what it means yet. Okay, that's
some of the examples of Unicode run. And
other interesting things are shavian
alphabet. This is constructed alphabet
to fix the English lousy spelling
system. So this is a phonetic alphabet
for English created by the very famous
like uh writer um
George Bernard
Shaw. Okay. Although I don't actually
know his work like I don't I haven't
read any of his work. So anyway, it's
English phonetic alphabet.
envisioned by George Bernan Shaw but
created after he died by uh his
foundation like by a competition. So
anyway there's that then there is desire
alphabet that's another phonetic
alphabet for English. Now this is also
interesting because in particular it
came from it's associated with the
religion moments
which is has a very colorful history
among Christianity in America. That's
right Gandalf. Thank you Kuba.
So you got this desire created by
moments
and which is also phonetic alphabet. So
they so you don't have all the bad
spelling lots of problems in English. So
so with phonetic alphabet you pronounce
words as it is written. So it becomes
much simpler and systematic. Anyway
desire alphabet is not too well designed
um because they they got several issues
and anyway they are not uh they died
basically they they never got picked up.
Uh and similar is the situation with
Shavian
you know you you still you like you if
you search online you might find some
fan clubs okay but basically it's also
uh dead nobody is using it
okay so these are phonetic alphabet for
English okay then uh then we got Tamil
which is part of the Indian language
okay then okay so I'm showing you just
some interesting things about Unicode.
Okay. Now, uh let's go back to I want to
talk about um let's do some coding.
Okay. Let's start to do some coding. Uh
can't char in stream. So, so let me go
to my blog and
so if you go to kasadi.org I mean
kasadi.info.
This is kxali.info.
You go down, you go to the program
programming blog. You can see these are
the things I've done. Uh like just today
and yesterday. Okay. Go. Okay. I need to
fix something there. So, open that page.
Uh print. Search for print. Uh search
for print.
Yeah, that's a mistake. You see that
an order list got a extra
uh tag. So that's why
that's why you are seeing this kind of
thing. Now refresh. Now it's fixed. Now
when I show this in browser, it
automatically does a validation. You can
see HTML XML valid. And that is done by
uh wait
uh
what
describe key press
this key and done by this command HTML
validate. We wrote this one uh two years
ago also live. So it fantastic. validate
a file HTML file or entire directory. So
if I have
for example P remove remove the
beginning tag show in browser go back
you can see error
buffer block.html HTML closing tag P at
position that does not match last open
tag. Okay. Position. So you can jump to
you can go to um so go to SH it'll jump
to that position. You see so it can also
do the entire directory. So let's do
that. So the key is press press which
directory this directory do it. There
are a thousand files in that directory.
So done validating HTML XML at directory
that no error. Okay. So we so you can
watch that we we cod it live about two
years ago. Just search for validate uh
HTML on my YouTube.
Okay. No comments guys comments. Okay.
So I've been talking so this is going to
be long. So I want to do start to do
some coding. So, so go to my programming
block and you go down
uh so so
this uh count char in string
I want to make some changes and let me
show you why. Okay, let's let's just go
to JavaScript
and uh and go to the directory and
search count
uh
search for length.
Okay, so let's increase that.
So, JavaScript string real length. So,
show in browser. So this is a function
to actually return the actual number of
unic code characters in string. Like you
might be wondering why is that? So let
me show you.
So if you have this you run it a
butterfly. So this butterfly is um is
unic code of course its name is
butterfly code point 129 419 and if you
run it length is two that's because
JavaScript is like quite [ __ ] [ __ ] up
and this is also true in Java and in C
you see so this is we are starting to
talk about programming language
design iss issues of a string. So basic
so the reason for that is in um okay so
I have to uh explain the reason for
that. Okay big fan thank you guys keep
the comments coming uh I want to learn
Linux search my website you have like
basic Linux by command line tutorial
kasali.info info, search for it, you'll
find it. Okay. So, so JavaScript the
reason it is Okay, let me explain that.
So, uh,
so let me explain why is the butterfly a
single character but is why is the
length two? Okay. So you you go to uh go
to my unic code uh go to my unic code
and go to the top unic code search and
here oh yeah we were showing so you can
type fire or you can type w a ter
and you can uh w a ter
wat okay so you can remove let's Say
remove this CJK. So you can say minus
minus CJ K.
Okay. What about this parenthes also
minus edograph
minus ID EO. Oh then you got some more
then you got a minus anyway. So
[laughter] so anyway so you can show the
character name you can show the ID. Now
each every each and every unic code has
a id okay that is the u
um
that is a integer okay starting from
zero you can also show the hexadimal
so that is the hexadimal of the the ID
so the ID character ID is called code
point okay if you are programmer this is
critical
every Uni unic code character has an ID.
It's a integer starting from zero. Zero
is actually the new character. Okay. So
character ID and character ID is called
code point. That's just the way they
call it. Okay. Code point just a
character ID. Okay. Then uh you can also
show so then you have UTF8 encoding. You
can show that and you can also show uh
UTF16 encoding. [snorts] So every
character what are encoding? Encoding
means you want to turn the character
into bytes because programming
everything is one and zero.
Each one and zero is called one bit.
Eight of them like 0 0 0
or one one one or one zero you know
eight of them is eight bits.
Eight bits is known as one bite. Okay,
one bite is eight bits. Okay, and and so
that's what computer we deal with byes
and bits. So, uh character encoding is a
way to turn any character
basically convert the to map the
character ID into bytes. Okay, so there
are several character encodings. UTF8 is
the most well-known and UTF16 is another
very well known and there are others
others before unicode like like Chinese
ones. Okay.
So
okay so here we know understand the
concept of encoding so we covered so
let's go down the so there it there it
is unic code for programmers open that
so you learn about unic code character
set encoding UTF8
and code point and basically you already
know about them character set is just a
set of all characters like we talked
about like the linear B coia form that's
a character set
character set run is character set
shaven alphabet tamil uh characters so
all of these together is the unic code
character set unic code is the the
character set includes all human animals
languages and symbols including
punctuations or numbers or whatever or
even all emoji. So that's a unic code
character set. It contains it tries to
contain everything historical or not.
Okay. So you got character set then you
got um let's let's go
uh where is it unic code for programmer.
So so you understand character set.
Okay. Then you understand encoding. So
character set including math symbols or
trademark sign or copyright sign or
heart or bullet punctuation or right
arrow or or French quote or the ninia
the accent characters you know so that's
all part of that's all characters in
unic code okay then what is a character
encoding encoding is to turn a character
into binary bits okay so there are many
uh there's UTF8 there's UTF-16 seen
there's GB18030
in used in China and there's EU used in
Japan there's ASI as ASKI is like before
unic code you know all these are
basically all before unic code so anyway
in uni code it defines a few of them one
of them is UTF8 and UTF6 remember
encoding okay this is about encoding
which means turn a character into ones
and zeros binary ary number. Okay, in
other words, it's basically turning a
integer into one and zero by a by a map.
Okay, you you because each character is
identified by a character ID. So then we
talk about character ID. Okay, so uh
encoding system uh unic code. Okay,
Unicode is a standard that created a set
of these um character set you know this
these definitions. Okay, so Unicode
character set include includes all human
languages past and present. Okay, and
code point is a character ID. Okay, each
character has a ID. So encoding is
turning that integer map that integer
into a bits into bits. Okay, and every
unicode character has a unique name.
Okay, that's also important. However,
a character may have more than one name
due to uh due to like historical and
backward backward compatibility. So for
example, let me show you some example.
But one thing for sure is that given a
name, it's always a unique character.
Okay? So this is known unicode character
name. But a given character may have
more than one uh name. For example, I
can show you uh for example the um
you know the
the form feed you see this invisible
character that represent a new line. Now
in EMAC we call describe character to
show this panel. So you can see it's
called 10 hexodimal is a and this
character
in in old unic code standard unic code 3
is called line feed. Okay. But the new
version they don't they don't give this
character they they don't have a name
for this character. So that so it means
this character it you know the the name
changed. But however the line feed
always refer to this this character.
Okay. So that's that's that's character
name.
So then okay. So then then we need to
talk about uh encoding. Okay. ASI
characters. So when we talk about line
feed like these characters they are part
of the asy as before unic code. Okay.
ASI character set is basically just 128
of them. This is all basically that's
all the symbols you see on your
keyboard.
Okay. Then um so here is asky characters
character ID in hexadimal
representation. There's a abbreviation
for each one. So zero is a character
known as new. And then you got unic code
symbols to represent the character new
character. Then you have also character
notation and c escape syntax. [laughter]
C escape syntax. That's the worst [ __ ]
Okay. So for example, if we go back to
the back slashn everyone is familiar
with in almost every programming
language that's character ID 10 known as
line feed back slashn
as you know in c string escape okay
so that's asky okay so
what I want to talk about is so we will
um
ask go back So,
so let's talk about so UTF8 encoding.
Okay. So, let's talk about UTF encoding.
Again, remember it's a map from
characters. Each character is mapped to
binary digits. Okay. Now, in UF 6 UTF16
encoding, each character is mapped
either to two bytes or four. Two or
four. Okay.
So for characters whose character ID is
less than 16 bits
then that character's UTF16 encoding is
two bytes. Okay. But if the character's
ID is more than 16 bits
which is two raised to 16. Okay. If that
ID is more than that then that
character's UTF16 coding is four bytes.
Okay, one bite is six uh one by is eight
bits. Okay, am I confusing?
Okay, so so so
in in summary in UTF16
encoding each character may be two bytes
or four. Okay, two or four. So that that
is when in JavaScript you started to
have this idiocy.
You see this butterfly becomes true.
Why? Because in because the butterfly
you you know if you know you want to
know the character ID the character ID
is this 1 2 3 uh I mean 129 419 in
hexadimal it's
f 98b
now
if you compute you know is this number
bigger than 16 bits that is 2 raised to
16 It is you know we can we can uh show
it.
So this number - 2 raised to 16.
Let's see it that's Python. So it is
indeed bigger. So we can also do it like
is uh like right true. So this character
ID is bigger than 16 bits. Therefore in
UTF-16
it it is it has four bytes not two four.
But in JavaScript a string is made of
uh so-called
code unit which is two bytes. So it
counts bytes. You know every two byte is
one index. Okay. So every two bytes two
bytes two bytes is one index. So when
when you ask for the length of this
character which is four bytes it counts
two bytes each every two bytes is called
code called code called code called code
called code code unit. So it counts like
two. So you you got two. So this is a
major [ __ ] to JavaScript
string design major. Okay. This also
happens in Java and other languages
which I can show you in this um this
guac answer. Okay, this guac answer
which programming language has code unit
as its its string index. Okay, so it
shows you like Java, JavaScript
you see and C I mean C and others. But
however this this mo this um
the
that does not mean all these languages
are bad just some of them
because in the case of JavaScript
you know JavaScript has lots of um let
me show you this page okay so let's go
to JavaScript now you go to uh so this
all about JavaScript strings okay so you
go to JavaScript string string.prototype
which is all the string methods. Okay.
So you can see so string.prototype you
got you got uh you got slice substring
subst str they are different because
JavaScript sucks very bad. Okay, then
you got add chart add chart code add
code point add very confusing also very
bad because this is old they they
updated with the new function similar
with the slice substring substr they
they should be just one because but due
to baggage you know bad design so they
created a new function that kind of
meant to improve the old one so you
don't use the old one so this this quite
a detail JavaScript is one of the most
comp complex [ __ ] Okay, so you got so
all these are string methods. Okay,
concat string repeat string trim trim
start trim end start uh pad start pad
end and search string index of last
index of includes start with you know so
on and regular expression find and
replace or find match uh and split
string to array and two lower case and
some other minor ones. Okay, so all
these are string methods. Okay, now
here's the problem.
If your string contains a unic code,
let's say emoji, very common today.
All these string methods are fact. Okay,
that's that's how bad it is. There's no
way to deal with them. All these will
wrong will be wrong. I can I can show
you. So, let's say let's I can show you
right away. Okay. Uh let okay let's just
start a new job let's let's uh go to t
today's talk show today's talk show and
uh let's just start a new JavaScript
okay so let's say string ABC I want to
turn it into a array so string split so
split by empty separator okay that will
turn all the characters each one into a
array elements Okay. And uh print it.
Okay. Uh wait.
Okay. Run it. There is there it is the
output. Okay. Now purify the code. Okay.
Now but however if you have a unic code
in it, you're going to be [ __ ] Okay.
So let's try butterfly. So you got a
butterfly there. What is the result?
This is the result. Now what those those
are not valid character those are you
know remember
the butterfly character the character ID
is more than 16 bits. Therefore in UTF16
encoding it has four bytes. However the
JavaScript programming language it
consider string as made of units of two
bytes. So it counts two bytes each. So
when you do this this butterfly becomes
two different things you know this is
this is two bytes this is two byte and
they don't they are not unic I mean they
are not like valid they may not be valid
unic code characters so you got this
like half character half character you
got [ __ ]
now this this nastiness applies to all
JavaScript string method S. Okay. So,
what can you do if you your string
happens to have a smiley? You know, a
lot of people use that or math symbols
or Chinese some rare rarely used Chinese
characters also for bytes. Okay.
Nothing you can do. Basically, you have
to write your own method for each, you
know, each one of these string methods.
Okay. That's how bad they are.
So JavaScript is one of the worst
programming language. Now what about
other languages? Okay, so for example,
guac
it tells you you know many other
languages have this issue. Java,
JavaScript, C, C and also Julia Gollet.
But the question is
in in any of these language if you have
have a string that contains unic code
emoji or other math symbols can the
language process it in the case of
JavaScript the answer is no basically
you have to write your own
method for every of the method okay
now I don't I I don't think there is
even a library to do I mean like a third
party library who does that? I talked to
the JavaScript creator Brenda Ike.
He didn't feel this is like a major
problem. So, you know, uh you can search
my blog, you'll find it, you know, my my
my article about that.
But what about other languages? Do they
have the problem? If you have if your
string is like a lot of emojis,
does your programming languages all the
string operations can they work on them?
That's a question. So for JavaScript the
answer is no. Okay, very bad. Now for
Goland the answer is absolutely yes. You
see even though Goland in Goland Go
language okay they are string
you see in go language when you have
this butterfly character it's considered
four bytes okay so because in Goland
they consider their string is cons is
defined to be a sequence of bytes each
bite is eight bits you know a sequence
of bytes so when you do length of this
we can we can try it okay so let's Um,
pull it back. Okay, copy that. And let's
do a Golan. Okay, paste it. I haven't
coded Golan for a long time. So, go uh
yeah, there's a template. So, you want a
Golan string and uh so there is a string
and let's say length. Uh, now I forgot
how to get the length. There it is.
Okay, fantastic.
and run it. You know this will return
four. Okay, run it.
Uh then undefined. What? Uh I forgot my
goland. Okay, let's go to Goland
tutorial. Let's refresh string. How do
you get the length? uh
rule of string literal. So wait, string
what is a string? String is a sequence
of bytes. Okay. Uh so I explain in
detail and uh string functions len. Oh,
you don't you don't dot you know my
brain is corrupted by Java by
JavaScript. [ __ ] with the dot. Okay.
Really?
You see four
you see so in Goland that is four but
however if you want to
like process unic code character very
easy all you have to do is you turn that
into runs so Golang allows you to turn a
string which is defined a sequence of
bytes into sequence of unic code
characters in other words they turn it
into a so-called slice of runs which
means it it became a dynamic array where
each element is a unic code character.
So you can do that by I don't remember
but I have like I I I've [clears throat]
wrote tremendous about it. Uh print
string by hexad decimal character. Okay
they there uh full detailed account
about string by slice and run slice. So
you want to turn a string into run
slice. Uh what you do is uh there. Yeah.
So we can do that. So copy paste.
So you say you give a type. This is
called casting in this C C++ idiotic
languages. Casting like the the word
does not convey anything. It's like like
cast a uh sword, you know, you're making
a sword. You you you shape it into
from a molten iron to sword. you know
you cast
idiotic. So run is a type. Uh wait this
green run is a type basically just means
a type of character. Okay it's a
character type now you add that
square bracket again that's a C idiots
convention that means this is array of
runs. Okay. Okay. So you put that in
front then then you just say uh uh
delete that link then you just say that
uh so let's say ABC
D E F then you get uh let's just say ABC
butterfly then you just get a array of
length four each one is a character okay
so uh how do you do this I god I haven't
coded golan for a long time.
Can you uh
I think that and the print x array
uh actually in goland they call it
slice. Okay.
So let's name it. Slice basically is
Golan's terminology for dynamic array
just like Python's list or Ruby's list
or JavaScript's array. Okay. So, does
that work? I think so. Okay. So,
yeah, I think so. No.
Uh unexpected literal. So, do we need uh
Okay. How do you do it?
Oh, you need the paren. So you need the
paren here.
Run it.
Fantastic. Okay. So it prints
it prints these four characters. Okay. I
mean those are the code points. So A has
the character ID 97. B is character ID
98. C is 99. And the butterfly is 129
419. How do I know? In Emacs, you do
describe chart. There it is. So you can
see the code point. Fantastic and
beautiful.
Okay. So uh so we explained so browser
we explained this point also known as
character ID. We explained code unit. I
mean we explained UTF-16 encoding where
each character is either two bytes or
four. Then we explained in JavaScript
the string is defined to be a sequence
of two bytes of six UTF-16 encoding. So
you got this weird you know you got this
[ __ ] and there's no way to fix it. So
every time you need to use some string
method you have to write your own. If
your string contain uh emoji. Okay. Now
in Goland
they their string is defined to be a
sequence of bytes not two bytes. Okay.
Just bytes not the code unit whatever
just bytes. So very simple kind of
following from the C convention bytes.
Okay. So when you say length of
butterfly you got four because in UTF by
default actually also they use UTF8
encoding not UTF-16. Okay. Now UTF8
encoding I we haven't explained but
that's um so each character in UTF8
encoding
can become either one by or two or three
or four. It's called variable. So
depending on the character it may be one
bite or two or three or four. So uh we
have an article on that UTF-16 encoding.
You can read about UTF8 encoding. So
open that.
So UTF8 encoding. So a character may
have one or two or three or four bytes.
That's UTF8.
This is this encoding system is also
co-invented by Rob Pike, the guy who
created Golan. Okay. So he's a very
talented you know very talented guy but
yeah but yeah okay so but but so UTF
uh let's see where are we so UTF8 okay
one or one to four bytes per character
now UTF 16 is either two byes or four
two or four
okay
so but now in JavaScript
they uh in JavaScript they define their
string to be
two bytes of UTF-16 encoding
and they there's no way to you know you
got a problem if you you got emoji in it
all the method doesn't doesn't work you
have to write your own okay in goland
each string string is defined to be
sequence of bytes okay just one bite so
butterfly you get four because in UTF8
Eight encoding above butterfly is four
bytes. Okay. But what if you have lots
of emoji you want to process? Easy. Turn
turn it into
a slice of run which means dynamic array
of unic code
uh code points character ID. So that way
you can process all the unic code easily
and efficiently. Okay. So even though
you see so we talking about string the
design of programming language string.
So you know you can see compare
JavaScript with Golan they are very
different. One is sequence of code units
like code units. The other one is just
bytes but in Goland you can you all your
string method can still work
because they accept the run you know the
slice. Okay. So anyway, so but for other
languages that's you know we can look
into I don't know but for example C also
have this just like JavaScript C string
is just like JavaScript but the question
is so if anyone of you call C# tell me
the question is if you have a string lot
of lots of unic code can you actually
use all the functions like
in C like Maybe they they have a way to
deal with it or or or what what's what
what is it? Okay, very interesting. And
also, you know, there's also Go C++ ROS
Python 2. Python 2 is strings are bytes.
But in Python 3, they fix it. They so
they they become each character is just
unicode. Okay. So, I think that's it for
today.
and uh uh and uh I uh kind of you know
actually I have a lot of things I want
to do but we didn't do but anyway we
explained what's going on. Yeah, we
explained uh you know what's going on
with the
syntax design of strings in different
languages and their relation to Unicode
uh how easy it is to deal with and what
not.
Okay. So,
so if you look at my programming
language blog, I have a new article,
programming language design, string bite
versus code unit versus code point. That
is basically what the topic we are uh we
talked about. So I did some summary
there. So we can see of the languages I
know you got goland
what is the string you got JavaScript
you got wam language the string are unic
code characters okay eac the string are
unic code characters powershell string
are unic code characters sequence of
Python string Python 3 string are unic
code characters okay Ruby same thing
pearl uh actually I'm not sure about
pearl I forgot
and F strings are also a sequence of
unic code characters. Okay, that's like
actually that's better because string or
sequence of bites that's basically just
Asian like 40 50 years ago. Okay, that's
it for today. Uh what do you think about
Acme Editor and Plan N? Uh I want to
start to use it. Okay, Acme I don't know
much about it. There's quite a few
videos and introduction of Acme text
editor by for example
um I can show you
for example there's a um
go go go
rejects there is a character kind of who
who eventually joined Rob Pike
to work on Goland he wrote a famous blog
about regular expression speed, the
regular expression engine and speed. Uh
his name is Rex, I believe. Rex
something. Okay. And turned out he's one
of the I learned
he he he did some of the social justice
warrior stuff. Okay. So I so I didn't
like him so much.
Uh
so regular regular expression limits or
should you read mastering regular
expression? This is a old article like
from 2010 or before. Uh I wanted to
anyway acme I don't know much about it.
There's quite a few videos. Okay. That's
Rob Pike's idea where you should use the
mouse all the time and stuff and plan I
don't I don't know much about it neither
but of course it's like the from rock
pike and uh and what's the other name
the like hell or something that's a
continuation of Unix. I don't know much
about it.
Okay, I think that's it for today.
Uh,
no, JavaScript do not have symbols
method.
Are you kidding? Are you sure? No, I
don't think so.
Having the characters be an or type is
bad in my opinion up there with
Markdown's lack of consistent
delimiters.
What?
Okay. Okay. Bye, guys.
14 views. 14 concurrent viewers. Say hi,
guys. Say hi. And uh donate to me if you
have a job. Okay, go to kasadi.info.
Okay, just go to kasadi.info. Kasar code
kasadi.info. Go to the bottom. Donate me
Amazon gift card, Patreon me, PayPal.
PayPal or Amazon gift card me $100 would
be good. Nice if you have a job. Okay.
Wait. Hi. Wait. Hi. Bye, guys.
That's it. So I shut down in 30 seconds
unless you got another question.
What browsers are you using? The one
where you go page by page looks like
Emacs. The ones where you go page by
page. this browser. What are you talking
about? This is Firefox. Okay. Now, if
you want to know, just search my
YouTube. There's one episode I spend
like maybe 30 minutes talking about
which browser I use because a lot of
people ask me that like why do you use
three browsers? So, this is Chrome, this
is Brave, this is the Brave browser
which I recommend the best. Okay. And
here is Firefox where I use Firefox for
my my my own web dev dev.
Okay, bye.