Hello, good morning. Welcome to another
episode of S talk show. We are going to
code Emac Bisp. Today we are going to
continue from two days ago. So
uh about two days ago we did one that
is on May 18th episode
657 Emac Bisp generic map functions on
hasht associative list and property
list. So today we are going to continue
that and I'm going to do uh write a
tutorial. So basically we are going to
cover these new functions in EMAC this.
Okay. So this is good for you Emacs
Emacs users programmers and Emac this
coders. If you are watching offline play
at 1.5 speed because I ramble. If you
are watching live say hi. Love to see
your comments. Okay. Uh nobody's here.
So let me uh I I'm just going to start
to work on it. Okay. So the problem is
Okay. So the problem is we got this um
so okay. So let's go let's go to the
previous talk show. So this is uh 659 is
today. 6057 is the two days ago. Okay.
So you got Okay. So let me copy that
link. Okay. Go back here. Let's begin.
Paste the emac this patch table and uh
grab those code. Okay. So the job today
is to write a tutorial for for this uh
map new map functions
uh uh you know write a tutorial into my
EMAC lisp basics tutorial. Okay.
On.info.
So something we need to uh refresh we
need to know when when is this uh so
there are few uh information let me just
um quickly add it okay so yeah so
actually go to go to the talk show
something I want to know okay so let why
don't we just copy uh copy the thing
copy close it uh
wait So yeah. Okay. So it's good. Close
it. Uh reopen it. Show in
browser. Yes. Okay. So these functions
we need to write and
uh and so let's add some links
here.
Um Emac basics and hasht write a
tutorial. Uh so there are a few things
we want to
know write a tutorial and uh check if
they are all these functions are
preloaded when you load Emacs you know
if because if they are not pre-loaded
then you every time you use them you
need to say require something very
annoying so check uh look into uh they
are created check emac news file okay so
there are few things we already Oh, they
are created. Okay. So,
let's Okay. So, so how do you know if
they are preloaded? The easiest, the
most simple way is just to start Emacs.
So, you can say run Emacs dash q dash q
means
um -ash q means do not load any in file.
Okay. So if you
uh
control C. Okay, let's try again. Uh run
Emacs dash
Q. So you see it uh launches a new EMAC.
Now control shift up arrow. Wait, not
control shift. Uh alt control scroll up
to
magnify the font for every window.
That's a new EMAC feature about few
years ago. Okay. So you can see so we
need to
um try to use one of these functions. So
so for example let's go to last time we
can we have a example of calling this
map apply function. So copy it. So back
to the this GNU plain GNU Emacs. So you
know so we are using emac keys. So
switch buffer is going to be control x
um b. Okay. Go to scratch buffer. Ctrl y
to paste. Okay. Uh now that's not big
enough. So control alt
uh scroll up. So now we got big. Now the
font is not too good.
Yeah, but but let's leave it with that.
Okay. So, evaluate this. Control X
control uh E controll
X control E. Okay, done. Then do the
same
here. Then do the same
here. Void function map apply. What?
Okay. So, it's actually not loaded. I
thought it's loaded because I tried it
yesterday.
What? Okay.
So,
apparently this function is not loaded.
Okay. So, by default it's not loaded.
So, that's a good thing to
know.
If the
map eel lib is
preloaded
answer no okay and uh
um okay so
um so they are created so okay so Emacs
version history
um
they the
mapel dib is created
in two uh
200 15 so 10 years
ago. Okay. So we know the creation date
we know and it's not loaded. Uh that's
annoying. So if it's not loaded that
means you need to um let me uh map
apply. So describe function map apply
jump to the source code. Jump to the
bottom. That's how you uh that that is
um that provide that means you so you
need require that's that's what you
need to call if you want to use any of
those function but I'm surprised that it
is not uh preloaded because I thought I
test
it. So
copy now. Ctrl Y to paste. Ctrl X.
Control E to load it.
Now now we controll XTRL
E. Okay. So now it
works. So I'm pissed that it is not
preloaded. Let let me try again. Okay.
So Ctrl X Ctrl C to close that.
And uh let's just try it
again. Copy. Okay. So,
uh go
to
xx.el. Okay. Create a file
xx.el. Paste that
there. And uh and uh let's
say let's just remove that
to there. Okay. So simplifies. You don't
even need a list. So you just run that.
Save it. Okay. Now go to
shell. Start emac again. Do
it. Okay. Now this is so
tedious. Control alt. Scroll up to
magnify.
Okay. Done. Now Ctrl X Ctrl F to open a
file
xx.el. Okay. Now move cursor down. Ctrl
X control E. Okay. So now finally we
know this function is not loaded by
default. We finally like verified it for
sure. H that's a that's painful. Okay.
So these are the few informations that
that's critical when you uh write a
tutorial because you want people to you
know you want you need to tell
people that
um you need to tell people when is it
created and what do you need to load if
you want to use it. Uh okay. So and also
another thing I found out is that these
functions are not documented in EMAC
this manual. Okay. So for example
uh search for map apply map applies.
Copy it. Now search for emac this uh
documentation eac manual search nfound.
Uh so the command you call is
um this is this index search.
Okay. So try it again. Map apply. It's
not found. Now go to the emac this info
directory. Let's try to grab it. So is
it possible that
um it's in the info file it's just not
in the
uh you know let's open any one of them.
So search for map apply info info none.
So this map applied. So these functions
are not documented at all. Uh which is
very informative because that
says these are kind of advanced
functions that you know it's not
documented. So it's only for advanced
users. Uh I'm not sure why they do not
document it. Try another one. No f not
found. Okay.
Emacs for success first. Hello. Hello.
First hello
Diego.
So, so that's you know this is quite
interesting to know that that these
functions we are trying to document to
write a tutorial today. They are
actually not documented in the e-mag
manual officially.
It kind of makes sense because you know
like I talked about the other day you
know
hasht or
uh hasht data structure
or or the association list structure or
the property list all the symbol
property list they are all uh collection
of pairs and hash table. Okay, hasht is
here. So they are all collection of
pairs and each one of them the data
structure they have their own you know
native functions to deal with them.
So
technically you do not
need you know these these extra
functions but but you know but they
provided so it's for one thing it's more
consistent so you can use any of these
functions to deal with any of
association list or property list or
hash table that's one thing
convenience I mean convenience and
consistency okay but but the other I
think uh more important is that some of
these functions actually
um you don't have a functionality you
know like map filter I don't think you
have a function in hasht that filters by
key so they actually provide new
functionality because if you don't have
these functions you have to write it
yourself which is very
tedious you know like when you start
programming these are kind of things you
too
uh you know in almost any language in
Python in pearl in wam language in list
like how do you partition a list into
let's say every item is three elements
suppose you have a list you want to make
it a list of lists and each sublist is
three elements okay or four elements or
n you know so how do you you have to
write a function to do that so there are
many ways
So this kind of so for uh so for example
you can look
at emac this basics you know function
take drop slice uh then uh map for each
for every sequence you know all these
work on list for every filter
uh filter remove uh sequence keep you
know they delete elements or keeps
elements sometimes by a function if the
function is returned true they keep it
or remove it or sometimes by by by a
exact literal element. So anyway, so
this list functions there are so many
and how do you write a unique you know
if you want to delete or duplicate in a
list right so you you have all these
kind of tasks
uh sort reverse join convert uh union
intersection difference partition and
group. So typically for beginners this
these are very interesting programming
exercises like I did this in 1990s with
wuam language. Wuam language already has
you know all these building but but then
you still need to do more. So and Python
added them like after 20 years you know
they you know Python like today
uh most languages has union intersection
and difference. Okay so they are in wuam
language since like
1989. Okay a little bit digression. So
let me show you wam language uh wam
language. So you go to list data
structure. You go to f language in depth
table of contents numbers boolean list.
So list operations you can get parts add
elements delete elements change element
check existence filter sort reverse or
get their order. reshape, split, group,
fatten, transpose,
uh, count, group, similar items,
combinotaurics that especially this
combinatorics very interesting. For
example, TPOS, you want to get all
possible
uh list of two things or all possible
list of three things, you know, and all
possible subsets, you know, these are
kind of combinatorial mathematical
functions. Or you want to get all all
possible permutations of a list or all
all possible subsequences of the list
you know so
and and you know so so so one of the
basic is union intersection complement
or difference. So uam language had them
in 1989 or so. Python added them around
you know pretty late 2008 or something.
So but by today like most languages has
has this union intersection but you know
the many things wuam language provide
tles subsets permutations they don't
have in other languages
uh in python some of them they added it
but in a special
library okay uh so anyway so so what I'm
saying is that these kind of things are
almost the very interesting programming
exercise for beginners when you learn a
new
language and
uh so similarly so I was saying so in
EMAC this so they started you see EMAC
this added this uh sequence
functions about 10 years ago so and
Today they added these you know uh
generic map
functions.
So if you don't have them you have to
implement implement them yourself. But
usually it's problematic
because to implement properly you have
to be concerned about
efficiency and also if you're going to
do all of these then the design becomes
critical like because you don't want
each one of them you know having
different arguments order or whatever.
So, so it is actually critical to have a
cons consistent set of uh of these
functions built in in the language.
So that is why you know this EMAC this
they added this 10 years ago which is
great
um which is great you know you you got
merge merge with merge uh map nested
elements map
pairs yeah but uh somehow they are still
not documented in EMAC this manual so
but anyway it's a it's a positive
thing okay so we learned you know it
came from 10 years ago. Uh and uh it um
where is this part two? Okay. So 10 10
years ago and
it's by default it's not loaded and also
it's not documented. Okay. We already
okay that's what we know. Now let's
begin to write the tutorial. So I
decided last time to add it a after the
hash table. So you go to hash table. You
go to emac list basics. Then you got uh
the data structure section. You got list
special
list and the list structure con cells.
Then vector then you got the these
sequences generic list manipulating
functions. Then you got hash table. So
the map functions I decided to add it
after the hash table. Okay.
So uh so what what would be the name?
Map functions. Okay. So let's just say
map
functions. Okay.
So
map functions. Uh let's say
generic. Generic. No
shortcut. Gener generic. There's
general. Okay. Well, I want
generic. Generic.
No. Okay. So that would be the name
general map functions. Now open the
hasht page. Copy it. Close it. Open this
page. Do it. Paste it. Save it. Close
it. Cut the title. Undo. Open it
again. Now change the title. Emac this
generic map functions. Okay. Go to the
top showing browser. There it is. Now I
need to delete those. Okay, I start to
write a tutorial. So update the time
stamp. Remove the old time. Uh what is
uh generic map functions.
Okay. Uh so
uh starting to write a tutorial. Okay.
These
are general uh let's say
generic functions that works on they
work on
uh okay so they work on let's go to
uh this basics uh
data structure they work
on association list Okay, copy that.
Split the page. Go back to the hash
table. Uh jump to previous location.
There, there. There. And
uh end hasht.
Okay. Copy the link there.
Okay. Uh okay. Then delete that. These
are generic functions that work on these
things.
They
are created
around they are in EMAC around
2015. Important
information to use uh to use them. Okay.
To use
them, you need to load. Okay. So what
what is the
uh I do remember but uh okay so let's
just write it require
uh map dot require
map I think so what is
it so comments questions posted okay I'm
going to get to
[Music]
Okay. Uh what is this? Uh this is part.
So they require. Okay. Require.
Yeah. Map.
Apply. Uh, go to the source code. Go to
the bottom. Provide map. Okay, that's
what you need. Close that. Yeah, just
map.
Okay,
so
so make it that they are in EMAC around
25. To use them, you need to load the
library.
uh they are in EMAC uh in Emacs 2015 and
uh go open the Emacs version history
page.
So 2015 they are in
EMAC
25. Okay, last time we checked it's in
EMAC 25. Okay, so close.
Okay. So they
are in EMAC
25. Okay. That's one
thing. Okay. And
uh and uh
they
provide a general way to work on any of
whatever uh
Okay. So,
let's something like that. Okay. This is
just a draft writing my tutorial and
create a hash table. We don't care.
Literal expression for hasht delete
length. Add entry. Remove entry. Check
exist. Check keys value. Remove all
entries. Apply function to all entries.
Get all keys. Get all values and
reference. Unfortunately there is they
are not in eac this manual. So now show
in browser. So now is our draft version
of the tutorial. Okay. Now go to the
talk show. We need to grab close close.
We need to grab uh the list of
functions. Okay. Uh part two. Okay. So
let's grab
them. Cut. Save. Go back. show in
browser. So we need to work on each and
every one of them. Okay. So there it is.
And uh now copy the file path. Close it.
And what is this today's talk show?
Let's paste them there. Okay. So wait,
what do we want to paste? So this is
part two. This is today.
So
um oh we already have it here though.
So okay yeah identical. So but before so
now we need to remove these others.
Let's just clean up. Okay remove this uh
emac 25. Yes. Uh, Emacs 25 remove
version history
removely keys
remove
show. Okay, so ED basics hasht write a
tutorial. So let's uh so let's go to the
front. So we write a tutorial. The mapel
lib is created in
2015. Uh look into the map. Our library
is loaded pre-loaded. Answer no. Okay.
So this basics
hasht hasht is
repeated. Uh delete. Okay. Merge the two
list. Show. Okay. This basics hasht
generic map functions. Okay. Go there.
Fantastic.
Now uh so
now you know this is a introduction what
is generic map functions and uh
introduced in
2016 and you need require map okay and
also mention they are not documented in
EMAC this
manual okay so let's go
um where are we Okay. So, so go to the
page
mention they are not
documented in
Elisp manual. Okay. In
in version 30.
Okay. For Emacs version
30. Okay. This is just a draft
introduction. We need to refine it
because so far we don't know if it works
on symbol property list. We know it
works on association list property
property list but I don't know if it
works on symbol property
list. So we need to uh check each one of
them. Now go back here close that uh go
back go back sequences. Okay, this wam
language uh very interesting
thing. So why don't we copy it because
we talked about it.
So
close. Okay. So now paste that there.
And uh this is what we want. Okay. So
the others are just supplementary links.
Okay. And we talked about list basics.
We talked about these bunch of sequence
functions that's very suitable for
programming exercise such as um let's
see sequence functions
uh you know for example union
intersection
uh you know some of these are actually
interesting ones and they are added
recently actually. So let's let's put
that there first.
Uh okay. So so for example the sequence
functions uh there is one called uh you
know like like all these are they are
especially useful if you do functional
programming. You know this map for each
sum and every uh and filter they are
especially
useful mostly their purpose is for if
you do functional programming because
otherwise most of the time you just use
you know do like do times you know like
a loop. So the power of these functions
is actually for functional programming.
Okay.
And there are some quite interesting
ones. Um so for example the partition
and group is very interesting ones.
They you know like sometimes you don't
you don't you don't see this in in let's
say go language or java I I'm not sure
uh but but usually you don't see them
but but in functional program means in
Hascar or camel you kind of see these.
Okay. Uh so but yeah so some of them is
interesting for example one of them I
want to show is um very powerful. Okay.
So for example, reduce is very powerful.
Uh take drop slice iteration guide.
Where is
reduce? For each map uh map map car map
indexed map index is also interesting
one. Interesting one because you want to
map a function to a list but sometimes
you also need the index. So that's why
you have map indexed you know and this
is for functional programming because if
you don't do functional programming then
you just do loop you know uh two times
uh but there is another one I wanted to
show
um anyway so we are digressing so let's
get back to write uh focus on writing
the tutorial
Okay. Okay. So here so we want to so
yeah so first of all get the uh we need
to get the uh example. Let's get on
let's just write like one uh
documentation for one of them. Then we
then I'm going to work offline for the
rest just to
show you know how do I write uh my
tutorial you know the structure the
design what you need to know what you
need to uh prepare to write them okay so
let's go back to um generate functions
so let's create a new section let's say
okay uh emac lisp okay So first of all
so so this is going to be map
apply this going to be map apply and the
describe function uh let's see what is
the uh syntax so that is that and now
call s bracket capitalized words so you
you'll see why okay so let's add a
definition list and let's make
uh add the code code tag and variable
tag. So you can see in browser they
became uh definition list like
that. So the var indicates they are
variable I mean the I mean they indicate
not literal. Okay the red is
literal. So you you can see by a glance
this design you know this design of of
technical writing format. So you see in
in my style you have this
um they are green that means you know
that's that string can vary. Okay so
anyway so that you got that I want the
bracket there and uh then you need to
say what that does. Okay so basically
this is what it does. So we can base it
off on the inline documentation. Okay.
So but I want to write my own style. So
apply a
function apply a function to each
element of
map. Okay. Uh return the result as a
list. Okay. Function is called with two
arguments key and value.
uh
[Music]
key and
value. Okay. Uh the default
implementation is you know I don't care
about that
because you know I I I want to cover
the the mathematical properties how it
is implemented is another issue. Okay.
Okay. Basically, basically it would be
something like that. Okay. Then you need
the example there and uh let we need to
simplify the example. Okay. So like I
said before, we just put that there. And
uh
then uh this aa just x key for
clarity. So say key and
value. Okay.
So pify
d and
Okay, that's the
output. Okay, syntax code show in
browser. So here is one of them kind of
done. Okay.
uh you know so we we can kind of you
know so this this needs to be apply
apply
uh bracket that curly brackets I mean
that's French bracket that's French
single bracket uh also do that that
there okay then make it
tag okay that's kind of better also So
it is um another detail here is that it
is very annoying that in EMAC convention
they capitalize the
arguments. So for example let's let's go
uh close that reopen to remove this uh
highlight remove. Okay. So let's
describe function. So you see map apply.
So let's you know here's the
documentation and let's jump to the
source
code. Okay. So you can see here's the
source code and here is the in inline
doc string and you can see they
capitalize this world function and also
they capitalize this word map. Why?
Because they are part of the argument.
So it is Emacs documentation convention
that for any arguments or parameters of
the function you capitalize it. Okay,
that's a EMAC
convention. You can see it by you know
in my EMAC list documentation page. Emac
Lisp and uh okay so lisp basics you go
to the function
section data structure function define
function function parameters do dark
string markup. So this page shows you
how to write the documentation string
just like like
here and uh certain conventions. So if
you have a parameters for function you
need to capitalize them by convention.
Okay. And this convention is very bad
because in EMAC
this the programming language is case
sensitive. So if you have a parameter of
capital A and a parameter of lowerase A
they mean different things. But now in
the documentation they become the same
thing because to refer them you you know
you capitalize it. So so now they become
the same thing. So they it's so it's no
good. It's ambiguous. It makes it you
know it's
ambiguous. So this is a bad convention.
But why do they why do they do it?
Because well because by convention you
don't capitalize your arguments uh
parameters. So effectively the entire
Emacs list this source code bundled with
Emacs you know the arguments are not
capitalized. So therefore you know you
can you know you can capitalize it in a
dark string to distinguish it from
common English words. That is why they
are doing it. Okay. But it's a bad
convention. you know, they
shouldn't, you know, if I run if I need
Emacs,
um, yeah, I would I, you know, I would
change
it, but it's, you know, Emacs is like 40
years old. There's a lot of
history. Okay. Are there lazy sequences
in ELISP? No. And that's a good thing.
Okay. Lazy evaluation is one of the
worst
Lazy evaluation is not good such as
using Haskell. Okay. But further what is
worse is when you have iterators and
generators such as in Python and
JavaScript. That that is far worse.
That's the worst possible.
They are kind of related because lazy
evaluation is a you know is related to
um you know the iterators and
uh iterable iterators generators you
know very complex because they make
what they do is that
they you know you have you have things
like that lazy evaluation for the
purpose
of part of the purpose is trying to be
efficient in saving
uh memory usage because if you have a
list of 1,000 items, you know, you may
not sometimes you may not need to use
all of them.
you only want to use, you know, like one
to 100, but potentially you want a
thousand of them. So, traditionally, you
just create a list of 10,00 items. So,
it wastes your memory, you know, because
you you don't necessarily actually use
it. So, then you have lazy evaluation,
which is a mechanism that that allows
you to have a list
of even million items or even infinite
number of items. But it they occupy
memory only when you use it. Okay. So I
believe that is basically essentially
just what uh iterators for. Okay. So for
example in JavaScript
uh JavaScript JavaScript in depth and
you have this entirely complex thing
called code called
uh function class iterable. Okay, you
got iterable object, you got iterator,
then you got iterator prototype, you got
iterable prototype which you know in
JavaScript they call interface actually
they call it protocol
uh and it's extremely complex. So once
you have that iterators and iterables in
JavaScript by the way Python so
depending on the language their meaning
differ slightly okay but in JavaScript
you have iterable then you have iterator
they are different things okay but once
you have them then you then you need
generator okay then you need
generator
idiotic and then then you have generator
function. Okay, so a generator is a
function that creates
iterable. Okay, and then a generator
function is a function that creates
generators.
Okay. So, it's entirely
idiotic for for what purpose, you know,
for because they want to save some
memory which I don't think is that
useful because you don't you don't
create infinite list. Okay. If you
really really want a infinite list, you
can do it in other ways. You don't
create a list. Okay.
But they try to you know these um you
know so that's the idea of these
iterators. So and also once you have
them they
become you know the the the the
programming the way it semantics the the
the be the runtime the it's it becomes
hard to p predict what's going
on you know when you have lazy
evaluation. Okay, there's another thing.
So I was talking about lazy list in
Haskell. So that has strong ties with
the iterator and generator stuff. But
then there's another concept is lazy
evaluation which means whenever you call
a function the functions argument does
not evaluate right
away. It evaluates only when it's used.
So that's another thing. So that's
that's what that that you know that's
another things I don't think it's
good. Okay. So I think we are done. So
uh webdev. So we talked about iterators
uh and uh we talked about
function the conventions for emac this
function inline documentation. So let's
uh let's copy it. Let's uh put in our
talk show. So we have
uh some a record of
it. Okay. Continue. Here we talked about
emac list inline documentation which is
no good with the capitalized words and
we talked about iterators
generators crap and lazy evaluation. So,
so JavaScript
generators very
complex.
Uh, so let me let me let me summarize. I
think that's it for today, but uh let me
tie up some loose ends on um something I
want to say. Okay. Uh dark stream markup
and uh today did we finish it kind of.
So this is the you know this is the
tutorial for this. So we kind of started
a draft documentation for map apply then
we need to work on each one of those.
Okay. And another thing is that there is
no documentation. I mean there's no
popup like you see in my in my tutorial
you can move the cursor to a function
name then you'll have a popup of the
inline documentation but I don't have it
for the map apply so let me let me redo
this
okay so that means I need to regenerate
my inline documentation that's done with
JavaScript let me show you okay so uh
generate map functions. Open it and go
here. So this this this you know we got
this list of things.
Now press press. Okay, that's what we
want. Now regenerate it. So you can see
there are now list functions. So you see
so now if you refresh you'll notice a
difference. Let's do it. You see? So now
if there's a documentation it should
show but it's not for example I can show
you a list okay tag it make a list show
in browser now go down if you hoover to
list you can see the documentation so
that is done in JavaScript so search
forjs so you got this popup data okay so
open it so this is a top of data. This
is JavaScript. In fact, it's
TypeScript. So, you know, um, so you
know, you got 35,000
lines. So, you need you need to add, you
know, about 20 of these. Yeah, that that
requires a whole
regeneration. Um, okay. So, that's
that. Okay. So, I think that's it.
So did I miss something? So EMAC this is
fantastic. What nature sparked your
curiosity to deciding to dedicating much
time on EMAC this? Well that's a long
story you know because so I started to
use Emac Emacs in
uh
1997 because I heard you know Emacs is
the most powerful. Now remember this is
1990s so there's no 1997 there's no
Amazon there's no eBay there's no you
know internet like today there's no
Wikipedia nothing there's only like 100
websites
1997 200 websites something like that so
but in the 1990s there's no Linux even I
mean Linux just began okay so you got
Unix you got Solaris and so on. So I
like you know so I was a wolfam language
programmer you know and wuam language is
one of the you know like very powerful
like on the cutting edge technology. So
it is well known for in the math
community mathematics or artificial
intelligence and also in lisp because
back then lisp is lisp programming
language is the well known for
artificial intelligence and in fact wam
language is you know lisp I talked about
in my last video and several others just
search for wuam language and lisp on my
website.
So, so I I was a programmer of Wuam
language. So, I but then I heard of Unix
and GNU Emacs like very strange what
what is GNU? So, I start to look into
and I you know I heard it's the most
powerful editor. So, I start to learn
it. You learn it just by um just by
reading you know reading the manuals
like there's a default
manual like when you start Emacs they
show a manual like interactive Emacs
tutorial there so you just go through
this that's a beginning tutorial how to
use Emacs like what is a buffer you know
they have strange terms copy and paste
you know they don't they don't call copy
and paste in Emacs they call yank yank
and uh kio so but you know but I'm a
nerd so I learned it and it's pretty
useful and so I started to I started to
live in Emacs in by
1998 okay then then event in in 2006 I
started to learn Emac Lisp
okay you know before that I already
started to learn schemisp
um because they have relation with uh
you know wam language you know so I have
like a lot articles about
um about my early experiences uh so let
me show a few okay so
uh what we want to show uh so okay so
info
search experience wam okay mathematica
okay uh Uh where is
it? Lisp and uh Lis Marco versus Wam
language. Wam language versus Lisp. Uh
so lots of old articles like going back
30 years
ago. Uh
on
list. Okay, here's uh my collection of
lisp related
articles.
Um so there's a particular article I'm
looking for that details my experience
of coming to lisp from wam language
written like 25 years ago.
Um it might be on
sadi.org may not be here. So
um you know all these are pretty old
articles 10 or 20 years old.
Um famous programmers on how come a lisp
sucks. Gio says don't iterate recurse
and get rid of lisp cons. Paul Graham's
infatuation with the concept of hacker
because he's gonna create a arc list
because he want a hacker language. He
believed the concept of hacker is the
best definition for the best language.
Why this mark sucks? Why closure is
dense? Closure is
popularity. Uh what is your favorite
list language code? Purity, deception,
scheme, disp and failure. Why chi this
fails and closure this succeed
uh and this maros and practical common
this
idiocy and the car and cutter idiocy the
lisp cons idiocy there it is there that
is the article I was trying to find yeah
on sadi.org
My impression of this from Mathematica.
So this is written in
2008.
2008 I think it's written in in year
2000s.
Uh I think it's written much earlier.
Okay. Anyway, so that's one of my
article. So I wanted uh to finish this.
I think we are done here. But uh there's
few things I want to talk
about about generators, iterators. Let's
see. Let's see if I have that. Um hold
on a
sec. Okay. So this is about the
tutorial. It's mostly done. So you have
a question. Let's
see. So why do I learn Emac?
Well, because it's, you know, I'm a
dedicated EMAC fan and uh gradually I
just learn more lisp because lisp is my
thing. Functional programming,
Mathematica, that's my
love. And when you learn Emac, Lisp, one
of the great advantage is that it just
make your editing so much more
powerful. Is it environmental? So, Emac
list is fantastic. Is it
environment not just single programming
language? I do everything with it. CRM,
websites, phone calls, SM lm.
Yeah, a lot of people uh do that. But
actually, I don't use Emacs for anything
other than text. So if it's something
related to text or editing or writing or
programming languages I use
Emacs any text okay but if it's about
playing videos or email uh or usually I
don't because in email you got images
you got you know or videos you it
becomes complicated
uh lazy sequencing
I don't think they are. Uh, let me
double check. No, I don't
think Oh, that's how you do those
popups. All the descriptions are in
JavaScript file.
Yes. Fantastic. Cheers for story time.
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for
watching. One hour. Okay, 1
hour. So we closed down in a minute.
So we started to write this tutorial be
you know you got to begin somewhere like
like the Alice in Wonderland begin at
the beginning because you don't take the
first step or like confusious says the
Chinese confusious you know you have to
begin like what's the word what's a
saying I forgot but you got to begin
somewhere so we got we you know so we
started here
uh we need popup. Okay, that's good. And
uh this this topic box needs to go
uh this topic box doesn't belong here.
However, you need a new topic box that
group that kind of group these um yeah
so this data structure box remove and uh
and EMAC this hash table
box remove. But you do need a new topic
box that's all about
this collection of pairs and man
manipulations. So let's add
it.
Listify. Okay. Link them. List them.
Then add a topic box like that. And uh
here you'll say emac this
collection
data structure. Okay. something like
that. So, and you copy the file path,
paste it, linkify, make a list, delete
the URL, and you need add
that somewhere here.
Uh so, so um say what you should say uh
key value
collection data structure. You know this
very annoying because this uh hash table
or key value collection there's many
names for it. You know dictionary
associative list
association hasht lookup table or map.
For example in Ruby is Ruby and Pearl is
called hasht. Python is called
dictionary.
Emac list you have association list you
also have hash table they are different
things then you also have property list
okay in wuen language it's called
association okay not list just
association
uh in Java it's called map and
JavaScript in JavaScript it's either map
or object
So very annoying. You don't have like
one central name you know
like each of these term is not optimal
because if you call it hash table what
is what the is a hash? Then it
confuses the concept with the hash
function. You know you you want a
function that
returns a hash key. you know confusion
confusion with that cryp cryptograph
uh uh
concept. So hasht well it's related
because you actually hash the key
anyway. So hasht is not a good term you
know it should better is key value key
value list or key value collection
that's actually the best term map is not
a good term because that confused with
the function of mapping something to
something you know it's like a geometric
concept geometric transformation that's
map so that's no good and dictionary
is most intuitive but then it confuses
with the English dictionary
concept. So, so anyway, so let's let's
just decide on uh let's say key value
collection. Okay, let's just uh we don't
want it to be too long. Okay, so anyway,
let's just say that
uh let's just say delete that. Okay.
That Okay. Now for each of these page
add this box.
Okay. Press press press press that will
do it. Okay. Now show in browser hash
table. Go to the
bottom key value collection. Go to
association list. Go to the
bottom. Okay. Now go to property list.
Go to the bottom. So you got all these
boxes.
Fantastic. So they are great for cross
reference. So when you are you know
doing association at least you can oh
you can know that oh there's also
generic map functions.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah. Uh, if you like my
stuff, go
to.info. Go to all the way down and pay
me. Okay. Amazon gift card, PayPal,
Patreon me. $100 is good. Bye.