hello good morning guys welcome to
another episode of star talk show
today we are going to do emac lisp
nothing but emac this heavy coding so
coding for one hour
and so if you want to learn emac please
join you know and ask me questions ask
me pertinent questions about emaclis
okay uh imac this coding so we're gonna
you know no nonsense today we're gonna
start right away so today so here is
today's topic and today is 2022 january
20th
okay so here are the things we're gonna
code the first thing is that we are
going to code we are going to write a
function
that adds a comma okay
uh okay 16 magnify the font
and turn on global high line mod so you
can see where is my cruiser
and then
on the pink window is all my keystrokes
such as moving cursor
you can see the keystrokes there and you
can also see the command name
okay i'm using a vera keyboard
this is kinesis advantage 2 and this is
ultimate hacking i recommend them
and you can find them on saudi keyboard
blog just search for it
and i'm using for our keyboard for our
layout and
fly keys
okay so here is a source code for soft
light keys and you can see the url
here
okay software keys a key binding system
for emacs fantastic okay now let's begin
okay let's uh enough with a dual so let
i'm going to write the command this
command okay so let's begin it
uh
okay start a emac this code
okay i'm gonna write this command
and make it into a
buffer
okay
begin to beginning to write this command
why do you
want to
comma
space
something comma space you know that
space is extra typing so it would be
nice if you just press a key and it
automatically adds one space to each
comma
and the remove redundant ones so that's
that is what the command do so defend
okay i'm using xa
i'm using
xr emac this mod okay my packages if you
like my stuff
you know stuff like keys is free you can
download on github it's no longer on
mailpad but on github and you can
uh download you know you can buy my
packages they are open source
so
emac this mod so define uh so
d for different
press space expanded nice so we are
going to write this is the command name
and
documentation add a comma
add a
space after comma
of current block
of code or
selection if you have a selection you'll
work on selection if there's no
selection you'll work on current block
of code block of code meaning
a paragraph basically separated by empty
lines okay
so we're gonna write so so so here's the
template uh and let's see hello guys
hello uh
toby sounds good nice hat
this is i bought this two years ago from
a thrifty store hello louie spore
from scandinavia northern europe i i
think
and uh
okay let's begin so email at least okay
so add a comma so
so
we're gonna add a comma add a space
after comma so
begin with
search for word
search for comma and oh so we what we
need to do is basically find and replace
find a comma replaced by comma space
so how do you do that this that's an
idiom so you go to search for xr emac
list
practical emac list
so my website practical emac list
and you want the idiom for find and
replace so emac this basics
and go down there is a um
writing a command okay it's a find
replace text so
at this point we can actually just copy
the code okay so here's a full tutorial
about how to do find replace so let's
copy it
saves typing you know saves typing and
so paste it here and remove this let
okay
make it pretty fine then start code so
first of all let let is a local variable
block block
local variables this is how you do local
variables in lisp so here is your
variables so we have case for search neo
so that means we don't care about case
forward because comma there is no
capital case so delete that
case fault search is a building global
variable so if it's true
that means case sensitive
if it's neo force that means
doesn't matter which case do you know
search for that you know so since it's a
comma we don't care about case for
search so delete that
so empty let okay
so go to
go to chart uh go to the beginning of
buffer okay anyway the the heart of
the code is this one okay while
search for word
comma
okay uh it's
describe function lookup the
documentation for search forward
you know let's look at what are the you
know optional parameters
so search forward string
bound no arrow count okay
so search for word
string
bound neo
no errol true
that's what we want okay then
once you do search for word emacs will
put the found string the beginning
position and position you know a bunch
of
data you know the found string and their
position into a
into a
global variable called uh match data
okay
behind the scenes so you don't see the
code here but it's behind the scenes
once you find it it will store the found
string and so on in the in a global
variable called metadata and there are
many functions to extract
those information so
once you've once you find it so this
return search forward returns true or
false true if it found it okay
so while you found it while we found the
comma then we do we call replace match
what that means it will just replace the
file stream in the metadata remember
it's behind the scenes so you simply
replace those from stream positions by
comma space okay simple so simple so
this so the second part we don't need
anymore you know just repeat if you
wanna
find replace again you go to
uh you
go to char
move the cursor to a position then now
you have to give a position
point mean typically point mean is uh is
the is the beginning of the buffer
usually it beginning of the buffer is
one point minute is one okay beginning
the buffer position beginning position
is one how do you know
you can call describe char for example
let's call describe char
and you can see
you see we just called described char
and that will tell you and here emacs
pops up a result you can see
position one of 277 that means in this
buffer there are 277 characters
and your cursor is at the position one
so
cruiser position begin with one not zero
okay
so anyway so let's go back here so yeah
typically you go go to char move the
cursor to a position and point me so why
why don't you say just one instead of
point mean because sometimes you have
narrow to buffer for example
select that narrow to buffer so
in this case that position you know that
when you have narrow to buffer which
means hide the rest of it
when you want to focus on this uh
paragraph or whatever function
so when this happens you don't you know
that beginning position is no longer one
so that that is why now let's widen okay
so widen back to the
so that is why you want to uh typically
you put it here point you know go to
move the
for me okay
so anyway the heart of the
code is simply just this line okay fine
so
we are almost done almost
okay now clean the clean the code okay
now
save it now um
okay now remember this command add a
space after comma of current block or
selection so first of all
you want to know if there is a selection
okay so let's do that okay
if
if there's a selection how do you know
you you call the command
uh
region active p
wrap
okay region active p okay that is the
syntax so this returns true or false
region active means there's a selection
like like that selection okay region
activity so if it's active then
you want to
have you want to assign the beginning of
the region
position and end up the region position
to a variable so let's define some
variable
p1
p2 that's
position 1 position 2 okay so
if region is active then
set p1
region
beginning rb
expand expand fantastic okay
and p2 region end re expand expand so
now predefine the code
so that means you know you set the
positions p1 and p2 that's the position
you want to begin with and end with
that if
region is active now what if is the
region is not active well if it's not
active you want it to work on the
current block of code this is
extremely convenient
so if it's not active you want to be you
know
find the current block so how is the
block defined block is defined by empty
lines so for example this is one block
this is one block
this is one block this is one block so
you know
so you want to beginning and end
position of blocks so
you have to write that okay so let's
write it okay
let's not write it because we have a lot
to do so you can you can find the code
example to find the beginning block of
end block at
here
you see
this code this page emac this get text
block
this function will return the beginning
position and end position of the
the
in other words current paragraph okay
when the when there's no selection this
is super convenient because you don't
want to always you know when you want to
call some command just work on the
current line or current block or current
buffer you don't want to have
to to make the user make a selection
first you know if they want to make a
selection like specific part of the
buffer they can then the command will
work on the selection otherwise make it
automatic so
get text block position this is the code
okay but in our case uh i have a package
that just does that okay
so let's just call
uh
yeah actually let's just copy the code
here so it's i mean so
instead of calling a package you know so
it's more clear for the tutorial so let
me
clean up here
so the part we want is basically
okay we don't want that
there okay clean the code so this
so this
block of code will set
p1 to the beginning of the paragraph and
p2 to the end of paragraph how does it
work
well it work by search backwards search
backward search for
any number of two empty lines
and also optionally if there's a tab in
space in between so any two number of
two empty lines meaning it's like
two empty lines you know beginning of
paragraph so you search for that and
also move the cursor
then
then you
you know so you search backwards so let
me show you how the code works so search
backward that means you move the cursor
the cursor will be somewhere here so if
your cursor is here for example anywhere
here when you do
then when you call this your search you
know back
to
empty lines so the cursor will end up
there
but what you really want is the
beginning of the paragraph what what you
want is the cursor to be here so that's
why you have to then search forward
again you know that's kind of um
actually this is inefficient code
actually you can just say
match data
uh
search backward match data
yeah this actually this can be improved
uh but anyway let's forget about it so
then you set the point so
p1 is the variable with the dollar sign
now in emac this you don't need the
dollar sign but typically i add them
so that
so that if you have syntax clearing if
you use xa emac be smart they become
bold and you know so the local variables
becomes more
obvious easy to see so p1 p2 so let's
add the dollar sign here wait oops
add a dollar sign here and add okay so
this
so in summary if there's a
selection then the beginning and end is
a
region beginning region and if there's
no selection then you have to do work to
find the paragraph beginning and
paragraph end so this is how you do it
okay so we got our p1 and p2 that's the
position we want the we want the find
replace to work on okay now
once we got those positions now
what we do is narrow to buffer narrow to
region narrow to region
okay this is
another
image this idiom you know if you call
emac list
text processing which is very convenient
it's the most uh basic common need if
you code any emac this text processing
you know if you are coder or
emac this user typically you want to
transform you know your code to
you know text processing so this is the
idiom so you narrow to region
p1 and p2 that's this line but you also
want to call save restriction
why because when you narrow to region
for example it's an arrow to region
select that narrow to region
you know once your function is done you
want to return
you want to return you know you want to
write widen
because otherwise when user calls your
function then
then there is then they just see a part
of the buffer they thought oh god this
function deleted my
my code you know so you want to
return
the narrow you know the previous state
so that's the same
restriction okay
and now you just put the code here
prettify okay let's show the whole code
let's clean up so we don't
okay so now you
do the find and replace okay
and uh
and here you need to go to go to char
move the cursor to point me so that's
what we talked about before you want to
start at beginning of the region okay so
now to region p1 p2 start it move the
cursor to the beginning
then start the search then do the
replacement okay that's that's it
okay so let's that's it
now evaluate the whole buffer so what
you call is you call um
in my case i called sauron current file
that's one of the command ink soft like
keys
which also runs javascript
perl python php you know
a lot supports many languages but if you
don't have if you are not using stuff
like keys you can call
eval region same thing okay so that's
you know so we already evaluated this
code now copy this
uh command name
now open a new buffer
some thing
uh okay now let's try it
something okay wait let's try it uh a
comma b comma c
magnify see the full glory now
okay let's
now let's call the command call it
paste
some add space you know you can see in
the mini buffer because i add space
after command let's see if it works
please
do it
fantastic fantastic
ten minutes emac lisp saves you one hour
safe saves you one hour in your lifetime
something like that okay so next time
so now you have hand pain like me
repetitive strain injury typing too much
here right here
so now you can
a dot b
comma c you don't have to uh type the
space anymore okay
now let's
improve this okay let's try something
else let's try
copy that let's try x
comma y comma z okay let's delete this
okay now remember it work automatically
works on the paragraph so let's try it
do it here
okay good you don't have to make any
selection
now but if i if we have a selection just
that
correct
fantastic it just works on this
selection so
so that command is basically done but
but but but we need enhancement we need
feature reach commands that's not enough
let me read the comments okay anything
anything you guys have um
why not add in the comma as you type why
not add in the space after comma as you
type
well that well that's a um
that's not a bad um
suggestion but however these
technicalities like how do you implement
that first of all you cannot implement
you cannot do that with a brief because
emacs abbrev only works on
characters only works on english
alphabet it doesn't work on comma in
fact comma is a
signal to expand a brief
you know what i mean for example
by the way you know i space it becomes
by the way
so
so btw is a abbrev when you type comma
comma act acts as a signifier to emac
these
it expanded
so
you know one
one you know we might be thinking okay
why don't you make a brief of comma and
make it let's show space okay make it
expand to comma space well yeah you can
do that but you cannot use the brief
mechanism because the way a brief
mechanism only works on
letters
and this is written in c code so you
cannot customize it okay
i have an article on that just search
for saudi emacs a brief you know this
article somewhere okay
so
how do you implement real time you know
karma space you cannot do that with a
brief
so what's other you know what's other
ways well you can
you can do that but
but trust me okay it gets complex trust
me the best ways
um
is probably just a function like like
you know like
what we did today
you know so the other way is like for
example you can add a hook
you know you can add a hook to
the insert character
let's see if there's an insert character
hook
ctrl u
control h a
then type for hook
that will list all
hooks in emacs
then you just search for insert
so you know emacs has
hundreds few hundred hooks i mean
there's one hook where every time you
type a character then it will call a
function
so what your function will need to do is
to check if the previous character is
comma or not if it is added space
otherwise don't
but that's not that's that's not good
because then
this function gets called every time you
type something it's it's you know
so i would say the best way is just um
what we did okay
uh
so these are kind of things experience
you have to pick up with the technology
because in theory why don't you just you
know add the spaces you type well that's
good but
to implement implement that is
a bit complex as far as i know
so
there's additions okay so
now we have a function
so what happens is that let's see for
example let's copy this text okay so
we're gonna you know
this so here is a text okay let's
uh let's okay
okay so let's say
here's a text okay let's add more comma
here
okay there's only only two commas okay
um
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
remove okay so search and replace search
for comma space replace by comma okay
one two three three commas there so you
see
so typically when we work with the text
okay let's turn off global highlight mod
okay so when we you know you write a lot
blogs or tutorials or your blogs or your
articles if you're a journalist or
whatever you write lots of old notes you
know notes to yourself
so you call the command
add space after comma do it it does it
but sometimes
sometimes you have code inside here so
so sometimes you have
some
x
equals to let's magnify x equals to x
let's see three
let's say this okay
three comma four comma five you know
you are writing notes you know learning
a programming language or something so
you have sometimes you have code inside
it
so if you could add a comma you know to
your thing it may it also changes
changes your code in this case
it's an array
typically it doesn't matter if you have
a space after comma or not but
some programming languages comma has
different meanings you don't want that
you don't want it to
change you know part of the text you
know code
so
it would be nice when you call this
command it will actually highlight
all the changes it made okay let's do
that
uh
okay so let's do that highlight the
changes it made
okay so
how do you do that okay so we're gonna
add
so we want
high
light changes made okay
so you can at a glance you know you know
you can like double check if if it
changes something you don't want
and
highlight
changes it made okay something like that
version
today's date okay
so so highlight changes made okay
any comments and questions no okay
okay so highlight change is made so you
want to find so basically how
what you're gonna do is you want to find
the beginning position
and the position
of every change for each change you find
the beginning and end position then you
tell emacs to highlight those positions
okay so what you do is
here is uh there's a tutorial
you go to emac list write a major mod
okay
then you go to
so all these articles are
tutorials about how to write a major mod
then you go to one of them is
uh
overlay highlighting click it
this is how you highlight a region okay
like temporarily so let's copy the code
cop
copy
back to emacs
paste the code here
so you can see we have two functions but
the essence is just this line
okay
the the essence is just
this line
okay so cut that
and paste it here and we don't need that
anymore okay so that's the essence
okay prettify the code so overlay put
let's see
okay so prettify the code
overlay put so overlay is kind of a
okay let me explain so what you what we
are going to do is make a make it
highlight now emax has two mechanisms to
do the highlighting
one is by
text properties text properties
so in e-max any text in a buffer
you can
add
properties to it called text properties
so
you see this buffer you can see pink
i mean you can see purple you can see
green you can see blue
they have a meaning okay
pink you know
purple means it's a um
anyway that's
i'm not the one going to explain that
this is a stuff like keys i mean clocks
are immaculately smart
anyway you see they are colored the way
they are colored is via the mechanism of
text properties
so
so in this region in any any of the
color region you can look for text
properties so
property is just something added to that
region of text that tells emacs
this
region must be blue this region must be
green this region must be bold and green
with red backgrounds things like that so
that's text properties
you can see
there
okay this article explains what is text
property and how do you
add it or change it or remove it text
properties so that's one mechanism of
how emax can
do coloring
you know that's one of the way the other
way is what we are doing overlay
highlight okay overlay so overlay is not
text properties overlays actually just
tells emacs
there is this
movable
kind of movable region
that any text happens to be in this
region will be highlighted in such and
such way
you know that's called overlay so
imagine it's like overlay it's like just
like overlay it can move around you know
you can say overlay the next 10
characters starting at position x
you know so
then then any buffer changes anything
comes within that
position it'll be highlighted so that's
the overlay mechanism
so two mechanisms text properties and
overlay for coloring
um things so in this case
we want to use overlay so what's the
what's the difference well
i explained here okay so you can see you
know just go read my tutorial basically
text properties is more efficient and
generally for permanent coloring
such as syntax coloring of a programming
language
the color moves with the text you know
it's attached to the text
meanwhile the overlay is kind of
temporary highlight for example you have
a document you want to highlight all
currencies of certain word
you in that case usually you want to use
overlay
okay so anyway in our case we want to
use overlay okay so overlay so maker
overlay
uh begin end so begin end position will
be okay so we need a beginning and end
position so that will be
um
beginning okay mb for match beginning
exactly so this tells emax to
to
this returns the beginning position of
the match which is the metadata
that came from the search forward okay
so match beginning and match end
okay
zero means the whole the whole regular
expression what whatever we searched
okay so beginning end we got that
okay so shrink a little bit
and face bolt okay so we don't want
facebook we actually we want red
so
color red so how do you
color red so you look at
text properties
abbrev template create key map keyword
completion
write your own common command define
face there it is you want the face
face is emax jargon for a set of
coloring such as font size font color
background color
font which font you know that's a face
so there are building phase so let's
look at building face red so these are
the building face okay
um
let's use highlight okay so highlight
so in instead of bold we say highlight
okay so i think that's it
so
uh in set mark active
no
okay
that is our code now if i region again
now go back here
turn off global highline mod
okay now let's let's
let's make the comma
okay so
let's remove the space after comma now
we are going to call our command let's
call it
so add space after comma do it
fantastic but however this arrow so
you see it added
it highlight you see it highlighted the
last comma but it didn't highlight the
previous one undo do it again
you see it didn't highlight the previous
one so we need to fix it
oh yeah we need to put this inside the
loop you see
you see that that's a while loop
you need to put it inside the loop
of course
cut that put it inside the loop
okay and
also match n plus one because there's a
space so
let me show you this inc
for one plus
okay match end position of the end plus
one okay okay now the indentation is um
let's do it like that way okay so make
overlay match beginning and one plus
match in okay
eval the code
switch to this buffer
undo
so you can see all the comma is like
that
the
or the comma doesn't have a space
okay call command
do it
fantastic okay this is the arrow so
actually the uh
add one is a mistake so
we don't want to add one
why because
oh yeah so i guess when you do when you
call replace match it also changes the
the data about match okay if our buffer
go back here
let's redo this let's make some other
okay
close that don't save
new buffer paste
magnify
make it
okay so
replace comma space by comma do it do it
do it okay just two okay now call our
command
do it fantastic success
okay that's it
that's it for that function is it good
guys
this will add comma regardless if space
exists or not that's true
wait oh oh oh that's a that's a good
point fantastic thank you
so we need to again fix our code because
when you do it again it adds extra comma
you see
that's no good you want to make sure
that there is only
one space after comma
because sometimes you you make mistakes
you know you don't want you know like
sometimes you type the space so
okay so here we
all we have to do is change the search
forward so let me show you okay so you
can see
there's a search for word
and
we want to change it by
research forward regular expression
search forward
and here you want the comma
you want to search for comma followed by
not space okay
okay so what you can do is um
[Music]
so that's how you do regular expressions
so that
square bracket means any character
inside
and the first correct symbol means not
any of those characters so this
essentially means not space
okay comma not space okay now we remove
this line okay prettify the code
eval the region show the pink window go
back
go to the cruiser i mean go to the new
buffer close it
do you want to save no
new buffer
paste okay that's not let's copy this
copy
select all paste okay magnify
so replace comma space by comma
do it do it okay now let's call our code
wait we need let's say
okay let's test this way okay a
b
c
okay
this is code
it will it should just change the first
one not changing the second one so let's
do it
do it fantastic
let's try again a b
c
d
e
f
g now let's put a space here
okay
now let's
do it
fantastic you see that that one already
has space so there's no change now let's
what if we call this command again
do it fantastic
okay that's it
i think maybe that's it for today and uh
so
delete that
save no
okay now
now i want to put this code back into my
talk show so press the key wait press
the key
it's back to my talk show page
showing browser
there it is a code back in emacs
color it
showing browser
fantastic
okay
so how long have i been talking today 40
minutes
any questions comments
were the later letters replaced no
the letters are not replaced because
we are searching for remember we are
searching for comma
followed by
a
[Music]
followed by a anything that's not a
space
uh
[Music]
what
okay let me try maybe you have a point
so let's try it again
comma comma let's just say comma comma
comma okay three commas let's do it
[Music]
you are correct
this code up
you see comma comma comma now becomes
comma space comma that's incorrect so
close that
modify our code
okay so
yeah okay i was hoping not to um
get complex
okay
so
instead of using not space so this will
capture anything that's not a space
and also replace that so there are quite
a few ways to fix it so what we want
instead is
you know one way is just like slash
slash b
ah wait
[Music]
let's magnify okay so
so slash slash b
b means boundary okay
let's just try it run it run it i mean
evolve the code new buffer
comma comma comma magnify
call the command do it fantastic okay
let's try again abc
abc comma comma space okay let's try
that
let's make a copy okay so we're gonna do
it here do it
do it
so let's check
correctness
comma space correct
comma correct
uh
well what happens if you have comma
comma do you want to add a
no i mean okay so i think this is good
yeah so i think this is good
so
it does not
destroy any characters is that true
yes that's true and it changes comma
only if it's after a word that's right
you know it changes only when the
character next comma is a word character
so
so if it's comma comma or comma plus for
example comma
period
you know in some programming languages
you have all kind of weird or comma
equal or something you know so let's
call it
no change good
correct no change you know we are
getting into trial and error which is no
good okay when you code you don't want
to try and roll you want to think about
the problem
you know study the language
study the problem
you know exactly what is the problem
you know exactly which function you know
you master the language you know regular
expressions and
all that you know exactly what it does
then you code it one shot clean
not
trial and error oh you know let's try
something what if it's comma followed by
a dollar sign you know
they tell then then then it becomes the
you unit testing the agile okay no
good
okay you don't need test okay so i mean
you you know when it's very complex you
need testing but not for the um
general uh coding okay so let's so this
is the code okay
color it showing browser
okay that's it i think maybe i should i
think that's it 40 minutes today 46 and
let's close down you know we got more to
do
so we we solved this first problem
uh so if you like my stuff buy me a
drink okay
those of you watching
in real time or on youtube you know
donate
patreon paypal amazon gift card you can
find the links on my website
or buy you know buy my emacs tutorial
master emacs
okay emac this
learn a little emacs get you far when
you are if you are emacs uh user
or you can buy
you know one of my packages now i sell
them because
they've been open source for like
10 years 15 years no pay instead you
take support you know everyone is gonna
ask you a question how do you do that
how do you learn
so okay that's uh so
let's see
so
yeah that's it for today okay so any any
questions
have you considered standard of comedy
okay
i'm not into comedy that much
not that i would not suggest to use
rejects for most of this stuff but why
not kill yourself by trying to learn
emacs keys
what does that mean
what
okay i don't know what you guys are
saying uh but and let's get back to emac
at least okay let's not get into
something else
so
so let me demonstrate i'm gonna close
down okay that's it for today that's the
main thing so
there are some more commands i want to
write
let's save it
for next week you know for next video so
highlight unicode
uh convert minute second two seconds or
vice versa so that's another thing we
can do
and start up a case sentence i
talked about that you know uppercase
sentence for example
you know for the for example you're
looking at this line
this line i press a key
you see now it's uppercase okay undo
redo
undo
redo magnify
magnify see the full glory
undo
redo
okay bye guys
yeah bye
so um
yeah so let me just clean up my
code
shrink
so
that's it for today
so that's what we did today
and uh
the next things save it for next time
okay
and show in browser so that's today's
code
and i'm going to
move this code into soft like keys
okay bye