good morning everyone
welcome to another exam talk show today
is June 12th 2019 3 o clock p.m.
California time and today we're gonna
talk about basically random topics
I haven't said I haven't decided two
topics but mostly something like random
technical technical stuff Emacs
JavaScript and related technical and
today so I have here in the comment box
you can see so there are some topic
topics listed there or i so go over
there and pick a topic you know go to
that link some talk show page and pick a
topic and all possibly we are going to
do a live Emacs Lisp coding where the
command log mod the Emacs command log
mod you can see you can see the
keystrokes on the left side of this
window for our keyboard Oh black key
layout two strokes you know so because
I'm using average people but people when
I do demo people don't know you know
those are not most of you are using
quotient so I'm thinking of modifying
this package let's see command log mod
ok that's the
it says command log mod so this is the
package which is four hundred lines so
I'm thinking of modifying this package
you know as a live demo so that it shows
the quoting keyboard they are if desired
meaning that is going to do a conversion
in real-time so what do you like so guys
so so you know what do you like to see
the topics type in the comments and
let's get started actually so I mean
that's that's correct
you know it's get started but meanwhile
so we got two people watching say hi
okay so right now actually what I'm
doing is that I'm working on my website
so this is how to run a Java Script you
know there are some parts I need to edit
you know this is what I do every day so
browser JavaScript on so for example in
this screenshot I need a new screenshot
this screenshot is old this screenshot
is from and C 2016 okay and it's done on
Linux so I'm you know I want a new
screenshot and and we can do that but
that is not the main topic because
that's I said I don't suppose it's very
interesting
so guys okay we got three person
watching you know go to the link and you
know pick the topic you'd like to see
then you know then let's get started I'm
not going to do this page now let's go
okay first so so let's just go round
about go to my website and I'll go
my blogs and talk about something
interesting so keyboard block let's see
the keyboard apartment people vlog we
talked about those those yesterday
okay this we haven't talked you know the
other day so this one we haven't talked
about before
this is fascinating so this is a tangi
keyboard basically a Japanese keyboard
to type Chinese characters hold on
second living closer to also my because
my human is watch on TV TV
so I'm back I am back
so this kanji keyboard kanji keyboard
this is a Japanese keyboard to type
Chinese characters so it's huge it's got
480 keys what year is is this is 1989
you know but this way of typing Chinese
characters is extremely inefficient you
know that's why you know this is the
early days people have not created much
of a input methods now input method is a
basically it's a software method that
allows you to type characters you know
more than you know 30 alphabets you know
for example for Chinese or Japanese so
those are input methods you know if you
need to type Chinese or Japanese or
Korean you need to do that
but before input method are invented
this is 1989 so people you know the
Japanese they are also trying to you
know invent you know thinking about how
to type Chinese of Japanese characters
so in other days there are things like
this where are you you know HP has
several choices you know Knight possible
characters you can type and they are 500
something cheese it's extremely
inefficient you know you so anyway
that's interesting
so that's keyboard stuff
let's talk about bass keyboard the bass
keyboard is the one of the worst
keyboard okay don't I don't recommend
bass keyboard - keyboard is very popular
among programmers why for one reason and
one reason most ly for one reason
because not marketing you know if you
want to get the same quality of keyboard
they are a lot better ones you know and
cheaper in a gaming community and if you
do not like the cameras you know fancy
you know coloring and style you know Tim
pH style they are not you know paint
choices - for example let's go to PC
keyboards for example you can pick this
CM master keys PVG keyboard this is high
quality keyboard and it's better than
it's better than the bass keyboard you
know I don't like - keyboard I you know
I despise - keyboard because why because
when you are good morning FMS it's like
wait you know when you go when you um
let's see you know you know IIIi despise
- keyboard because
because they are you know the quality /
price ratio is no good is too high okay
and this day they fly they are popular
among programmers because they market to
book web programmers for example let's
let me show you this headphone okay feet
headphone this is extremely popular you
know you see all the young people you
know by these speed headphones the big
headphone as far as technology you know
pure quality everything is considered
divided by price you know divided by
price is important because you could
something could cost you know one dollar
versus something cost a hundred dollars
you know there's a big difference so
anyway you take the quality / price the
bead headphone is one of the worst
possible they are almost like a scam
however in the past like five or ten
years they become hugely popular you
know big brand is unheard of before they
become hugely popular why because they
because marketing you know they have
people you know the marketing is a
billion dollar business industry you
know they have people they they try they
try to make celebrities you know singers
and stars to wear them in some cases pay
them you know say hey Michael Jackson we
pay you you know ten ten thousand
dollars see without this headphone you
know to do a you know when you are
talking to you know when you are doing
YouTube or something so that's why they
are hugely popular but the quality is
you know it's so you know same
similarly waiting a similar way the task
keyboard is it's just no good okay -
keyboard is is no good I mean they are
reasonable quality but they are the the
price but basically you can get much
better deal if you go to in into the
King kima's community and
and by many many choices some of them
are like $30 like this optical switch
$40 very good optical switch or you can
buy the brand name you know CM
coolermaster Coolermaster those are also
excellent and many many other choices by
the way so anyway so that's the pass
keyboard and in the past few years they
started to go into the gamers community
you know because before you know they
arose as a keyboard quality keyboard for
programmers but now they could get into
gaming but the reason is easy to
understand because in in the chemical
community you have like hundred times
more people the market is hundred times
larger than the programmers community by
the way so bass keyboard is popular
among programmers but why but how come
you know the programmers doesn't know
about other things because you know
typically you tend to stay in your
community you know you don't have time
you never you know you are a programmer
you don't necessarily know about gaming
although some programmers are cameras
but in general gaming permit gaming
community and promote community they are
separate just like you know programming
programmers and mathematician community
they are separate you know
mathematicians they do their things you
know but what you read every day
the people you talk to the things you
hear I like different that's why
different communities like different
coaches get opinions and stuff your
perception or different
so if MSA is what are your thoughts are
low profile keyboards I feel like they
are more ergonomic and lest less
fatiguing when typing after having RSI
low profile keyboard are you talking
about non mechanical so in general okay
I don't think low profile keyboards are
a good thing at all I think they they I
mean it if if if you are typing
if you need to type a lot such as a
programmer you don't want low profile
keyboard I'm talking about low profile
such as such as you know you know
portable keyboards or Apple's keyboard
let's see and to get apples keyboard and
Apple Apple's keyboard are the worst
with respect to organ Amex Apple
keyboards today
like this year you know in the past two
years three years apples keyboard are
the worst not just economics but also
worst in quality was you know they may
get damaged you cannot be repaired we
have to buy a whole thing like every
three months you know if you are in the
Apple community you know it's it's well
known Apple keyboards so Apple keyboards
today is very bad but in general Apple
keyboards are the worst in terms of
ergonomics if you are a programmer you
know don't use Apple keyboard it's gonna
it's gonna you gonna get our side you
know it won't happen it's not happening
right now but who knows you know that's
the thing you know most people all those
people who got RSI you know the years
before they do now I think oh that won't
happen to me until it happens to you so
don't buy yourself so don't buy Apple
keyboards and also about these low
profile keyboards they are no good ok
never type on a laptop keyboard for
longer than you know five minutes its
laptop keyboard that got me eyesight the
foot my first hour I say in 2006 so my
opinion about low profile keyboards no
good except except when they are
mechanical now today you have several
mechanical kind of lower low profile
like this let me show you I have one
actually I wonder if I can show you yeah
let me show you them on a second
so this is habit keyboard listen they
say me of SME one for my review and this
is low profile key mechanical keyboard
so the travel is like half of the
typical Cherry MX keyboard so this I
recommend I recommend very much as far
as how does this compare to a normal
mechanical piece I don't have much your
opinion about that so let me actually
let me show you the keyboard now my
camera is extremely bad so it's you know
you won't see much out of it but anyway
so this is you know this is my desktop
let's see if I can do this
okay I'm gonna change some settings here
so you can see a big video
give me a minute
you
okay now you can hear me and let me add
the video video capture device okay
video coming up USB camera nice sixty
okay so there's a video but let me
change it so it's even bigger okay so
anyway so that's my keyboard and this is
the havoc keyboard so I actually never
use this for like more than an hour so I
can paint but anyway this is not
economic I must have economic ones so I
don't actually I haven't used it much
that is why if it is ergonomic I'll
definitely gonna use it for week weeks
and see how they compare but anyway so
so if you want thin profile go for this
this is good you know mechanical thing
profile keys but never never things like
apples keyboard of all black art
keyboards so that's my opinion about
keyboard about the low part Popeye okey
so anything else
so yeah okay so that that's about
keyboard let's go to another topic name
so keyboard programming there's this
interesting interesting things about
Unicode so in Unicode you have these
boxes this these characters that is
designed to draw borders and boxes for
example these are you or Unicode
characters you can see the character
name pumps drawing light vertical and
left that's the starter and this one is
flux drawing heavy down and left now you
can create these boxes you can create a
maze and there are also these characters
that you can create these images so
that's a fun thing too so those are
called Unicode drawing they are
typically called you parks drawing that
Curtis parks throwing characters and
then you have these block yeah block
character stop shade medium shade tight
shape okay that's about that UNIX web
dev
okay
I feel kind of lost talking about these
random things it's because it doesn't
seems to be focused and you know I
somehow it's like it no interest okay so
I got this fan like 10 years ago from
Chinatown
I guess so this is classic Chinese fan
it's so hard today in California in you
know I mean San Francisco mountain view
area in this week as three days is
extremely hot but however it's no harder
than then Taiwan or South Asia those
countries so let's start this
let's go through the topics then let's
see what else download you know Steve
Jobs and idiocy of typography now this
is one of my big rant the gist let's see
how long I've been talking the gist of
this thing is you know in typography
community similar things happens in
photography community calligraphy
community grammar chameleons grammarians
community okay you got this people these
idiots they choke up their stuff is they
kind of like a high art you know like in
typography community you know there
there is this documentary documentary
okay this is made in 2007 it's kind of a
movie so last for an hour so they talked
about a type of typography and the
heretical font I mean even go to let's
go to my website a Saudi website so you
can actually see the YouTube videos you
don't see that on my browser here
because I don't have JavaScript on and
also it's my local
file so you go to the info then you go
to web there
code and Benny in UK oh that's
interesting but is that isn't UK summer
right now UK which part of UK are you
had so anyway so good go to the Donald
Knuth's Steve Jobs and idiocy of
typography you know so why Donald knows
and why Steve Jobs because both of them
fail into type architect ography first
both of them are I mean they are high
achievers you know they have done great
things but both of them are inspired by
typography so that's a good aspect of
typography typography you know Donald
Knuth spend something like 10 years to
create tick
you know the typesetting language solid
black okay let me show you this article
you might have already seen this algo is
very popular the tech pestilence why
tech sucks okay this is one of my
article in fact I did a talk show on
this thing you know so Donald Knuth the
famous computer scientists created this
tech technology to typeset mathematics
not just for math but for tech
typesetting you know typography why he
did that because when he was writing his
book the art of programming the there is
no digital typography you know it's you
know this is in the 1970s 1980s you
don't have you know it's not right back
today you have found you know true type
font or whatever you can print you know
laser laser printers and whatnot they
don't have that practice so Donald Knuth
he wants to write the other programming
and in that book there's a lot math
formulas back in the 1970s and 80s math
are always is
they are you know usually typeset using
the mono space courier you know very
ugly so analysis you know try to solve
the problem so he basically spent ten
years and he created Tech and the MIT I
found and you know basically nobody uses
and to me Tech is one of the worst
technology you see it's not just you
know it's a pestilence if you are
interested you know read this article
and read my talk show over there we are
now going to talk about that today but
so who knows you know he he spent ten
years yak shaving to create the tech
instead of working on his you know the
art of computer the other programming
because you know dolly I don't it's
supposed to be seven volumes but may not
only three or four volume came up I
don't think he can do it you know he's
like 80 years old now but anyway you
know that's called yak saving yak
shaving you know by the way so let's see
sorry
yak shaving there's an article from
1980s about yak shaving best to for yak
shaving Emacs okay this article is from
year to year 2000 okay so I don't think
this is the earliest article on yak
shaving but you can read that is fun
eMac is the best tool for yak shaving so
anyways so that's know what what how how
he relates to technology so he is
actually a pioneer of modern digital
typography now Steve Jobs is also very
is also fair you know fair into
typography because you know
you know if you search Steve Jobs in
tight type of typography on YouTube
you'll find some stories I'm not going
to repeat them basically he you know
he's inspired by typography so you know
so very much on the Mac you have you
know Mac in the 1990s is the most
beautiful graphics but anyway back to
the topic the the thing about typography
and community is that they they think
you know when you listen to for example
when you watch this this article okay
this YouTube when you talk to this oh
you go on I read some type type type of
a community you know you listen to them
they are bunch of idiots okay they are
like how do you compare you know it's
like you know how in photography
community you know photographers some of
them think the photography is the
greatest art you know they show some
pictures of the you know historical
photos you know maybe in world war or
maybe in protests riots
you know historical moments you know
great photos and they choke up to oh
this is how great how important it is
that's all okay for half of it
is nothing no odd about this is like
little to none no art about it you oh
you have is the technology is a camera
you know you just take photos you just
take photos and in fact that's what we
have but that's what we are doing today
everyone's got a cell phone it's kind of
you know camera and you just take photos
this you know it's not like for the
photography is no way or compared to
painting painting you actually have to
take ten years to learn
not so with so you know when you
actually compare the heart there's
really no art in photography you know
it's like all okay so that's
that's photography and in a same thing
you can see it's that kind of a same
thing with the comb areas you know like
sometimes you
have to go marry like some paid pittance
you know grandma sensitive or sometimes
called ramen as nazies you know they say
Oh split infinitive oh you know the many
of the technical grandma jargons they
say you know how important our kites you
know they have like tens of style guides
like the the the AP prayer style guides
the what whatever is whatever standard
the past and you know the style guide
you know like they have lots of books
guys on how to punctuation should be
used you know let's go to let's show you
another article the more on necessities
of typography okay let's show you that
article this typography idiot so
although all these people are idiots
like I - and - okay you know
typographers are concerned about - and -
because they are actually different you
know some of them are longer a bit
longer in the finger and positioned a
little bit higher then you know there
they are like five types of - all dashes
you know so look at this these morons
you know this is from Wikipedia actually
this this this passage is from Wikipedia
around year 2010 or some Erica
so he says traditionally an e/m - like
so or space
eeehm - like so has been used for a - in
running text the elements of typographic
style recommends the more concise spaced
en - like so and argues that the length
and visual magnitude an e/m - belongs to
the padded and cosseted aesthetic of
Victorian typography you know they are
tracked they are making fun of each
other you know each different schools of
that
typography guides okay nan says the
spaced en-dash
is also the house style for certain
major publishers penguin
Cambridge University Press and Routledge
among them however some long-standing
typographical guides such as the Chicago
Manual of style still recommend unfazed
p.m. dashes dashes for this purpose the
Ox of all guide to style year 2002
section 5 point 1010 acknowledge is that
you know so this is a glimpse of how
this how these typography communities
that the the type of things and attitude
and tone they are talking about so it's
like each one of them is like they've
got a hate and soul you know in practice
it doesn't matter you know you can
just use the ugly at s key - you know
let me show you ugly SP - like so and
I'll be it okay you know that's that's
this is the s key - okay let me show you
the en - this is e m - oops
eeehm - let me show that so ii am i have
a om - so the key is M - okay so this is
e m - this is a C - you cannot actually
see the difference unless I change the
Emacs want to be something not the mano
space so let's do that
pitch so now you can see you see this is
a ski - this is Ian -
and let me show you the en - okay that's
Ian - and let me show you figure - this
type of graphical idiots have all these
things the fee good - actually I don't
think I have the shortcut for it I do
okay this is the figure - and this this
is the - - now now this ASCII character
is called
- man - - when you just press the the
minus key on your keyboard okay actually
let me show you the Unicode so that you
can actually see clearly what they are
so you so you can see me so you can see
that so you got a M - you got Ian - you
got figure - you got - Mac - - now if
you really care about these things you
know if you are of the pedantic
typographer kind of people then you know
each of them have proper uses for for
example I'm not going not going to
explain but good morning is shown thank
you for the donation I'm gonna be the
commenting a bit so yam - yet you know
so these are things typographers are
concerned about not just that then they
are they then okay then they are
concerned about ligatures like the
stupid ligatures and and by the
way typography is also one of the thing
that this elite type of hacker idiots
chant about it all the time especially
the unix you know the UNIX philosophy
fax these type of people champ about
this all the time like they
talk about our hacker news about you
know they are just idiotic okay so let's
go back to the topic of yeah the topic
of the yeah okay we are on topic we are
talking about how the typography
communities in idiotic the bottom line
is that they they are craft okay that
the typography is a craft or grammar
writing as a craft or calligraphy or
photography as a craft they they are you
know they are not like very difficult I
mean really something critical art okay
they are not what these people community
claim them to be these people when you
watch like you watch this documented
documentary they the way they talk you
can see that they think they are the
kings like the typography like you know
they take camera you know of all the
people or the you know street you know
science advertisements you know they
show hepatica type you know
they show how it is everywhere they talk
about how it affects your mood you know
they talk about how oh because i'm
Avantika because then it affects
humanity smooth Aminata
is this
idiots people okay and a lot of
programmers follow this kind of flow
your flow like I have my followers who
do that but really it's this it's like
it you know it's it's blown out of
proportion is it's really the typography
it's not really that critical not
important at all I mean yeah so okay so
that that basically is the topic about
this typography yeah that that kind of
covers this so let me read the comments
so
[Music]
Midlands in the UK Midlands where is
milind and yes is summer but the weather
has been bad this week okay as long john
says as soon as whatever type of graphic
scheme you are using is consistent it
shouldn't matter which you use you're
welcome yeah thanks so thank you for the
donation quick episode thank you so I
think typography is critical insofar as
communication is critical good
typography should communicate well no I
don't think so I disagree well I mean
that's the thing that is the thing you
see so the if you cream type typography
is critical
insofar as communication is critical
well communication is absolutely
critical because that's you know we have
to communicate to do anything -
including - you know keep keep us being
alive we have to communicate but not
typography you know ten feet without
typography you can all you need you know
you don't need you can use mono space
foggy
you know just pick the most ugly fonts
without any you know the so-called
typography without any of that pick the
most ugly fun possible and we basically
communicate like you know there's no
lost of content no loss of anything now
with well of course that depends on how
what do you mean by typography you know
like so good you know some people when
they stink typography they include like
they were you know they include you know
printing they say printing that you know
if you cream printing is typography then
there's no argument of course printing
is critical
Prinny is you know critically important
without printing or technology we're
gonna fall apart you know the we the
whole USA but you know by next month you
wouldn't have food to eat so printing is
critical but printing is not typography
okay but you know if buddy
you are the typography fan you might you
know kind of include training as part of
Tiger typography you know so you know so
that depends on your definition but if
you you know think typography if you
define it is a kind of sort of art of
designing types you know typefaces font
designing printing like which like how
many spaces between lines how long how
long a line should be things like that
then that is typography that is actually
the definition proper you know
technically proper and is this critical
not really is this is it good we're good
to have yes obviously you know it's good
to have you know nice you know design
you know you have plenty of space you
know make it easy to read but also
another thing about type of typography
is that they say they claim for example
of these dashes they would claim it
makes it easy to read but not really
okay
some things in typography does influence
the ease of readings for example line
length and how many space between lines
that's obviously important you know
because you know or if the font is too
small or it you know it's critical but
that's not typically what this
typography people like if you watch this
documentary documentary that's not
typically what these kind of people talk
about they talk about the you
know little design issues like like this
Ian - me and - the thing you know the
ligature you know that's that's the
that's their concern and especially
donald knuth idiots with his teeth
you know this micro positioning of a
symbol like to him it's the important to
get it right like a little bit micro
pica you know whatever subpixels
okay so that autumn optimized good
communication so yeah so I think that
concludes okay that's a good topic today
that concludes the topic about
typography Google Maps let's go and look
check out where is Midlands Midlands in
England okay so the Midlands is the
geographical middle region of England oh
okay so that's kind of just a general
word I guess the party in between north
and south okay okay so that's typography
now I wonder I should whether I should
continue and talk something more about
typography because you know after all
that's a that's a good topic 40 40 40
minutes so anything else anything else
Sean and FMS so I'm thinking maybe
that's it for today because usually I be
I talk for you know an hour then becomes
90 minutes name becomes 2 hours so I
think it's probably better you know I
just talk one topic per video you know
like maybe today it's a good time to say
goodbye and you know this tomorrow and
do next one so so typography yeah
there's something about yeah it's it's
one of my big wrench let's see what else
okay so let me go over some of my other
blog things let's just see
so keyboard apartment programming
Department what we have okay this is a
bit history the history of get you can
see this is my blog from 2012 I say I
say been using it for several months now
before was SVN and CVS before I can say
I find get better kids man pages are
totally incomprehensible that is true
that is still true today in fact I was
just reading you know I was just trying
to do something today and get you know
about how to read it's totally
incomprehensible like this not many
people who actually understand it okay
of course you go to hacker news just
like the you know like in the 1990s you
have UNIX people talking about esoteric
things they think they understand but
they but it's really you know not very
many people understand kid really and
that's bad because you know if you look
at the whole popular population when you
create a tool it must be designed you
know how it however you know you think
it is good technically but the design
must be you know you must look at how
many percentage of the population can
use your tool can understand your tool
you know to to a good degree let's say
90 80 percent so if you look at the
population so forget how many percent
actually understand get you know if you
look at all the programmers who have to
use kid every day how many percent ten
percent no less five percent less one
percent
well I would say actually this depending
on what you know just to what degree you
claim you want to say to understand get
you know like it is just crap you know
but but but these kind of opinions will
go nowhere to order
you know UNIX philosophy things people
in fact get get as a tour is one of is
the last it's the last software of the
unit's philosophy school I would claim
of the UNIX school okay because it is
actually not like small small spherical
kitties like it kind of like huge let's
see what sorry get chicken real my
roommate is back so so I have a good
tutorial okay basic here basics here and
if you have used git then you know the
complexity I'm sure you know you know
you already know how how impossible to
understand it is but if you haven't used
it you know for example one example is
referred change yes and and the
difference you know you have the okay
River change you know you have git
checkout you have had you have this
checkout head checkout him and you can
check out a commit ID and you can revert
to you know it's very complex actually
and in fact if you try to read the man
page okay let me call the real git
checkout okay let's read the man page
you can see that you know nobody
understand you know I would cram this
than 1% let let me put a scientific
scientific
so this cream can be verified you know
as yes or no true or false
okay I would claim that less than 1% of
all the people who makes a living by
programming you know professional coders
who you know people whose primary income
is from programming okay of all those
people who has used it okay
well this one's a week okay every every
week once a week of all those people I
would claim less than 1% of people
actually understand get let me let me
make it more precise let's say less less
than 1% of people who can actually um
well understand it
yeah we can make it more precise by
let's say less than 1% people who
understand let's say this syntax who can
actually explain this thing I skip
checkout branch then start point you
know like you just should you just show
them this lie and tell them to explain
and you can you can verify whether they
succeeded in their explanation by for
example you ask 100 programmers to
listen to his explanation and see if
those programmers understand what he is
talking about so that's a claim okay
less than 1% for saying that people
understand get so that so that means is
it's not good um - okay well in one
sense you can you could say it's
actually some tool are good even though
most people do not understand it because
some tools are for example you could
sprain you could say you know that some
tools are low level tools you know so
they provide some kind of foundation I
mean they are low level so so on top of
the tool you can create
oh you know GUI or whatever you know but
you rely on the notable thing but that's
not true for kid you know kid is not a
low-level - okay
it's a code reversion system
it's not in any sense a low-level tool
its low-level only because it's it's its
design its exhibit low-level nice
because everything is like be
incomprehensible that is why and by the
way I I think a few years ago I have
seen a PhD thesis that that says a you
know the thesis is you know his ph.d
paper is about ravit it kind of a new
kid okay he claims you know he make made
a comment like it is nobody understand
it you know he incomprehensible and he
narrows down you know so this is his PhD
research he narrows down the problems
and he creates he created a new system
based on kid ok but a new system that
don't have this complexity so so I've
seen a PhD paper on that I think you can
probably probably find it you know you
know if you just search for get I don't
know it might be difficult to find it
but anyway yeah I think it was on Hacker
News anyway so it's a PhD paper but you
see I I think such a paper is really of
little practical effect I mean the life
is just gonna go on over his comment
read about that you know that's that's
another thing about technology is that
people really actually it is not the
quality of design that get get software
popular it is not that at all in fact
the mostly is about some many other
factors social factors about marketing
for example
about for example white kid became
popular you know back then so I was
talking about this my old block you know
there was back then you disobey sigh
it's just so funny it's so funny to hear
about it now do you see these people
this article white switch to pasa pasa
is the alternative we wish ravit
software version system okay by
canonical so they wrote an article why
switch to pasa in 2009 now remember in
2009 they are several other skid is one
of them mercury is one of them pasa is
one of them is mercury small way or no
get mercury is the two most popular then
do you have pasa they I think you have
yeah you have others but back then in
2009 no no one of them is more popular
than the other so they are like
competing eventually get warm out you
know basically all the other disappear
like they nobody is using them anymore
eventually you know one by one so what I
want to say before get software revision
systems it is very complex and
oh yeah white white kid became popular
you know popular popularity of
programming languages in software mostly
due to social causes almost nothing
having to do with the quality of the
design you know or the language okay so
kid
why did get warmer because first of all
because Lina's Lina's Lena's mother
Nina's Lina's you know he's very
extremely famous because he wrote the
Linux kernel so he's already you know a
huge major celebrity as a star so he
created a kid so there is a tremendous
marketing associated with that you know
this is just because like for example if
back in 2009
if you are new you know you want to pick
a software division system oh you know
so you see oh this kid is a mercury or
this about buzzer then you then then you
saw you know okay T is not by Lina's
Lina's oh yeah I know that guy oh quit
oh yeah he's a great code at all so you
automatically you know there's a
tremendous positive positive info for
you to pick it already without actually
you know trying it the no Curie you know
me I don't think he's made it's created
by any anyone's popular you know it so
there's no such marketing force for
mercury the positive things you heard
about ma mercury would be its simplicity
I would say and also because it's
written on in the Ruby
yeah I think it's written on Ruby Ruby
your pattern so remember back in 2009
Ruby on where you B's was very popular
back then because Ruby on Rails around
the same time so you know Ruby is over
the place so you'll be unreal oh this
you know it was a big framework
revolution then later on other language
copied it so so so I think mercury is
Rita Ruby don't quote me on that Ruby or
Python so maybe you see Oh Ruby oh great
yeah you know I'm a I'm a Ruby
programmer and you know so if I choose
mercury you know I would be able to give
me a gift it would give me more power so
that's one of the positive point about
mercury and and it's simple to
understand you know and pasa is mostly
the the the high point about pasa is
like it's free software support it is
the most one of the mono choices is one
of the most free free software like
copyleft and all that but they failed
they are the first one to go they failed
miserably and today he may even Emacs is
is using it now okay so that's about it
today so okay no more comments so ten
more seconds
now I'm gonna shut down type anything
any questions and thank you guys for
watching
have a good day more good stuff what
like what kind of good stuff like
tutorial 1 because tutorial wise you
know forget tutorial wise I don't really
have much thing to say because you know
and so I have this teacher for real and
this sketch tutorial they are focused on
the most practical things you need to do
like every P every person who uses get
you know there are certain commands you
use every day you don't have to
understand the get you know but for most
people you just you know get poor kid
come on get poor get commit you know
kids status it come in that's it you
know that's you know and sometimes you
need to get lock and you know so my my
key tutorial is the you know focus on
the most practical commands it may just
tell you the commands they do not act
you know try to explain kid because it's
it's almost impossible to actually
explain kid ok but you do have some
effect use about what is head you know
so that's what have the problem with kid
you have all these jargons head so
anyway so much you draw is mostly
practical so you know if you never used
it I think this might be useful to you
as far as rent goes I don't have much
friend about Gibbs yeah so I accept you
know I think it's one of the worst you
know what whatever rent I already talked
about ok thank you guys for watching
thank you Sean bye have a good day