good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
xl tv 2020
may 16th saturday 7 00 p.m
san francisco time how are you guys
hello luis cook captain
alan vanya and
uh atmostic
hello guys so we don't have a topic
today
what is the topic going to be today
so i don't have a topic you know post
your questions
uh put my name to it and we'll talk
about it
uh as usual we have 1 000 topics but the
thing is you know someone has to break
the ice
someone has to say things then once i
look at something
then there is fantastic topics okay
uh now let's go to let's for example
let's go to
art block art
block okay and let's look at
uh rage
uh comics you know rage comics is
fascinating
okay uh let's put this here so you can
see
let's see look at my windows
rage comic that's what we need rage
comics
pepe let's show pepe now but
now here's a video that's a fantastic
video someone made
you know there are two videos here both
of them are fantastic
the first one is titled hong kong
pepe and this guy whoever created this
you know
he he has a youtube account however the
original
video he made it private for some reason
i don't know why probably because google
censorship but anyway let me show you
okay
so go to talk show and today's talk show
and let's uh put on uh
pepe and its history and also these rage
comics
now rage comics is also really fantastic
thing
you know this these are uh what you
would call folk
art that is artwork made by common
people
not professional artists
uh you know and not academic you know
high art that's what they call high art
like
uh you know picasso and stuff
uh folk this is and and today the
millennial generation
idiots they call these memes like memes
or
idiots these these are called folk
folk folk folk
art proper okay so we have rage comics
now uh why is it fantastic because rich
comics
is you know made made by people but
it captures the human emotion
in the most basic
manner possible captures human emotion
in the most
basic manner possible look at this one
this this is me okay
[Laughter]
and uh so we and and these are
characters from rage comic you know from
4chan
and this is oh this is uh probably 10
years old by now
um and you know you look at these
you know has anyone done research or
compilation of who
you know the guy who draw any of these
faces for example we have a few famous
ones for example
this girl you know uh usually each one
of them has a name
this girl and this this face this face
this face this face
this phase you see they are pretty uh
fairly simple this phase for example
fairly simple but they capture
the human um facial expression
and of course some of them are uh from
uh photos for example the jackie chan
uh and i i think this guy
and this guy is a chinese basketball
player
and there we have obama uh those
those are not good art those are kind of
idiotic things
but you know and and look at this one
you know the one side black one side
white you know
it's that's art you know that's art
that's great art
this you know using this seal weight
style and it it captures
the mood you know something how do you
describe it
uh some dark you know sadness chocolate
darkness looming or
melancholy or void
and we have this cereal guy
so this rage comics you know i uh they
are fantastic
when they when rage comic began about
i don't know 2008 or something by the
way you can find them
an article on wikipedia you know the
history of it when it began
the first few years they are fantastic
then gradually they become
more uh lemon
and also we have this guy you know this
guy is sitting in front of computers
just staring at the one on the screen
and you know it's fantastic so that's
about rage comics
and let me show you okay
and there's a quote to go with it oh the
th
is a great history there oh
brave new words that have such people in
it
now this is shakespeare's the tempest
originally you know shakespeare's
tempest
act 5 scene 1 and it is also
quoted quoted in flatland the romans of
many dimensions
and also quoted by brave new world by
aldous huxley those are both
both of these are famous fictions
flatland a romance of many dimensions
let me
move it here so you can see
uh am i doing okay
keep the comments coming guys okay
uh youtube not receiving enough video on
maintain smooth stream
[ __ ] yourself uh
okay let's go back to what i was talking
about rage comics
okay sakura lighter who is it alan
eric good morning uh
hello master hello master
xr fans
[Laughter]
neuro craft hello neuro craft
nimshan shikoh hello
jesus someone gave me 100
what kind of money is that uh
oh jesus i don't know what kind of money
is that let's look it up
vanya thank you vanya for the money
that's what i'm here for that's my xrtv4
crescent moon one side dark one side
white
captures the groom exactly well put
exactly groom is the word groom is the
proper word
to describe that uh
that uh this guy okay groom
so okay so let's let me finish the what
we were talking about so rage comic you
know
uh oh brave new words that has had that
have such people
in it this uh okay so
hold on a second let me let's prepare
today's talk show
okay let's get the topics up so we have
rage comics and we have pepe
let me just let me talk about that pepe
okay
uh rage comments pepe and let me talk
about that
uh this this money what
is it let's find out what money is that
oh and and and and um wait
that's a great quote chris and moon one
side dot
one side black one side white
captures the groom okay let's copy that
thank you vanya
magnify so you can see better and uh
okay
and exhaust start command mod
so you can see oops [ __ ] that's not what
what okay let's let's do this okay so on
this pink window you can see
all my emacs commands for those of you
emacs users so you can
observe the official efficiency of it
let me adjust it properly
okay so today's talk show we have uh
so rage comics and
let's go back to where is my firefox you
know
and let me try to tell you about this uh
way of manipulating windows yeah some of
the day
so let me show you okay so rage comics
pep and it's history
uh and that okay so let's um
reach comics okay so rage comics you
have
these quotes okay
and then you have flatland okay flatland
and brave new words
yeah i'm not being efficient here
flawless and brave new words that has
such people in it um
hold on second flagland okay flatland
copy it copy it and go back here
yeah show the keystrokes there there we
have
oh great many comments we are talking
well
i'm going to answer the comments okay so
let's
talk about um
the pepe and his it's history okay let's
talk about this page
pepe and it's history no you know pepe
you guys are probably have seen this is
quite funny you know
and these people today well we have to
thank
we have to give credit to where the
credit is due
the millennial generation these idiots
but they
you know they some of them got talents
they
they created the rage comics and they
also created this
meme stuff memes you know it's not easy
to create a great meme you know they say
viral you know this millennial
generation idiots
jargon's viral it's not easy however
you know the scientists have and
psychologists
have especially the from google you know
these big corporations they
marketing marketing department
for something to go viral is critically
important in a capitalistic
society such as usa because that's
marketing that's what
that's the that's a success of marketing
by the way did you know
a diamond is forever have you ever
heard of that phrase now that is one of
the most
successful marketing okay a diamond is
forever
that is that is a phrase created by the
db
or diamond company they created the
phrase a diamond is forever and
then that phrase stuck in every
american's
mind you know it's just it's becomes
part of your brain
part of your thinking especially of
course for women
because the women they want they love
diamonds because they
you know that's uh gift gifts from men
and wedding you know you are supposed to
give the girl
diamonds diamonds is forever this phrase
is the mo what is the most successful
marketing phrase in uh
in modern america in the past 100 years
or something
so because because now every time you
know if you
going to marry someone you are going
to give a diamond tip usually oh you
know usually that's
like supposed to be the tradition it
becomes a tradition
not so 100 years ago you know it's not
like that
but because you know so there's the uh
diamond a diamond is forever
let's search i have an article on that
of course
let's see if we can find my article okay
exactly your diamond is forever
there it is now this is a um sensitive
topic
you know i'm i'm going to get banned if
i talk too much about it but let's look
have a look
the female mentality okay now someone
will accuse me of being misogynist
you know they don't even know what that
word means
anyway the you know you see the girl
looking at the guy
the guy's head is a house
now this is the ad now remember now this
is not just
i i didn't draw it this is an ad
for mortgages and this ad appeared
around 2003
now you see this is before the social
justice [ __ ] time
you know social justice the gun began
mostly
they they rose to the top around 2016.
okay but you know they you know they
started to rise let's say 2010
the social justice kind of thinking but
anyway this ad is 2003. you cannot have
this ad today
if you have this ad today oh my god this
is you're gonna be canceled you know the
cancer culture of culture [ __ ] this
[ __ ] the millennials [ __ ] the social
justice
but anyway this this is white people
american
add you know plaster over yahoo you know
the
big giant websites a girl looking at the
guy with with a big house because
because this ad captures the mentality
of
uh women i mean the tradition of society
you know women picks men you know men
a guy wants to [ __ ] every girl so we
typically women has a choice you know
you the they pick
who they want to marry with who they
want to have sex with
so that's the um anyway that's reality
that's that's how
things are in the world and there's a
reason for that why is it women
choose why can how come why is it not
for example a woman
a woman wants to [ __ ] every guy but
while guys are kind of you know they
want only one
one one right uh woman why is that why
is it
not like that well because biology you
know there are
good reasons i talked about these um
once or twice before
so there it is there it is you see now
here is another ad
okay showing two diamonds one is a small
one
you know a small one and and the other
one is
big one now the small one has the
caption oh michael you shouldn't have
the big one has the caption oh michael
diamonds
so guys start to uh learn golan
okay start to learn programming so one
day you have
your possess the ability to
to um to endow
girls of your choice with these things
you know
so this is an ad this ad by the way this
ad is on time magazine
you know one of the most respected
magazines
in english time magazine of usa american
time magazine 2002
uh november 4 4 this
ad came from time magazine 2002
okay so so what is this
so then it comes the phrase a diamond is
forever you see
you see a diamond is forever so this ad
is
uh paid by you know the what's the
company
uh you know i think it's dbs i'm
yeah so anyway so you see this ad again
it's a successful ad because it kind it
kind of captures
the the how things are the way things
are just like rich comics you know
we we talked about rage comics right
uh let's see
yeah okay hold on a second let me
copy the link i need to get the link so
we can
so we have a record of what we talked
about
a diamond is forever okay
show in browser so that those are the
topics we've been talk
we've been talking about
okay lots of comments i'm going to get
to them
am i doing okay i suppose oh like okay
so that 100
money is 1.3 dollars
okay um so okay so let's let's this is
where are we where are we so
so diamond is forever you know that's
one of the most successful marketing by
the way if you have ever studied
marketing
or if you are not a nerd you know a lot
of people most people are not nerds so
you
they have been you know one of the
common job is
for example salesman salesman is one of
the common job
almost anyone can do as long as you know
you can talk
so so when you join the sales force
you know they show you books about how
to do marketing how to be a great
salesman
you know how to pursue persuade people
to buy things
they don't want so so
there are huge tons of marketing books
you know and
and in them you'll find this they'll
talk about these
diamonds forever you know this is one of
the greatest
marketing success okay so back to
you know so i was saying you see these
two ads they capture
how things are just like the rage
comments comics okay
you know they they in order to be
successful you want to be truthful
when people you know like comedians for
example successful comedians when they
say
when you say something it kind of
capture the situation capture
how things are so
so that's about okay rage comics and
diamond is forever let's copy that
okay so let's hold on a second
uh and let's i'm gonna talk about pepe
okay
in a second
so let's talk about pepe okay so let's
see pepe
pepe and it's history now now in this
page there are two videos both are
fantastic the first one is a great art
great art made by this guy he's got a
youtube account let's play a bit
uh it's too loud jesus hold up
you see you know you can go to my
website and watch this
or just search for hong kong pepe
now this is not easy to make okay this
must be his name
simon nietzsche me something like that
it must be him to create it so i've
looked at his youtube
uh he he's got a few youtube videos you
know it's not easy to
do this he must be a professional
working
in the uh with multimedia today you know
since the millennial generation since
about 2010
there is a new profession kind of the
rise of a new profession that is digital
media profession
oh digital media profession
well thank you again uh vanya
so uh there's a question let me answer
the question okay
uh
the wolf guys jordan bellfort the wolf
of wall street has 75
giga uh
gigabytes of sales tutorials learn from
wolfgang
so okay so pepe so so um
so this guy created this great you know
digital media is a new kind of new
profession
um you know you know like before
be before the race of digital media you
have
for nerds you know who work with
computers you have you know maybe
3d artists uh and you know 3d
3d artist is important for example all
the animations movies you know 3d
uh special effects you need that and
then then you have programmers like us
you know we
use computers but but beginning around
you know late 2000s or 2010 let's say
there's more and more needs of this
digital media
uh experts you know so you can
manipulate photos photoshop
and create these uh memes like these you
know
or 3d programs like art you know
actually
alan it's kind of uh like that
so the other day alan is doing showing
us how to do
blender you know uh creating a thing in
blender 3d
so but so so that you know they becomes
a profession
a digital media expert
uh which i don't know how to do you know
um so back to these so this is a great
artwork now
now the the second one the history of
pepe this is
uh fantastic okay this this video is 10
minutes
but it gives you a account of the
entire history of pepe you know what why
is it represent
become becomes a meme and you know quite
interesting i didn't know much of it
because i
wasn't you know i know you know i'm too
old i'm kind of
much older than you guys so i know the
history of the internet i know the
4chan i i watched i witnessed
the birth of 4chan
wikipedia reddit uh hacker news for
example
discuss and blogs blogger for example i
witnessed the birth of these
things and and before wikipedia then the
first one is slash
slash dot you know so
i've been using internet since uh 1992
technically actually before the internet
there's
aol online i didn't use there's a
compuserve so i started to basically i
started to use
the online network network since 1991
with compute serve okay compute service
online service
um you know so so
in 1995 the internet kind of began
then it becomes more and more and more
popular so i've
you know seen it all but however the
the fortune the internet memes so they
began around you know beginning it
mostly began with 4chan
4chan so pep is also came out of 4chan
i didn't really pay much attention i
mean i'm not
part of this group like it's
you know i see it i go there sometimes
but i'm not
you know that into it so i didn't know
what's going on with the pepe until like
2016.
you start to see it everywhere but so
anyway
uh watch this video okay it captures
some
uh short summary of the history and i
think it's
you know i i do i don't have time to
verify it but i think it's a
good account
so let me read the comments okay so pepe
so let's
that's about pepe and we gonna
remember there's a quote so let me uh
quickly talk about this thing
flatland a romance of many dimensions
and there are two quotes in this book
one is
all brave new words that have such
people in them
now this is one of my favorite quote of
all times
all brave new words that have such
people in them
such as the people on 4chan you know
like and
all our discord you know sadly discord
joining sadly discord okay
now the you see when you look at people
you know it is like diversity you know
that's proper english word diverse not
not as
the malay the social justice scan is
you know meaning of that diversity is
the proper word you know you
you see all sorts of people you have
presidents
you have prostitutes you have
politicians you have
uh unctuous salesmen you have
businessmen
you know magnets or you know
billionaires then you have
poor you know homeless people uh
then we have you know nuts programmers
and and people with psychological
problems you know also the people
uh some people you know the lifestyles
are very different than you have
monks you know that exist monks who
really really live in uh oh oh still
life
i'm kind of but you know not not like
the typical monks
you know so it's when you look at you
know all the words you know peop
you know all the people in the world
it's really uh diverse all brave new
words that have such people in them so
that's one of my favorite quote quote
the other one by the way in in this
fiction
flat learned is fi-fi how frantically i
square my talk
you won't understand it until you read
this one by the way
this so what's this book this is a
a classic you know kind of very popular
among
uh math community why because this book
it introduces you introduces you
to the concept of higher dimensions that
is
fourth dimension fifth dimension sixth
dimension
and so on reading this book although
it's not a math book
it's you know technically it's a science
fiction so they are talking about people
who lives in
in a two-dimensional land you know they
are talking about these people
so it's not a math book at all there's
no
mention of equations nothing like that
it's just a
technically a science fiction you talk
talks about
these people living in flatland land and
their stories and their
history but however after you know this
is a short fiction so you'll finish it
in
one hour or two if you read fast you
know a few hours
once after you read it you'll have a
great
understanding of the higher dimensions
fourth dimension five fifth dimension
you know so and so on
like most programmers most people you
know this is
important most people they don't know
what it means they just see
you know movies they talk about oh from
10th dimension
oh and and time travel and you know
[ __ ] idiots
they don't know nothing now here's the
important thing one of the important
thing
this is a geometric dimension which is
different from time
has nothing to do with einstein [ __ ] you
know
most these common people they'll say
they'll think oh einstein einstein
instant this or that or fame and [ __ ]
common people idiots
so anyway read this book i highly
recommend it
many of you probably have already done
so i read this book uh something like
three or four times
uh the first time is like uh 1995
also and by the way there's also chinese
version okay so
for those of you who read chinese
there's a chinese translation of it
you can see on my site uh so this is
very famous by the way there's also
movies made out of it okay so there's
like
animations you can well i have it i have
it
uh let's see
a flatland or an introduction there
there's quite a few
sequels and also animations made out of
it
you go to my website you you'll find
them because this is very popular
now again now this book is a short
fiction they're talking about these
creatures living on two dimension and
this book is
divided into two parts the you know the
first part this word the second part
other words
the second part actually
um you'll learn about higher dimension
but however
this book is kind of a dark okay this is
this this is a dark that's
you know this is part of the reason it's
great it's not actually just
it's not actually trying to teach you
mathematics although it is
part of the goal and and it's done great
great job but the first part
is basically a mark
a mock summary of human history
okay a mock summary of humans history
you can see for example some of the
sections
title concerning
the women okay
and you see
concerning irregular figures
okay now you have to read deeper than
that
once you read it you understand what it
means concerning irregular figures
section seven section eight
of the asian practice of painting okay
section 9 of the universal color bill
section 10 of the suppression of the
chromatic sedition
you know section 11 concerning our
priests
so this is a kind of very dark mock
summary
of human history
so okay that's it about that flatland
and the quote brave new world
and we talked about pepe already
so okay let me not read the comments and
see how long
have i been talking uh
30 minutes
okay so let's see what you guys are
saying
okay i need to drink coffee
this rich man's coffee okay from
uh costco you know costco
in america is kind of the um
it's not react you know it's not
richmond but it's not for rich people
but it's it's kind of the
main uh the medium the middle class
americans they fat americans
you know they go there and they you have
giant warehouse of oak
food you know all the rather high higher
high grade food
uh okay coffee
break now this is the break time inter
intermission you know we have the
english word
intermission something like that
vanya says also are not by
not by instagram artists okay uh
animal killer uh something something
something something
something something something animal
killer says
i know guy called sally who drew
the original troll face did i
original troll face now what's the troll
face
uh
alan says uh me guest
rage comics topian okay that's that's
either spanish or
french eric says what is the current
state of windows versus mac versus linux
do you prefer using mac os
i can answer that quickly
to answer that you simply search i have
an article on that
exactly why i switch
to mac to windows
you know typically you'll find articles
about why i switched to mac
but i have an article why i am switching
from mac to windows
now you read this article you'll see the
full detail of it
okay but let me quickly answer your
question
uh well the answer to your question is
at the bottom
okay and here is a photo of my aboard
now now this is the moment of history
now i no longer live there i lived in
that place
starting around 2008 2009 you see
this place now all my videos before
march are made in that place
uh but i i no longer
live here so it's a history a change in
my life
so this is this photo is 2009 and that
that is my food
uh you know very basic basic
basic basic is what i like
and i had i had these big giant yamaha
speakers
anyway so that is my setup
before and i also have this
imac 1999 so anyway the question is
uh mac versus linux versus windows which
is better you know
basically the question is like that so i
have a
answer to that written in 2018
state of mac versus windows versus linux
2018 people kept asking me
so uh do you do you do which one do you
use now uh
what do you think you know do you think
it's worthwhile to switch to windows you
know people have been asking that
as far as i know for 20 years you know
for 30 years
30 years uh since 1990
you know windows it used to be mac
versus pc
you know it's a big topic people talk
about every day
uh then you know every day
in the 90s 1990s then that kind of
died out when windows became
uh when windows and mac becomes more
alike
because in the 1990s so before year 2000
windows and mac are very not like each
other because
windows is mostly command command dos
you know command line
well actually yeah primarily you know
window is not
intuitive you know it's in in in early
1990s is command line okay dos
but mag is the first one that
popularized mouse for example mouse
graphical user interface
you can draw photoshop adobe illustrator
uh 3d programs they are basically most
of them
vast majority of them begin life on the
mac
for 10 years so you don't have that on
on windows you know desktop publishing
word processors uh clock express
you can you know format things you know
desktop publishing you know that's
basically mac invented
it then you know pc gradually copied
copied it so anyway there's a question
you know windows or mac you know what do
you think basically
the situation is the same okay as as to
which one you should use
let's first focus on windows versus mac
okay
mac is much more easier to use okay
much more easier to use the the user
interface
uh everything is just great great uh the
design is fantastic
okay
windows your questionnaire and then oh
you know
intuitive your complexities it's hard to
use
but however mac is often like twice as
expensive for the same
uh physical hardware power twice as
expensive
including every peripheral you buy you
know like the
same mouse exact exact same mouse
you buy it from the pc community let's
say it's twenty dollars you buy it
on the mac community max store it's
forty dollars
that is true for every peripheral like
dongles or whatever
so mac you know if you have money you
could go to go mac okay so
mac is much easier to use windows not
not so
but however windows you can play games
you know for all the games you can play
you know if you want our gamer of course
you go windows there's no basically no
choice
you know not you know you'll hear mac
fanatics or linux [ __ ] they'll say
oh
yeah but every every game is now
available on the mac or linux or linux
steam you know they get excited over the
past 20 years
no yeah you know if you ask a real gamer
uh yeah you're gonna play games on a mac
or linux know
you are [ __ ] idiot you you they you
can tell you are a fanatic you are out
of the
uh you don't know what you're talking
about you you are just
trying to you want to believe you know
you you want to believe
so if you want to play games windows
that's your only choice
and you can buy graphics cards
on the mac you cannot basically you know
you pay you know 2 000
and you still get lousy uh system
so that's basically windows versus mac
which one to choose
so there's no one good answer depends on
what's what's what you want you want to
you have a lot of money
well maybe and you don't play games
maybe you you know go with mac
you know or you if you want you know be
not to spend that much money and you or
if you play games go with windows
they are you know window is usable very
usable today
uh you know windows 10 and now
and and also let me mention another
thing for
security you know prevent corporation
corporate prying eyes in general mac
is better more secure and also windows
has a lot more viruses by the way it's
not a fault of windows
windows got more viruses because
not because window is you know they're
secure no
you idiot it's because window has 10
times
more people using it than the mac okay
10 times
therefore if you are a virus writer you
write one for windows obviously
okay that's window versus mac now linux
linux is
the worst [ __ ] possible the worst [ __ ]
you know the the worst the most
difficult to use
when if you use windows you're gonna
spend one or two hours every day
just to deal with you know things to get
it to work
uh trying to install this doesn't work
oh you go to stock stack overflow
and linux linux distro and [ __ ] all
the information you found is 10 years
old
you know you all the answer is 10 years
old then you have to talk to people how
do you
[ __ ] linux [ __ ] [ __ ] the linux idiots
and we have these you know extremely
idiotic
idiotic people linux people you know
they will sometimes say oh
uh uh gnome versus windows 10 which is
more easier to use
[Laughter]
you know it's like a [ __ ] a piece of
[ __ ] versus let's say
versus a diamond which one is easier to
use
[ __ ] linux fox so linux is the worst
[ __ ] possible but but however
it's free it's free my man my friends
it's free
you know the best things in the world is
free the the best things
in life is free you know exists free you
don't have to pay
you know that's the story of linux
and you know yeah and if you are a
programmer if all you do is programming
you don't play games you know
the purpose of you using a computer is
programming you know python
pearl uh the golan uh
lisp for example yeah then linux is good
okay you you do servers so you know then
then you go linux okay
so the linux you know if you are a dev
linux is kind of the
you could say the best of them
well yeah kind of so
okay so that's the summary of linux vs
smack
you know a mac versus pc versus linux
which one you want to go there's
actually you know it's
it's hard to not to choose if you don't
want to pay
you go linux it sucks the worst [ __ ]
possible
you know if you play games go windows
now if you have lots of money
and you can go you know like show off
you know bring your macbook your
latest apple watch you know the [ __ ]
apple you know
fox yeah you go to starbucks you know
you sit down and you know
show off yeah
that's a good for apple
okay uh what's my thoughts about having
kids
i like to have kids actually i'm not
married
and i don't have kids but actually
that's something i would like to have
uh and i'm a schizoid
personality that means i'm kind of a
loner personality so i don't
easily um you know i'm kind of a very
extremely independent person independent
like no
emotion no attachments what whatsoever
with other
people so for us it's harder
anyway i like i i think i like to have
kids
possibly maybe not you know who knows
what happened
maybe not
so back to reading the comments and
maybe that's it
today uh so how long have been talking
uh i've been talking about
50 minutes okay let me
go back read the comments you got a
question for me post it now
okay now it's the right time
uh indian currency so
vanga is from india now india
indian currency that's a loophole or
rupee
right something am i correct now let's
see unicode
unicode let's go to unicode
god this takes so long
show in browser
now we let's go to currency
next page
culture keyboard common punctuation
let's show you
you know i'm gonna show you some of
these very interesting
unicode stuff uh and where is
currency
where did it go currency money okay
oh i don't have uh i used to have words
about it so let's see
what is this
bengali bengali is it bengali or bengali
bengali up sign and indian rupee sign
okay that's that one indian rupee
oh so one dollar usd is like 100
indian rupees something like that
okay so thank you thank you vanya
anyway you know it's uh great thank uh
donation thank you so
uh let's see what else
alan lapping stuff
live action role playing uh
c car blood and
haven't pretended to be a thing i think
referring to your name
oops yes i was laughing with uh
russians of late on youtube
uh message retracted what does that mean
did does that mean you deleted yourself
allen
north india or south india so talk about
auto hotkey how is it going for you so
auto hard key
let me let me talk about that a bit
so you know i have a tutorial on auto
hard key of course hold on a second let
me copy the
url for the money
unicode currency symbols copy okay close
close and paste it here so we have a
link showing browser
there there it is today's topic and
another topic is why i switched
from mac to windows yeah we have it here
paste it here okay
so close that
you know called keyboard symbols okay uh
let's not talk about that
so let's answer the comments uh auto
hard key okay so let me talk about auto
hotkey
go to my programming blog so i started
to
work on windows yesterday
you know i've been using you know
windows
i started to use windows at work
in 1999
to 2002 using windows nt
in fact you can see a picture of me so
let me show you
keyboard block so i'm going to talk
about auto hard key so
keyboard vlogs so today i did a lot
small updates on several pages
computer keyboard gallery so let me show
you
so you so this keyboard is the
cheap the cheapest generic keyboard
i bought for six dollars
back in 1999. you know back then my
favorite keyboard is the
cheapest generic pc keyboard
like this one you know six six dollars
if it has extra buttons or it has you
know
special shape or ergonomic or speaker i
don't know i don't want that all those
[ __ ] i want the cheapest generic
pc keyboard no special buttons or no
extra buttons no
those no strange arrangements you know
those are no good
that's that's back then so this is my
my keyboard and this is actually my
favorite one
six dollars cheapest one you can get
so this is a picture this is my office
in
in 2001 at nootopia
so you know back then i have off office
and
and quite big you know you know as big
as my room
right now shared by you know two of us
me and another guy and i got you know
that's back then you don't have that
today
so this is my you see this pc
that is that is running windows nt
you know so so i've been using windows
nt
for uh four years but however
i my first computer my personal computer
is around 1992 a mac 2si
i'm mostly being a mac person so
throughout 1990s i'm a mac person so
only until
only in 1999 to 2002
i started to use windows and that's
windows nt that's my work
you know we use this so we are doing uh
we are developing one of the first or
the first
you could you could say the first uh web
store
the the system for web store like yahoo
even before yahoo store a massive scale
so i'm a you know i'm developer of that
and we i use windows nt to connect to
the server so
you know anyway so that's windows nt
but i have never used windows as my
personal you know
home main machine until
until uh 2009 you know that's
that's discussed in my article
why i'm switching from mac to windows so
that's 2009
but anyway what's my point my point is
that what i'm going to say
i was going to say
yeah okay auto hotkey so
so so my first window experience
is from 1999 to 2002
then from 2009 to
2012 about three years
that is when i'm developing ergo emac
smart
that's also the same time so anyway so
2009 to 2012
windows is my main machine at home
so and by that time i'm i'm also a
keyboard and you know i've been a
keyboard nerd since 1991 because i wrote
my own vorack
layout on the mac anyways so
auto hard key is one of the great
utility on windows
that allows you to create your own
shortcuts or
keyboard remap or automation you know
some sort of automation
so it's one of the greatest
i would say it's a one it's it's it's
the
greatest tool if i can if you can only
have one
uh software for keyboard remapping
you know that kind of thing or launching
programs then
that the best one you know is auto hard
key
so i have a tutorial of that you know
this is written
you can see written in 2009 but however
i stopped using windows around 2012 or
so this page and related pages is
getting old for seven years
it's you know it's speed rotting it's
bit rot
when you write a tutorial on programming
or technology
they will bit rot if you don't update it
because you know this new version of
autohotkey
you know and things change for example
back then you have windows vista
then you have you know windows 7 windows
vista windows 10
and the user interface changed entirely
from you know restart from whatever
before to 10
because now you have touch screen and so
on
so things change you know so so the need
for shortcuts also changed somewhat so
anyway so i have a
little hockey tutorial but i haven't
been on windows for
uh seven years by now but yesterday
i started to kind of i'm not sure for
i'm not sure but i started to do
dev on windows i have a service uh
tablet so you know emacs doing
programming doing stuff on those
windows like like using us using it as a
developer
for real so that's when you need all the
shortcuts you need to
very fast efficient way to do things
like get to i want to open this folder
in you know in explorer i want to show
this linking browser in specific browser
uh you know chrome or firefox or that
one i want to
have you know quick ways to switch to
the window or whatever to a directory
or get a path of a directory or run this
file
with this path run a program with this
path
things like that so i started to uh
install auto hotkey again
and so i'm going to update my autohotkey
tutorial there's quite a few i need to
update
let me show you okay so they are
actually i've kind of collected here
autohard let me show you okay auto
hotkey
uh let me show okay autohotkey
windows key remapping
frequently asked questions okay
and uh complete list of microsoft
windows
shortcuts there are actually tens of
them like 100 almost
uh then emacs auto hard key mod you know
i wrote auto
i wrote a uh auto hard key mod in emac
list
because back then the one that comes
with all the hotkeys no good
so i wrote my own so i haven't been
updating it for like seven years
it's still good actually it works so i
when i'm out
on a mac so i cannot show you much about
hotkey
i need to eventually i need to set up my
windows machine so i can uh stream from
there
so any more comments okay let me quickly
finish and that will be done today okay
let me finish quickly um
okay let me show you just a few more
things powershell okay
if you want to let me tell you this okay
let me
yeah this these are important let me
tell you
now if your main machine is windows
and if you are a nerd maybe you are a
programmer or if you
use windows at work you want to master
windows okay
and the most important thing you want to
master is powershell
some of these things i'm gonna tell you
powershell you want to master it through
throughout
okay it the operating system shell is
kind of the
command line it's kind of the window to
to the whole system there are features
what it does what you can do with it so
you want to master powershell
you can begin begin at the beginning
which is my tutorial
okay so actually my tutorial about
powershell is not that great
but you could spend 10 minutes reading
it then you
move on because i tell you
you know these days people you know they
search the web for tutorials but
actually
many programming language languages they
have entire
set of tutorials and documentation
within powershell
for example powershell is actually
available on the mac too
let me show you okay
let's open new window let's magnify
let's see if we can magnify this
uh yeah let's magnify okay so i'm gonna
show you
uh pssh
powershell now it's cross platform so
it's available for
windows of course but also mac and linux
you see i'm running powershell
now it says type help to help so let's
type help
there it is you know the start start
with this article you know you can read
the
entire thing actually i need to
this is not the full help okay wait help
help
you know anyway starting with us this
article you can actually read
the there it is the entire uh tutorials
and documentations about powershell
without needing any other tutorial
and this is actually the most accurate
because it's from the official
you know so my tutorial uh usually tells
you
about those things so you can start that
so powershell you want to master
okay and also many of the most
fundamental things about windows you
want to master
registry you want to know what they are
inside out okay you want to understand
registry
and you also want to um okay so windows
console
windows console is going away okay so
forget about it this
this page is going to go absolute
um so anyway that's about and also what
one more thing windows in the
environment environment variables in
windows
very important also when you study
powershell you also learn this
very important you want to know the full
thing they are connected
powershell windows environment
environment variables
and the registry they are connected
because on windows
the environment variables are stored in
registry so you need to know
these things so anyway i think that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
uh so one more
uh ending quotes oh my god you skipped
my question above
please read okay
uh
g90 okay hold on a second
i'm gonna we're gonna finish in five min
in five minutes three minutes or two
uh show my anti
keyboard cartoon i posted on discord
okay alan
allen is our in-house artist oh yeah so
he's got a
comics you know he he he's a um
he's an artist he draw
he alan draw me memes okay there it is
[Laughter]
let's see uh there it is
this artwork by allen
okay so
i knew okay i'm gonna finish we're gonna
finish okay in
two three minutes i'm gonna finish
reading the comments
simp what is simp rather be a pimp
anyone can join cell phones okay
thank you vanya again
okay so what mean db i just pulled that
out
yes hello everyone
so
so jim j team 90 what is your question
i as i mentioned before if you have a
question for me
put my name to it
so here's a question what are your
thoughts on having kids i answered that
awesome thanks for the response
which platform do i actually like i
i don't know you know because you know
mac
is the best but uh most expensive and
not compatible and you cannot play games
on the mac so
it's hard to say it's hard to say you
know linux is free
but then it really sucks the worst [ __ ]
possible in
every way in every [ __ ] way linux
i mean we are not talking about let's
say
mac and windows and linux are all free
okay and i'm a nerd you know i'm a
programmer so
you know i know sister means since
[ __ ] 20 years ago
i know you next season me i have used
you know all the several quite you know
solaris
you have used you know professional
systeming on solaris
for three four years but linux is
the worst [ __ ] possible even for a very
you know extreme nurse is the worst
[ __ ] possible linux [ __ ] the linux
and these people you know these eunuchs
linux people they
you know tightening windows so playing
windows and the kernel and they
need [ __ ] idiots and they
they don't even know you know they don't
know things you know
you know when i talk about linux it's
gonna be 20 hours
non-stop i'm gonna tell you all the
technical details these
linux unix [ __ ] they know nothing
about
the file systems the file permissions
user group
you know root wheel uh
but by the way i have a i have ten
thousand articles on that
search focus unix philosophy search for
linux tutorial
uh i don't know what's your i didn't see
your question
j team90 although i like kids okay so
uh messenger because i made a typo okay
uh you had the cheapest generic pc
keyboards other
uh quality theory
yeah the j team 90 is
trying to you know he's trying he's
posting uh the md5
i made up again the md5
is this this number you tell
you tell some number it's better it's
it's below what i have in mind i'll send
this many money in donations bigger than
i don't know i don't know what you're
trying to do
you know i'm anyway that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
bye and join discord now let's turn up
you know today i have a trick you know i
i i hit
the obs then all the cb
cpu usage is lower
so i've been talking for one hour and
six minutes good night guys have a good
day