Hello guys, good morning guys. Welcome
to another episode of sound talk show.
We are going to code wufam language
today. Wufam language uh we are going to
write a function that exports woofam
language uh two-dimensional graphics
into SVG.
So two-dimensional graphics that's
fantastic. Let's try one of them. Okay.
So, we're gonna This is going to be kind
of boring and dry for you guys because
I'm just going to code very technical.
Uh if you have questions for me, you can
ask me. So, this is Wuam language. We
just evaluated this code and it
generates that. So, that's 2D graphics.
Now, I want to export it. So uh
so let's see.
Okay. So let's export this one. Okay.
Uh it has a built-in function to export
graphics.
So for example export
uh and uh then so you so let me magnify
so you can see.
So here's a code. Okay. Let's um
run it. So it's great. So actually I
don't I don't want this. So let's modify
this. Okay. So
we going to write a function to export
SVG graphics. So let's see. So let's you
know I'm just going to start working on
it. Start a Woof code. Paste it. Pop
into a new window. Uh I'm using Safly
Keys. uh and I'm using Emacs. So Softly
Keys is a package in Emacs that allows
the most efficient key binding. So you
can search on the web safely keys,
you'll find it. It's on GitHub. There's
lots of videos. If you are watching this
offline play at 1.5 speed minimum okay
uh so I'm using softly keys and the pink
window shows all my command calls and
the names as I type them. So close for
example close you can see close current
buffer can you see it yes so close that
and here I'm using kasawa mod so you can
see
there it is kasawa wuam mod you can get
it it's free on the web so go to the
website you search for it you'll find it
kasaw wuam mode uh this allows you to
code wuam language in emacs and uh Wufam
language you can download for free. Just
search for kasali.info wuam language
tutorial. You can download it for free.
It's the most powerful most advanced uh
programming language than all others by
a magnitude. Okay. So you can download
it. Uh you can watch my like hundred
over 100 videos on wam language in the
past on YouTube. Okay. So example mode.
So let's close close that. So so uh let
me modify something here. Uh again we're
going to write a export to SVG. So but
first of all let me show uh get this to
work. So
so graphics grid I don't want graphics
squid. Okay. So let's just say that uh
okay so that's so that's two graphics.
Okay. So
uh
copy all go back here select all paste.
So that's one of the graphics. This is
second graphics. Now let's export it. So
let's export.
Okay. So export what's the syntax and uh
okay. So the first argument is going to
be a file name. So xx. SVG. Let's just
say that. Uh let's say X X uh Y. Okay.
Then okay, select all.
Uh yeah, select all graphics. So
uh let's look up the documentation for
graphics.
That's yes, that's what we want. Let's
turn on JavaScript. It's already on.
Magnify. Okay. So copy the whole go
select all paste run it. Okay.
Fantastic. Now you can see it's it's
exported xxy.svg
that's in the document folder.
So go to document xxy. There it is. Open
it. There it is. Uh open it. Uh so you
know SVG is a XML file. So let's switch
to Kasa HTML mod. So here is the source
code for the SVG. So you can see lots of
these repetition lines you know. So this
file is 56 kilobytes.
Uh it could actually be smaller you know
just all these you know these are maybe
50 lines or 100 lines. It should be just
you know 5 kilobytes. So it the
generated SVG is like 10 times larger
than necessary. That is why I want to
write my own customized
export uh to SVG uh command
because if you look at SVG so if you
don't know SVG uh let's look up. So I
have a tutorial on sudi.info just search
for it. Uh if you are here, say hi.
Okay, let's see. Let's Hello, Simple
Postman.
So, let's pop this out. If you are
watching this offline, play 1.5 uh
speed. And if you are uh watching here,
say hi. Uh if you have questions about
wam language, ask me. Okay, so here's
SVG tutorial. SVG is just XML. Okay, so
it's just like HTML. So you know you you
paste that then you get a line. So
because there is a line primitive you
can see
uh okay so let's magnify let's magnify
the browser more. So um so it's larger
is always easier to see. So 150 is kind
of too large anyway. So here's a line
and here's a rectangle by the primitive
rectangle and here's a circle by the
primitive circle and the line a line is
very simple you can see it's just the xy
coordinates
the starting beginning position and end
position okay but what wuang language
generates is that it use uh path I mean
you see it repeats this style this you
for every line, you know, you shouldn't
need to. You can put all these styles
like all the repetitions, you know, so
on and on in into one one place. Can I
do it? Yeah, actually I can do it. I can
let me show you. Okay, so all these
styles. So first of all, go to the
directory, make a backup. So in case we
made a mistake, now go back here. Now uh
now copy this line. Let's modify it and
let's make it motor line so I can see
it. Uh
so you see all these repetitions. Okay.
So
so the whole style
can be make it one line. Okay. Cut it
can be placed here. Okay. Then this path
um I don't need it. Okay, so that should
do. So now we just delete all these
styles. So
let's
Oh god.
Copy
find replace that by empty. So replace
replace replace
uh shift and so replace them all. Okay.
So you can see and now save.
Okay. Now go to directory refresh. Now
you see we already saved half of the
file size. Fantastic. So you see the
problem is just that when you use wam
language language to export to SVG it
the the result is not too efficient.
Uh however we have another command. So
let me let me do it again. Okay. So
let's say uh wait
refresh
edit. So let's say uh this is original.
Okay. Then
this is a
Okay. Rename them. So here's original
and here is the the one we modified. So
now let's make a backup of the original
and let's uh let's name
replace a space by underscore. Now we
want to I want to uh call SVG optimize.
Let's see how much it can save. So
there's a command. We did a live stream
about a a week or two ago. So
SVG optimize. Uh there it is. Okay. Type
V. So do it.
Done. Okay. Refresh.
Okay. So it also saved. You see it also
saved half of the files. I mean file
size. So let's uh put it to HTML mod so
we can see the code. And let's just
Okay.
So let's uh
make it multiple lines. Okay.
Okay. Go to the top. Okay. So, you can
see it did something similar like like
what we did. Okay.
Uh yeah.
Why is this? Uh
okay. Yeah, it did something similar.
But anyway, this is still inefficient.
Okay, because you can see here the
stroke is repeated all over.
So that's why we are writing we want to
write uh oops we saved our original.
Okay, that's why we want to write our
own uh export to SVG. So let's get
started. So this is going to be uh you
know extremely technical
because
so most of you won't understand. Uh I'll
explain along the way but um but it's
going to be difficult because unless you
have programmed wam language for a year
the even the my explanation wouldn't
help much. So you're going to basically
just watch me code. Okay.
So that's the reason that's a whole
setup about why uh you want to write
export to SVG. So here is a sample code.
So let's put it back. Syntax code show
in browser. So that's what we talked
about uh code.
Uh
okay. So let me uh see the question.
Have you ever thought about creating uh
creating procedural geometric art for
sale? It seems that you are a huge lover
of such things according to your blog.
Yes. Uh for sale, you know, you're not
going to sell anything. Uh you know, the
artworks
especi
you you're going to not going to make
money unless you are one in a one in a
million or one in 100 million artists.
Then maybe you become extremely famous.
Then uh you know one in a million very
rare
especially if you are doing mathematical
art like you know the geometry
you know there's no money for it
uh so mostly I love this subject you
know visualization of geometry but this
is mostly for
you know for the beauty of it and also
for like uh illustration for mathematics
and educational purposes.
Now uh let's digress a little bit. If
you don't know, of course there's MC
Cher, one of the most famous uh
for creating mathematical art. So for
example, that's Assher's work. Uh of
course, he's not rich, you know, he's
pretty poor. He became famous like I
think after he died he became more more
and more famous. So anyway or his most
vast m you know most of his works is
math oriented. For example this one one
of my favorite this one shows the um
perspective okay perspectivity. So you
distill. So for example this one
beautiful you you distill the
mathematical aspect of it. Then you what
you get is this. Okay. And you can
distill this further by just showing you
know this is already pretty much
distilled. So because you only see lines
and square you going you only see lines.
So that you you see this this image is
the essence of the mathematical essence
of this. But this one is more attractive
to in uh you know to average person
because it got this you know fantastic
creatures but the the mathematical
essence is like this and you can
generate this you know so it's very you
know so I'm very interested in this you
can generate this uh using wuam language
okay so I've done you know I've done
quite you know quite a lot related
things like that okay so here here is
Another Asia's artwork. Uh this one is
named Chameleon. I think you know again
it's mathematical because this shows the
regular uh this is called uniform
polyhedra I believe
and then someone build it in second life
which is like a virtual reality you know
a friend. Um, so this is in Second Life
in in in three-dimensional. So you can
walk around you can you can you know in
Second Life you can walk around as a fly
like you can so you can view the whole
thing like you are inside the building
and she uh you know she also build other
things you know it's on YouTube you can
watch uh you know just search for
math blog on.info info you'll find this.
Okay. So I you know so I'm into this um
so that's Asher and uh that's another
asshure and that's another Asure. Okay.
So
so yeah so what I'm so yeah so let's get
back to this uh yeah let's get back to
this expo. So this is going to be very
boring. You you are not going to see
graphics because this is um that's what
I need to do. um today. Okay. So, close
that. So, today's talk show. So, what's
the next thing? So, you uh yeah, so
let's begin to write it. Okay.
Uh let's begin
from language.
Okay. So, are we are we like ready?
Yeah. Good. Okay. So
write a command to ex let's document
first export
2D graphics to SVG.
We want to do this because the the build
in
export
function
creates
huge file
size. Okay. Okay. Let's begin. So the
most most simple one is let's um so
let's do a circle
circle centered on 0 0 and radius one.
Okay, that's a graphics. And to show
that graphics, you just say,
you just say graphics and that. Okay.
Uh uh let's wait.
Let's say prim equals to prim stand for
graphics primitive. Okay. And then
graphics uh prim. Okay. Then option
axis.
Okay. So you can see if we
copy that
paste there. Oh, you got an extra comma.
Remove it. Shift enter to run it. So you
can see we got a circle. Now we can
export this. So So we start to write a
function. So let let me uh so export uh
let me show you. Okay. So export
if you export copy that. So
xx circle
SVG. Okay. We can run this in here.
Okay. Run it.
Is it done? Uh yes, I think so. Go to
the directory. Search for xx. Search for
circle. Uh, refresh. Search for search
for
Okay, not here. So, where did it go? Oh,
it's not done yet. No, it's done.
Refresh. There. Okay. So, you open this
file. Then you uh
switch to XML mode. So you can see
you know it generates this hugely
whenever you have a circle it generates
a very inefficient
SVG representation because you know it's
trying to represent the circle by path
so the whole file you know just one
single weight actually what you know our
circle actually also contain the axis so
that makes it more complex but but
however the circle itself self is
represented by
path you you know so it's so the file
size is 15 kilobytes very inefficient a
circle could be simply just a SVG circle
tag okay so for example let's go back to
SVG basics
and you can see a circle is just that
okay
let's try again so close And so this
time let's not include the axis just
circle. Okay. So run it.
Okay. Done. Now go to the directory.
Refresh. Search for circle. There. Now
you see now it's 869
bytes. Open it. Circle. Perfect. Now
switch to X8 uh XML mode.
uh XML. Okay. Now this one single long
line. Now
now make it
separate. Okay. So you can see it
represent a circle by using a path.
So instead of a single circle like that
you know just 50 characters it represent
a circle by a path. So you get this huge
you know bunch of numbers you know those
C the C stand for those are cubic uh
uh cubic uh what's what they call cubic
um uh let me show you okay so path
basics so you go path then you can go
down those are uh cubic
um what's the name basia curve okay so
it represent a circle by using a cubic
basio curve which is kind of
approximating a circle. So it's not it's
not very good. First of all, it bloats
up the file size. Then it's not actually
100% accurate because it's like
approximating a circle. So I don't like
this. But I was told by someone that in
industry actually all circles
in in the end are represented by a lot
of it is represented just by uh basia
curve I heard
but
anyway so I want to so I want to ex I
want to write a function so it export uh
something like this. Okay, let me show
you.
So, here is our circle. So, let's copy
that. So, I want to write a
um a function that export just
just this this single line instead of
these a bunch of things. Okay.
Okay. So, let's delete that. Save it.
Close. Okay. So, let's go back to the
code. So, let's start to write it.
Uh,
you will not be easy. So, hi Karan. I
hope you are having a good day. Yeah,
thank you.
Um, okay.
Uh what's the name? Uh
let's just say export graphics. Okay, so
you want to define a function. So,
so what is a function uh inline
documentation?
Uh so this is how you define inline
documentation in wam language. Okay. And
so first of all we need to uh design
this function. What is the argument?
So this will be graphics.
We uh okay. So take a graphics and uh
name
export
graphics
object G to a file
named name. Okay. Uh
in SVG format. Okay.
G
G is a
graphics
object.
Okay. And uh yeah something like that
name name is a string
in current.
Okay. So that is a uh usage inline
documentation.
Okay. Now let's write the function. Uh
yeah.
Okay. So how do you so it takes two
arguments. So we're going to use a
pattern matching. Uh so there two
argument. The first argument, the first
thing is a uh
graphics. Okay. So what this means it's
taking any argument whose head is
graphics then it will match. This is uh
doing a pattern matching. The second
argument must be a string. So file name.
Let's just say file name. Okay. uh that
means this means anything match anything
and name whatever match was file name.
Okay.
So that so
it will um
well first of all before we write this
it will be nice to output through string
okay so so write a function that output
to string okay that's the first thing
write a function that just return a
string then you can later on add a
wrapper to export to write write the
string to file okay So let's just um
yeah let's not let's quickly let's do
this. So it it needs to output to
string. Okay. So something like that
something um
oh god we need to go faster. So this is
going to be a long video I think but no
more than I hope no more
you know to complete this it'll take
more than three hours four five
because there's lots of graphics stuff
going on you know lots of and coloring
and styles but to create a simple
version to just to demonstrate it this
works it'll take like an hour or two.
Okay. But but I think we're going to
just go do for for an hour or 90
minutes, then I'm going to stop. Then
I'm going to code offline.
Okay. So, back to this. So, so it needs
to return a string. Okay. So, uh uh uh
graphics to string. So, let's rename
this. Okay. Let's just go all the way.
Okay. Graphics to strings. Uh string. I
mean, let's just
make this all the way. uh
you know go through the whole coding
return a string that is a SVG format
representing
G
graphics object G. Okay, that's that's
that's
the uh yeah. Okay, so now let's write
that graphics to string. Okay, now you
don't now you don't need file name.
Worry about that later. Okay, now return
uh string. That's it. We done.
Okay. So the first thing you have to
worry about is what are the SVG um like
the the headers you know. So
so this will work actually that may not
be valid you know.
So for example uh some escape quotes.
Okay. So this so if you have a SVG as a
file let's look at uh this okay so you
need this uh I think you need both of
them
okay so let's copy that close close
okay uh escape quotes
escape quote okay so you need the SVG
XML header Then
then uh god. So open that again.
Then you need to close it. Yes, of
course. Close. Close. And then you need
to
Yeah. Okay. So no. So XML header then
SVG something something something
then okay the view box those are
complicated.
Uh god.
So width, height, height. What how
should it be? So let's see what's the
default width and height. You want the
export. So you know
actually writing this is fairly
complicated because it gets fairly
involved. So what's the default width
and height?
Uh what should it be? So 1,000 pixels by
1,000 pixels. Let's say,
oh god, this is going to be complicated.
So
100. Okay. I mean, let's say 1,00. Okay.
So, and uh Okay. So then viewbox is the
coordinate customized coordinate. In
this case, the same. Okay. Then SVG
version. Well,
okay. I don't know. So, okay. So,
so right now this function is just
return a static string. Okay. It haven't
done anything with the argument yet.
Okay. But it works. So, let's try it.
Clear just to make sure. So clear the
function then define the inline
documentation then the function okay and
this part this part let's just say that
okay so
so let's
copy that
paste all paste run the whole thing
then let's just say uh
let's say graphics to string string.
Okay,
call it graphics to string.
And what is your graphics? The graphics
is going to be let's just say that.
Okay, paste it.
Shift shift return. Fantastic. So, it
just run it return the string. Okay,
later on we're going to save the string
to a file, right? To file. Okay. But now
we need to actually do something with
it. You know the input.
So how do you turn a So you so you have
this something like this circle. Oh god
this is going to be very complicated. So
example. Okay.
So when you have something
like that, a circle, you want to turn it
into a
you want to turn it into
this. Okay. So in this case will be 0 0.
Oh god. No.
So this cx and c y they are the
coordinates. So in this case it's
arranging 0 0
but here you cannot be 0 0. So you know
this represent the circle but here you
you can't be 0 0 because 0 0 in the SVG
coordinate they are on the upper left
corner.
Oh god this is going to be a lot
more work than I expected.
Yeah. To write this it's going to be
take you know
you imagine it'll take two hours but
it's more likely is few days
30 hours to make it everything.
Uh so anyway so here is a coordinate you
want to turn that into a string like
that and radius one. Okay. But
but you got so but um
Oh god. To figure out the whole
coordinate is very complicated.
Oh
Yes, it is. Oh god. I think maybe I'll
abandon the project.
Sherry says, "Thank you." What?
Okay. So, this is this is difficult
because
so you got a single circle at this
coordinate 0 0, right?
But in real life you know your graphics
is likely to have hundreds or thousands
of circles and lines. So you have
literally few thousand coordinates. Okay
you have you have you have few thousand
coordinates.
So one of the thing you need to do is
when you have a graphics you need to
know what's the uh boundary like outer
bound the maximum x coordinate the
minimum x coordinate
and the maximum y and minimum y so that
you know how many pixels they are in
total width and height. Okay that's the
that's the first thing you need to know.
So,
so for example, graphics may be you know
many other circles or uh line uh you
know line is represented like that for
example 0 0 to uh let's say one two okay
and actually
uh wait
so that represent the line okay so in in
real life you might have you know
thousands of circles and lines in order
with different positions.
So what so so the whole thing cut
so this you know this this may be a real
life input.
So you so you need to find the boundary
maximum minimum. Okay. So
yeah that to code that is um
there might be a building function to to
get that uh that's so that's one thing.
So once you know the maximum the
boundary the maximum and minimum X and
also for Y then you need to
scale that to within your SVG
width and height output. So your your
SVG paper is 1,000 by 1,000 pixels,
but you need the internal coordinate to
to scale whatever is your max to this
1,00.
So this part view box is your is your
custom coordinates. So you need to scale
it there.
Then you also need to translate because
because the Wufam language
you see the coordinate
you know the the the middle is you know
the it's math coordinate the middle is 0
0 but in the SVG
0 is at upper left corner so then you
need to translate so for example let me
just mark mark right here. Okay. So,
this will need to time a scale
uh x scale and this part will need to
time
times a y scale. Then you need to
translate.
So, uh
x
vector you know you need you need to
translate x trans vector. Okay,
something like that
plus and this will be y trans vector.
Okay,
something like that. Okay, so yeah. So
let me let me clear that up.
Uh
yeah, something like that. And so
very tedious, you know, to do this. You
have to think about it, you know, and
get it correct.
So once we have that then then for each
circle you just turn that into this
string.
Okay, do you guys see what I'm doing?
Uh simple postman says my master degree
was partially
oh my master's degree was partially on
mastering complexity. Decide on the
expected complete output. Dissect it
into major parts and code bottom up to
return each part step by step.
Hierarchy. Yeah.
Uh so wait, how can I magnify?
Okay. So
yeah, I think you know actually I think
I'm going to stop. Oh god, because this
is going to be lots of work, boring
work.
Um
I wish it just would work, you know. Why
is Wam language, you know, creating a
file that's like 100 times larger? I
need this. I need I really need this
because,
you know, in my project, I'm going to
need to do
I I I need to do hundreds of these uh
two-dimensional images.
You know, I I talked about this. You can
check my YouTube. You know, there's lots
of hundreds of 2D images. If you create
them in SVG, I mean in PNG,
the file size is still pretty large, but
they are ugly because you cannot scale
it, you know, when you scale it up, it
becomes ugly, you know, they be lines
become jagged, you know, like like like
that. You see, but if it's SVG, then
it's perfect. But the problem with SVG,
you know, each one of these image is
going to be like
half megabyte. So that's not good. Oh
god, why can't wam why didn't WF
language do this correctly?
The ex you know the the building export.
Yeah. Okay. So let me think about do I
really want to write this?
It's going to be several days of coding,
you know, like 30 hours.
Uh
so how feasible? Let's see how can I
really quickly code this.
No, you cannot do that. So I mean you
are saying that
you are saying that we just take the
output and optimize. So you cannot do
that because let me show you. So here's
a circle and let's turn this into XML
mode. So you can see it's using a path.
Uh okay. So let me explain this. So so
okay. So let's break the lines.
Okay. First of all, a bunch of styles.
Then here's the data for the path. Okay.
It's all just um
coordinates. Okay. Uh
okay. So all these are just coordinates.
So what is doing is that it's this
capital C that is uh cubic basier curve.
So it's got you know it's it's very
complicated cubic basia curve.
So let's go back to circle.
It should be just a circle but but it's
doing it's using the path to emulate
circle. So what is the path? So the
specification if you want to
you know do basio curve and cubic basio
curve is that you you you use a command
C. So where's C there? Okay. So you see
here you know to create this this curve
the code is this one. So you
start M means move to. So move to 0 0
coordinate then cubia you know cubic
basia curve then two control points then
something something you know so okay
here's the explanation so C
every C is followed by 1 2 3 4 5 six six
numbers that means three
coordinates okay two of them are
controlled points. The other one is the
coordinate on the curve.
So if you have played with uh Adobe
Illustrator or any kind of vector
graphics, you you can see you know you
drag the line to control the curve.
So that's cubic basia curve. That's what
this line is. Okay, this long line. So
what it's doing what it is doing is it's
it's emulating a circle. Very
complicated.
So if we want to turn this thing back
into a circle
that's not easy. Okay. So that's
that's that you know that's that's
that's
a magnitude more difficult. So this is
like involving mathematics. Um
and uh at best actually you can only do
a guess because
cubic basia curve cannot represent a
circle 100%. They are just
approximation.
So when you actually try to reverse it
back to a circle. So find the circle
center and radius. You cannot do it
perfectly. I believe um
wait yeah actually maybe yeah yes yes
you can actually I think you can all you
have to do is that so for each C so
let's let's show it okay so for each C
replace C by a new line C. Okay. So you
can now you can make it the structure
clear. So that's uh
you know that so it's got
one 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
cubic basier curve.
Okay. So so the first two so let's see
one two number three number four number.
The first four numbers are control
points. So this the fifth and sixth
number that's the actual coordinates
of the curve on the curve. Okay. So for
each C you find the last two coordinates
that's a point on the circle. Okay. So
right now we are trying to reverse this
this path emulating a circle back into a
circle. So for each of the C you find
the last two coordinates and this one
and this one this one this one this this
one this one this one all those points
are the points on the circle then you
sum them and average them then you get
the center of the circle
then
from the center of a circle you compute
the distance to one of these you get the
radius
okay so that's how you turn this back
into a circle. Um,
now it's not trivial. Okay, it's it's
not trivial. So, yeah. Okay. But now I
understand. Um,
okay. So, back to this solution. This is
more precise solution. We convert it
by ourselves.
Uh but
how difficult can it get? So you you
find the scale then you find the
translation.
Another problem is that in SVG the
y-coordinate goes down. The lower it is
the more positive it is. But meanwhile
in standard mathematical coordinate the
positive for y is up. So you need to
flip it again. And so that's a hell, you
know, that's usually hell because it's
very fairly confusing.
So you need to flip the yaxis.
Uh god, how do I know it's very complex?
Because I have tried to work on it
before
uh on some other issue because I was
trying to write uh plotting software in
JavaScript.
Uh and I can show you the code. Uh let's
see. Uh
so
let's go to comp. Let's go to my home
directory. So that's my website. So
JavaScript
uh search for draw. So I like like five
years ago
I was going to write
you see. So this is written in
JavaScript using SVG
uh and uh adaptive sampling prototype.
The more curved is a curve there's there
will be more points.
Okay. So
so you can search for JavaScript and you
can see the code.
So two files the first this file is the
library is actually in Typescript.
uh 700 lines of code. Uh and the others
the other uh the other code is just
this.
It's well it's still 50 lines of code,
60 lines of code.
So it's trying to draw a simple um
spiral.
Yeah. But you can see sign cosine they
are tangent.
Uh
so I know so when you when you want to
plot a curve you know s cosine whatever
you want to show it in SVG you have to
do you have to do this coordinate
translation and also flip the y-axis. It
it turns out this is fairly confusing.
You know, you spend hours to to get it
right.
Um,
yeah. So, let's go back to
So, I didn't uh wait, you know, I didn't
go too far with this plotting uh curves,
but there are libraries like I think
there are quite a few.
Uh, okay. So, what are we doing? So
yeah, back here. So
this is fairly complicated man.
So we need to do that that and and for
each graphics we need to turn it into
like that then line similarly
then
oh god this is difficult.
So imagine
what I need to do. So typically what I
need to do is to
you know for my project there are
there are hundreds of these thousands
over you know over a few thousand over a
thousand of these
two-dimensional graphics.
So you can see each one of them easily
have
a th00and points.
Um
so you have to
apply translation to this.
But then the the other difficulty is
that then you have colors and styles for
each line or circle. You see? So that
means to turn that so that get that's
actually more complex because in wufam
language
whenever you have a a style let's say
red here
so when you have a style called graphics
directive like red or thickness or you
know line thickness or color.
So where wherever whenever you have a
graphics directive it applies to the
subsequent elements in a list. So we are
having a list here.
So if you have let's say blue here
that means you know these three circles
are red then this the rest here is blue.
So each graphics directive applies
sequentially until there's another one
overriding it. So if this one says
thickness
that's another directive. Okay. So
so you know this won't override over
here because there's abs it's absent
there.
So anyway, the point is that each one
affects subsequent style of graphics
primitives,
but that's not how SVG is done. So for
SVG,
either you put a style for each of the
graphics primitive like here or you
group them together and say what style
it is.
So you need a way to convert this
sequential kind of ordering
into grouped items. So for example, this
red circle circle circle, you need to
turn that into a list by itself.
And that's not so easy, you know,
because you know because from my example
it looks very simple.
But actually in real life graphics you
might have lots of arbitrary nesting. So
you you see you might have arbitrary
nesting of graphics. So that gets really
complex because you have a tree
at each depth of a tree the coloring are
sequential. Okay. But
that's that's for the the the same like
brothers and sisters in the same level
the curling are sequential but then you
got parents and parents and or children
in those cases of course the colors spec
you know the if the parents specify red
all children should be red unless one of
the children
has a older brother that says different
color. You see that's how it's supposed
to be you know so that's how complex it
is. So to properly convert
to properly do the coloring for wam
language graphics
this hierarchy based and sequential
based when it's in the same level
you need to turn that into a proper
nested hierarchy
or have a style for each element.
So that's the specification of this this
problem and uh that is not easy.
Do you guys see what I'm saying?
Uh yes. So
if you it would mean that you need to
cover each shape with a corresponding
tag. Yes, that's true.
Uh
so path is the most general general way
to represent any shape. So let me get
this. So
yeah, we are not going to call this.
It's it's getting too complicated. God,
I hate when this happens, you know. I'm
gonna I'm going to do a live stream. You
know, this is trivial. Uh then it turns
out then you when you actually do it,
it's not so trivial. It's not
trivial.
Uh
so path is the most general way to
represent any shape. Yes. And that's why
the standard export use it instead of
the specific tag.
Uh yes and no. In general yes but
however understand that path can never
can technically
cannot mathematically represent a circle
perfectly.
So it's doing approximation okay
you know because it's using ba cubic
basier curve to emulate a circle okay
that's not good that's that's a really
kind of a problem okay
uh but the rest of the primitives line
rectangle you know or ellipses
uh actually I'm not sure about ellipse
uh I think so yeah ellipse Yeah, you
actually path has a way to represent
this ellipse exactly. Wait,
if path can represent ellip ellipses
exactly then that also implies it can do
for the circle. So,
oh I see. So, it actually path can
represent the circle precisely.
However,
it's not via cubic basio curve. It's you
have to uh you have to use um
arc you see. So I spent I spent quite a
few months uh doing this you know. So
here's a JavaScript that shows
interactive JavaScript.
So this thing so you can see this thing
which is a el major radius uh let's say
minor radius and you can also rotate it
rotation
uh let's let's go to here okay this one
is easier to see
so it is possible
to use path to represent a circle
or it lists all part of it by the path.
Exactly. Okay. So you can see
but however you must use the command a
for arc. Okay. So a is followed by one
two three four five six seven seven
parameters.
So, so you can
so for example you can represent the
circle exactly using path but not by the
basia curve you have to do it by the um
okay this is too large uh god
you have to do it by using the arc
parameter okay but however the wolfam
language is not using that it's using
basio a curve. So it's like one complete
It's just wrong. It shouldn't do that.
Okay. So yes, it is true that path can
represent
path is a general, you know, can
represent any of the
primitives in SVG as far as I know. It
can represent um you know so where is
it? Um
line. It can represent rectangle. It
could represent rectangle with corners.
It can represent circle. It is polygon
and polyline and
and uh and text you know text is font
kind of
uh and cubic spline. Yeah, that's path.
Okay.
Okay. So I mean okay we learned more
about this. So why didn't WUM language
use the arc? You know, it's sucks.
Is an SVG file always plain text? Yes.
Or is it mixture of plain text and
binary? No. It's always plain text, you
know, it's actually just XML. So, I have
the entire tutorial. You can read
practical SVGs, you know. Uh, it's
entirely XML.
You can embed bitmapped images in SVG
like a photograph, you know, but the
format for that bitmapped image is
turned into I believe um
uh is turned into into a ASI um what's
what's it called? Um base 64. I believe
it's using B 64 encoding. So, so in the
end it's still text. Okay.
If the programmer who implemented this
export algorithm didn't use anything
except for path then it's lot of digging
into uh it would mean that you need to
cover each shape. Yeah. I mean they they
have to cover each shape anyway. So
anyway, so what we going to do now? So
um
god this. So I have to think about what
am I going to do? Do I spend so to code
this fully
will take
I would say 30 hours. Okay.
to code this, you know, to write a
robust version of this export graphics
to SVG,
it'll take me 30 hours.
Is it worth it?
So, you see, I'm I'm checking out. I'm
thinking about do I want to do this or
not? 30 hours and say one day. One, two,
three, four, five days. Yeah, something
like
30 hours.
Um,
but I really need it because if I can
get this to, you know, if I did it, then
these thousands of images of my plank
projects, they will be very efficient.
You know, beautiful graphics, small file
size.
Yeah.
Um
but 30 hours. My god.
Okay,
I think that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching.
Okay. So, I think that's it.
Am I going to do it or not? I don't
know. But I know for sure I can't I
cannot do it like in live stream
because
this will be just you know me coding uh
very complicated stuff.
When it's very complicated live stream
doesn't work because you can't possibly
expand
the steps what you are doing.
Um
and it's very boring to watch.
Uh yeah.
Okay. So, but so I have to think about
am I going to code this because
especially nasty because when you have
you know let me show you when you have
nesting this nesting graphics you see
um
when you need to figure out about this
colors thing.
Okay, let me think about again.
That's still doable though.
So I can definitely do it.
So what is the advantage? So if I write
this, I can publish it so other people
can use it.
There will be you know
benefit to
many people but usually not too many
because very few people use wam language
in the first place
and then they wouldn't know I have
written it because it's you know uh hard
to find.
Uh
yeah, but then but I going to use it
mostly for myself.
I have to think about this. Okay, so
that's it. I think that's it.
God, this is
painful.
W. So is there did someone else have
someone wrote the package? Let's say
let's search. Okay.
X SVG export. Uh okay. Export graphics
directly.
Okay. including
region plot and graphics object. The
exported SV file is mesh meshless and
retain vector quality. Okay. Allowing
for high resolution. Okay.
Oh, export string function can also
generate an SVG string representation.
Fantastic. I didn't know. Export string.
Okay, you learned something new.
Let's see. Is there a documentation?
There it is. Okay. Basically the same
except that it doesn't write to file.
Okay. Fantastic.
Okay. Then
X XML package provide tools like XML
SVG.
Oh,
graphics to symbolic SVG to convert
graphics directly to into symbolic XML.
Oh, which is the foundation of SVG
enabling advanced man manipulation such
as animation.
This capability allows for the creation
of interactive SVG including animations
of moving elements. Okay. While
exporting to SVG is efficient for vector
graphics large or complex uh something
for optimal results especially with
plots containing sharp edges. It's
recommended to use vector formats. Okay.
Yeah, but
okay. So why is
So does anyone actually talk about how
large file it generates?
That's you know that's really advanced
because vast majority of people
they don't know you know they just
generate SVG they don't you know they
don't know the details of SVG so they
don't they they don't even know the
issue
so let's see this guy export hi I'm
using I'm new to wam language I would
like to export plot Uh,
okay. This guy is talking about 3D. No,
you cannot do that.
Okay. I don't think none of this
actually
dives into detail. None of these
actually understand what I'm saying.
uh
because what I'm doing is
advanced. Now let's look at this link.
So did they explain
is does it explain
No, it doesn't.
So, can I customize the command?
No, I don't think so.
Yeah.
You see it turns everything into basio
curve. idiotic.
Okay.
So question,
do you have any desire to discuss lisps?
Yeah, sure. Whenever I'm doing emac
lisp, you can kind of ask me about lisp
usually
unless I'm, you know, seriously trying
to code something. Uh, I've read a lot
of your articles on this topic, but
still can decide if it's a good idea for
me to create my own list that compiles
to see.
I think you only know only you know the
question because for average in for the
general people
you know for for programmers in general
the answer to that is no because you are
just creating you know you are just
creating your own language you know
that's if you like it you have your
reasons only you know if you really love
it you want to do it for hobby just for
the love it whatever uh yeah
So, but if you have to ask somebody
else, the answer is probably no. You
know, only you can decide it's worth it.
So,
yeah, that's it. That's all I know. I
don't know about writing a compiler. I
don't really know about it. So, I cannot
help. Okay, bye guys.