Hello guys. Good morning.
Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Kar Talk Show. We are
going to code Emac Lisp Emacs the most
powerful editor in the world. Okay. So
this episode is just for you guys who
are using Emacs
uh you know
Emacs okay the most powerful editor so
especially useful for programmers
and what we're going to do is we're
going to install a spell checker so
let's see so close that showing browser
okay close that showing browser episode
make spell checking in Emacs Microsoft
of Windows. Great. Again, now if you are
using Linux spell checkers,
spellch checking works out of the box.
But if you are working on Windows, you
got a problem because the GNU people,
especially Richard Strowman, they
intentionally make Emacs worse on
Windows because according to them, they
want the great Emacs open, you know,
free software, richest free software
foundations concept of free software,
which is a abuse of the English word
free. You know, to them they think free,
you know, they abuse the word free to
mean freedom and they abuse the word the
concept of freedom to mean freedom in
software according to their opinions.
Okay? Like like typically freedom in
western society means am I alive? So if
you are watching this offline play at
1.2 to uh 1.5 speed because I ramble. Uh
if you are watching this online right
now, say hi. Okay, so according to
Richard Storman, the founder of free
software software foundation and the
cause of the opensource movement
beginning in 1997 also
Richard Stallman. Okay. So he founded
free software foundation uh and
according to him
freedom you know so he abused the word
freedom. Now the word freedom in western
society means you are not controlled by
any person you know like free you know
you are free to speak about anything
about your leaders about your government
about politicians you know you are you
have the freedom to do that.
But according to Richard Stman, he
he thinks that freedom includes about
the software, you know, that like the
software, the the iPad, iPhone,
whatever, you know, you the application,
the Twitter you use. So in his opinion,
freedom includes the ability to for
example I write a software and I must
give you
you know I can sell you my software but
I must also include the source the
source code so that you can you know
copy it you can make modifications and
you can resell it.
So basically when you resell my software
according to Richard Stman's principle
then basically you robbed my ability to
make money with it. But according to
Richard Storman that is you know part of
the concept of freedom. Therefore he
promote you know that he abused the word
you know free software foundation
um which is um free software foundation.
So for in case you don't know you can
look up there it is FSF free software
foundation their website and Wikipedia
okay so free software foundation and uh
you know their website so according to
him whenever you sell software uh you
must include the source code free you
must allow the users to be able to
modify it and resell it things like that
Okay. Uh so that is his opinion. So but
he
does not say it's just uh one of the
opinion he insist that is the what
freedom means. So if you sell your
software if you are ethical you know I'm
a let's say I'm an ethical person. I
create software that does you know very
good. that doesn't spy on you, doesn't
do any nasty things and I sell to you.
But however, I don't allow you to like
make a copy and resell my my program.
So if I do that, according to Richard
Strowman, this guy a [ __ ]
you know, do we have a picture of him
here? Somewhere somewhere, you know,
you'll find it. According to him, you
are evil because in his opinion,
if you sell a software but not does not
let the user like resell it and other
things, then you are evil. You are, you
know, you are like not promoting
freedom. So, we got this Richard Stman
[ __ ]
Okay. Now he's you know so he's not
actually not too bad you know he's not
too bad a guy you know because when you
talk about bad people in the world you
know so many politicians leaders and in
history um there are a lot of course and
many of them caused millions death.
So in general, Richard Storman in my
opinion is not, you know, such a great
evil person
and uh he has, you know, he's the, you
know, he's the leader of this free
software foundation movement. That's
okay because you need different opinions
to compete. You, you know, you must
allow. So Richard Stman's opinion about
software is one of the opinion. You must
also allow other opinions to you know to
thrive to compete including open source.
By the way rich open source is a split
split off of the Richard Stoman's free
software foundation movement. So they
became and they became enemies. the
open-source software foundation they
their idea is that as long as you
include the the source code then you are
fine you know but Richard Sman disagree
he he he because Richard Sman he you
know he deeply believe his own specific
principle about morality
around software okay so Richard Sman
hates despise the open-source movement
Okay, they are like they are in a war
but open source movement won't of course
because today we don't hear free
software foundation we just hear open
source open source partly because open
source has been
uh taken by the taken and refried by the
deep state you know very powerful
organizations like Google like Microsoft
Google Microsoft micro systemystems and
uh you know Oracle you can count lots of
like Facebook, you know, lots of them.
So anyway, that is my opinion about
Richard Snowman. In summary, I did a lot
videos talking about it about like two
years, two or three years ago in my
older videos. Okay. So why are we
talking about this? Because we were
talking about Emacs. We want to have a
spellch checking ability. Like right now
I'm in Emacs as you know, but I cannot
spell check. So whenever I want to check
something if I spell correctly uh
you know I I I wrote a command to look
up dictionary. So this correctly is
incorrect.
So you have to you know so if I want to
check a spell that's what I do. Okay. Uh
you know so now it's correct. But but
this is this is inefficient. You know,
usually typically in any text editor,
you can press a key and it'll just
highlight the incorrect spell word and
if you right click it, it'll just
correct it, you know. So, Emacs has that
feature, but that feature is not
available
on Windows. When you run Emacs on
Windows, so if you run Emacs on Linux,
you have that feature kind of built in.
And part the reason for this is because
Richard Stman and his scan of people you
know who who who the Emacs de he he
doesn't want Windows version of Emacs to
be to be very good. Okay. Okay. That's
kind of digression.
Hello GPS.
So what so what I'm doing today is going
to I'm going to try to install to make
spell checking work on Windows
and I'm having red wine. So this is red
wine.
So if you are busy man if you are a busy
man you just want to get things done
this video is not for you. So for you if
you are using Emacs on Windows just
check out this this page these two
pages. Okay. So this EMAC easy wing
ports
by the Eddie Zaraskki guy. Okay. So this
website on source forge easy wing ports.
So check it out you know. So basically
what you need to do is you need to
install hunbell hunspel or aspel
that's two programs you need for emac
spell checking to work on linux it's
already there you know uh and emac is bu
so it or just works out of the box but
on windows you so you need to install
either aspel or hensel and you know from
this website easyw ports and then you
need to configure get you need to set
the path. You need to set in the
environment variables. You need to set
the execution EMAC execution path and
stuff to uh in order to get spell
checking to work
for Emacs on Windows. Okay. Another
website you can check is this old Reddit
I mean this Reddit. Okay. So tutorial
spellch checking with hunp spell for
Emacs on Windows. Okay. So, this post is
five years old. 2016
uh wait uh 2000 well five years ago. So,
that is like 20 um
2019 something 2020.
Okay, let's turn on JavaScript. So, if
you are a busy man, don't watch my
video. you know, you can just try to uh
go to these two websites and figure out
how it works. Yeah. But good luck. So,
what I'm going to do today is, you know,
I'm going to try to make it work. Okay.
So, any comments?
Okay. No comments. So, let's see.
So in order to get spell checking to
work, let's start to work on them. Okay.
So go to the source for so they are
uh god. So thanks to these people who
suggested me you know what to do. So I
tried it few years ago but I didn't uh
get it done.
So okay. So how to get spell checker to
work? First of all, what are the
commands for spellch checking? What are
the commands for spellch checking in
Emacs? First of all, that is a question
and I know one of them is I spell okay
uh let's see
uh let's see I spell word okay that's
one of the command you can use that will
just check the spelling of the word
under ka okay it doesn't work right now
because I don't have you know because
for example let's say put the place ka
there call it I spell word do it And
what does it say? Uh and uh I spell
check version blah blah blah released
0.6 or greater is required.
So that's the error message I got.
Uh okay.
So what are commands? So I spell word is
one of the command and another command
is fly spell something. Okay. Let's try
fly spell. Fly spell
uh fly spell mode.
Okay, so you got several uh so let's
do it. Okay, so error. So it says error
that release 0.6 or greater is required.
So basically I got the same error. So, I
got Ice Spell installed last time a few
years ago. I tried to make it work, but
then it says release 0.6 is required.
Okay. So, anyway, so so now let's um
but now let's just get the commands.
What are the commands I need? Okay, so
fly spell mode is one of them. And uh
why don't you just do a propose command?
So you can see in a pink window a
propose command. So that command call it
uh by this key. Then type spell it will
list all command names containing the
word spell. Okay. So you got you got all
these commands related to spellch
checking.
Okay. Uh, check dog. Now, where does
check dock came from? I don't know.
Let's look up. Check dog. Uh,
oh, fancy. Check the style and spelling
of everything.
So, this package must be something I'm
not aware of. Okay. But anyway, I'm just
concerned about
spellch checking, okay? I don't want to
check grammar and stuff. Usually, those
are [ __ ]
You know, those those software that
checks grammar or stuff, usually they
are just [ __ ] Okay, you need to learn.
So, this is about writing. Okay,
spelling is one thing. Of course, you
need a spell checker. It helps a lot.
Uh but the grammar checker usually they
are just [ __ ] Actually today with
today's AI there are some good ones but
usually they are [ __ ] because when it
comes to grammar and writing style
usually those suggestions are just bad
for you because because when you write
the art of writing they are just it's
very fluid. Okay. If you use the correct
grammar and whatever they suggest your
your writing becomes a boring piece of
[ __ ] just like today
like I read a story you know a few days
ago that the professors you know they
have to grade homework and a lot
homework done by students today are done
by AI you know they just ask uh gu you
know ask AI bot write please write me a
essay about uh let's say the relations
of USA and uh and United Kingdom you
know give me a short history whatever
whatever essay
you know so the AI bot will create
absolute perfect grammar and well
organized thesis you know but the
professor you know the per professor can
see it right away this is created by AI
because when you have something written
by AI the grammar is Perfect. Perfect.
The organization is perfect. The style
is kind of perfect journalism style, you
know. Everything is like so perfect. But
the content is devoid of humanity. It's
like there's nothing empty, you know.
It's like written by a robot, you know,
basic essentially. There's no spirit.
There's no like your your character, you
know, what you are thinking. there's
none, you know, just like kind of fact
and you know, like like logical and
fact, you know, so it's bland.
Okay. So, so this this this is uh this
this is a point that agree with my
opinion that all these uh grammar
checking software and style checking
software they are [ __ ] Do not use it.
Okay, my recommendation. This is my
personal recommendation because I am a
guy I'm into writing very much since
1990s. I'm obsessed about writing
writing style and all that. Okay. So, so
uh that is a piece of experience I'm
telling you guys. So if you are into
writing you know writing is not a good
thing to spend a lot of time into.
you want to go somewhere, if you want to
go somewhere, if you want to make
America great again, go into
mathematics, engineering, and
programming. Okay, that's a real thing.
If you go into, oh, I'm going to study
history. I'm going to be study uh
English writing, grammar, literature,
you know, that's that's no good. That's
well it's not no good but it's
it's not uh it's not very practical.
Okay. It's not very useful and it's not
very good. It's not you don't have much
job prosperities needed. Okay. So don't
go you know go don't go into writing and
stuff. But however,
writing a good to be able to write well
is still a good um a very uh useful uh
skill
especially your thinking and analysis
abilities. So it's good to practice
writing because when you write you hone
your ability to think about things and
analyze it because in order to represent
your view you know whatever is essay
topic you know you have to think you
have to analyze and you have to you know
so when you write you have to make a
good argument you know or organize your
opinion organize your thoughts
you know and present it. So it helps
writing helps develop your logic
abilities, your analysis abilities. Why
writing?
Well, because when you write, you need
to give it out you know publish it for
someone else to read it for. So when
someone else who don't you know who
don't share the brain as you they will
be able you know they will be the judge
you know when you present your writing
they are the judge to see you know to
you know so it's up to them to
understand exactly what what your logic
your argument is. So when you write well
they understand they may not agree but
they understand. So that is the power of
writing and and why writing is a great
exercise is a good thing to a good skill
to have. Okay. Even if you are not a
engineer
uh even if you go into whatever you know
politics or law you need to writing is
uh fairly important still. Okay.
Uh
okay. So anyway we digressed a lot. We
got into fly spell uh many commands.
Okay. So let's close that. Close that.
So these are some of the most important
command for uh spell checking in Emacs.
Okay. So showing browser.
So oh Jesus another new version of
Firefox. You know Firefox been updating
every day uh lately. So anyway, so we
discovered we we know we know some of
the commands for uh spell checking. Now
we need to install the programs. Okay,
let's see the comments. Ching, thank you
Hank again. Do recruiters look for you
on your YouTube? Uh recruiters
not for my YouTube but for my LinkedIn.
You know, I have a LinkedIn. I haven't
updated for more than 10 years. I
haven't logged in for like 10 years.
Yeah, actually I logged in like few
years ago, but I haven't touched it for
more than 10 years. So, so I get emails
like, oh, oh, we saw your resume
something, you know, sometimes.
But my YouTube, I got I got sponsors,
you know, like the keyboard like, you
know, a month ago. uh from uh what's the
um Razer, you know, the Razer that makes
keyboards and gaming devices. They
contact me, hey, we like to sponsor, you
know, something like, hey, um you know,
we like to sponsor you
Razer and and and I think another
company, but I I didn't reply. So, you
know, I'm not into I'm not really into I
should I actually should reply. So, I
become like one of the no more know me
YouTubers, you know, make money,
make money. Oh, by the way, today's
sponsor is VPN. I Oh, yeah. That reminds
me actually I got a sponsorship from VPN
request. You know, the like northern you
uh like VPN you they are uh very popular
on YouTube, you know.
you know they send me an email saying
that oh do you like to you know work
with us you know something
maybe I should you know yeah but mostly
I want just you guys to donate to me
okay I don't want you know I don't want
like in the middle of my video this like
oh today's sponsor is VPN guys I really
like VPN because do you know do you know
guys how important is VPN because the
virtual network because the government
something therefore
you know, you just go to this site and
use the code kasadi and you'll get 10%
discount, you know, like it's kind of,
you know, it's marketing. It's a
marketing capitalism of the American
way.
Um,
well, I mean, some of it is good, but
usually becomes hard when you don't
want, you know, when you don't want to
talk about [ __ ]
um you know so the you know so I don't
I'm not really into so I just want you
guys to donate to me I'm not making any
money okay I'm not you know so thank you
Hank and uh you other people you know
donate to me by
by going to kasadi.info info. Okay.
Click click kasar code kasadi.info.
Uh and and you can go all the way down
to the PayPal section. Patreon, PayPal,
Amazon gift card. Pay me $100. Pay me
100 bucks. If you
have a job, okay? If you are
professional programmers or something,
you know. Uh
okay. So let's see what is uh uh yeah
YouTube. Yeah, I got some solicitation
from the you know some some keyboard
reviews and stuff.
Nice keyboard broad. Thank you broad.
Hello blue three. Now blue three is a
emac advanced EMAC coder. If I recall
correctly, blue three wrote a thesis,
a bachelor's thesis or master thesis
about, you know, some Emacs
uh compiler technical details.
That's you right if I recall correctly.
Blue three says, "What's up with the
cyber decks? The handheld computers
AliExpress ready with cramped keyboard.
think you can work home this
home list magic on it. Cyber decks.
Okay.
Now, I heard of a cyber deck, but I'm
not too familiar with it, you know. It's
like a little little small screen
computer, you know, cyber deck. I don't
I'm not too into that
cyber deck. Okay, there's a Reddit
forum. Now, let's look at some pictures.
Uh, yeah, you see this little, you know,
computers
that, you know, I guess allows you, you
know, it's good for hacker types. Let's
turn on JavaScript so Google knows who
you sleep with. Now, open that. So, you
see this is kind of typical cyber deck.
What they are good for? They are good
for you know if you are on the go if you
are a hacker you know you you know
that's what you do. Uh but I'm not I'm
not that type, you know. I'm a you might
call me, you know, I'm a if I may say
I'm a computer scientist. I'm a computer
engineer. I'm a mathematician.
You know, I don't go around like hack.
Oh, you got to hack this. You you got to
break this network in 10 minutes. You
know, that's not my thing. And that
field is very different from
engineer and from programming from
architecture from creating you know uh
you know that's you know that's just not
my thing hacker cyber deck so cyber deck
is uh attractive to the hacker types
you know so let's see you know so you
got this you know okay cyber deck cyber
deck Okay.
What what am I going to do it? You know,
tiny cable keyboard, tiny screen. You're
going to ddle with it. You know, you're
going to hack some pass password. You
know, Unix. You're going to Unix and
Linux and something on this little [ __ ]
No, that's that's not my thing. I you
know, so I'm into battle station. You
know, I have a full screen, full
powerful keyboards. Okay. My that's my
battle station. That's what I'm into.
I'm not into
the cyber deck stuff.
Okay. So,
do you have a preferred or go to
programming language for auto automating
tasks? Okay. Of course I have a
preferred language that would be wam
language that will be goland and f okay
that is general purpose okay let's write
it out
preferred programming language okay
for industrial programming
programming okay
and Functional
in industrial
uh
programming
programming. Okay. F#
wolf frame language
general purpose
general purpose scientific programming.
Okay. Um and so that is my uh preferred
languages. Okay. I I have a tutorial for
Golan and Wuang.
You can see them
here.
Uh, language. Beautiful. You know, I'm
I've been, you know, I'm working on it
every day. Uh,
fantastic 3D graphics tutorial coming
up. So, Golan,
one of my best tutorial, Golan. Okay.
And, uh, what is this? Um,
and the Wuam language and F. I don't
have a I don't have a tutorial for F F.
Okay.
Uh, wait.
What? Cuz what's going on?
What?
Wait. I [ __ ] up something. Okay. Copy
that. Wait. Not Cass code.
Copy that. Paste. Close. Copy that.
Link. Okay. Whatever. So that is my
general purpose preferred
general purpose programming languages.
Okay. Uh let's see. Goland F wound
language. What else? Is there anything
else? Let's see. Um
uh well Emacs list is kind of special.
If you do text processing that is the
best. Okay. So, Emacs this is best for
text processing. Okay,
that's the best language for text
processing.
Okay, what else? Let's see. Uh,
Goland PowerShell. Well, PowerShell is
is just necessary if you do things on
Windows. So if you work with Microsoft
Windows as a professional
you know whether you are a programmer or
whatever you know as a professional so
PowerShell okay Python is [ __ ] well but
Python is like mostly used for machine
uh machine learning stuff okay Java is
[ __ ] closure okay anyway so th those
these are the my best programming
languages now yours particular question
is about
for automating tasks. Okay, that's a
very specific
purpose. Okay. Uh so for the purpose of
automating automating tasks
for automation.
Okay. Then your choices are let me tell
you
your choices are uh on Mac it's
Apple script.
Okay, that's basically that's that's
what you got on Mac is Apple script.
Okay. Uh let's see. So you can look up,
you can read about Wikipedia, Apple
script.
Uh on Windows
it's
PowerShell
and
auto hard key. Okay.
Showing browser go down. Okay. So on
Windows you it's necessary. So you study
PowerShell and Autoarchy. Okay. So I
have a tutorial for them of course.
Search for
why I love PowerShell. Uh so where is my
PowerShell tutorial? PowerShell
PowerShell. The PowerShell tutorial.
Copy it. Go back.
Paste it. Link V list. Okay. And what's
the other powershell and auto hotkey?
Auto hotkey tutorial. Okay, there. Okay,
so on windows if you want automation
these two
are necessary.
Now what is what specific do you have in
mind? What do you mean automat
automating task? For example, there's
another automation of task that is in
browser. So if you are a corporation
that creates browser uh stuff such as
Google or NodeJS you know NJS the
corporation or if you are a corporation
you have a huge website based on website
you need to uh do uh unit testing you
need to do lots of testing automation
you need to do automated testing of
users using your website Then in that
case that's more very specific. In that
case there are quite a few uh you know
either based on Python or JavaScript you
know that's so-called headless browsers
that does automation. So you can you
know you can automating login and user
clicking on some buttons you know to get
some query or whatever. Okay. So that's
very specialized.
So what do you mean by automating? Okay.
So well on if you are on um Unix then
if on Linux then bash Python you you
know Python pro you can do lots of you
know Linux doesn't really have a
automated automation um architecture
okay
despite you might think it should but
Linux actually sucks.
you know because I actually I have a
story to tell anyway about key key
binding. Anyway,
Apple has Zshask
automation. Well, you know that's that's
um well ZSH is just a shell just like
bash. It's a better bash, but
it doesn't, you know, it's not very
specialized for automation because if
you argue that on Apple ZSH is great,
then you might as well use Python or PHP
or even Pearl, Ruby. So like lots of all
kind of language works.
Another question, do you use a web
framework for my website? No, everything
is manual, coded by Emacs
character by character, uh, tag by tag.
Okay, basically
uh, love the small autocompletes you do.
Is it Emac thing?
My autocomplete. Oh yeah. So that so you
were talking about. So there are
several. Okay. So one of the most
powerful is um Emacs a brief feature for
example PSW PowerShell you enter so that
become powershell w for woofam language
u becomes woofam language okay so um
you know I got lots of them so that's
so you can look at my a file so all
these are a brief So for example,
probability prob uh probability.
Okay. So probably prob probably. Okay.
So punctuation punctuation.
Okay.
Um product is PD and so on. Okay. I got
like
1,700 of them. something like you know
1617. So a brief if you want to know
about abbreviation you can just go to my
website search for emac abbreviation
you'll find my article so in five
minutes you can set up what I have okay
and another thing
okay so let's copy copy that and uh
let's um paste the link here so you can
abbreviation. Okay, so that's one of the
feature for completion. And another
thing I use is um is called uh is
basically just this. Okay, let's see.
Press Z. Wait, press uh what what is the
key I press? Yeah. Okay, so that that
key. Okay. Uh
so if you can look up so the command is
called hep expand. Okay he expand is
part of emacs building. So what it does
is that it allows you to expand any word
that occurs in all your buffers. So ABB
I do not have a abbreviation for that
but however I can expand it to a brief
because it occurs in one of the buffer.
Okay. So I just press a key it becomes a
brief. So let's say let's try another
example. So um
auto hotkey right? So let's for example
auto hotkey here. So if I just type auto
h then hippie expand there it is. Okay.
So, two things abbreviation you have to
set up yourself. That's what I use. Go
to this link. Okay. The other thing is
hippie expand.
It will expand according to whatever you
have you know the words in your or in
any of your buffers. Okay. Do I have an
article on that? Yes, of course. You
know, go to my just search for Emacs
tutorial. Go to.info. info emac blog
search
completion okay you will find everything
you need to know like all possible
features of completion in emacs okay
that's like you know 15 articles name
completion you click on that then you
can see there it is hippie expand click
on that that's how you do it okay
uh so I have all these tutorials but of
Of course, people don't read them. Uh,
that's too bad. Okay, so let's copy some
of them. Close that. Uh, name
completion. Go back, paste the link
here. Okay, and search, you know.
Anyway, so linkify them and uh listify
them showing browser. Okay, now I was
going to inst going to install spell
checker, but I guess I didn't. You know,
we talked random for lots of things. Um,
so maybe not. I'm just going to do this
offline then.
So far so good. So far so good everyone.
Eight people watching. Six Six people
watching.
So, uh, love the small autocomplete. You
use a web framework. Okay. Uh, Linux
doesn't have an architecture for task
automation.
Uh, but system D does. Oh, okay. I
didn't know. System D is something
everyone hates.
Yeah, but I'm I haven't been using Linux
for 10 years, so I don't know
now more about abbreviation. Okay,
so you guys mentioned I'm using phonetic
alphabet. That is correct.
So right now I'm using my bookmark
feature to jump to my abbreviation
setup. So you can see right here go to
the top. Uh so actually I'm building up
a shorthand system. So you can see first
of all you have the data most used
English words. So open that show in
browser. So you can you can go to this
web page you know just search for.info
most used English words. So that will
tell you, you know, at least of 5,000
most used English words.
Why do you need to know that? Because
when you design abbreviation, this is
important data.
You want an abbreviation for the most
frequently used words. So for example,
U for you. Uh
uh
W is for width. Okay. So how uh H is for
half? Okay. So like Okay. Uh close that.
Close that. Wait.
Go to it. Copy it. Switch to talk show.
Paste a link. Linkify now.
Okay. Now go back to my a brief page. Um
okay. So that's a most used English
words. That's one thing you you want to
know. You need to know when you design a
abbreviation system that is what kind of
characters to expect ex what you know
what words you want to have abbreviation
and what is the characters you want for
that word. Okay.
So and a quot you know my own design is
is this article kasar shorthand system
you can go to it showing browser. So
this is kasar shorthand system.
B for but, D for does, F for,
H for have, K for no, L for let, M for
more. So why? Because these are the most
frequently used English words. The top
100 most frequently used English words.
So you got
then, you know, then there's others.
Okay, so you can read this article if
you like.
uh if you you know so let's go let's
paste it here
okay then let's then there is this
article which is which tells you how to
set it up in EMAC you can have you know
abbreviation for commonly used words for
arguments you know a arg for argument
for example new buffer arg
uh or actually actually I changed that
you know actually now it's
amentment
AGM okay so this is slightly not updated
anyway this article is about setting up
abbreviations in Emacs how to do it
okay so
so that is how to do it okay so that's
that article so let's put to today's
talk show go to today's talk show uh and
make a link. Make it a list. Go back to
uh that. Okay. So, you can see this is
my abbreviation. Okay. Um
you know there then so there's so you
begin with common commonly used English
words then you have
uh frequ frequency within the top 1,00
words. for example
anymore
you know so my abbreviation is actually
based on phonetics good observation
anyway this is a this is this is a huge
topic you this you know it's very deep
you can spend a year dive into the
design of abbreviation and shorthand
systems and there are historical um
there's quite a lot history of design of
it. Okay. So for example like sha
shavian alphabet
uh which we recently talked about you go
to unic code um shavian alphabet. Okay
so you go down there is uh Asian
language construct constructed language
shavian alphabet. So this alphabet is
designed as a efficient shorthand system
for English
and it is based on phonetics.
So the idea is that you give a you give
a character
a letter for each phone in English. So
when you use this system Shabian
alphabet your spelling is 100%
corresponding to the pronunciation. So
you don't have to guess oh in this case
it's you know it's it's a or is it O you
know you don't have to guess it's 100%
precise.
So, Shavian alphabet the history of that
is derived from the
um short
short writing system called um
something okay uh there are quite a few
okay so anyway there's a big history
about shorthand systems of English okay
and and you know so you know shavian
alphabet is one of
Okay. So, let's close that close
abbreviation file and start talk show.
Yeah. Let's paste the link here. Uh
there we have it. You know the things we
talked about. Anything else?
Do you have one in file name completion
tutorial?
Uh that one is pretty simple that all
you have to do is you Yeah. So
um so if you go so you talking about
file name completion for example I want
to open uh for example
okay for example go to my computer
programming blog show in browser so that
is done by bookmark so I just
you know type the key for bookmark
cancel so you can see the key here
bookmark jump okay so the key, you know,
is this easy keys on my special
keyboard. Okay, bookmark jump. Okay, so
do that and type cp b com computer
programming block that open this file.
So I don't have to like type and type a
file path. Okay, so bookmark is the most
important thing showing browser. There
it is. Okay,
programming block. one of my uh tens of
blocks.
So once you have that, so this
bookmark
is critical because you don't have to
type the file path. Okay. So is there a
tutorial for it? Of course.
Of course. Go to Emacs and search for
bookmark.
Uh in fact, I don't have to search it
for it, you know. I can just go to the
table of contents Emacs tutorial
practical Emacs tutorial. There is a
section on file and open save close file
manager diet batch rename files and
there is bookmark.
Okay, you got to read it. So
you know you got to be efficient just
read stuff. Okay, there it is bookmark.
So bookmark
is extremely useful. Okay. So you don't
have to type you know file path. So
that's one thing. But what what if you
want to open some file you rarely open
like the files you work with every day.
You can make a bookmark for them so that
so that you don't have to type the file
path. Okay. Something went wrong.
Uh okay.
Is my stream still going?
you know what what is going on with the
memory
Google Chrome.
Okay.
So the other thing Okay. Thank you. So
the other thing Okay. So let me
recommend one more thing. Okay. So you
just go to
um programming block. Close that. Okay.
So I don't want to go to programming
block. Okay. So, actually
close that. Close. Close. Go to today's
talk show uh and paste the link. Go to
the bookmark. Open it. So, just go to
Emacs tutorial. There's a section on
completion. Okay. Uh so you go down font
font size split window files buffers
find text copy text find replace unic
code y space and so on and on and just
go to uh miscellaneous and emac
principles. Okay. So where do you find
abbreviation? I mean where do you find
uh completion? There it is. EMAX
efficiency.
So you can see completion hippie expand.
We talked about a brief mod. We talked
about keyboard macro. That's another
thing. So you go to completion.
So this page tells you everything you
want to know about completion including
file name completion. Okay. So I can
just recommend you know you know you can
read it but I can tell you that all you
want to do is just turn on um
let's see you know Emac is fairly
complex but anyway all you want to do is
just turn on
uh
fedo mod. Okay this one fedom mod. Wait,
actually turn on feed vertical. Okay,
just turn it on. That's it.
Copy it.
Close the bookmark and paste it here.
Link by make a list show in browser.
Okay, I think that's it for today and
I'm going to install spell checker
offline. Um,
okay. So, we've been talking for an
hour. Anything else?
Um, so we I need to install spell
checker actually. Spell checker.
Uh,
so yeah. So this is going to take me
hour.
You know, you have to install this this
binary, you know, software, then you
have to configure it. Uh, yeah. So
anyway, I'm going to try to do it
offline.
Bye guys.