hi I'm going to show you a max Keeble
macro today so I have here I have this
file which is actually my keyboard macro
tutorial and the task I want to do is
actually you see this table here that's
this table and I want to change it to a
list instead of table so what I'm gonna
do is I'm going to record a macro so I
can play that macro and change this
table to a list format and I can call
the macro again on other pages so let's
let's begin so first of all I want to
place a cruiser at block I want so start
a macro select the block narrow to
region remove the mop then go to top
replace table press equals two and um
replace that by nothing do it for then
replace again table by nothing do it for
then go to top again search full caption
okay and just cut the line then go to
top search for T edge
I should have used such instead of I
called every place but that's fine so
exit cut it go to table crabby replace
again TR TD replace it by Li for go to
the top to it again crabby replace TV
he replaced it by slash pal I replace
all go to the top again one more time
cover replace this time is /t d TD and I
want to replace it by let's say
aerospace do it for and now again go to
the top insert UL then go to the bottom
then go to the last left bracket
we actually go to the bottom we remove
blank lot lines insert slash you know I
okay space and widen okay that's what I
want now stop mark well so now if we
look at the browser yes that's what we
want that's
okay well there's a mistake that the
last night should be you al not how high
you know it's a pain whenever you have a
mistake in Marco you have to do it all
over again so well what should we do
well actually let's try to edit the
Marco then because yeah okay so I'm
going to call save last okay wait named
Lansky ball mark well let's say to UT
okay
now insert key ball macro T DT okay and
now I want to find this is should be you
yeah so that's my motto
so let's copy the Marco and go to my
Emacs in it
Emacs settings actually I have a Marco
file okay to the bottom paste it here so
this is the saved Marco so we have where
by KO TT here like execute I'm aqua so
let's go back and see if that worked
so now I need the table table again did
we make a backup no okay
so let's just do that get checkout
okay so that's a table so let's so call
the mock well TDT no because it's not
right because because we didn't save the
mock lock was that I mean we saved it
but we which we edited we edited it but
we did not evaluate the code so now we
evaluate a code go back to here and we
good again curse we open now you see
it's table again so now let's do the
macro call tt that's good
you see that's you are so let's reload
so that's what I want
so that is done that's recording a
marker and name the mark well then
insert the marker so you can see the
code then save it so the the point of
saving it is that the point of saving it
is is so that you can put in your emags
in it so when you start Emacs you can
call the marker again you know it's
saved so it's close that close that
yeah so close that now there is say
another file I want to do here let's see
if I so this is another page with lots
of tables and I want to call my mark on
it so let's say it's such table okay so
this is not going to work because
remember in my mark oh I I first select
the paragraph the block of text assuming
that the whole table is the whole table
does not have empty lines in between so
so it won't walk there I know so let's
go back there okay all these got lines
in between how about let's just remove
those points for now I should be recall
the marker so that it doesn't assume the
empty eyes but for now let's just remove
those empty lines do you know okay
table so there it is so we can let's try
to harm aqua cutie yes yes that looks
like it that's working table
search for table next table come up such
call such call such call such call such
call such normal caption okay let's take
a look now in my macro I also removed
the caption but sometimes I may want it
but you know for this example let's just
forget about that I'll fix my page if I
need to later so let's look at it so
that's good that's good so so that's
good that's good
so yeah so that's that's done so that's
the use of Markov let's see what I want
what else I have
so you want to a demo of mark well
change table to list we did that play it
now when you play it you can the command
you Yuko is call as keyword macro
which is this one there and so anyway I
have this keep keyboard marco tutorial
that contains everything you need to
know about keyboard macro what we have
talked about is already written here so
you can read it and what else so that
example we did a primal to region lines
yeah so so when you record a keyboard
mark or yeah let let me show you example
so let's go here so I have let's say I
have so let's say I have a bunch of
files what I want is to show the title
of the file for each path each path so
how do I do that we can do it by a
marker for example so let's start mark
well open the file go to the top search
for title okay then
start mark such to go to move closer to
the end of angle bracket then go back to
the beginning of angle bracket copy
closed file paste had a return and go to
the next line go to the end of Lonnie
had a return then moved closer to the
next line so that's it that's how do you
recover Marco so now we stop Marco you
can see here so we started Marco here
and we stopped the Marco here so now
let's call Marco again call as kewal
Marco you see code again code again and
you can do you can do there's a repeat
complex command you see on the left
panel you see the command repeat complex
command and the last command is this
call as Kiba Marco so I just say yes
and I can use the same key to call it
let me make sure you well let me show
you up like clients to Curacao select
all the lines then call a Primark or to
region lines something screwed up yeah
but but you see several of them works
how because well there's error
something's good because this file
actually does not have any title so yeah
so you know that is why it screwed up so
this one shouldn't be there
this one of rhyme alcohol but call
Esquivel Marco yeah so wait
yeah because okay the cursor needs to be
in the beginning of line so let's try
that
there it is okay so that's qo Makos okay
that's it for today thanks for watching
bye