good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of South our
show today is September 13th monday nigh
o'clock a.m. san francisco time and
today i'm going to talk about bunch of I
guess random things and okay random
things now if you have a topic or
question posted okay let's refresh
come on in Justin so Justine you have
any questions or comments I'm gonna talk
about random things okay so let me show
you okay so let's go to pass our talk
show some talk show I got lots of things
I'm gonna talk about so today I prepared
okay let me show you this amazing d3
JavaScript you know so so in October I
decided come on is it wrong crazy
in October I decided I'm going to spend
one hour on d3.js and one hour on react
Jia's and one hour on on my project of
creating playing curves in JavaScript so
let me show you what they are
so okay remember those things and I'm
going to show you this Emacs variable
pitch Mart very interesting okay so on
the Left window is my Emacs commands all
the Emacs commands you can see okay
let's put that there
come on in Clemen so you guys if you
have a question or topic post it okay
I'm gonna stop talking random so let me
show you this d3.js thing keyboard very
interesting keypad close that okay
that's let me show you some of the
interesting things one by one okay copy
that I'm going to show you that to close
that show that get cookie set cookies
empty buffer range function array dev
blog I don't know what is carat oak come
on II meant so what I want to show you
the d3 okay so go to my programming
block showing browser and back to Emacs
search for d3 okay actually go to the
Dyer directory search for d3 there it is
so here is the article showing browser
back to Emacs copy the file path new
buffer paste in large buffer turn it
into a URL and go to my website so show
it now t3 I studied so I'm going to
study d3 and react.js
and you know one hour each day so I'm
going to master them in October and d3
is quite interesting if you don't know
already t3 t3 is a kind of the
supposedly the best JavaScript library
for doing graphics like I'm going to
show you okay but however I don't like
d3 I try to study at this kind of
esoteric you know the design is it's
kind of weird
okay because why is it weird this
article experience so I wrote this
article d3.js visualization a quasi
science so it's kind of one of those
it's quasi science but in like Perl you
know they the author the author is this
guy Mike Bostock
okay he's got some kind of you know
weird ideas that he wants to push so but
anyway but it's very cool though and
it's very it's a great you know very
dense library and it's a it's been
around for like almost 10 years I think
it was d3 so I think he was a Stanford
student something like that Stanford
University it's just down here and so
before it's called
I think prototypes something I mean it's
it's there's another graphics library
anyone remember the name green deck so
anyway it's a very popular graphics
library I forgot the name it at moment
if you look at Wikipedia you'll find it
I mean if you go to Wikipedia d3.js
you may find the previous solution so
anyway there was a graphics library for
JavaScript very popular then you know
from his experience he created a new
version and that version becomes d3 okay
which is what we are looking and I'm
going to show you now now this article
okay it's a kind of quasi science from
this article I understand I start to
understand why t3 is so weird you know
I've been doing visualization
programming for like at least 10 years
since 1990 okay and I study math you
know geometry differential geometry you
know algebraic geometry the the things
this d3 guy taught talks about this Mike
guy he talks about it's a it's a quasi
science ok it's not it's not math it's
not you know a regular computer science
he's talking his own things like he's
trying to push a new some kind of a new
era new thought you know I would say you
know like the Perl code back then or
like the pattern you know programming
patterns you know like kind of in my
opinion ok kodesh ideas so but anyway
the the library is very solid ok so for
example you see all these though these
are done by d3 but however there is one
spectacular one I want to show you
good-morning bathroom you so I want to
show you this spec spectacular one ok so
another thing about this guy he's
creating a something called
visualization of algorithms so the thing
you are seeing is a algorithm for
sorting
oh no it's for fish yet shuffle so you
can visually visually see how it works
kind of so that is fish yet
now Fisher Fisher yet chef oh it's it's
just random random lands Asia okay like
you have a bunch of playing cards you
want to random random nice them the
thing about that is that you want to
randomize it in a you know kind of true
random way because anyway so that that's
what that fishery is shuffle is about I
have a JavaScript library
I mean JavaScript function I wrote for
that sorry
JavaScript fish Yates algorithm there so
so it's on my website you can see the
code you know it's just five lines of
code
the trick about this function is that if
you are not careful I mean if you don't
know math you know probability well then
you can easily make a mistake I mean you
can you can just random random nice the
array order any way you want but however
it's not truly random so you know if you
do statistics you call your function or
million times you'll see there's always
buyers they are not truly random so
that's the thing that's why this
algorithm has a name feature yet shuffle
it's not a it's very simple algorithm
it's not it's kind of almost trivial so
it's not something you know deep at all
so anyway so what I want to show you
about these guys this page is there is a
spectacular there is a spectacular
application okay hold on second why is a
space key not working okay so here near
the bottom it starts to get interesting
so here he shows a visualization of
sorting I think it's related to sorting
sorting and partition something like
that sorting
so you can see you can visually see how
the algorithm works okay yeah so you see
we start with a random columns of colors
then you can see gradually near the
bottom the lighter color goes to the
left the darker color goes to the right
so and it's very beautiful you know you
look at the graph and this graph you see
this graph it's not trivial to do okay
it's not trivial to do so you know he
this guy he knows a lot about geometric
algorithm it's it's Cod computer
computational geometry this field
subject matter is called computational
geometry so in computational geometry
there are a lot of algorithms and those
are not trivial okay you know every we
have 30 years accumulated knowledge
about computational geometry I mean it's
a it's a it's a field you can study for
years and they are also dedicated
journals to computational geometry and
for game engines for example you kind of
have to know if you are going to do a
game engine like 3d game engine you have
to know these so anyways so this guy
wrote this article about and this this
one is spectacular I wanted to show you
this one
look he is generating amazed by the way
all these are done in JavaScript so
JavaScript you know I really want to
finish my package about partying curves
like visualization of math and stuff
this is what you know I'm very
interested so I want to get back to that
so good morning Matt and Matt you are in
Germany right good morning
bartholomew in germany quintic in russia
just in Canada and
z Tron crazy in Germany yeah okay so you
see this but there is more
this is even more spectacular okay here
is a another way to generate that this
puzzle this maze they call it this is
called maze okay now there's another
word in English called labyrinth
labyrinth actually has a specific
meaning labyrinth
labyrinth is actually just one path like
there is no Auton alternative choices
there's only one path it came from the
Greek mythology okay let's look it up
el ABY RI and T edge I think that's
correct
okay there's also a movie labyrinth
there it is Wikipedia so labyrinth has a
specific meaning the you know it is from
quick mythology basically I think
basically means it's like a maze but
there is only one path the there is only
one path okay now I remember
okay it looks like that the classic
labyrinth right so there is only one
path right so you go go go yeah minor
Toros in labyrinth yes and that is
spectacular
in very extremely interesting Greek
mythology let's let me you know many
mannitol
sorry a love of Greek mythology
okay let's see if I can find my page
okay meet methodological creatures in
second life that's very interesting
there and this story flower paradise is
also very interesting but we are going
to digress and digress so much anyway so
this is in this is in second life you
have these avatars so this this bird is
a harpy
okay and this is Medusa very the most
famous Medusa and you have mermaid
mermaid is not exactly from Greek
mythology it's kind of Northern Europe
you know Scandinavia I think mythology
so you have several beautiful mermaids
you know all these are in second life
okay I did a video on second life you
can you can check it out and then you
have this monster fish then you have
weird wolf then you have spiders okay so
so that is digression let's paste copy
the buffer delete that TV that I mean
articles enlarge the buffer what is is
showing browser
okay programming that I don't care about
that go back to excel talk show and
paste it here okay
showing in browser so so back to the now
we back to the okay I didn't find my I
didn't find my article because
[Music]
sorry arts so go to my arts article saw
arts okay then we have seashell gallery
no the these seashells I actually have I
collected back in 2002 around 2000 I
bought them you know in year 2000 I was
working in dot-com companies and so I
bought this seashell
they are extremely amazing actually I
showed I should show you some another
video I should take them out and show
you so these seashells are spectacular
you can see they they have different
shapes and different you know variations
and they are of course they are related
to math in several ways one is the
spiral you know the victory the various
ways to generate spiral actually I can
show you that mathematics of seashells
and so and so on so seashells you see
you have this flat top top shell this
this one is called tough shell it looks
like that and then you have this tusk
shell is it's kind of like the opposite
extreme you know so you can model them
in math let me just paste my url here
and let's go here let's I'm not going to
talk about that topic so this is this
this this this one is stunning
Mathematica you can see how seashell or
modeled basically you use this
parametric formula and you can plot them
okay so let me show it here you can
check it out check it out so we actually
we digress so much so you know I want to
use JavaScript and and and I want to get
back to my writing programs of doing
visualizations of math like this this is
written in Mathematica like 20 years ago
and you have the cutaway view of
seashells you can see it's quite amazing
seashells and there there is one you
know some of this you see these
seashells have this kind of variation
decorations they are just spectacular
look at this and look at this one it's
just amazing and look at this one with
the you know fluffs going out
so did I cut my hair yes you just spin
over and cut it I did you didn't notice
yesterday I could at few days ago must
be almost a week some yeah
monotone Manito actually I want to show
you that Minato we begin to digress so
much we were talking about JavaScript
let's go back to there we will go back
to there but let me remember what the
things I want to say so they the yard
I haven't finished showing you this
visualization this is another one I'm
going to show you okay but right now we
digressed into sods okay some arts block
here then you can see the Greek
mythology Europa and the bull this one
we talked about in one of my videos and
a love of the mythology of the Greeks
this girl she is Artemis is the greatest
pitch in history Artemis so anyway yeah
monitor so anyway right so you guys if
you are interested you can go read that
I mean just gonna post it here
what is this okay close it here so I
want to say Naruto you know monitor is a
queen you the the creature mannitol
what's wrong because they there's a
queen who made it with the white pool
okay so then they got these their
children that their child is monitor but
how do you get a you know feed a girl to
mate with the pool you have to trick the
white ball so so there's a story of that
this is a Greek mythology and yeah and
monitor is in the library labyrinth and
there's so many stories about that you
know that then there is a greatest Smith
ok greatest nerd the greatest nerd
in Greek mythology like us you know not
who are interested in mechanisms
computer science you know there is one
greatest God the god of nerds he's named
anyone remember the name if you know say
it ok oh and monitor and the labyrinth
okay these two guys this guy tell dad
Alice
okay data us and his son i carriers you
know he I think they were imprisoned in
the libraries at one time and and and
dad Alice he he's a great engineer okay
yeah he is a great nerd but I was
talking about another guy anyway the
tattered Daedalus he invented wings and
they just flew you know they that's how
they escaped but his son is too arrogant
you know he's too young
like like you know today's programming
hotshots you know like you know they
think they know what you you know they
think they know everything so he flew
too high near the to towards the Sun
against his dad's advice and he fell to
his death
so anyway there's another engineer
that's a god you know Smith I forgot the
name in a moment but anyway they should
have invented emails yeah
the morning marks marks in Russian maize
is okay missus that that would okay we
never go back to break to Greek myth
again now what do you mean Shamokin
Good Morning Joe Morgan speaking in
Russian I don't understand nothing okay
so let's go back to JavaScript now look
at this one okay so hold on a second we
already saw that wait did we miss
anything okay we already saw that this
one we already saw that this one looks
the same but now now here is the most
spectacular one okay not yet not this
one anyway so this one is about
pathfinding so you have algorithm to
solve the maze solve the maze and
typically this is done using back
backtracking algorithm now actually this
might be just a maze generation
algorithm
I might get confused anyway you know you
can read the article but then there is
there's one I want to show you okay so
all these are written in d3.js of course
that's his library he wrote it now this
one is not too interesting
okay and it's too slow and look at this
one randomized depth-first traversal on
the other hand is all about meander
okay so anyway randomized depth-first
traversal okay let's see the next one
yeah that this now this one is prims
algorithm on random graph okay not very
interesting okay here is another
approach not interesting wilson's
algorithm
now this one is spectacular this is the
one I want to show you look at this one
now this one is truly spectacular and
you know I'm truly impressed by this
this graph so I want to show you this
article mostly just for this one what
use are randomized binary trees not at
all but apparently they are pretty
that's cool I was just talking about
random binary trees versus so did binary
trees okay green deck says is yes those
these are drawings in real time of
course you can replay it you know it's a
in fact you can look at the source code
you can just right-click and look at the
source code let's see then you'll see
you know you're being comprehensible
it'll be a bunch of SVG I'm pretty sure
it's SVG oh it's using canvas
I hate canvas there it is here's the
code okay so you can see
I want to see the actual canvas do they
show that okay you should be able to see
the actual canvas code I think oh wait
oh wait yeah canvas is not SVG so yeah
there is no canvas code that you know
the Java Script generates the image
directly it's a bitmap canvas is speed
map so anyway I wanted to show you that
this page this all with this JavaScript
III that's what I want to show you okay
okay so link of ISO so another thing I
want to show you is that eMac eMac
speech mode okay for example let me show
you what what I mean okay so if I for
example let's go to aid my eMac Lisp
okay so let's go to a Emacs Lisp code
magnify so you see here is the Emacs
Lisp code so let me let me go through
some some place where there is a big
chunk of code you know okay so here so
normally it looks like this okay this is
why it normally looks like using mono
mono space font how they call that I
can't remember words how they call that
not not mono space
so let's go to my mano-a-mano space
yeah that's right they are calling it
mono space that's right so anyway here
is SVG this this is a CSS code so you
can show them in monospace font or you
can show them in a very variable pitch
phone you know you max stupid Emacs
jargon in the serif sans serif font okay
variable width font so let me show you
let me show you okay so I copy that I
make a new buffer new window and paste
paste the code here and I'm going to
magnify switch to saw Emacs lease mod
okay
magnify go to the top entries so let me
I want to show you them side by side
okay so search for
okay
so there you are so they are they are
now side by side you can see on the
right is what you normally see because
all code are displayed in monospace font
on the left is using Siri font you know
just a sans serif font variable with
font and the the thing interesting is
that actually very you should try to use
variable-pitch fund because actually you
show for example for example if you look
at this line on each line of the same
width variable pitch variable width font
will actually display more characters
and in fact it's more readable you know
you can decide yourself which one is
more readable like tell me what-what do
you think the left one is more readable
or the mono space fun so anyway how the
the command to do that is just called
it's called variable pitch Mart okay
sorry
Emacs variable pitch mod its built-in in
Emacs okay Emacs proportional font and
here is a screenshot of two examples
mono space versus proportional width
font and the command to code is this one
variable peach mod okay so for example
let me show you I just call variable
pitch mod coil again to turn it back and
you can see if you look at this line you
know in variable variable pitch mod it's
much smaller so you can actually read
more things so I recommend it I've been
using it for several years but then I
turn it off then I turn it back again of
course you don't want to use that in
Python in Python it's not suitable
because Python you know it
you need an indentation you need to see
the indentation but otherwise it's good
for in javascript in eMac beasts or any
other list code in CSS file in HTML in
you know almost other languages so
that's about that so close that close
that close that poof a modified do not
save close that window back to talk show
let's okay close that back to Emacs
close that close that switch to browser
close that refresh okay let's go to the
next topic
I like to read one more so you like the
mono space okay the reason I stopped it
is because I stopped using it because I
I forgot
every time I'm talking I cannot my brain
is like whacked I cannot remember any
words being already talking talking for
30 minutes okay anyway next next topic
show that d3 mace thing we did that show
the random click a random quick okay so
I want to show you if you go to my
website copy that okay see shout did we
put see shout here and just put it here
okay so you go to you go to NOx arts
close that okay yeah this this is the
math of seashell back to Emax paste it
here yeah okay so I want to go back to
sorry dot info so this is my website you
can go down go down go down go down site
map so near the bottom there is a site
map you click that and it shows all the
articles on saudi tour info so you can
see there are
this is a very long fire so let's go all
the way to the bottom so there are three
thousand seven hundred sixty seven files
on saudi dot info and you if you go to
my Emacs page let's go to Emacs so Emacs
proportional found ok let's copy that
there you go to my Emacs go to the home
page there's also a sitemap so on this
page there are several hundred sixty
articles so what's interesting is that
you can click the random nice you see
you click random nice they are random
nice the least and of course this is
written in JavaScript let me show you
the script let me show you so this is
the page this is a page locally and
magnify and such fourth rjs there is the
this is the file let's open it you see
it just just 10 10 lines 15 lines but
however to do this it takes you several
days first a year to understand
JavaScript in order to do this so so
anyways so that's about that so anyway
so this is this random nice is very
useful because close that back to Chrome
so I have Java JavaScript home you can
random nice then you can click because
that way you actually find interesting
articles you never seen before it's like
you know if you go through my website
you see you know you are kind of
familiar with the structure so you don't
actually see new articles but with
random nice feature you actually start
to see new articles and same thing with
the solid our info site you know 4000
Arcos random nice
and you see these JavaScript actually
you know that JavaScript I just showed
you only 15 lines it's not trivial is
I'm not kidding okay it's actually it's
not trivial to do you actually have to
know tom well because otherwise it will
be extremely slow you know you are
trying to random nice so that's why you
know remember we were talking about
Fischer JavaScript Dom random nice you
know that Fischer algorithm two random
nice array elements that that algorithm
is used here so I have a article that
that that is a tutorial of how this code
works close that close that close that
so let's paste that okay so I mean it's
not trivial because you have to you have
to the JavaScript needs to read this
list okay that part is easy then you
have to manipulate this this items they
are not they are not simply your ways
but anyway after you money you randomize
them you have to replace the original
list so you have to insert back so if
you do it naively you will be very slow
when you have like 3,000 items you will
be very slow I that's what I found
okay so that's about that that's about
my site map which what I want to tell
you about it's available for solid info
and also for Emacs and I'd you know next
time we do videos I can just use that
you know go to random nice so then we
have many interesting things we can talk
about so close that Emacs tab space
indentation cellar close that theater
list okay close
yeah so I was telling you about variable
proportional found so on my website
actually I switched them I switched my
website CSS to proportional font now so
you can see it wasn't like that before
actually I can show you how it's how it
is done
yeah let's just show you so go to go to
my Emacs blog showing browser then go to
Excel commands new buffer let's go -
lets go to somewhere that's more code
okay for example this one okay copy the
URL back to Emacs open the file magnify
so here's a file showing browser and
yeah I want to show you see so so what
we do is we open the CSS file magnify
and go to search for email is right here
so we are right here you see this
font-family:arial sans-serif that's why
now if we delete that line let's say we
delete that line then refresh browser
now watch watch the change okay
refresh the browser do it you see it
becomes like that okay yeah so that's
that's what I want to show CSS close
close close close copy okay we already
did that close sure okay so next topic
show Emacs variable-pitch mode we did
that raining hearts okay we can okay so
let's take a break and see the sorry
Vidya
see the comments so you gonna rewrite
your website soon react no I'm not going
to react
yeah I I'm not I don't think I don't
think so I'm not gonna write rewrite my
website react my website is basically
it's just a static website so some
essays I just saw he did some stuff on
Crozier - yeah I did one year of closure
room looks very interesting what run
Justin says what field of Emax do you
use our Mac okay so let's go to Emacs
blog showing browser go to practical
Emacs go to where to download then you
have windows you have Mac on the Mac I
use this one yeah let that one okay any
other questions or any topics so let's
go to the next topic
javascript raining hearts copy that
labyrinth closed at new buffer paste
enter
I don't think it's the same the one
brewing stores I don't think so
so anyway anyway so why am i showing
this this is just something I wrote I I
wrote this out of nostalgia
you know fact this is very popular back
in like year 2000 1999 where you have
any snow you know on websites and I
didn't know how that is done I didn't my
first touch of JavaScript is in 2006
also even back then I don't know nothing
about JavaScript you know
because javascript is very a fairly
complicated language so I didn't know
how this works but eventually I know in
actually I understand how this is done
you guys know how this is done this is
pure JavaScript okay okay let me explain
how this system does anyone know how
this is done like technically how is
this possible if you know say it ok but
let me tell you so this is done the
heart of this technology is actually CSS
okay it's not JavaScript so so how is
that how does that work so in CSS you
can create layers okay so you know
layout in layers just like almost like
Photoshop layers so you have one you
know image up you know before the other
one so the fun one will hide the back
one so you can click create almost
almost infinite layers and so you can
create layers then then these hearts are
each heart is actually just a layer you
know G's each heart is a HTML element in
its own layer so you actually have like
30 layers going around
then what do you use JavaScript for the
JavaScript is used to move you know to
position these elements you know it just
need just reposition them that's all and
and so this code is only like 50 50
lines and it's just yet so that's how
it's done you use CSS to create you know
each element on its own layer then you
use JavaScript to reposition them so you
have to refresh you know you see this
line the last line said in turbo run a
code F of F update positions and the
second argument is update speed now
update speed is is like you know just
seconds like every 0.9 second you update
you know what every time you update you
change the position of each each heart
you know element that that's all so this
is this is interesting because you know
on the surface you would not think is
you know so in a sense actually it's a
hack you know there is no foundation
there is no you know architectural
structure that that create these moving
things rather you just create layers you
know put each element on its own layer
and and use JavaScript to move them like
every second you update the position so
it's kind of like a hack okay so that's
about that
cuz that
Cosette okay then there's some other
interesting things about on Twitter um
on YouTube okay so let's go back to a
guy wrote a chat program in CSS really
do you have a link a chat program it
must have some JavaScript right it must
because you cannot I don't think you can
actually have interactive chat in CSS of
course then I mean you also need to talk
to servers right definitely
definitely you need JavaScript but once
you have JavaScript what does it mean a
chat program in CSS I will I would say
majority of the code would be in
JavaScript so we are bugged morning if
the moving hearts was never in was never
an intended modern feature how would it
be implemented in JavaScript could you
have one layer for the heart's rather
than 30 no you cannot let's see so is it
possible to create that raining hearts
such that you are not using the CSS
layers oh yeah you can yeah yes you can
you can actually you can do that easy oh
yeah I never thought of that though you
can do it easy okay all you do is so
let's go to JavaScript all you do is all
you do is using canvas or SVG yeah you
so you use you use JavaScript to you
know to create SVG SVG is for drawing
you know so this is actually the proper
way to do it you use JavaScript to
create canvas or SVG then you can you
know you just draw draw things yeah
so Justin says it was written by sneaky
guy like to get message he retrieved an
image like to get message she retrieve
an image what does that mean I'm not
sure
why is Google sensing that geez okay so
that's about that so let's see what's
the next topic
d3 visualization across the science we
talk about that myth mythological
creatures in Second Life we talked about
that seashell gallery method of seashell
okay then some random things Canisius
laptop oh that's yeah I wanted so this
one so apparently some cartoon featured
this image I guess some Japanese anime I
don't know which one what's the name but
anyway I run into this so that's
interesting you know and also
interesting is that actually there is
someone a Japanese who created this
layout I'm gonna show you here okay so
he created a economic layout for laptop
so in this picture you can see this is a
normal laptop keyboard layout however
you can rearrange the keys into this
form this into this layout and in fact
you save space you see all the keys you
see use you have lots of empty space you
know no keys is missing you have all the
keys but however in the new arrangement
it's much more ergonomic you see and
it's also symmetric but but you actually
saved you know 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 like 7th
space because why because of the
spacebar the spacebar is taking 7 space
by itself so so this guy it's on github
you know so he created this you know he
he hope that this will catch on and you
know so it becomes a standard keyboard
layout it's actually a good idea you
know
so okay so that's about that let's go
back and paste the link here so what's
the next topic so such this line we
already okay
delete that see next topic I'm too old
to change cue layout
background images background images
loaded via pseudo selectors first
forever loading index page okay yeah
okay so let's see let's see what's the
next topic 53 minutes maybe we talk 10
more minutes so questions comments oh
you know any other topic just posted
okay so let's see now I'm like I'm
pretty much done with my topics the
other things are kind of random ish
computer languages what is is oh oh yeah
so someone on someone on my youtube
channel asked me a question
he says you know he he watched my video
but he's usually not you know not live
when I'm like so he asked the question
about new list so new new list is
actually it is a lisp dialect and it's
pretty old it's like 15 years old or
maybe 20 years old and he found it very
interesting he's having fun with it
YouTube YouTube sorry okay good morning
his stress Hanks are glad I caught your
live stream may ask you what you work
for work as I don't work for anyone I'm
not working I don't have money that's
why I'm very I'm I'm poverty below
poverty yeah but my profession if you
can call that I'm a programmer you know
so if you go through my channel
community various channel go to YouTube
beta
and go to go to comments okay go to
comments comments
so he asked me a question
we
search for new lisp lisp
okay so wait you need to click finish
that
oh yeah so Steve edge Steve edge ask me
the question about newly's so let's go
to new lease okay I talked to the guy
back in 2000 the inventor of this
language so I think he's a very
interesting guy
lot smaller I think he lives in South
America something like that you know
very is an interesting guy so he created
new lists in 1991 oh wow so it's it's
almost 30 years ago now so new list is
kind of like a scripting it's a light
language is a scripting language and
it's Lisp so you know you might check it
out it's fun I haven't I haven't
actually tried it so anyway that's
that's about that I don't know much
about it yeah YouTube interface is
horrible okay I agree a mobile it's even
worse yeah you okay so anyway let's go
back to business this just random chat
so yeah let me get a drink let me get my
drink
yeah I want to chat about random things
now sleeping schedule my sleeping
schedule that's an interesting topic
netiquette anthropology that's
interesting topic Kinesis laptop lambda
logo - oh that's interesting topic this
is the inscription of God H in stone
thou shalt not and etc this book is
written by granham news yes that's
donald growth and pastor ching ching
now granham is a mathematician granham
is also pretty old
he's like 70 or 80s you know so but I I
kind of I tried to read this book back
in 1990s like 1994 so I didn't like it
at all turns out I didn't like it so
anyway this page is a correction of Lisp
language logos that involves a lambda
that's a key it has to have a lambda
lambda otherwise you know I mean I focus
on logos that features the lambda not
necessarily Lisp so I love it so much I
love math you know math symbols
symbology because to me why I see math
formulas for example you know a bunch of
math formulas let me show you okay so
let me show you some of the least math
America so let's go through language
tutorials let's go to math America
and this is mathematical ogle hyperbolic
Nautica heatran and this is Mathematica
notepad this is linear algebra this is
my notes back in 1990 1993 I wrote them
original originally in Microsoft Word
then later on I converted to Mathematica
so this is linear algebra and then here
is mathematical code you can display you
see you can display them in math
notation like that I talked about this
many times you know various different
notations a notation system yesterday or
you know this week I talked about syntax
and things like that
and here's Mathematica you know
interactive animation in you know
graphics and code I wrote this package
doing that this is in 1990s so I'm going
to try to write them in in JavaScript to
update my plane curves website all these
packages I wrote anyway implementing
Mathematica in : oh yeah so there is
this project by this guy coworker I
think he work for Wolfram so he is
trying to
I might be wrong who he is I don't know
who he is anyway so he's saying he's
trying to implement Mathematica or a
similar kind of system in : that would
be very interesting so Jupiter you know
it's very popular today Jim Jupiter
basically copied the Mathematica
interface this this interface you are
seeing
it's called notebook interface you see
this is notebook this is you know bad
Mathematica is back in 1989 even so you
know Julia just copied it so question
Matt says so what's your plan on react
so do you plan to make a tutorial for
your website yes I plan to but but you
know I wouldn't don't expect it to be
very good because I actually already
have one it just just might random notes
I yeah so I don't think I plan to write
a public you know nice tutorial because
that will take you know that will take
like almost like one month full-time I
already you know I already studied we
ArcGIS
about half a year ago I studied for one
week and I find it very good ok this is
one of the library actually understand
you know I get idea you know and I think
it's is great so I only studied for one
week and I stopped you know I haven't
used it but I want to get back to I want
to kind of I want to try to know it well
yeah we actually is because that's
because I'm kind of old school almost
out of touch with today's modern you
know NPM and all that kind of thing
whenever I try to use them I get
frustrated and
you know the so anyway but I'm trying
now I'm trying to maybe no react well
and maybe write some apps in it possibly
and I'm also looking into electron so
that I get to know you know the kind of
them how they do things in JavaScript
you know supposed to my ways you know my
old-school
fundamental way so what do you think
green deck says what do you think about
geo cities and and neo cities modern to
your cities analog in general do you
think individual homepage are better
than social media yeah definitely
absolutely you should have your own page
it's absolutely better than social media
and if you can you know just create your
own domain I mean you know bio domain
that you know that will cost you like
$10 a month and you will pay like and
and get a hosting like $3 a month you
know you can create your own website so
geo series is the old it's one of the
earliest websites that lets people to
have a home page now geo cities is
before blog you know before Google
blogger in other blogs before the
blogging platform so before that you
have geo cities which you can go there
which Esther account and you have your
home page and you can put whatever there
so I think so I'm not sure what happened
with geo cities you know they they went
out long ago and and then you have neo
cities but I am not too familiar with
the history of Geocities so Yahoo geo
cities Yahoo geo series was was a web
hosting service it was founded in
November 1994 by David Barnett and John
rains is now and was called Beverly
Hills Internet
for a very short time before name
Geocities so he was from Yahoo Oh Yahoo
bought it on January 1999 oh yeah
so Yahoo bought it on January 1999
Geocities was acquired by Yahoo at which
time it was alleged allegedly the third
most visited web site on world wide web
yeah so geo cities there it is the
history of the internet you know that's
that's way back then you know you can so
are they still alive like can you still
I guess no they only have Geocities
Japan though okay yeah but I was but you
probably can find some geo city websites
on wayback machine you know in the
Internet Archive then you will see how
the web looks like back then you know
it's like very different style from
today so anyway so what do I think of it
I don't know so that's that's so I know
neo cities I haven't used it I heard of
a feud I heard of it a few times so was
it too popular in Russia or something
like neo cities is it created by your
Russian or something
so justin hays says I've been thinking
of getting rid my home page yeah
you mean a domain you have got your own
domain you know home page it's kind of
for most people you know for vast
majority of people including programmers
you I mean most most people and even
most of you you know you don't really
have much to say like you know so if you
can you know you might create a home
page a domain it's cool right
but it's cool for like one year after
that it's just sitting there not the you
know it's just in there forever
basically that's that's that's what
happens to vast majority of people
because you don't you know you don't
have things to write you know they're
much and also if you are thinking of
creating your own blog you know like me
you know blogging every day for the road
for 30 years that's tremendous work you
know you have to realize you're gonna
spend like an hour at least minimum on
average statistical average like an hour
a day you know every day every year
years after you you have to do that and
you have to you know writing blog is not
that easy you spend several hours to
write one blog so it's not easy okay and
usually especially today there's no
readers maybe you have ten videos your
friends your mom it's something like
that okay so it's not easy to do and
also for vast majority majority of
people you don't have you you don't need
to you know say something that you don't
even need to blog you know you go to a
social network you know so unless you
are writer or unless you are someone
like you know like me he wants to talk
about things also things then yeah you
if you are the writer type of guy that's
good for you and also for most most
people you have to go to work right you
work eight hours a day you get tired
you're gonna you know spend time with
your family or something like that
you know you don't want to write blogs
so so yeah so it may not be for you give
your opinion on Jupiter my opinion is
that they just copied Mathematica
notebook
they said it on their website but
otherwise and notebook is a great
interface okay I had this complaint long
time ago I flame with this
programmer idiots okay you see now after
30 years 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13
this is 14 15 16 17 18 19 up to 30 after
30 years this programming idiot this
mainstream Python Perl openness that
will including these
now they start to Oh notebook
notebook you know think Jupiter copied
notebook this idiots wait where are they
30 years ago like it especially for my
experience talking to the these idiots
the comment is phonetics every time I
talk about about Mathematica they know
nothing about it but they did they don't
get the idea they don't not nothing
about it they instead they just say oh
you are a troll you don't know nothing
you don't know this
you don't know this way at all okay
sighs the guy with the most idiotic
opinions you know that's what they say
but now now the society the the
programming programming population now
the AI you know the population now in
general oh they realize Oh Jupiter you
should use Jupiter this is you know
great interactive notebook what a
idiots you know and you see let
me tell you the history the revolution
evolution okay kind of the history of
programming language interface okay let
me tell you that so the in the beginning
you have well this is not an accurate
history but basically you owe free yoga
let's say in a beginning you have
command-line interface
yeah okay the eunuchs idiot sure okay so
open open a new show so you have let's
see d let's see D let's move this over
here so so here's the charlotte's can we
magnify let's not let's just can we view
okay
magnify okay bigger yeah that's not too
big let's try okay so CD this is Shou
okay so this is shell sorry Todd
sorry info for example okay there you go
there you go so we can do LS LS - al
this like that Oh al and you can go to
Saudi for example casado
like you do LS then you have this this
this this she'll is Unix
Unix civics are true okay
for example then you do LS so you can
you clean so let's let's launch VI VI
let's see which file actually we go to
we need to go to test to zero that okay
then this then VI VI X t20 tap-tap-tap
stupid
okay so XT tab yes okay there it is we
are in the land of VI now what is page
down let's see ctrl F yeah ctrl F now we
need syntax colouring okay now so syntax
coloring is coma sy n I think child
moves no syntax items defined for this
lavage
you yeah okay quit : q yes now we
need to open the JavaScript one instead
of typescript okay open it now : is why
in Jesus no syntax for JavaScript what
age are we living in so VI uses there is
no default syntax screen for JavaScript
okay wait wait we don't don't don't got
don't don't put the what there
okay don't put word in the comments
okay that barrier barrier you are new
here you should watch few few of my old
you know videos like just search for you
know go to youtube search for go to my
channel go to my channel first sorry
channel on YouTube then in a box search
for UNIX philosophy okay I explained
that a million times
you know what do you use Mac wait what
do you still use Mac you know Maggie is
Unix
you know I explained that too many times
okay so you know that you you here the
entire hour
you know attacking on that notion okay
what is Unix oh yeah Maggie's you UNIX
Apple is Unix
even Apple suppose UNIX okay so you
might check it check that so entry okay
so how long we been talking so we should
end okay we ending in two or three
minutes let me ask you me see so oh yeah
so the I was going to give you a history
of interface human-computer language
interface computer language instant
interface okay now so in the beginning
you have a shell okay you have I mean
you have the command-line interface then
then the then the next step up is
interactive you know it's still
command-line interface like Python okay
let's say I tagged Python and there we
are so three first four there it is
Python so let's say x equals two
okay Python so three four five okay this
is a list in Python array in Python okay
then type X you know so then then let's
say X the the first element okay you got
three okay so that's Python now this
this now people code is the idiots the
programming idiots in the industry they
started to call this I cannot remember
any words when I'm talking to people I
my brain is like at 50 percent rip oh
yeah they call it rip oh yeah I talked
about this thing in one my video so
should I show it yeah
again it sure let's show the article so
you go to you go to jargons okay repo
okay here's a repo the idiots code n
repo this this the the term repo or EPO
became popular around around like 2009
for for about five years I don't hear it
much today but it's a you know people
start to call it repo because Python
started to have repo Ruby Oh like all
languages started to have repo now so
but but repo is basically is the same
exactly the same as the interactive
command-line interface okay it's just it
just like bash okay just like bash now
the next level up of computer language
interface is what you would call
you might just call it notebook liking
Emacs okay for example I can open any
buffer and in any new buffer or any
exist existing buffer okay for for
three-plus and I can evaluate this code
evaluate let's open another buffer hold
on a second let's open another buffer
here and let's show the oops let's show
the message buffer okay so here you can
see all the output okay so I can
evaluate that you can see we get seven
and you can have for example set Q okay
let's switch to saw it is mod magnifier
magnify set Q okay set x equals to 99
okay then we can say plus x1 okay
evaluate that a debugging oh we didn't
we don't we have to evaluate this line
first okay do it now I can evaluate this
one okay do it so the answer is 100 you
can see here 100 you see so this way
let's call this interface the notebook
interface this interface is much better
than the shell okay the wrapper
why because in this interface you can
evaluate any expression anywhere you
want you don't have to keep the order
okay you can for example we just did we
try we can evaluate this part again or
we can evaluate this part again or we
can you know now we don't want that we
can change it to a TA and evaluate that
part again oh then we could make a copy
let's change it to to evaluate that so
you can evaluate anywhere you want and
also
another advantage is that you can save
it every computation is saved you know
you can just for example now I'm gonna
save these files so xx today's state dot
yeah now it's saved close reopen you
know and magnify you can open you know
you can you have it saved always like
shell you have to ensure you know if you
want to save you have to like start you
know as you know let's go to the Linux
tutorial you have to shell let's see
there is a way to save shall pass
terminal okay so T max man page reset
terminal terminal control sequence keys
virtual console is this UNIX fax bash
prompt key terminal and lock lock
terminal session okay this is how you do
it you can there's a genome there is a
anyway did you have techniques to long
term no sessions then okay so I'm
telling you that this notebook interface
is better you can save it you don't lose
things you can experiment you can
evaluate any expression anytime okay so
this is better now of course in Emacs
and this can be turning in any buffer
not necessary a new buffer for example
in my talk show page this is HTML I can
just paste the Emacs Lisp code right
here and let's evaluated okay let's
evaluate it okay let's let's say 1000
okay
vennett you see the answer is 1000 for
right here you see
so the code can be anywhere so this is
this is what I would call notebook
interface but however in Emacs its text
only and also today you know in oak mod
you know these industrial idiots you
know people start to like oak mod you
know they say oh how it is great how it
is you have you can evaluate code how
you can duplicate scientific data how
they call that day of
okay they have a word for that oak mati
so let's go to practical Emacs let's go
down go down go down go down go down oak
mutt topic okay so you have source code
markup yeah so Scott mark markup then
you can evaluate you know any language
code in oak mod you can you know it can
be Python code can be this can be even
Java or Ruby pipe you know and call that
many languages you can evaluate it by
the way you did
so this oak Oak modding odd you know in
a way it's another notebook interface
okay you can evaluate code anywhere you
know it needs not to be sequential like
in shell but if you want it to be C
sequential you can you know you do is
every time you just go down and and and
make a new code you know and go down you
know if you want it to be sequential and
you can also search you know you can
search the entire buffer using Emacs
such facilities you know you can list
matching lines and things like that so
notebook is far more powerful than the
interactive shell okay
now however in oak mahogany max you
don't have it's not graphical mean you
cannot have images for example you
cannot well you you could you know but
in Emacs is hard to do you have to spend
out one hour to figure out how can you
display images I mean even if you do
that you you cannot have sound you
cannot have embedded you know sound or
embedded video you cannot so because
it's not actually a graphical interface
but in Mathematica you can that you can
do that okay back in 1989 okay this
Industrial Common Lisp a scow
tie-down Pro fax idiots in Mathematica
you can do this in pack in 1989 you know
this and of course today so back to let
me show you the Mathematica yeah you
know you see this so I wrote this this
notebook this
this-this-this I wrote a package a
mathematical package to plot planing
plain tidings and symmetry you know like
the pictures here like you know I have a
I showed this before in my previous talk
for example what is this not not this
there yeah they're here so you see all
these images are generated by
Mathematica for example you see these
three you see this these three images
you see it says output 277 these three
images all you have to do is just type
this line of code one line of code it
gives you that this is this is
Mathematica and this is 1997 okay the
fact the industrial c c++
Haskell Python the industry or coder
idiots
so I everybody see in 1997 but but this
is available back then you see the code
you not not remember you see this
two-dimensional notation those are
automatic not like tech take these
another the most worst idiotic
technology download gross tech free as
in free beer that's why it's popular in
any it refused to die okay so this you
see this this notation it's automatic
okay it's not like you have to type
special command to format it you type
the whole thing if you wanted to be
two-dimensional math notation you just
press one button it shows like that this
begins now this feature of
two-dimensional notation
it began in 1999 okay around 1999 when
Mathematica version three came up so
anyway so so I wrote this package that
does that so so back to the here so you
are looking at what you are looking at
is the this is called a notebook
interface the notebook you see you just
type it is you know just like Emacs
except it's far more rich than Emacs
because you can have code you can have
you can have headers you can have you
know section titles you know chapter
title you can collapse them you can
expand them collapse basically that's
like oak mod you know you just show the
titles and you can have you know images
and you can have anime
you know a video that's this you know
that's Mathematica okay so so yeah so
I'm talking about so I'm talking about
the in the computer language interface
you know the the several interfaces in
the beginning you have command line then
you have kind of notebook and also
graphical notebook now by the way this
this kind of notebook interface they are
there are some variations and they are
popular in math community since like
1991 okay when I started to you know as
I study math you know back in 1992 I
have this kind of interface for example
in MATLAB MATLAB uses the similar
interface almost all math software they
have this they use this interface okay
so now today people started to get it I
mean the bootcamp becomes you know
Amanda industrial programmers so that
guys as you know in the industrial
programmers they started to not a lot of
people are aware of this you know
because because of the the Julia you
know they they copied I mean they said
it on a website we copy it we copy the
user interface for Mathematica but if
you I mean they do that today it's kind
of okay but if you do that in 1990s I
don't think you would be ok you get sued
I don't know if did they talk to
Mathematica or not I don't know but
anyway they they just they they they
basically like they they copied almost
exactly the Mathematica notebook with
the cell you see these things on a on
the right side those are called cells
you know each one of these is called a
cell
they almost copied you know as far as
you know I have I haven't actually never
used Julia but but I looked at it you
know for a minute or two you know I
think they copied almost exactly
everything
so you know so what's my point you see
my point like my typical videos and my
philosophy is that most people in
industrial I mean industrial programmers
they know they know so little you know
but that's okay okay but the thing is
you know this typically you have these
hacker types UNIX philosophy people ok
UNIX philosophy or Python
you know Python priests they tell you
what you should do they all like they
tell you what you should do when if you
don't follow then they say you are a
troll or you are idiot ok they tell you
you need to follow their idioms like for
example in this they say oh you need to
for example let me show you some ok not
this page let's go doc sorry
let's go through my Sardi so you can see
a lot of code here ok so for example my
list code you know they tell you let's
go up ok for example if you do not for
example let me show you this ok if you
have parentheses if you show a code in
public with parentheses parentheses
light like that without you know proper
properly formatted you get you get
flamed to death this you know least
furred idiots ok that's another topic
yeah I can talk about this topic
formatting issues for one hour so let's
let's do that next time but that the
basic bottom line is that you should
programmer programmers should not format
each line line by line
that's what plumbers are doing every day
till even today they are they are they
tell you to press you know for example
if I switch to Emacs this mod ok the D
for you Italy smart you press you press
tab here to format one single eye then
you first have here then first time here
and then you have that idiotic edit
mod parted mod that blame falls this
idea that basically they tells you to
format each one manually you have to do
it manually for every line if if this
line for example
is not formatted then you press tab then
that line becomes fact you know it pay
it's based on the formatting is based on
previous line so you know since you have
to do them one by one manually you know
that's the way people are thinking these
industrial people you know but but
that's fine but the thing about them is
that they tell you they think they know
everything about the universe like they
know the entire universe universe and if
you don't do their way they say you are
a troll you are idiot you don't not
understand nothing
I got flames about this for like ten
years
you know people post my comments on my
my Emacs blog
oh this saga oh I'll read it for example
hacker news oh this guy is a idiot
he you know look at his parentheses you
know he did he doesn't follow the
convention because he know nothing know
because you are idiot you don't know
nothing then I wrote it works out Emacs
ly smart okay let's switch to it so
let's go to I press a key now it's at
least smart okay now if I look at this
lines okay this hanging per hand in
parentheses okay I press tab I press tab
key one shot look at look at the screen
look at what happens okay one tab the
whole block gets formatted no no manual
line by line factory Magnus people
okay them so that's a situation
about you know so that's so my point
about all this talk about the user
interface about the Mathematica notebook
you know it's just you can you can see
you know if I don't know if I'm
convincing to you
I'm persuasive enough you can see that
the mostly they don't know things most
people the average the suppose the the
wisdoms of the crowd okay this is you
know it's actually just by these few
people they think they know they tell
you what to do and there are several
people like that in emacs community you
know I don't want to mention names
they've right you know they've written
many very popular packages they are like
that okay
and so then you know so that's what I'm
saying and the thing is you know you
have a coat so everyone you know it's
like is it same thing in Python in Perl
you know you have a coat okay so you
know hope to keep in the same time
society so okay so what how long were
you been talking so okay so let's read
the comments two more minutes okay you
know so I was I'm always worried about
you know maybe I'm too long or something
nice and then sometimes I think of
it so what does it matter you know I
wonder why not only they do things like
Jupiter you know that's because time
because the you see the ideas the
thinking shifts you know over every 10
years every decade kind of do you have
new generation so in the situation in
society changes you know today you know
for example in the past 10 years most
you know the the hot things are about AI
about neuro networks you know data
science you know so you started to have
a lot kind of mathematicians you know or
programmers started to you know suddenly
the idea about math especially
statistics becomes you know they start
to have an interest in that you know
because you need that for data mining
for this neural network kind of thing
because studies statistics you know the
math subject statistics is a major part
in in in the AI approach that you know
neural networks or you know data mining
kind of thing so in Google in
facebooking all these big companies you
start to have a lot of people working on
that and when you working in statistics
that's math then you you suddenly have a
lot of people from the math you know
community not the traditional
programming programmer community you
suddenly you have inflow
of the math community people and what
does math community people know like me
Mathematica that's what we know this
this interface is what we are used to so
I'm guessing so it's kind of gradual so
so then you know program I started to
see oh you know this you know then this
idea gets spread then someone
implemented then JavaScript you know
because it's on the scene they
implemented Jupiter you know Jupiter I
think it came yeah you came from the AI
background you know you know it's food I
think I'm pretty sure that's true the
Jupiter you know the engine is kind of
from the you know data mining kind of
backgrounds so okay so let's just read
the comments and I'll be it for today
let me quickly see if we can see if I
can answer all the comments so we can
get a drink oh so I have an old version
of him so we had that that is that is
important I need to find out oh I'm all
Americus why that's why I remember I did
set up my Linux so wim version I think
wondering what the is this
UNIX this is this is UNIX V me
improved version 8 2016 2016 is not too
old anyway
why not no index the chat hung Saudis
website what do you mean why not no
index no index you mean you mean prevent
Google from searching it this is not a
emoticon during sales analysis you know
try to learn Emacs Sunday it's not what
I don't like it
ok I'm just going to answer questions
address to me sorry some old version so
the chat should be no index on Saudis
website the part should be no index on
Saudis website is the chat thing what
are you talking about interesting joke
sorry I'm going to try to make the
hearts in browser with pure J's cool
yeah let us know if you have you know
you know paste a link next time show us
yeah you be nice you be nice to see know
so you can actually so the modern way is
actually to create them with yeah canvas
or SVG have you tried Emacs evil mod no
I don't need to because I'm using
sapphire keys which is which is more
efficient than Evo mod just locking I
found city to run seriously about that
so I sat higher ranting his self this
had rap along ago yeah well I talked
about that subject Beast you know the
Ripper term came from least you know
because starting around 2000 I the
industry program has started to you know
a function of a meme started to became
popular and they got the term Ripper
from from the the book SiC structure and
interpretation of computer programs I'm
they got that they got that term from
that from scheme basically so Aintree
gonna one says i coded the FFT analyzer
thing
glitch platform note that the frequency
scale is agreed Andrey you are the guy
who talked about he keeps talking about
that library right I don't know what
good what you are saying I mean so
what's your goal what's yoga so Derek
says I have not given you honest try
hundreds a smoker's no Index the YouTube
livestream thing on Saudis website fees
what
what no index okay
stress what's the more efficient thing
then Evo marks off like keys you don't
know yeah you haven't watched my video
stuff like it's okay this package you
can go to the URL
okay so home page this is a home page
you know check check it out I strain
there
okay thank you guys for watching I hope
to see you again if you like my stuff
paypal donate patreon okay I have like
links you know on my website at the
bottom PayPal or by my by my tutorials
programming tutorials how to live stream
on your own YouTube like you are doing
Google yeah yeah Google OBS yeah that's
what I use this program so well that's
it for today thank you guys bye