hello
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sun talk show today I'm going
to talk about geometric inversion
geometric inversion that is what it is
let me show you some pretty Graphics
okay
uh open that
and
let's see open that
geometric inversion open that
and uh
open that
open that okay so geometry let me show
you okay so geometric inversion we're
gonna talk about that and the
stereographic projection which is a
video we did last uh a week ago so this
is the stereographic projection and we
are going to derive their formulas so
what is the formula for stereographic
projection and what is the formula for
so this is stereographic projection and
what is the formula for geometric
inversion so this is what you are
looking at you see the grid becomes that
you know this a bunch of rectangles uh
squares becomes that
and becomes that you know depending on
whether the center of the rig square is
in the middle or not
so this is also this is also a geometric
inversion two-dimensional case and this
is also two-dimensional case but we made
it into a three-dimensional tiles we
added a thickness so it becomes
beautiful like that you can be done can
be used for garden decoration so you if
you have a house you have a garden you
want tiles you can do this but then you
know we did a video talk of this one
live coding so
you see the squares in the middle
becomes smaller infinitely smaller so
you don't want that when you want Tire
tiles in your garden so you do some
geometric transformation you apply your
function to the 2D plane so they so you
get rid of the tiny infinitely small
squares so you get that and you can do
again you can make it a tie or three
tests so this is beautiful okay we did a
video of these and then then you have 3D
this is a three-dimensional uh uh
geometric inversion
you know you have a bunch of Cubes
evenly spaced in a space you know then
you do a inversion then you become that
okay you can rotate it so here's the
code yeah let's let's run some code okay
so let's see if we can do that let's run
some let's start with language so we're
gonna explain geometric inversion
stereographic projection yeah then we're
gonna I'm gonna show you what is the
relationship between
uh actually there's more fantastic
beautiful geometric inversion so this is
a nested inversion of bunch of circles
so you begin with these seven circles
arranging in a hexagonal way then you
invert each circle with respect to each
one of them then you do it again then
you do it again I believe three times
four times then you get this spectacular
Graphics so all these are geometric
inversion okay
so in this one and this one and this can
be used
for a gate you know Iron Gate you have
if you have a house you have gates in
front right you know usually reach
people's house have a gate in front and
they have like Curly cures decoration so
you can use that as a pattern uh you
know Iron route curly cues you know for
the gate decoration or or floors you
know and so all these are geometric
inversion you start with a pattern on
the left a grid it becomes that and you
if you start with the a bunch of
parallel lines in arranging a pentagon
away symmetry rotational pentagonal
symmetry five-fold rotation then you get
this figure
on the right so but if you have a
hexagonal kind of a star grid then you
get this picture and you if you have a
colored squares like that
then you get this picture on the right
so all these are geometric inversion
very fantastically fantastic okay so
this is 3D 2D case and like we explained
we can do it 3D case
okay so all these are geometric
inversion and here's a definition I'm
going to go over and also this spider
web kind of thing beautiful fantastic
that's also geometric conversion
uh and then we're gonna explain how it
relates to a stereographic projection
they are related mathematics and also we
are going to derive each of their
formulas okay then we are going to code
Wolfram language we we're gonna code a
spectacular Graphics I hope so I hope
this video is going to be one hour
and I hope I have a good enough time to
do that if you have comments questions
post it okay
uh
uh the streams am I doing okay the
stream speed current bit rate is lower
than the recommended bit rate
okay so it looks like it's okay now so
geometric immersion so let's do it
so first of all I want to yeah let's see
what we want to do so today's talk show
is here I'm using emacs and stuff like
keys so here's a source code HTML page
and here's what we're going to talk
about so we showed a bunch of graphics
uh and I'm gonna show you the definition
okay let's start with definition okay
geometric inversion
so
um very easy okay so you can just go to
my website uh it let me show you where
which page that is
yeah so so this page so this page you
just search for Saudi
uh
a visual dictionary of spatial plan
curves I did this like 20 years ago and
then you just go to inversion
geometric inversion then you'll see so
here's the definition okay you start by
uh let me see if uh what I
let me show you this okay yeah so let's
use G algebra Okay g algebra is a kind
of free application on the web you can
use to build this to draw this Dynamic
Graphics so
so inversion okay geometric inversion is
a transformation
of the plane let's stick with the 2D
case so you have a plane you are given a
circle okay of radius R okay and it's a
transformation meaning at any point give
a point on the plane
You're Gonna Change the position of the
point to somewhere else okay for every
point so there's a function so for each
point the function takes one point you
know two numbers coordinate X and Y and
it returns another two numbers another
point you know X and Y so given any
point it returns another point this is
called a transformation or
you know in Geometry you call this
transformation or you can just call it a
function okay so given a point it
returns it it moves the point somewhere
else so how does that work you know in
order so you give them a circle usually
a circle of radius one so here is a
point p and uh
and it Returns the point Q okay Q is the
return value okay so how does it work is
that you draw a line from the center of
the circle to the point to the given
point so this line and this line will
pass you know it will intersect the
circle
then you take the distance from the
center of the circle let's call that o
for engine okay center of the circle to
the point P that the distance
and the new point is the point on the
line on this op line such that
the distance op
times the distance to the oq is equals
to the radius squared okay so do you see
what I mean so let's let let me let me
um let me draw that okay so hold on a
second let me sure that so let's start
to make
okay so let's draw this
see if we can do that
so given uh let's see
yeah
okay I cannot
it's you need to go here yeah so okay so
now oh wait
that that
uh Snape and sketch Okay so
so given the distance oh and
okay op the distance op times the
distance oq
is equals to r squared I is the radius
of the circle so if you want to know the
if you want to know that this so you can
manipulate this formula so all Q
equals to r squared divided by op okay
that's a line so the distance Okay so
so the distance o2q is equals to the
radius divided by o2p so let me go back
to the G algebra to show you
how how these transformation works
so you can see as the P moves further
away Q becomes
the the point Q gets closer to the
circle
if the p is near
the circum you know is on the circle
then Q is also on the circle if p goes
inside the circle then Q goes outside
you see so this transformation basically
swaps All Points outside of the circle
into inside and every any point inside
the circle becomes when go to go to
outside so you can see there is some
kind of symmetry of the p and Q point
you see the further away is p the the
closer is Q to the center the closer is
you know op then the further is all Q
so that's uh so this is kind of like a
mirror so you know like if you have a
mirror
you know the right side becomes the left
side the left side goes to the right
side you know if you have a l it becomes
L like that on the other side so in in a
similar way but the the line of the
mirroring is not a straight line it's a
circle so anything outside gets
reflected you you know you can kind of
say it gets reflected to the inside and
inside swapped to the outside so it's
fascinating so this is a geometric this
is a definition of a geometric immersion
okay
and uh okay so let's
so that's the definition so let's let's
um
and with this definition there are
certain very interesting properties so
remember we begin with a point and we
get a new point
and and and then we can we can prove
that
align if you are given a line in the
plane and you do the geometric inversion
for every point of the line
with respect to a given Circle then you
know of course if the line lies outside
of the circle then the new points will
all be inside of the circle and they
will become a circle so a line becomes a
circle this is one of the property
you know you can prove it and a circle
will also become a circle so let me show
you okay so let me see
so here is the inversion of a lines you
see these vertical lines they become
these red circles and if you have
circles like that the blue circles you
know horizontal with respect to these
yellow circle this inversion Circle then
they become the red circles like that
Circle will become circles
and lines will become circles too
so in fact you can consider
a line is just a special case of a
circle you know when the circle gets
infinitely large it becomes a line you
can think of it that way just as you
think of the reflection you know
reflection is a line where the left side
gets becomes the right side you know
like the symmetry of a human
um but with inversion it's like
reflection but everything gets inverted
inside and outside so you can think of
this circle when the circle becomes
larger and larger and larger they you
know the circumference becomes flatter
and flatter and if you take the limit to
Infinity it becomes a line it becomes
the normal reflection so you can think
of it that way
okay so so let's let me show you some of
the so here's the animation so you can
uh see how it works the inversion of a
circle becomes another Circle so let's
let's do it uh let's do it a line first
so here is the line the blue line and
the red is the image of the of the line
so you see
given any line you can move the line
anywhere so with respect to inversion to
this circle let's move these
to the center okay so with with respect
to this yellow circle I don't know if
you can see that the yellow circle is
the inversion Circle so this blue line
becomes this red circle so if we move
the line watch watch where it touches
the circumference
so you see a line becomes a circle and
when the line crosses our engine it
becomes a line again so you see so here
you can kind of see the how lines become
circles you know you can you can
consider that
a line is just a degenerate Circle a
line is a special case of a circle when
the radius becomes infinitely large you
see
now you have a small circle now it gets
larger larger larger larger larger
larger larger larger in infinitely large
it becomes a line so it's very
interesting so anyway the point here is
the line gets becomes a circle or lines
okay
now let's try uh let's see another case
with the circle
and you can prove all that you know
there's proof here you can read them uh
later
[Music]
um
so
so let's show a circle case
uh where is it
here
and no not here
yeah here
so here is a case of a circle so we have
a circle here if the circle is further
away you can see the red circle is its
image so
circles become Circle
okay so that's the geometric inversion
and here you can also see how it becomes
a line you know a circle becomes a
straight line and it got swapped to the
other side so anyway again
any point outside of the immersion
circle gets mapped to the inside you can
see p and Q There
here is p
so this point gets inverted over there
and this blue circle gets inverted into
the red circle and we can move the
circle about so you can let's see
enlarge the circle so again the blue
circle is outside it becomes
inside
and let's shrink it a bit okay so if we
move the circle
cross it and if we will move it inside
you can see
how it becomes goes to the outside and
you can see here is when a circle
becomes a line
and swap to the other side you can see
very interesting okay so geometric
inversion
so that's how all these Graphics are
so you know in this case you begin with
a colored grid like that and you do the
inversion it it becomes like that and
here is a mechanism let me show you this
way this one so this one is you know in
1800 also this is called porcelainia
personally a limit linkage something
like that
basically it's a mechanism to turn it's
a linkage it's a mechanism called
linkage that
that essentially demonstrates based on
the geometric inversion principle so you
can see
you can see this is a mechanism you know
you just got a bunch of bars fixed on a
point on a pivot or however you call
that
so this so if you move this point on
this line
you know this linkage forces forces the
two points such that one is the
inversion of the other
so
so this is useful when you have robotics
for example
the legs of a dog you know you want to
control you know you have a motor that
can only
go you know round about but you want the
legs to move you know back and forth so
this is one of the you know there's all
sort of linkages that does that so this
is one of the earliest to turn a
circular motion into a rectilinear
motion
uh and uh
you know and the the math principle
behind it is uh inversion okay
so that's and there's more there's
another famous linkage called Hearts
linkage uh I don't have age or I don't
have a you know interactive demo of that
uh and let's show you something
interesting okay so here is a geometric
inversion of a sine curve so so this
blue thing is a sine curve so you can
see the P Point moves and the red curve
is its inversion
so you can see and the green and the
green is the
uh
the the given Circle to invert so
again any point outside of the circle
goes through inside you see Q is here
and the
when when the point P reaches the circle
its image is the same you know p and Q
are same then when the point is inside
it goes outside so you can also move the
let's see if we can move the
yeah so we can move the
you see now the blue line is the you
know assign curve so now it's outside of
the circle so the image becomes very
small inside the circle
see
very interesting Okay so
now we want to
yeah now we want to derive the formula
Okay so
hello immortality
uh everything good say something guys
uh this bit rate problem uh okay so
let's see
so we demonstrated geometric conversion
uh what do we do next
let's see so I want to
spiral so here is another interesting
one let me show you that one okay so you
are looking at this spiral this spiral
is called archivitamin spiral it's a
family of spirals so there's not just
only one of them there's like multiple
of them
one parameter
so you can see this animation shows you
uh different Archimedes spirals
and this animation is this more so all
these are Archimedes virus
Archimedes spiral is is defined
by this
[Music]
um
polar equation
radius equals to angle raised to the
power of n so given a number n
let's say n equals to 1
then you have radius equals to Theta
so that means as you know Theta you know
so this is Polar Polar equation Theta
just turn around okay Theta just go
around so Theta
basically this means when R equals to
Theta that means when Theta turns the
radius is proportional to Theta okay so
it kinds up it's a kind of proportional
um
you get a proportional
spiral so as as when you have more Theta
you have more distance from the center
the radius okay so you can see that's a
result R equals to Theta
now but if you add power to Theta you
know theta equals raised to 2 second
power or third power then you get other
things you know you get other
kind of spirals
okay so that's Archimedes very well so
let's show you so there's a g algebra
you know so at this rate I don't think
we can start to code uh
okay
so anyway so this is our comedian's
spiral you can you can drag this to
change the
end to see different
uh spirals so so all these are comedy
comedian spiral
so when is n equals to 1
okay this is when n equals to 1 okay so
let me show you so you see this is these
are comedian spiral okay midi spiral so
when when when the power is one you have
the formula R equals true Theta and this
specific spiral is called Archimedes
spiral
now when the power is not one then you
have
other spirals that's called our comedian
spiral Okay so
you it's hard to see
uh let's see
you see this so it's a family of spirals
so when when the power is negative then
you got things like this and then it
becomes like that
okay
and you often see these as
you often see that
as
[Music]
um
anyway never mind okay so
so there are many different spirals they
are using architecture in decoration and
so on
okay so so that's a comedy spiral but
what about the inversion so let's show
let's show the inversion of a swipe of
this spiral so somewhere here
here
okay so the blue line is the archimede
Archimedes spiral okay so let's check
make it one and the red line is its
inversion
this this screen is the inversion Circle
okay so you can see
you have different Archimedes Archimedes
virus and the red the red is its
inversion
and basically our comedian spiral
inverts to it itself
uh
an Archimedes viral
its inversion is an again Archimedean
spiral so you can kind of see the blue
curve in the red uh a comedians virus
okay
so okay so that's that's that's about
some some of the fancy you know we are
showing some of the fancy Graphics of
the inversion
so just to get a sense of what it looks
like
I love my emacs tutorial okay thank you
today is not emacs so okay so now what
we do next
oh yeah so let's run some of the code so
let me just show you so we did this
in past video
uh let's start with fan language
so next I want to I want to derive the
formula but
you know so here is Wolfram language
code I want to derive the formula but
that's gonna be
another half an hour
and I was planning to do
coding it you know coding a fancy
graphics
you know these are old we did last time
so I'm just running it so I can show you
so
so here is a geometric inversion a bunch
of squares
and uh and this one 3D tile very
interesting let's copy it here's a code
copy it
paste it here run it
and okay so let's make this pretty
so you can see uh when the math formulas
and that's a source code so you get this
thing it's running again
so you get this thing you you begin with
this image then you do a geometric
inversion then you get this okay then
you you add z-axis you know you make it
three-dimensional so you get this
and then you just add thickness to it
then you get that
okay so that's you know that's that's
the graphics we did last time
uh
and I just want to
show them again
[Music]
no I don't want traditional foam
brunette
okay so this is a bunch of Cubes
uh and inverted geometric inversion in
3D so can we show the cubes
now let's not do it okay
okay I wonder if there are something
basic about visualization questions like
the distance between a point and a
straight line
distance between a point and a straight
line
yeah you uh
um
yeah you can do that but let's let's
move on with uh what we're gonna do
today okay
so
so let's see what what we want to do
next
we want to derive the geometric
inversion formula
Okay so
so how do we do that
uh
and we want to show the relations
between geometric inversion and
stereographic projection okay so if you
don't know stereographic projection is
just like that so let's let's let me
show you the relationship okay
so
and start paint okay so let's see if we
can do this
so given a line
given a circle
so in a geometric in stereographic
projection this is a 3D case but you can
also do it on 2D so this here is a 2d
case so this is X and this is
why so what you do is that you project
the line
you know given given a point x
given point on X this point is p so you
draw a line from the center of the
circle to P then this line
this should be a line straight okay so
how do you erase um
things
yeah this is not good
so anyway so you draw a line passing the
point p
and passing the center of the circle
then you will have
this new point and this point is Q
called Q
this point is called Q so this point Q
is a stereographic projection of the
point p in a two-dimensional case so any
point p on the x axis you can it
corresponds to a point on a circle Q
okay so this is
this is kind of a two-dimensional case
so you can do it in three dimension in
the same principle applies
so that's how we get that okay we we did
a video last time on this
uh and you can see
given given a image like that
you know you have the result like that
on the right side
and you can also demonstrate this by
shining a light
onto a ball you know the light must be
at the North Point of the circle
then you know then the shadow
automatically becomes their you know
projected point
okay so this mathematician uh friend
segment Henry Central he did a video
fantastic okay so you go
watch that video
so anyway and and there are other
interesting so this is you know very
useful in math it's using uh complex
analysis
so anyway so
so we have the stereographic projection
so how does this relate to inversion
okay so let me explain
so here is the stereo you know
stereographic projection
and
this is not good so let's let's do
so if you have
um yeah so what's what is the relation
between stereographic projection and
geometric inversion okay so let's do it
again let's do the graph again so here
is the x-axis
here is the y-axis
and suppose you have a sphere here
okay so you put so given a point p on
the x-axis you draw a line
through it and here this point is Q okay
so this is stereographic projection by
definition any point you know on a
circle you project the line
uh wait actually we did it wrong
it should be from the North Pole not
from the center of the circle okay but
so so there should be a line like that
so and this point is called Q so here's
a that's a stereographic projection
now how does it relate to inversion so
now imagine there's a circle twice as
large
so the circle goes like that so here is
the center
okay so this large circle now now you
are going to do
so before given a point P we want to
find the stereographic projection of the
P of the point p
so you just draw a line from the North
Pole to p and the intersection
with the circle is your image the result
of P okay so any point P will have a
point Q on the circle on the
stereographic projection Circle the
small circle
now you can do you can do this without
using stereographic projection
to get the point Q okay how do you do
that use you can do that with geometric
inversion so you just imagine a bigger
Circle twice as large so what you do now
is you invert the point p with respect
to the inversion Circle then you can see
you get a point q and this coin Point Q
will be just
it will be exactly the same as the
stereographic projection
so you can see any point on this line X
and when you do inversion remember a
line inverts to a circle to this small
circle so when you do inversion with
respect to the large Circle
and since it becomes a circle because a
line becomes a circle and this since
this line is outside of the circle so
any point on the line goes inside the
circle and any point touching the circle
will
not change
so you can see this line x-axis becomes
the
becomes exactly the stereographic
projection Circle
okay so that's
um
that's their relation so that means when
you try to code this image you know we
you normally we use the
you know we try to find the intersection
of the line and the circle to determine
the point but now
you have a different method instead of
you know trying to find the intersection
you can just compute the distance of
of the North Pole 2p you know
times the North Pole to Q will equals
two times the radius of your
stereographic projection so you can find
that point so you don't have to do the
intersection anymore so that's a
different technique
so let me show you Wikipedia Wikipedia
has a good explanation Okay so
let's see
uh inversion okay
so here is the inversion so they explain
they expand inversive geometry
um and you can see this beautiful
animation that's fantastic that's
inverting a
mandelbrot set
some sort of mandible set inversion of
Lambda mandible set okay
okay and now let's go and they explain
the same way I did and there's many
interesting properties
uh and uh Circle become lines and here
is how they explain
the relationship between stereographic
projection
you know with respect to the green
circle
can be equivalent can be you know is
actually equal to the inversion of a
circle twice as large
you know so this point becomes that
point that point becomes that point
so two ways to do it
Okay so
so now so that's the mathematics of it
uh so next we're going to do
next we uh so there are there are a few
things we can do now
uh one is to derive
the formula for stereographic projection
okay
we're gonna try to derive the formula
for that
uh
for this projection and also we can
try to derive the formula for geometric
inversion that is given a point in the
plane x y
you want to find the formula that gives
you the result point
the coordinate
so we can derive those formulas then
the other thing to do is to actually
code it in Wolfram language
okay so let's so what do we do first
um let's see so the here is inversion
so here is the stereographic projection
and inversion so
so how do you derive the formula you
know that that's I haven't been doing
this for a long time so
let's see basically basically all you
need is trigonometry okay
uh you don't need you don't actually
need to solve any equations I don't
think
but how do you do it oh my God I forgot
so basically given a circle this small
circle
and and uh
given a point P you want to find the
coordinate of Q
and how do you do that without using
equations you know you can you can solve
it by using a equation of a circle and
the equation of a line
so you have
um
yeah equation of a line
is two variables equation of a circle is
also two variables so once you have that
you can you have two equations with two
variables so you can solve you can find
the Q
um the intersection point
you have two in this case
but
so that's one way to derive
the formula
of stereographic projection
but is there another way without using
equations
for example let me let me show you okay
so for example let's let's use let's
cheat okay let's use Wolfram language to
solve the equation
but anyway you'll explain so
equation a circle is x squared
what
plus y squared
equals to r squared okay
so this is how you do equation in
Wolfram language
okay so and you can
you can you can make it look nice
so that's a formula for a circle
centered on the origin okay so we can
plot it
come to plot okay
foreign
works
okay you need uh three arguments I
expected
oh so you need X Y X Y minimum Okay so
Wolfram language needs to know which one
are the variables so X is a variable and
you want to plot it from negative two to
two okay
and Y is also the variable and from
negative 2 to 2 okay let's do it
okay so then you wanna say
oh it doesn't know what is R so you have
to say the value for R in this case
let's say I equals 1.
okay so you got a circle
of radius one
uh now we want the line
now you um
now this circle is centered on the
orange you know zero zero we don't want
that you know we want a circle centered
uh above orange above the engine we want
the small circle okay so again we are
trying to stop we are trying to find the
formula for
the stereographic projection so we want
the circle centered above so
so in order to find that formula we can
just
yeah so this is a basic analytic
geometry if you remember you can just
say x minus
one okay
and we place y by y minus 1.
I think so let's try it
okay yeah so we kind of it worked we
should not move X so X should be X Y
minus one okay
so there
so we got a circle now centered on zero
one
okay and that's not you know
so now we need to work this out so
we want to know
we need to decide on what what is the
radius we're gonna use so let's use one
so
so this is radius one yeah okay that's
already radius one right so that's the
formula for a circle
now let's what about the formula for a
line
okay I don't remember my
um my analytic geometry since 30 years
ago so but but we can easily do it
just by trial and error so a equation of
the line is going to be
let's just start over okay
so equation of the line is going to be y
equals to something X
Okay so
yeah you need to know the slope okay the
slope is
so we want to find this one okay yeah
okay in order to know the line you need
to know the P Point P first
ah God so p is going to be a variable so
once and so you know so let's suppose
Peace point p is a point such that P
equals to A B okay A B is some constant
so basically we now we want to find a
line we want to find a equation of the
line
that passes
the North Pole
that passed past this point which is 0
2.
okay that's one of the point it passed
and it will pass another point which is
a b okay
now we don't know what is a b but
I mean we assume it's some constant so
we want a formula
that represents a line that passes
through these two points
okay
now I don't remember my my calculus but
this is an easy case we can actually
just derive it
okay with uh with
um
you know with basic understanding of
vectors
so the point p is two coordinates A and
B in fact B is zero because remember we
want the point p is always on the X x
axis
so p
equals to a0 okay so we now we just have
one variable okay
so we want now we want the
equation of the line that passes these
two points very easy okay
uh very easy so
now in general the equation of the line
is
y equals to
m x okay m is some slope
right so that's the equation of the line
it's a linear equation because there is
no powers involved so let me let me do
yeah so that's correct
okay so that's a linear equation this is
a general form of equation of the line
and now now you you now you just want to
find in terms of a
so you basically have well God this is
back to
linear algebra so
uh so what we have is
P equals through a0 a is a a is X so
so we have
y equals to
M A okay that's
that's the first case for the point P
then the other case is for the point
zero two okay so let's do that
so Y is two
so we have 2 equals to MX
m
and what is X x is zero so
m0 so that's just two equals to M okay
so now we got 2 equals to M then we know
y equals to 2A so that is our
this is our formula for a line
that
that passes
0 2 and
and passes any you know any of the a
yeah so that is our Formula 2 equals 2
2A and let's write it let's let's uh
and say it again y equals to 2A so y
equals to
to
a so this is
so yeah so now a is a variable let's
just say a so let's plot that
there it is we got the line
but it looks like this line is incorrect
uh
did we get it correct
okay
so I'm not sure
where are we going so this is incorrect
I have to think about this
a lot
so right now this is incorrect so
because this line passes the point zero
zero and
wait what are we doing
so we we want the line
that pass this oh yeah so we got mixed
up
so if you want the line
passes okay so we need to actually
write a lot more
formulas
uh
I don't think I can do it I mean
I cannot do it in
five minutes
it'll take some time
so
we are trying to find the formula well
the general formula is okay we can just
try out in arrows okay
the general formula is just that okay so
just that so this allows you to see
so let's say one over two
okay and
yeah so this is yeah oh I forgot we need
to add
you need to move the line up so there's
a constant we forgot the constant it's
at 2 okay
so zero yeah so here we have a line that
passes the point zero two so here is
zero and here's two that's what we want
we want the line that passes the North
Pole of the circle
um
yeah and now this number is just the
slope okay so this this number we can
Define m
equals to let's say 2
okay so let's copy that let's put it
here
okay so this number can be
one and half
okay so and if it's one
[Music]
uh let's say 10.
negative 10. yeah okay that's good
that's likely
so now let's do this
[Music]
manipulate that expression
with M goes to 0 3 2 3 in step of
zero point
one okay
okay so now we got a animation
interactive animation so you can see
so all these
uh lines of an equation that passes
through the North Pole
so let's play it
yeah so this is exactly that is our
equation
that is our equation of the line so now
now we have two equations okay
one equation is this one
equation of the line
with a given M okay
m m is you know whatever whatever point
we want you know that's why it's
variable
and the other equation is the equation
of a circle here this one
uh yeah that one
so we have two equations these two
okay and we want to solve it
okay we can solve it we can try to solve
it by substitution you know y equals to
that then you just put replace this y by
that
you know replace
this y by this and the
then you got a equation of one variable
X then we sub you know we can do this by
hand
but
it's quite tedious to write here I have
to create another
you know so we so we got the equation x
squared
uh
x squared
Plus
MX
plus 2
minus 1
squared
equals to 1 okay so now we
simplify this this MX 2 minus 1 is
M X Plus 1 squared
and you have to multiply them out
then you got
you basically got the quadratic equation
okay like X raised to the power of two
then you try to solve for x
but let's try just just use the Wolfram
language to solve it okay let's see
if this works sub
attempts to solve the system
expression of equations or inequalities
okay yeah we can use that
so solve
that and we want to solve for x
try it
huh empty
okay and domain
oh okay so you have to the syntax is
incorrect instead of the list you have
to say
end
so that's one equation
and the other equation solve for x
what
clear m
I'm trying to do some
yeah examples
let's try x y
okay now it's better
yeah so you can see here x0 Y2 is one
solution
and here is the other solution this is
the part we want
exactly
now now yeah exactly now what is m m is
just R A here
uh yeah
so actually yes so now we have a formula
we derived
ourself
that given an
point
p on x-axis we can find the point Q
and the P the point p is two numbers so
how do you uh work this out so
in P is basically just m okay so Point P
has two coordinates X and Y
and the y coordinate is always zero
so you can think of the point p is just
m or some transformation but you know
basically Point P would be m
so given M you have a new point x
exactly yeah so that looks correct
because I've worked up with this
you know many times before in the past
20 years this formula is correct so for
example
let's um
let's extract
okay so now we have this um
let's define it a solution okay
solution equals to
that okay so now
so when
now let's you know when when the p is at
our engine
which means m is zero X is zero
the result point should be
should be 0 0 as well so
when m is zero
let's replace m
by zero
okay so when n is zero
it gets
these
it gets that it gets the other point so
there's something that needs to be fixed
let's say when m is one let's see what
happens
x equals to negative one y equals to one
x equals to negative one
okay the formula is not correct
okay I think that's it for today we
you know this we we failed I didn't do
any preparation so you know we tried to
derive the formula of the projection
formula in 2D this is this is really
simple you know uh I haven't done it for
a long time
uh so
you know
so we we are trying to derive it you
know that's the that's the that's a key
here you know uh
but there are many ways you know we
you can also look you you know there are
so many ways to drive it you know right
now we are trying to use uh you know
linear equations multiple linear
equations of a circle and the equation
of the line we can also do it with a
um
with a vector you know you just um
wait can you actually derive the formula
by using vectors
you probably need some geometric
theorems about
you know classic Asian geometry
um
yeah I don't know so
let's let's look up Wikipedia and I'm
gonna shut down in a minute yeah I'm
gonna shut down
uh Wikipedia so we want
stereographic projection
I have to go I'm kind of
tired
sitting for too long so here's the
stereographic projection you can see
they give you the formulas they show you
how to you do they show you how do you
derive it
you know it's it's so simple that uh you
don't even there's not much derivation
but you do have to be familiar with
you know the basic analytic geometry
um
yeah it's uh so
no
I'm trying to say well actually I gotta
go guys
so terrible this is a terrible video
I gotta go I got you know my wife is
calling me
bye guys