hello guys so I'm starting streaming so
today's today's topic is going to be
lisp machine keyboards now actually I
don't know if I'm starting streaming or
not because because I think I am
wait actually I wasn't prepared you know
I don't know if I should have closed my
windows and stuff sails keyboard raise
the keyboard now razor keyboard is a
worst okay don't ever buy razor keyboard
because you know today's you know it's
all about marketing you know basic
keyboard they market to gamers you know
you know it's all about marketing like
today you have this let's see are there
people watching ok I'm actually not sure
I'm live so I might you know just quit
and start over but anyway so I was
talking about razor keyboard yeah raise
the keyboard you know they it's all
about marketing like today you have you
know you know that headphone you know
called P you know this is very popular
you know it's you know the headphone
it's the the mark the symbol is just be
be stand for what P I forgot but anyway
that is the worst headphone ever you
know with regards through the headphone
quality divided by the price so the
ratio is the worst but however it's very
successful o beat right it's called beat
the brand name beat headphone and I see
my friends wearing that oh and I'm going
oh my god you know it's very successful
because of marketing you know that's the
thing about today's you know cooperate
cooperate wording America especially
you know you make a product it's almost
like more than 50% of your resources is
spent on marketing you know so you know
you know design and manufacture you know
that's important but but marketing is
like more important you spend like
million dollars to market it so and
successful marketing is act is more
important that for example you have to
you know how how the beat headphones
became successful you know I read one
time I read article this is like five
years ago even you know because they you
know they you know celebrities you know
Hollywood stars and musicians you know
you get them to wear beat headphone you
know like you pay them you know you they
probably paid them so you pay them to
wear the headphone beat headphone and
teenagers you know they saw that that
you know that this hi guys so one guy
watching say something here you know so
the PD headphone you know celebrities
musicians they have millions of
followers teenage teenage girls and boys
in much especially girls you know
especially you know some of the
celebrity you know the singers they the
teenage girls they follow her like crazy
you know teenage girls and and you know
so they see you know you wear the beat
headphone and they're gonna buy a bit
headphone - they have no idea about
headphone quality you know the
engineering stuff so okay so what I got
one guy watching is my video Korea or
not you see the video the YouTube
streaming as far as I know is such that
oh I need to change the title saw talk
show okay
say something man say something so I
know you are here
so this is some talk show list machine
keyboard and other keyboard stuff okay
so I need to put that there and do I
save it no okay so I'm gonna talk about
least machine keyboard that's today's
main topic okay I got one guy watching
it's just blank and I guess I I'll just
start then because you know anyway the
stream is going to be recorded so people
I mean it's like hybrid of streaming and
video so later on people can watch it
does a video so I'm just going to start
to talk about keyboard yeah and by the
way so in and also so don't buy razor
keyboard don't ever buy razor cable
anything made by razor you know
apparently they came out with a new
model
this is optical razor optomechanical you
never know what they are saying you know
actually yeah just don't don't buy a
razor keyboard if you want an optical
keyboard app optical mechanical key
switch by this this one there are two of
them
you know let's magnify so one is made by
this China brand called bloody you know
it's got worthy because cameras like it
you know ting ting came on Timbo is they
you know and there's another one made by
okay there's bloody yeah there's another
one by Tesoro
I think Tesoro is also a China brand so
anyway if you want mechanical keyboard
yeah me up tickle switch you know
optical switch mechanism by this one of
these and by the way optical mechanical
switches is fantastic it's because
it you see this is how it works it you
know use uses a laser or laser or any
kind of optical to turn the key on and
off so it's more reliable and it's more
dustproof and waterproof and it's a
lasts longer because there is no like
you know there is no metal contact you
know so but it seems it seems in the
keyboard community the optical case
which did not pick up you know didn't
become you know very popular however
from what I've read I have not seen any
negative I have not seen any negative
opinions about you know optical key
switch so anyway so I'm gonna talk going
to talk about least machine keyboards so
this machine keyboard
oh yeah that's a big history you know
this machines is the I mean if you are a
programmer let's see how many people
watching one guy watching nobody's
coming up oh because I I suppose it's
because so it's a works it's a work
hours people are working okay so well
that's too bad
so I'm just gonna talk about I'm just
gonna to talk about so this machines you
know if you are a programmer and
especially if you are Emacs user you are
probably a fan of these machines you
know it's so you know it's one of the
it's a legend so they are actually
several this machine keyboards the most
famous is this one let me magnify the
screen so this is the most famous
let's see space-cadet keyboard what a
name by symbolics they are different
versions this let's see so this this is
a clear picture you see they have shift
key drop out they have control key
mataki control Mehta
super hyper and top and the Greek you
know there's caps lock so this machine
keyboard is essentially how Emacs Emacs
Keys Emacs key mining became popular so
so they are as there are several list
machine keyboards but to understand
their history you kind have to know
about list machines a little bit so I
give a little little summary about these
machines and by the way yesterday
there's a guy who emailed me and gave me
a great information about the magnifier
he gave me great information about some
history of this machine keyboards and
that guy is last spring cough last
spring cough so this is his website you
know you can read about it by the way
this is my website so you know this
sorry thought info keyboard you know you
can just google search sorry keyboard
you'll find my keyboard block so anyway
so let's go back to this machine key
words so this machine keyboards they are
used by these machines and this machines
are computer hardware that are designed
to run Lisp the language by the way at
least the language stand for list
processing that's the original name I
mean that's the acronym that's well it's
mental list processing and the idea its
invented in nineteen sixty something
1970 1968 or something like that the guy
who invented his John McCarthy and he
was created to do math
basically it's well not to do math but
to to emulate how math is done something
like that I mean it's it's it's it's
like math math math inspired I mean you
can go to Wikipedia and read about Lisp
on these machines you'll find of course
you'll find much details but anyway so
you have so people so there's a lisp
language by the way it's today is still
used it's it's using Emacs Lisp in Emacs
and it's also there's Common Lisp and
closure and skinless scheme lists or
there's a branch called racket
you know racket language so but mostly
you just see see it in Emacs so he Maxie
Solis portly let me show you some maybe
I'll show you a you know my disk code so
let's go through wait wait so nits that
that that that and it's go up you see
this our list code let's let's go up
nits okay no no hmm
let's see some big code okay so these
are just list code these are emag list
but closure and racket skimming they
look similar well close this razor thing
I don't want from a razor razor is the
worst keyboard yeah they do all sort of
things they so they mark it you know
they market to cameras you know with
pretty pictures they spend huge amount
money to resource to market to cameras
and they they they raise the price you
know like for the same quality and same
you know quality old technology of the
keyboard you can get it from other brand
that that's much better for example if
you want to buy from name-brand
get it from Logitech
get it from Coolermaster those are good
ones don't don't ever buy racer also
racer the company they deliberately
remove like they all you know in some
models at least they remove the keyboard
memory and they removed remove the
firmware you know software to program
the keys but they call it their keyboard
you know programmable but actually that
requires you to to have their driver
running in the background and or you
they require you to connect to their
cloud you know internet connection so if
you don't have their driver installed or
if you are not connected to internet
your keys doesn't work your you know
custom programmed he's doesn't work you
know this so that's Razer Kibo is very
bad so let's go back to Firefox oh yeah
so let's go back to the talking about
list machines so lease machines so yeah
so there's a first first of all this at
least Lisp language then people created
list machines that's designed the CPU
the entire machine is to design to run
these programs efficiently so the first
one is around 1974 it's called it's
called cons machine it's used at MIT
then around 1978
there's cutter machine then 1981 there's
symbolic symbolic is a company name it's
a lisp is a company that sells list
machines and another company that sells
sells list machines is LM I am I stand
for this machine Inc and these two
companies they are pretty much enemies
they are competitors there's a rich
history behind them it's a feud you know
they and Richard Stallman is also
involved you know in the
and by the way Richard Stallman has
written some very popular article about
Lisp
the language in history don't shut them
you know don't trust his words you know
he's got of course he's the free
software foundation creator of free
software foundation and he had his
opinion is very biased you know when you
are someone you know each of us have
opinions are biased you know so when you
see things how you see things is usually
how you how you see things is usually
from your perspective you know biased
towards your European of its you know
what you know your ideas even
unintentionally you know some some
people lie or politicians for example
they they they lie or they you know they
intentionally do bad things but other
people but even if not intentionally
each person I usually see things that's
you know towards his own view so anyways
Beatrice Norman has wrote article that's
widely you know a popular open source or
Emacs people you know everyone wants to
you know link to it you know you know
this is the hit list history but
actually don't there's many things wrong
in it
don't so don't trust his what'd he say
100% anyway let me show you okay so oh
hi guys break the loop fine finally I
got to person watching so so let me
answer the questions but before that let
me show the me before I forgot let me
show you some of the lists
it's got with my Emacs block let me show
you some of the article that counters
which is storm and store story so Emacs
miscellaneous
I just want to point it out you know
because it's important you see history
is towed by winners you know there's a
saying that history is told by winners
which is you know logically true I mean
if you you know your enemies are wiped
out you know they don't get a say you
know to what history is so today you
know Richard Stallman he's got you know
free software foundation and he's alive
and he is telling his stories but before
the least machines you know the history
of Lisp you know there's this machine
Inc there's you know Symbolics the
companies you know the people they have
found us they don't get you know they
don't get to say you know because
whatever they say is wiped out by
Richard Stallman because Richard
Stallman is more famous for Emacs for
example you know so but anyway so let me
just point out the articles let me find
it actually I don't even ok so so what's
his name ok actually you'll find it by
just such it's just such for this common
list problems ok that's how I remember
where to find the information
fundamental problems of Lisp ok on Lisp
then ok famous programmers on how common
lisp sucks you know I'm I'm not a fan of
Common Lisp I think it sucks it's one of
the worst one of the worst language ok
so so this page there are several famous
list they are lisp cards you know they
created their part of the lisp you know
the top these experts they are
fundamental they are pillars of lisp
they created
and you know Road aspect of this you
know many of these guys sky steel is you
probably know his most famous Richard P
Gabriel he started he started a company
that basically gave us XE max today so
you know Richard Gabriel program you
probably know he is famous for hacker
news you know the you know with the
start of Y Combinator they know wine
grape that's a guy okay that's guy I
wanted to get her talk about so they
know wine rep he's a founder of
Symbolics
so he's one of the founder or one of the
earliest programmer I think he's a
founder of Symbolics Symbolics is one of
the first lists machine company company
that sells the least machines hardware
so he has written an article so all
these people you know these are list
cards they you know they have read they
have wrote about you know how common
lisp sucks you know the thing about
computer programming culture is that the
programmers you know most of them like
mass vast majority of them like you know
whatever you see whatever you perceive
in a particular programming language
group mostly it's it's garbage
okay it's hard for you know for like 10
years when the language is hot but it's
not true history and it's no is it true
good advice when you know like idioms
like programming patterns you know
defensive programming you know you know
that the period come and go you know
whatever you know people are fashionable
about it then you know at that at you
know when you you if you have different
opinions people attack you like this
hacker type of people know you are
stupid you are a troll you know they
attack you you know like programming
patterns is like almost is crazy
crazily popular into the
mm and today you don't hear it much you
know patterns and before that is Opie
you know object-oriented programming but
anyway so let's get back to the topic so
Daniel when grape he died he died in
yeah he's article so let's go look this
program Daniel when raped that he died
in 2012 it's kind of sad so he he so
okay so he he is a guy I'm talking about
and he wrote a let's go back here let's
go here so he wrote a article that
counters Richard Stallman's history of
of Lisp where do I find it
I don't know I have you know as many
articles here I don't remember where
they where they are linked from but
let's let's just type then you know way
way please
history there it is
Danielle wine rape be butter to reach a
storm and story of this history so you
know read it you know if you are
interested in this peace treaty so we
did in in the sense that it provides a
counterpoint you know an adult
alternative you to Richard Stallman's
you know perspective of bliss history
and listless machines so let's get back
to this piece lists machines so I'm
talking about the you know this
programming this language and lists
machines you you you need to know a
little bit about them their history
before you can understand you know list
machine keyboards a by the way I'm not
you know here too you know seriously
give you a history but you know it's
just you know I'm just talking over
about the things I know and this list
keyboards they are you know they are
interesting you know they are
fascinating in many ways because did you
did you know that where does the Windows
key came from who invented it
you know who invented for example the
Menu key you know I'm on Windows
Microsoft keyboards on the right side
you usually have a Menu key or app key
who invented that who invented the
windows keyboard obviously okay the
answer to both of them is that Microsoft
invented them both of them around 1994
or something it was invented the first
keyboard that has such key is let me
show you is the most famous Microsoft
economic keyboard
this one so this is the first keyboard
that has the window key and the Menu key
these two keys they debuted you know
debuted on this keyboard and this is
around what year 1994 but however these
two keys I mean the inspiration of the
window key windows key came from the Mac
the Mac's command key in option key okay
so where does max idea of command key
and option key came from they came from
this keyboard 1970 the cell keyboard sa
IL sa I our central Stanford AI lab yeah
so this keyboard is the mother the
mother of command key and option key and
therefore Windows key no they did so it
is from this keyboard that you begin to
have this you know command mod Oates can
oh you know modify a bunch of modifier
keys and what about ctrl key ctrl key
and Shift key so before this keyboard
you do have ctrl key and you do have
Shift key now Shift key comes from
typewriters obviously you know you you
know typewriters mechanical typewriters
in the early days you have to it's all
mechanical right you have to push your
bar and that shift the level so when you
press Shift key you know when you hold
it down it shifts the levels you know
under the key then you press another key
they strike different letters you know
capital letters so that's why it's
called shift and then and control key
I'm not sure what's the history of the
control key but I I imagine it's it's
from
teletype or you know some kind you know
machines of that era yeah I'm not sure
what's a history of the control key okay
so let me go back and read comments I
mean then we go back to this oh yeah
maple okay so break the loop ask about
maple versus Mathematica okay that's
okay I would recommend Mathematica for
sure okay so what if you don't know
Mathematica is a symbolic symbolic
mathematics software you know a software
that does symbolic math and also for
programming they are called symbolic
algebra systems that's how people call
them before computer algebra system so
they were called computer algebra
systems
now some Mathematica is one of the most
famous for doing that and maple is its
competitor it's my voice from Canada
Toronto it began in a university I think
University of Toronto but anyway so it's
a software you can buy to you know do
symbolic computation for example you if
you want to integration derivatives
solve equations sub linear system of
linear equations sub differential
equations so you know you know of
multiple variables or sub matrices
matrices and if you want to do them
symbolically symbolically not not just
numerically you know so if you want to
do that that's what these software are
for now I don't actually have experience
with maple I mean I started Mathematica
I programmed in Mathematica for 10 years
in 1990s I don't actually have I might
write maple for an hour or two or
something but basically but in my
opinion go with Mathematica okay I mean
these two are competitors you asked
different people
some people will tell you you know they
prefer maple but actually I'll tell you
for sure go with math math math America
because the reason is that Mathematica
is you know from the guy Stefan Wolfram
Stefan Wolfram is a certified genius you
know he were my author price when he was
like a king or something he got a pH PhD
degree when he was maybe 16 or something
and he is a physicist you know back then
and he went on to create Mathematica and
he created his company Wolfram research
and today you probably know about you
know Wolfram Alpha famous for so anyway
so why do I mention him but what I'm
saying is that so he he's the guy you
know he's got the big ideas and he he's
got a vision you know so he created
Mathematica the language he's intimately
involved in very every design of
Mathematica the syntax how it should be
the semantics so so so he created math
America and today Mathematica has become
so many so many other things it's not
just for math it's not just for symbolic
computation I mean in his words it's for
taking you know you know mm it become
you know Mathematica is for technical
computation and today is for everything
I mean literally like you can just that
type you know it it it you know it's
it's got AI engine it's got you know
image processing like Photoshop I mean
scientific image processing it's got you
know you can ask it questions and you
know so it's got many things but anyway
let me go back to my my view back in the
1990s
so back back in 1990s mathematical it's
got basically my opinion back then I
pretty much still hold the opinion is
that Mathematica is a the syntax the
semantics it's got a programming
language basis so it's it's got a kind
of consistent up
or you know you might say opinionated
it's got a a point of view you know on
programming so it's got a system it's a
system you know that that you know in
the beginning it does mathematics
symbolic mathematics they need you know
it's things got added it's graphics and
other things so but maple maple well
okay I don't know much history about
maple but from my point of view back
then you know of course why when I want
to buy Mathematica or maple I this
question also present to me you know
which one is better I went with
Mathematica and you know I was very
involved you know because back then I
was very much into math so but maple
more look like you know it's just you
know it's just the software you know
like think of it as an application that
does that does symbolic math then so the
syntax is is like is I don't remember
exactly so I think it's kind of like see
and kind of like MATLAB so so
Mathematica on the other hand the syntax
is very particular very different in
fact okay let me put it this way
the syntax of Mathematica the
programming it's a programming language
actually this better viewed as simply as
a programming language and that language
is Lisp so mathematical so this is how
we tie it to into our today's topic so
Mathematica is a lisp
in every aspect it it is a lisp some
people say it's a list done right but
maple is not least at all so it's just
like you know a programming language
that you know so anyway that's my biased
view you know so and I don't I haven't
heard about maple much these days
because Mathematica is by this guy
Stefan Wolfram so he's got a vision and
company and everything physics you know
cosmetology
you know atomic you know subatomic
physics you know he's he's that guy so
and he's he's successful you know he's
running a company but maple I almost
like you don't hear it much these days
you know so obviously it seems you know
Mathematica is like you know just most
more successful so anyway that's
Mathematica and maple okay I don't I
don't actually own any obscure or retro
keyboards actually I don't
you know P because I write about
keyboard you know I write you know about
keyboards hundreds of pages thousands of
pictures people get a impression I have
collection people keyboards actually I
don't I only have like maybe four
keyboards and they are all economic you
know the expensive
ergonomic keyboard and basically the
company send it to me all right you know
I asked them to so I can do review for
them and by the way my review is not
biased you you can trust me on that you
know because you know my character I
don't I don't get money to say good
things about things you know you know
anyway so I only have like four
keyboards and they are all organ re
modern keyboards so this Canisius
advantage it's truly economic this
ultimate hacking keyboard and this
expose keyboard so that's that's I think
that's what I have now so let me answer
the other question are they a computer
programmers whose opinion sorry I highly
respect yeah they are are they like any
names that comes to mind yes definitely
I'll tell you well Stefan Wolfram is one
of them okay he so he created
Mathematica Mathematica is written in C
I don't know today I haven't you
well actually well yeah Mathematica is
written in C and also written in C and
Mathematica itself so it's like most
Lisp you know it shares many traditions
and conventions and you know with Lisp
so these languages most of them are also
written in C the core you know is
written you see why all the others you
know are written in Lisp by you know
same thing with Emacs Emacs you know
Common Lisp you know many
implementations anyway so so mad okay so
and okay so what what about other
programmers I respect they are quite a
few quite a few so because I've flame
you know I criticize about lots of
famous programmers people think you know
I think I'm just a true actually I said
this many times they are quite a few I
respect
Heidi first of all let me let me tell
you some of the scumbags I despise okay
Larry war he's a guy who created Perl
okay now he's a good person okay what so
when I say scumbag well that's not true
you know I you know that's just sick
he's dramatic okay that's just
hyperbolic so Larry well Larry war he
created Perl
I don't think he's he's a trash he
doesn't know nothing about computer
science or infirm language saying but
also he's although I you know he's not a
bad guy as a person as far with him with
respect to morality but he but he is
kind of mean you know on borderline he's
you know because he's kind of like you
know what you call snake oil you know
sale like he he says you know probably
like you know the most three important
thing about programming is you know
laziness
you know he spew out all these you know
dramatic jargons you know like but
probably stare today so Larry well I
don't
I despise very much and yes our Eric s
Raymond I think he's a very questionable
guy and he's not just he's you know he
okay with respect to technology he is
into like UNIX philosophy he want to
sell the idea of UNIX philosophy I mean
was if today that that idea is kind of
dead you know almost young people don't
know about you don't hear it much but
back then in the 1990s and 2000's every
programmer is like oh yeah you should do
it this way because UNIX philosophy
that's complete okay so here's
I have say you know almost everything I
talk about I have a bunch of articles
about it so this your UNIX philosophy I
discuss in detail you can read about you
can read about it so this one
there is another one then
okay UNIX philosophy and this and he
over here this is a variation article
from Usenet dated around I think it was
early was 1984 so if you read this I
mean anyway we are getting into far so
so anyway I don't like okay let me
mention another guy Martin Martin
something he's a guy who who who is the
father of extreme programming kind of
agile extreme programming and you know
something-something injection
and he's also yeah inventive of UML so
let's look up by searching for UML
you'll find his name is what what a scum
you know tech move with respect to
technology I don't know I don't mean the
moral character of the person you know
for now that's let's not get into that
there are some programmers I really did
I think they are more or apparently they
lie they they you know they they try to
sell the earth stuff get money you know
get ahead you know they are kind of you
but let's not talk about those for now
ESI is kind of their you know Eric s
Raymond is Eric Eckstrom is the founder
one of the founder of open-source it's
an organization it so he's also the
founder who created the hacker logo have
you remember the hacker logo it's a game
of life you know like seven dots you
know he created that you know he think
hackers needs a logo and you know a lot
of young people just start to use that
logo he so he's kind of like a code
personality he likes to you know he what
he he likes to create a code same way
with Larry war he this both of these
hours of code characters now Larry were
basically subsided because Perl you know
probe kind of died away then ESI is kind
of still around however today I kind of
support here so because today now the
social justice warriors they they they
become extremely powerful they rose up
and yes I is very much against it so I'm
I mean support of years are him you know
you know politics is complicated you
know it's really complicated because you
have these different partitions or
leaders you know you know
maybe maybe on the whole maybe you know
this guy you like very much but he
doesn't have much power but on the other
hand there are two other guys let's say
a and B and you know you have to vote
for one of them you know so you know if
you don't if you support your guy C
let's say then you you get wiped out
because you know a and B is far more
powerful to see you you know basically
have no role so you you kind of have to
you know choose a and B you know they're
like political affiliations that's how
you know political group forms but it's
very complex so for example the ESR guy
huh you know I only like on my hand you
know I think he's a very questionable
guy you know he questioned morally
questioned questionable also his
opinions on technology like UNIX
philosophy is also questionable but
however today the social justice
warriors they are extremely powerful and
they are - they are doing extremely evil
things you know they they senseless
people they they lie play blatantly and
they are like in most mainstream
organizations media blatantly lie and
you know race you know and it's not
getting to that but so there's this
essay it's social justice you know can
so what you're gonna do
so this ESI and he's opposing it you
know so I well you know so I support a
start in you know in this case you know
because that's more important and also
Richard Stallman you know Richard
Stallman sales the idea the ideology of
free software which is which I think has
led to a very great damage to society
but yes but however Richard Stallman is
as a moral as a person you know if you
look at all things considered he I think
you know he's a good person he does not
intentionally lie he's not a you know
you know devious guy he just believes
in this particular philosophy you know
which is become ideology like a monster
but however he's you know he's not in
you know
All Things Considered he's you know I
think he's a good person so he is also
again is you know the social justice so
he so he kind of you know he's a pillar
you know kind of so you can you can
abide by him you can you know form a
group to fight greater Evo's so that's
that's a situation so anyway so let's
talk about yeah so okay let me let me
just get back to and let's find the who
is a guy who created Martin okay what's
the name what's the jargon for software
injection you know something something
injection Martin the Martin guy so he
created lots of jargons and stuff Martin
Fowler yeah what up what a scumbag that
guy I said okay
more or you as a person I don't know
much about that person actually I do
think he's a good guy he's not a bad
person okay I haven't looked yeah I
think okay he's a good person
but from technology yeah dependency
injection he he likes to you know all
these kind of code guys you know they
like to create they always like to
create jargons like questionable joggers
and also notice this is important
whatever they say usually this is not
mathematical it's not like a
mathematical theory you know in men in
computer science or computer programming
there are many things mathematical
theorems you know that you have lambda
calculus you have you know Y
Combinator's you have they are math they
are math theorems so they are you know
historically great you know absolute
this a valid you know it's valid I mean
the the theory may not be necessary
to be useful but it's it's a it's a math
theory okay so many computer scientists
for example the the McCarthy okay John
John McCarthy for example I would I like
okay I I like I admire let's say I don't
know much about John McCarthy but I like
his opinions about idea about Lisp
for example but anyway so this code kind
of people they like to create lots of
jargons UNIX philosophy is one of them
like UNIX philosophy what the does
that mean
oh it means you know small it's
beautiful it means kiss keep it simple
stupid you know it means you know it's
kind of a fuzzy things if you look
deeper you know okay what exactly you
mean small it's beautiful so when when
small is too small when is it too big it
cannot be defined it's like they go
fuzzy so basically you know it ends up
like whatever they like applies whatever
they don't like it applies you know it's
like when you talk in the 1990s or 2000s
when UNIX philosophy is still popular
you talk to UNIX people you know when
you criticize or Linux you know when you
criticize UNIX they say oh that's not
Unix like tar tar it's not Unix
UNIX is a kernel okay ty it's not Unix
or the you know UNIX you know the shell
bash that's not Unix
yeah it's very bad it's not that's not
Unix on the other hand you know for
example when Apple created Mac OS Mac OS
X you know they say it's this is Unix
this is the the most solid you know
operating system then they all oh yeah
let's you know Mac is UNIX UNIX is so
great because you know you have the
shell you have the ha you have the X
Elevens you know so it's a code you know
basically is you know the thing about
code is that if you are in yet you don't
think it's code
it's like religion so code and religion
has kind of similar
when you believe it you when you are a
member of it you defend it you don't see
it as a coat so anyway that the topic
window far but okay who else I like it
or dislike for example whether or not
people so yeah okay we talked about
Martin Fowler so late who else I admire
it okay this for example the guy who
created typescript let's see
what's his name his his name is Anne
Angie or something let's go to Wikipedia
typescript so what's his name and he you
know if you guys know us just type it
yeah Anders Anders hell hey
Hattiesburg I cannot pronounce your
names
Anders yeah so I think I admire him very
much although I don't know much about
him I haven't studied much what he does
but I know he he he quit he he wrote you
know design and rode typescript as you
know he's a leader you know he he's a
big guy you know in Microsoft you you
have teams you know under under him but
but he also created oh yeah let's see
Wikipedia he also created you know he
lead or created or wrote the team of
compilers but anyway
so he's a guy I greatly admire for his
technical abilities and he and also you
know some someone like him you know in
contrast to the Martin Fowler guy or the
Larry Walker guy or years uh he is quiet
you know he doesn't you know pop up and
say oh programmers you should be lazy
you know let's do a dependency injection
I even inject inject my ass you know he
doesn't do that so when you know he's
just you know he created compilers you
know he whatever is sound you know he
doesn't create code you know jargons you
know UNIX philosophy that's kind of
so you know these people create
joggins cause it's create a problem
because every time you say something
then there's a hundred people there was
they'll tell you oh you should do this
way because you need UNIX philosophy oh
oh in this case just to a dependency
injection you know this is crap
I mean including from your friends
that's the problem of code you know
you're talking about something and your
friend you know someone you know or
respect they will pop up and they'll
tell you about you know a programmer
programmers should be lazy
oh you know you should do injection
there's something like that you know
that's a problem and they also other
people hired at my example for example
guy steel guy steel
I have Castillo is who one of the guy
who created Emacs in the beginning
before Richard Stallman kind of or they
together created Emacs guy style guy
steel let's see where's his articles
let's see famous formulas yeah you know
and he also wrote an article you know he
gave a talk about don't eat rate because
and get rid of cons you know cons is one
of the major problem I call a
fundamental problem of Lisp and you know
in this community especially the Common
Lisp us we argue you know I argue with
him all day day and I you know they they
think I'm stupid they call me a troll
but you know so you can read Richard guy
steal you know he says okay guys guys do
I respect
okay I haven't studied guys they're
still much but I know he he's also you
know he's also a mentor of scheme the
language in the beginning and I watched
a few videos you know one or two videos
by him is very smart and quick you know
he's old now but he still you know very
quick and you know so I admire him as
well I I admire him you know one thing I
find problem is it's like questionable I
mean silly is that guys do is on the
Java design team you know packing like
in the 90s night 1990s in 2000 he's is
one of the guy in a Java design team so
to me it's like why did when did why the
hell wait why did he join that I mean
you know I just cannot stand it you know
he is like part of the Java team but
but I you know this is not a problem
because you know when you are famous you
know people invites you to be on the
chair of some committee or something you
know and he may or may not have
contributed to Java I mean he even even
suppose he contributed to Java I mean
you have to be I mean well Java is just
a different language I mean there are
many forces in you know Inc programming
it's not just like you you know one
single guy design a language and you
know everything is up to me well yeah
you can do that but but when you're some
other language you know started by Java
some Microsystems you can just go there
and change everything you know so anyway
so this guy still I respect this I mean
quite a few I can I have to
for example there's also a famous
computer scientist who whose first name
is disk draw something like that can eat
he is known as EDM I think can someone
type it he's oh is it oh yeah let me go
through my YouTube
so oh wow I've been talking so much now
it's like 56 minutes and I haven't even
began to talk about these keyboards
that's good we can we can do more yeah
it it's it's good W disk try yeah his
name and it I never heard people
pronounce his name but he is one of the
often court quoted guy in the Lisp
community because he's dramatic he's
also a troll you know you know the the
the the word Stroh has changed over the
past three decades you know anyway he's
kind of like dramatic or shall we say
argumented or you know you know he like
like he sometimes attack other computer
scientists just purely by his opinion
you know he so so this guy at AE ewd I
admire him as well you know I so he has
created many theorems in computer
science I don't actually know the
details but but that's life you know
because there's they are literally there
are thousands of theorems and you know
nobody knows I mean even if even a
computer scientist you only know like
very little you know if you look at the
whole thing
but anyway so ewd some of his opinions
are disagree for example he's one of the
guy who said that index of arrays should
start at zero so so the e/wd guy he has
wrote a bunch of notes you know he like
he's famous
there's a website that collects Oh his
notes they are like number the ewd
something one two or three you know
seven you know and one of the I've read
several of them so but one of them he
talks about why array index
start at zero I disagree at all I mean I
don't find it convincing and I think
index should start at one and again I
have article well let me just push my
articles
language design should array index start
at 0 1 ok so you can read that and you
know here is his article ewd 8 3 1 he
argues that it should start at 0 I
disagree and I think his argument does
not make sense he's flawed so anyway so
they are so I've mentioned a few people
I admire this this kind of lot more I
have to think about not ok so in this
community there are several and there's
also people outside of this community
for example ok the Python guy Kaido I
don't like much I think he's his
opinions on program he's his opinions on
programming is like suprise it's it's
you know like these are famous people
right I mean when you create a language
and it becomes popular why the when does
the language become popular it's not
really because the technical quality of
language much of it actually have to do
with social reasons you know marketing
and social social causes many causes and
when a language become popular of course
you become popular
it's like celebrities in Hollywood you
know so Michael Jackson you know he's
very popular well he's very popular
because actually he really seen great
songs I mean he's really great guy but
anyway in many cases how you how popular
are you not necessarily because what you
have done you know how good you are
anyway
programming language designers you see
usually become popular but if you look
at computer science or mathematics
you know those who actually contributed
the most important hard to know theorems
often they are not popular in among
computer programmers they are usually
unknown you know so what am I saying
so anyway so yeah so there are a lot
computer scientists you know you don't
know so so I admire so these people what
about Donald Knuth Donald Knuth actually
I I never I've read some of his books I
read a lot of his stuff in 1990s
actually I don't I don't like his
opinions and ideas in general I don't
like his writing style I don't like his
jokes you know his jokes never was never
funny I don't he
I don't like his opinions in general his
opinions on writing style I don't like
his stuff I don't like his creations in
general I don't like the so called
literate programming I think it's just
academic idiocy
you know literate programming you know
these things you got a code following
like in Emacs Oak mod you know you want
to do literate programming and when Poe
is popular you know there's a ton of
people you know people they want to you
know literal illiterate programming in
Perl you know and news also created tech
you know the the language for
typesetting mathematics and I think is
that's also the most idiotic equation in
computer history in fact it does a lot
of damage to to the math community to
what could have been you know oh okay
let me show you another article okay so
so he is the article I wrote about why I
think Tech sucks you can you know read
about it yeah if you want
so I shall we go back let's go back to
yeah let me go back to top to emac this
keyboard for for a bit then because you
know that's the original plan to talk
about these keyboards so I wanna yeah
okay so let me just you know maybe five
minutes we'll finish so the so there are
these lists machines and the first one
is sale keyboard si il that Stanford let
stand for Stanford AI lab and Stanford
AI lab is created by John McAfee
the guy who created Lisp language and so
this keyboard is the one of the most
earliest in 1970s and before and
actually at that time there is no lease
machines yet list machine doesn't exist
until 1974 or something like that but
anyway so this so this keyboard is the
granddaddy of like this machine
keyboards and major influence to other
keyboards it's so the so then comes the
night keyboard Knight bibo around 1974
it's inspired by the sale keyboard you
know because you can see the color
scheme is similar and many keys are
similar Knight keyboard is invented by
this guy called his name is night tom
night you know what the name you know
like knight in shining armor's and he is
actually a computer great one of the
great computer scientists you know as I
learned more about him on week on
Wikipedia and elsewhere and you know
because he he wrote the original kernel
for the IPS operating system that ran on
PDP six and pdp-10 I have no idea how
ideas work so PDP six of EDB ten you
know the thing about history
said you actually have to live you have
to live in the period to actually know
you know I didn't start programming
industrial programming in UNIX in I
started in 1998 industrial programming
on UNIX so you know but even if you read
a lot history you can get some sense but
you know it's different from when you
actually lived there like today you know
today's generation you know they don't
know what's going on in 1990s they don't
know the they don't know Perl they don't
know how at one time Perot is the most
popular language and supposed to be the
like the end you know the last scripting
language you know in Java Perl and Java
you know today's programmer they have no
idea if you were born you know if you
are millennial if you were Boeing
knighting you know 90s you have no idea
like you don't know but I know I can you
know you have to like live through the
period then you have the experience if
you just read history
it doesn't walk you know first of all
because history is only you know like
just you just have one book or two books
like very few pieces it's different from
everyday experience what you hear on TV
ad magazine ads you know everything okay
so anyway so this is night keyboard and
so this night guy designed very you know
a lot of things he also designed a my
MIT list machine processor so you know
he's a no computer sign of the great so
night keyboard then you have then you
have actually then you have the
space-cadet keyboard night key keyboard
basically then became the space-cadet
keyboard now they are like several
varieties of space-cadet keyboard cutter
keyboard is one of them
and then there's also and and this you
know there are several like as small as
I know I've seen three varieties
I mean meaning that they are in
different boxes you know they are made
they have different company names you
know printed on it but the keys in the
design and the layout are the same you
know you got the thumb keys you got the
Roman one two three four keys you got
you know control metal super hyper you
know that of course you got the top key
you got the Greek key
so the here's another one from ami ami
ami is list machines Inc which is the
enemy of the Singh bollocks you know
they are enemy because of their
political differences LMI Richard
Stallman supported OMI
which is kind of more of the free
software philosophy you know reaches
rome and supported our ami but basically
I am I failed you know because
fundamentally because just because you
know communism doesn't work well that's
that's the eighth period so symbolic
kind of you know success you know
successful until the AI winter came and
you know I think symbolic is actually
still alive I mean as a company I mean
although it it's not active but the
company is still technically still still
there I think okay then then after you
know space cadet is the most famous then
after you got several the least speak
keyboards okay I think let's see if
there's any questions about thanks for
the questions are there more questions
type it
so what would you change the term
dependency injection dependency
injection okay this will make me sound
stupid but I don't really actually know
exactly what it does okay but I I can
tell you I'm pretty confident you know I
don't have to know you know you can you
can think I'm CD I'm just doesn't make
sense so my argument is invalid that's
okay but I can just tell you that
doesn't make sense
and it should be if there's a problem
you know just I haven't looked into
details I've read a little bit sometimes
you know but I don't remember the
details so I don't know what should a
should be the proper term but but you
know and you could first here's a
situation when you create a computer
language jargon or maybe math jargon or
in any other science jargon in chemistry
in physics first of all the purpose of
jargon is that to facilitate
communication and also usually it must
have a definite meaning I mean we we
don't we don't necessarily wanted to
have a like formal mathematical
definition but in general it it always
have a depth you know for a good jargon
for the validity of a jargon it always
have a definition that among
practitioners you know scientists in
that field makes sense you know we
constantly need to use it now jargon is
like you know that's that's a good job
and the job ends like dependency
injection that's kind of like code
jargon okay I can tell you it's kind of
like code jargon it's like of many
programming you know many activities in
programming you can like give anything
or jargon and you can like sell the
jargon you can tell people start to use
it like defensive programming patterns
you know for example we have patterns
right remember patterns like
you know and then we then later on we
have anti-patterns you know they they
but the thing is why you know do you
actually need the jargon defensive
programming do you need it anyway what
the factors I mean defensive programming
oh-oh-oh-oh patterns you know let's say
your specific example do it we have a
specific examples of our patterns like a
factory pattern okay you don't need it
actually you don't you don't need it you
know that you you like in patterns you
know in patterns code you have factory
patterns then you have other patterns
you know you have quite a lot you know
it's kind of like it's just a coat you
know you don't need to get job jargons
basically okay and also when you create
a jog and there's also the quality of a
jargon so what does that mean the
quality or good quality of a jargon is
that when you say it when you name
something even people don't outside the
field they they see the name they
immediately understand it without the
explanation I mean like you can do this
statistically like you throw the jargon
to a bunch of people and let's see how
many people get it right you know if
majority of people get it right as
compared to another jargon then then you
know the the that jargon is a good one
you know that's one of the aspect to
church how good is a jargon you know you
want it to be communicative on the other
hand these kind of jargons created by
this code head leaders are not usually
opaque you know they are typically a peg
like when you say something it it has no
meaning to any you know programmer until
you explain to them you know that's
anyway that's that's the kind of thing
so that's what I that's what I say about
the dependency injection you know these
joggins created by these people like
UNIX philosophy
dependency injection or laziness is a
virtue of program things like that they
they also have another element that is
dramatic like when you throw these
talking out it's you know two
programmers they they are traumatic they
catch the eye and then people want to
know what is it so this kind of jargons
the code they have a that quality okay
that's that's what I'm that's what I say
so okay let me read the the questions
and it will be done so do you have any
opinion on chong kham Mac junco Mac Mac
yeah he amended Craig no I don't know
much about him yeah I don't know much
about him he I from what I heard he when
he was at he's a self-made man okay so
he I think he grew up poor or something
and at one time he stole you know he was
a team or something he's he break into a
he's he stole something like you know
something bad and but he is self-taught
you know so I I think he's a great yeah
I don't know much about him but I think
I guess I think he's great and also he's
you know very capable of course
obviously of course far far more than me
all these people are doing you know they
are far more than me and he also you
know open a company that's that's a
great car you know takes great skill
I mean opening a company linear company
is a different skill then the typical
nerd you know or engineer skill so
[Music]
Denis Richie Ken Thompson I don't care
about them
Chuck Moore or Chuck Moore is a creative
creative force
I don't okay I don't know but Denis
Richie and Ken Thompson you know I know
they created a see you know and but to
me
see is the worst is the worst
programming languages its worst it's
it's the father of all things that's
wrong in programming industry okay in my
point of view okay I know I I mean a
little bit biased and it's a bit high
but hyperbolic okay but that's kind of
my stance okay I think C and UNIX are
the worst they are the they are
everything wrong in the computing
industry okay they I don't like C and C
you see precipice and C press press the
thing about C is that it's it's a it's
it's complete pure garbage okay
then use you know that the famous worse
is better
richard by richard gabriel okay one of
the Lisp this guy lucid he created XE
max lucid inc richard richard are
gabriel okay he so he wrote the piece
was is better very famous among these
programmers was is better you can look
up it's on Wikipedia to so in what's
better so in that story so see is the
one of the example of what is better so
it's like a virus you create a virus
then people you know make it popular
make it fast
that's important make it fast you know
do and fast you know just forget
everything else
forget about correctness forget about
extensibility for forget about good
design just create some garbage but make
it you know make sure it runs very fast
and very simple simple in the sense of
seeing simpleton like you know idiotic
simple not in the sense of where
designed and
make it extremely simple like scheme
okay simple in the sense it's it's it's
idiotic me you know just elements you
know simple elements so simple learn
fast
you know then use you spread it you know
you know you know you spread it that's
see let's see and UNIX okay then you get
people used to it then people want to
improve it then you get other things
like then you have C++ it's it's a pile
of garbage or not another pile then you
have Java unit then you have JavaScript
it's so that's how did you know that's
how virus works from the philosophy of
wars is better okay you know that's so
the worst of it's better it captures the
social you know it's you know it's you
can say it's a philosophical point of
view it captures the social aspect of
software I mean still it's a point of
view I mean you can believe it or you
can leave it you know it's up to you but
it's a point of view that says you know
there's a social acts aspect where you
know instead of focus you know the
success of a technology you know it's
not necessarily how good it is of course
you know obviously it's never you know
just based on technical merit but it's
it's based on many social factors and
the point of view of what is better is
that a focus on a particular kind of
social point of view such that you make
a product you know just try to focus on
the aspect that sells it you know like
um you know get people addicted you know
kind of like underhand tactics you know
kind of like kind kind of like that I
mean that's of course many you know
gaming you know Microsoft you know they
all practice that you know the Apple
even Apple you can say okay I think one
hour and 20 minutes there's a lot of
talk but but I've been going like on a
raw raw I'm just talking
Kaido van rossum yeah I don't like that
guy I mean I well I think he's a good
person but I I think he's opinions on
programming language is not good he's
not good he Kaito van Rossum his opinion
about program he first of all okay he's
very anti functional programming like in
the sense it's almost like if you are
Haskell programmer for example yo if you
are this programmer so Kaito van Rossum
he's like anti like you you can say like
he doesn't understand functional
programming he don't know what the
it is but however I mean he's you know
he has his opinions of course everyone
has different opinions so his opinion
the in his I opinion basically he thinks
you know all your functional programming
you know marry merits what do you think
is good he don't think it's good so his
language Python is just you know not
good if you are into functional
programming yeah so thank you guys
that's a lot talk you know I enjoyed it
thanks for coming and hijack so thank
you guys for coming let other people
know about my videos you know I want to
spread it you know yeah you know I don't
want I don't like to you know tell
people to thump up and stuff but you
know so if you like it
you know maybe maybe comment and you
know say something and and that that
people know thanks talk to you guys
theta
oh I think I should have aid I kind of
you know maybe I should go you know have
a fixed schedule you know a regulars
stream but I'm always not too sure about
that
because every time I have a fixed
schedule like a plan like a master plan
then I tend to fail because if there's a
master plan then you know I feel like
I'm on stage like I'm
sponsible like Oh today's topic is is um
you know the quality of this was
something you know like I have to
perform you know usually I do better
when you know it's just spontaneous like
I can just rent whatever anyway thanks
guys for watching I'll see you next time
bye