good morning good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
so today we are going to do wufang
language
tutorial wolfram language for
programmers
if you are a beginner that's good
but it's this is designed for
programmers so wufang language so let me
show you so let's go to
um muffin language so i did several
videos before on graphics and on several
other things i i have like over 10
videos on wolfram language but today is
going to be from the ground up so you
know that i teach you the complete thing
wufang language
hello a
oflemia thank you
uh i only watch product placement
thank you flamio
uh so wohan language so let's let's
begin okay so
let's see okay so
so today's talk show um
let's go to so let me let's begin
so wufang language tutorial and you can
just search for xsa
and you'll find my tutorial okay so from
language tutorial and
this is what we gonna cover so
whatever i
talk today is all written up so if you
prefer to read you can read the whole
thing this is the most condensed now let
me tell you what this tutorial is about
this is not for people who never
programmed before okay
but this is for people who never
programmed who never used wufang
language or mathematica before
and especially it's designed for
programmers like for you guys who
program in python java javascript golan
php you know if you are a programmer you
you'll find this tutorial uh very
helpful there's uh
you know
you'll find it very helpful um
and and i'm not going to cover
mathematics like how how do you use
wolfram language or mathematica to do
equations to solve linear algebra to uh
you know derivative calculus that kind
of thing so that
is often used for wolfram language but
i'm going to just teach you the
programming how do you program it and in
particular understand how it works
because wufong language is a term
rewriting system
it's based on
it's a symbolic pattern matching
replacement system that's what term
rewriting is
so this is unusual you know you you you
do not see these kind this language in
just about any language not in haskell
not enclosure not in least
not in functional you know
very rare you know so
so i'm going to teach you that okay and
i hope uh so this will be like one hour
and uh let's see so
so wolfram language tutorial and what
else i want to say yeah oh yeah so where
do you download it you so you download
it here it's free you know it
it begins to be free about three years
ago so you can just look at stefan
wolfram's uh you know post about
you know releasing it free and then
you know you can read my tutorial about
it you you know you can download it here
so uh where do you download it uh here
we'll find uh for developers
okay you you need to register you need
to give your email and you know
and your you can get it so what you'll
get is
or you can also buy raspberry pi
kit it comes with wolfen language come
with it free that allows you to run
wufang language or mathematica on the
raspberry pi but not outside
so uh oh you can just buy it
and which i recommend i recommend you
just buy wufang language or mathematica
and because it is a
a lifelong tool it's great for uh you
know it's a lifelong tool especially you
if you are interested in mathematics in
sciences chemistry you know you you want
to need to do a lot of math
not just math and programming as well so
programming is what i'm gonna teach you
today hey uh george from romania hello
uh
hello guys so okay so that's the
background you that's where you to
download and uh
uh see what else i want to say uh
yeah wolfram language yeah so and let me
also tell you you know
wolfham is a bit confusing there's a lot
of jargons who from engine from script
mathematica what's the differences and
so on so
wolfram engine is the free download you
can download it that's that's like the
compiler you know that's that's the
compiler wolfram engine okay that's what
you need
and wufram script is a is a
terminal interface to the wolfram
language for example let's show let me
show you okay wolfram script
so
right now you are looking at wolfram
script it comes with ufam engine okay so
if you download ufo engine ufram script
is the basic uh interface let's say
333 plus uh two
okay 35 so let's do something you know
let's do something more complicated
expand
some 1
8 over
x squared
plus
y
plus x third power y
okay and i need um
so expand that
to the third power
and let's add a square root somewhere
okay
plus
square root
x
squared plus
y okay let's see what happens okay so
you got this
magnesium you know they got you got this
equation so that's the wolfram script
that's the interface to the woofer
language okay so woofer mentions the
compiler from script is the interface
then there's another uh interface when
you
uh buy wolfram if you buy mathematica
and or if you use a raspberry pi
then you'll have the
graphical user interface so let me
demonstrate
so here is the graphical user interface
so let's enter the same equation let's
put it here let's enter the same
equation here
copy
paste it here
evaluate so you got this more beautiful
uh you know typesetting mathematics okay
that's about the
wolfram script
is the command line look command line
interface with my engine is a compiler
and uh the wolfram notebook is
when you
use the graphical user interface okay
that's the interface font so
so i've been going for 10 minutes so
let's begin wufang language okay so i'm
gonna teach you from the ground up
so first of all uh um
uh yeah so let's see um
yeah wolfram language um
[Music]
okay hold on a second let me let me go
to my talk show
uh today's talk show here and let's post
the link
okay delete that show in browser okay so
that's my wufang language tutorial so
okay so first of all let me show you
strings okay wufang strings strings
this is a string okay so string is the
most basic in every language you know
you in language you quote it with a
double straight quote nothing else this
you cannot use single quote you cannot
use triple quote like python and so on
that's the only way okay just double
quote straight code string
so that's a string and if you want to
print something you say print okay so
print
three plus uh plus two okay
so that's uh print you can use you know
you can do it here as well wolfram's
uh wolfham script
uh then i'm gonna show you yeah my
wolfram
let me show you my uh
emacs
uh interface to the wolfram language
okay so move from emacs
so if you just search that you can see
some woofer mod so this allows you
allows me to
do wolfram language in emacs let me show
you so copy that
so if you have questions comment post it
post it okay about wolfram language so
let me show you my wolfram uh script mod
okay the pink window shows all my
command cores and as you see as i move
cursor and or if i delete something
everything shows in the pink window
you see all the command cores and all my
keystrokes okay so let's start a wolfram
language
so let's
paste so we can you can see
let's try to evaluate this uh the same
command okay so
i press a key
oh uh
error because
i need to exit the wolfram language
from the terminal uh for some reason it
only allows certain instant instance of
engine runnings okay so
now i run it
okay you can see the output so you can
see the output is here
so this is the this i'm using the
xor woofer mod you can download it for
free
this is how it looks like
and it's um
[Music]
it's on uh
github
okay so let's show uh javascript script
okay so
so this is a wolfram xavu fan mod you
can download for free for example i can
i can do completion expand
uh press it and
there you know it auto completes
by uh it has built in
it has about 7 000 building commands in
wolfram language okay so anyway
so string we covered string so let's go
to the next thing
we covered string we talked about
wolfram engine we talked about several
interfaces uh the
the wolfram
the
wolfram script interface the ufm
notebook
interface and uh emacs interface
okay strings so so let me tell you so
strings so how do you get the length of
string so that's string
length okay so let's say
abc
okay that's the function for string now
in language
uh everything you do is just a function
call there's no special syntax let me
let me talk about this
so in other languages for example in
java you have objects you have class you
have references you know
many
many complex things and the syntax is
different you have four uh for loop your
special syntax you have
uh you you have while loop in c and c
plus plus you have you know
i plus plus syntax you know you have
those sort of syntax you have class you
have objects you have reference you you
have different data types now you
and similarly in java and so on
in language everything is just a
function called an expression everything
okay there's no no class no special you
know this is a special thing this is a
special object this is this has
inheritance there's nothing nothing like
that nothing
everything is just a value okay
expression and everything the way you
compute is just call called function
everything there's no class
nothing else okay the most simple
possible one
rule rules
governs the whole language okay so
string length is a function that returns
a number of characters in string and you
can also have unicode in it
but let's skip that then if you want a
new line it's similar to other languages
you put a uh backslash n for example
let's say
backslash backslash n
that gives you uh what
oh yeah well not not there so
you are doing string length here so
uh backslash
backslash
backslash n
cd
and that's going to be two lines okay so
that's a escape character
okay then stream functions so you have
string length for the length and you
have string join this is how you join uh
two strings so let me show it because it
stream join okay so let me show you this
because it illustrates another uh thing
about ufam language abc
d e f okay
so that joins to stream now there's a
shortcut a shortcut syntax so you can
see you can say abc
then that that's a shortcut for string
join
def
okay so you can see that
and you can do similar in uh
you know you can do
for example common that uh run it
uh
okay so you show you you can see there
it is the output abcdef okay
and
and similarly you can do it in
in woofam script
what
i think there's a bug
it did
yeah
oneplus 3 43 okay
now paste that do it okay there it is
for some reason it screwed up before
so shortcuts okay many wolfram language
remember wolfram language is just
functions functions and expressions
values there's no object there's no
parents relations there's no instance of
something instance there's no such thing
there's no exceptions okay there's not
nothing everything is just
expressions value value you change the
value by applying a function
now i you know i'm being a bit
repetitive this is important because
this is a whole
you know you have to remember this in
your by heart because this is the whole
principle of language okay just
functions functions and expression
nothing else
now functions you know many woof and
by default there are there are
uh 6 000 uh seven thousand functions so
let me show you all a list of all
functions okay
so for example you do that um
names okay so that shows
that shows all the functions in language
okay so you can see
there's a lot you know
mathematics you know
anything so
but
and let's see how many are there so
let's see let's go up
so you can say
so length is the general way to see uh
how long is the list okay
so you see there are 7 000 building
functions you don't need to load
libraries no libraries like you like if
you need to do regular expression oh i
need to load what what library is it if
you need to go over directory get all
the files in a directory you have to oh
do i need to
load system or you know import system or
nothing like that okay
so if you want to know the other
directories uh of a file for example you
can just do these um
i believe
i'm giving i'm i'm getting ahead of
myself so let's go back to uh one thing
at a time so we'll we'll get to it so
so shortcut okay remember shortcut is
important because mini ufam language it
works by functions you just call
functions find the function you want
called the function that's how you do
computation from language
and the
function names are always very long for
example it string length is string you
know very long string length string join
there's no
you know function name are full that
means you can always find the function
what you know just by searching function
names and you will always know what the
code does by just reading the function
names just like lisp okay
so function names so but
the problem is typing it that's why many
functions has a shortcut for example
string join is is done by that and for
example let let's give another example
so how do you create a list it's like
that okay three four five
okay that's a list or array you know
depending on which language
name you know
but this is called the list or array in
wolfen language at least
and uh shortcut for you see it output
like that so that's a shortcut so if you
wanted at least three four
five
that's a list
so
the important thing to remember here is
that this wolfram language everything is
a function okay everything is this
syntax function name followed by square
brackets and something however some
function has a shortcut so
a list is done by using that so
for example we can say
let me let me show you some of the
shortcut things so for example list
three four five
true
now what is that equal equal equal that
is a shortcut so that should cut is
same q let me show you okay
uh
that
okay so this expression
this expression you are seeing
is a shortcut for this expression
okay so
remember everything is a function
and functions are full names and some
function has shortcut how do you find
the shortcut if you look at the wolfram
documentation there's they'll mention
the shortcut okay
uh
so we already 20 minutes we're kind of
going too slow um
so let's uh look up ufm documentation
let me show you okay ufm
uh documentation so
this is the official ufm documentation
you know 7000 building functions so
there's a lot to go
through you know i'm not going of course
i'm just i'm giving you the basic
principle today
so this
you know read them okay so in here you
know the wolfram website the
documentation
has the same documentation exactly the
same as the
as when you use a you know building uh
from wolfram language so they are
exactly the same
okay so let's look at one of them so you
know you see you look at list so for
example i click on list
and
you can you can see
[Applause]
you know the wolfram crashed this is bad
demo and it crashed
because i was trying to i was
trying to increase the font size
you know anyway this is how you do it
okay so
you can see the documentation again now
increase the font size you can you see
this part that sees that shows the
shortcut for this function name list
okay
uh okay so
so let's go back so i i need to cover i
need to go quick so what else so we
covered we covered um
let's um
okay so we covered a few things uh let
me let me
let me explain so let's let's write it
down
everything is expression
you compute
by calling function okay
every
7k
field in functions okay
no need to load lib okay there are
libraries of course but you you don't
have to load them they are also external
libraries so you can
you know have add-ons and things
but by default there are 7000 building
functions
no need to load library and every
function name is full
so you can
[Music]
understand
by just reading the function name okay
so that's some of the principles and
okay then
many com
commonly used functions
has a syntax short cut
for example
plus
can be written as
one plus
two
okay so that's some of the things we
covered now let's um
so we covered uh so let now let's go
back to
we are um
so we are talking about string so now
you know that you know so how do you
join string how do you repeat a string
how do you do regular expression how do
you you know everything about string
you
now you almost already understand how to
do it because everything is just a
function you just find the function name
you need
and in the for the stream functions all
stream functions will have the name
string in it okay so let's uh show
example so this is the power of being um
of this system you know everything is a
um
you know function uh name
so if you want to know
all functions that contains the word
stream you know
anything when you are working with a
string you all you have to do is just
find the function so um
so
you know usually there's a lot of string
join string length stream match string
pad left string part that's that extract
stream uh stream partition that divide
the string into a list of strings okay
uh string position find the position of
a string
so there it is so that's so basically
like we don't have to cover you know
like usually in other languages string
join you use a plus sign
then there's a method string join you
know you string dot join you know
then there's when you want to do a
regular expression you need to create a
regular expression object then you know
something like that
so wolfham language is now you already
understand everything oh yeah
essentially you already understand
everything you need to know about string
string is just about straight quote and
anything you want to do it is a function
convert string to numbers you know
string drop which delete parts of the
string okay
delete a
continuous sequence of string string
delete allows you to delete
several characters so you know
uh string three
tells you whether a string contains a
pattern and things like that okay so let
me let me get let's do a regular
expression examples okay
so reg and and by the way everything i
talked today is all in my tutorial okay
so uh everything i talked about about
how to list functions here and how how
do you show the documentation or
function is is already
on my website okay so you can just read
it now let's do an example of regular
expression so let's say
i want to know
something
let's get the email address okay so
kasai at saudi.org that's my one
you know that's my primary email address
something
says some
cat okay so that's a stream now you know
suppose you have a huge stream i want to
extract the email address so let's how
do you do that so let's do um
stream parts i think that's a function
okay string cases
uh you can so how do you what is the
argument to a function you click on that
it shows you the documentation
you can do it in the same way you can do
it in uh
in the um
in wolfram script
but you have to use
anyway i'm not going to go
anyway let's get back to let's get
focused because there's a lot to cover
so string cases so let's just look at
the documentation here string cases okay
string or pattern okay so the first
argument is a string
there the second argument is a pattern
now first of all i can just say okay so
let's say
just a literal so
string cases
will return all substring
that contains this pattern in this case
it's a literal string so you get two
two occurrences of this of psi in this
string okay now but you can use a
regular expression so the second
argument should be a regular expression
so how do you do that so you do that by
regular expression not surprising the
full function name regular expression
okay so now you say now we let's try to
capture the email
address well we can just do okay same
thing but now let's try to use a pattern
to capture the email address so
that will be
anything
a to z let's just force let's just do it
simply okay let's
forget about the proper formal email
address so anything a to z
one or more
followed by a add sign
then
then a to z again
um followed by a dot
now a dot in
regular expression means any character
so we want a backslash dot means a
literal dot
then let's say oh let's just make it
simple so
we got it wrong so
oh yeah one or more so there
there it is so you see this is how
this is the example of using regular
expression to extract email address okay
so far so good
uh how am i doing so how many people are
watching five
grand total of five great
okay so let me um
so we've been how long uh we've been so
we've been going over this string and
we've been um
wait what is the other error
two hexadecimal digits are required
after
uh backslash oh okay so you need two
backslash oh god
wufang language has
toothpick syndrome
just like lisp because the only way to
quote
string is double quote there is no
special
string for regular expression so
so whenever you need a backslash you
actually need two backslash
so uh let me let me have a uh sip okay
so let's go back um so we'll go on
um
string okay so string functions and we
covered regular expressions
um so with regular expression you can
you can
extract substring
you can also um
you know so here's a documentation for a
regular expression okay subway uh
yeah so many many string functions they
they um
take an argument that's a regular
expression
okay so string cases is one of the
example when you want to extract part of
the string
but there is also string match queue
that checks if a string contains a
pattern
these two strings insert into string
delete substring
yeah so you can also use a pattern to
which is this function string dd
and you can also search text pattern
matching oh yeah all these
string
uh so string starts check if a string
starts with some
pattern or string ends
string match queue
string contains q
string three q if it doesn't contain
some pattern string position
you give a pattern and it returns the
position you know the index where the
pattern occur and string count
returns the number of occurrences so all
these functions they most of them return
you know they take a
pattern regular expression
okay just like just like our example
here
and
the
when in wolfen language when a function
ends in a capital q
that means it
returns
just two things true or false okay the q
stand for question so
so it's similar to lisp where many these
are called predicate functions so in
this search function returns uh search
function name
ends in a p okay p for predicate in ub
for example search function ends in a
question mark you know and also in skim
this the ending question mark so this
function so when those functions means
they either return true or false nothing
else so in
language case they end the function name
ends in a queue
q is a reminder for question
by the way this is a namely the art of
naming issue
you know so why why does rufun ends in
queue why doesn't it ends in p as in
predicate the traditional way well
because predicate what the is
predicate you know most people don't
understand it unless you have studied
logic you know so move um
language the design the naming of things
they they tend to be
very uh
more understandable so q just means a
question okay so
[Music]
so there's a question does wufang
language have list style reader markers
uh no no it doesn't have this style
reader markers but however you can
define
you can define your your own operators
but you cannot
yeah you can define your own operators
with
uh you know with semantics to go with it
um
but
you cannot you know you can it's not
like at least you can
re redefine um
[Music]
in some minor way the way it passes the
the the nested syntax okay
so
you know if you want to do uh yeah
anyway so that's my answer
uh okay so any anything uh so let's go
on okay so so we covered string
okay so this is
so we already talked for about 40
minutes this is not going to um
it takes it'll take another hour to to
to
finish
so
so far we covered string
and some basic way some like very basic
way how the wolfram language functions
uh
uh works okay we cover stream then
then you have uh basic you know
arithmetics you know how do you add how
do you subtract uh which is very simple
let's magnify okay so no second
so
so let me let me think about
how am i where do i want to go now um
should we
because there's a lot to cover
um because we haven't get into symbolic
symbols you know symbolic computation
what does symbol mean you know because
so far we only cover string then symbol
is the most important thing and list
this is also the you know basically
list and symbols that's the heart of
wolfram language
then we need to cover pattern matching
uh
and we need to cover expression
structure
uh then then symbolic pattern matching
you know and there's also other things
like true and false that's very simple
uh equality equality test you know um
very simple
uh you know everything else in every
other language very simple
uh
and wolfham has switch
or switch both uh like conditionals
but these are in every language but you
know so what's more important is the
what i want to cover specifically about
language that will if you understand it
you'll know a lot about language that's
the symbol and the list
list and the expression okay
uh
so but i i don't think today you know 40
minutes
it will take another hour
to do so
so wufami expression okay so let me
think
um
then yeah then we have to cover uh
wolfham functions so any other
comments or questions
so the question is so you couldn't make
your own string syntax that's better
suited for writing regular expression
that's correct
so i guess you identified a flaw of
language yeah so no you cannot
uh and uh i
yeah we'll find the language string
i would say
it's somewhat painful it's just like
lisp okay so that's the case with lisp
as well
you know
you know you know i'm going to digress
if i talk about this because the reason
this this
you know in language and in this speech
like that
is because they stick to a very simple
principle so
if you want a string there's only one
syntax you know double quote
um
well i guess what you are saying is that
in common lisp for example or in other
you know in common this if you are very
very advanced common this user you know
suppose you study
coded for five years common disk then
you can you you you can use the
leader marker you know which is
different from macro so you use a reader
markup feature to change the syntax so
that you can create your own and but i
don't think that's practical because you
know not very few people do it
and in emac this for example you don't
even you don't have reader markup okay
so in emac this
an enclosure this
you do not have
reader marker you know you it
it does not lets you change the define
reader marker okay
in e-mail
and in uh
closure lisp
i'm not sure what's the case with skim
lisp and i'm not and i but i do know you
can do that in common this however very
few people do it you know it's usually
just
yeah you you don't see that in real life
code yeah it's a it's a feature but you
don't see that
i would claim
you almost never see it basically you
never
you know practice practically speaking
you never see it
so anyway the
you know so anyway so that's
yeah so you do have comma escape
sequence so you know um
yeah so you have uh escape sequence like
slash n
backslash and backslash t
for tab backslash quote for escaping
double quote you you know if if you want
to know you can find a list of them uh
so
uh so let's just uh find language so
let's go back to um let's see uh where's
the documentation
okay so i need to turn on javascript
so this is all these are kind of
confusing but basically there's only one
product okay wufang language or
mathematica they are essentially the
same thing mathematica just refers to
the product you know with the
so you can do all these graphics um
but i want to go to the documentation
and
there it is
so uh yeah so what we are talking about
string so yeah string escape
oh yeah i need to turn javascript
so where is the um
properties of string special characters
uh with
a list
so we want to know a list of all the
escape sequences
you know wolfham language they have like
a million pages uh
it's fairly overwhelming um
i read you know anyway
anyway i don't want to get over you know
you can find it in a few minutes
let's go back to the wolfram language so
we covered stream
um
yeah i think maybe we uh let's do it
next time then
i mean so
yeah that's too bad i cannot finish
unless we go we take another hour
to let's do it um
let's do it
in a few days in my next youtube we'll
do we'll continue with
with others
kind of disappointing because this video
is not complete
um
so
ssp
so who are you
what's your discord name
show the discord name so i can um
show you the score name so i can bang
you hey justine do you have to pay to
use wufang language no it's free so but
you can buy it if you want i recommend
you or you can just download for free
for developers
for heart for you know for
for internal development you know read
their license agreement
so just and hey justin so do you think
wolfham notebook is great for math
taking notes yeah it's fantastic
okay i was going to um
we we kind of um
see how long 47 yeah that's it for today
so let yeah that's it for today we close
shut down in five minutes because i
cannot
cover the whole other things let's do
something fun okay
so uh
notes so
uh
type settings so let's show some uh
interesting things okay
let's say nest
a
function three times okay
next
we want to nest recursion basically the
function f with argument x and three
times so do it you see because language
is symbolic
so right now we don't have a definition
for f
but however it still works
because it just returns symbols but now
if you if you actually define f so let's
see let's define f okay
let's say define f uh let let's let me
do the full uh syntax so it's easy to
understand so let's say function
so it's a function of x
so and what you want to do um
let's say 1 over x okay
so that's a function
now if you evaluate
the recursion you know
recurse f 3 times the first argument
being x
you what you get
what
one wait
that's not uh did we this is correct
so what is f3
so what is if
ff3
what
oh it's a
oh yeah so it just invert yeah that's
yeah that's right if we say four
it's gonna be x that's right so this is
not a good function i want the nesting
the behavior is correct though but so
let's i want to define
let's say 1 over
square root of x
so we define a function
to be that 1 over square root of x
now let's do the nesting okay
so
three
f at three is that
repeated
repeated okay so
but now what if you give a symbolic
value let's say fx
let's say t okay
so you get a symbolic value
what if you repeat it twice
let's say uh t
let's say y okay
uh why is it the value
so anyway so let's try to repeat
uh
i don't you see what i want is i want
nesting i don't want it to simplify
right now it's simplifying because it's
similar it simplifies because the way
our function is is
works so let's
so let's prevent it
prevent it from having a simple
simplification by doing that okay so we
define function to be one over square
root of x plus one
so now
we evaluate
evaluate now you can see the nesting
evaluate fantastic
evaluate evaluate fantastic now evaluate
it because three times fantastic
okay
so that's so is it
yeah so it's great for uh type setting
okay automatic
any any question any other questions i
think that's it uh i think that's it for
today okay
yeah so thank you guys for watching uh
bye guys
i'm shutting down in two minutes
so there's a question about keyboard
well you have to um
question about keyboard
using my slot and keyboard is real
wide
can because of my mouse usage
elbow pen yeah i don't know it depends
on your situation you have to take a
photo and show a photo hey reason
so we have a lot of people watching
background watches so thank you guys
for checking in
from romania okay bye guys
you