Hello guys. Good morning. Welcome to
another episode of South Talk Show. Am I
alive? Yes, I am. Today is
March 17th, 2021.
And today we are going to do Doom Emacs.
There are a lot of people watching here
and I'm a little bit nervous. So, this
episode I'm going to try Doom Emacs for
the first time. And I know the guy Henry
uh wait, not Henry, the um Henrik
Listener is watching.
So, if I made if I'm stuck somewhere, uh
you guys uh please tell me, okay? Uh so,
we don't so I don't get stuck and and
we're going to go on. So, I think this
today is going to be uh
we'll be probably a longish 1 hour. I
hope so.
Because I haven't
uh I haven't tried uh Doom Emacs before
and uh
So, you know, I I know a lot of people
wants to watch this, you know, they want
to see drama. You know, they want to
see me get angry or stuff. Uh so,
anyway, I think it's fun to try it.
So, let's do it. Uh is there anything
else? Okay, so the background image, you
know, I was trying to look for a
background image, you know, uh and then
I found this one, the Doom Emacs logo,
okay? This this is So, this is from this
guy. I'm sorry I didn't uh get
permission before use. Uh so, this is a
Doom Emacs logo and there's a color
version, but let me show you the uh this
is a SVG file. So,
So, this fantastic. I I love this one. I
love this logo. And there's also a color
version. If you just search for Doom
Emacs,
uh I'm not I'm it's not showing up here,
but there's a uh color version.
So, this guy, who is this
uh
related
You know, I hate I hate people that who
doesn't put, you know, the author's name
right there clearly. But anyway,
thanks to this guy for the background
image.
So, Doom Emacs. So, let's do it and this
is SVG file, okay? It's fantastic. Um
Okay, let's do it.
Uh so, I'm going to try install Doom
Emacs from the ground up for the first
time and from scratch, okay? And we I'm
going to need to read a lot of the Doom
Emacs GitHub. I just I just try to read
it, you know, I so to get a sense
what what I have to do.
Uh so, Doom Emacs is a apparently a
Emacs, you know,
normally called distribution. So, you
install Doom Emacs, it got it got Emacs
and
all the packages you need. Uh and
apparently the the
uh standing, you know, the outstanding
feature
Yeah, that guy
Zazam Boni, but that's not, you know,
that's a nickname or, you know, his not
real name. But maybe he goes by that
name.
So, people think you are going stream a
video game, okay. So, we got 19 people
watching. So, comment, okay? Comment,
guys. I love you all comments, random
comments or questions.
So, Doom Emacs is a Emacs distro and
apparently the main feature, you know,
it's very fast. It's it contains all the
packages you need and it tries to not to
be, you know, force you into one way of
doing things. So, you can still
um
customize your Emacs
uh much. I think that's the gist and,
you know, it uses a lot new technology,
new to me, okay? New to this old
old coder.
Uh and I I haven't used Spacemacs
uh Spacemacs neither, so I, you know,
let's try it. Okay, so first of all, I
need to, according to the install
instruction, I need to uh let's magnify,
okay?
Uh mini- minimalistic, those are the
outstanding features. Uh so,
prerequisite prerequisite, you know, so
I got Git, I got Emacs 27 has uh I don't
have Ripgrep. I need to install it.
Let's install it Ripgrep now, okay?
PowerShell.
Okay, choco
uh info
Ripgrep.
Okay, there it is. Let's magnify
properties. Uh let's magnify, okay?
Yeah, unable to modify sure Oh,
it did it anyway, so let's install
Ripgrep. Oh, I need PowerShell admin,
okay? So, let's install PowerShell
admin.
Uh choco
install
Ripgrep.
Yeah.
Uh yes, no, yes, do it.
Do it.
Okay, that's uh Ripgrep. It's installed,
okay? Installed, then close it, so we
have um
close it.
Uh then you need GNU find. I don't I
don't like GNU find. Uh you know why?
Because
because once you install GNU find
then the it has problems launching VS
Code.
Uh
you know, long story, I'm not going to
going to talk about it, so
so GNU find uh info
find you tails, okay?
Yeah, that's the one, but let's not
install it for now. Optional FD. Now,
what is FD?
Improves file indexing performance for
some commands, okay? What is SD? Let's
have a look.
Uh SD SD is
FD, okay? FD is a program to find
entries in your file system. It's a
simple, fast, and blah blah blah
alternative to find, okay? It does not
aim to support all find commands. So,
apparently, it's a command line command.
Okay, so this I can install actually.
So,
you know, it's interesting to look into
at least
new technologies. So, first of all, let
me magnify the font.
Okay, so FD, so
let's see if it's here.
FD
Oh, there it is. So, apparently, this is
a popular this is a find GNU find
replacement, great.
So, how I should So, okay, so install
let's run the get
uh
right?
Let's install the get, okay?
So, where do I want to install? I mean,
not PowerShell, I mean the Doom Emacs.
So, get clone, let's see. Wait.
What What are these commands? So, get
clone depths one
uh from Doom Emacs, okay? So, download
it to my Emacs
uh
in a directory, then
then run this command to install Doom.
Okay, so
you know, there's some interesting
things going on. So, Doom apparently is
running some kind of shell script.
Uh usually, I don't like that.
So, okay, let's start E-shell again. So,
start E-shell. First of all, run this
command, okay?
Fatal destination path
uh
.emacs already exists, okay? Okay, so
let's uh let's fix that.
Emacs. So, here is my as you can see
So, here is my Emacs in it. I'm just
going to rename it
old.
Okay?
Done, okay? Close it.
Now, uh back to E shell.
Run the command.
Cloning it into Okay, it's done. So,
let's go back to
uh let's open my Emacs D. Let's see what
happens.
What?
A local variable list in uh contains
value may not be saved. What?
Uh
Git commit major mod Git commit elisp
text mod. Okay, so it's got
Okay, right now I'm trying to open my
Emacs
uh
in it directory. Okay, let's run it.
Let's open it.
Uh wait, this is not the one.
Open it. So, it's it's got some
directory uh variables that
runs the program, the local variable
list. Okay, so do I want to run it? No,
I want to look at it first.
Okay? So, now you can see now I'm in my
uh Emacs in it.
So, these are
uh Doom installed these.
So, let's you know, let's uh have a look
what what they are. So, being
Yeah.
It's asking uh you know, it's got some
Emacs variable in it. You know, don't
run it. I just want to look at it.
Okay, so Doom, so this one
is actually uh apparently a shell script
or something like that. Let's open it.
Yeah,
ignore.
Okay, so it's a shell script.
Uh it's running bash. Oh, man. I wonder
you fight would I Do I have would Would
I have problems if I try to install this
because I'm on Windows?
Uh
let's just search for Windows if it uh
says
Okay, so here is a line specific to
Windows.
Okay, I don't know if they are run or
not.
Uh
I know doing Emacs runs on Windows for
sure.
Probably, yeah. Um but
I don't know. So, core, let's look at
core. What's in core?
Core command line. Oh, okay. So, all
these are Emacs list files. So, Doom
Emacs has uh apparently some kind of
system of itself.
Um
Let's see. Don't evaluate.
Doom version constant Doom Doom, okay.
So, am I Am I doing good? Let's look at
the uh comments.
Okay, no comments.
25 people watching. Okay, no comments.
Comments, guys.
Okay, so
So, okay, I'm looking at the core uh
core Doom Emacs, I suppose. Uh it's got
it's got a module system for packages.
Uh I know it's using one of the latest
uh
Emacs
functional programming base package
system, something like that. It's not
using Melpa.
And by By way, yesterday uh there's an
interview of the author Henrik Lissner
by another guy. I posted, you know, you
can find it, you know, interview.
So, apparently
Henrik
he's been using Vim for 14 years. Then
he's switched to doing
you know, he started to code Doom Emacs.
Okay, so what am I going to do now? So,
now I got this um
I got this Doom Emacs Emacs in a
directory. So, apparently Doom Emacs
will run off of this in a directory.
Read me license probably GNU 3.
MIT license. Oh, that's interesting
because typically the Emacs commands
they insist on GNU
GPL or GPL 3.
So, MIT license is actually more free.
You are more free to do whatever.
So, what is this .md file? So, Doom
Emacs, okay, table of contents, okay,
this is just what we read in the GitHub
page.
So, modules, let's look at it.
Modules app checkers completion.
You know, this is what I usually do when
I want to install a program. I want to
know not, you know,
I as opposed to you know, just run
whatever, just install it and start to
use it. I usually want to know
what they put on my system and you know,
who wrote it and
things like that, you know, look at the
nature of the
thing.
So, you have modules config, okay,
default.
Okay, lots of Emac list files. Okay,
let's let's Okay, let's start to
actually install it.
So, back to Doom Emacs. So, now I
actually get cloned the thing. Now, I
need to run this uh um
Okay, untitled. Let's go back. So, I
need to run this line. So, what does
this line do? Okay, so it just called a
shell script doom install.
Okay, I have a question. So, that doom
This doom is a bash script. I mean, you
know, it's yeah, you know,
shell script not even bash, boon shell.
So,
would that run or do I need some kind of
do I need a sigwin? Never tried on
Windows. On Linux, I had to sync it
instead of using the normal package
system. Kind of weird.
Cist at least says
Uh so, I have you used the six keys
macro keypad from Tech Keys. What are
your thoughts? No, I haven't used that.
Today, we're going to talk about Doom
Emacs and just that, okay? Not keyboard.
Uh good morning, bot. So,
Now, I I run into
kind of question or problem because I
need to run this shell script, but
but I don't have bash, you know, I don't
have bash installed.
I don't have boon shell installed. So,
wait.
Wait. Wait, hold on a second. This is a
Emac Lisp file. Yeah.
Uh so, why is that why does the first
line you know, the shebang shebang
line says
that user been environment shell.
Okay, let's read.
Uh mod Emac Lisp lexical binding case
something, okay? That's the local
variables Emacs is asking me to run. No
such file script blah blah blah.
Uh
Emac launch the garbage collector isn't
as important during command line
operations. A higher threshold makes
something something. So, it's getting
serious. It's adjusting the garbage
collector, the Emacs garbage collector
stuff.
Uh prioritize
uh
known by compiler source files. Okay,
but so this is a Emac list.
So, this is a Emac list file. This is
not a boon shell script. Okay, let's
just follow the instruction, okay?
Follow the instruction. So, now go to
shell, paste that.
Let's hope it runs, okay? Enter.
Okay, user been environment not command
not found. So, what's what's going on,
guys? Do you guys have any suggestions?
Get the WSL2
to run the script. It's the best way on
Windows. Yeah, so
Okay, don't tell me I'm going to botch
the Doom Emacs
at this point just because I'm on
Windows. Because to install W, you know,
Windows Subsystem for Linux, that that's
going to take me 2 hours because
uh
25 people. So, anyone any any
suggestions on
how do I run this Doom install?
It Let's uh
Let's read, okay? So, install then read
our getting started guide to be walked
through installing configuration and
maintaining do do Emacs. Okay, okay,
hold on a second. Let me read
read the documentation to solve my
problems, okay? It doesn't mention
anything about Linux or Windows.
Uh okay, it's good idea to add Emacs
been to your path. Wait, but hold on a
second. What is that um
So, these are the commands.
Okay, hold on a second. Why is that
You know, wait wait. Go back to go back.
Okay, what
Okay, why is that
What is this in environment? Okay, so
I'm lacking in my Unix
know-how. So, what is this
being ENB?
Use a being ENB. I don't remember what
is what that is. Use a being ENB.
Okay, yeah. So, ENB is a shell command.
ENB is ENB is a shell command for Unix
and Unix-like operating systems. It's
used to either print a list of
environment variables. Okay.
Or run another utility in an altered
environment. Okay, I see. Without having
to modify the current existing
environment. Okay, so
So, basically it's it's going to call
shell.
Boom shell, but with a clean
environment, something like that.
Okay, but here
uh
In practice, ENB has another common use.
It is often used by shell script to
launch the correct interpreter. In this
usage, the environment is typically not
changed.
Okay, so it So, basically this line
means it actually want to run the boom
shell, not bash.
I suppose, am I correct?
But what I don't understand is that
you know, it says to run a shell script,
but the code is actually Emacs Lisp. Am
I
Okay, Luis Prado says there is a section
about Windows on the FAQ. Fantastic.
Thank you.
Try Doom
Doom.cmd. It's include with don't do
Emacs. Okay, great suggestions. Finally,
I'm passing this
uh
Okay, so
Okay, so now let's go back to
uh let's go back to the
FD we installed. So, there is a FAQ
about Windows and uh let's see how do we
solve this on Windows. First of all,
let's search for Windows. See what it
says. So, it doesn't mention anything
about Windows on the GitHub page.
Uh but
uh apparently FAQ, okay. So, let's open
that.
Frequently asked questions. Why is it
called Doom? Uh is it a fork of
Spacemacs or Prelude? No.
It's called Why is it called Does Doom
work on Windows? Oh, there it is.
Does Doom work on Windows? Click.
Click. Click. Click. No response. Damn.
GitHub needs JavaScript.
Okay, now it jumps to Wait, what? You
Normally, you shouldn't need JavaScript
to jump to a page.
Uh
Does Doom
work on Windows? Click. It does, but
there are caveats. Caveats. Emacs is
inherently slow on Windows, okay? There
are more steps to setting up Emacs and
Doom on Windows, okay? Windows support
we always lag behind. Yeah, yeah. Mac or
Linux, yeah. Because I many don't use
us, don't use Windows, okay? That means
uh fewer
uh guinea pig.
Something, something, something,
something. That said, Doom does have
happy Windows users.
Oh my god, using WSLs or scoop
chocolatey.
I'm sorry. I don't think I can finish
this. I I don't think I can continue
because to install Windows
uh subsystem for Linux.
You know, that's a big thing. That
you know, I don't want to just go there
and install it. You you know, in order
to install that, I'll have to take an
hour or you know, to carefully see
what's you know, options and so on.
So, it does work on Windows, but
requires Windows subsystem for Linux or
scoop and chocolatey.
I Okay, but I do have chocolatey. So,
maybe that work. The getting started
guide will walk you through what we
know. Okay. Okay.
So, at this point, doing Emacs is not
you know, we you know, let's say you
know, it's not Windows friendly, okay?
You can we can see that it's focused on
Linux users.
Uh you know,
for Windows, it's a second second rate
citizen.
So, you have to read getting started
guide to walk you through what we know,
okay? You know, I
I happen to use Windows now, you know,
uh
3 months ago, I was on a Mac, and before
I was on a Linux, but
Help. Uh okay, so
okay. Bummer.
So, let's see what um
Try doom.cmd.
It is included with Doom Emacs, okay?
So, let's try that.
Oh, there it is. There it is. The FAQ
didn't say that, okay? doom.cmd open
Okay, so there it is, doom.cmd
for the down doom script to Emacs, okay?
You know, this this this is what I don't
like about
Emacs distro that requires a shell to
install. You know, I noticed that's the
case for um
uh for
anything, you know, there's a package
helm, you know.
It's kind of strange you require shell,
you know, just do everything in Emacs
distro.
So, there's less of dependencies. You
know, I understand it's more
cumbersome.
But anyway, so
so I can run this, okay, um how do I run
this actually?
Yeah, I I need to command, you know.
Okay, so
you know, they
uh it's probably a good thing to also
have a PowerShell version because these
days PowerShell, you know, command
uh dot exe is getting obsolete. You want
to use PowerShell. So, how do I run um
command exe? I haven't you know, the
Windows prompt.
Okay, so there is command exe.
And uh how do I run this? Okay, so let's
see.
Yeah.
Okay, so uh install. Okay, so first of
all, CD to my directory. CD to
users xah
dot
Emacs, okay? CD to
bin
Okay. Duh.
Then run
run doom dot cmd.
Now, normally I would take my time to
read, you know, what what it is running.
But, uh okay, let's have a look. Forward
the dot doom script to emax.
Set arc set command shift. Okay, let's
just run it.
Let's read,
uh
command will just frustrate you. Yeah, I
know about. Okay, so let's run it.
Ah.
Dot is not recognized as internal. Wait.
What the
Is it backslash or
Yeah, okay, let's try it.
Ah, emax is not recognized as internal
or external command. Okay, so
I kind of know what is the problem. So,
it's trying to run
So, this
command dot exe script, uh batch script
is actually just a wrapper.
So, it's actually running, you see, it's
running
this command, start emax.
So, okay, at this point I cannot
you know, I have to manually install it.
I have to look at So, basically it's uh
telling me to run emax. You know, I
don't have run emax as part of my
environment uh path.
executable path. So, start run emax Q
uh Q means no in it, nothing, then
arguments.
Okay, install.
The argument should be installed then
L
then init
el then F doom run or startup
hooks.
Okay, so is this
Wait, how how is this is this this is
actually installation, right?
I mean so far I don't have it installed
yet.
I should have known I mean I should have
read up before
to know that I need
to run this on Linux system or install
the Windows Linux sub subsystem for
Linux first. So introduction, features,
install.
Yeah, so this actually
install things.
Uh let's read the comments. Does Choco
not add Emacs into path like scoop?
Uh Choco does, but I didn't install
Emacs via Choco. I installed Emacs in my
uh manually basically.
Uh you can see
Wait, what?
Bookmark bookmark change on disk. Okay,
I
you know I
It says bookmark change on disk because
I swapped out all my init files.
So right now I don't have my bookmarks.
Uh so in my download folder you can see
here is my Emacs.
So my Emacs is just in my download
folder. So
So actually I can modify this. Let's try
this, okay?
Start run Emacs. make a backup first.
You know, instead of
let's let's try to
mess with it.
Now
now replace backslash by
always backslash is right. So copy that.
Paste it here.
backslash
So I have my full path to run Emacs.
Okay, maybe that work.
I hope so. I don't know.
So if command equals to run oh,
okay. So if command equals to run
otherwise.
Now where is the command?
I don't you know, I don't know.
I don't know command.exe
you know, the batch script
that much. So let's just try it again.
Please no Emacs is not recognized. Oh,
yeah. So it's you know, it's looking for
Emacs. Okay, so
let's copy this again.
Save.
Okay, so let's do it again.
doom.command
Oh, installing straight
fantastic.
Installing straight now straight.el is
the new
Emacs package
system.
Based on declarative.
uh,
configuration or something like that or
functional programming. So, installing
straight cloning use package. So, looks
like it's fantastic. A command line
interface for managing Doom Emacs.
Include package management management
uh, usage Doom a command line line
interface for managing Doom Emacs
include package management diagnostics,
unit test, byte compilation. This tool
also makes it trivial to launch Emacs
out of different folder or with a
different private module. So,
environment Emacs the
So, is it actually
setting my environment variables?
Uh, normally I don't like that.
Emacs the Okay, so
So, anyway, looks like
it installed Doom Emacs. Let's shrink.
Let's see what happened. Update.
Go up a directory. Shrink.
Uh,
um,
So, what is going on now? So,
So, let's look at init.el. Let's see
what's there. Oh, Doom. So, here is the
Doom Emacs
um, logo.
Okay.
In a strange case that early init.el
wasn't loaded, you are using uh,
chemacs.
Or you are loading this file directly.
We do it explicitly. Okay.
So, Doom initialize, that's the command.
Let's see describe function Doom
initialize. It's probably not loaded
yet. Okay.
So, this is the Emacs in it.
Now, the next question is how do I start
Doom Emacs?
It seems at this point you can just
start Emacs and you'll be fine.
So, let's see. Run install. I already
installed. Then read our getting started
guide to
to be walked through installing
configuration. Okay, so
getting started guide. Let's open that.
Okay, getting started guide. Okay, this
is a big page.
Venturing into actual use of Doom Emacs,
you know, how it differs. So, GNU Emacs
is one grand old adventure, let alone
Doom Emacs. Before you start, you'll
need to set up Emacs, Doom, and its
packages. Then learn how to take care of
your new puppy operating system. This
guide will walk you through installing,
using, configurate configuration, and
troubleshooting all all these things.
Okay.
Okay, so
Oh, so here is actually the full
uh detail about installing on Windows.
Okay, so
uh
Oh, it requires also LLVM.
That is, you know, that's a huge thing.
Scoop uh chocolaty. Okay, Install Git,
Emacs, Ripgrep, uh FD, uh
with precompiled binary, Git plus Bash,
okay.
So, let's just run it then. Let's um
So, I already installed
the Doom utility, okay. So, this is the
Okay, Doom sync. This synchronize your
config with Doom Emacs, okay. So, this
You know, these are not standard Emacs.
This is just part of the Doom Emacs
thing.
Doom help, so you got all that. Install
Doom manually. Oh, so here is how to
install manually.
Okay, I don't know what is Chemacs.
Update and rollback. Okay, so it's a bit
complex. You can update, and then you
can even rollback.
Of downgrading, migrate, then configure.
Configure Doom. How do I start? I just
want to start it. Module, package menu
management, installing packages.
Okay, so
disabling package. Wait, how do I begin?
How do I start Doom Emacs?
Oh, wait. So, it's um
it's actually
set here, I think.
Oh, yeah, here. Help, install, sync,
environment, upgrade, build, purge.
Now, is there
Do I just type Doom to start it?
Okay, no no comments. I I got 32
I've
I've got 32 Doom Emacs fans watching me
struggle probably.
So right now I think I installed Doom
Emacs. How do I
Uh
Okay, and and now I'm in command.exe. I
don't know how to use command.exe.
Uh
and there is no Doom start.
Okay, so at this point let me just try
to start Emacs.
Let's just start Emacs my usual way and
see what happens.
Okay.
Yeah.
Run Emacs.
Okay, warning.
Okay, so warning.
Now, how do I magnify the font? Oh god.
Warning, an error occurred while loading
init.el. Error in Doom Emacs core. Doom
is in an incomplete state. Run Doom sync
on the command line to repair it.
Why is that?
To ensure no violation you should
investigate. Okay, yeah.
Okay,
at this point I'm stuck with the Doom
kind of installation.
Why? Because mostly because it's more
Linux oriented, you know, it doesn't
have
if I may say, it doesn't have smooth
installation for Windows. Or unless I'm
on a Windows, you know, Linux on, you
know, Cygwin or something.
So, right now it says
um
basically my installation is not
complete or something or incomplete
state.
But, why is it incomplete state?
And see.
I thought I ran this correctly.
Oh, you have to call install, don't you?
Wait.
What? Uh
Let's see.
Oh, yeah. There it is. Okay, my mistake.
So, let's go back to Doom install.
Generate an environment variable file.
See Doom help ENV for detail.
Generate a environment variable help.
Yeah, sure.
You see, this uh this problematic
probably Unicode or something control
characters not showing correctly.
Uh generate environment
variable file. Okay, yes.
Okay, fine finally I'm installing it.
So, you are watching me
uh kind of go through the process and my
experiences of installing Doom Emacs.
So, finally
it's installing.
How long have I been talking?
45 minutes already. Okay. We don't we
didn't
we don't get to um
to the fun part of starting to explore
Doom.
Okay, it's actually running quite a few
things. Build building helpful
building stuff. Clone Elist some
something.
Oh.
Cloning Cloning smart parents.
Uh projectile, it's installing
projectile package. It's installing a
bunch of Emacs packages. Company for
name completion. Swiper
another completion. Ivy heat hydra,
which is a key binding
thing.
AMX
Uh that's the
uh that's execute extended command
replacement.
Installing console projectile. Okay,
projectile with console interface.
Installing Ivy rich, installing W grab,
installing themes, installing
solar solar themes.
Installing Doom mod line, installing
Anzu. I don't know what that is. Evil
Anzu, installing evil.
Installing Git gutter fringe for
decoration. Installing perspective mod
for what it what that is, I forgot.
Installing evil.
Uh it's very evil. Lots of evil stuff.
Evil embrace, evil escape.
Evil exchange.
So, what's up with you guys?
Justin Scofield, hi. Justin, so is using
Doom here?
I got 35 people watching. That's
probably that's the most I've got while
doing this live.
Could it be optimized much? It's insane
how much bloatware is getting installed.
I wouldn't say that because the Doom
Emacs author is watching.
You know, it's a Emacs distribution, so
that's what it meant to be. You know,
the whole it's installing, you know, the
whole thing so that
uh so that, you know, you have
everything or you know, like IDE.
Oh, it's installing a lot evil packages,
but I don't use evil, you know.
So, I'm going to once after
installation, I'm going to run Doom.
Then, I'm going to try probably try to
uh install C-c-l-i-k-e-y-s.
But, I suppose I won't have time today.
It'll be I'll be
It'll be great if if I can just start
Doom Emacs today because I've already
been talking for 45 minutes.
Okay, install evil vimish, install auto
wide snippet, lots of packages. Don't
install Doom swin snippet, install tired
um
FD
tired RSync Oh my god, installing a lot
packages and do full session.
Get commit, magit
get time machine
flycheck
So, the last time I ran, you know, I
also wrote a Emacs distro like 10 years
ago from starting around 2008 to
uh 2012.
Uh that was Ergo Emacs. So, you know,
the Emacs distro is the purpose of that
is that so beginners can download it and
have everything set up. You know,
including all the languages smart for
all the different languages and so on.
So,
and of course there's a lot work. I can
see
Do Do Emacs, you know, it's
but
but Ergo Emacs doesn't have all these
things. But back then, you know, back
then, like 10 years ago, you don't have
there's no Emacs package. There's no
Melpa or Elpa yet. So, Elpa began about
10 years ago. So, that is when
you know, thou tens of thousands
packages become, you know, all over all
over people start to write them.
But before that, like 10 years ago, you
have to
you know, you just search the Emacs
wiki.
And you don't have build scripts like
that.
So, okay, it's still installing. Oh my
god, this installing tons of things.
This must be at least
over a hundred packages. Now, let's look
at um
Let's look at modules, okay?
Modules, okay, it's installing Okay,
installation done. Finished.
Have fun.
Okay, it says finished. Doom is ready to
go. But before you Doom yourself, here
are some things you should know. One,
don't forget to run Doom sync. Then
restart Emacs after after modifying
uh any file, okay?
Two, if something goes wrong goes wrong
wrong wrong, run Doom doctor, okay? It's
pretty fancy. It even got a diagnose
got diagnostic script that is very
complex as far as I can
you know, those kind of thing are very
complex. Doom doctor
diagnostics.
Uh
three, use Doom upgrade to upgrade Doom,
okay? I'm not going to do it today.
Access Doom's documentation from within
Emacs
uh by pressing space HD Okay.
Okay, so I have now I have Doom
installed.
Okay, now let's see, let's look at the
packages it includes.
Okay, so
so this is the package structure of
Doom.
Uh calendar, well, you know, lots of
packages. So, let's go up one directory.
Refresh.
Uh okay. So, let's see how many package
are there. So, I'm going to go up
um
uh to the PowerShell and include.el.
Get-ChildItem Name Recurse include.el.
Let's see how many
packages. Okay, now let's see, can we do
count?
I'm not too familiar with PowerShell
yet, so WC should do it.
Okay, uh measure something.
Measure-Object.
Okay, so 518 packages.
So, here are all the packages Doom Emacs
installed.
Okay, I'm ready to start doing Emacs.
Now.
Okay, so now
let's close this window. So, this is my
This is my old Emacs.
Let's start Emacs
from
the way I know it. Okay.
Hope that runs.
Fantastic.
Doom Emacs, that's what I'm doing here
today for. Doom Emacs. So, I got Doom
Emacs to run on Windows after, you know,
some
uh
obstacles.
So, first of all, uh first thing is that
this is the font is too small. I'm
getting old. So, how do I
Oh.
Well,
how do I magnify the font? Well, first
of all, I don't have the menus.
The The Doom Emacs the tech nerds, you
know,
Henrik.
Uh they removed menus. So, I'm, you
know, wait. Yeah, so how do I magnify
the font? I don't know. So,
So, if I don't know have the menu, then
the alternative is to call meta X. Okay,
so meta X
Let's try.
Con-
uh alt X
Oh, there it is. Okay.
Uh now the command to magnify font is
uh
Now, I don't remember what's the command
to uh
magnify. I mean, to magnify Let's
search, okay? Control H I'll just use
what I know of GNU Emacs and let's try
in Doom.
Control H A. Okay.
I'm I'm running a propos, so search for
font.
Okay, no. Let's try again.
Control C
Control
H
then A, okay, then type font.
Hey, it doesn't show much. Okay, let's
try again.
Meta X
a p r o p o s apropos then type font.
There it is. Now, finally
I have all these
Okay.
Control X 1 to expand.
Now, control
um
control plus. Let's see if that magnify
font. It doesn't. Okay, so I have to
find the font command to
um
Oh, doom adjust font size. So, doom has
its own. Click on that.
Uh okay, that's too much. I don't know
how to use it.
Now, there you know, Emacs by itself has
a um
a command to increase font size, but I
don't remember what's the command name.
That's why we are looking at this.
You know, I want to increase the font so
I can see and you guys can actually see.
Uh I don't know. So, let's first of all
Uh
what?
Uh okay, so first of all, let's go to my
own Emacs tutorial so that
so that um
So that we can see what's the command
for enlarging font, okay? Search for
font.
Uh best Unicode font. Okay, yeah.
Emacs you need
font setup.
Test Okay, so the command is called
text-scale-adjust.
Okay, now we uh we go back to Doom.
Alt-X
text-scale
adjust. Okay?
Call that again. Hey.
Call that again.
You know, I'm a bit clumsy here because
I don't know
the Doom key uh
how to use Doom yet.
Now, control H B should show my buffers.
Uh no, it doesn't.
Control H control B.
Uh control H control B is undefined.
Okay.
Control X B.
Okay, the font is too small.
Uh the font is too small.
So what is the
So we are back to the Doom screen.
Uh it doesn't
So adjust text font size is just uh l-
buffer local. It it's not global.
So anyway, I got Doom to run. So
So the next step is obviously to study
Doom
how do you study like documentation?
Uh and look at this this are probably
Unicode but it's not showing on Windows.
So open documentation let's try that.
Okay it's
it's again too small.
Okay okay I think maybe that's it for
today because
because you cannot see me too much you
know I need to
increase font the globally so I can read
it myself.
Any comments?
Space TB okay let's try this space TB.
Fantastic Doom big font modding able.
Space TB
space TB fantastic.
Okay now I've finally we are somewhere.
Uh
Oh change font
accidental emoji as funny as accidental
tab so
So Doom Emacs space TB
Uh wait space TB wait can't find B
what's going on?
Space TB
space TB
space TB okay.
I want it larger though but I don't know
how to do that. Let's try control U
space TB.
No it doesn't work.
I mean the standard way is in Emacs
plain Emacs is control U
to give a argument space TB.
Wait space TB.
Okay.
Doom Emacs configuration framework for
GNU Emacs tailored for Emacs bankruptcy.
Blah blah
documentation, release notes. Okay.
Okay, so here is Doom Emacs. Let's try
to but how do I use it? Because let's
try my um,
you know, GNU Emacs standard command.
Let's open my website. So control X
control F
that's for opening a file.
Uh, and I want to open
web
Ergo Emacs
um,
uh, Emacs
blog. Okay, let's see. There it is.
Do I tap or what?
Okay, so
here is my Emacs blog. You can see.
Okay, so Doom Emacs doesn't support
shift select. I press shift and arrow.
It does not seems to work.
So how do you select? Let's try control
space. Okay.
Let's try control space. Okay, control
space
selection works.
Okay.
Now, am I
So by default it's using evil mod,
right? So
can I get into command mode or
something? Let's try.
Type J. Oh, I am. Okay. So J for go
down.
Uh,
JH
um, you know, I'm using war out
keyboard, so I forgot. I don't use V
much.
Uh so I don't remember.
Anyway, I remember it's J H uh and uh
How do you do this? Okay, mistake.
Control Z for undo. Wait.
Yeah, what?
God.
Control G.
Yeah, control
back slash undo. Okay, that still works.
Okay, Doom Emacs is installed and I'm
looking at my own uh web page. Let's go
to Dired, okay? Let's try Dired.
So technically, I should spend time to
read how to use Doom Emacs. Oh,
everything is colored.
So what might what um
So I don't think it's It might be using
Dired plus mod.
But uh it doesn't say.
Okay.
Okay,
Voon Voon Not says evil is enabled by
default. So you must type press V to
enter visual mod.
Okay, but anyway, space space H
I mean uh control H also works without
visual mod.
So anyway, I think that's it for today.
I mean at least
I got
you know, I got Doom Emacs to run. But
however, I'm not able to give you
like my
comment
commentaries on how it is because there
are apparently there are quite a lot of
things to learn.
You know, like I cannot use it
with just knowing playing new Emacs.
Almost. Let's see.
Control X B to switch buffer.
Now control X control B to list buffer.
Okay, now control X O to to switch my
focus point.
Okay, let's go back to Doom.
Okay, so Doom
open document, open private
configuration,
jump to bookmark, open project, recently
opened files, over agenda, open
documentation.
Yeah, so I need to read the
documentation. There's a lot.
So it's using evil mode by default.
Okay, I think that's about it today.
Uh
You press control Z. I'm Doom author by
the way. Oh, oh, right.
V not V not is the Doom author.
I recognize the logo but late.
So
uh
it you know, V not is the Henrik
Lissner.
Uh
E- evil is enabled by default. Okay, so
right. Uh let's see what's interesting.
Any any any thing interesting comments?
I
uh because I think that's it for today.
Um I talked about I talked for over 1
hour, just 1 hour 6 minutes and that's
So anything interesting I can try. Uh
uh
Henrik, can you like tell me something
fun or something
um
you know, or some special features of
doing Emacs or something like something
I should
something quick I can read or uh you
know, I can
uh do with doing doing Emacs.
Uh space bar is where all the Doom
options are. Okay, so I know that Doom
Emacs has uh
this
you know, leader key system which is
part of uh
you know, I think it's uh
it's derivative. I mean, it came from
evil mode or something which I
eventually adopted in soft light keys.
So, in order to call, you know, the key
binding for commands is you know, you
just press space.
Then, you have all these commands. Okay,
so space
O is for open, P is for project.
Q is for quit session.
Okay, okay. So, this is much Okay, so
you have to learn
all these key bindings. Uh switch
buffer, switch to last buffer, buffer
jump to bookmark.
Okay, fantastic.
So, um what's new?
You're welcome. Making Doom install less
opinion opinionate opinionated and
easier to Windows. Okay, so so Vina says
he'll try to work on Doom install less
opinionated and easier. Yeah, I guess
That's great. Thank you. So, I mean, I
guess that's uh you know, making things
work
in Windows
is one of the way uh to increase your
use user base. I mean, even though, you
know, many of the Emacs people,
including me, I don't you know, I don't
like Windows.
But for reasons I have, you know,
for for one reason is that, you know, if
you want to play games, you have to be
on Windows. Right, but you you play a
lot of games, right? I mean, uh I I
listened to your interview uh in last
video like it it looks like you played a
lot of games, Doom
and all that.
So, don't you have to use Windows a lot?
I mean,
uh
So, I think okay, we're going to shut
down I think we're going to shut down in
5 minutes. So, guys, just say uh and
Henrik say whatever, okay?
Say what whatever you want to say and
uh and we shut down in 5 minutes.
So, Doom Emacs for myself, you know,
I I'm not likely to use it, you know,
I'm doing this show, you know, for show
because a lot of people like to see it,
but you know, because I'm getting old,
you know, I've been using Emacs for a
long time myself.
Uh I'm getting old, so
you know, I want to
you know, it's not likely I'll use I
never tried Spacemacs Spacemacs um and
uh no,
you know, I have my own system, so
you know,
too old to spend time to investigate
uh another Emacs system.
That's for me, you know, that's just for
me.
Uh but many of for many of you uh and
also many of my uh watchers, you
probably you know, you guys are younger.
In fact, I learned Doom Emacs, you know,
I heard of it like almost like seven
seven or 10 years ago. You know, and uh
I never tried it. I No No, you know, I
never tried it. So,
I heard people, you know, from my uh
Discord, you know, saying great things
about Doom Emacs. And I also heard
uh people in Emacs
uh San Francisco meetups saying great
things about uh you.
Amrik. So, and yesterday So, yesterday
one of the uh guy, William, in the on
Discord mentioned, you know, posted your
interview video. And I thought, "Oh,
that's interesting." So,
So, So, thank you for, you know, thank
you for uh creating Doom Emacs, which uh
gives another uh
you know, different perspective,
different, you know, different
environment for Emacs users.
Uh so, uh re games. Yeah, but I have a
second Windows PC for gaming. Oh, okay.
A second window for PC and gaming.
Uh
Yes, and they asked you if you want evil
installed or not. Right now, it
installed evil. Okay. So, yeah.
Evil, I never actually tried to
uh learn it neither. So, anyway, let's
let's show Doom, not Wait, where is my
Doom window?
Uh
What?
What? What? What? Oh, okay. So, this one
close.
Okay. So, let's uh let's go back. Let's
space. Let's Let's run Let's uh switch
buffer, okay?
Space
uh less than sign
and um
Let's see. Type M.
E. Oh, so you can switch buffer by just
typing. So, let's try again.
Space,
comma.
Space, comma.
Um
switch to workspace buffer. Okay, so
there is also workspace buffer.
index.org
So, actually
space, okay, space less than equal sign.
I want to switch to Doom.
Okay, now I want to magnify
the pen. Okay, so space
um
Okay, normally in Emacs is control X 1.
Okay, that's your works. So, control H K
then control X 1.
So, I can see the documentation for this
uh select
select other windows. Is that's a
command. So, what are the keys? Okay, so
so apparently Doom Emacs also changed
the format of this page. So, let's show
control X 1.
So, this is the Emacs online help for
this command delete window delete other
window.
Uh normally it will also show key
binding. Okay. Okay, so key bindings.
Okay, Doom Emacs map W C O.
Okay, let's try.
First of all, let's split. Okay, uh
wait.
Global map. Okay, so
so there's
uh control a few key maps. So, it's
getting complex because I don't know
evil mod. So, evil mod
doom leader map. Let's try that. Okay,
first of all,
control X 2 to split the window.
Uh wait, does that work? Control X 2.
Control X 2.
Wait. Where is it? Okay, so actually
it's split into three panes.
Now,
W control O. Wait.
Uh
W
control O.
No.
Wait. Space W control O.
That's that seems to be the one.
Space W control O.
Okay, thank you guys. That's it for
today. Thank you thank you
V not for doom emacs and uh
Bye guys.
I shut down in
30 seconds or so.
I think you want C W C O.
C W C O.
Oh, okay. Let's delete all the window.
Now, I want to switch buffer to the doom
dashboard. Now, this is this is the This
is the fun
image.
So, you could also change the leader key
by changing the Doom leader key.
Okay, another thing I noticed, there is
no
uh scroll bar.
Doom
Doom is the hackers the hackers uh
uh set up.
Recently opened files, okay, let's open
that. Okay, so yeah, there's no
uh
s- vertical scroll bar. So, how do I
No, it it's not Also, the mod not the
mod line is also modernized, so you
don't see the you know, the old ugly mod
line.
But, usually the mod line says, you
know, what percentage Oh, there it is,
in the middle.
So, I'm at line 50.
So,
uh
Okay.
Bye, guys.