Hello. Good evening. Good evening. Good
evening.
Good evening everyone. We are going to
code
cascading style sheet.
Uh welcome to another episode of Sound
Talk Show.
So, we're going to do cascading style
sheet, okay? So, we're going to Let me
show you what we're going to do. So,
we're going to draw you can you can you
see there is a uh very faint diamond
grid, you see?
Those are parallel lines crossing each
other. It's a square grid, but rotated
45°. So, you got diagonal lines, you
see? So, this is done in
cascading style sheet entirely, just
this code, okay?
And we're going to do today we're going
to draw parallel lines. So,
you know, so you're going to know how
it's done. We're going to draw parallel
lines horizontal and vertical.
Then we're going to uh create a
rectangular grid by mixing them.
Then you just rotate it 45°. That that's
how you get this diamond grid.
Uh then we're going to do polar grid.
Polar grid, the way you do it is you
have a radio uh
a radio gradient, okay, in CSS. I'm
going to show you radio gradient. Then
you're going to have a conic gradient,
which is a sweeping lines, okay?
Like a clock, okay? So, radio gradient
is like a circles, concentric circles
and uh okay. It's easier to show you uh
but we're going to do it, okay? So, uh
you have here is radio gradient. So,
let's
uh change color, rainbow color, let's
say five colors, six colors, and make it
top left center. So, here you see
circles, random color. So, that those
are radio gradients, okay?
And uh what is conic gradient? Now now
radio radio gradient is very old, like
10 years ago, more than 10.
Uh and but
last week I learned about conic
gradient. This is also old by now, 10
years old, but I didn't know about it.
So, conic gradient is like a sweeping
lines, like a clock, okay? So, you can
you have a you know, they it creates pie
chart, which we did yesterday.
So, all these are conic gradients, okay?
So, we did uh
we did pie chart yesterday uh
repeating conic gradient. Okay, so uh
so, you can also have repeat and we did
pie chart. So, there.
We did this yesterday and uh then you
also have color wheel, I mean, like
spinning wheel animation. Fantastic,
amazing CSS, cascading style sheet,
okay? And today, we are just going to do
um so, you know about
conic gradient
and
the radio gradient and when you combine
them, you can great create a polar grid.
Now, do you guys know what a what what
is a polar grid? Polar grid is a
concentric circles then lines crossing,
you know, from the center.
Okay, so that is what we going to code.
So, let's begin, okay? So, let's begin
uh just if you are here, say hi, okay?
I'm just code uh in Emacs, my supreme
power of Emacs and if you don't know
already, I'm using soft light keys, the
most powerful key binding system in the
universe.
Uh
4,000 lines of code, soft light keys, go
to the top and you can go to this URL
showing browser and you can get it for
free for Emacs users. So, it's more
efficient than Vim, NeoVim, etc., you
know, uh so, uh
I have like tens of videos talking about
this and introduction and install and so
on.
Okay?
So, no need introduction today. So, now
let's start talk show, okay? So, let's
do parallel lines and diamond, okay? So,
let's go there.
Uh wait, what are we great? Yes, great,
great. Yes, go there. Showing bars.
Uh
Wait, why is this slow, you know?
Now it's super slow. What process is
using the disk? You see, because just
10 minutes ago, the
Microsoft, they started to do a update.
So, when whenever it begin update, the
the Windows like mobile installer
max out the disk usage and the system
become
non-responsive.
So, I don't know what what what is going
on. Anti-malware
service.
Okay.
Okay, let's get back, okay? Parallel
lines. So, let's do parallel lines,
okay?
Search for
parallel. So, let's first of all do
horizontal, let's say.
Okay, so horizontal parallel lines to
do. Yeah, we are doing it. So, can you
see? Yes, insert insert a class and
let's say parallel, okay? Let's just say
that and make it that and
and go to the top. We need to insert the
style. We already have it for the
diamond grid. Where is the diamond grid?
Yeah, diamond grid is
is for that.
And now, yeah, so let's go up. So,
pop this out.
Paste Wait. What?
What did I paste? Parallel, okay. So,
copy that, paste, cut the parallel,
paste the parallel So, paste the
parallel. So, that's a class name.
So,
So, what you're going to do? So, the
parallel line we we just going to have a
simple parallel line. So, so you don't
need variables, okay? So, you need a
background image. That's right. Just one
of them. So, delete that. Delete that.
And what is the property you need?
Parallel. So, you need repeating linear
gradient, okay?
Degree zero, okay? So, because we want
we want So, by default it goes uh
from
top to down, okay?
So, let's see. Uh
Uh So, let's see. Let's say black.
White, black zero, white zero. Uh
transparent transparency
Uh
What is this?
Let's say
Uh
Let's just say that, okay? Let's see how
it goes. Height and width, okay? You
need width and let's say 200, okay?
Height
200, margin, padding five, okay?
Clean the code, format it.
Uh then close that, showing browser.
Do we have parallel lines? We do, but
they are gradients. As you see, this is
not perfect. So, we need to fix that.
If you are here, say hi, okay? So, now
let's uh fix that. So, parallel cut move
to the top, okay? Now, you want you see
the issue is that you see right now they
are gradient, so they go from black to
gray to white in a gradual manner. What
you want is a sharp change. You don't
want the gradient. So, how do you do
sharp change? Well, what you do is you
um what do you do is kind of a hack
well, it's not a hack. You you you make
the color change.
You make the color start point
to be at the same place. So, for
example,
start black, then white, then
uh then black,
okay?
Uh let's see. I'm not
I'm not sure. So, check. Okay, you got
nothing.
So, you want white the key. Okay, so
check. Something like that.
Refresh. No.
Okay. Uh
yeah, I think your syntax is wrong. Is
it must they be in one line? Is that
right?
Do it. No. Okay.
Can there be a space after?
Oh, so we learned something interesting.
You see this
um you see this repeating linear
gradient. If you have a space there,
that won't work, okay?
That's the syntax. You see right now we
don't have a space, you know?
So, repeating linear gradient is a
function. So, in other words, function
you know, function begin with the
parent, right? After the function name.
But
in CSS, if you if you um you see if you
reload, it works fine. But if you
introduce a space back to browser,
refresh,
it up. Okay. So, in CSS function
name
cannot have a space after the function
name. And okay, I didn't know that.
Uh which is not true in I believe in
most programming languages. You can have
a space after function name then but
nobody does that. Anyway, so repeating
linear gradient. Okay, so uh what So,
what is the um
uh what is the Okay, so
uh so you need to figure this out. So,
start from 0°.
Uh let's say 90°. Okay. What is that?
Right, 0. So,
uh by default it is
Yeah, by default it's going from top to
bottom, I believe. So, why don't we
check uh repeating linear gradient.
Um
Did I say by default which way direction
it goes? Top to bottom, I believe.
So, check linear gradient. So, yeah.
Direction
Default is to bottom. That's right. So,
the
the default direction is uh let's see.
See, random direction, rainbow colors,
random direction, random direction,
random direction, rainbow colors.
Let's make it six colors, random colors.
And uh direction let's change, you see.
So, by default it's top to bottom. That
means by CSS that means uh
180°. Okay.
CSS is kind of weird. Anyway, so
let's just get this done, okay? So,
uh
So,
So, by default, top to bottom, that's
fine.
And start with black.
And then uh then you want
Then you want a black
at 30 pixels, okay?
Then start white at 30 pixels.
What Wait, what What is it you want to
do exactly?
You want uh you see, now it's no good.
Uh
Okay, so you have to think about this a
little bit tricky.
Hello.
Hello, I day.
I hope your channel grows, man. You
seems like a nice guy. Thank you.
Thank you. I don't know.
I'm a nice guy. Yeah.
Okay, so
uh so let's see.
You want
uh let's
Okay, so you want um
So, begin with a zero, then
then start at
the uh so
wait, begin at zero, then
then white begins at
Okay, so we need to do this.
>> Okay, so what
you format, so begin at zero pixel. Then
add how many pixels? So you let's say 10
pixels per line. 10 is too small. Uh
20, okay? 20 pixels.
Uh
so add 20 pixels dot
black and in fact
20 pixels white.
So
uh let's say 10, okay? So 10 is easier
to
understand what's going on.
So
Okay, so for now let's see black
and black at 10 pixels, then at 10
pixels
white.
Uh
God, this is
So start white. Start white or black?
And then let's begin with black.
How many pixels you want the line to be?
Just one, okay?
So black
and then here black one. Then
then
uh white one pixel.
Then
uh white nine 10 pixels, okay?
Uh
Okay, let's try that.
Go back here, refresh. Fantastic and
beautiful. One shot coding and it's
correct.
Okay, so let's make it two pixels uh
width, okay? And this instead of 10
let's say 20.
Refresh. Exactly, that's what we want,
okay?
That's what we want. Let's keep it.
Perfect code.
Okay, so here's the code how to do it.
Uh parallel.
Let's say let's keep it, okay?
So that's what we want. Perfect. Pop it
out a CSS. Prettify it.
Oh, yeah, okay, that's good. Uh width
200, yeah, yeah, so that's the code.
Okay?
Good.
Copy.
Close. Now go to the parallel section.
Uh paste the code so people can see CSS.
Paste.
Showing browser. Fantastic. You see the
code. Back to Emacs. Sync task color at
showing browser. Fantastic. That's
parallel lines one thing do. Done, okay?
So cut cut cut cut cut. Go to the top.
Make a new section. Paste and go to
delete the time created show. That's
parallel lines in one section. Now next.
Uh so that's horizontal. Now let's do a
vertical one, okay? Cut paste. Paste and
uh
Vertical pipe parallel lines, okay? Now
let's just say XV parallel, okay?
Now the code um
well, we don't
the code we are just go to uh here and
add it, okay? So
copy paste and go back here.
Make XV parallel. V for vertical, okay?
Now,
vertical is easy, trivial. In fact, you
just say 90 degrees because you want the
you want the gradient direction to be
pointing to the right. So, you say 90
deg. That means degree, okay? Close it.
Now, go back to browser. If we refresh,
we shall see it.
Do it.
Fantastic and beautiful.
Okay? So, that is done. Once you got one
thing going, everything is smooth.
Smooth sail. Paste it.
Syntax color it all. Show in browser.
Fantastic. Cascading style sheet
tutorial. Parallel lines and vertical
parallel lines. That's right. Next,
we're going to create a rectangular
grid, okay? Or, also known as a grid.
Uh okay. Mhm, to do. Yes, and we are
doing it. So, we don't need to do tag.
So,
um well,
in this case, uh rectangular grid, okay?
So, you need to
create a div.
Create a class.
And the class name will be X rec grid.
Fantastic.
Shrink it.
Copy it.
Go to the style section at top. Pop it
out. Go down here. Paste it.
And we are going to copy some code here.
And dot, okay? Class rec
grid.
Okay.
Now, in this case, we are going to
combine
both of these. Combine them.
How? Well, because the background image
can take more than one image. You see,
this repeating linear gradient or any
other gradient, they
actually creates a image
by the
by the CSS spec. You know, in other
words, the CSS output of those
gradient are actually images. I mean, of
image type. If you read the CSS spec,
okay? Like the Mozilla I read on the on
the Mozilla reference.
So
So, um
but the background image can take more
than image. So, meaning that you can use
more than one of these repeating uh
gradient, okay? Let's do.
So, let's let's just go here. Let's uh
there is uh one background image. Still
it.
Okay. So, uh
what
already have it, okay?
So, the second one, okay? So, we just
need the second one. Comma, okay? That's
that's the first one, okay? Now, we just
comma and the second and here is the
second one. Perfect.
So, we got two of them.
Is it done yet? I think so. I think so.
So,
close. Showing browser, okay? Scroll
down. Scroll down. Scroll down. No.
You got something screwed up, do you?
Okay?
So, let's see what is wrong. Wait, did
we get the red gradient? Let's
um
format the code. Prettify.
So, you got linear gradient, okay? You
want to compact them.
Now, uh
prettify. Now, let's introduce some red
because I always like some red
to make it like, um,
so you can see
where they are. So, you got a background
image, you got two images, looks right.
Close. So, why is it not showing search
for that? Did we get the class name
correct? Yes, okay.
Refresh. Okay, so you got this.
Oh, I see. You see? I know what's going
on. So, let's go back. Go back. Search,
search, okay.
Pop it up.
So, the reason is that because when you
have two images, they lay on top of each
other. So, the first one,
uh, the first one is the lowest, is that
right? So, you need to go to background.
Okay, so I've been working on my CSS in
the past month heavily. So, if you don't
know, check out my visual CSS on
xahlee.info.
x h l e e c s s. Okay, search for it.
You'll see xahlee how to add CSS, okay?
Xahlee is a prominent web developer,
okay.
Uh, so xahlee code, you can go there.
That's my home page.
And you can go to dev blog or directly,
you know, programming language
tutorials. Directly jump to CSS.
By the way, this is good like that
because I have
a zoom
text only. So, this is looks like that.
Uh, because, by the way, do you guys
know what I'm talking about? So, let me
show you. So, Firefox settings, you
know, this make a difference.
So, when you have zoom, uh, right now I
have zoom set to 150%
huge to me it's it's like humongous.
But, when you do live stream, that is
suitable. You know, to you it looks
huge, but to other people, you guys are
watching, you know, it it's not too big.
Because otherwise, it's like too tiny,
you cannot see. But, anyway, here's a
zoom text only. So, if you un
unclick it,
so where did you see? You unclick it,
then you go back to my
uh
my home page, you see this got perfect
formation. JavaScript in depth and CSS.
But, if you have uh zoom text only,
which is great, by the way,
uh
but then some part of it got screwed.
This is true for all websites
essentially essentially.
You can make a website that this doesn't
happen, but then
uh then you got some other undesirable
effects. The
heart of the reason is because the
the REM font size versus pixel size. So,
you can either specify everything in
your web design using pixels, which is
like hard-coded, or
you can specify part of it by REM, which
is a default font size.
Now, it is important when you set font
size to use REM because
because people can uh you know, because
people can
set their personal font size.
But, if you your website, if you specify
font size
by pixels, then it disrespects
each person's, you know, their font
size. So, that, you know, so that's no
good. So
you know, that's not a good practice. So
anyway, so anyway, we digress, okay? So
let's go back to um
Yeah, so what I'm saying is that okay,
so let's go back to um
cascading style sheet, okay? Then go to
uh where is my blog? Okay, we need to go
to the blog because recently it's not
here even.
Okay. So go to radio gradient background
image there. So image
the uh order multiple image the first
one is on top, okay?
Uh okay, so the first one is on top.
So that's why you only see the red one.
Okay, I believe.
There it is. You see, you only see the
red one because the the top one just
hides
the the one at bottom. So what you want
to do is actually you want to use
transparency trick, okay? So you
instead of saying black, use uh instead
of saying white
all these white parts needs to be
transparent, okay?
transpa-
-rent
transparency,
okay?
Okay, there is the CSS keyword
transparent there there.
Uh what's going on?
Okay.
So can you see can you like that, okay?
Black black transparent transparent so
that's uh
Yeah, the first one is at top, right? So
the second one then
then you don't want blue white, okay?
Actually, you can say transparent, too.
Okay, now refresh.
What? Oh, you need to put this back. Put
it back.
Refresh.
Fantastic and beautiful. Oh, we're
missing
uh the last element. Now, how do you um
fix that? Okay, we done that. Uh
Nobody is watching. Okay.
So
so far so good. Yes.
So far fantastic, but
but how do you fix the Yeah,
well.
Uh well, that's because, you know,
refresh, you see that you see that's why
you don't really fix it. It's just um it
got clipped.
Yeah, so there's nothing we should fix.
We should leave it like that. So,
fantastic right
rectangular grid. Now, let's just copy
the code, okay?
Now, clean up the code, so make sure
people get the right thing. Clean up,
okay.
Uh rectangular grid
uh yeah.
Yeah, so okay. So, you can like
Um
>> Can you No.
It doesn't, you know, you see it doesn't
um
I I want to auto format. Oh, you can.
So, you all you have to do is just
put a new line in the first item. You'll
You'll You'll format it
each
item per line.
Okay, so anyway, so that is the final
output.
Fantastic and beautiful, okay? Close it.
Now, go to grid.
Rectangular grid here.
Make a CSS pre tag. Paste it. Syntax
correct. Show in browser.
Fantastic and beautiful.
Last job, polar grid.
Okay, the principle is the same. So, we
already um
So, it's not difficult. So, the
principle is the same. So,
new section.
Put the title polar grid.
And new div. Add a class X
polar grid. Let's just say that, okay?
Copy. Now, go all the way to the top.
Let's work on our style sheet again.
Again, you need two parts, okay? So,
let's copy this.
Copy.
And paste. And then, we need to say
polar completion, not parallel polar
grid.
Yes.
Fantastic. Power of Xah Emacs system,
you know, Xah Fly key is also everything
is fantastic. Now,
Okay, so first of all, so you need um
you need first of all, you need a radio.
Okay, so
instead of repeating linear gradient,
you want radio. Okay?
Radio gradient.
That's right.
Template.
Okay, circle at center. Okay?
Center. Okay?
And yellow green. Hm, okay, let's try
yellow green. Okay, now delete that.
Delete that. Okay?
Uh yellow green, no, that's not what you
want. So, but let's refresh. Let's see
what we have.
Polar grid, nothing.
Okay, oh yeah, you need need to put it
back.
Refresh.
There, you got some kind of red green uh
radio. Okay?
Now, let's see.
Okay, let's put it back. Uh polar, let's
work on this directly and set this to
CSS marks, our CSS mod. So.
There. Okay?
And so we can like directly um
we don't have to pop out and pop back.
So.
So,
remove the second gradient for now.
Okay, so just one single gradient. Let's
work on one at a time.
So, what you want is um
you want them to radio out. So, yellow
at let's say 10% or like 20 pixels. 20
pixels, let's say.
Green at 20 pixels.
Uh yellow and uh
Hm. okay. Well,
Okay, let's try that.
Refresh, fantastic. They don't repeat.
That's right. That's right. You forgot.
You actually want repeating radio
gradient, okay?
So, copy that completion repeating
Wait. Wait.
What?
Not radio gradient.
Repeating
Oh, what?
Oh, wait a minute. Don't we
I forgot. Do we have a repeating radio
gradient? I know that I don't have a
tutorial because you can see it's not
even colored in CSS mode.
So, repeating radio gradient. Can we
actually have that?
There it is. I just didn't know about
this. Yeah, obviously.
Yeah. So, we can actually guess
we can actually do guesswork about the
syntax. Well, the syntax is, you you
know, typically exactly the same as a
radio gradient.
Okay. So, the syntax is exactly the
same. No, I don't have color for that,
you see?
But,
we will we will add it, but let's try
this first, okay?
Refresh, it should repeat. Red, yellow,
green, yellow, green, yellow.
Refresh.
No.
Okay, so you want
So, you begin at yellow.
Uh which is zero, okay? Then this is
always confusing this stops.
Begin
then color and change color but at same
stop then and, okay? So that's how you
do it.
So you begin.
Okay, then you repeat the color.
Let me show you
like that, okay? So you begin refresh we
can we can syntax error, okay.
Yeah, that's the problem. So let's make
it
HTML mode and then this power bar.
So put a grid here we are working on
this section.
Now
format it nice.
Now it's nice you can see.
Now yellow and pink So then green and
yellow and that
and let's see.
Oh, you want narrow lines, okay? So
close that this
refresh, okay now that's okay. So
um
yellow
Okay. Refresh fantastic.
Closer.
But we want you see we want a little
green I mean we we want a little like
gray lines.
So, let's copy that that for reference,
okay?
So, we want
paste that for reference. We want
something like that.
Can we just copy that? Yes, I think so.
Copy copy copy copy, okay?
Paste.
And
uh no.
Mhm.
Close.
Refresh. Fantastic.
Hm. You see you you see the jagged
um
Can you see the jagged rendering?
Oh, they don't enlarge. Oh, that's
interesting. They don't enlarge the
image.
I wanted to enlarge the image. So, we
were talking about let's try again,
okay?
So, control zero to return to the 150%
zoom.
Now, alt TS to
show the settings.
Now, let's go to the zoom.
And this time
zoom text only off.
Okay, when you click off the things
jumped around.
So, there, okay? Off.
Now, close it.
Now, you can see
you see now they zoom the whole.
And when they zoom the whole, you don't
have um
you know, it's good. So, anyway, but you
are seeing you see they are um
you see there's aliasing.
This is called aliasing in computer
graphics, meaning that you see it's not
smooth.
Uh
very interesting. So,
yeah, I noticed, you see
Let's see.
What if you show this page in
in Chrome-based browser, okay?
Right now, this is Firefox you are
looking at.
Maybe in Chrome-based browser they do it
better, you see.
You see you see aliasing there.
Meaning uh jagged, you know. So, anyway,
so let's try.
Press Press
Brave. Press a few keys to go to launch
the Brave browser.
There, okay?
Now,
it is still they're still jagged. Now,
magnify.
Yeah, so this
algorithm, you see the text you see here
how smooth they are. Perfect smoothness,
you see you see this E
you know, it's a circular. It's but you
see this C, it's perfect.
But now, look at this, you know, it is
not. It's jagged, you see?
So, that means the rendering technology
for graphics in browser in CSS, they are
not still
I mean, that they they they are kind of
like not perfect, okay?
Oh, anyway, well, part of the reason is
because, you know, we are doing we are
not just drawing circles. These circles
form because they are
an effect of the
of the gradient.
Okay, so we are not exactly just drawing
circles. If you just draw a circle,
you can check out the
you know, the corner um
round corners, okay, CSS, you see?
Can you see it's perfect? It's perfectly
round when you draw a border.
So, anyway, but it's still not perfect.
It could be, you know, better, I I
think.
So, anyway, so we we did draw this
fantastic. That's what we want. Yes,
okay.
Let's make
Let's Can we
do a screenshot? Yes.
Fantastic.
So, we have a record of what's going on.
You see this fascinating stuff.
Okay, now back to here, showing browser.
Okay, now control zero to
go back to
150 zoom.
You see some of these line become
thicker than others. That's also an
effect.
Funky.
Uh
okay.
Yeah, you see some some lines became
thicker. Anyway, so
Okay, 5 more minutes, we'll be able to
finish this. Okay, so let's go to let's
pop the up, go to polar grid.
Fantastic and beautiful. Now, delete
that and now
you just need Now, you see this
repeating linear gradient radio
repeating radio gradient is not colored.
That is what
The reason is because I didn't know
about this function.
So now let's make him color, okay? So
copy it. Go to CSS mode Emacs Lisp,
okay?
Jump to the source code.
Go there.
Okay.
1,000 lines of code. Now you just need
to go to properties. In fact, just
search for gradient.
Search there, okay? So here is CSS value
keywords. They are not property names.
They are value
keywords. In this case, functions, okay?
Paste it there.
Make it a string syntax there. Evaluate
the file. Close it.
Now
to do close it. Uh custom talk show,
close it.
Uh parallel lines open.
Now now open to the CSS. Yeah, we can
you know go back to the CSS. It's not
colored now, but you close it
and reopen it. You see? Now it is
colored properly. Repeating linear
gradient.
Wait wait wait wait. It's a repeating
radial gradient here, okay?
Anyway, so it's almost done. Almost,
okay.
So you just need um
copy, comma,
duplicate.
Now this time you want repeating conic
gradient, okay?
Okay, let's see what you get by default.
That's my template, okay? That's not
what I want.
No. So we want So now
now we have a conic gradient.
Okay, so it like that.
Right. So, what you want is something
similar
like that.
Okay.
So, you need to say degrees. Okay, so
stop that.
So, black 0° Okay,
then
No, actually they don't draw lines. They
draw sectors. Okay, we found the
problem.
Yeah, okay.
Let's Let's keep going, okay?
So, so 0°
then
uh add then add
1°.
Okay. Then here 1°.
Transparent 1° and here um
third 20°. Okay, so they need to be
degrees, not px.
Okay.
So, let's see. Yeah.
Can you uh Can you format it syntax? No,
you got a syntax error. Where?
Uh line 53. Okay, let's go to 53 there.
Why?
Because repeating
conic gradients. So, why can't you
Syntax error. Oh, yeah, you need to be
together. That's right.
Remember, you cannot have a space after
the function name.
So, the top one
So, this should be at the top. Okay?
There. Okay, so that is top one. Okay?
Now
Oh, doesn't matter because doesn't
matter. Okay.
Close it.
Go back. Now
showing browser
scroll down
Perfect.
Perfection.
Okay, I think that's it for today.
Do we have how many people watching?
Four. Okay.
Uh you guys too shy to say hi, I guess.
Okay, so but anyway
So, we got a polar grid.
Is it useful?
Not that much, I wouldn't say.
You see
you know, so
if you want to use it, you have to make
it gray.
And but I don't think it's useful. It's
because if you really want to use it
let's say for plotting polar curves,
then you
you know, then you because CSS cannot
draw curves. It can, but you're not
really.
So, you really need to go to SVG.
Okay.
But for this, for example, diamond grid,
is it useful? Sometimes.
Is it you know, is this rectangular grid
useful? Sometimes because you want a
decorative background, you know, you
make it very light gray.
So, you know, so you know, decorative
background. So, similar for this, you
can use it for decorative background,
but
I don't think much of anything.
Okay, that's it.
Thank you guys. Thank you for watching.
If you enjoy my stuff, pay me, okay? Go
to my ksadi
.info.
Fantastic. Uh lots of stuff. Go to Go to
Go to
Go to and there and at the bottom
uh
PayPal me, Patreon me, Amazon gift card
me, okay?
Anything else? I think that's it. Bye,
guys. Bye.