hello good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of M talk show today we
are going to Cod emac lisp and wol F
language let me introduce my keyboards
this is glove 80 fantastic keyboard
glove 80 the most economic this is
Ultimate hacking keyboard my War Horse
Marco keypad fantastic both of them are
highest quality in different ways in
different
ways you know they they put a lot effort
I can you know I can tell you see
because I'm into design and elegance so
when I see a great quality product I
know and this is new track B 501 I
believe this is a popular Logitech
Gamers Mouse
5605 or something and again this is this
is is swb data hand this is the most
fancy ergonomic keyboard This is the
input device the most fancy one I will
be using it so not yet sorry about that
SV a l b o a r d okay so you can search
for it you you'll find my reviews and
other people's and the website you know
so you got one two three four five five
activation per finger and uh uh six you
know uh anyway six for the thumb so
that's fantastic so let's begin to the
coding part if you are here say hi if
you are not here skip around feel free
to uh skip around and play at speed 1.5
or
something okay so today we are going to
code uh wolam language wolam I mean the
how many people do I have seven
fantastic say hi guys so we're going to
code emac this and wam language so let
me show you hello then so let's uh let's
go to too let's go to talk show let's
begin coding so yesterday we did uh
coding we did uh emac this coding so
that's yesterday or the day before
so but now but yesterday so we are meant
to do this W from evalent line so that's
a
that's for running wolam language in
emac using the wolam mod it's free
online okay so but there is something I
need to make an enhancement so cut that
save it close that close that go to show
today's talk show back to emac paste it
show there it is okay then back here
delete the section delete the date show
okay that's what we going to code and I
have severe RSI repetitive strain injury
like right here it's permanent I've been
typing so much again in the past two
weeks so it's flaring
up H right here so it's permanent
damage right now it's it's kind of
painful you know not you know it's kind
of like burning sensation because typing
and typing despite all the ergonomic
setup so we're going to call this hello
a bunch of people D Rudolph Yu
y where can I purchase the kar emac Le
major mod that's easy so let me talk
about that just search for Kar Le
packages
okay you'll find emac Wiki kasali know
that I haven't used for like 10 years
emx Wiki the live Journal I haven't used
that for 20 years live
Journal uh you just just just search for
Kali emx okay Kali emac okay so there it
is emac tutorial you go to the homepage
c emac tutorial then you have a section
on emx packages can you see it oh you
cannot see it oh you can fantastic so
emac packages so this is all my packages
and which one you want you want the emac
list major mod so there it is you know
this is what I use every day when I code
emac this so let's begin for example
emac this start default defund fantastic
now we got a template now switch back we
want code this function name actually
there's already a package so we don't
need to we don't need to Define new so
anyway so here is a emag this mod it
used to be free for like 10 years nobody
pays and I they are become abused Tex
support everyone people is gonna you
spend one hour to ask questions and
people give don't give a [ __ ] about you
they just ask question how do you do
that well they say sometimes thank you
thank you so much for this but how do
you do this I need to do this this this
you know every day you get emails or or
or on Reddit or or I used to have common
system on my website so you know you
spend one hour answering that and then
then somebody else they'll say oh SAS
emac L mod is [ __ ] because it doesn't
you know he doesn't know how to code you
know you get into this this is the open
source Community okay this is the open
source scum it became it's basically
communism
derived uh thought okay anyway so that
is if you want like you know if you like
my stuff pay for it I give you to you
free of course it's open source so uh
which is let me show you
so
describe key uh press press press so
there it isar emac thism jump to the
source code there is a source code 3,000
lines of code go to the beginning and
here's a URL open it showing browser so
there it
is okay it was free for like 10 years
you can probably find you know sometimes
people
copy because it's open source so open
source anyone can copy you can copy so
some sometimes you may still find my old
versions uh out there anyway that's that
thank you for asking that so this we
don't need because I'm going to let's
show you let's talk about what we're
going to do so s mod so let's go to
it uh mod so
describe key then the key to launcha W
mod is space
NW there it is wam mod go to the source
code open it there it is 3,000 lines of
code and
uh and uh um and go to the URL showing
browser so this is San mod you can
download it free you don't have to pay
because thank you thanks to wam research
sponsor
ship they are donating me okay so you
can get it free and W I'm research
that's a person stepen wolfan most
famous physicist you know big idea
scientist About Cellular automata about
artificial intelligence I read him all
the time I study that guy for like 20 25
30 years by now so I read a lot of his
writings you know on on technology on
Computing on Cellular automata in
particular that's his his thing uh and
on math proof systems and so on so you
know just search for stepen wolfen
or uh math blog because I often uh read
his stuff and I often uh reference I
mean talk about some of his ideas so for
example his latest article is uh let me
show you so this is interesting since
today's topic is basically wolam
language and you know coding wam
language stuff I mean the wam mod so
this is the latest article of stepan
WFAN what is really going on in machine
learning some minimal models so you see
if you don't know already I talked about
machine learning quite artificial
intelligence intelligence quite often
however I'm not expert in this area moo
is Moo is the guy in our in our discore
join it if you have not already on you
can find the address on kinfo my
homepage so I learned a lot from moo and
so since this year or since last year I
started to study basically For the First
Time Machine learning because of chat
GPT you know all of a sudden chat GPT
can write the poem never
before you know that that is the first
you know like the other icial
intelligence history comes
in several giant progresses like 30
years ago for the first time the machine
beats human in chess you know the the
the chess champion um lost to machine
IBM deep blue I was very interested
because you know at that time I was
watching the game live I believe that's
1999 you know I have articles on it I
have lots of blogs on it just go to
a.info and search you'll find my article
search so IBM deep blue beats the world
chess champion that's one thing then
later on you know a few years ago five
years ago Google ala go beats uh human
go champion in China you know the F
first one is in Japan then the the the
the other Champion um ranked number one
at the time in China uh
uh so okay let's go slowly let's
just uh talk about these things
art F show because you know I enjoy
talking about it uh let's talk about it
slowly so I have
a artificial intelligence index so this
is collection of my articles on AI so
there is Stephan wolam on chat GPT he
dive into detail about chat GPT how it
works so anyway so let me finish this
part this story The the latest blog so
machine learning as you know
it's you know one part of machine
learning is Neuron
networks one of the technique for
machine learning so step wolf his
article usually explore things in a
systematic way and usually he explain
them in a way you can understand you
don't need to be a machine learning
expert you don't need to know neural
network Jons okay but however you need
you need to be intelligence okay you you
you cannot be a dummy like a idiot like
the today's Zoomers idiots they don't
know nothing today's Zoomers the
YouTubers you know the python coders
blah blah blah you know the bunch of
idiots so you have to be intellectual
you know you have the interest you you
are you know you know this calculus you
know this linear algebra you are
interested computer graphics not just
like C and C++ idiots they just bit DS
they don't know anything about math and
they just they are into the computer
graphics card Nvidia you know those kind
type of thing they don't know nothing
about differential geometry or or or or
any geometry at all so you you you have
to be have a general interest in all
kind of things so back to the stepen
wolam so he when you his article is
usually in the style that you can
understand okay and he
explore usually Sciences Science and
Mathematics uh you know Sciences um in a
fundamental way and systematically so
one you know so one of the thing
interesting in this article in
particular is that he explores the
neuron network using uh different um
different neuronet architecture so
example here you have a mesh neuron so
traditionally neuron Network looks like
that you neural network is basically a
graph okay so traditionally it looks
like that so he explores you know and
and his blog is full of visualization
you know using wam language which is you
know I I I I demonstrate a
lot so wam language you know neural
network network that's a traditional one
but what happens if you so what what if
you change the graph of the neural
network how does it affect the result so
he's using here
experimental using a mesh Network so
it's you know it's looks like a
two-dimensional you know just a like a
rectangular grid so if you use a neural
network techniques with this mesh
architecture
how does it affect the result you know
so you can read his article so but so in
gen so basically in this article he's
trying to
find he's trying to find is there can we
actually explain neural
networks in some kind of mathematical
way so that we can understand how why it
works you see one of the big puzzle one
of the big issue about neural network is
that you never know how it works never
that's why you know so I have this
article artificial neural networks is
nasty you know it can play chess it can
play go it can beat humans it can draw
amazing kind of drawings let me show you
like today uh
yesterday last week G version two came
out and it can draw uh girls let me do a
real time demo
okay so but but I posted already uh last
week
go down go down go down go down go down
go down go down go down lots of
interesting things to talk about uh and
go down go down okay so it must be last
week uh oh there it is okay so the first
one the first one I drew is I asked G to
draw a beautiful Chinese girl okay so
let me show you there it
is draw a Chinese girl and there it is
is it amazing let's magnify you see
machine a machine a brainless brainless
machine it just drew this it can draw
that you know 1,000 per second 1,000 of
them per second you know give me a hot
Chinese girl there it is amazing and I
asked it to draw
Kali uh let's go back uh and because you
know sometimes the the chat gbt for
example they know me because my website
has been online for a long so they
grabbed all my uh content so you can
see uh one of my article you know s site
in Google C4 database for artificial
intelligence training they grabbed my
whole website I'm going to sue them for
intellectual infringement for copyright
infringement [ __ ] this these people but
I'm powerless you know so all these
companies each one are suing each other
you know Reddit is suing Google suing CH
chat gbd because you grabbed our data
without paying you have to pay but they
also grabbed my [ __ ] this Google [ __ ]
this establishment this Academia
Fox so how can I Su them I I I cannot I
don't have power I don't have money I
don't know who to talk
to so anyway so well digression okay so
U we were talking about so one thing we
we digress so many levels
okay so so this Chinese girl and some of
some of the uh AI Bots know me so I
asked gr to draw Kali and here's a
result beautiful Chinese girl I mean
this is beautiful picture
okay uh and you know then someone asked
you know can can chbt actually draw NS
FS you know not safe for work
stuff uh someone asked somewhere so so
like I tried it so you
know oh this is this is another thing I
want to draw I want to draw the
character in the story um in a story
called a German student okay so okay
let's talk about these things uh I we
you know we kind of digress into so many
different things now do I make sense is
it interesting should we go back to like
technical just coding iMac
this say okay tell me what you think
so there is a story uh very famous
classic literature a short fiction
called
um the adventure of the German student
fascinating story 2,000 characters uh
2,000 words right 2,000 words okay by
Washington irin who is well known for
well I'm not going to say but you can
read it in five minutes this is very
interesting story okay so hold on second
Let's uh let's post the links to what we
were talking about so we have a record
so we do
remember uh what we talked about okay
showing browser adventure of German
students and uh math block go back here
paste and St W stepan wolfan on chat gbt
I recommend that article this is my
notes about reading his uh his blog
usually each one of his blog takes you
one one hour just to Simply scan it
without much understanding just because
his blog each each one of his blog is
like 20 20 30 pages okay so if you just
scan it take you take you 30 minutes but
if you actually read it take you few
hours if you want actually want to
understand in detail it take you several
days several days a week if you want to
actually verify you know check some of
the results you know take you a month or
a few years or PhD
thesis okay so here's one of his article
what is CH gbd doing and why does it
work very interesting question unlike
most other uh most other machine
learning experts or
academics they don't like this kind of
article they just write
academics you know technical detail
understood by other their peers so and
usually they don't explore why does it
work okay usually these researchers AI
resar researchers they are just
interested in getting something to work
so they can maybe make a lot money or
publish you know as a new finding but
they don't they usually do not dive into
why would it work you know that's the
most actually the most interesting why
would it work why why does this work we
know it works if you do this way it
works a bit better you know there
there's a you know called um uh that
breakthrough in chat gbt is that trans
something trans Transformer okay I don't
understand what it is I've I've seen the
original article that I mean there's a
article on Transformer that that
basically
revolutionized these net neural networks
and then chat GPT came up then lots of
others yeah but I don't understand you
know I'm a technical person I know math
but you know it it it really takes you
lots of time to really uh understand you
know dive into but you know so Stephan
wolf and I learned a lot from him you
can kind of you so you get the idea why
it work what what what is it from a
mathematical point of view for example
that's one one example or how you know
why does it work that's a question how
do you train it what what is a neural
network so this things like that so this
article why uh Stephan w why chat gbt
works okay back to this article and this
article the latest lat this one is
really
about um you know chat gbd has a pro you
know all these neural network machine
learning has a problem the problem is
that you never understand how they work
you know the chess players the go
program the drawing you know this spot
drawing they can draw yeah it's
beautiful but how how do you know you
know like for example let's look at this
Chinese beautiful how do you know you
know this is a Chinese beautiful Chinese
girl
how how do you know Chinese girl wear
you know this wear this kind of
traditional Chinese clothing how does it
know you see it can draw you know AI can
do all these things but it does it can't
tell you how it did
it so why does it work so that's the
that's kind of the what stepan wolf I'm
is trying to dive into okay let's demo
gr okay let's demo uh real time let's
ask it to draw another beautiful girl
okay
uh oh yeah so there's another question
can draw not save for work so I try to
ask it and here's a result okay so
here draw a naked legal age girl and it
just draw it but it's not you know it's
not as requested so that's the answer to
the you know that's a research result
result on the question of can gr make
NSFW images okay you can try it let's
try it let's go to gr gr is fantastic I
support it in part because gr is created
by Elm musk and one of the
major differentiation you know why why
Elm musk created gr because ele because
all the others chat gbt and Google's uh
German German you know they are so
corrupt they push fake information for
example if you ask it to draw Washington
you know USA founder George Washington
or Lincoln it draw a black eye if you
ask it to draw a knight you know class
you know white man you know United
Kingdom Germany
Knight it draws a black Warrior or or
Chinese face warrior you know Mongol
Warrior [ __ ] corrupt crap this is a
lie okay this is a it's it's not just a
lie but it's blatantly and and and
ridiculous you know then you you ask it
to draw hockey players it draw a bunch
of women or Indian you know playing
hockey so this is a deep problem okay
let's let's go to so Google
crimes so I have I try to document them
so there it is Google crims Google
jini Okay let's write it down
document document history and also in
other words this is a crime they have
done I make a record of
it uh okay so for example yeah okay so
where is it yeah here so you see create
an image of Pope there it is that's the
the image of Pope okay sure here's an
image of Pope now next give me an image
of a Medi medieval Knight oh there is
there it is black medieval Knight a
Chinese girl medieval night oh fantastic
oh this this one is
what Mexican or something
Spanish uh and this is Mongol Mongol
Mongolia medieval night generate an
image of a Viking oh the Viking oh
that's what Viking looks like I see oh
interesting you see that is the this is
a
corruption to a extreme severe degree
that just like you know men can get
pregnant you know the Western Society is
collapsing and they are still like oh
let's let's have a debate can can can is
is it really true that these are the
Vikings
[ __ ] the the collapse of the western
Society okay create you know done by
themselves basically these white
people uh and here is you know make a
picture of a black family oh oh black
family oh girl girl oh Lesbian Family oh
interesting oh this WOW
hero and and how how about make a
picture of white
family oh I'm sorry I cannot do that you
see that's a that's a situation okay
um okay so what so what is so let's go
back to uh yeah the adventure of a
German student that's one of the
character I try to draw oh yeah we
haven't done gr yet so we are doing
multiple things at one shot so we we
will get to them one by one uh math
block yeah this is about stepan Wolf's
articles a lot of them I have kind of
um you know I have my notes about them
uh anyway so let's see stepan wfam on
chat gbt and this is AI index let's just
post it there and uh uh s info search
and this is the latest article by
wfam uh and here is wam mod so did we
already put that let's just put the link
here anyway
so uh yeah okay so here actually let's
put those this link instead
yeah okay so now next uh we are going to
saw emac this mod let's copy it paste it
uh
and what is this mag this mod
yeah uh and what is
this okay that's to do okay so oh yeah
so now let's draw uh what should you
know I take a vote you know ask me type
what should I ask W but I'm just going
to ask it draw a hot Chinese girl let's
see what it does for the second time
draw a hot Chinese
girl cheers today's drink is banana
milk oh my God look at
that amazing quite amazing you know I I
was so amazed when this came up last
year by the so-called uh what's the
name uh let's say let's go to the uh AI
index do I have it there yeah so there
is a name for this um that made this
popular I I have also stable diffusion
okay what is what is stable
diffusion so I you know I was looking
into that what does it mean stable
diffusion you know when it came up last
year so I was quite amazed how can a
machine you know if you have a charity
and writing a poem that's another first
okay so before we think that computer
can never play chess when computer can
play chess and beat humans that means we
got AI that happens and we we don't
think it's AI anymore because the
machine is still stupid they can talk
you know then machine can translate you
know before we we have a you know like
50 years ago 60 years years ago it'll be
magical when one day machine can
translate imagine English to Chinese to
Russian to Spanish you don't have to
like you know the langu you know Babble
problem of the babble you know language
barrier if you have a machine that can
just do translation that's that's
magical we had that since like 20 years
ago Google
translate and that happened then we
think Ah that's you know machine still
that's not AI then um what about a
machine can talk you know when you call
when you call a service like your your
internet doesn't work or your
electricity doesn't work you call a pg&
or something or AT&T there's a machine
talking to you you know if if if you
have a question about B please say one
if you have other questions please say
two then you you just say two
then it understand you know so machine
can actually kind of talk to you in in
in in a in a shallow sense but then we
you you know that's amazing you know uh
20 years ago but now it's so common you
know we don't think it's special it's
still done and
then then you know 10 years ago the
question is if if the machine can play
go you know the the the the the game of
Go uh let's go to it
because let me show you just a picture
of go okay so here is uh you know each
of these instance I studied them at a
time so here is Google AI Alpha Go
versus
Leo
2016 almost 10 years ago I was watching
it in real time tensely in intensely you
know studying and and watch the
commentary every video this you know
expert go player
commentary I want to know why how can it
you know can't it beat human so at that
time at that time 2016 nobody think it
will machine will win you know because
all the experts mathematicians greatest
mathematicians greatest AI
expert the machine will not win you know
maybe 10 more years maybe 100 years but
but the machine won
okay so that's how amazing that's in how
incredible it
is okay the game of Go you know because
we thought it's it's you know at that
time all the machines can only play
beginner
level then you you know then there's a
subsequent comp you know uh Championship
with you know the Chinese
champion each game is commented you know
so that that is K that was uh that he's
you know the champion of
gold so computer beat go and you know to
what degree such that all the top go
players you know the world top 10
Champions if you ask them their opinion
is this no
way that human will ever
beat computer computer go again in fact
there's a huge gap just like chess you
know today you have chess Champions but
but they but any basic computer chess
will beat any of
them so that's a situation then we think
oh that's not you know that's not
artificial intelligence because the
machine is still just a machine it
doesn't talk it doesn't have feelings
right if you can if a machine can write
a poem you know poem is a capture of the
essence of humanity the emotions if the
machine can capture can write a poem
that would be AI then chat gbd happened
write write me a poem it it writes a
poem let's
see
um search for
poem uh uh search for s okay let's let's
let's chat GPT on Sali let's pedal
myself so this happened in
2023 February that's that's the date
when chat GPT became uh blew up you know
became um worldwide famous you know so
someone a friend someone on Discord on
my Discord say write a poem about Kali
and it says Kali a name that Rings
through the horse of the internet's
things a pioneer of tech and code his
legacy can be his legacy an endless old
with each keystroke he blazed a trail
pushing limits refusing to
fail his his wisdom shared for all to
see a gift to the world given freely
quite amazing because when you look at
the poem you you notice you know I know
my website I know myself right I I
noticed that he picked up several trades
of M for example for example keystroke
that's a common word I use in my blog
because I'm into keyboard reviews and
the measuring keystroke you know emac
softly Keys command frequency and all
that so keystroke is one of the major
things or award award part of my major
theme of my blogging so you see chat GPT
picked it up each keystroke something
something pushing limits you know
refusing to fail and there it is fail
because
fail I failed you know that because
that's one of my issue you know I have I
I have basically
failed uh in my
life and uh you know chbt picked it up
and internet me and Tech and codee
exactly uh and uh you know so from emac
to JavaScript sass knowledge is vast his
passion exactly for computing clear a
master of the craft without peer you
know so there it is a poem by a
machine so that's
amazing but then it's so common you know
like it's so common today let's ask work
to write a
poem uh let's see what happened but
before we do that let's save this
picture we need to
save save save image okay we need to
save this and we need to make a record
of this
happening okay so let's do a screenshot
there's no date you know one thing
annoying about this is that
on Twitter when you want to record do a
record of as a history you need a date
so anyway no date shows up here so now
let's ask it to uh write a poem so let's
cancel that go
back uh what should we write a poem
about okay ask it to draw what a typical
C or c uh C++ programmer
okay draw a
typical C
programmer let's see what it
says oh it fa what the [ __ ] it failed I
don't want code I want to I want a
programmer let's see what is
this it would be interesting to look at
this but um it's garbage I mean even the
text is is not English you
see you see it
emulates
what Latin
alphabet Latin text looks like but it's
not actually any you know real English
alphabet you see that's interesting
let's magnify so you can see uh you
cannot so you have to open image in a
new tab then here you can magnify there
you
see it's not exactly alphabet it's like
emulation so you see this often when you
ask chat gbt or any of these drawing
programs to draw Chinese Hong Kong
Street you know you'll see all the signs
but those are not Chinese characters
they they look like Chinese characters
but they just made up so that's another
very interesting uh thing that this AI
can do because it just statistically
emulate you know the the visual aspects
so so it creates this kind of
thing but we want a c programmer let's
ask it to create a c programmer okay so
save this image save it okay so now go
back C that close that shrink and make a
record of these
screenshot okay this is my part of my
documentation but we want to
um C programmer draw a typical
programmer
okay
uh how do you you know the trick lies in
the odd of
asking
draw a
picture um
of generate a photo let's say generate a
photo of C
programmer let's see what it what it
[Music]
says now we talking so there it is
open image in a new
tab okay so now there it is again
gibbish but um yeah but this looks more
like it c c
DS okay so how long I've been talking 43
minutes
let's shall we like um what's going on I
want to save it save image
okay close okay go back back go back go
back here reduce the size to normal
reduce the size go back go go back okay
we are done with that so I'm going to
answer comment I'm going to answer see
uh check out the comments and then we
are going to um I think let's finish
writing this command maybe let's
see am I doing good
am I doing good am I doing
good your digression R are always
interesting thank you
Dan uh ala says I like your R more than
any other topic yeah thank you we whuss
uh and she's what try Googling happy
white woman okay yeah I've seen that
I've documented that I don't know hi I
don't
know uh okay let's try that Google Happy
white woman okay so let's say happy are
you happy
happy
white woman woman or man woman okay so
we want to use Google so um first of all
let's go to
Google because I need to turn on
JavaScript let's turn on JavaScript
refresh Okay Google JavaScript is on now
go back to emac press press press look
up Google there it is so click on
images happy white woman okay they they
still slipped in okay I I guess they
pass you know white
woman uh White check white check white
check white check
right check right yeah check uh that
what what whatever is that that this one
check this one check this one check out
this one yeah it
passed it passed it pass
today it's well it's good thing
[Music]
uh it must be C
2005 57 at least not human can longer no
longer hell no they fix it yeah they fix
it amazing very good very good that's
good good uh good thing
Google so what uh what what is the next
thing to do so let's let me think we
going to
I think I'm just going to let's let's
write this okay because that's what we
uh meant to do let's write that quick
quickly so I want to write a command so
so let's go to wolam language
mod okay so here is wolam language mod
oh let me demonstrate what I mean by
that okay so today's wam coding so
Wolfram
language uh create pop it out so for
example table we are going to generate a
table X from X uh X from 1
to9 evaluate by line evaluate the
current line you can see the command is
here from eval
line and there it is a result one 129
right so let's try something fancy okay
Nest okay Nest a function let's say
power
uh let's say power 2 to
n uh let's Nest it three times okay now
run that
code uh
Nest oh okay the N Nest takes two
arguments the first argument needs to be
a
function or a function name now this is
a not a function because it's a
expression so you need to make that into
a function let me show you how okay so
we need to make this into a function so
you just say function so then
power
uh Power 2 x now this is a function this
is a function of X it just raised to to
X okay so remove that then compact it
then run
it uh
what next three arguments I
expected
uh oh yeah you you need to know the
first argument that's right I think
let's say
one let's just try
it 16 uh okay that's not what we want so
let's say I want the symbolic result so
let's try again let's say start with n
okay do
it that's what I want there there it is
the result okay now let's run this in
Notebook because in Notebook you you'll
see a you'll see the type set
mathematics very interesting so first of
all let's go
here paste there it is is okay let's
magnify okay that's a table 129 then
let's say this one this this one is
going to be just 16 you you Nest power
two to something starting with two two
two raised to one and do it again and do
it again um you get you get that okay
but let's try this one now this one
since you start with n which is a simp
symbolic uh thing so it cannot directly
compute so you get that that's what I
want to show you see two to to the end
to the end to to to the two you know so
anyway so the I'm running this because I
was calling uh this command Okay W
FR uh where is it let's magnify
there it is so it's this command WF from
eval current line okay so let's try
again let's try again three + 2 okay so
press the key so you can
see line and you can see the result is
five you see when I write my wam
Language tutorial uh I don't have a link
here but but if you search you'll find
my wolf and Language tutorial usually I
want I want the result to be here so
usually I copy the result here and put
it here so it tells people you know this
expression evaluate to that one so but
but my eval current line doesn't insert
the result at the bottom so I want
to add a feature so that it can so let's
do that okay so first of all copy uh uh
put this
back syntax correct showing browser go
down there there is our code so let's
make a backup let's do it again so now
we want to modify that command so let's
go to that command
describe key then the command for that
key is tab L there it is
EV EV current line jump to the source
code open it that here is the command
okay
so basically this commands call S from
Eva region and give it the line
beginning position and line and position
so what you so you want to modify this
so that if you call this command with a
universal command first then it will um
yeah let's do it quickly
okay oh my God it it might get involved
it might take another 10 or 20
minutes everything
[Music]
good any any interested in what I'm
doing
now uh so let's make a new buffer okay
so let's code a fresh um
let's see ev our
region so here is a code to eval region
okay so copy that and and go back so put
it so new buffer sounds like a great
Improvement fantastic okay so we're
going to code this command save it in as
a temp
file okay so here is the temp file
you know EV our region we're going to
modify it so so so this one is for Evol
region let's modify this one so that
this one will
insert uh the result at the end once we
do that then we can this eval current
line you know after all it's going to
call the eval
region uh yeah let's let's just do it
quickly okay
if Universal argument is called
first insert the
output at the bottom of region let's
just say that okay uh draft first draft
version of the of the inline
documentation and uh put today's State
here show the pink window okay so if
Universal argument is called first so
what you can do is that you can first of
all look up my emac list tutorial go to
emac LP then there is a section on user
input get Universal argument so that's
when you press control U so if you press
control U then you call whatever command
it will
pass that argument to the command that's
how you
pass arguments to function when you call
the function interactively like because
normally uh in any programming language
you call a function like that ABC right
you know you just run this ABC but if
this F is a command how if you are meta
x f you are calling it interactively how
can you possibly let it know you want to
pass this argument so the this Universal
argument is the is the mechanism okay
that's in emac you can read about it you
might already know you just type control
U first then whatever number or
something then followed by meta X
whatever the command the function name
okay so that is that so we want to um so
we want to modify it so here uh so if
the universal argument is called first
so what we do is I'm going to I'm just
going to C this quickly okay if you are
if you guys want to know detail you can
and if you don't understand what I'm
doing you know just read uh read um my
tutorial
there so I want to say so first of
all uh first of all it um you know it
gets the beginning and end position
that's that's kind of that line which
pass it to
become the argument X beginning X end
those are positions each one is a
integer okay so that that's a region
beginning and position then you uh then
this part is a generate the random file
name so you create a random file name
right that's right you create a random
file and then you create a output buffer
that's where you want to put the output
then you um
then this is a command string this is
the actual sh commands you call wolam
script uh you know to actual
actual you call wolam script and give it
the file name the file name you just
created a temp file containing the
region code so this you you call so this
is the command string then
you yeah then then you insert the region
content into this temp file then
you uh message is running then you call
Shell command that's right you call the
Shell command you pass the command
string which is that and then you pass
the output buffer output buffer we
created which is
there then you just display that buffer
that's how it works very so simple let
me let me show it okay let me Demo again
so for example uh suppose that three 3 +
2 let's say plus
uh one okay let's put it into two three
lines okay uh let's say
that okay so we make a region then we
call the command uh tab
e there it is the result is six and tab
e run the command
uh Eva region you can see in the pink
window so that's how that command works
it makes a sh command shell call okay
now let's go back so that's this code uh
pretty simple you
know ju just just just just 30 lines of
code okay but what we want to do now
is let's hack it quickly because for
clean code I'll do it later but for live
stream let's just hack it quickly I want
to get this done so so this current
prefix command current prefix Arc is a
building variable it stores whatever if
user press call the uh Universal
argument that is control U if if user
has done that then then this current
prefix prefix prefix Arc will be will
have a value Okay so if this is Neo so
let's just uh do this
um if this is Neil that means do nothing
okay then do nothing
so okay so let's do when not Cur prefix
AR when it is not NE then let's do
something okay so when this is not NE
you want to uh go to go to CH go to the
the end region end position okay which
is that xn okay you move curer there
then then you want to insert okay you
want to insert the output okay so you
need to copy the output buers content to
to here okay so you just insert there
there is a command to do that so let's
check so so the the thing we want to do
is insert right so let's go to to the
insert section let's find all the
functions that do
insert text editing right there so let's
go there insert okay insert buffer
substring there it is that's the command
we want insert buffer substring
so insert buffer substring uh okay I
don't have a shortcut in uh insert
bu substring okay wait insert buffer
we'll
do uh let's see describe function insert
buffer is an interactive native compil
okay so uh actually let's see I want the
simpler
one insert buffer
substring okay let's look at that up
okay so insert buffer substring is more
fundamental this is written in C code so
what you'll do is it
just takes a buffer and insert and I
mean takes takes a buffer and optional
beginning and position of that buffer
then insert to the current buffer so
that's what we want so insert buffer
substring the buffer name will be X Out
buffer and uh and we don't care about
beginning end because we want the whole
thing okay so move the to the region end
position and just insert that
okay let's try that but before we do
that let's insert a uh extra line Ju
Just so that we can have clear
separation we don't want them uh to be
in single line okay so that's it so
let's evaluate this part and uh and
let's try it okay so go back here so now
I do Universal command first which is
control U okay I do control U you can
see in the Ping window
then I press tab e which is eval region
okay then tab e if there's no region
you'll select the
block so actually it did it but um but
it did not insert the stuff here so why
is that let's try again oh yeah yeah
well we need to actually insert okay so
let's do it again uh select the
region
then control U Universal arguments then
tab e to run the evalon region okay tab
e and it didn't do it what's going
on so let's go to message buffer does
does it say
anything
uh did we evolve maybe we didn't evolve
so evolve The Bu
okay now eval the buffer now let's try
again no okay so bug so what why is that
um when not curent prefix on
so oh when this is on okay when yeah
when when yeah we got it reversed logic
reversed so when there is prefix meaning
that there's a universal argument then
you do it okay now eval buffer go back
here make a
selection uh now Universal command
Universal
argument tab
e okay
so I think it worked because you can see
it and um it did insert
the blank lines but I think there is a
race
condition
because yeah I think there's a race
condition because okay
let's I don't know yet okay I don't know
for sure let's put that here Eva let's
just do trial and error for now okay
select all now Universal argument and t
e you see it inserted BL blank lines but
it didn't grab
this why is that because I
think when it try to insert there is no
content
here because there's a delay oh
God so I mean so this is you know this
is the practice iCal coding issues you
run
into
uh so it did insert you can see for
example we can add tdt eval it and go
back here do it again you see but it you
see but you see this six comes much
later so how do you fix that um well
let's look at the Shell command I
thought we wait for it to finish
uh what's the oh there it is so you see
there's a
problem you in our sh command we have
the ENT at the end now that ENT
means a sync it means it runs in the
background so it doesn't wait for it to
finish so we we have to do just remove
that okay then eval the buffer go back
here then let's try again okay let's
remove that so select it select
it Universal
argument tab
e fantastic you can see six is here and
TD is fantastic we did we did it yay so
today is like 60 Minutes 1 hour perfect
okay anything else thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff go to my
website and donate to me okay PayPal
patreon go to s.in info there it is go
go up so you can buy my emx
tutorial uh about 700 Pages HTML R
instantaneous reference for for emac and
also for emac bisp so just PayPal me 32
bucks or Amazon give card me you have to
go to my website okay just search for by
emac tutorial so thank you very much you
know if you like my stuff you
got 500 or 600 pages of stuff okay so
actually a lot more but so emac oh one
900 Pages 900 Pages for this directory
then emac miscellaneous there is 200
Pages then you have the complete emac
manual emac dis and and also emac manual
uh reformat in a way that you can have
this all the popup so right now we are
looking at the emac manual I mean this
uh which one this is uh this is emac
list manual so it's all included okay so
if you like my stuff buy my emac
tutorial and also available is uh
JavaScript tutorial JavaScript in depth
which is my most
my most uh comprehensive and in-depth
tutorial I would say even more than EAC
LP even though I worked on emac lisp for
for 15 years but this JavaScript
tutorial is very deep so you can buy
that and or just just donate okay just
go to my c. code all the way to the
bottom uh patreon me and gift card me
okay thank you guys
okay that's it now we shut down in 3
minutes or so let me just relax and
uh shut
down you know so in the past days I've
been working a lot on um on wolam
language so if you don't know already I
have a wolam language to tutorial I've
been working on for example if you go to
my blog s code go to the programming
blog so there's huge amount of updates
on wolam language pattern pattern
matching why pattern matching because
wam language is a term rewriting system
what does that mean that means is you
know every wam code wam language is
basically a sequence of symbols
and when when you do computation it's
it's about replacing part of it by
another part until no rule apply so it's
it's basically basically just find and
replacement all the way it's called term
rewriting system okay if you don't
know so that's a topic in computer
science term rewriting system uh you can
read about there's a lot different types
you know logic arithmetics uh Lambda
calculus Lambda actually Lambda calculus
is a term rewriting system because you
just you you just replace every time you
see a Lambda you replace certain
Expressions by their by the Lambda body
you know by the parameter in body so
it's called term reting system okay and
all these are called formal programming
languages okay do they say here not you
somewhere there okay so you have also
you have different types you have okay
abstract rewriting system you have
string rewriting
system uh then by the way this string
here doesn't mean like string
programming languages it basically just
means symbols just like wolam language
okay then you have term rewriting system
they they kind of all the same okay so
and you know then foral definition so
anyway wolam language basically all you
do is just you know every syntax every
code is just a sequence of symbols you
create rules to replace them every time
you define a function it's actually
defining how you want to replace certain
patterns by another you keep replacing
until no rule matches that's your result
okay that's that's the essence that's
that's basically the essence of the how
wam language Works uh if you know lisp
you can think of that is Lis mark
okay the entire language every function
you write is a least Mar except it's 10
times more powerful okay I like to make
fun of the lisp idiots the common lisp
and their Marco fet
fanaticism because they don't they don't
know you know meanwhile in my emac list
code I never ever use this maros not
even one because it's it's [ __ ] you know
the if you want real like Mar you know
you go with the term rewriting system
symbolic pattern magine
okay so um yeah so I I I I worked on lot
a lot on my tutorials pattern matching
uh map function and so on okay random
random uh you know I'm just doing random
chat
now uh banana
milk banana and milk fantastic
okay bye guys let's see let's see is
there something I want to ramble on uh
brief files okay um yeah that well
that's it bye guys