hello guys
welcome to another episode of some talk
show
today we are going to do wufang language
we are going to have fun and coding a
bunch of seashell stuff
now look at these fantastic seashells
now you know there are all sorts of
seashells you know there's this tusk
shell
um
then there is these you know all sort of
so we are going to do
uh called wufang language you know
mathematic mathematics formula to model
these c shells like this one okay so
it's about pure wufam language and
today's 2022 january 21st
okay so let's begin so um
let me prepare
um
the
the my emacs commands okay so on the
pink window you can see all my emacs
command cores and
keystrokes
okay for example you can look at the
pink window you can see
it's okay so
okay so let's do that so let me show you
so let's plot this okay so copy that go
to wolfram language we i already have it
open so you want to say parametric plot
3d
okay and you want to give this formula
paste it okay
and this formula you know
uh and you want to say
uh let's say
u from 0 to pi and
v
from 0 to pi for now okay
plot it okay so we have part of it
wufang language fantastic now copy the
previous input
that is ctrl l then you want to um let's
see
make them look nice so this is a formula
and now let's increase from two pi let's
say six okay u from zero to six now it's
better
now let's say
u from zero to twenty
plot it fantastic you you have part of
it you can rotate
you can see
and the
v from 0 to 2 pi let's say
fantastic now it's closed okay now let's
say not two pi let's say six so we can
see a sort of gap
okay this is pretty good
so that's what we are going to do we are
going to do this a lot formulas and we
are trying to uh model
all these seashell shapes and look at
this one you know some of them you know
people cut it apart and you can see
inside so this is nature nature natural
construction it's amazing
uh and you can see
uh
you know
let me show you some of these
open that
okay yeah so you know cut away view
and that
and this one
okay those are not and some of them are
exotic you know i was into seashells
starting like 20 years ago i kind of i
collected collected them a little bit
and you know some of them is just
amazing so
what i would like to do is to
characterize them
codify them into mathematical formula so
you can you can have a equation
that models all these variations
now the basic variation i mean the basic
thing about seashell is that
you know basically it's sine cosine you
know it's like um
so let's re let's delete this one we
don't okay so basically it's sine cosine
you know if you learned uh calculus
or
uh
analytic geometry
you all know how this works you have
sine and cosine and you know formulas
parametric formulas for sine and cosine
and you
twist them
so that's the basic form
but however you look at all these
variations you know this so this is a
basic form of seashell but
then you have so many variations okay so
actually let's um
let me close this
let me do something here so i have this
uh url
uh
open
copy close
oh it's on sorry.org okay nevermind
so
so we want to model this by a
mathematical formula and uh
and
and there are many variations for
example this is basically this is like a
you know normally you
rotate a circle
around an axis
and the circle as you rotate you
increase the circle size then you got
that kind of shell you increase the
circle size and also you move it down
along the axis so you got this um
you know this is the basic shape of
seashell but then there are variations
for example this one
this one is kind of like instead of
rotating a circle you rotate a triangle
and you got this shell this shell is
called thatcher shell amazing
okay and this one for example it it got
rips like along the along the
shell so this is
you know a very interesting uh
math
exercise you know for those of you
programmers into mathematics for fun
this would be very fun so you want to so
when you rotate this circle
along the axis and move the circle down
you know you generate a c shell but
every so often periodic periodically you
want to
have them have these ribs
you know like like um how would you do
it
yeah so in other sense you rotate a
circle but every
every once in a while you
all of a sudden increase the circle
by a little bit then then decrease it so
you you get these bumps you know so
very interesting to explore you know to
try different formulas and and for this
kind of thing the best tool is
language
okay mathematica okay so let me
introduce you i mean so i talked about
muffin language a lot
and you can get it for free since like
two years ago so if you just search for
saudi uh language you can find all my
tutorials so you can download it for
free
or you can buy a
raspberry pi it come with it
or you can just buy the uh
pay it and buy it student version or
hobbyist version
uh then
then
i mean streaming
am i still streaming i got disconnected
streaming health
okay so
so
um
so yeah so so wolfram language okay so
model modeling t-shirts so i have a
bunch of tutorials you can see
then the difference between wolfram
language from engine mathematica wolfram
script i explained them all because it's
a bit complex you know if you go to the
woofam site there's lots of marketing
oriented talk so i give you a clear
uh explanation of their differences
then
uh here's a tutorial about wufang
language wufang language syntax and
wufang language tutorial for for
beginner okay so you don't have to have
any experience with language and
if you are a programmer this would be
good for you as well because language is
uh quite different from all other
languages from least has it's bit is
mostly
similar to lisp okay it's symbolic lisp
and pattern matching based which is the
pattern matching is different from uh
haskell or camera or other functional
languages such as f sharp
f sharp haskell or camo
so it's symbolic pattern matching kind
of like uh least marker but far more
advanced so i did uh several talk show
about wolfram language that there's uh
10 or so of them so you should check
them out on the details of wolfram
language but today we are just going to
do these uh fun things okay
so let's go to talk show
and uh
okay so we
intro code formula so we want to do that
so let's um
fix this this is not looking good
okay so
let's say two pie
it kind of
so this this is this is this controls
how yeah this controls how much it grows
let's say 10
let's say
okay so
part of it is clipped
i don't want it clipped so
so first of all let's
make a copy of it and let's make it um
you know
let's change the format so that
uh it's better to be displayed in the
in the website
so open the c shell
so showing browser
so we are going to modify it
let me put this here ufram language okay
so
now watch this part
showing browser that's better that's a
full complete wolfram language you can
just copy and paste and run it
so apparently i have i had some uh old
wolfram language packages uh for drawing
these let's open them you know
they are written like 10 years ago
more than 10 years ago so
i'm not actually certain they will run
okay so let's open them
so there it is seashell
okay magnify
this mathematical unknown book is from
project visual playing curves history
length okay
continue
revert to our styling continue with
updated styling okay so
so this is old graphics
woofing language let's run them again
i think i'm going to get errors because
do it
yeah
window okay so
show it
yeah no okay show it again show it
render all is the problem
do it
show it
fantastic
now let's see
okay so
you see the code is
you know the this code is written in
2002 so 20 years ago
so you see this is this part it looks
pretty but it's not supposed to be that
way so
save it
and let's open the other one
okay this one
let's magnify
okay 2002
run it
comments and questions posted okay
comments and questions i i want to see
them
oh okay so this one is spectacular look
at that look at that thing so this is
what i'm you know this is kind of what
i'm talking about it you know it
okay so let's try to evaluate this
um
20 years old wufang language code
do it
fantastic
so this this is the one where you get
the
bumps
fantastic
but this is not a full thing so let's we
want the full thing so let's see
four to five
4 to 10 let's see what happens
okay so
u apparently u controls the
height
oh wow this thing is
you know this uh
this is a user interface problem of
wufam language
you know it kind of shrinks the
okay i think i should uh go on let's
so i need to i'm gonna work on this
offline i guess so let's try again so
plot points let's remove them so it's
automatic
okay you cannot remove the power points
because
you need the plot points okay
hey scott long time haven't seen you
scott the expert on cpu and gpu and c
language great to see you again
how are you doing i hope you are doing
great
um
so wufang language okay so this is
fascinating you know
so you know in order to know this to do
this actually a lot of thinking is
required you need to look into uh let's
let's make this
okay so i have explanation on what these
parameters do but let's make this part
uh
you know formatted uh like a
rendered like a traditional math
equation so you got things like that so
anyway
yeah two so
right now
we want to so we got a formula
that
looks like that you know that
models this seashell
but this one it doesn't i mean we got
the basics down but it doesn't look
pretty we want something that looks
pretty like that
so that will
that means actually it will
involve several hours of coding and
before we can even do that we need to
understand
the um
you know we need to look at these
equations uh for the to understand what
exactly they are doing to be able to
have a you know nice plot
then
if you want it to be to look like this
you know with a wireframe on part of it
that means you're gonna
you're gonna have to code wufang
language for a few hours so this is
something for me to do
so
let's save this for now
can you make fractals yes of course uh
in fact in fact it's building uh but i'm
not going to do it today because um
continue continued fraction
mandelbrot oh there's the mandelbrot set
okay so
let me
i don't
mentor okay
so
mandelbrot said distance my number said
member queue
mender board said plot so this is the
one you want to use let's look up the
documentation there there you see it
okay
so let's copy it
i smoke too much
that's why i but so there it is
mandelbrot part and you can also plot
judy asset
so uh let's go to the documentation and
you can see manual world part plot and
julia set plot
copy it
paste it
the net there it is
okay now can you
uh you cannot zoom in like that you have
to
uh you have to code a little bit
so anyway you know because you know
wolfram language has seven or close to
seven thousand functions building so
basically everything you need
anyway so let's get back to the to the c
okay so we did
so we have this one uh
this one
it's wufam language code
and then we have this one now i need to
i need to uh clean them up you know i
need to do a lot thinking i cannot i
cannot do it while
uh doing a live stream
can i no because
because this is a para parametric
formula you have to
you know
for one thing i haven't really done math
for a long time
so anyway so so that's what we are doing
today so you know let's just have fun uh
so what do you what's the other one so
this one
okay this one also doesn't look so good
but we got the basics
now now let me show you another page
okay so another page what i really want
to do
is
uh by the way by the way
if you open this you can see
you know this file for example let's
save this file okay save it as untitled
one and b
okay save it now go to
go to the
desktop
so this is the file uh let's
highlight the current line so you see
where my cursor is so this is the file
and we if we open it
now wolfram language source code is all
just uh text text files so
if it's text files how does how does it
represent the graphics well it
basically it
uh
base 64
the images so you can see here are the
graphics
and also you know this part so why do
you see this kind of thing
you know let me let me magnify you know
rule box roblox superscript box what are
those those
represent this formula this thing you
see here you know rendered
as a math formula
but if you are a programmer you if you
came from the uh you know programming
background you probably don't want this
so you can just convert them
press a button
convert them to the ascii form
then you save the file
you see the source code in emacs also
changed now but this is not the form you
want you want the real input form okay
so
i believe that's a that's a key
save it
okay there you have it you can you can
you can see now
it looks like that it's kind of read
more readable the you know the the
actual
uh
file of the notebook
and you can press the button to convert
them anytime you know so this is the
this this
format is called standard form this
format is called um
input you know it's here cell
convert to
input form
raw input form standard form
okay
so this is standard form this is input
form
and this is raw input form well input
form and input form they look the same
except that the source code if you have
raw input form
then it's readable like that
but anyway
usually you don't care about the you
know i mean foremost
i mean this is for i'm i'm talking about
this
thing
this is a the actual notebook wolfram
notebook
uh
format
so i'm talking about this thing so that
for you oogmod you know emacs oakmod
users or markup markdown or html
users so you can you can understand how
um how the format of the wolfram
language
uh notebook
is actually and you can manipulate them
program
programmatically
either using any language you want or
you can use language language ufam
language has lots of functions that
generate notebook or control or
manipulate notebooks so you can like use
wufang language to manipulate this
just
like
the way you can using emac lisp to
manipulate
uh oakmark oak mod files in
emacs
so i i have article on how to do that
you know a tutorial on how to use emac
disk to manipulate oak mod
uh just search for it you'll find it
so anyway so
so we got this so what's the next thing
to do so
okay so let's go to talk show close that
i want to
okay show i want to
uh
plot some formulas okay here
so back then about 20 or 20 years ago i
did a lot of these explorations and
someone sent me
send me formulas
to plot
different seashells so let's do them you
know i want to create the images in
language and put them up and first of
all you need to convert these formulas
into the woofing language
syntax you know he's using some other
software so let's do that okay uh
math parametric equation for seashell
the following are some math formulas for
seashell by mike williams okay that's a
guy
uh so this is 2005.
so let's do them they are based on
parametric okay so
so let's do let's start to code them
uh okay so copy
so copy and
now let's
modify them so this is a normal way of
writing a parametric formula so you have
three functions f x f y f z
and you have two parameters u and v so
this is a function that takes two
arguments u and v
two parameters and returns a
basically three values three values a
vector of three values so a function
takes two parameters and returns a
return three values a vector so in order
to write this um
so let's turn them
yeah that okay hold on a second
so
okay so now we we're gonna turn them
into wufam language
uh syntax
okay
parametric plot 3d and uh wait
so we're gonna modify these
so this is a vector
of three things comma
comma
and r1r2
so r
equals to
let's say
uh one okay
r2 equals to let's say two so
and uh cosine okay so this is
so we want to change all
parenthesis to square brackets okay so
let's do that
okay do it one shot and
also for sine and cosine you want to
you want to capitalize them okay so you
see
so let's do that
do that actually
and this part
needs to be parade not
okay so that is the
okay also this part ah got this a lot
a lot
editing to do to convert these okay so
that is basically the formula in wolfram
syntax and now you want to say
you from
0 to 6 okay
something like that
v from 0 to
10 okay
now i think that's it now dd that
okay copy that back to the wufang
language let's paste it
run it
okay so
it says
you oh you and v not
not you and u n v okay
paste it
yeah dd
run
okay
so okay this is cb so this is you know
so so basically the seashell is based on
a
taurus the c-sharp formula is based on
taurus so what you need to do is
actually to move it so this one is not
moving
moving the
circle around the line
so anyway so
drop that
show in browser you can see this is
before this is after
before
and after so we're gonna delete the
before we don't need it anymore
and the
syntax current
refresh fantastic this is just a circle
okay so
a torus not circle
okay then he says blah blah blah then
replace r with r times u the pi okay so
is this boring for you guys
uh
so no comment okay so
let's do the next one so let's let's see
this one
okay so paste it here
and
okay we have the code magnify magnify
copy it
paste we're gonna modify this radius of
the tube okay so
there's a lot coding to do because to
convert this to a wufam language um
syntax
yeah this is this is a lot to do with
this
to convert this into firm language
syntax okay so let's show the pink
window so you can see what commands i'm
typing
so we are going to write
so so so you know it
it's very tedious to convert these to
frame language syntax but
so what we can do is actually we
code
emac this on the fly
to record a command
that help help us
turn
this syntax into wufang language syntax
but that will take you know five minutes
um in fact i have it i have the code
from 15 years ago i'm not sure it runs
well
so anyway so let's convert this to firm
language syntax okay so
and do i have it
replace mathematical symbols okay what
is that one
okay not that
do
[Music]
okay so anyway so
change bracket
pairs
parent to square bracket that
do that again
uh
then you need to do that here
do that here
okay so that's the
so let's double check
we'll find language syntax and then you
need to remove the xyz
yeah so so
this w is a function so you need to
replace that by a wolfram language
function
[Music]
uh here so
you need to replace by a wolfram
language function so yeah so it's a
function yeah
[Music]
okay so
okay so this is actually a lot to do
function
u
um
[Music]
so that's
how you define a function
equals true so that's one way to write a
function
the other way to write a function is
[Music]
and okay this is actually a lot to do
here so
so here is a function
yeah so both of these are the same let's
use that one so we don't need that one
anymore
so that's a function
and now you need to replace by
replace the
parentheses
by
square bracket okay
and now you don't want the fzfx
anymore
and now you want to put them into a
bracket then you add a comma because
this is actually a vector represent the
vector of three
uh
okay so i think
that's it let's double check
and also you know these variables you
can see
yeah
you know this you you can see these
variables are using capital letters but
usually you don't want to do that in
wolfram language because wufang language
building functions start with capital
letters
so
yeah for example that n is a building
function you you cannot do
that um
you know that's why it's blue in
southward mod that's what i'm using sour
frame language mod
uh
let's just say cn okay so replace all
capital n by c n just for now
okay do it do it let's get this to run
quickly
okay now
let's shrink shrink okay now
now this
part is
the original and here is the new
now we want a parametric plot
okay and put
this
formula there
and
u
0 2 6
v 0 to 10 okay
copy it
paste it
run it
okay so
okay it looks like it's a shell it's a
seashell all right
so tedious
okay so we got this
um
so let's remove the original here
so this is our new formula
that's
now
again you can make it
you know into a
render it into a formula so anyway so
let's put the code back
go back to browser
refresh
so this is original this is new
uh
you know you can just copy that and
pasting open language now let's delete
the original
okay now syntax click
refresh fantastic
okay so
so this is for my website so
i need to go through each one of them
and also add a you know add the result
uh
picture of the
of the thing
and you can see this
you know if if i really want
a pretty picture this is not good enough
because
you need to increase plot points and you
need to get rid of this clip
so let let's let's try it okay
so plot point let's say 55 to get rid of
the kinks
so now you you see now it's much smooth
you still see some kinks
you see
you can still see some kinks there
and also this double line is no good
you know
possibly
that happens because
because you have overlap
or something
so you need to trick the parameters and
so on so let's see
let's say 60 okay let's say plot point
so there's a lot tricking to do
uh and now it's too big
and uh
and you don't want this clip you see
so you want plot range o so you want to
give it an option
okay
do it
fantastic now it's beautiful now it's
beautiful now however
however you see i don't like the color
so we need to change the color also this
double line still is still there
so you have to figure out why this
double line occur
okay so now
now let's make a copy of the previous
input let's modify it let's add
color okay
uh i'm not sure what is the
color function
q okay yeah
okay this this is goldie but i don't
like this
kind of goldie
okay so plot function
color function
rainbow
temperature map let's say
okay so let's magnify
now it's much prettier
fantastic okay
so we did one of them
let's um
let's just do this okay just temporarily
so we got we we make a copy of these uh
wait
we screenshot this thing
then
we go to emacs show in browser
so that one should be this one uh
periwinkle okay so this one is supposed
to be periwinkle
okay so hold on a second so let's i need
to create a directory named i
okay close it
then move the image here
back to browser refresh fantastic
fantastic
okay any comments and questions
you know so that's what we are doing so
this this is one of them periwinkle now
which one is periwinkle let's see let's
get back to uh this one
wait no this this one is called winter
trap
now which one is
periwinkle let's see
p-e-r-i
no i don't have periwinkle okay so let's
let's search uh google let's see if
what does periwinkle um what
periwinkle seashell
yeah
okay so this it looks like that
that's periwinkle now
so this one is top top shell amazing
extremely beautiful amazing you know
notice that it you know it's kind of
flat
so to generate this you rotate a
triangle around the axis
but but meanwhile not you you rotate a
you know a triangle around the axis and
meanwhile you move the triangle down but
besides that you also move the triangle
away from the axis
so that way you get a you know you get
this
you uh cone in a in in the middle
so
so there is a formula for top shell i
believe he gave so we have to do that
this one
this one but the but the editing to
convert these to a wufam language syntax
is very tedious so
in order to do you know there are there
are a lot more like like 10 of them so
in order
so in order to do that i have to write a
emax command to help me so i can press
one button and it converts them
uh that we do that in another day i
guess but right now let's just try to
see some more fun seashells so okay okay
so
so we haven't found out what's a
periwinkle um
now look at this one this one is another
one
quite different so this one this one is
tiny okay this one is like
like uh very tiny
uh and this one the funny you know one
of the funny things uh this one is
called truth
something yeah tooth shell you know the
the vernacular
jargon for this shell is tooth shell but
because it looks like a tooth
so
so i wanted to so which one is
periwinkle
uh
and also this one you know so many
spectacular ones so this one is called
uh nautilus
uh paper nautilus shell you know i have
this
somewhere in a box i should yeah
somewhere in the box i should
next time i do this video i should take
them take them out and show you this one
is amazing this one is
it's just like paper that's why it's
called
paper nautilus shell because it's so
lightweight lightweight and
fragile it's just like a piece of paper
uh and it's like
semi-transparent you can see it it's uh
it's about this big it's amazing it's
beautiful
paper nautilus okay so
and there is
snail and there is this exotic one
okay but periwinkle did we find any
periwinkle uh no never mind then
never mind but some of them you know i
truly love these you know they their
shape so okay let's go back to the code
okay so let's
let's maybe do one more so let's see
something interesting conch shell
ring called periwinkle maybe let's do
that one
uh
which one is this so any questions
do you have those command logs with the
files do you ever look back at them to
see what you did what do you mean
command logs
with the file so we what files
so
i talked for
15 minutes now and maybe that's it for
today so
yeah so that's it for today so
i want to do some of the interesting
ones so let's do one more okay
ring called periwinkle let's do that
okay let's do this one
okay
so here's original
let's put original in a comment and
paste it here here is where we modify it
change n to c n
and now let's let's repeat this tedious
process again
and
so
okay
and
so
so again we have a function
this time let's write them as
function of u okay
[Music]
it's not
okay let's just get this to work
number of turns
radius of the cube
remove the backslash slash
okay
okay then parametric
plot3d
add the formula
and u and v let's copy from here
okay so
that should be it
paste
do it
no
something is wrong okay so
oh w okay so w yeah
w needs
w is a
it's supposed to be a function but right
now it's not written as a function but
anyway that's uh
let's just get these two
let's focus on
the fun part
and not working
so yeah okay let's change the w to a
function
okay w is a function
so
okay
double check one more time cosine sign a
power okay so
double check copy that copy
back to here
paste
evaluate
oh pi
pi is the problem pi needs to be capital
because remember every building
symbol in wolfram language starts with
capital letters so when you have
lowercase pi it doesn't know what it is
it's just think of it as a
undefined variable
do it oh
fantastic
now let's let's magnify
these thing let's have a look
okay wrinkled periwinkle something like
that
now plot points let's make them
copy that
and
paste it here
do it
oh beautiful
this thing is beautiful
fantastic now
now let's increase the plot point double
at 160 per
um per parameter
wow it's taking some computation
now let's turn on let's see how much
memory and stuff it's using cpu and gpu
okay it's taking some time to compute
coffee and milk
comments and questions
that's it for today
fantastic okay this is this is great
this is great
so
so let let me do this
let's do this
okay
let's put this on my website and that
will be it for today
fantastic this beautiful thing
let's see what's the best angle to view
you know you need multiple photos
without animation you need multiple
photos because you cannot see the full
glory
so but for now let's just copy that do a
screenshot of this
okay and now back to
back to here
okay so here's the code and remove the
original periwrinkle
and
then
add
an image
fantastic and color syntax color the
buffer
is shown in browser
fantastic wait
why is that uh did i defeat some parts
yeah okay so
oh here yeah that's right so
remove this part we no longer need
fantastic that's it thank you guys
hey thank you scott for coming by
uh okay so if you like my stuff you know
pay me and
um
and i actually so i have some news i
want to share so
the wufang language the wolfram
you know the uh the xiaohufem language
mod
i'm going to release it to um
it's going to be free so
and i want to say
you know the wufang language is you know
i'm sponsored by wufam research
so i think i'm going to release the um
uh let me show you okay so wu from
southern language mod so
here here's a
the code
500 lines
i'm pretty yeah i think i'm going to put
it
you know probably on github or something
so it allows you to code wufang language
in emacs
okay
bye guys
so i'm i'm shutting down
i'm shutting it down in a minute
so fantastic um
okay so
close that close that
close that
so you know this huge amount of things
to do you know we i already spent one
hour on this but you can see how much
time it will take
to make you know this
wolfram
language mathematical model
photo for each one of these shell
and today
we only
you know we we we just touched the
surface you know we just showed some
pretty graphics using the building
parametric plot 3d
but if you really want a nice plot like
that
it involves a lot more coding
so it's gonna be few days worth of
coding
a week
to do this so
that's what i have to do
bye guys
hello justine you late
uh yeah
bye