hello welcome to another episode of Star
Talk show
today we are going to code
event of code 2022 problem uh day seven
we're gonna continue we didn't finish
last time in wolfam language okay and
today we might do we might start to talk
about something else depends on you know
whoever is here uh if you know comment
and I'll maybe talk about that otherwise
we're gonna continue we're gonna
continue with fam language probably
because I asked and there are two people
who wanted to see wufam language Camille
and the random icon
okay so let's continue code with rhyme
language there's a lot to do
okay
so okay nobody is watching so let's
let's begin okay so let's begin code
Wolfram language so today's talk show
okay uh uh uh yeah show it and let's go
up so day seven we did day seven
let's see day seven okay so let's let's
go to it let's put the link here
day seven
okay copy and go to sounds talk show
today hello a googler
Okay so
so here is day seven
we did two times uh and we still didn't
finish last time some day seven is uh uh
one of the harder problem
okay
so uh Google says I vote for graph
Theory Network science I'm interested in
this topic
uh graph Theory Network science okay
um yeah graph theory is very interesting
and especially For You programmers and
for your interesting uh for you
industrial programmers like web dev or
whatever or Linux you know uh so for you
people graph theory is one of the
mathematics topic that you might be
interested and you might be good at
graph Theory so graph theory is part of
discrete math okay uh I don't think I'm
going to do a topic on that because I
don't you know I learned graph Theory
long ago so I'm I'm just gonna
Rambo something about it
okay so uh here is uh this is not really
graph Theory but this is all possible
ways to visit and nods okay this is a
problem I did in like 20 years ago in
wufan language of course all the
possible ways to visit in knots so it's
this one is not graph Theory okay but
however I mean it's an interesting
programming problem you know since we
are doing event of code so
the problem is given n naughts let's say
n is one two three four five six so you
have all these possible ways so you want
to there are two problems one problem is
find a function you know the function
takes n and I'll put another number that
is all the possible ways to
to Traverse these n naughts okay to um
is there a specification yeah to connect
all these knots
that is the problem doesn't matter they
cause or not okay and
so write a function that computes how
many possible ways to connect n dots and
this problem there are two subparts one
is if you can see the Symmetry for
example for example let's go simpler for
example if the knot is 4 then there are
these three ways but however you can
look at these two they are essentially
the same you just rotate it so there's a
symmetry reduction so if you count
distinct ways
let's say yeah you can you can start to
think of this as a graph okay so uh
distinct you know this is this this
graph all these uh space specific type
of graph they are called a loop
okay a graph is a loop when there is
uh one and only one path that connects
them or something like that a loop you
know the uh there is a definition
so graph Theory you can look up
Wikipedia I learned a lot of things from
Wikipedia you can learn especially so
Wikipedia is a great resource for
mathematics and computing but not for
politics anything politics you know
related to any news sensitive you know
uh
uh China USA Russia you know any news
any
news sensitive topics religion or vote
you know all those are corrupted on
Wikipedia so but however for technical
topics programming math Wikipedia is
fantastic okay it's almost it's
basically the best resource so you can
learn you know traditionally you can
learn this you know by going to a
university take a course but today you
know if you are the auto didactic type
of person like me you learn by yourself
you can learn essentially the whole
thing you can in fact be a master of
graph Theory just just by reading
Wikipedia
keep reading it and do you know
understand it you know read it for
several months for half a year you'll be
you'll be uh expert of graph Theory okay
but otherwise you usually go to
university or take a course and they
they don't teach this month much because
scrap Theory they are part of discrete
mathematics okay so to a mathematician
you know the traditional mathematician
this is not considered I mean this is
this is part of math but they are not
the mainstream mathematics so what is
mainstream mathematics they are topology
analysis complex analysis uh you know
uh algebra you know differential
geometry algebraic geometry very very
Advanced very high level you you have to
spend four years to to to even have a
basic understanding what they are
manifold you know a variety algebraic
varieties and today and in the past 30
years you have topos and lots of complex
ideas these ideas you don't even
understand until you spend four years
studying mathematics be a math major in
you know in University
so that's a professional mathematics
typically they focus on those things but
graph Theory
and discrete mathematics
okay this and recreational math these
are also very deep okay these are also
very deep this is not trivial and
combinatory common combinatorics graph
Theory logic
discrete mathematics this oh and the
finite mathematics this kind of thing
are very easy to understand because you
you spend you know 10 minutes you
understand what's a graph and your
immediately know some problems that's
not solved okay that that is unsolved if
you can solve it you'll have a million
dollars right away
you can understand that in one hour you
know you can understand the whole other
questions about graph Theory you know
enumeration and so on so so let me say
again traditional mathematics that are
um that are spread by professional
mathematicians they are typically
topology complex analysis analysis
and uh and the analytic geometry I mean
and analytic number Theory
um
and uh in facto's Chaos Theory uh
dynamical systems
basically they almost all of them
involving calculus okay uh
um and oh and there in the algebra you
know abstract algebra group Theory field
uh
um
you know those are traditional
mathematic algebraic geometry and so on
differential geometry
but on the other side you have
discrete mathematics and finite
mathematics
where typically you don't have Infinity
you know you deal with discrete this
discrete means uh not continuous okay so
you either discrete or
end or it doesn't involve Infinity okay
so this finite math graph Theory
um
uh recreational
mathematics it's also you know same city
for children but but all these things
and game Game Theory Game Theory okay so
this is and also logic this is a bit
not mainstream of the kind of the
professional mathematics okay
however they are very deep okay they are
not trivial so grab theory is one part
of it and uh
um you know I'm I'm giving a like very
very rough description you know
that not necessarily true
I mean that that's that's not
necessarily
um
you know you can't really say that
provisional mathematicians doesn't do
graph Theory a lot too so anyway graph
theory is very interesting okay
and uh
and what I want to say about it yeah I
cannot give you a course uh because it's
uh quite involved uh
but yeah I wanted to show you some of
the book I recommend okay
so
let's see
graph
okay
okay so it's not there so you search for
book
math books for math books okay so there
it is one of them and the free math
books that's another and math and
geometry books so I have some of these
books you know I'm a math fanatics
especially when in the 1990s I'm a you
know I wanted to be a mathematician so I
read all these books
well most of them I read at least half
of it you know or something
so uh graph Theory you want so the best
the book I learned graph theory is this
one
fantastic okay grab Theory Book okay and
yeah I recommend it on my live stream a
few times so someone also bought it who
is this guy
photo by Renee okay Renee
uh he haven't been you know for him for
a while anyway so
this book is great it's pretty cheap uh
you know that I learned graph Theory
from okay
and this book is also great I learned
group Theory from in the 1990s so these
are these two uh
and uh
then okay let me show you some of the
math books okay
you know many of these if you know you
can read my website I highly recommend
you if you want to study uh complex
analysis this one is a great book visual
complex analysis and this is another
Super interesting this this book I I'm
interested in the most tidying and
patterns okay you know you you study
Tidings and patterns it seems silly but
this very deep and this book is almost
like the the reference there's no other
again like I said before this kind of
mathematics topic so this balloon 2 you
might say you know this this is not
mainstream you will not find a course
that teaches this in University
well except except you know this
professor guambam
you know he's uh one of the top
professors on this topic and Shepherd
gunban passed away uh I I read and I
realized one of them passed away a few
years ago
five years ago something three years ago
recently uh I don't know about the other
but anyway so back in 1990s I was
studying this book and actually I wrote
to the professor I have some questions
you know I I wanted some reference you
know in his and he sent me a bunch of
his his work and references reprint you
know he printed out he sent it to me
male male you know it's postal mail to
me
I still have it stacked somewhere but I
failed to be you know I
I failed to
um continue to do mathematics but anyway
so this is a fantastic book okay it's
out of print but Dover
uh printed again with this idiotic cover
you know don't worry is a publication
that they reprint books you know books
that has gone out of print or people has
forgotten
typically double repeat reprint stem uh
and with and and they you know they
usually they have idiotic illustration
like this one you know like because this
is this is um because this one first of
all it's beautiful just aesthetically
you know if you don't know anything
about math you just look at this one is
beautiful okay this and this uh [ __ ]
idiotic for children okay
but besides Aesthetics this one this
tithing actually illustrates a
particular specific example that's rare
it's like a you know one of those
counter example you know is this
possible nobody knows for many years
until someone made it then it's a you
know big big uh Discovery in math
you know then we know oh this is the
example or counter example it's possible
so this this besides being beautiful it
has steep meaning you know this this
illustration but Dover the idiotic Dover
let me change it to children's
Children's illustration book the [ __ ]
idiot anyway so I recommend this book
okay some books I recommend so that one
and of course you guys might know Stefan
wolfan since I'm doing uh wolfam
language all the time so Stefan Wolfram
I read this
I read this book basically three times
uh in particular chapter one two six you
know in during the 2000s so this is
another topic that many of you
programmers might be interested again
cellular automata that's the topic of
this book it's not the mainstream
mathematics okay and Stefan wufam
doesn't even consider it math he you
know he has his own Vision so but anyway
you know this book is controversial and
it's very tedious to read because every
sentence every every page he or say
Stefan wolf and will implicate I'm the
greatest scientist
repeats every every page here on repeat
oh this pattern create is random you
know creates randomness
you know very tedious but however
however it has solid content you know
this this book is about uh 2000 Pages
something like that okay one thousand
over one thousand two thousand Pages
like this thick heavy
so this book I can also recommend you
know endless topics as a programmer or
as a young people you have today in this
topic to learn
so you uh and the group Theory okay also
interesting so this book so I recommend
that so okay I recommend those books
meanwhile and also today you can learn a
lot of these almost all of these uh on
Wikipedia you know like I said you can
spend years you know I I read
encyclopedia for like an hour a day
since 1990s so before Wikipedia I go to
the library there's Encyclopedia
Britannica then there's Americans
coilers encyclopedia and there are a few
others you I check in them I check them
out you know I'm a I am a fanatic of
reading encyclopedias on all sorts of
topics
so but today
truly you can just spend years on all
the math on Wikipedia you will learn the
the issue is that are you willing to or
not do you want to spend the time you
know so like I said to many of you uh
young people
stop you know hanging around Fortune
hanging around read it hanging around
Hacker News posting [ __ ] [ __ ] posting
memes and being a non you know stop that
there's so many so much to learn if you
want to
um
do something useful or even to stay
relevant you know study study you know
uh you know and you you can be a great
programmer or mathematician or related
field and and but also that this that's
what I am you know I'm that type of
people I'm a nerd but if you are not a
nerd well most likely you are not gonna
watch my video
but of course there are some many other
fields you can go to you know
just don't waste time uh you know don't
do stupid things you know do something
useful to yourself make yourself happy
and have a good um
life and have a good career okay so
graph Theory very interesting okay so
but I cannot
um
I cannot teach you uh you know I
um yeah I'm not uh qualified to do so
uh so besides those few books you know
finite math and recreational and those
so discrete math there are also books
like
um for example on this page
I have collected many of the uh free
textbooks uh that's available that's
open source okay that's online and open
source I have so I've collected them on
my website so if you want uh
introduction to number Theory you know I
collected you know I I looked them over
so these are resources these are books
that I have I trust okay so you if you
trust me you can follow if you want to
learn you know so this one is very basic
number uh beginner number Theory and
this guy Edwin Clark
he's uh he's a Critic of Stephen
wolfram's book okay he's a major critic
of Stephen Wolfe anyway so but he he has
written you know Elementary number
theories so you know it's good
and uh the uh introduction to number
Theory and algebra so this one I
actually don't know much about but I
suppose it's okay
so number Theory there's a probability
you know all from the you know these are
actual textbooks so you will spend
several months to actually read them you
know several months you know they had
you know 400 Pages 500 pages and then
you have many calculus textbooks so I've
collected a few they are all open source
okay you know just like like today the
USA for example at least USA has become
so corrupted so corrupted by all the
high-level Powers you know like you go
to college it's like tens of thousand
dollars a year
but that's not all you know one textbook
you know you go to college you buy one
calculator stick textbook they are one
hundred dollars two hundred dollars
Jesus that's an incredible scam to uh
impossible to believe degree you know
even back in the 1990s
when I was going to college you know I
you know I bought calculus books those
are like fifty dollars and very
expensive but today is like few hundred
dollars
but the the thing is calculus the topic
of calculus
has not really has not act you can say
for True for sure like
the topic of calculus for beginners for
undergraduate has not changed zero
change okay
so you can you can actually use a book
from the 1990s makes no difference
absolutely
okay and so you can go to use book or
use people throw them out you know a lot
of tons of use book you know but today
you have to buy one because the
professor says then you cost 300 200
that's
incredible scam okay incredible scan
you know what because I and and then
some of the book you know
at one time I looked into why okay so at
one time I looked into why is today's
takes textbooks so expensive I I love
textbooks because they they are No
Nonsense if you want to study Physics
chemistry you know mechanical
engineering or Electronics engineering
or calculus or many of the topics linear
algebra you know analysis textbooks I
love textbooks because they don't talk
[ __ ] you know they just you know you
learn this this your your master each
one of these takes Humanity several
hundred years
to create you know because
this these are basically the essence for
example calculus you know took Newton
Newton leftness
all their life
to to actually try to make make them
into like a coherent thing then many
many mathematicians ever afterwards to
to iron out the you know the the flaws
the you know to make proofs to make the
a differential
logically sound you know
so it all these all textbooks are there
the essence of human academic learning
Okay so that's that's progress you can
learn them you know you can learn the
entire subject you know just spending
several months you know on the book so I
love textbooks chemistry or whatever you
know so I looked into so why is textbook
so expensive you know
because a huge amount of scam but you
know by this
he likes people you know um
for example let me show you
um so go to search so excites search
we have a lot common a lot of people
happy New Year oh only for [ __ ]
so you can see you know I have I looked
into you know five years ago why is
calculus books so expensive what like
what the [ __ ] 250
230 dollars you know it should be free
it's the same thing from 1990s there's
no change on the on the subject of
calculus
okay
so you know it turns out you know it's
just scam okay there are reasons you
know
the you know of course the because USA
is
they focus on you know capitalism and uh
capitalism free market is not bad what's
bad is that there's a lot of corruption
so they prevent you know for example
they prevent you from you from using uh
used textbook
because if you use used one nobody will
buy it so they they tell the Professor
in some way to force you to buy certain
books you know and and and lots of other
reasons so that's why uh textbooks
become so expensive
a huge scam okay so anyway that's about
textbooks and that's about
um some of these uh books I can
recommend calculus and linear algebra
um and then gets harder real analysis
that's when you finish calculus you have
real analysis then you have complex
analysis I love this topic complex
analysis then differential geometry and
here is Richard Palace uh my mentor who
taught me so many things in mathematics
you know then then there's and then you
get into topology and logic is kind of
separate logic is not mainstream
mathematics okay but still it's a deep
very deep topic and and and this
this homotopy type Theory I hope to
learn
um before I die I hope to have some
good understanding understanding of it
before I die you know homotopy type
Theory which is a New Foundation of math
mathematics that is suitable
for doing it by computer
you know there's a big there's a big
question you know because traditional
math and Computing it's there's a
certain incompatible incompatibility
until until about 10 years ago there
there is this mathematician
who came from traditional math
background uh this guy okay
so I have some notes this guy vadima
waldowsky a Russian I think he he he
died three years ago you know uh pretty
sad he died three years ago pretty young
um so
he
you know so he basically he created
this New Foundation of mathematics okay
which he calls homotopy type Theory or
uni univalent Foundation of math okay
that's a that's a
this this is a very interesting topic
and probably interesting to you guys
because and I know lots of you are
interested in Haskell you know and today
we are more and more focused you know
interested in provable programs you know
correctness has Scout type Theory so
anyway so this I recommend okay
I hope to learn myself then this
category Theory I don't you know
category Theory I don't give a [ __ ]
about it I don't care but
actually I do have a page about it I'm
thinking of deleting it
because I haven't read this book I don't
like category Theory okay category
theories
you know it's it's valid for sure it's
valid you know I I'm not really
qualified to say
to to to give you my opinion about
category Theory okay I'm not qualified
because I don't really know I don't
really understand the subject
but I can tell you all the Haskell
people talking about it they know less
than me okay and the category Theory
becomes you know popular among program
was because of Haskell because these
idiots they don't know nothing you know
these people they're talking about
Haskell all day and all night they tell
you Haskell this way or that way because
category okay these people
don't know any of these basic
mathematics okay that's that's that's
the Haskell people the [ __ ] idiots
okay so I I
but has but but category theory is
indeed
uh you know of course it's a valid uh
part of mathematics it's uh and it's
also related to Foundation of math okay
but I wouldn't you know
you have to learn it eventually if you
are interested in Homeopathy type Theory
okay so category Theory you can base it
on homotopy type Theory okay so but
anyway yeah you know so the the big
reason I don't like category theory is
because it's a all the fad it's
corrupted by these Haskell people idiots
okay they don't know anything about any
of these topology differential geometry
you ask them what's a group oh they
don't know they don't know a thing but
they cannot tell you a category this is
a category of something something
[ __ ] idiots okay category Theory
okay that's my some of my um
introduction to some of the math stuff
okay
so I talked for 30 minutes let's look at
what uh comments we have
do you have any advice on how to read
academic papers as I mentioned I'm
reading about graph drawing layout
algorithms in another recent development
only described in papers no well if you
are doing that it looks like you are
already fairly Advanced you don't need
my advice how to read papers
how to read papers well Focus pay
attention
try to understand what he says that's
what you want me to say about it
your video is very helpful thank you
Russian friend agreed hike saw
any book you would recommend that runs
through rigorous math proves with all
the involved steps and examples like
well all these books I recommended you
know all these books I just talked about
they are kind of like that essentially
all mathematics is like that okay
uh prove for even in odd numbers what
yeah so you know that's from your
question I can tell you don't have basic
math so you know you need to go through
calculus
um you know and stuff
a mind test okay I don't know what is
mind test
uh Jeff Money says they sometimes make
you pay for online homework now so that
you can buy used books yeah
pay for online homework
Rudolph says agreed on textbooks the
best span of the bug open source
textbooks yeah
what do you see a small low level
computation
uh
what do you see a small level
computation or math in other words do
you see math as an abstract build on top
of computing or the other way around
that question that depends on your point
of view
um you know that's not uh that's you
know
because first of all you are trying to
presume you are trying to presume there
is some kind of hierarchy
like you know
you know let me say you know let me just
go 3D you know
uh free thoughts on that thing
so you are presuming that there is some
kind of higher Rocky or or is is math
better more fundamental than Computing
or is Computing more fundamental than
mathematics
yeah but what do you mean by math what
what is Computing that you have to
Define what
doesn't seems to make sense
from the you know that that kind of
question
okay so I think we let's begin to code
Wolfram language I want to start to code
so let's close and let's put some of the
links to my talk show so we have a
record
okay the Ping window shows all my
command course
okay my textbooks are expensive
cause that because that notes on new
kind of science okay because that
okay math textbooks
close that
fun math books okay oh yeah I forgot to
there are some
uh fun math books I should mention a few
so these
yeah these are easy easy going okay so
there's also a book on Knots which I
actually I haven't read uh I don't know
if it's good this is these are old books
from 1990s
so not not theory is also a great
um very interesting topic okay and then
there's this
um Flatland
which I have a copy
it's it's out of copyright you know so I
have it online this is a fantastic
introduction to the idea of dimensions
you know for example when people say
higher Dimension fourth dimension Fifth
Fifth Dimension what does it mean so
this book
is a fiction this is you know you
classify these books a book as a science
fiction and they
they solidly it solidly introduces you
to the to understand the concept of
Dimension okay so then after reading
this book you'll know what it means but
this book is not just about dimension
this book is very popular okay there are
several movies out of it you know you
probably already know if you are into
math but if you haven't heard let me
give you an introduction this book
Romans of many domain dimensions
it's very short okay you can you can
finish reading it in three hours okay
it's very short it's it's a science
fiction technically uh
and there are two parts okay
the second part of the book
introduces you makes you understand what
is a higher Dimension fourth dimension
Fifth Dimension it makes you understand
it without any math there's no formula
in this book it's a science fiction okay
but you'll understand dimension in
mathematics by the way it's not time
because today you know if you haven't
studied math you know you go to YouTube
You'll see oh Dimension oh Magic oh
ghost oh you know our instant time and
travel time travel [ __ ] idiots okay
those are just brainwashing those uh
those are you know almost all of it any
YouTube video when they if they talk
about Dimension okay
90 more than 90 95 percent you know more
than 95 99 of them
it's [ __ ] you know they they are uh
you will be misled okay 99 of YouTube
any one of them if they talk about
Dimension okay you're being misled don't
read them okay don't watch them
you know except I can recommend you know
since we are on topic of math I can
recommend this one YouTube uh called
blue brown something okay that I highly
recommend that's real math okay three
blue one Brown
okay
so if you want to learn math I can
recommend you can actually just watch
every single one of his video
I highly recommend this is a real
math okay lots of math on YouTube this
is our audio [ __ ] then you know they
mislead you
I mean here's a question do you really
want to learn math
math is the real mathematician
mathematicians math you know the math
that gets you go to space build Rockets
you know those real okay
then
you can you can you know then this three
blue one Brown It's a good Channel you
pick some topic you eat that's easy okay
there's some some topic is more advanced
you know and and this guy is also a
programmer so uh so it's suitable for us
you know a lot of us also our
programmers so you can you know neural
networks machine learning uh so this is
a good Channel okay
he teaches you real math
meanwhile okay meanwhile let me say a
few this number file
it's idiotic okay number five number
file then there's also programming file
or something
I don't recommend okay
um
yeah of course and there are a lot of
professors you know so many okay if you
really want to learn also the homotopy
type theory that guy also has given
lectures you know and also a lot of
professors on cutting edge of these
highly Advanced you know topology or uh
you know or even category Theory they
talk on YouTube but usually it's very
very boring you have no idea what
they're talking about you know
but anyway so the three blue one brown
is a good uh resource okay I recommend
this and nothing else because that's
majority 90 percent
99 of the YouTubes talking about math
they are just pure [ __ ] they they
they they they
mislead you to uh to to to
um
bad thinking okay
okay so that I can recommend so let's
see what else so yeah this book is great
okay
for flatland oh yeah so
the part two introduced you know teaches
you about dimensions of math part one is
entirely different part one is a mock
history of the dark side of humanity
okay
uh this so go read it okay on my website
you can just search for
uh it's uncle.org okay just search for
you know you you go to kasari.org
and go toward the English then go to
literature Classics then you'll find it
flatland a romance of many dimensions
this book I read
four times okay through different years
in 1990s in year 2000 in then last time
I read it's maybe five years ago I read
it at cover to cover at least four times
and I also made some annotations so like
if you go through you'll see some of my
annotations
uh for example those those are the
annotations I made myself okay so check
it check this out flatland a romance of
many dimensions
okay uh then what else let's see let's
go back let's go back what is this okay
flat end yeah so let's uh yeah so this
page copy it
uh link
for math books oh it's already there
okay go back
close graph Theory okay very interesting
I don't know anything about it
okay let's go back
um we already talked about uh 40 minutes
now let's do uh
okay let's code Wu fun language let's
solve day five so day five
day five is the problem
here's the day five so it gives you the
input like that it's a text okay it's a
text file of input like that basically
it's like the Unix Linux
directory
navigation so you type CD to go to in
that directory you tap type LS to list
files and CD okay so you are given this
text as input
and uh essentially you want to build you
want to construct this directory
structure a tree basically
and then the question is problem one
find all directories whose size is less
or equal to 100K
get the sum of their sizes that's the
that's the problem okay so you need to
pass this
this is one of the more difficult
problem you know your code typically I
would say two or three hours
so you you have to pass this and uh and
try to build a
direct a tree out of it
so there are many ways to do it you
don't you don't have to be on the tree
you can just build order file path so
you'll end up with a list of file paths
so that's one way
but the best way is actually to build a
tree that's the that's the ultimate
solution to this problem because once
you have a tree
that's real structure because the
directory is a tree so you you truly
want to build a tree but building a tree
is not easy
so you can walk around by not building a
tree so you you just build a list of
directory path
then when you need to find those file
size of some directory then you just go
through each one very inefficient but
you you go through each file path and
you know and have a lookup table of
their file size but this is
not the optimal solution
of course the event of code doesn't ask
you for a optimal solution it all all it
asks you is to give the answer so
so you can build a file path or you can
build a tree okay now
we I'm going to be on a tree but when
you build a tree
there are two you can you you can build
a tree directly you know as as you read
this each line by line
you as you read them you build a UV or
the tree so that's one way to do it
another way I think it's easier but less
efficient is that you go through this
input then you build the file path first
so after that you have a list of all
final paths
then you go through the file path you
build a tree out of the list of file
path that's what we are doing that's
what I'm doing so
so last time we did so we have a list of
file path okay so now let's see
so now so here's the Wolfram code let's
start to
um do fam code okay so let's see
what is this okay so let's start with
fan language
do I have more coffee yes here is my
coffee
so
you start a new
fan language and say three so start the
Wolfram engine
okay and magnify it okay
and now you go back to
coffee
so let's start to look at the code
comments okay
am I doing good comments
okay so happy New Year yeah today is the
last day
uh so we're gonna start to do this so
what is the um
so we described the problem
we want to okay copy the problem let's
first of all copy the problem
so today's talk show yeah that's
preliminary okay
let's put this back so here let's start
the problem okay
okay wait so create a text
okay so that's the problem input that's
a sample input
um
and
let me show you the code okay code
analysis
problem analysis
analysis of the problem okay so now we
need to copy
the Wolfram language code
open that
more firm okay copy that
and go back here
paste it
and what else so this is
a band of code day seven
then day 7B we didn't finish then we
continue with day 7p
okay actually we need to copy this
Okay so
what's the difference
okay so yeah so
copy that
put here
okay so close that
so we want to see
so if we show it in browser so we have
two code here one and two we I want to
see what's the difference okay
so the the map function expression path
okay let's let's start to call them
let's go to the first one and see
okay so here is the input
so we split the input okay
so the input is that X input we split
into lines
process each line at a time build a list
of file path first then turn the path
into a tree that's the algorithm outline
each element is again a list of the file
names so yeah so the path our path is
not a string but rather it's a list of
the names in file name
that way it's easier to manipulate
okay so let's so then we have path then
this is X line parts list so what is
this
yeah so that's the input
input lines you know
so we have the least
so this is a list of least
this is at least each element is a line
and that line is again represented as a
list so for example dollar sign CD is a
list of three elements okay
so this is the line parts list okay
then here's the list of directory names
current is it used anywhere
size lookup table so we're gonna build a
table lookup table which is a python
dictionary of key value pairs the key is
the
is the is the fail path in least form
the value is the size of that
file okay then directory tree is our
tree again it's a it's a dictionary it's
a nested dictionary okay and here's a
code
so this code it will be incomprehensible
to you guys but but I understand it yeah
so after this
so after this we we would have file path
built okay so we so the file path will
be built
yeah so
so yeah let's see
map a function to find our path okay
so if we just run that let's see what we
get
okay
so here is the
Wolfram code
run it
go down
then type X path
unit so you can see each one is a
directory let's show them in column form
so each one each one is a list and it
represents a full path okay so we have
built
the path okay
now our problem is to turn to go through
this list of file path and turn them
into a tree okay and the tree is going
to be a nested dictionary
that is this part
so let's let's see let's
uh
be all the tree uh
Mystic dictionary
by
going through X path okay
that's what we need to do we stuck on
this
last time for an hour
so what we need is to write this
function you know
after the map we'll have the tree okay
and okay so that's one thing cleared
okay now we understand this now
now
go back
now let's see what is this input how is
this one different from previous
let's try select all paste run it
same thing
okay
so the same thing okay so
yep
let's see let's see screen them up
so go back and let's see let's pop it
out
this is the first one this is the second
one
so let's see what's the difference 200
lines
190 eyes okay
I'm 54 okay
looks like the same to me
yep
yep so we don't need this part
okay so here's our code now let's work
on this code
okay now
now we need to write this function now
this this is the path
so
okay let's write this function
we got a list of path
for each one
given a path such as
suggests that
you go through so you essentially you
want to do this okay where the key key
key is each one each element of the name
okay let me just think about this
so
again we can use this I thought about
this last time so I think I kind of know
what to do
so we want to miss a function
we want to use fold okay
once you we want to use fold
once it has a result
so fold
results
so let me let me write a simple version
so we can see what exactly is the
problem okay so
so other people can understand we want
to show a independent
I mean a standalone situation of what
are we doing
which is also helpful
to um
for us okay now we want to know each of
these string or not
so
so let's take the last item
and let's show input form
okay so yeah so each element is a string
great so the string will be used as the
key of the dictionary
okay
so this will be for example a b
C
okay
so given this input a list ABC you want
to build a dictionary
such that
you you essentially want to be on
something like that
okay anistic nested dictionary so the
first one is with key a the value is
again a dictionary then you take the key
B the value is again a dictionary a
dictionary is like a container like a
folder then you take Key C and the value
is again a dictionary okay so you want
to take this input
and
okay so let's try
given that input you want you want a
structure that is like this how do you
let's write this structure okay
let me show you
so there is a key a okay then the value
of key a
is again a Association
okay
and the value of this Association I mean
the ending this Association you have a
key B
and whose value is again
an association
can in this Association
which is a dictionary
you know in wufan language you have a
key C
and uh
and this key C the value of Key C will
be uh
file size or just no or just what let's
just say what
later on we'll have to make it a file
size
so this the last item is it always the
file or directory so in some case it's a
file in some case it's a directory yeah
we we don't know I mean we do know
because we know because we have built
this
size lookup table for example let's have
a look
which is a dictionary
that
where the key is a list
representing the full path and the value
is a
file size so given a path if
if it exists as a key in the size look
curve table
then that thing that path is a file
okay so that's how you tell
uh size lookup table we built before
okay so now
the problem
okay is that okay problem turn this into
this
this thing okay and here's how we're
gonna do it
okay
last time we stuck on these for an hour
okay so now so essentially we want the
function to do something like that okay
function will take a value
map okay
map
take subsequent values subsequent value
and uh
and
foreign
are you guys still watching
I need to I need your input I need your
encouragement ones
stuck you know
I mean this is the actual starting to
code it this is the problem
yeah I know how to code it but I have to
you know just
think about it for five minutes no
talking no moving that's the thing
that's a problem
so you want to function so the function
takes at least the function takes takes
at least of things
each time
he wants to set an association already a
given name we have a name.3 each time it
sets that
and set it to a Association so each time
so each time it
I think
okay let's see what is our treat is does
it already exist
I mean it does it's an empty Association
yeah this is a shortcut for
for the association okay and there's
nothing inside so it's just it's it's
just like almost like this
um hello I'm watching great Sam okay
so okay so
so each time
you want to associate two okay so let's
look up the documentation for associate
two okay so you do that you press that
key I'm using subwoofer mod which is
which is open source on on my GitHub
okay you can just find it here because I
will find mod it allows you to code
Wolfram language in emacs you know so
you can it's on GitHub you can go uh
grab it
sponsored by wufan research
so uh back to so this is Association
so we want to yeah look up the
documentation for associate two so you
give a value yeah so this allows you to
so you don't have to do assign yourself
you can just
yeah so the tree you want to modify this
Association so you say the tree and what
you
so this allows you to change
or add a key value pair so this is this
associate two function
allows you to
add or change a key value pair
right yeah so he said what we want to
use yes because we need to do this so
okay
so you so you call this you want to
assign or modify the tree Association
then here is the key okay so you need a
new key value pair
uh the value should be what should the
value be
we need to pick some uh some
some symbol that's not used can we use
none
okay none is a building symbol let's see
what is it
uh it's used for options that's not what
you want okay so let's see
we want some okay should we use no no no
it represents
no it's like Neo in this
absence of an expression or result
uh no we don't want to use no we want to
just use some symbol
um
let's see
you know anything that's unique we can
use
uh
yeah no those are not suitable so we can
use one which is no good we can use zero
okay let's say zero
so each time you encounter one of these
ABC you do that okay where the key is X
you know as a function
so okay so looks like that so far
not so good
it's let's clean this
so it's easier to see
so we have a function of one variable
so each time you
you know you map to the input you get
the thing so you do that
is that all maybe that's all
then let's see let's go through the
steps so
the first time you do that the second
time the x is something else right
the second time you want these
yeah okay so that that's this is
this is not all the second time you want
that so you you want the function to
apply
to this one of these input
and you want it to return
you want it to return
you you want it to so
when you take the first input you want
it to return
a function that can
he wanted to return
I don't know what so
well not necessarily
you can so if you have one thing you do
that then when you have the next thing
you have the next thing you want
so if this is the first thing when you
have the next thing you want
you want that
where the x is the input
wait no
associate to no
yeah actually this is what you want
let's think about this
the first step
then you want that
then the next step is what
something like that
[Music]
uh
it's
let's see
yeah something like that
so you you want to make this a function
uh so that's one way to do it I mean if
you do this way you are using associate
two
uh so in fact this is incorrect because
you are associate two is basically a
sign Association to the tree
so
here you are modifying the tree
and what does it return
so you need to know what does associate
to return
okay so we have it
associate two
has attribute hold first
effectively modifies the value of a in
place
yes
but what does it return
you see typically these
modify you know value in place those are
procedural programming thing
so when you do associate two
this is equivalent
to
uh
wait this is equivalent to something
like that
okay
yeah
uh but
but when you do these you see what it
does it return so it it certainly does
not I don't so this will not work it
does not return
a variable you see when you use
associate two the first element must be
a variable so in this case
this value
is not a variable
it doesn't say the Wolfram documentation
doesn't say what I returned
Okay so
and I'm pretty sure it won't work
can this walk now can this walk by
itself
can you actually let's say XX equals to
that okay
let's try it
nested Ducks Association nested
dictionary so
you know so if if you want the first
element
I mean let's say you want a key by a
okay a must be a string
you see
so now if you
um get the key
of a then
that's key B
you got that so you see this can work
correct so you can
simply do this
okay so now
so one of the question is do we use the
map or do we use some kind of Nest okay
let's see what is this
so you see
if we are given that input
one way to do this is we construct this
input and then we just evaluate this
expression
that can be easily done yeah maybe we
should just do that this can be easily
done by uh by a pattern matching so
basically given a list we use pattern
matching
then turn turn the list into this
expression
and it will evaluate or we can just
evaluate
explicit three
so yeah so this shows that you can
evaluate them them in one shot then you
have the structure
okay but that's but that's for one thing
that's for one of the full path
so if you have another full path
you know let's let's see if this works
let's say you have now
um
you know for example this one
correspond to that
but now let's say if you have
the first one is always the same let's
say but um
B2 let's say C2 okay something like that
can you do that and still maintain the
Integrity of that
okay so a B2 C2 so let's evaluate that
oh yeah then we need to assign the tree
okay so wait
so let's copy the tree
uh can you
can you actually assign like that
if you do that no you cannot
wait
you know obviously you cannot run both
of these because you do if you do that
the tree is gonna be Rewritten
you know once you execute this line it
doesn't know anything about that
so
so you cannot do this
uh so you want you you need a God
you need to
so do you guys see what I'm doing do you
guys see
yeah we cannot do that okay so we need
some other way to accumulate
so maybe back to
um
back to use associate tool
oh
actually this is the best way
why can't we just use this
is your reason
okay let's let's try that
let's try
clear X6 okay
now let's just say
let's do that
integer in that is protected
okay
but it will work if you set XX to
Association okay
okay make it empty
okay now it's empty Association now
evaluate that
oh
tag missing a missing key apps and ABC
okay
so that means you cannot create a key
before
before you have Association
you know so you have to run this first
equals to
empty Association then you can you know
you have to do it each one
okay you cannot
this is just like
when you have a
directory path of multiple directories
in the path that doesn't exist
in many programming languages you cannot
just create it one shot you have to
create the
The Parent Directory first then create
the directory of that children then
eventually you have a list of
directories nested
but in emac bism you can create them in
one shot emacs will automatically do it
for you behind behind it so anyway so we
back to this
so in order to you cannot do this one
shot in order to do this you have to
build Association for that key first
then okay
so that is also understood
and you cannot do this assignment
because
the latter overrides the previous
but you can do this though you can do
this by building each one okay
so again back to this problem
we have a list of path and this is just
one single path
turn this single path to
to that we can do yet so we can do that
this will run
but not this okay
map for each one so this will run
so given a path so
yep yep so use a pattern matching that
turns this expression into that
then
you need to assign it to the tree
somehow
because you need to accumulate them
so use a pattern matching to turn this
path
into that
then you need to attach it to the third
tree variable
so then you can say maybe
Grant root
this
is
something like this okay
so do that first
let's say this let's say
XX equals two
now you cannot do this neither because
then the next line you're gonna render
again you'll just override it
it just overrated
you know it really
I hate this he really is best if I just
do it offline
then
um
where are you guys you know those people
who wanted to watch say something
uh
four people
okay I'm going to
yeah I want to solve this okay yeah
and we can do this okay
uh so now
fold we should use fold really or reduce
also known as reduce
so if you use fold
every time it returns
and follow the function so let's see if
we're gonna use fold then we need a
function
takes two things
okay and uh each time the B is gonna be
an element from there
and the a will be
the a will be
okay it returns a result
foreign
in terms of results
catch the play again
takes a new element
so the results so we cannot when you
apply fold
you are going to have
Last Resort here
and then you take a new elements
okay
so for example
let me show you okay
fold
KF
okay we can show this
so that
let's see the
that
okay
now the question is
you know we can do that
um
so each time it Returns the result
that's first argument
so you want the right of function such
that
you want to
again we want that
so
new to this channel is that a coding
challenge yes
so this is
so we are doing the Advent of code
um
day seven you know day seven anyway so
we stuck on this I need to think about
this
um
you right now this is a problem okay in
Wolfram language
we need to turn a list of path into a
nested
uh
dictionary
okay so I want to focus on solving the
problem
so
so when you return
so F takes two arguments
and uh
the first argument should be so we are
trying to make that into
these
we are trying to create a function
that does that
what about our pattern matching
function
so many so in so many ways we need to
focus on what God cannot jump around
so
the result will be
association association you know
something like that
so right now I'm thinking of two ways
one is by Patent matching where you turn
a list into that
and for example this list into that
but the problem with pattern matching
yes you can do that but the problem is
that it does not accumulate like once
you assign to the tree
then it overrides the tree
so
a
so it would be so you know and this this
syntax of those is actually just this
okay
this is much simpler to understand
um
okay so you can use the pattern matching
to turn that into that okay yeah you can
do that
provided that X the tree is already a uh
yeah you can do that so use a pattern
matching so solution
solution is
let me let me say solution solution
use a pattern matching
into
okay
oh
and uh
yeah we can do that
then if we do that then that's solved
what do we need to do this I think we
got it solved okay forget about using
fold so let's try this pattern matching
solution
so a patent matching of that thing
okay let me show you guys okay
you can that syntax slash slash dot
means replace repeated okay so here you
wanna say
X whatever
followed by
X
low line low line
okay that means first element then
one or more element
okay
so you match this pattern when you see a
list you break it into two parts first
element then rest element
then you want to replace by
replaced by that okay
the first part is X this and this is the
tree
okay replace it by
that X
equals to
an empty Association okay
repeat that okay and this wipe
this y underscore underscore
they mean
one or more times yeah I think or zero
or more let's see
so we are doing pattern matching in
Wolfram language so let's go to uh
patterns
Panda matching syntax
okay
so we
here to
too low line
means
any sequence of one or more expression
one or more okay
so
no this is incorrect
because
this way here just add everything to the
root
so we
looks like we still need the nest
you know it can be done it's just that
we have to think about this
um
sequence of Expressions okay
any sequence of zero or more expressions
now if you do this
it's going just to add everything to the
root
you know
so can you use map then
map
yes function you don't know how many
uh better to use fold
fold
that
okay then when you return
when you return fold
will you return a thing
huh [ __ ]
okay I think I'm gonna go for a break
so
okay a break five minutes and I'll be
back okay
break five minutes
okay something like that
foreign
and back
okay so we need to
write a function that
the function
returns
the function returns we need to write a
function so such that
the function takes two arguments
and the F and uh second argument
and we need to actually apply
this function
to
the first argument
so we want
a function like that
okay let me show you what that means
we want the function
um okay
let's say A and B arguments okay and we
want it such that
uh hello Greek we want the function to
be such that a
applied to B okay this is
this is a function we want the function
takes two arguments A and B and the
function body is apply A to B
okay so this this is a function and when
we do
when we call
when we call this function
let's say to a list of values one two
three let's see what it returns okay
yep that's what we want okay so this is
closer to what we want
again the problem is turn this into that
okay into that
so
so this fold function is what we want
okay and so given a decent path like
that
we we can turn that into okay so but
this function needs to be Association
okay
uh it we it needs to be something like
that something like that
so
so the first argument needs to be the
tree
yeah so fold you can give an extra
argument which will be used as the first
of the first so this
this part will be the tree
okay so for example
try that
yeah it's it's missing absent so
that's right because you know each step
we need to add it to the association so
let's modify this
so at each step this function needs to
actually
add Association so argument a
[Music]
so what is the tree now
with the three the trees are empty
Association a dictionary okay
so the tree so the trees so so this
function takes two arguments the body
will be
take the first argument which is the
third tree which is the association then
then add a key that's right add a key B
and this key B
will
have a value of empty Association that's
right
so
okay
so so we are going to call this fold
function okay fold function let me show
you what how it works what does it do
so this fold function takes three
arguments fold by the way is just like
reduce in python or other languages you
know you
it takes several arguments the first
argument is a function the function
takes two arguments
then
you'll just Nest each time it got the
result it will feed the result as the
first argument to the function and the
second argument will come from the least
okay one two three
so you can do this
you can do this
okay so we got that
uh in part missing is not a symbol yeah
okay I can understand so let's try this
ABC key
because integers
uh integer can also be a key so why is
so
in the pile assignment is not a symbol
let's try this okay let's try to see
what happens
okay empty that's error what is the tree
the tree is still empty Association so
why is it wrong
so in order to see what is wrong
we can
use a fold list so it will show each
step
as a result okay
we got that because you know because
it's trying to assign a key
where the key doesn't exist something
like that
so let's
um
so let's not say the tree okay let's
remove this part and see
again
tag
tag string in a equals to B is protected
oh [ __ ]
he needs to be Association why why is it
not working
so this if we do that this will mean
so if we run this code
what it means the first step is that it
will
you know here's a body of the function
so
so he will feed now now instead of a b
let's use X Y so it's
so it's perhaps more clear
okay so the first step what will happen
is that you will take a
Let's ignore the tree for now okay
ignore the tree so you take this at
least you know then do reduce so the
first step
what happens is you get a
you'll get this a there
okay then
then you'll get B here
yeah that's the way that's that's what
we want
so it seems to work but it doesn't why
is it
should work not so far logically the
tree so let's just try that
first of all make sure what is the tree
the tree is still a
empty Association okay so now we do that
it should work
oh okay
foreign
I think I know why it's not working
because
at each step
at each step you
you return a thing which is
the thing that returned is you see
the thing that returned at each step is
this assignment
and what is the what is the result when
you do these assignments
you see it needs to be a symbol or it
needs to be some
some
it needs to be Association
so when you do this assignment it does
not return
this Association
you know the the key value here I mean
it does it doesn't return this empty
Association
so you need to return the association
okay we can do that
so
you needed to return the association
assign it
okay so what you can do is you put a
semicolon and the USA return that
okay I think that will work
you know the this part semicolon is a
shortcut for
like the lisps p-r-o-g-n
it it groups a bunch of Expressions into
one into one unit then Returns the last
expression so it returns this so we
so at each step we create a new key
then we return that Association okay
yeah
so now we try this
please
make it work
[ __ ]
can we actually do I mean this should we
can do this right
I mean this let's do this step by step
you see that works
that works and now what is the tree the
tree is association with one single key
that's correct now what if we do the
tree
a
we get a empty Association that's
correct
now you can say
yeah we almost got it to work but
there's some logic somewhere
so
so can we do this now can we do can we
say now we add a new key
B
equals to
Association the empty one
you see that also works
the value returned is the association
okay now
we can evaluate that that's an empty
Association that's correct and now we
can let's try the the tree it's going to
be nested key a is Association then of
that Association key B is an empty
Association
you see nested Association that's what
we want
so this will mean you know A and B is
the path
component of the path and this means
directory a contains
directory B and directory B is a empty
directory
so all these so far works
the problem is somehow trying to get
into fold now
yeah you have to create a directory I
mean you have to create a key dictionary
before the next one you cannot just do
this one shot
so um you know that's a that's what
we've been working on trying to figure
out
so you know again the problem is here
okay
in Wolfram language
um
so
so we are so we use fold okay so this
code is essentially should be correct x
y equals to Association
and uh
and return that
yeah so why is this not working so it
um
let's try our code again
so first of all it's clear
and it's clear that the the tree now
okay and now let's run this code
this code should um
with start with the tree
and return this value
I don't understand the key absent a
so this means it cannot find the key a
why can't I cannot it find the key let's
try again the 3A
so let's do it again so it so the first
step is the three a feeding to the
function x y
so you got the 3A equals to empty
Association
that's right
so Y is uh why is the what
show stack Trace yeah
now let's reduce this by
let's just say
not so much
missing key a you see that is a bobbin
missing key a but what
why are you missing key a
because this will mean
the tree
I don't know
so now
let's stop using fold then simply call
this function
and give it a argument two arguments the
first one is the tree of course the
second one is
a
okay let's run that
you see it's got a problem
so it says Association in part
assignment is not the same symbol
in pod assignment this here
here is not a symbol or something okay
let's try a different syntax let's not
use this
so instead we say
instead we say that uh
associate
Association
Association X and Y
you know so what and what I'm trying to
do here is that
we are trying to find a
alternative Syntax for these
and that alternative syntax will be
let's try it
so you say it's assignment okay
so Association
[Music]
oh I think maybe I understand
wait no
very annoying Association
associate two
we don't want to use associate two
we want
um
Association a PIN to prepend to know
what the [ __ ]
associate two let's see Association
magnify
okay Association
so you can assign like that where
associate is a symbol
whose value is an association
so when you do that the
that part
must be your symbol
that is why that that is that that is
why
we have the arrow
this X
is not always a symbol
because in our case that X becomes
is actually something like that
that's right so when you use these
syntax you know to
when you use this syntax to assign a new
key or change the value of a key of
Association
on the left hand side it must be a it
must start with some symbol
yeah but we do have symbol the symbol is
the tree
you know once you do this the left the X
becomes the tree
so and we have shown here you know it
evaluates to that
it's the tree the tree is a symbol
so
foreign
why does this line does not work
the tree
the tree is a is a empty Association
right
so we have a function here
takes two arguments X and Y
and the body of the function is this
so first of all it's set X
you know
um
y equals to an empty Association then it
Returns the
X racket y
o the return value is incorrect that's
right
you see the return value that X bracket
Y is just the empty Association
that's right
so when you have a empty Association
you know so this is the three this part
becomes empty Association then you add
that doesn't make sense that's why you
say that's why you see empty Association
in positive assignment is not the symbol
that we found the problem
so
we don't want to so we want the function
to return
this thing but not evaluated we don't
want it to be because if you evaluate
that the value is just empty Association
you want to
return this the how do you say this kind
of the syntax of that thing then
evaluate
yeah so we can do that
so we do that by
code okay
and this is getting very Advanced
Warframe programming language
okay we're gonna do this hold hold means
don't evaluate it
okay then you can say release hold
okay
to evaluate it
this is like least Marco very Advanced
far more Beyond this macro
yeah so you can you know actually take
some time to work it out so what you
want to do is you say you want to return
hold okay
hold it hold this entire thing
okay hold this expression
you want to return that then when the
function call happens you want to say
release hold
here okay so let's cut that
uh actually yeah
yeah she
let's say release hold okay so you want
to say here
okay then put this X Y inside
you see
you see this is about symbolic term
rewriting this is summary writing
Network or you can think of it as least
Marco everything is symbols
so again
this function
is applied to arguments here the tree
and the string a the three
let me explain the three is the empty
Association let's just make sure
assign it you know third tree is the
empty Association
so when the fun the function takes two
arguments x y
the first thing it does is release it
you know so you got this X Y form then
assign it to Association which is empty
you know assign it to a MTO Association
then return
return the held version of that just
that symbol x y
so when the function is scored again
you'll release that hold okay that is
what we want to do I think I'm pretty
I'm pretty sure something good but
probably could be wrong again
okay so now this uh release hold okay
here
okay and here the last part is gonna be
hold
okay so this is our function and apply
that let's do it
work
[ __ ]
yeah [ __ ]
so okay it's it's not working but let's
try this one time release holding
release hold missing key
why is it the [ __ ]
okay so let's see
let's say m okay what does it actually
do
uh you got uh
so you want it to return the symbol
God this is terrible you know this
shouldn't be this hard
something
you know we simply want to turn that
into that can we use this for me instead
let's just use eval let's use pattern
matching to transform it
then eval
yeah but when you but you have a nested
situation here
so when you want to turn a flat list
into a nested situation you have to use
Nest or fold or
or the repeated pattern matching slash
slash Dot you know one of these ways
that's
yes you essentially you have to use one
of these ways to turn a flat list
this represents a path okay so this is
not actually x x input this is uh
One path
turn this file path
represented as a list
into this
okay
and so a flat list into a Nestle form
there are several ways to do that one
way is to use
a repeated
um
pan imagine replacement okay this this
thing called is called
um
replace repeated you see there
there okay so
so this is the
um
you see slash slash
dot that's a shortcut syntax shortcut
so you can use that
to generate a nested situation from a
flat list or you can use fold which is
what we are trying to do
but so far failed or you can use nest
okay the difference between nest and
fold is that fold takes two argument you
can take a list of things
each time you take a new item from that
list
well if you use nest
again you know let me show you nest if
you use Nest it doesn't take
extra thing
it just
um
uh it just it just nests the function
you know five times
so it doesn't take a new input
so in our case we need to take a new
input each time from the least ABC
so therefore
we can use
you know the replace repeated or we can
use fold
it's possible to use Nest too but then
you have to embed you have to embed this
list into the function
you know you have to embed the list into
the function
but let's use fold okay for these small
like that suitable it returns that okay
fold
you know it creates nesting from a flat
list right makes sense
um
and now but
okay and basically we just want to get
these you see this this is a solution we
want to turn that into that
and we want to do this multiple times
for each different
you know path
so like why is it so difficult so we
want to turn of ladies into that
problem is
there are two problems one problem is
how do you get these two
um
you know if we want to do this turn that
into that
that's what we are doing with the fold
and
so why why is our fold release hole
doesn't work
you know let me show you how the whole
things work
hold one plus two okay it doesn't change
nothing but you can say
you can now say release hold
okay and you can do that
then it becomes three
so hold
simply kept this expression as is
you know that's why we want to keep that
as is
okay maybe we move this part Association
inside the release hold
yeah maybe
okay
she's [ __ ]
why why is this so hard what the [ __ ] is
it
okay maybe there's release hold all
[Laughter]
yeah God every time you do this whenever
there's a issue with the evaluation it's
very complex
okay it really removes only one layer of
hold it does not remove inner currencies
in nested hole that's the thing
so you want
um
yeah non-standard evaluation so
I thought there is a release or
okay evaluation control
uh evaluates immediate evaluate function
argument release hold
hold all complete
is there a release or I think there is a
release or
no well okay what is release
his uh system related
oh yeah it's real it's absolute Okay so
hold hold form defer
the evaluative given a wolfam language
input
okay hold evaluate and evaluate release
hold hold complete hold pattern let's
see hold
um
yeah these are very fairly complicated
[Music]
map hold
apply
apply at least to what
or complete and very very
complicated
attribute hold on
sequence hold
sequence object appearing in the
argument of function okay
okay I got something wait no I don't
know what is going on
okay uh
hold release oh yeah
function release hold why does this not
work
what about BDS
let's try hold form okay
no it's still doesn't work
let's let's see what is the tree
the tree is empty yeah
something is really wrong here I don't
understand
let's let's try evaluate
causes the expression to be evaluated
even if it appears as argument of
function
whose attributes specify should be held
unevaluated
okay
so evaluate inside hold
on Jesus so complicated
hold all
is an attribute no attribute is not what
we want attribute
no so we'll find language is just like
lisp where this symbol has many
properties you know you can attach
properties to this symbol
similarly in Wolfram language
symbols can have attributes you know
they call it attribute instead instead
of properties so you can give a function
or any any symbol several attributes so
when it's when a symbol
has the attribute hold or
then when it's evaluated as a function
it will not evaluate its arguments you
know so that's what this holder is for
okay so uh you know this is useful when
you want to implement your own if
statement or why a loop you know you
don't want to evaluate argument right
away you want to check if it's true or
not then evaluate this part or that part
so that you so that's that's when you
want to attach
these hold first hold rest you know
attribute you want to attach this
attribute to a symbol
so that's what this
code first
hold rest is also an attribute
and hold all
that's also an attribute okay that's
what these hold are for
okay
now however what we want to do is what
about hold or complete that's also an
attribute okay so you can attach it to a
symbol
you know just like lisps symbols
properties okay
so those are attributes hold all
complete hold first
hold
or hold first hold rest
hold all complete you know those are
attributes you attach to
symbols
now
hold is not an attribute you know hold
is just like a function
it you just attached some expression you
you know then it will not evaluate
anything in the expression
okay
well the way it works because the hold
has the attribute hold all okay so it's
kind of confusing okay
so that's so that's why we want to hold
this part
you know X bracket y because if you
don't hold it then
it is it just returns a empty
Association
so your function
returns a empty Association
so and each time it takes two arguments
you know it doesn't work because empty
your Association
you know it doesn't attach to the the
tree
and see where we are yeah so here is the
way we had it
you know this becomes empty Association
and you you know
so when the when when this evaluates
this x is a empty Association
and why uh
it's about assignment is not a symbol
yeah so this x becomes an empty
Association
and that y becomes this a
but this form
must begin with a symbol
we wanted to begin with the tree
okay but it's not
because this x bracket y
wait why does this why does this not
work
you know function
you know this
this should be
evaluate to this okay this equals to
Association
you know this should evaluate to
[Music]
yeah so we got a problem we don't I
don't know what the problem is
so there's something we don't understand
uh
this should return
[Music]
that
okay this should return this
oh exactly it did
wait no but we did assign it to our
empty Association
foreign
what
so right now it's missing a
yeah but we assigned it right here
why is it missing a well it's not
missing because we actually just
assigned
the the a should become the empty
Association I don't know what's going on
so let's modify this
let's use a different syntax like we
talked before so
instead of that okay let's write this in
a different syntax okay
right yeah here
so instead of that we
want to say associate
uh
okay
X
okay and right arrow
we write it this way they are equivalent
okay so let's write that way
it should be equivalent
so copy this line
and paste that
all right
copy
DD paste yeah
doing it same thing
same [ __ ] thing
not the variable with a value
and you get the tree
okay uh okay I think we're gonna I'm
gonna shut down then five people
failed today
this problem
pretty embarrassing
so
um
we have
you know the situation is that we have
at least a path
show them in column in one vertical
column so you can see
that
this each one of these represents a full
path
you know but as a list we want to turn
this x to into a tree structure
by using a nested dictionary
uh dig like Python's dictionary but in
Wolfram language that's called
Association okay
so it's like this associative list
so we are so the problem is to turn at
least a full path like that into a
nested dictionary and we failed at that
for the third time basically
and you know we worked previously two
hours for and we failed
so we have been trying to work on One
path at a time so basically this
represents one
you know one of these
path we want to turn this list into this
this will work by the way you know for
example if I run this
you know so you got the nested
Association
you know we got the association a
dictionary we got a key a whose value is
Association and it has a key B whose
value is a again Association
so this expression works
so for that you can
but we have problem you know we have
problem right now turning this into that
just for this one
single path that's what we've been stuck
on for the past hour
and
and uh
incredible incredible I can't I can't
believe I stuck on this problem
uh [ __ ] this kind of
um
yeah so so you know we tried a few
things to turn a flat list into a
into a nested structure we can use you
know repeated replace or we can use fold
or we can use nest
but apparently forward is more natural
however
we are running into this problem I can't
figure out exactly
and the reason
seems to be let's do hold again let's
let's try a hold again the reason seems
to be
yo we got what
we got bracket five and yeah okay
the reasons seems to be it's returning
empty you know we got this evaluation
situation you see
you see you see here the error message
makes it clear what's going on
the arrow is basically we have a empty
thing there
Association you know that empty
Association that
need to be a symbol like needs to be the
tree
okay that part needs to be you know this
part if this is
the tree will work
you see this is up this should be the
tree but somehow it's not getting it
you know why Chen Soo why why is that
um you know maybe you know uh Wolfram
language can you say quickly quickly I
think there's a delay like 30 second
delay between I seen your message and
you know because I'm don't know who fan
language but did did several tests okay
so what is the problem
um yeah so
so we uh it's getting an empty list
or maybe you should return
because the value of that weight
yeah I don't
there's something
so do you know quickly we need I I'm
gonna cross because I I think maybe I'll
shut down I need to go
this is two hours no good one o'clock
when
one two three
almost three hours maybe because
uh for the first time you would evaluate
us Association
oh
no well because we give a tree here you
see
so you know for example if we can move
this third tree
and add a new argument
you know that's how you that that's how
you can give a first argument to fold
let's
for example
fold
let's say for a function f the first
argument let's say a then let's say at
least
b c d
you see the first argument will be a
you know so here the first argument is
the trees there is somewhere
we can use print
okay so we can use print here
to figure out what's our problem so add
a print
so
you know what we're gonna do is we add a
print statement
debug
okay we want to print what the [ __ ] is
this X and Y
okay print the argument okay now let's
see
ah so you are right
wait okay
oh the first part the first time you
need to hold the the tree
I think I think you are right
Maybe
oh that GA is protected what
we need to reuse go back to release hold
okay
something like that something like that
okay we uh
so let's see let's print okay so when
the first time it's called
it's holding the tree
the second time it's called
so can we do release all
okay so we need a release hold
okay is there a release or
let's let's try it yeah
okay what happens if you have release
hold
then you have hold
then you have nested hold let's say one
plus two okay let's evaluate that
paste it
oh you don't only release one time
let's let's just add another release
hole this is just hack hack it [ __ ]
yeah let's just add another release hold
yeah where it should be uh
where is uh what
too many
ways here
wait we we need to forward here
right
uh too many [ __ ]
foreign
here
so let's
okay let's just do here let's do it
twice
where's our fold
here okay
it's really hold twice
and maybe we need
you know the
evaluation precedence
through this whole time
random hacking is not gonna do any good
you need to understand it but do it
so yeah you are correct I think you are
correct
in that
okay I don't know so I think that's it
for today we failed another three hours
okay
bye guys
I'm gonna walk offline I need a break
yeah bye guys Happy New Year end of the
year bye