hello welcome to another episode of s
talk show we are going to do Advent of
code day
six okay ad Advent of code day six so
let's go to today's talk show let's
begin
it
uh podcast talk show vend of code day
six so this is
today uh let's begin wam language pop it
out refresh
yeah oh yeah so my keyboard is this is
kesis
360 the wired version okay I have a
review on my website just search for
keyboard kesis 360 and this is Ultimate
hacking keyboard
switch back so you can see so okay so
let's begin coding actually
so Advent of code today's uh
there okay let's see the problem if you
are here say hi okay
hello number
six uh let's see day six Advent of code
day six
magnify let see weird arrangement of the
problems you know so this this is a mini
logic puzzle figure out how are how do
they arrange this Advent of code day
numbers you see 1 2 3 then four comes
here five comes
here how how did they you know what is
the logic behind it that's a mini puzzle
okay but anyway we're going to do day
six I have not read the problems yet
so I will try to finish it in
our at least part one okay the fairy
quickly brings you across island island
after uh this is day six yes wait for it
after asking around you discover that
there's indeed normally a large pile of
sand
somewhere
here but you don't see anything besides
lots of water and a small island where
very are you trying to as you try to
figure out what to do next you notice a
post on
wall drop a on day six on what day you
will drop it what you talking about okay
trolls go
away uh you know you type of for Chan
type of people uh that does doesn't do
anything to
me so uh so wait so let's double check
video check audio check and uh yeah yeah
I'm good to go so back to day six so as
you try to figure out what to do next
you notice the post on war near the
fairy dark boat races boat races uh open
to public Grand pric is an all expensive
paid trip to desert island that must be
where the sand comes from best of all
the boat races are starting in just a
few minutes you manage to sign up as a
competitor in the boat races just in
time you or the organizer explains that
it's not really a traditional race
instead you will get a fixed amount of
time during which your boat has to
travel as far as it can and you win if
your boat goes the farest
farest as part of signing up you get a
sheet of paper your personal input that
lists the time allowed for each race and
also the best distance ever recorded in
that race to guarantee you win the grand
prize you need to make sure you go
farther in each race than the current
record
holder okay so appears to be many
races
okay you that you make make sure you
have to make sure you go further you go
farther in each race than the current
record holder
so there seems to be multiple number of
them and uh in each one is there one
record holder for all of them or each
race have a different record holder you
don't know I don't know so the organizer
brings you over to
the can you see it yeah so the organizer
brings you over to the area where the
boat races are held the boats are much
smaller than you expected they are
actually toy boats each with a big
button on top just like ADV van of code
to problems holding down the button
charges the boat okay uh and releasing
the button allows the bat to move oh
okay charge and move uh charge stop
release
move so it's like the opp oos it of the
gas
pedal bools move faster if their buttons
was held longer but time spent holding
the button counts against the total race
time
what you can only hold the button at the
start of the race and boat won't move
until the button is released okay you
can only do it once
so you press to char
and release to
go and you can only do this one time in
the beginning okay for
example time 7 15 30 distance 9 40
200 the this document describes three
races okay the first race last 7
milliseconds the re
distance in this race is 9
mm
what okay the first race last seven so
the first
row
is how long is the race the second row
is the distance the record in distance
okay okay the second race last 15 m M
milliseconds correct the record distance
in this race is 40 milliseconds millimet
Okay the third race is 30 last 30
milliseconds record distance in this
race is 200 mm okay your toy boat has a
starting speed of 0 mm per
millisecond for each whole millisecond
you spend at the beginning of the race
holding down the button the boat's speed
increases by 1 mm m per
millisecond
Jesus so when you hold down the button
the
duration will increase your boat
speed increases by 1 mm per millisecond
so increases
by so you hold it for one
unit of
time your boat speed increases one unit
of distance
something so because the first race
lasts seven milliseconds you only have a
few
options okay the
uh so so the last something something
second means that's the duration of the
race that's given so one of the race is
seven
unit of time the second another one is
15 units of time so this is a limited
amount of time for the entire race
during this time you can kind of decide
how long you're going to hold the button
something like that okay so so because
the first race lasts 7 milliseconds you
only have a few
options don't hold a button at all that
is hold it for zero milliseconds at the
start of the race the boat won't move it
will have traveled zero millimeters by
the end of the race okay you have to
charge it you have to you have to press
the button at least once otherwise you
go
nowhere hold the button for 1
millisecond at the start of the race
then the boat will travel at the speed
of 1 millisecond per millisecond 1 mimer
per millisecond for 6 milliseconds okay
right so you have a limited limited
period of
time you know you know limited period of
time then during this time you have kind
of decide how long you're going to hold
the buttons so this is kind of like race
condition you know raise condition is a
computer programming Jon but this is not
exactly a rise condition but literally
it is a raise condition so given a set
of time amount of time fixed amount of
time you have to de decide how long
you're going to hold the button and
uh so then the rest of the time your
boat is going to move according to how
long you held the button so the problem
is a maximization problem or
optimization problem so essentially you
want to
determine how long you're going to hold
you know you you want to find the point
how long you going to hold it so the
Bool Mo moves the maximum distance
something like that okay option hold the
button for three something after it's
remaining four something travel time the
boat will have gone 12 mm okay so let's
see you hold it for 3
milliseconds that means your speed is
three units per second let's drop the
Millie the Advent the code okay
let's just drop the m m milliseconds and
Millet let's just say so you hold
it for 3
seconds then that means your speed will
be three distance 3 m/
second then if you hold for 3 seconds
you have four more REM remaining seconds
so 4 * 3 your speed is
12 your distance moved okay then hold
for 4 milliseconds and something
something so you if you hold for four
right then your speed is 4 m/ second but
now your time for the boat to move is
three 7 minus 4 = to 3 so 3 * your speed
which is 4 4 * 3 is 12
so okay so we can skip the rest of like
I don't have to read it stupid I
already got it so let's see let's let's
just scan it hold 4 six six then we
travel six hold for seven you hold the
entire duration so you travel
nothing
okay uh opinion on pas language and its
creator worth I think he's a great
computer scientist worth reading I mean
well okay he's a great he's one of the
great computer scientist okay the
Creator Pascal now is it worth reading
that's a different question because
there's a lot tons of great computer
scientists let's say hundreds of them in
the past 60 you know since 1950s in the
past 70 years there are hundreds of
great computer computer scientists but
is it worth to read them that's another
different question because there's so
many you know literature you know you
can you know if you really want to read
one guy all his works you know like
Donald G Stefan wolf they are all great
computer scientists you know the latter
one is more of a phist anyway so there
are so too many of them okay if you
count you know the inventor of
networking protocols you know there's
thousands of them greatest they are gen
genius you know or or not not
necessarily genius but they are great
but is it worth to read them that's a
different question because there
are there are literally millions or
millions of uh books you know on
computer science or anything related
about programming
so
usually in gen generally speaking it is
not
worth your time to read the original
writings by these greatest guys okay
that that that comes with the context so
if you are a beginner if you are let's
say a college student University student
okay your time is best spend to read
textbooks because or Wikipedia Wikipedia
is what I do you know or before
Wikipedia it's encyclopedia because that
that kind of format allows me to jump to
specific topic I don't know and with
links to other articles so I
can I can precisely read what I want to
know okay so anyway that's another
another thing that's a pref that's about
preference about sources of information
anyway so there are millions of books so
if you are a beginner beginning
mathematician you know if you are still
in college your best time is best spend
to primarily read just textbooks or or
or Wikipedia okay
because that is a cumulative condensed
and M and you know in a nice format and
all the information came from all the
greatest mathematicians or or
programmers or scientists you know in a
well organ ized format that is the most
efficient Source read read
textbooks
now if you just do that of course that's
kind of boring but you know so sometimes
occasionally you read some people some
of the greatest person's uh original
writing for me for example when I was
younger that used to be mathematicians
you know who died 100 years
ago galwa Newton leanis actually I
haven't read them you know because when
you read the original 100 years ago or
200 years ago the English also changed
or sometimes they are in Latin or you
know or translated version so it it you
know the time has changed so it
doesn't really benefit you that greatly
so anyway so if you if you are college
student your primary focus you should be
textbooks but you should also you should
you should you should you know
occasionally read some of the greatest
original writings so because that gives
you kind of the different idea how they
these people thought originally also you
also learn some via context you also get
to understand part of the history of the
subject such as programming or computer
languages or computer science okay so
worth is one of the guy I can recommend
I I have not read him though I know this
I know his name because I you know i'
I'm old I've been 30 years coding uh
let's see 30 or 20 30 I've been coding
30 years so I read you know occasionally
run
into uh these people their work and what
they done done so I would say the Pascal
inventor is a great guy okay what about
programming Wiki is not good
uh okay focus on the topic okay we're
going to do uh you know Advent of code
so okay I understand the problem now
next since the current record for this
race is 9 mm so wait so what is the
record okay so the second row is the
record there are actually four different
ways you could win you could hold the
button for two or three or four or five
milliseconds at the start of the
race 2 three four five let's see two
yeah so the stupid record holder who
don't know
mathematics who don't know who is not
aware of
optimization
algorithms but anyway
so in this second race you could hold
the button for at least four
milliseconds and at most 11
milliseconds and best and beat the
record a total of eight different ways
to win in the third race you could hold
a button for 11 seconds and no more than
19 seconds and C be the record a total
of nine ways you could win oh okay so
it's not just optimization problem it's
like
combinatorial among these different ways
that you could win you probably want to
select one of them let's see to see how
much margin of error you have determine
the number number of ways you can beat
the record okay you so you you you you
don't just optimize you find all the
possible um combinations
so okay that beats a number so to see
how much margin of Errors you have
determine the number of ways you can be
the record in each race in this example
if you multiply these values together
oh you get
288 you get 288 so 4 * 8 * 9
because okay four is the number of ways
you can beat the guy for the first race
eight is a diff uh number of ways you
can beat the guy so find the number of
the ways the number of ways to beat the
record then you multiply you get their
product another stupidity of Advent code
you know why do they want the product
this is because why don't they just say
give the sequential number of ways
489 that seems simpler but Advent of
code they want a
number why they want a single number
because that makes it easier to kind of
submit the you know the answer like the
answer is always just one single number
but again and you have
ambiguities so the solution for this to
input is 489 right you multiply them
together but what what if um you know I
made a mistake my solution is
849 but I multiplied them together I got
the same number so so I also
win okay so that's a design one of the
design
issue
but the chance of that for those for the
product to be the same number is Slim
practically SL speaking okay anyway
that's about the analysis of
this day six problem part one okay
determine the number of ways you could
beat the record in each
race okay what do you get if you
multiply this number right they want the
product okay so let's begin so this
let's commence there's only three
um input okay let's commence
coding
uh yeah uh
what commence coding okay so the input
is kind of like like that so you want
um first of all you want to turn this
into a list into a wolam language list
okay so into whatever your language
so read string
[Music]
um no not read not read string read
string is from a file so you
want split the string input you want to
split
by let's let's just say by default is
SPL split by any wi space
okay
uh input two equals to okay let's try to
finish this at this rate I'm already 22
minutes okay at this rate I won't finish
but I shall finish it in two hours Let's
let's say I I'm not going to you know
this is interesting because I'm doing
this live so there's a speed issue so it
will be interesting in some of the next
videos I'll do a Advent of a code where
the only goal is to see how fast I can
finish a problem you know so I don't
speak I don't talk like you just stop my
video and I just talk for two minutes to
explain what I'm doing then then it's
all quiet I'm just coding and see how
fast how fast speed
coding because there are people will
complain anyway
so that would be interesting A variation
of the style of coding so anyway today
I'm just going to talk I like to talk so
let's go
slowly so now you you got the input so
input is actually kind kind of
the
okay I'm just goingon to solve this
quickly
so yeah I'm just do it you're going to
do it in easy way okay input two equals
to so input
three uh in in so we're going to split
so let's split the first one by actually
uh so we got a list of items you want to
select them only if they are numbers
okay let me show you some interesting W
language so
cases okay let's look at the
documentation for string cases what does
it do magnify magnify and uh turn on
JavaScript string cases pattern give a
list of substrings okay that's not what
we want we
want okay cases which select elements
from a list of items okay so
cases so first of all
we split in we got input two is a list
of uh these items
okay let's put it here okay uh okay so
so let's put it
there so we got a list of items
then
h no you run into the wind window size
problem okay anyway so you see this this
this is uh let me show
you
tree form at percent means last output
so you see each one of these item is
actually a string so once you got that
then you want so this is a list you want
to
select input two and what is a criteria
the criteria is a function and wait is
it a function or is a pattern pattern
okay so it's a pattern
so okay pattern then we say anything
where the head of the thing is
a oh God pattern
um okay something like this
okay let's see if that works number form
number okay so I
forgot let's look at the string
Expressions which is a alternative to
regular expression or number string okay
so here you
say number string is a pattern
okay let's see if that
works paste run empty
so yeah string string string um so here
is so the pattern will
be
okay stream match
Q yeah actually I don't want patterns
okay so I don't want I don't want
cases I think I want select select
select something from a list with a
criteria here the criteria is a function
so there are two ways to select a sub
list one is select one is cases select
takes two argument the first one is a
list the second one is a function
okay and cases the second one is a
pattern you know act you know you can do
both ways because you can always convert
a function to a pattern or pattern to
function
but
but I can show you both ways actually
actually I should stick to one one
approach you know otherwise this video
is not going to end so let let me do the
select first okay so select if so if
that argument is a
string so if x is a string and
uh well actually not just a string you
also want it to be a number
okay ah God this is getting
starting to get
stuck okay so let me let me let me let
me just think about this so a
pattern a
pattern such that it is a string
and so if you want to do this so a
pattern it's a string but Al also with a
condition
that so X we give a name to the pattern
X okay so also with the condition
that uh yeah okay so actually this
function we can just do that string
match
Q X yeah and
uh okay okay so select from input two
with this function what this function do
is take the argument X if the X
matches that pattern the number string
is a pattern means it's
all numbers okay so if we run that copy
it
see nonatomic expression expected at
position one in select nonatomic
expression nonatomic so what is input
two oh input two is not defined oh we
didn't oh okay so we we forgot to Define
this select
all paste paste run there it is you see
we got just a purely list of numbers now
we can also do this with
cases uh so in this cases we will just
have to do basically the same thing
here uh now if you haven't coded wam
language you probably don't understand
what I'm doing but this should return
the same thing you see so anyway so
let's comment that let's use a function
so
select from this list and with this
function okay now that let's say
input three okay then all we have to do
we have to do another thing is to
um you see now it's this is a flat list
we want to make it so that we want to
partition it let me just show
you partition
takes two arguments the input and we
want to group it by three let me show
you what it
means oh we forgot to Define input three
so Define input
three okay then partition
it so you see this is a very different
way of doing computation from typical
python Java
C++ you know you in those languages you
don't pass this input like that rather
you first of all SP split by new line
then you get a line like that then you
split by
yspace okay then you got a list of items
then you drop the first item okay then
you got a list of
numbers you know that's a typical way in
other languages but I'm going into a
variety showing you different style so
you split by y spaces okay
then then you split you don't even split
by new line new line you just split by y
spaces so you got a bunch of
items like that then
you then you use a function to filter
out this elements that's not a number
string okay then you partition it you
partition it to this form we want okay
it it this is um I would say least
efficient but it's faster I mean faster
in the sense if you are doing prototype
this is faster
okay okay so we got the partition let's
say let's call this input four so we get
into a habit of always put a assign it
to a variable so that way it's easier to
see which uh is what
then in eventually we're going to merge
them because we don't you know merge
them into one single
line why double glasses that's been
explained in each of my video okay one
is near citedness the other one is old
man's reading glass
okay it it's been explained in past
videos so many times opinion on Pascal
why about what about programming
language wi can not good what's your
advice guys that's that's that that
topic which programming language to
learn I talked a million times go to
cali. info on top this a few video watch
them okay you
know so by now I have done 500 something
videos for in the past three years okay
so anyway partition get us that input so
so let's concentrate back to the problem
so we got time and distance so we want
to rearrange so let's do a
transpose
uh okay so let me just show
you why this is interesting oh you did
you assign it not
yet okay okay so you transpose it so you
got this pair this this is more natural
for our for for us so 79 so let's think
about the algorithm how do you solve it
79 so seven is the total duration you
have and N is the the record you want to
beat okay so let's think
about so seven so seven is so seven so
you
[Music]
can the possible ways to so here is the
problem the combinatorial problem you
want to represent seven as a sum of two
numbers so 7 equals to 0 + 7 or or 1 + 6
or 2 + 5 okay 3 4 five 6 7 different
ways to repres % seven in terms of two
sum sum of two numbers okay 5
4 3 2 1 Zer so they are these ways to
represent
seven um and you know the so the First
Column represent how much how long you
hold down the button
okay so you partition them like that I
mean you know you partition the seven
there's a
proper term for that I think it's called
Partition partition of a
number then you can find all sort of
algorithm partition number Theory okay
so you see there it is in number Theory
and combinatorics a partition of a
negative integer n also called integer
partition is a way to write in a sum of
positive positive integers Okay so in
this case the general case it doesn't
matter how many of them but in our case
we just want two so we want partition 7
into two integers so anyway these are
the different ways then for each one so
there is a result
though so this will equals to so in
general you have a for
example then you have equal so the the
equal will be the final distance
traveled
so so that means a a becomes your speed
is that true you hold for 1 second you
your speed is 1 second one one m one
meter okay if you hold for 2
second giving a speed of 2 mm right so
very simple so so the First Column is
your speed
basically then basically you want speed
times speed a * speed so trial so
trivial B is the remaining second so a *
b gets your distance you traveled okay
so that then you
want okay so a * B then you want to you
want this number to be greater than
greater than the given you know the
given uh what is the given record you
know the
given
record okay so first of all so first
okay so let me
explain let's explain the problem from a
mathematician's point of view this is
how I solve problems analyze it to
death okay so am I still
good is this
interesting is my live show interesting
eight people watching
concurrency okay
so so you got this uh so this is Trivial
in Wolf language because there's a
function that do does this
partition so anyway
so so let me write down so people can
understand
list or possible
partition of the number into
two int
okay here's possible
partitions and
uh multiply them you get the distance
traveled okay
okay so what else
so so D let's say d equals to A * B
okay uh let's write
this D is a
distance okay
so okay then you want to find
such that D distance greater than
greater or equal or greater let's
see uh greater
than greater than the record okay record
then
first
part then multiply them
all is the answer
okay okay so now the heart of the
problem is to find this partition in
well in fact this partition is so simple
you don't need you don't need some fancy
wolam algorithm you
just you know it's just one two three
what the it's just one two 3 four
five okay let's
begin let's begin coding the
shed okay so now you got input so now
you want to increment
so
so we can you know there there's so many
ways to do this one of the ways if you
you know one one of the concern is
whether you are worried about
efficiency last time day five we got
stunned by effic efficiency run out of
problem because if you are not concerned
about efficiency you can simply generate
a list you know all the list you know
just go or if you are concerned you
don't want a intermed mediate long list
then you do some kind of loop you know
you just you know it's very easy you
know Loop and check Loop and check so
you don't get a you don't first of all
generate the entire list so let's see so
we need to look at the get your personal
input just so simple oh notice big
numbers so you want to be
careful so pop this back showing browser
so this is today's talk show and go to
the
top and uh let's say advant of code
input let's go to my directory and uh
Advent of code pass in let's copy that
close okay let's make a link so this is
going to be Advent code day six input
okay user input so cut open paste save
close make a link make a
list show in
browser there it is our advant code user
input
okay so what's next uh yeah so yeah
let's have a look at the user input is
it is it a humongous
okay so 95 to 1,000 that's small so if
you're going to generate the entire list
is just 1,000 items 2,000 items right uh
yeah so many
ways so in this case I'm just going to
generate a whole list I don't care about
the about the Advent
okay pop this back to um wait make
wait
what wait
wait oh get did a d bunch of
oh
make a backup okay showing browser
yeah still good still good now pop it
out okay back to here so
now so now now
we solve the problem okay so let's see
so given a pair that's a duration and
record you want to go through so the key
is this things so let's try to start to
write them out in code okay so the key
is kind of like
this
if
that return
a right something like that
okay two numbers if that
is oh so
um yeah so h
so first let's write a function okay X
and Y so let's say AB so it's compatible
to our naming so you don't get confused
okay so function
AB uh let's kind of trying to capture
this this this is we're going to we have
to do this anyway so this here is a if
statement if AB equals to record then a
else
else zero in this case lse one because
eventually you're going to product add
them all
together
so so AB so what is A and B A and B is
um what is a and b oh a a and b is the
partition of that number
so
so we can do a
loop let's
see you know we don't care about speed
because the Advent of a code there's no
criteria so we just do whatever you know
this is one of the thing that annoys me
about event of code because o chaos is a
number so on internet you
know when you code you know so many
different languages people don't really
look into about efficiency or not they
only see like this code does this gives
the answer so if it's shorter or it's
dramatic in some way or it's lot of you
know it's incomprehensible you get
points right so if you really care about
all kind of issues in this input like
day five whether they have identity map
or you know you uh like wor for nothing
you don't you don't get points you know
nobody you know unless the person dig
into exactly how your code works you
know nobody cares so this is one of the
thing that annoys me because I tends to
always come out with the most utmost
correct and efficient
solution so in this case since they
don't care let's just you know Brute
Force would force would force the
out of
it
so you know if we're going to boot Force
let's just um let's yeah let let's do
some interesting things let's look into
WM languages number
[Music]
Theory facilities okay let's
look there is a
partition you know let's use the number
theoretical partition
function let's say what what is
partition partial D okay that's partial
differential equation or
something but we
want number Theory partition of a number
okay let's see what is partition P gives
a number PN of unrestricted partitions
of integer that is like almost what I
want integer mathematical function
suitable for both symbolic and numerical
manipulation Partition p automatically
thread over this okay so partition PN
gives a number PN of
unrestricted partitions of integer okay
I'm not sure what it does okay so let's
say seven what uh wait
seven oh okay so it
just you know it just give all
possible
what oh it gives the number the number
PN of unrestrict so there are total of
seven ways I mean 15 ways to rep seven
or sum of integers something like that
okay now partitions Q oh oh wait in uh
there I I saw inter
partion
okay I'm not sure what that is let's
just explore okay try them
out let's say what is this partition Q
okay partition Q is
five gives a number qn of partitions of
integer n into distinct Parts okay in
this case you cannot have repeated you
know uh issues okay so but the function
we want
is integer partition
okay the function we want is probably
this one let see integer partitions and
gives a list of all possible ways to
partition the integer n into smaller
integers okay it gives partition into uh
into ad most let's try this okay
inter part integer partitions 7even okay
see okay this is the diff the number of
ways you can partition
seven what do you mean y integer
partition have you read the problem have
you been
watching
so or did you just came on uh integer
partition is what we want okay so let's
give a second
argument uh
that's wait what does that mean integer
partition
two okay so at most two elements so now
we want exactly two
elements
okay
[Music]
now so why so 7 07 is out so is
70 so they are
older oh okay so interesting so many of
these case are
redundant 0 770 they don't count because
that's the case for any number and then
you have one two then the orderer does
the older count so if the order doesn't
count so you have 1
162534 1
162534 right the order doesn't
count then you have this possible
partitions integer partition of seven so
and now
[Music]
you so now but the order in our case
actually matters so for each one of them
you have the order matters okay
so so 61 means hold for 6 seconds and uh
then one let's see does the order matter
because ultimately we want to do a *
B so since it's multiplication
multiplication the order does not matter
in other words in mathematicians shgon
is called
communicative or Community uh what what
is the word commun um you know
multiplication anyway order doesn't
matter okay so in our case order doesn't
matter either so once you got the P
partition you just multiply each pair
then if that number is greater than the
record then you return
the first part of the pair
wait
so because this problem okay it's a bit
tricky
because you see the
old let's see again does
it so for seven if the duration is seven
you can have hold for 1
millisec so it runs for six seconds so
you total got six or you can hold for 6
millisecond then your speed is six so
the result is also six so you see they
are the same so the they are the same
but
however the ends the question ask
you so you can hold for 1 millisecond or
you can hold for six millisecond the
result distance is the same okay like
this one six case right but now you see
it tricky because
now okay in that case the one six pair
doesn't count so because the solution is
489 the number of ways you can beat the
record in each race so actually so
the the order will even the order
doesn't matter but they will count twice
okay so this means if you care about
efficiency there's more ways to
save your computation but anyway so the
solution is 489 so let's see in the case
of 489 wait how does
it oh so the first example you have four
possibilities four possibilities in this
first example of 7 second
duration you have four
possibilities why
four so what is the record the record is
nine
okay oh okay so 6 * 1 is six that's
smaller than nine so it doesn't count
Now 52 and 43 both them their product is
greater than nine 5 2 is 10 43 is 12
greater than 9 but however for each one
of them they count twice because you
have the order the difference so the
total possible ways to be the record for
the
first race is four ways you see these
two pairs times
two so that's why it's four you see It's
Tricky so we know the order doesn't
matter so if the order doesn't matter
okay so
you so wait so what uh wait so if a * B
greater than record then what you do
then you count it as
two you know because two ways otherwise
zero okay then you sum this
number it's going to to be the total
possible ways okay let's this's
comment okay
so then you apply this function to a
list to this partition list so let's
copy that let's just do a let's just do
a
yeah let's just do a example okay so we
don't care about this mathematical
thing so for example we
can integer partition seven okay integer
partition to two
then
then then you select just like we did
before you select um
you select this
list then
your your function is this
okay and the
function wait you select the list the
function needs to take one arguments
okay you select from a list okay
okay
so okay so we kind of need to uh Nest it
function actually
[Music]
so let me just code so width is the
local
variable x equals
to
X first element okay then b equals
to second element
okay so X is one of the these pairs
right then you assign them to A and B to
break them into two
elements then if a equals to B is
greater than the record but what is the
record well the record is the record
came
from uh the current record came from the
second part of the input
okay so I can kind of I can let me just
hardcode it for now so I can show you
how this works so the record is nine in
this first case Okay so let's do
it okay error so you got some error
somewhere uh let's see what what is your
problem Oh you you forgot to copy the
the whole thing nested
pan empty that's not
correct so we select out of
these and
uh empty that's not correct so the
function is this
function this function takes
X oh you need to map wait
select function with AAL B why is it
empty
okay
hi KAS hi FK hi Hank of
flamio white double
glasses stupid question you know that
question being answered a thousand
times okay so Focus why is this not
working
so a is the
first part so
X oh wait you oh oh
right you need to return
true okay so I know what's going on so
because you need
to return true so you don't even
actually you don't care about what is
actual uh pair you read you only care is
is that you count the number of them so
you don't want to use select you want to
use count okay something like
that uh now let me this is a good time
to for me to introduce saam Language
tutorial you can download it free just
following this link you get the w engine
you know I talked about that many times
so anyway wfam Language tutorial then
you got a bunch of my best
videos Exposition on the wolam
language uh where's the video okay now
it finally showed up though you know
I've done probably
100 on you know tutorial on wolam
language okay so search for Wam Language
tutorial then what we need is about
the a function that counts the number of
elements in a list According to some
criteria okay so what is that function
name list operations let's see position
your list operations get parts of list
add elements delete elements change
elements check item exist list all the
functions okay sort and so on this
restructure this combinatoric join Union
different where is account
uh so you know you have join Union
intersection list combinations tple
subsets that's combinatorial and
permutation list restructure restructure
we've have used partition split split by
gather we want some kind of count okay
flatten that's not we want list order
sort uh okay rotate rotate left okay
check item existence that's right
count now count does a does count by
um by a pattern okay they always work by
count by pattern so let's use count
then so instead of Select we should use
count okay
okay count takes two arguments the first
is a list the second is a pattern that
determines okay so in this case the
pattern is going to be let's remove this
function the pattern is going to be
that a anything B
anything okay and with with a condition
such
that such
that a * B greater than 9
okay let's try that let's just blindly
try
it two that's correct because this 52
and 43 now once we got that number we
need to multiply by two because 52 is
one answer that beats the record 25 is
also the answer beats the record it's
because it's
symmetric
so so this so we already like got a
solution so let's remove that to the
code explanation
part you know just show some move
language thing
uh actually let's delete
that anyway so this count works okay so
then you just times
two space is a implicit multiplication
in W language okay so you just times two
that gets you the total number
of things okay then you do the same for
a second and the second um race then you
do it again for the third
race then then you got
it okay let's we can try the second we
can try the you know let's just try
um right so the second race is what 1540
let's
try 15 is the input and 40 is the number
okay so
paste
eight
correct Okay the third one is what
30200 okay
30 record 200
okay
10 I'm incorrect what the
oh
wait what the third one is
3200 so I got the number
correct and so why is
it oh God we got run into
issues let's
see integer
partition
wait so why is it uh okay so the
count let's say select let's say cases
okay one two three four five these five
items oh
identity problem you see this
155 they it you know you the two numbers
are the same it only count as
one tricky
okay so okay so you got that issue
okay
so so we want to what do we want to do
so oh God this so we have to do extra
check now it's getting
cold okay so so yeah so there's a case
of
identity if the pair of numbers are the
same you don't multiply by two Okay so
you so okay let's start code
okay so you can first of all do a
integer partition okay
then
you yeah okay
so you don't want to you don't want
Count okay you want cases okay so you
want to return all the possible
cases okay then once you got all the
possible for list of
pairs
then then you want to check
if wait
so let's see if I can do a
transformation within this function yes
you
can okay
so
so actually you can do count again wait
can
you no account doesn't allow you that so
you need cases you need to R return all
possible cases so so once this is true
you
return if
a equals
to B you
return one else you return two okay so
let me show you
this okay so we are working on the third
column 30
200 30 200
okay run it so that's a number
so so you add then you just add them
together total at percentage percentage
means the last
output so you got nine okay so does it
check check okay so here this is what we
want okay so we don't do count anymore
okay so so far so good everything
checked out okay so now we we just apply
this function to the entire thing
okay uh okay so we're going to map this
function to uh let let me let me let me
write in a way so you can understand
function this is the body of the
function then we map okay okay we map
two elements the
element input five map to this input
five list and uh the first element is a
function okay so we map this
function and uh so the function X so
this 30 will be changed to X X this 200
actually the 30 will be changed to the
first part of the input
okay then the the record will be the
second part of the input okay
so once you do that you just got a bunch
of list okay okay we forgot something
integer
partition input five do we have input
five yeah we do so input five so we map
it to input F you forgot wait what did
you
forget so map a function then
you X
cases okay
it should
work uh so when is the integer partition
position one of integer partition seven
must be a rational
number yeah why is it not a rational
number I don't get
it so cases integ
partition and here is the second
argument first
argument input
five
let's see map thread okay let me let's
see so map thread does parallel map okay
so let's call map
thread so let me show you what's going
on okay map
thread
[Music]
function list okay and list is going to
be input five okay and what is the
function the function is going to be
this
function okay but now this function now
takes two
arguments X and Y okay
so so let's name it something more
easier to understand
duration
record okay so this part
is
duration and this part
is record
okay let's remove the common okay so I
think this is it
let's see if we get errors or not okay
there's some errors so what is
the same
problem so function takes two arguments
duration and record and here is the body
of a function now what does this yeah so
the body of
function okay let's just for the sake of
debugging
let's make it simple let's just do that
okay let's just return the argument
itself right okay very simple now but
what what what is the problem you run
into let's see the function duration
records interger
partition
what okay let's try to change this
function by
that
integer partition 72 must be a rational
number integer partition
72 what do you mean it must be a
rational
number oh
string we forgot to turn this the the oh
God string to
number okay we because our input is now
not you see our
input you know it shows like a number
bit but actually it's a string because
in wolarm language it doesn't display
the quote if you want to display the
quote you have to
say ah
if you want to display the quotes
you have to
say yeah my
keyboard you have to say input form so
that shows you the quotes you see now
you just you just need to turn that into
expression two expression now those are
numbers for example I can show you now
input
form those back slashes back slashes you
see are postfix notation so F so if you
have F back slash back
SLG that means G bracket then F inside
you know so that's it's like Unix pipe
okay that back slash back slash okay so
all we have to do is just um add two
expression here okay so let's try
again there it is now percentage
percentage sign means the last output
let's say input form let's see now they
are numbers because you don't show the
quotes Okay so now we
got uh we got this this this is the
solution okay let's try it
again
no
what what's going
on
duration and record
cases so why is this not input five yeah
input
five let's
see
empty
record uh I'm not sure this is let's
let's put a condition that make sure
they are integers no that's not the
problem
so AB greater than
record let's make sure the Precedence is
correct yeah the operator
presidence you are right about Goan
thank you for the advice okay I
forgot Charles sh I forgot what
conversation was that well you were in
Kar
Discord so anyway we got a problem let's
focus on solving the problem Oh my God
it's 6 7 8 it's almost 1 hour and 30
seconds I mean 90
minutes it's
cold
almost done okay almost done now I don't
get why is
this so here is our
function takes two arguments that's
correct the body of the function
is is you select all possible cases
uh but it turns out it returns zero
so why does it return zero so let's say
the duration
is seven right one of the record the
record is
nine so if you run
that right so two and two is four right
so in a different case you have 15 and
40 15 and 40 40 is a
record shift
enter right so you got
eight right so in the third case
of 30 and
200 30 you got nine right so the
function here is correct did I forget
some kind
of so why is the map thread not
work let's make sure let's double check
the input
five those are numbers right right so
you map
thread why why does it return
empty God the what's going on why
is it return return
empty let's
debug
what's
oh you don't want map yet I know what's
wrong because instead of taking 79 it's
actually T taking seven and 15
yeah idiotic okay I understand
I don't know if you you guys know what I
mean but
um but for example our previous code
will work okay 489 right okay let's not
worry about let's
not let's just go with that okay
so this is very simple you map a
function to a bunch of inputs actually
the map thread will work if we don't do
the transpose here so because we do it
we did a let me show you okay we did a
transposition where is
it yeah you
see we basically turn this list
into
this so if we don't do that then we can
use map thread but but if we do that
then you you want map okay map that just
means a function takes two arguments
then you have two list each time you
take one from each list that's map
thread okay in Python in emac
list you just use map map does the same
thing if you have the second argument is
more than one list like two or three
then the function will just like thread
them over but in w langu which you have
to use map thread because the reason is
because map takes the third argument
that says levels like which depth to map
to the
tree so anyway so this this is our um
this is our we've been taking too long
so let's let's just move on uh this is
our solution okay so wait let's just get
the solution so once you get that what
do you do you add them together together
right you multiply them together okay so
how do you multiply
uh you can you can just say times in
front
Okay times add add let me explain this
one okay so in wam language there's a
syntax shortcut when you have
FXX let's say AB okay usually AB when
you have that syntax that means
um that means apply a and uh to the
argument of B okay these two are
equivalent because in wolam language
everything every code you
code before the wolam engine does
anything it transform your syntax to
this always to this nested bracket form
so it's just like this everything
becomes this nested
thing so these two are 100% identical
you know W I'm just before it does any
computation it transforms this into that
okay so in this case we want to
multiply let me show you how this works
okay
so in this case you have the output that
right you want to multiply them together
so what you do you can
apply the times
function
[Music]
to to that okay so the shortcut is
just times add
add okay syntactical shortcut wolam
language will transform this into that
before it does anything then it does the
computation okay so that's why we are
doing that here so you can look so let's
try you see
288 so that's a solution okay so what
what else so now we have the whole
solution let's copy it the whole
solution let uh
new window paste it here run it to a 8
okay now we um we use the user input
okay so the user input is uh let's put
it back syntax C showing browser so here
is today's solution
okay now first of all let's do the user
input to make sure that code works okay
so backup pop it out and now the input
is this
thing okay slash okay so the input
equals
to uh read
string
okay copy all back
here
paste
okay are you sure yes I'm sure shut the
up paste there
submit that's not the right answer oh
your answer is too low
what what's the with the user
input
and is some tricky thing again
what 1 one one
60 Z I mean 60 why is it
not oh God
so the input is interesting because it
only have four lines I mean four
things so but by our
computation by our
computation one two three four wait so
we only got three
things why why why is that
you see the input got four
races but we only got three let's
see 45
9772 I mean 45 okay we got it
wrong 45
9772 and uh 95 is here so some numbers
got
dropped we don't have one one one Z
our passing is incorrect
somewhere okay input two input three 45
97 72
95 then 30 4 510 6211 1 0 okay then
input
four input four got up oh that's
right because before we are hard
coding yeah yeah
yeah so now yeah so okay I know what's a
problem so
before we have hardcoded the partition
so we have three
items because there are three Rays so
this three should be a number of rays
now in this input there are four races
so okay let's do
that stupid uh let's see
number of races okay let's just say
that
so
input you split by new line okay
then takes the
first
two then you split
by then after you do that you want to
split
by
by wh
space
okay then you got the first line one two
uh you split by y space the minus one
then the
length
H minus one okay this this is the number
of
races H okay something
wrong oh yeah you take you want to take
the first item
no what
uh
that's right so then
you then you take the
length oh okay what
the Yeah but why can't you just put the
minus one there
oh so it you see
this we we run into a operator
precedence issue so this minus one they
connect you know that's why so you need
a paren if you want to do it that way
you know that so that is
your okay I don't want want
the I don't want to use the back slash
notation it's the same
anyway
so the number of races is this number
okay so then you put that here partition
two number of races okay they are easier
ways but let's just get
on okay select all paste
run
40 wait this is not right again so let's
see
partition
what why do we partition three
before
yeah okay
this
so
three hello from Brazil hello
Marcos uh
partition so we want to partition right
so input
[Music]
for
we we got the number of races wrong
again what's going
on
two oh we forgot I forgot
to take the first
item yeah yeah okay so now let's do it
again input string and our function copy
it
paste there it is yeah I'm sure it's
correct you
[Music]
idiotic
crap that's the right answer of
course okay solve the problem thank you
guys for watching this is fun 100
minutes smooth Smo
selling we didn't get stuck anywhere but
we just went to a lot explanations on
how this code
Works uh okay now let's pop back so we
let's pop back let me show you okay so
basically that's it for today we got a
solution now the solution is like you
know this number of lines but you can
combine it
tremendously so now let's do that
okay let's see the people here watching
are you guys you know are you guys
watching how many
people
fantastic so we did we
finished we solve the problem uh we can
go on to part two but no let's do that
another day okay part two another day
that's will be better and uh okay
sponsorship
time if you like my stuff go check out
my website and let me show you what you
can
buy you can of course you can just
donate to me pay patreon me okay Amazon
gift card or PayPal okay right on talk
show page or if you want something in
return besides my talking s talk show
you can buy my emac
tutorial this is comprehensive well this
the best tutorial for emac and emac lisp
okay I've done like over 100 200 videos
of emac lisp coding in past two years
okay emac is the best tutorial okay so
you can click that and you know go to my
emx
tutorial then there is Buy ex emac
tutorial
okay I can read it online why should I
pay why should I pay because you are
beautiful
okay uh okay that's emac tutorial and uh
another one of the best thing I'm proud
of is my JavaScript in depth JavaScript
is a very complicated language okay and
I have the most comprehens ensive I
would claim the most indepth and
comprehensive and easy the most extreme
easy and
concrete and
correct tutorial by example of the in
English Okay in English on
Earth okay my JavaScript tutorial on
Earth my JavaScript in depth okay it's
better than Mozilla for example Mo
Mozilla JavaScript tutorial actually
sucks and uh I would say there are
possibly two JavaScript
books that is possibly better than mine
depending on your taste of the style of
the tutorial you know some you know
there's so many styles of writing and
many styles of organization of a
programming language
tutorial uh different styles of
explanation uh you know so I would
say in this earth there are possibly two
JavaScript tutorial that is you might
consider better better than mine one is
one by um Douglas Crawford the guy who
invented invented Jason okay he's a
great guy you know one of the you guys
asked me is it worthwhile to study worth
you know worth has
been dead for like 10 20 years you know
Pascal the creator of Pascal that's
several generation ago so if you want to
read
someone who is still alive I can
recommend Douglas Crawford he still does
a lot videos on JavaScript you know he's
very old now he's 60 something or 70 you
know he's like I'm getting old myself so
Douglas Crawford I've read quite a lot
of his stuff so anyway he has WR written
a book about four years ago okay the lat
of course he wrote previously JavaScript
the good
parts okay dig digression digression
time JavaScript the good parts so he has
written a new
book okay I mean his video uh JavaScript
beta part is very good okay that's
someone who is a great programmer I
would classify him as a great programmer
as opposed to computer scientist you
know they are different but in he's a
great programmer but
also
um is a great uh programming language
expert
okay uh and but anyway he he's has
written a book and you know search like
um just search the web okay so so let me
okay let me try to find the
book uh okay JavaScript book review
2023 there it is so there's my book
there is the these are old JavaScript
the good parts by dougl sfold like 15
years ago and JavaScript by this is also
fantastic definitive guy by the Rhino
book by this guy whose name is
um yeah David
Flanagan that guy I also highly respect
so Douglas Crawford and David Flanigan
David Flanigan is into writing
programming language
tutorials okay I'm I'm I'm telling you
my opinion and and I'm going to claim
this is the best opinion on PING
language books because typically for
Zoomers you know you don't know which
one is a good book you know you go to
online there's lots of grifters okay
they're going to tell you oh this is the
best book that is oh JavaScript ninja
you know they all have opinions blah
blah but they don't know okay this
Zuma generation or late Millen gen they
don't know okay the best JavaScript
book is Ral book okay this is a new
version uh about three four years ago
even so previously is 15 years ago but
this is a new version okay by David
Flanagan that's one of them possibly
better than M better than my JavaScript
in depth then the dougas
scold okay 2018 how JavaScript works I
highly recommend that okay so this is
another book this this one is not too
thick okay so it doesn't really cover
lots of things it doesn't cover the
entire JavaScript uh P you know the
library and you know it's it's thing
it's more like telling you how
JavaScript is designed okay anyway I
highly recommend it then this one is
also someone I highly respect Dr AEL
rashme okay he's he's written a series
of JavaScript books you know exploring
es6 and so on you go to his website
you'll see but he has one like one book
for the latest because JavaScript every
year there a new version so so he
started to have so many you know deep
JavaScript Theory and techniques
tracking tackling JavaScript ungrad from
upgrading from
JavaScript oh tackling typ
script sh scripting with njs you know
he's got several speaking JavaScript ES1
to es5 okay anyway this
guy his JavaScript is also the best okay
but his his style is more like very
technical and dry very extremely
Technical and dry okay and uh often go
into a depth that you can you know you
can't be bothered to know you know even
you know if you are a good Google you
know you you are a goog programming web
for end for like let's say two years you
are an idiot okay you don't know
JavaScript but anyway so you know so he
goes into a lot depth that like so much
detail that you can you you almost like
you you'll never find it useful
something like that okay so this this
guy so I can recommend the exploring es
e
es6 that that's a EDR jargon you know
that's a nickname for JavaScript 2015
something yeah you know anyway and then
there's ecmascript you know another name
stupid but anyway it's just JavaScript
okay so this guy Dr Axel rumme okay I
can recommend his stuff so in
summary actually in summary check check
out my article go read it in depth
JavaScript books review 2023
okay so that one and
then then there's this one okay six s
structure and interpretation of computer
programming in JavaScript okay this new
version um then this eloquent JavaScript
I do not recommend at all okay this
eloquent this is this this one this
eloquent JavaScript is for begin
now this guy is a expert okay I can I
can tell you he's a JavaScript expert
but however his book this particular
book eloquent JavaScript is a
idiotic verbals book JavaScript book for
JavaScript beginners and it's also for
Javas and you know for like almost like
you never programmed before okay and
also it's in a style that's elaborate
telling a story like he's going to Once
Upon a Time he's going to say once upon
time there's a JavaScript and my
experience something something and I run
into this mountain and I found this
Trail and this is and I I feel that this
is analogous to this JavaScript
function the idiotic okay
eloquent
JavaScript and then I give you my
analysis about Moosa
Mozilla they are JavaScript tutorial
okay it's misleading you read
it you you get you you you you run you
code in a bad way you run into problems
okay moosa's JavaScript tutorial now
Mark exactly what I said okay mozilla's
JavaScript tutorial there's tons of
things on mosa the Firefox thing you
know so but they have one one section
called JavaScript tutorial that is
teaching you JavaScript that part is not
good okay however mosa is excellent in
fact nowhere else on
Earth you will find alternative is that
the mozilla's coverage of the
latest bleeding edge JavaScript stuff
okay for example Dome or can you use
some new you know JavaScript coupling
with CSS latest CSS yes you know that's
still experimental or some JavaScript
the latest development you know which
brows you know for example JavaScript
every year there's a new version so you
want to know can I use this function in
this which browser supported and things
like that and sometimes the function
behavior is
not finalized yet you know those kind of
thing latest bleeding edge mosia is the
best source and in fact there's no other
source no other books no nothing okay so
if you are
a professional web dev JavaScript of
course you need to use Moosa you have to
there's nowhere
else the W3 school is the most idiotic
and tutorial point and Java Point those
are pit you know those are idiots you
know they four beginners okay that be
they become the most popular anyway so
that's my summary of JavaScript book so
you can buy as a donation you know you
can read them online of course but as a
donation you
can pay me and you get a I give you a
download so you can read offline
wherever you go it's HTML okay it's HTML
it's not PDF it's not ebook Okay it's
plan HTML so you can run in any
browser
uh you'll have a hard time if you if if
you try to run it on a phone I think you
need to translate or something I I
haven't done that anyway so that's some
of the summaries of my
books well yeah kind of you can buy okay
so that's it for
today thank you guys for watching
bye-bye
guys oh yeah oh yeah oh yeah we forgot
to do the second part
to for the shortest code SH shall we do
it yeah I can I can do it in in 10
minutes uh well but I started to talk
about JavaScript is it still worth the
time it's 2 hours
already so wh
says I'm a Vim user and I got very high
got very high one day and wanted to know
what the life of an emac user is like I
found you by accident
accident through that
audio and I love your content thank you
thank you very much
W okay yeah so right now should we
condense the code no let's
not uh where's the
code you know I can make this code in
one line actually I can do it quickly
let's do it okay so let me do it
yeah so first of
all copy okay let's make the code in the
shortest number of line you know in one
line so let me let me
concentrate uh input two input three
okay
so so stren input you so you want to
number of races so let's actually
rewrite the whole thing so string input
so first of
all split by a new line so we split by a
new line let's not Define that we split
by a new line
then
okay so for each
line
we we split Again by yspace okay then
then what you
do each time we split Again by
yspace
then okay then you
select okay so let me actually I need to
try try this
out yeah
so yeah so then
you
no
so now you got that then
you yeah so right now we care about
shortest so let's just write things my
way okay so let's
not
spring speed okay so actually you just
need that don't need that don't need
that
okay okay so now you split that then
what is the next thing you want to uh
select
select so you want to select
uh select our
cases okay we can do
select so cases this this is your your
number and you want the pattern anything
so Cas is
anything with a condition
that string
match X is number string okay so let's
try
that no something wrong wrong okay so
cases anything
so Cas is anything Cas is to take two
arguments case is string match
Q X number string
so Y is
not
stream
match
for
oh default case is level spec one yeah
so we want level spec
two that's what we
want so once you got that then what then
you want to
partition
uh actually how do you partition you
want to know the
length Okay count so now we need to make
sure there's no extra lines okay
stupid I mean there's no extra line
return character so now we can
count so count pattern okay so count
input we want to count the number of
lines okay so string
count so actually not count string
count we want to count the number
of new line chart so that tells us
how
many okay so we need to re reread this
input
because because we just modified
it oh no it's just
one right okay so string count plus one
okay +
one
so that is a number race okay so that is
actually the number race so what is
this don't need that don't need that the
number of race you don't need
that the number of race is actually you
need to put that
here okay so
wait that's
good now
partition now
partition you want to partition let's
see can you have it in a functional
form Le no you cannot I mean you cannot
have it in a curried form okay so you
have to use the
partition so the partition here is just
this okay then
yeah yeah that's what we want one two
three one two three four yeah because
there are four races yeah and uh here we
transpose actually you don't need to
transpose and two expression okay two
expression at transpose okay you can do
it either way
so
okay
okay so this part now is just here okay
so that is our solution single one
single line solution
okay wait that's the
wrong that's wrong uh what was the
answer
before
I forgot what's the
answer
got the answer
somewhere but now it's hard to debug now
you
what
wait
okay something is wrong there
yeah
did we forgot to
transpose
read oh you you so
you
don't need to don't even need
to don't need to partition
okay uh actually you kind of need to
so so string split
input
so
yeah
[Music]
actually let's
just apply a function okay and the
function is going to
[Music]
be the function is going to drop
the first
item
for
okay that's what we want so
then then we do a transpose
actually
you
got actually you don't need transpose
okay so we are simplifying a lot of our
code we yeah simplifying a lot code so
now you use map thread
instead so the first part is
is okay so this function and
uh in this function it takes two
arguments okay so this will just be one
this will just be
two simplified so
much okay some error no worry we figure
it out
so first of
all that's right so you map
thread you map thread and
uh
okay you map R you forget about
total
oh we forgot to uh change it to
expression oh yeah there it is
expression that's
why
that's
right
that's that seems right
so do we need
to
times right we need to times them
together
easy what was the uh the answer I forgot
what was the correct answer before let's
see do we uh I think
2 612
736 yep that's a correct answer copy it
let's put the correct answer
here okay so you don't need this let's
see map thread correct
we fantastic one single line solution
okay this this is the this is the thing
okay paste it here there it
is okay
so fantastic now now we can copy the
wolam language here and uh paste it back
here here so it kind of shows you kind
of like nice
format I'm not sure it's it's nicer but
uh let's let's do it my way okay so here
is
solution HTML color it there it
is now the shortest solution is here
okay so now
let's let's put it
here show this solution and
uh annotate
nicely a of
code
2003 day
six okay shortest Solution on earth now
I can still make it shorter than though
so how do you do yeah let's not to worry
about that but anyway so copy that put
it back and uh
this P one
okay
okay that's complete this is the
solution shortest
code and here is more explanation kind
of
approach bye
guys