hello everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show we are going
to do emac this coding
and let's begin
so i'm going to show you this is this
video is going to be 15 minutes or 20
minutes so i'm going to write a emac
list command i've done many emac this
tutorials uh just search youtube you'll
see so but today we are going to write a
command that
does html demote headers
so what does that mean so for example
header
you know something okay something
let's make it
you know header 2
so you got something then let's make it
else header 3
showing browser
so you see we have headers but if d mode
i want to write the command so i can
press a key and it becomes
h2 becomes
h3
and h3 becomes h4 okay that's html
headers now if you don't know html
okay so if you don't know
html i have a html tutorial for
beginners okay just search for exactly
html
tutorial so you can
learn it okay so
but today emac this let's begin coding
hello guys hello
are you
okay so
so let's begin
uh headers okay so let's start a emac
this
code
and start coding now let me double check
my voice my video okay so
let's double check one more time
video check audio check okay we're good
okay so let's begin so we want to define
a command different this is a template
okay and define command uh and let's
document documented the most important
thing version today state and uh
this uh this prog uh this command is
going to
demote
html headers
uh
now where do you want to begin the
region or the whole buffer okay let's
say the whole buffer
let's just say that
except
except h1
others h2 becomes h3 act okay
and uh
h6 remains the same you know h6 is the
smallest
header possible so you can see here's
the html text complete list so you can
see you have
page structure tags
so you have article section then you
have title section heading so h6 is the
smallest one possible there's no more
after six so what so if you want to demo
them what you gonna do when you have h6
leave them unchanged okay so that's the
design that's a plan the goal of the
command okay so let's begin so
so you know so we're gonna call the
command so in emacs you press the key
and you'll change it
you know similar to org mod if you use
oak mod oak mod has that feature so okay
so
so we are coding start to code it demo
html headers in whole buffer
and on the ping window you can see all
my command cores and keystrokes i'm
using a vorack layout and kinesis
advantage 2 keyboard and ultimate
hacking keyboard okay you can buy just
search for xrd keyboard
then you can find them okay i have
reviews and all that buy from my amazon
link
and support me by buying my emacs
tutorial okay so anyway
so you can you know you can search you
know you probably already know already
know if you have watched my videos i've
done tons of uh emac these tutorials
okay so anyway let's begin so
to change header so
so
so primarily
that's about find and replace text in
current buffer okay
find replace text in current buffer so
that's all we're gonna do so let's go to
emac list you can search for it you'll
find it emac this basics and go to let's
go to practical emac this
and there is a section on find and
replace text okay so this page tells you
how to write emac this code to do find
and replace and this is all we need so
just this page let's copy it
close it let's go back to talk show
let's let's uh
programming blog close let's go to talk
show and let's
paste it here so later on you can see
on my talk show page you can you can go
to the link okay so find replace text so
what is this talk show so let's go back
to the code so
actually all we have to do is just copy
and paste
copy copy and essentially that's what
all we need to do okay so let's yeah so
let's paste it here and uh
yeah let's delete that okay so let me
well i'm gonna explain go over so let
declares the local variable so you want
case fold search set it to neo that
means when emacs does find and replace
it will
be not case sensitive
it will be a smart like like if the
well anyway i'm not going to explain but
you know because i expand on this page
in detail so basically you want to set
this variable this is a building
variable that controls cash case
sensitivity so if you set it to neil
that means don't
don't don't be a
case instead don't be smart okay do
whatever exactly what we are trying to
find in replace if we try to find lower
case then
find lower case do not find the upper
case and things like that okay so case
for neo so set a variable local variable
that's this uh let is for let's turn on
highlight the current line okay set the
local variable then go to char point min
that means go to the beginning of the
buffer move the cursor to the beginning
of the end
and while search forward let's do h1 uh
let's skip h1 because h1 is the
basically the first header usually you
don't want to demo that okay so
beginning with begin with h2
okay and search forward is the command
you want to use so while you
try to find h2 and if it found it it'll
return true so this while statement will
be true okay so this is a whole block of
code
so when it's true then you want to
replace it by
h3 okay and here is the same thing you
just repeat it okay so let's delete them
for now d them so this is the code this
will replace h2 to h3 okay that's a
that's not the whole thing but that's
part of it already okay so we can
evaluate the code and we can call it
right away okay so we need to name the
function so let's name it cassatrol html
the mode
header
h2 h3 h4 h5 h
okay that's it leave h6 okay so
now
eval the buffer look at the look at the
pink window you can see run current file
that's uh that's how you evolve buffer
you can call eval buffer but run current
file is my uh my own function so anyway
so now emacs knows this command now we
can meta x encode okay so go back here
uh go back here showing browser what is
this this is today's talk show so you
can see some example let's do it here
okay
so
before we call it let's double check our
code so
we
go to the point go to the buffer
beginning and start to search for it neo
means uh okay so let's look at the
documentation for search forward okay
uh describe function
search forward so here's the
documentation here's the syntax what's
uh here's what the arguments mean so
string optional bound
bound is neo that's good no error true
that's right because we don't want it to
pop up an error when there's no h
h2 right so okay replacement okay so
that's it
if other buffer corrector okay this
let's uh let's try it on on our talk
show page it should change this one to
h3 okay
let's call it
html
the mode
headers there it is okay
do it
oh
it worked you see it changed that one
but we forgot the end tag so let's go
back and fix it let's undo
okay and go back to the code and fix it
so we need another pair here
okay so let's
so this block is block of interest
and let's make it a program block so we
can
make it a syntactical unit so cut it put
it here
prettify the code
so you can see this is the block okay so
we can copy that block paste it again do
the same thing except this time it's
gonna be
ending tag so we need the slash ending
tag okay put a put a comment here
and purify the code that's it evolve the
buffer
go back to this page let's try it again
so this something h2 will become h3
okay doesn't matter where your cursor is
because we are doing we remember we went
to the beginning of a buffer the cruiser
you know the go-to chart point mean
that's the beginning of a buffer let's
move in the cursor to the beginning of
the buffer and do it there so let's meta
x
x html demo headers
do it fantastic you see that becomes h3
now go to the browser
now watch this part we're gonna refresh
and it should be become
smaller like that okay
refresh fantastic
almost done now back to the code now we
just need to repeat this for h3 h4 h5
okay
now the code might be tedious but you
know that's the way how emac these do
these okay find replace
okay so now it just uh so that's h2 part
now let's uh actually
uh it's okay so h2 let's h3 becomes h4
and same thing here
h3 becomes h4
and
h5 becomes h6
same thing here h5 becomes
h6 fantastic shrink the code let's let's
remove the comments so
remove the redundant command pretty file
the code
make them smaller
and let's combine these two blocks into
one you see
you see these are h2 to h3
these are h3 to h4
and these are h5 to h6
so let's make them a syntactical unit
because you see right now this is a
syntactical unit
and this is a syntactical unit you know
what's what's this p-r-o-g-n
do in e-magles in this in general is
that they are just a
grouping of code blocks
similar to
the c languages concept of
braces curly brackets okay
so uh anyway so let's remove that okay
so let's
so now now you can see now it's one
block one you see sync tactical unit
okay let's do them here and here
okay and shrink the buffer so you can
see the whole thing
remove the comment remove the comment
prettify the code and remove the empty
extra lines okay prettify the code eval
the buffer fantastic we have three code
units
that one two
three you see
okay even the buffer go back here well
this page is already done so if we call
it again the h3 is becoming gonna become
h4 so let's call it
do it
did it did it do it it did but however
it
you see once it the command finished it
moved the cursor to the beginning
uh
we don't want that we we want the
cruiser to stay where it is okay but
first of all let's verify if it
worked so well it did you see h3 becomes
h4 now refresh they'll become even
smaller
fantastic
okay now let's fix the problem we don't
want to move the cruiser okay so what we
can do
is
you know so
we can call
save excursion
okay
now what does save excursion do let's
look up the documentation describe
function
ctrl
h f okay that's the default key okay now
save excursion yes
please
okay there it is the documentation
here's the syntax and here's the
explanation
save point
the current buffer execute body and
restore those things now what does point
mean point means just point
is emac list jargon it just means the
cruiser the cruiser position okay so
save the cruiser position the current
buffer and execute the body here and
just and restore those things so that's
what we want so it will restore the
cruiser position okay so
so let's now bring back the whole block
of code
inside it
prettify the code remove the extra line
evolve the buffer
go back here now let's call it again
this h4 will become h5
and my cursor will stay
in place
stay put okay let's call it
do it
failed what
h4 becomes h5
oh we forgot we missed h4 oh god okay
copy that paste it here
h4 becomes h5 we missed we missed
h4 becomes h5 now pretty five the code
okay so h3
h4
h5
yeah okay evolve the buffer back to this
page call the command
do it
wait
now it becomes h6
h4 becomes h6 okay
no good we forgot to change here
oh i know what's going on so you see
you change h4 to h5 then it runs the
code then h5 becomes h6
so it demoted twice so what you want to
do the order is important so you want to
first
do h5 to h6 you want to do this part
then you do this part
h4 to h5 then you do h3 to h4 then you
do h2 h3 okay so we just need to reorder
reverse the order now there's no easy
way to do it to reverse them so let's
just do it manually
okay so that goes here and this goes
here 25 the code let's double check
h5
h4
h3
h2 fantastic done i think we
we done
eval the buffer
switch to this buffer now let's call it
again h4 should become h5 okay do it
fantastic you see fantastic do it again
they will become h6
fantastic okay demo html headings not
refresh let's check
refresh
yeah it worked you know because h5 and
h6 they basically have the same size so
it's hard to tell the difference in
in you know html uh in browser rendering
because i can tell you
uh do i have an example uh
somewhere maybe not
anyway
so we done we done that
okay so delete those uh so this is
today's talk show let's
pop the code back to my browser show in
browser i mean back to the talk show
page so you can see the emac this code
here now
syntax color them back to browser
refresh now it looks pretty
okay that is what we want to do today
and we've done it
how long have i been talking 20 minutes
fantastic
hi friend show me this channel because
of your emacs tutorials love the streams
keep it up thank you
james thomas jens thomas oh james okay
great fantastic thank you
okay so that is done
yeah let's call it a day so i was
thinking let's do something else because
there's
you know because i want to i'm writing
this command not just for the live
stream but also for myself because i
work on working html all the time so i
find the need to do this okay yeah so
let's wait why don't we demo a real word
practical
example
you know this is not just academic
talking
real world so why do i need to what do i
do why do i need to do this because look
at this page
so this is my javascript tutorial so you
can you know check it out fantastic
javascript in depth
and here's a page on sparse array what
does it mean javascript is a language
that sucks
so there's tremendous amount of
complexities you have the concept of
sparse array and you have the concept of
array array-like object
you know it's it's not really it's
array it's not array but it's array-like
very complex and javascript because
javascript array is not really an array
object it's very complex chiptune thank
you of lamio quick one today
so okay so let me demo demonstrate this
uh
this page sparse array javascript and
that'll be it uh so i'm gonna show you
why do i need it okay
so copy the url back to emacs and open
that url
url in emacs buffer this is my local
page now go to the directory shrink the
font size so you can see this is my
javascript tutorial it's got some 900
pages including html and css tutorial so
you can see
html
and visual css
visual demonstration of
cascading style sheet
okay and javascript in depth and
javascript reference you know and the
dom which is the practical part of
javascript and svg fantastic now i need
to show the svg clock so you can write
those
you know
reading my tutorial so okay so back to
the uh so i'm work i've been so you know
takes a lot of time working on them that
that's what i do every day for the past
20 years uh so for example on this page
javascript spots array copy the url yeah
i already so it's this page
so now you see this h2 i want to change
them to h3 so you see
you see this h2
h2
i want to change them to h3 okay so call
the command
it's not html demo we just wrote do it
back to browser
now
refresh you'll see the headers become
smaller okay watch them
refresh fantastic
okay so that's it for today but let me
tell you why what is the reason i want
to change demo the header why do i want
to make them smaller because i wanted to
write uh add these okay let me just show
you
i want add the section tag you see that
you see that section tag
that
uh
wait
uh wait
what
anyway what uh what's going on
wait did i change my keyboard
back to browser undo
undo
yeah so okay let me show you okay so i'm
going to add section
do it
then this part
basically i'm adding this section okay
this is so
like this this thing okay
so um
and here too
okay
and but i'm trying to find the key
and to jump the tag to the ending tag
but i forgot where is the key
all right
anyway
you know i'm using side html mod so i
also need to add here
do it
then add here
do it oh lots of topic you see that's
that is exactly why i want to add a
section to them
let me show you in the browser you'll
see
it becomes clear you see
refresh you see every you know each one
of the section becomes there's a box so
it's very clear so it adds clarity
on the section
headings and one more thing i want to do
is to remove the date for each of the
section okay so how you do that another
emacs trick okay showing browser okay so
you can see here here is the tag that
added the data so i want to
these matching lines all lines contain
the class state excel so you can see we
just added them a bunch of them
now we move the cursor to the beginning
and
delete matching lines so the same thing
they are all good
showing browser
there it is that's it okay so uh if you
like my stuff buy my emacs tutorial okay
so
did we show emacs tutorial yes so you
can
find my emac list
tutorial and you can buy them okay or
donate paypal me thank you thank you
guys
bye
fantastic you see this is what we i want
i want these uh
section boxes you know the let me talk
about html i'm gonna shut down in one
minute so
extra you know so uh so you know in html
why do you want to add an extra section
because it the advantage is that it
group things
so in other words
it creates a grouping
it creates a syntactical grouping
of the content
that mirrors the semantic you know the
hh3 you know
if you don't have the section let me
remove them okay you see
this is a section let me show the pink
window so you can see what command i
call so you see
i can highlight them
and that command is uh next window of uh
that command is html select element
and now
i can i can
i can press a key to delete those
section element you see and that command
is such html remove tag pair
okay so that that is uh
why that is
that is
that is extra demo of my
html mod you can also buy the package
thank you guys bye
you