hello welcome to another episode of
guitar talk show
so today we are going to explore
uh the data structure of stacks
versus list
so basically in Python in Ruby in
JavaScript you all have a list or array
data structure okay and there is also
data structure called stack
uh so we are going to we are going to
try to implement a efficient stack we're
going to do that in Python in JavaScript
in Wolfram language and we are going to
time it to compare with millions of
items and push and pop and let's see
whether our customized efficient stack
data structure is going to be more
efficient or faster than the building
using the building smart array or smart
list so python JavaScript
Wolfram language we're gonna explore
okay so if you are if you don't know if
you are new to programming I'm going to
explain everything okay and we are I'm
also going to demonstrate the lists list
programming languages list which is
basically made of cons sales we'll get
to that okay so basically essentially we
are going to implement
lists con sales impact on JavaScript
movement and time it okay
so why do you need to do that so let's
speaking okay uh if you uh you know
comments post comments and questions I'd
love to see it okay
okay so Wolfram language uh yeah I mean
python JavaScript and uh the keyboard
I'm using this is exposed I talked about
many times uh in lots of my videos you
can see reviews here so the Expos is one
I recommend I also recommend kinesis
Kinesis 360 is also good glove safety is
also good but it's not out yet
srail new 76 is also good but too
expensive 500 somethings same with the
Kinesis 360. Apple maker I just
discovered is pretty good or you can buy
any of the others okay
so anyway so exposed is what I'm using
and over there is uh over on top and on
the side you cannot see but over there
it's uh
it's a ultimate hacking keyboard I have
reviews on my website okay
okay it's hot and even think of
so yes Stacks we're gonna Implement
start stacks
okay let's begin then
um
Samsung show today's talk show uh so why
do we need to do that okay first of all
let me show you uh Wikipedia articles
so you can read it later okay so there
is a stack data structure not that uh
not simple Wikipedia
uh okay I don't want the simple English
by the way simple English is a good
thing
but
um
53 languages yeah
stack okay uh
data abstract data type okay
there it is so a stack is a data type
you can think of it as a as a pile of
plates so when you put some data such
such as numbers or string you you push
it to the you put so it's like plates or
stack of books you put it and you put
another one on top put another one you
can pile them up so it's like a list
okay so uh it's like a list of things or
sequence of things okay a pile of stacks
stack of plates or books then if you
want to get the there are two operations
are allowed for a stack that is get the
first item so you can take out the first
item remove it and and get that value
okay so you can like just like you
removing books of a stack of books and
you so you there are two operations push
add another thing to the stack or
pop which is take out a thing from the
stack okay two operations so it's a list
but only two operations uh you can add
to the front or take from the front
that's what stack is
now let me explain so some let me
explain so that's a data that's a stack
abstract data type okay so there are
no there are two
now there is another the most
fundamental data structure in every
programming language okay
that's called array okay now
the the jargons array least stack
uh
they mean different things in different
languages so depending on language for
example
so let me say again array vector
array Vector list uh
purple
these four things
depending on the language they may mean
different things but they are there are
two standard jargon let me let me show
you okay so in Python
so first of all let's think of a list
you know it doesn't matter it's a stack
or what let's not care about specific
properties let's say we just want a
ordered sequence of things
what is it called in different languages
so in Python it's called
um I believe they call it list okay so
in Python it's called the list you just
do it like that okay let's put it let's
put the link into my website
so in Python it's called a list now
let's go to uh let's let's go to in
wufam language it's also called list
okay
okay so wufang language and you write it
like that or like that two different
ways
okay
so
let me explain what are we doing list
vector
uh array let's say array
let's hold them this way array Vector
purple
list actually let's put this here
because it's most common jargon
so all these
all these jargons
essentially means almost the same thing
exactly what they mean depends on the
language okay
so don't don't get confused sometimes
you know if you are programming or in
python versus you talking to people
programming in Wolfram language or
Haskell or JavaScript when you say at
least they might think of at least
something else different from you so
first of all remember that different
this these jargons have different
meanings in different languages okay
so
so we look at python week so wolf and
python so first of all if you want a
older sequence
all the sequence of things
typically
they all mean just order the sequence of
values okay uh
but they differ
in some
so what's the difference uh they differ
in some algorithmic properties
for example
okay for example can you uh
how how fast
is it to access any random item let's
say nth item
okay
that's the question
so if you have at least let's say 10
things let's say a million things now if
you want get the one ten thousands item
is it is it instantaneous I mean does it
make difference does it make a
difference if you get the first item or
some millionth item
you know so that is the question you see
all these things are just lists all the
sequence of things so why is it
different well because depending on you
know computer how it's implemented the
exact machine may it be Abacus or a
turing machine or physical turing
machine or whatever or CPU today is
modern you know electronic computer or
is it DNA computer or quantum computer
you know so but a sequence of other
things is a fundamental natural
mathematical concept you cannot Escape
it so there is a concept of ordered
sequence of things okay in English we
just call a list okay all the sequence
of things but when you actually want to
program it you know requires a machine
hardware and uh
and algorithm and you have to write down
the algorithm in a programming language
that specify the instruction what to do
with the machine
when you actually do that then
two you know to to create something like
an older sequence of things then you
have questions like how fast is it to
access a nth item
there are different ways to do it so so
you have that question and uh
um and you also have a question of can
you add items to the list
okay
can you add items uh or and is it slow
or fast
okay so you have that question
you know so one thing I want to tell you
remember that these are not
fundamental concepts in mathematics so
this just depends on what machine you're
working on what length programming
language you're working on it depends on
the machine the CPU the instruction set
the programming language okay so that's
why you have these questions how fast is
it to access nth item and can you add
items to the list
or can you delete items in the list
okay
so these two are the the most
fundamental question to to these bunch
of jargons very confusing because if you
are pro if you are a beginner you may
not know
so it all depends on the machine on the
implementation and on the programming
language and each programming language
they may use different jargons but in in
essence typically you just have a
ordered sequence of things and you have
these properties about them how fast is
it to access nth item and can you add
items to the list is it slow
oh and or can you delete item to the
list okay that's a fundamental
properties algorithmic properties these
properties
came from the Implement implementation
and the programming language and also
the machine okay
now that's a situation okay so uh let me
let me write it down so uh people can
easily understand uh
for all the sequence of things okay
that's one thing now
this is very confusing topic okay very
confusing topic that's why we need to be
very careful we want to
now you want to memorize exactly what's
going on here okay so first of all
so you have different jargons for all
the sequence of things okay
then you have
um what do they mean okay
okay so let's put that
uh
different jargons for order they've seen
ordered things
all the sequence of things is a natural
math
concept
you cannot Escape
okay that's the important Point all that
sequence of things that's a universal
concept
okay
now
implementation detail okay
implementation detail
okay and algorithmic
I'll go with
make okay I don't have a shortcut
properties okay
implementation detail and algorithmic
properties
okay
so they differ in some algorithm with
proc properties
and uh
the most fundamental
huh
the most fundamental are how fast it is
it to access any nth item
or in other words
does it take longer time
to access
items far from
the first okay that's a question
okay so how fast is it to access any any
nth item and these other questions can
you add items to the list and is it slow
or fast that's a two most
fundamental differences
okay
and let's add another topic
why
does these
differences exist okay
because it depends
on the machine
AKA computer
and depend the design of the machine
depends on the design
of the machine and Depends
on the
implementation
of the algorithm or
the programming
language
implementation of its list Vector array
data
data structure
foreign
okay
that's so far that's what we have
covered
okay now let's uh put this here
that's so far what we have covered and
let's move let's remove this okay
now I'm explaining the preliminaries why
why do we need to do this why can't we
you know we are explaining the
preliminaries uh so now next we want to
so now
so this is why
we need to try to implement a efficient
stack okay
so and let's add what is a stack
what's a stack
okay
is
like a stack of books
you
have two operations
push and pop
push is at
an item to the top
pop is remove an item
on the top okay
that's a stacked data structure so a
stack is just like again it's like an
ordered sequence of things but in this
case you cannot you know get the nth
item you only allowed two operations
take item from the beginning and drop it
or add an item in the beginning okay
now let me explain now so we talked
about how the
um you know so
exactly the algorithmic properties
depends on the machine and depends on
the programming depends on the
programming language how it implements
it
okay for example in list I mean in lisp
for example emac bisp
for example I'm showing you some some
emac this code for example in list
languages including common lisp imagine
scheme list racket lisp
they are fundamental data structure is
called a list and the way this list
sequence of things other things the way
this list in lisp
is implemented
is is by a method called linked list
okay and
with that implementation
how fast how fast is it to access in
item very slow okay the further away
from one the slower it gets okay that's
that's that's lisps list
uh and can you add items to the list yes
but only at the beginning
okay it's very fast constant time you
know you can add item to the beginning
or you can delete the item from the
beginning however if you want add an
item somewhere in somewhere in the
middle it takes a lot of time you you
essentially have to do a it takes
yeah it takes more time you know it's
not constant the further away from
you know from the beginning the longer
it takes
so that's the algorithmic property of
the
lisp Lisk list okay so let me show uh
let me let's write it down
property of least
least okay
including common lists
this
emac list
scheme lisp
a racket list
but not closure
please okay
it is constant
time and fast to wait it is
slow to access
nth item
the
further
and
his form one
the longer time it takes
okay
uh
but it is constant time and fast to add
an item to the beginning of the list
or delete that item okay very fast so
you can always add or delete items in
the front very fast
but
if you want to delete or add nth
at add
the nth item it's proportionally
slower okay so that's the
algorithmic properties of lisp's list
Okay so the lisp list
now let's uh let me show another point
this this is traditionally
is called linked list in
computer
so so far that's the things we covered
so lisp's list is called linked list in
computer science you know so kind of
confusing
hello guys so okay so let's start to
implement I already uh so it I already
took 30 minutes oh so just to
explain this Prelude took 30 minutes so
now let's begin to code you know so you
have some general idea why you know
what's what's a arraylist Vector turbo I
mean they are all just sequence ordered
sequence of things why is it why your
programming language has all these okay
you now you know and so mathematically
they are just ordered sequence of things
so basically the whole thing we are
doing today is not a mathematical
concept you know this topic took me 20
years to understand so you know I begin
programming in 1993.
you know wolfam language Pearl python
then PHP then JavaScript and also
closure so I did you know a lot it took
me and at least I did some scheme lists
too and emac lips of course I've been
coding images for 15 years so but this
concept of you know what why why are
there these things why are they
different why can't they just all be
fast why can't you just you know create
a array that's you know you can go you
can delete elements at anywhere you can
add element anywhere and why can't it be
fast why not you know so all these
took me 20 years to actually finally
understand and and
I would say even the C C plus plus these
hardcore programmers they don't want
they don't know they don't know they
don't know why
array is fast I mean why array is
constant access time okay let me explain
a few more things
so this is the topic we are going to do
we are going to about to begin coding
but let me explain few more things okay
so we explain linked list okay links
list is very important critical concept
okay let's write it down
okay critical concept linked list
uh
okay so first of all okay hold on a
second actually you know before we can
actually fully explain
what is linked list we need to explain
what is the array first okay so let's
explain what is array
critical concept array
sees array
C or Java array
and
so that's a critical concept okay let me
explain that uh
critical concept C or Java's array and
okay
Okay so
so this in the beginning there is this
thing called array now let me explain
exactly what it is
again it's just a sequence ordered
sequence of things
mathematically it's an ordered sequence
of things
but
this jargon
array
by convention
has a specific
algorithmic
property
it is
okay so what is the probability of array
the
implementation so
fast constant
access time to any item
but
the
array
cannot grow or Shrink
that is cannot add or delete elements
if you do you basically have two
create a new array okay
so first of all critical concept and
this is the most the most of them all
the most important data structure in all
languages you have this array
oh yeah I wanted to say
fixed length array
okay
so it's so it has these properties very
fast constant if if you want the
millionth item
you'll get that value just as fast if
you want to get the first value okay
constant time magical it's almost like
magic you know it's it's it's it's so
almost like Quantum Computing parallel
you know that this is a very weird
concept you know this is very weird took
me uh you know 15-20 years to understand
why is it access you know the median
items is as fast as as assessing the
first item
why is that because imagine a hardware
Abacus you know if you are using app
because you have to move your hand
you know to the median item
you know it all depends on where where
your hand is you know so you have to
move the further away from your current
hand position is takes longer but that's
not the case well imagine a tuning
machine you know a tuning machine is a
kind of a abstract machine you have a
tape you need to move the tape if you
implement array on a tuning machine
how is it possible you have this
constant time access okay this puzzle
took me like 20 or 30 years to
understand
and eventually I did about about seven
years ago about 10 years ago and that is
let me explain okay so and I
and that is
um
hello George so we are going to
implement stack but not yet we are I'm
just explaining the background
um
uh
knock Saudi org okay
so you just go to
study.info there's an article I want to
show you so let's say constant okay Y is
array access constant time
now the reason that this data structure
array sees array or Java survey again
depending on the language each language
use different terms but in C and Java
the meaning of array is more Universal
okay so when people say array typically
it means like C programming language is
array or Java programming language sorry
okay so when you have an array in
implementation of the ordered sequence
of things then you have this property
constant access time doesn't matter
median item or first item is the same
same speed to get it and very fast so
it's magical why does it happen even you
know so if you you can look at Wikipedia
you know it has 10 pages you know 10
000 words but no explanation why except
this one single line okay one single
line brush it away hand waving okay they
effectively exploit the addressing logic
of computers
what does that mean what do you mean
effectively exploit that addressing
logic of computers
so
people do not you know you ask
programmers even or basically
essentially all textbooks are you know
you go to Amazon you buy the classic
textbooks on algorithms none of them
as far as I know none of them explains
it
why is array access constant time they
don't explain it they just say it's
constant okay then you they tell you how
to implement linked lists and and others
but they just assume they will just
begin with a real array the data
structure it's just constant time no
explanation and in fact for my
experience talking to you know the low
level programmers I'm not a low-level
programmers but I talked to C C plus
plus Java they don't know neither they
cannot explain
they they'll just say array of access is
constant okay if you don't know you are
an idiot that's that they don't know
they don't know themselves neither
but somebody knows of course there's
always some someone knows the answer
those are the people who actually
designed and implemented
the memory chips or CPU chips they
desired they design the electronics how
it works those people do know okay
those people actually understand because
even if you are a c programmer
you wouldn't know even if your assembly
programmer you wouldn't know why because
the answer has to do the with the design
of the memory chips how it's accessed
okay essentially it's just parallel in
nature
so this is uh
very important thing uh answer okay
and I learned that from this guy a
famous Chinese blogger a programmer and
computer scientist Ying Wang
so you know why is array indexing faster
than binary search that's the way he put
it but basically you're already indexing
is constant time and fast doesn't matter
which element you millionth or the first
element your access because
how the electronics and memory chips are
designed it's basically essentially the
answer is just parallel okay that's why
nothing now this has nothing to do with
mathematics okay this is not a natural
mathematical phenomenon
you know it's not a math Theory nothing
like that it just happened you know the
it's engineering it's history okay it's
the reason
array access is constant time because we
are using this particular design of
memory chips and you know the
electronics electricity running around
and transistors and they are lined in a
parallel way that's why
array access is constant time okay that
is why
so because so this is very fundamental
this is the most fundamental thing okay
this is the most critical and
fundamental property
because of these then
then we begin to talk why the
implementation details algorithmic
properties you have you know array
Vector turbo stack
all those depends on this all right
access is constant time
okay they all begin with this then from
this array data structure then you
create other things such as linked list
stack circular list
or even hash table it all depends on
this property array access is constant
time okay so this is very fundamental
and it has been a big puzzle for me and
none of the programmers I
I've seen able to explain to me until 10
years ago I
found this guy's article
not in textbooks not in Wikipedia
basically not anywhere you know I wonder
if gnuth
I wonder if gunus in his other
programming if he actually uh discussed
that so if you read good news you know
other programming if you know uh tell us
okay maybe maybe Groove expanded
I want I really want to see I really
want like to see
Okay so
so we have this
um
we touched on you know why array access
is constant time
so now
so this is critical concept array okay
so in Java in C you have the array
concept fast constant access however you
cannot grow or Shrink you know that's
another person in question
so because mathematically if you are the
genius from Mars or from outer space you
are the greatest mathematician you know
your math abilities is beyond all
Humanity
so you want an ordered sequence of
things
but why is it you cannot grow or Shrink
wait what what's going on how is it
possible you cannot add to an older
sequence of things
well because well we're talking about
computers you have a specific machine
you have a specific implementation and
it
so happens again because of the
electronics not necessarily other
machines like Quantum Computing or based
on other you know DNA Computing or based
on Abacus not necessarily but
specifically
the modern times our electronic computer
specifically because of these
you cannot
add
elements to array
okay you can but basically basically you
have to do just delete the whole thing
make a copy and and you know create a
new array with the new element in front
or what wherever you know that's
so that is why
again because of the hardware electronic
design of the memory and CPU okay
so
so okay that is why
uh let's see let's write it down okay so
we want to write down this copy across
back to emacs
um
why is the right access constant time
and why
cannot we add
or delete elements in it in constant
time
okay
in other words why can't we do it fast
you cannot
critical concept array okay and why it's
already access constant time and why
cannot we add our daily element in it in
constant time because
the CPU okay I mean because the memory
chip the way memory chips is designed in
electronics okay electronic computers of
today of today maybe not tomorrow maybe
you know
current technology okay so one thing I
want to emphasize again all this is just
happenstance it's not mathematical
property this you know constant time and
these are not part of theoretical
computer science okay many of the C
programmers see first they don't know
okay these programmers they don't know
these all these the things we are doing
today is not part of theoretical
computer science okay they are just part
of
Computer Engineering okay all these you
know complexities is not
natural okay it doesn't come from nature
it just came from the way we happen to
design uh electronic computers
okay
okay now so
so now we start to
um so so we have the array of c and Java
okay which is fixed length you cannot
add to it but access is fast doesn't
matter which item okay from there then
we developed other data structure with
different properties for a sequence of
older things and one of the most
prominent is called linked list okay
sometimes just called list
but again different languages use
different terms so
how do you do a linked list so first of
all what what is the property of linked
list linked list is such that you can
you can add or delete items in the front
very fast constant time but you cannot
access arbitrary items fast okay and the
way it's done is by
okay we already took 15 50 minutes
we we are now going to code
Okay so
but this is important so let me just
show you a list code okay so list okay
let's start to show code
let's start to code okay so start emac
lisp
uh
okay let's let's code so I'm going to
code a list I'm going going to show you
how
linked list is designed
okay but let's write down the properties
first I mean so what is uh linked is
what is the linked lists list okay
linked list or in short list is a
connected connect
is a
nested
tail nested
sequence of two items
okay that's
what it is okay
and for example
let me write an example a
suppose
we want a list
of items
a b c d okay
in linked
list
it looks like this
okay
okay
so you can see it's just you have a pair
of things then you just Nest it so if
you want the list of ABCD or older
sequence of things the way you implement
if you want to implement it as a linked
list then what you do is you start with
the pair and
so the first item of the pair represents
the item in your list and then the
second part of the pair is again a pair
and the first part of that is the item
of the list and the second part is again
a pair so all the way until you reach
the last item d
a b c d d then the second part is just
new or some other thing like zero or
special you know special item indicate
that's it okay so you have this nested
structure
to represent at least
and this is how lisp programming
language
Implement their list okay so let's show
some emac example emac this then let's
then let's start to um
so for example
uh let's say
list okay
how we want to to do that a b c d
and I hope this is I hope I can do this
correctly
so that's the least it is equivalent to
now in in this this pair you are seeing
it's called conspire and it's written
like that
uh wait
let's not use ABCD let's use one two
three four because we avoid the symbol
problem
one two three four Okay so
let's
one two three four
okay so
now let's go back so we have a list
there and uh this list is actually
so in lisp remember other sequence of
things this call at least
and it is actually
implemented as a linked list and it
looks like this okay let me show you
cons
to
cons uh
cons three
cons
four and Neo okay that's a linked list
okay how do you know how well we can
show they are equivalent so let's try
I I'm not sure this will work but I
think so so we're gonna evaluate this
you know testy quality
evaluate it Neo Okay so
wait
you see true
you see the output is true let's start
again
you see true
this shows how list
this list
is implemented as nested pairs okay
okay so there it is linked list this is
called linked list in computer science
okay so let's uh go to Wikipedia so you
can see you can read about it later okay
linked list you can see that
you know that pay us you know you just
nesting pay us okay
now this linked list again the property
of this this way of doing a older
sequence of things is that it's very
fast to remove the front item so add
items to the front however it's very
slow if you want to get the 10 000 item
you know the the further away the slower
it is because it has to go through all
the
uh you know kind of nesting links
okay that's the property
okay and let's let's write down the
property
uh
algorithmic
property of linked list
did we already write it down somewhere
there it is we already did algorithmic
property of uh
these predicts list okay
okay so and it and this linked list is
exactly also the most efficient data
structure for a stack because remember a
stack is there's an older sequence such
that you can always add or remove items
in the front
just just these two operations push and
pop add or remove items in front so it's
it's very fast forwarding to this okay
let's add a
header
okay
and that is exactly what we are going to
do what we are about to do we are going
to implement
a linked list in Python in JavaScript
and in Wolfram language okay and we want
to compare the speed hold on a second
there's one more thing one more thing
one more thing I want to explain
why we need to do that I mean so let's
explain Python's list okay
Python and Ruby and JavaScript
python Ruby JavaScript
their list
all chord array
is a smart array for like a bit for lack
of standard term
okay
so in python or if you program in Ruby
or you know actually I don't you are
yeah it's an impact in Ruby and
JavaScript you know if you are familiar
with them they have a data structure
called um
list well in Python it's called list
and in Ruby
uh George what is Ruby's list or array
data structure church is an expert of
Ruby and JavaScript a professional
programmer so in Ruby
I don't know really well but I only I
just learned it um
do they call uh Ruby I mean what's what
is the official jargon for Ruby's at
least do they call it array or list
you can find that by searching it quick
quickly
okay so Ruby in Ruby it's called array I
guess
yeah Ruby
so Ruby calls it array
in JavaScript it's called also called
array okay
so you have this so let me explain this
one
so mathematically
you have the concept of ordered sequence
of things
but however
when you have a machine a physical
machine and a programming language which
is a written instruction on how to
manipulate machine
so when you work on an actual machine
you need to you know you need a
programming language to you need a
actual instructions how you manipul a
machine
that you need to design the you you need
to implement the data structure you need
to make this abstract concept of order
the sequence of things into some actual
instructions
so when you do that you have issues you
have issues of implementation detail in
algorithmic properties
what are the issues that is the issues
is it fast to access any random element
or can you add or delete items in the
element is it gonna be slow so you have
these questions com comes up okay
uh you know why the why the why are
there these issues because you are
actually working with the machine you
know machine programming language turns
your code into actual instructions you
know do this move this here you know
that's why you have these things and
these things came from again all based
on array array is um
uh because it so happens uh
of the digital electronics so array you
have the array
uh implementation which is fixed length
but fast random access time okay array
so from array then we started to do we
can have linked list now so the question
now is what what about python Ruby
JavaScript what do they do okay now we
know in lisp they there this is linked
list okay in this
uh but what about
python Ruby
you know this it's interesting because
you know you have this annoying issues
you know one is that you can access any
item fast but you cannot add items you
know what what the pain in the ass or
you can add items to the front very fast
but then access any random element is
very slow so it's like like a dilemma
so what does python Ruby JavaScript do
well what they do is what they call they
they create something called like a
smart array so basically what they do is
they they just have a fixed array
a fixed length array
so that means you cannot add or remove
element
however when you want to add elements
the programming language is actually
smart they so when you want to add
element it just
it creates a new array but with lots of
empty spots so later on when you add
elements
it doesn't have to recreate the whole
so that's why it's called I call them
smarter array because there's no no
standard term smart array basically it's
a
you know it's a array but it
automatically
expand you know create a new array with
lots of empty spots so you don't have to
constantly recreate the array every time
you want to add an item
so usually it doubles like if your array
length is
10 then you add one more item then it
internally creates an array of 20 spots
so and it it keeps the index you know it
adds your item but after that it's all
zero empty
but it's hidden from you from your point
of view you are just seeing an array of
11 items but beneath it it manages this
empty spots so that's a smart array that
is done in Python
in Ruby in JavaScript
okay
okay so that
so that is the explanation so far why
are we going to
what are we going to do why are we doing
what we are doing today we are going to
try to implement a stack or a linked
list in Python and we are just going to
keep adding item push items to the front
to see which is faster is the default
implementation you know python is is it
is it fast or our own implementation
linked list okay let's see
so that is why we are coding today okay
so far uh previously it's just the
explanation okay let's start to code
python
but let's write it down first
it's such that
they
entirely internally create a new array
with double the length when you want to
add a item to the array and
hide that from you
okay something like that okay
okay now let's Implement Stacks in
Python okay
okay so we are in Python
okay let's start to code python Okay so
we are going to use a turbo so uh
so what we're gonna we are going to
um
so
an ordered sequence of things
with two operations
push
push is at an item in front
pop is delete an item in front Okay
that's what we're gonna do so
so you have first of all you need to
create uh create uh so you need to write
a function
and that's that's I don't know how I
don't know if I can do it but let's try
it okay
can you have trouble of empty Element no
uh well yeah but can you have Tuple of
two elements okay
you have uh empty list
okay you can't even actually have an
empty list okay God
foreign
[Music]
so
so to create a linked list we need a
pair a data structure of pair so and in
Python the pair is done by Turbo Okay so
so what so we so we want to create
um let's see create
okay creating this okay and uh
and here x list okay
X this is whatever pythons list okay and
then
we want to say
we want to Loop through it
look through it okay so let's do a loop
loop through Beast
dictionary Loops through dictionary
iteration iterator to list in memory
list okay
yeah so we can do that
for item
for XX in
exist and what we want to do is first of
all create a variable
foreign
can we do that actually I don't know
okay something like that so you need the
turbo here
something like that
okay
can we run it let's run it let's see
there's a syntax error
finish okay let's call it
one two
okay run it Chase okay type Arrow
creating this takes one position or
argument but two are given okay
yeah okay yeah so you need at least
okay done it
okay it runs so now let's print it
run it
fantastic fantastic
so we we have implemented a linked list
or stack at least you know the how to
create it we need to implement push and
pop okay but but now
um but now let's see type
okay
now you you want to see the type of can
you run that no invalid syntax okay now
type class turbo exactly okay
now let's Implement pop
it's in this uh
the name is too long okay
let's just say link to list
okay so now we want to
Let's remove that okay we want to Define
push and pop okay
push okay
now uh
Okay add an item to
the front
of linked list area okay
so
so add an item so
item okay
X
Okay add X Okay so
that's it
okay
Let's test test it
X
to
and say X1
run it fantastic
run it fantastic now add
X2
add a push LL okay
push LL
U wants X1 and push an item let's say
three
okay we got we should have three one two
okay now print X2
Arrow LL is not defined oh yeah this is
the this is should be X planet
fantastic we have a linked list in
Python a stack
so anyone else anyone is watching four
people say hi guys say hi something give
me some you know encouragement give me
some feedback so we
we did
linked list in Python fantastic now
let's
um now what we we need to implement pop
okay
hey
pop
delete the first item of linked list XLR
okay so pop doesn't pop this just take
one element so
so um
so
so xxll you want to take the
second item Cooks a nice keyboard thank
you fantastic thank you
so pop link list so how do you get the
second element of a tuple in Python so
let's see
a dictionary Tuple so how do you get the
second element type of iterable I
believe it's the same as the
um
same as least okay yeah
yep
so return that
second element Python's python is
indexed by zero so the second element is
one okay so run it so far so good then
let's say X3
equals to Let's copy that
let's say X3 equals true path
pop X
2 x 3 equals 2 Pub X2
now print X3 unit
fantastic
so
that's
we have
implemented linked list in Python
and so you do that's all you need this
push and pop is similar to the lisps
car
in the cutter okay
push in this is called car
you know with your name historical but
if you call this you know and the Qatar
in this is Pop basically
okay so we got so now we got a stack we
got a linked list which is
the standard implementation for stack
push and pop so so now we want to test
how fast how fast is this compared to
normal you know just no use Python's
normal list and delete the first element
you know how fast is it
so let's uh so so
um so let's
let's implement
then let's try to implement
using the normal okay
you don't you don't need to create
because you can create uh
you know you can just create a listing
python it's building so but what if you
want to push
and let's say list okay python list and
the pop is also this okay
push python list you know we we want to
use a function here because otherwise
we have the cost of function call
because we are going to call push and
pop for 1 million items something like
that so and we want to compare the speed
of our implementation using of the stack
versus pythons you know
so that's why we want to
do a function wrapper otherwise it's
unfair comparison so
foreign
x to the front of python least XL Okay
so
so how do you add an item to uh
two pythons list let's see
python list count item check existence
go to item uh change item delete item
get sub list delete sub list
replace at least you know I think our
stack is going to be way faster than
python now that we are doing it
uh during this okay you can join this
you can do but uh do they have let's see
these methods you know python is oop so
you have
okay in Python you know they don't have
a pre-paint
they have a paint
or extend so the the way a python this
implementation is that it's very
efficient to add to the to the end but
not to the front
you know it just depends on your
implementation you can reverse it either
way so in Python they do a pen so
so let's use a pen because it's faster
you know we just have to remember the
you know the order are different
because we want to be fair to to
Python's list
so let's so return so what did we return
this append okay copy that
so here is uh let's see X list okay so X
list
then a pin X okay
that's okay
push
push python on this okay so that's that
should be it add x to the front to 2D to
the end
okay
the then pop is the delete first item so
how do you
do that in Python
oh there is pop
wait
if this pop there must be a push too
what
let's try you see a push I think it
might be a pain left
where a pen in Python will act as push
okay are you sure
but let's try if there is a
push okay
instrument
right this object has not attribute push
okay but what about top
okay so python has pop but no push
idiotic python
yes Bob but no push
python is the worst language okay I
really
hate it you know I talked about this in
lots of my videos search for it you'll
find it so python doesn't have
pop it has
it has pop building but not push okay so
we want to imply and push this just say
append is there some shift or I believe
I have them all listed here yeah
remove first occurrence okay that's not
Okay so
so first of all let's focus push how do
you implement push okay append
uh
okay maybe there's a pin left but it's
slower because I believe we one day we
tested with George you know George there
uh we we test on Discord and uh
which end matters so
so push is append okay and the pop what
about pop X list okay so let's do pop
uh
pop DD the last item
to do the last item of
of python Beast
exist okay so DD the last item in return
it
okay so you just do pop okay
let's try Okay so let's now try it
let's try our code
uh so
okay
okay then let's say why
so print it print the type and now
push python list okay
push y1 give it three then print it
should be one two three then pop
of Y2 print Y3 it should be one two
again okay
run it okay Arrow
so
pop LL okay we got the variable naming
incorrect
pop python list okay
hmm
okay open it
exist pop what
none type object has no attribute pop so
here
so X list
what
so there is pop
but
[Music]
um
but
why is it not working
stack uh Line 39 Line 39 there
X list pop
so X list so this is Pop python list
so Y2 is a list and you want to pop it
why can't you pop it
return xlist dot pop attribute error
none type object has no attribute pop
what are they talking about
anyone knows
it doesn't return
oh what
we move the last item and return that
item
it doesn't return right
where's the
you know that's the error message
read 10.
Y2 is none oh right thank you
so let's see why two oh yeah right Y2 is
none so should we return or not
let's check so in our function
we do return it so when you push
normally when you push you want to
return
yeah normally yeah that's the case in
lisp in linked list so when you push you
want to return the new list okay so so
therefore we need to have it return so
so append
then
then return this okay thank you
secondary account thank you
okay fantastic now let's try it also to
print uh
Y2
now let's double check one last time
because next step we are going to time
it we are going to push a median item
something like that so double check the
they are actually doing the same thing
so we have
linked list linked Turbo so yeah we add
one two three we add an item
then we drop an item
okay now in the python list you have at
least one two order is the other way
then one two three
then you okay so we need to actually
return the item here
not just return the new
um
thing
so we need to modify here
X2 here push
just return the list
and pop
pop
leads to the return that item but it
also needs to
God
pop needs to return that item
also modify the variable
so
okay so this is what we need to do
so XLR
equals to
excess LL equals to the second part but
you first
something like that so you get the first
item
of this nested Tuple you get the first
then you
set that excess cell to the rest item
then you return first okay
yeah that's that's when we that's what
we want let's do it again let's run it
double check one more time
all right let's run it double check
okay check
check
uh what are we doing
create push in pop okay
create push three
okay then pop
then pop okay
in pop Okay so
pop
[Music]
then when we pop
oh yeah this should be zero okay zero do
it again
create push pop
okay
then then we need to print
X2 okay
create push pop
between X2 so X2 is not
it didn't change
when we pop X2
wait
uh maybe it's better if we
create then
push X1
uh
push when you push
push X
two okay
green X1 X2
so X1 and X2 should be the same
okay let's forget about pop and let's
forget about the others so just to
verify
so they are not the same but
um
false okay hold on a second
okay your name again
create
comments comments okay comments push
print X1 yeah we need to
X1 is yeah
pain yes
two is
okay x one is that X2 is that
they are not the same what
X2
oh yeah obviously they are not the same
but I made a mistake
no okay so obviously they are not the
same
so we don't need a type and draining
again
X Y is next to X
x 2 is that
obviously they are not the same then
when you
pop X2
when you pop X2
so X2 changed
hold on a second
and let's say
pop one
there's no X3 so
so you pop you print the pop value then
you print X1 and X2 okay
do it
so when you pop X2
the pop value is three
so it didn't set X2 is
X2 Remains the Same
you see x 2 should be
one value removed but it Remains the
Same so the pop
okay yeah so you know I know what's the
problem because
because you see this xll is local
it does not ah this is more
difficult than
imagined this excess xll is local to the
function
so
so you need to kind of
how do you
wait python is passed by reference right
so
exhale
so if you just
pumped value is correct okay
uh
but however
however
it doesn't
um
it doesn't change
these
it doesn't actually delete
the elements
so
so we have to think about so
X2
X2 is a turbo nested Turbo
okay so when you call Pop LL
U it's defined it takes a tuple
uh and does does anyone know how to
solve this
it takes a turbo
oh yeah so here you are creating this is
uh yeah this is a complex issue of
python so here you are creating can you
actually use pop
I believe you can
so these methods so can you actually use
pop
okay let's do a alternative
implementation so pop it's a turbo so
you just pop the Tuple
that's right so you pop the total XXL
Pop That
okay
now let's see
purple object has no attribute part
python
when you have a turbo
you want the same Tuple
you want the because you know it has to
do with the references
foreign
methods
does anyone do we have a python coders
here
Luther Turbo
convert each other to triple triple gain
or change
oh yeah that's why turbo cannot change
but
yeah but how do you how do you implement
it I mean how do you implement linked
list with turbo
maybe we shouldn't use turbo then let's
use
let's use Python's smarter way to
implement
um
yeah let's let's do that so what we're
gonna do is we pop this out so here's so
here's today's talk show
so here's our python code we're just
gonna make a copy of it and do a second
implementation so syntax correct
and let's do a second implementation
this time we use Python's list
to implement the pairs okay so not Turbo
okay so I think that's that
then push is
now since we are using Python's list
yeah we still push to the front okay
so uh
so yeah so
so if you do
let me show you
so if you do this that's not good
because this creates a new
least
you see it's a tricky problem because
you want to modify that you don't want
to create new so here you have
oh I think secondary got a solution
uh
no
let's keep going to going here so
if you push
you don't want to create you don't want
to return a new entity you want to just
modify that entity
oh my God this is problematic because
then you're gonna have recursive lists
and God this is
close to two hours now
so
um
so the problem right now is to implement
push and pop
the problem now is that when you give a
you know
list
you want to return the same list you
don't want to change it because that's
what push and pop do it modifies the
least
but if you say
you know if you do return this that you
know that actually return a new
different list
so
so therefore to fix this one for example
you want to
um
you want to let's go back to list this
myth
generate at least this comprehension
uh these methods
oh God
so okay so let's use append then if you
use a pen that means you also add to the
to the
right
okay let's let's use a pen because that
way you don't return a new list
okay
a lot of complexities in frustration so
wait that wait that's not uh wait you
can't you can't do that
because the point is you have you you
need to Nest them
the point is that you need to Nest them
so
oh God so there's a lot of operations
you have to do so given at least
you need to
remove
so the argument the argument here is a
nested list python list each each
element has has just two items
so when you push
yeah this is hard to do you because you
need to
you can just create a new one you need
to
when you push you need to
you need to
put the first item
to the second item
in the new first item is the argument
yeah something like that okay so let's
try to do that
so when you push you want to something
like this okay
something like this
so you this is new item
let's say x new okay so this is new item
and and you and you can you can just
return that because that just create a
new thing
so you actually so you need to
so actually
yeah so this is
the this is
something like this okay so you have the
first and rest
and then you want to say
you want that to be the X
new okay and you want the rest to be
to be
foreign
so this way you just modify the turbo
you don't actually
replace create a new entity so yeah so
this way you modify the top only C
maybe they'll walk
but you do this there's a cost of the
assignment that should be fast because
it's just references
uh yeah so okay can we does this work
push LL
okay
turbo object does not support item
assignment yeah
turbo okay
what
okay so it's not a turbo then
so this should be that
okay
okay we are getting close
uh create one two
let's say create one two three
okay X1
then push
it doesn't work
okay yeah it's a mistake
next one is four yeah so we
there's some error
thanks area is a list of two items okay
okay so first
rest okay
and let's turn it in what yeah
yeah so
thanks you know
new is um
oh yeah so this should be
so yeah
oh wait and then you get recursive thing
yeah you get recursive thing yeah God
this is how to implement we got a
recursive list
I'm not sure we can I can do it
um
you know so the problem is pretty simple
implement
you know at least you know linked lists
in Python
and right now it just failed at push
so okay well but the solution is to look
at python
where how you can
maintain
the reference yeah but the thing is if
you do that then
you know even you know you you know
essentially you are going to recreate at
least that defeats the whole purpose
of linked list you know you cannot every
time you create a new item add push your
item you you you do not want to recreate
the whole list so
and yet the problem is yet you want to
maintain the reference you know that
that argument
must not
have a new reference you know
first rest
so we don't actually need the rest
the second element is
yeah so that's a problem so here what
you can do is like copy
something like that
do we have an example here
but you cannot use copy because you do
then that's just creating a whole
Beast which is super inefficient
um
so do we have any python experts
dictionary Topo said sequence types
sequence types
sequence times dictionary methods
so
copy nested list so we I do have a
yeah so this is how you actually make a
copy
so what you do here is
and just say list
that
but that defeats the purpose although
the re you know that
because this is making a copy of list oh
wait this is the shadow copy
I'm gonna Shadow copy is not good
because it's using references you got
then you get recursive you know like we
did we got a recursive list
basically infinite so this part is
referring to three to one
and
something like that you know
juicy boy
so juicy boy do you see what I'm doing
do you understand
do you do you have a solution
so so actually we got stuck
we got stuck in implementing a linked
list
in Python
you know while trying to maintain the
properties of linked list efficiency
and not just LinkedIn this we need to
create push and pop which means it needs
to you know give an argument it needs to
modify the argument
and meanwhile not recreate you know the
copy of your list it just it should nest
so we are stuck here
and as far as I know at this moment I'm
not even sure it can be done
okay
I'm not sure it even can be done
so we essentially failed
in python so far I would conclude
um 80 confident
it cannot be done eighty percent
confident
you cannot create a efficient stack
structure
in in Python
without getting into C so I mean you can
write a library using C
for example let's look maybe there
probably already is you know you have to
code C module I mean create a python
module in C something so python
attack
there it is there it is okay there's a
stack Overflow question how to implement
a python stack you see people actually
ask those questions
uh okay let's check you know many of
these are low quality blocks
they write that because they want money
you know ads
so let's look at some of them
okay stack Overflow usually is
trustworthy
no push pop okay first implementation
the following stack implementation
assumes at the end of list will hold the
top elements of the stack okay
idiotic you know it's it's not a stack I
mean it's just it's just push and pop
using the default
python list
so let's see you know it's just
it's just a rapper you know
you just reverse order that's all so we
push it just called append so there's no
change no actual change
you know it's just python Beast it's not
really your stack
second implementation the second
implementation as soon as at the
beginning of the list holds the top okay
yeah it's just a wrapper so it's no good
you see so he says these are optimized
for a painting and piping from the end
inserting or removing item from
beginning of this is much more expensive
because uh python does does have a data
structure collections the key
okay that's not
okay that's not what we you know they
are just talking about which side is
more efficient to add it doesn't
actually touch on the nursing data
structure
so I doubt you will find the answer
online so what's time you know this
these are the most idiotic usually with
the
you know pretty picture
this uh scam website
what's a stack okay
implementing a python stock stack so you
just use the key in a list of key
now I wonder so the library the key or
key are they using
wait key is not a stack actually so Keys
No no good
you know they are just using these they
are not
uh yeah you see a pen pop
whatever
using this to create the python stack
okay using collections.dkey to create a
python stock Okay so
the corrections module contains the key
which is useful for creating python
stocks the key is pronounced deck okay
deck and standard for double ended key
oh it's idiotic
so stack okay again
so the real answer is lies in the D key
how do they implement this
is it just a wrapper or is it actual
C code where is it
returns a new D key object initialize
the key are generalist generalization of
stacks and keys okay
suppose let's say safe memory efficient
opinion part there it is okay
this is what we want this is what we are
trying to do
so right now
what we have to do is to look at the
source code of D key
okay to see whether it's actually a
python code
I doubt I think it's C code
okay because so far from Alex you know
from my experience I don't think
it can be done
so
so yeah so we have to look at the
collections the key source code okay
let's let's search for that
so Library locations
um source code okay where's my
okay let's let's put some comment here
there is
okay
let's see if this collection is the key
let's see if it's
source code is in python or C okay
search for that
uh we need python okay there are python
documentation now
we need the python source code
can we actually so where's python
Library
and let's just go look at the live
python Library
so
python you need to print uh
you need to print version
prints
module
you need to print Python's Library
location
okay
oh yeah so I think okay let's go look
okay python
what's the difference
okay those are binaries
there it is collections
okay
yeah so you see
it's a c code what is this ABC
collection AB ABC in Portal
wait is that
there it is the key
this module implements specialized
container data types providing
alternatives to Python's general purpose
building containers dictionary this set
table exactly
so D key so there it is
so and
so in needs so this I need
let's see
search for that copy list all lines
containing it
from collections import okay
let's go to it
go to it
Okay so
you don't get the source code because
the source code is in C
this matching lines DF
pop item named top of most common okay
one key copy
okay
so there's cash
so why is it named abc dot p y does
anyone know
why is his abc dot p y there it is the
that's a that's a cash
but
can can anyone confirm this is
this is C code or not
so
right now
we want to determine
the source code of
python collection start D key whether
that's C or not
there it is source code
wait
no this
solutions problems of hacker rank of
python module but
foreign
no
so let's go to python source code
python GitHub
C python I suppose
modules deep
collections
turn on JavaScript
[Music]
callable generic areas collections ABC
in Portal in apy this is what we have
seen
but where is the
does anyone know python code us out
there nobody
okay so nobody I guess
wait where's the how is I paid us
and I'm very organized
I mean how is it uh
and see it's go up
here is what is this
okay this I don't know what are those
files
DLS
there it is
so there is a key
yeah so I don't know how pythons
source code is
arranged
um
connection not there
so we need to know
okay so in this case
you need to read up
the python implementation detail
which I've never read before so
standing and embedding
something like that something there
so
Library reference
magnify
collection packages
container data type abstract base
classes for containers oh that's what
ABC stands for
abstract Base Class okay so key the key
is implemented as
of as the abstract data class
okay
so what I want to know if D key is
written in C
and
99 sure
but
I want to be 100 sure
okay
so so that's why that's what we are
doing
so
collections okay container data types
okay abstract Base Class container data
types
okay so you have the key
this module implements specialized
container data types okay alternatives
to pylon's general purpose building
containers okay it's not in CD key
this is a class so it's an object
so the key is supposed to be a
generalized stack
meaning that it can be a key or it can
be a stack
uh
Keys is is
uh first in less up something like that
it's you know
you know it's like a line waiting a lie
so the key
so you have the key but does it mention
how is it implemented
changing version 3.5 new methods okay
software that's updated uh
so okay
so this is alternative data structure
okay and but
where is the C code that's what I want
to know is it written in C
source code oh here source code
wait is it it easy written in Python
so source code is just init
dot py okay
source code is just init.py okay
connections this is a source code
and okay so you can use self
that's right
but if you do that only if it's um
Okay so
okay now it's getting closer so it's not
written in C
it's not written in C so
let's go back
to the documentation
and let's read about this class
Corrections
this like container with fast pens or
pops on either end okay so let's look at
that
key object okay
whole one performance in either
direction okay
the release objects supports similar
operations they are optimized for Fast
Fixed length operations and incur om
memory movement costs to pop
and insert exactly
operations which change both size and
position of the underlying underlying
data structure okay that is
what we've been talking about
okay so if max length
is not given it's not specified under
and Key May grow to an arbitrary length
otherwise key is bounded so
this key
it's like stack but open in both ends
so how do they Implement that I suppose
it's doubly linked list
okay so but we are getting closer we are
getting closer to look at how they
Implement that
so
so here is an example of how to use it
so you import it
then you just say key
right a key is a string
tray over the keys elements GHI
what
the key
deck that's a string
so you have pop
return is removed right Mouse item then
you have pop left
then you have
these con this this bothers me so the
input is a stream
what
okay let's search for pop
foreign
what about the abstract data class
abstract basic class
doesn't say much
so this file is 1500 lines
1500 lines
and I suppose we can be we can read you
know if we have time we can read the
entire thing
1500 lines which is not too big
so the key
try import the key import error so
try from underscore connections
okay
so try from underscore collections
yeah it's in C I'm pretty sure
so what the is underscore
collections
you see
so underscore collections there
what is this
oh what the so how many values is
this
1000 lines not too much and it's search
for key
search for D key okay
underscore collection subscribe based
classes for collections according to pep
3119 the python pep
foreign
introduction introducing abstract-based
classes
2007 kidovan Rosen idiot
rationale acknowledgment rational
specification
anyone here python experts we need
python experts
okay if you are say it
so and right now we are trying to find
out this the key
Library this the key module is it
written in python or in C
let's search dqe okay and uh
I try to implement it today in the past
hour and failed because of the reference
issue
I cannot do it without screwing up the
properties of a proper key data
structure
and so
yeah so actually that's very interesting
in fact because I thought it's just
possible
it may not actually be possible I mean
from a functionalist point of view from
a functional point of view I mean what
it do
yeah of course you can just create a
nested
Tuple
but but then you don't have the
efficiency property
that's a problem
especially because of the operations
push and pop they need to modify the
variable
you know the variable whose value is a
list ordered sequence
you cannot return a new one
so
so but in order to do that you need the
language needs to be able to use
references
you know reference to that
object
uh
uh no is you still need to you need to
modify the object so you need to somehow
working a lower level
so right now I don't think it's possible
to implement
an efficient stack in Python
with Python language unless you go into
C code
and that's what we are trying to
determine now so
search the key the key is not found here
so what is the underscore thing
so let's see abstract Base Class
collections according to pep okay you
need testing okay you need tests are in
test collections okay
abstract reason Okay so
so here
you see right now what is the difference
between Collections and underscore
collections
you see so there is that
there is that
so it's trying to try from underscore
collections input D key
then
multi-sequence register degree multiple
mutable sequence
so if that fails yes
underscore collection start metaphor
sequence okay so the key is in this
low-lying collections ABC
but here
that's one thousand lines
but I'm not seeing any D key here
okay
the key all so this is all exported
symbols
multiple set muted
ball set okay that is
that is that okay mutable sequence okay
now let's go back
leave collections
abc dot p y abstract basic class
basically import all
okay and this form
okay again it's import from underscore
collections underscore ABC
and uh this init shows that
shows that
all the symbols it exports so search for
the key yeah there
but then you can see it's
try to import from
underscore collections
so that's the
these matching lines that's all the
currents there is so okay so the main
one is just this one must be
underscore collections abc dot mutable
sequence dot register D key
okay
underscore collections
underscore ABC
multiple sequence
dot register
uh
uh so multiple sequence not register
okay now let's go to the underscore
so there is multiple sequence
okay so there
so you are importing this yeah so you
are immutable sequence wait
beautiful sequence.register
so there it is there is pop
uh
there is beautiful adult sequence that
register
okay I failed to determine whether it's
in C code or not it will be another day
so
now it's two hours in 30 minutes thank
you guys for watching
zero people watching now so three
so we so today we the first hour we
expand
you know where it is summarized in three
minutes we shut down okay
so first hour we summarized
the problem we are trying to do which is
uh where is it
okay you know the the jargons
you know the concept ordered sequence of
things and what's the difference between
array list Vector turbo
why are there these things uh the reason
they are there and the meaning of them
the algorithmic properties
and why do you have those differences so
why do you have you know this array key
why are they different why is that
sometimes you know
the algorithmic properties are different
the reason what's the cause then we
explain what's a stack then we expand
the lists list how it's implemented
which is a linked list you know the
jargon then the critical concept of
array the most common Concept in C which
is a fixed length but a random access
constant Random Access time for any
element element and from that and then
we explain why is it constant access
time this is the most important why is
the C array or Java what the concept fix
you know array why is it constant
access time and because for that that's
a well that's because the machine
implementation the electronic the
physical machine
uh because the parallel circuit
basically that's the nature of the
parallel circuit in memory
in memory chips so
so that's why array access is constant
time
then uh
then so from that it's basically all
programming language is based on so you
have constant time array access then you
have linked list then you have Smart
array which is done in Python Ruby
JavaScript
uh then
then okay
so then we are trying to implement
linked this in Python
in particular we are trying to use it as
a stack so we are trying to create a
data structure in Python with push and
pop operation such that
they are efficient they are very
efficient using linked list
but so that's the second hour the second
hour in the third hour we were trying to
do that and we failed we failed because
we
we can't make it
actually do what they do
so then I try to search the third hour I
try to search
whether you know the apparently there is
a library called
um
call these collections that implements
what we wanted they call it deck or D
key deck I suppose let's let's see we
keep hedia is that
um
oh yeah so okay there it is double ended
key okay so a key is like
um a key is just like a line you know
you waiting a line so the first person
come in the line the first person to go
and double any ended key just means you
can
you can move in both ways
uh so once you have that then you it's
kind of generalized stack okay so anyway
so so python has this Library
but
I failed to determine whether that
library is written in C or not
because if it's written in C then it
showed that
you know it's true that we cannot
implement it in Python code we have to
dive into C because the Python language
does not expose
sufficient
um
thing okay so I'm not able to determine
whether that's written in C or not
but meanwhile it does appear it's not
written in C
so if it's not written in C
so that means it's possible to implement
this
this efficient stack or deck
in Python code
so then so the question is how to do
that
so we spend one hour trying to implement
that and the difficulty is that you need
to
somehow manipulate the reference
uh and I I wasn't able to do so
so I don't know maybe I'll you know so
that's it for today
bye guys I'll ask some python Expo
expert Dion is a python expert
bye guys