Good evening. Good evening, guys.
Welcome to another episode of Cloud Talk
Show. So, we're going to start to code
JavaScript
in depth functional pro programming
today. Functional Programming Supreme.
This is my keyboard, Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard 80, UHK80.
Uh, search my YouTube, you'll find
reviews. Okay. Uh, now let's get on to
uh code. Okay. So, here is this talk
show showing browser. So you can see my
Emacs. So those uh the most powerful
editor Emacs that I'm using the ping
window shows all my uh command codes and
keystrokes. You can see uh why can't I
just um so you can see
oh it didn't wait what happened to my um
it does not let me move my cursor up
anyway. So let's focus on JavaScript.
Okay, JavaScript. So we going to do uh
functional programming. Okay. So let
let's start to do it. Okay. I'm uh going
to teach you something about functional
programming in JavaScript. Okay. Uh hey
brother AC. Hello. Awesome. The show uh
the show is still on. Yes. Yes. Uh yes.
Test. Test. Audio check. Video check.
Right. Okay. So JavaScript. Okay. So
let's go to uh let's begin JavaScript.
um JavaScript in depth and uh scroll
down. So this is the best tutorial on
JavaScript my tutorial. Okay, so let's
uh just just go to um
functional programming. Okay, so you can
you can you can check uh miscellaneous
at the bottom there's advanced section
about functional programming uh
JavaScript exclamation uh before
function. I should move those away. Uh
anyway, here so JavaScript style guide
for functional programmers. Okay, so uh
I have a bunch of tips. If you're going
to if uh you want to format your
JavaScript code, I recommend Deno
format. Deno, okay, demo. Deno is the
best thing. [snorts]
Download Deno. Okay, uh Deno is much
better than MPN, MPM or NodeJS. Okay, so
I recommend Deno for code for formatting
and uh uh disable auto format for code
block. uh if you want to do that yeah uh
sometimes you need to do that because
sometimes you have anyway there there
are occasions you need to do this okay
but let's go back never use v so anyway
I have some tips okay but first of all
so these are basic tips uh arranged from
the most easy to understand easy to do
then to the most advanced functional
programming tips okay so in the
beginning the so for example uh by the
way you can see uh my code you know my
functional programming code this is um
this is unic code so let's go to unic
code I got a lot of things to do uh to
talk about so
uh at this rate we'll never finish so
for example this is uh unic code search
you can type anything let's say f i e
and uh it will show up uh let's m let's
shrink
It will show up all the characters as as
you type. Uh for example, f i e show up
uh dynamically or unic code whose name
contains f i r e. Oh, let's try water.
Okay. W A T E R. Okay. Let's say fruit.
F R U. Okay. There's only one Unicode
character contains whose name contains
the word F ru. Okay, let's say uh you
know when you try something uh funky
that's more interesting. Let's say
number n u mb e r. So n u n. So y
capital case
n u mb e. Uh so you got more than 500
characters that's number. Okay. So let's
see. So let's try. So now let's do at t
h o u n. So you got 122 characters, you
know. So these are all
uh characters in different human
languages that represents the number
10,00. Okay. Very interesting.
Okay. So you can see this code. This is
Unicode. So let's go to Unicode uh.ts.
So that is the uh
that code is the
search. So that is that JavaScript
search typescript.
Okay. So this um wait that's the data
part. So search is this part. Okay. So
this is all pure functional code. Okay.
So that's the I'm talking about that
because I was I was going to tell you
where the screenshot came from. So I
mean the screenshot just give you a
sense of like what functional
programming style looks like in
JavaScript. So you can see this file.
Okay. So this file is only like 300
lines. Okay. Pure functional
programming. Fantastic. Okay. So we
talked about that that close close um
close close. Uh we got a lot of things
to do actually. Uh don't close that.
Okay. So showing browser what is this
unic code block close show in browser.
Uh okay so why so I want to tell you
about functional programming guide.
Okay. So beginning in the beginning you
just don't use var and always declare
variables. Okay. Declare them by let or
constant. Okay. Never use double equal
because double equal they automatically
do type conversion. So then you get a
situation if you do compare empty string
versus empty array it will come out
equal or some some weird result you know
double equal so don't use that use
triple equal okay so there's full detail
about that so all these are easy um to
do uh things never use forin loop
because for in loop you uh they they
will go up to the parent chain which is
basically never what you want they go to
the prototype chain. Okay, so you want
to use object keys instead or for of
loop. Okay, object keys uh then do for
each then uh then you can also do um you
know so there's a a bunch of ways to
list properties in JavaScript. You can
use object.key keys or and uh uh object
get own property names and reflect own
keys. You know they they are a bit
complicated because in JavaScript you
got the issue of innumerable keys versus
symbol keys versus string keys. So each
way to to list the keys differ whether
depending on whether you want the you
want non innumerable keys to be included
or if you want the symbol keys to be
included. Usually you don't want okay
but uh sometimes you do and or if you
want them to go to up the up one up the
uh prototype chain so that so that if
you want that that then you use for loop
but almost you never want that
okay so so so
the key here is don't use for in loop
okay because most people don't know they
just like for in uh because that's the
most familiar because that exists is in
lots of other languages like Python but
that's a mistake if you do that in
JavaScript that's a mistake for in loop
don't use that okay use for of loop so
for of loop that I have an introduction
so let's see for in loop um uh for of
loop for of loop is introduced in 2015
okay so use that don't do forin okay so
we so this these are tips for functional
programming and as well as some other uh
basically JavaScript tip tips. For
example, this for in loop that's not
really about functional programming.
It's about um JavaScript problems you
want to avoid. Okay. Anyway, let's move
on. So width never use width. In fact,
width got uh you can't even use it today
because they um in Deno for example they
um
the in in in in any code that contains a
module of JavaScript they automatically
evaluate it. They turn the mod into a
use strict mod which does not allow with
statement. Okay. So anyway that's a
width statement. I don't know if you
guys even know about that because nobody
use it in. Okay, so never assign array
by index.
Okay, that's another um issue like
sometimes in other programming languages
you just create an array and you assign
array index zero equals to something
index n equals to something right don't
do that in JavaScript okay because that
easily that will create a sparse array
sparse array means you got array but
some item does not exist like you you
got this complicated situation like
array but some item that doesn't
actually exist so what happens S if you
map, you know, map some function to the
array, weird things happen depending on
which method you use. For example, if
you use map, they skip these nonexistent
indexes. But if you use some other
function, let's say array.form or field
depending on the method. So then then
they will automatically
view these empty indexes by a value of
undefined. Okay. So um so depends on the
method. So you got the complic
complicated situation whenever you call
a method on array you have to think
about oh whether this is sparse or not
which method I'm using on it whether
that method how they deal with
array when it is sparse array. Okay. So
in general you never want anything you
you never want the situation of sparse
array to happen. Okay. So one of the tip
to avoid sparse array is just never um
assign array element like that. Usually
this is not a good thing to do anyway in
algorithms. You usually you want to
manipulate array in a systematic way
like push pop shift and shift. Those are
common ways to
>> [snorts]
>> um common uh methodology in data
structure uh in algorithms because those
are stacks you know so when you use
array like a stack you you want push pop
shift and shift okay so that's a common
way to do it but if you need to uh
remove items in array for example array
represent let's say some some list of
things that's important things so when
you finish with that thing you don't
want the list you don't want it to be in
a array right suppose suppose this array
means a to-do list or uh existing bank
account something right so if a count is
closed you don't want that element to be
in an array anymore so in so if you want
to systematically deal with array you
use a splice key splice
uh method okay so array prototype these
are all array methods you want to use um
uh splice or even better if if you are
doing functional programming you use two
spliced. So this two splice is added in
2023 two years ago. What does it do?
It's exactly like splice except it
returns a new value. It does not modify
the array. Okay. So it's like so you
know the JavaScript is trying to fix
lots of things trying to improve. So
this new function two years ago two
spliced. Okay. So anyway that's about
array.
So uh am I doing good? Do you guys like
what I'm doing? Because I want to move
on, you know, because I'm, you know,
usually I don't like to like give a
tutorial, you know, because I I got lots
of things to do. I I need to work on my
tutorial. So uh so you know so this page
if I continue to expand each item
quickly. So we are here about never
assign array by index we are almost
halfway. Then you got the issue about
the delete operator basically never use
it. Okay. So how how am I doing? Do you
guys want me to like um go through this
or
or I move on to something I want I I
need to do for my website. So I explain
alone what I'm doing. Okay. So let me
know AC. So let's see what you guys
think.
Uh so let's see. It's very annoying.
Every time you click on this, it
automatically create this uh you know
channel stuff. So let's see. I look at
all things not to do in language at my
level. It's faster. I look at all the
things not to do in a language at my
level. It's faster. Okay. I kind of
understand what you mean but not
exactly. Yeah. I I guess that's one way
to um
not to do. Okay. So avoid things.
That's one way to
learn I guess. Uh or something. Do you
use flight check? Uh no I don't use
flight check. I never used flight
checker.
Uh nor lint. Okay. So
in fact I despise the the jargon llinter
that came from C idiots. Okay. They they
the word llinter as far as I know it's
from 1990s. It's from the C programming
kind of or C++ community. They have this
concept of llinter. What what it what it
does is that it's a it's a tool. It's a
command line tool basically that check
your code. They they they do several
things like they they try to warn you if
you have uh you know they they want they
they it's kind of like a style checker.
Okay. It it's style checker and also
kind of a formatter. Sometimes it helps
you reformat your code. Sometimes it uh
so that's what it is. Llinter. Okay. But
usually it gives you like lots of
warning. Oh, by the way, you should you
shouldn't name variables with
underscore, you know, like style guide,
you know. So, so anyway, that's called
llinter. I despise that.
So, so in in the realm of of software
formatting style guy there's something
very important happened in 2009 around
2009 that is the invention of the go
programming language who came uh which
came with a automatic formatter for the
whole language like you can format
10,000 files all files in a directory it
just format in one way one way only so
you don't debate about oh but I like I
like this way of formatting. I like you
know space instead of tab or whatever.
So that's go format. They
revolutionized
the programming industry around 2009
2008 or so. Go language. Okay. By Rob
Pike and uh and another guy or two but
Rob Pike is most famous. So he he get he
almost always get the credit. Rob Pike
and another guy. I have to look up robot
robot something I think so go format
okay go goland they come with it you
know you don't have it's not like a
separate tool it come with a compiler so
go format is so you format entire code
in in source directory right and and
also there's one very critical thing
about it okay unlike the lintter
okay go format is like a tool that
completely understand the go programming
language syntax So it's part of the
compiler. It's not exactly compiler
compiler because they do different
things. They have different
requirements. But if you're going to
write it, but anyway it's like a
compiler. It it it understand the uh go
pro programming language syntax fully
grammar. Okay. [snorts] So it can
reformat code. So this is the most
important thing when you have a code.
Let's um Okay. Let's say let's say uh
yeah let's can we do go? Yes. So, okay.
So, let's do go uh land. Okay. I'm
starting to digress. I want to get back
to JavaScript because I got a lot of
things to do. Okay. So, let me talk
quickly. So, go. So, for example, here
is um go uh file. You can run it. It'll
just print uh 33.
Okay. First time it needs to uh load the
Go compiler. So, there there you go. 33.
Okay. So you can say uh
hi guys
supreme functional programming. Okay now
run it.
Fantastic. Okay now let's
make it the whole thing one line. Okay.
Goland supreme. Run it. Wait. Okay. You
know when you want to make them one line
you have to do you then you need the
semicolon. Okay. Uh, [clears throat]
wait.
Okay. So, make them one line. Okay. Run
it. Fantastic. Goland. Okay. Now, here
here is go format. Okay. Look, look
carefully at go format. So, now I press
the key. It will call it will Oh, it's
already done. Wait. Uh, let's see. it
will call
uh my um
wait let me start my start
command log mode start
okay it doesn't so global stop
uh glo What?
Global stop.
Wait.
Global command lock mode. That will stop
it. Okay.
Now close that new window
and make it small. Now
start command look mod. Okay.
Yeah, for some reason it's not let me
move cursor up. Uh it used I should be
able to but not today for some reason.
Okay. So, let me um so we digress over.
So, let's go back. Okay, let me go back
quickly. So anyway the the the the
critical thing about the go format how
it revolutionized the industry is that
first of all it's bundled with go
language and it's not just a llinter
llin lintter the llinter is like the
most idiotic thing they don't understand
the programming grammar language grammar
it's just like trying to do some text
processing you know to try you know to
try to tell you if you formatted
correctly or whatever lint okay from the
C++ plus plus idiots I despise them
because not you know this is not
superficial complaint that because they
are brand they don't work correctly okay
when it comes to like proper design so
anyway go for go format okay
it revolution
re it create a revolution in programming
industry with respect to coding style
and formatting because of two things one
is that because it it it it it
this tool or understand the uh
programming language. Okay, that's one
thing. Okay, so it can format the whole
line. For example, um let's do it. Yeah,
it can format the whole line even if you
have them in one single line. You see,
right now it's one single line. Let's
run it. It works. But now I press a key.
I have a command written in Emacs. So I
press a key that which does call the go
format. You know the shell command. It
does it behind the scene. So it it so I
call it No, wait. There's a mistake
there. So let's um
So save it. Run it. Okay. Hi. Supreme
function of programming. Now call go
format. Press tab F. You see
now you can run it again. Still works.
You see what go format does is that it's
capable of if you have the whole thing a
valid code in one single line it will
format it correctly. No other llinter or
whatever format did this before. None.
Zero. Okay. Zero. Like when you talk to
the C programmers they don't understand
their brain are Their brain are
the C and C++ coders. Okay. Now
listen one more time. Okay. Before go
format
there is no line program in whatever
whatsoever language. If you have a
programming language that is valid but
you put them into a one line single line
there is no llinter or what whatever
that you call it that that will um
reformat it into multiple lines. Okay.
Go format is the first one that did
that. Well actually there's one before
that wufam language. Okay. Okay, wolfam
language beginning in 1996
which I demonstrated this about this
format many times. Okay. So, Wuam
language did it in 1996 with Wuam uh
Mathematica version 3. 1996
that that is like 10 years before Golan.
Okay. But Golan
but but Wuan language is like the in a
scientific mathematical phys
physics community. So it's, you know,
it's a bit different from the the
industrial programmers, you know, the
operating systems, the file systems, the
web web or whatever. So, but Goland is
the first one that that revolutionized
this um with the go format. Okay, it
format the whole thing. It understand
the programming language grammar, but it
also
is able to format from one single line
to multiple lines.
None of the lint does it. Okay, so
anyway, that's a major digression. Okay,
so uh I started to rant and a lot of
people like that because now I got like
oh 19 concurrent viewers. [laughter]
Uh so uh so actually I got a lot to do
about JavaScript. Um because every time
I start a live stream I wanted to do
some JavaScript then I got distracted. I
just talk about things and I never get
to do what I actually need to do because
like usually when I do live stream like
I talk about like just what I I just did
you know 20 minutes about the format it
doesn't benefit me you see you know to
uh to you guys maybe uh some uh many of
you find it fun and uh informative right
but it doesn't do anything to me to my
website you know that's not the work I
need to do I got lots of work I need to
do. So anyway,
uh so if you Okay, so if you guys like
my stuff, donate. Okay, go to
kasali.info, donate to me. Okay, so
let's see what um uh yeah, so I
digressed into the llinter. Yeah, so I
don't use llinter and fly checker. I a
lot of people use it. I actually never
get quite get what it is. Um so I don't
use it.
Uh okay, so let's see. Uh so you can see
the point is trying to get us to higher
levels. Okay. Uh absolutely this great
great fantastic. Thank you for the show.
Got to go got to jet. Let's focus on
Java. Okay. Let's go back to JavaScript.
Okay. So now so JavaScript. So we we we
were talking about you know uh
functional programming style guide.
Okay. So we we talked about uh you know
something you never should do and what
you should do instead. Uh JavaScript and
never use width. Never use width and
never assign array by index. Okay? Never
use delete operator because if if you
use that on array object then it will
create sparse array. We talked about
before it will create sparse array
array. You don't want that. Okay. So but
if and if you want if if you use a
delete operator on object it will uh
it's no good because a better operator
for deleting properties on object is the
reflect.delete delete property because
you know what that's another pothole in
JavaScript because when you use delete
operator and if your argument is not a
object let's say you know delete let's
say three you just say delete three
three is just a number or a string you
let's say delete delete hello world what
happened it will return true meaning
success
because [laughter]
you see delete [snorts] object it
returns true when property exists and is
deleted. It return true also when
property does not exist and it will also
return true when the argument is not
even an object. Okay, so this like
up Okay, so the return
value is not indication of success or
not. It just like
it's almost it's almost it's useless.
It's almost like always return true.
Whenever it return false, it doesn't
make sense. Okay. So that's why they
created in 200 uh um in 2015 they
created reflect delete property. Okay.
It basically do exactly the same thing
except it return true only if the key
exists and is deleted or if the key does
not exist.
So
but you but it basically it returns true
when you know for sure it's given a
property and uh the no it no longer has
that key. Okay so this is a you know so
this is another one of the JavaScript
script fix like they have lots of it in
2015 10 years ago and then since then
every year. So JavaScript is a language
filled with this holes like every time
you have like 100 method you have to
know which one is you know you shouldn't
use or which one you should use because
that one fix that issues you know
JavaScript is like that okay so never
use delete operator okay and and uh okay
so then never use the argument object
the argument object was created because
before the rest parameter was invented
okay the rest argument like the rest
argument. The rest parameter for a
function means when you need to write
create define a function that allows it
to take
infinite number of arguments such as
plus or multiply. You know if you want
to write a function like plus you know
you might say plus 3 4 5 or 3 4 5 1 2
you know the the number of argument
varies. So that so that's when you need
to use this uh rest parameter feature
which allows you to have a function to
accept arbitrary number of arguments.
Okay. Now this is the rest uh parameter
is created in 2015. Okay. Well before
that there are many techniques to to
make this happen. Okay. So one of the
technique in other programming languages
such as pearl is you have this argument
object which is like a variable a
predefined variable in a function.
Whenever you define a function that
variable got created and that variable
is a array that holds the values of the
argument passed to the function. So you
can always know you know what what
arguments are passed to a fun to the
function by the arguments you know the
predefined variable. Okay. So this is
when
when JavaScript does not have the you
know the the dot dot rest parameter uh
syntax dot dot dot but but it has this
argument way to do it to do basically
the same thing. It allows the function
to know you know to accept any arbitrary
number of parameters. Okay, this is one
mechanism to make that happen. So which
one is better depending on the language?
Pearl use it this way and uh but the the
rest parameter is more like more is
better because it's explicit because
then when you define a function you can
know exactly you know whether it ex
accept arbitrary number of uh arguments
but but if you use the argument object
if you design your programming language
to be this way then if you have the
argument object then you don't even need
any parameters. in the functions at all
because any user when they define a
function they can just have empty
parameters because they going to just
use the argument arguments object right
they don't need to have actual declare
any uh parameters so so so that means
when you have this argument object that
kind of make people not it defeats the
purpose of having explicit parameters in
the function
So which is not very good because
usually you want uh people to be
explicit about what the function accept.
You know also you know when you do this
when you if you design your programming
language using this argument um method
[clears throat]
then it then your function does not know
at compile time how many argument it
takes. It it will only know when it's
called. So that creates another kind of
problem. you will not be able to like
check correct correctness and so on.
Okay. And and it you know so any
function can pass any number of argument
basically. So there's no you know you
you lose the specification for
functions. So this is very bad. So
that's why they created the rest
parameters. So in 2015 but they the
JavaScript people they try to maintain
backward compatibility so they don't
remove you know very bad. So don't use
argument object. Okay. [clears throat]
Okay. So looks like um so I got you know
there are more things but I wanted to do
uh actually um you see I wanted to do so
let's let's do them. Okay. Uh and and
then that's it for today. Okay. So uh
how long have I been? Oh only I've only
been going 35 minutes. Okay. Yeah. Am I
uh Yeah. Okay. So, let's see. Uh focus.
HTML has gone back to the uh
the dark ages. It's one of the worst
idea since MS DOS. Is it HTML? Okay.
Okay. So, I wanted to do so this is F.
Um Oh, yeah. So there there's some tips
I want to uh tell you guys which is
advanced functional programming. Okay.
[snorts] So and okay let me finish this.
Okay. So never let me just finish this.
Okay. So so and so never use the
argument object and never use the
property constructor. Okay. The the
property constructor is supposedly okay.
There's some edit I want to do. Okay. So
let's just let me just work on my stuff.
Okay.
So let's say functional programming uh
search for
okay go to it search for argument
never use argument uh don't use argument
it was this um
it was designed
before rest parameter the
syntax were introduced. Okay, let's just
say that
verify. Okay, so we we we want to um
Yeah. Okay.
Uh
refresh
uh function argument destructure. Okay,
that's another feature.
Never use the property constructor
because constructor it's meant to let
you um know which function created the
object something like that. But the
problem is that JavaScript the the the
mechanism is extremely convoluted. So
the way it is um the user can change the
constructor
to anything they like and also the
parents constructor. So so the bottom
line is that it's never guaranteed
you know when you use a property
constructor you can never guarantee what
it will correctly work. Okay so it just
does not work.
It will work when you use the
constructor property
uh for building objects such as the
building you know functions array uh
object object data object um date object
function object
data object okay regular expression
object but when you use it on your user
created object is not guaranteed to work
okay the intention was that you use this
the way you poet normally is to um
to know like uh the the the like to know
which function created on this object.
Okay, so that's what this instructor
property is supposed is supposed to
mean. Okay, but that's no good. Okay, so
I want to make some modifications. Okay,
so let me go to it. Uh,
so
update the date. Okay. So,
so property key type prototype. Okay.
>> [clears throat]
>> Actually,
maybe doing this is not a good idea
because you because it's probably better
if I just keep talking. Okay.
Yeah. Because if I just going to work on
my website, uh it's probably boring.
Okay? Because what I'm doing is like I
want to make some improvement because
before you see the link is embedded in
the word. But in some situation I think
it's better if you move the link
outside. So if people want to know what
is the prototype property, they can
click here. Uh and so go back. So
instead of you know so um
instead of embedded link in the wording
here because it will kind of confuse the
wording. Basically what I'm saying here
is that where so where is the
constructor property came from
basically it's a magical property okay
by specification every function has a
property key a string of string type
property key named proper type okay so
that is where it came from so uh so this
should be lowerase property key opty key
string let's not say string okay so you
know so if people want to know more
about that prototype key I mean where
does this prototype key came from well
then you go here then again it's magic
okay every function defined by the
keyword function has a magical property
key of string type prototype named
prototype by specification okay it just
by spec okay it's just there and where
does the constructor came from again
it's like a magic but it's more complex
because
you know it came from the prototype then
you got a object then you got the
prototype got the property uh I mean his
whose value is object data object and
that data object has a property called
constructor so and so whenever you say
constructor it's actually querying
an object's parent
via the prototype. That's how it finds a
parent and the parent has a um um yeah
prototype value whose value is the
object and that object has a key
constructor. So that's how anyway very
complicated. Okay.
Uh
so
okay so maybe that's it for today. So
let's see 42 minutes.
Uh I got some Okay. So let's work on
this one. This one is easy to work on.
So let me tell you guys about this one.
Uh standard object constructor. Okay. So
we are still on the constructor page. So
on the constructor page, you can move
down move down. So so let's let's let's
get into detail. Okay. So where does the
constructor constructor property came
from? Well, it's basically by spec.
Okay. Because every function has a
property key named prototype and that
keys value is a data object and by spec
that object has a key named constructor
and the value of that key is the
function itself
which is the uh like you know so it's
kind of convoluted. Okay.
So this is why the constructor property
came from. Okay. So anyway, then you go
down then what's the purpose? Well, the
constructor property is meant to let you
find the creator function of a object,
but it's not reliable. Okay, so
typically this is how people use it. You
know, you define a function then you say
um new something new that
class or function. So that creates a
object. Then you can say
object.constructor constructor to try to
see what what function or class created
it. That's how it is supposedly to be
used. Okay, but not reliable because
people can assign value to it any
anytime. Okay, any anytime. Okay, so
value [clears throat] so what is the
value then? Depends. Okay, so that that
that because of that because of the
parents because of that then then
therefore it's that okay. So tip do not
use the constructor property. Why?
Because the value can change anytime.
Okay. And uh even the property key can
be removed. So okay and here is an
actual example. Okay. So what I want to
do is I want to remove the console log
to something better. Okay. So let me
show you.
Uh
okay. So
so let's see. Every function has a
property key prototype except our
function. So evaluate it everything
returns true because so it kind of
verifies the statement. Okay. So what I
want to do is I want to uh change the
console.log to console.assert.
So let me do that. Um
yeah so do that and uh then do that what
do that do that okay so now run
everything now there's no return value
because what console assert does is that
if whatever the argument if it's true
and it doesn't do nothing okay so if
your assertion whatever you think is
true is actually indeed true. It doesn't
do anything. Only when the argument is
false then it will print just like
console do.log
it you it'll say assertion failed. Okay.
So when you change console.log before it
just print true true true you know. But
if you change it to assert, it makes
your intention more clear because you
are because you are trying to tell
people you are claiming that this value
will evaluate to be true. And if that is
actually the case, don't do anything you
know. So when there's no output, that
means this assertion is all valid. Okay.
So so we are trying to verify every
function has a property key name
prototype. Okay, so everything is true.
Now go uh go down search for log. Now
again there's something we want to
change here. Run it first of all. True.
True. Okay. Fantastic. Now uh change
change to assert then run it. Fantastic.
Okay. Now put it back. Now search for
log again. So there's more to change.
First of all run it. So typical use of
constructor property. Okay. Now uh now
let's change that to assert run it no
output. Fantastic. Okay. Now put it
back. Search for log again. So there's
one more part we need to change actually
more than uh this more. So run it first
of all true to true to verify whatever
uh we are trying to verify here. So what
exactly we are trying to verify? I
forgot uh this value of property key.
Okay. So we are trying to check the
value of property key.
So
uh so first of all you define a class
function then you uh define a object
that's new you know that class okay the
new you create a new object then you
define a get uh prototype so you get the
parent of the new object PP okay so then
you check does the object JJ has the
constructor key force that means Means
the constructor property is not its own
object. Okay. Now does the PP object
which is a JJ's parent does that have
the constructor key? Yes. Okay. So this
is actually yes.
And the PB constructor value is is the
function itself. So you know you run it.
It's all true now. So let's change to um
press press that that. Okay. Now run it.
Fantastic. Okay. We change them to
assert. Put it back. Now search for
next. There's uh so what is this one?
True. [snorts] Okay. So the value of a
property key constructor is not
guaranteed to be the constructor
function. Okay. This is when something
nasty happened unexpected because user
can change change at any time. So let's
write it. It's false. Okay. I mean it's
true. So now let's change it to uh
console alert assert right no output
fantastic okay so let's make a comment
somewhere
to indicate where did it um so that's a
object then this is a function functionp
prototype so you set the functions
prototype to that okay object then
constant so you then you create a new
object out of this FF F class then when
you say you know the constructor of that
it become false because because of this
line you see because because that line
changed the parent.
Okay. So uh so we should make a comment
somewhere. Um
you know we can say change the portal
portal type
of f of f
f.
You see so when you do that then then
unexpected happens. Okay.
So let's put it back. Search for next
log and okay. So this is testing of all
the building constructors. So showing
arrays constructor.
So create array aa. Okay. Then does it
has own key constructor? No. False.
Okay. Does it does it so what's the
parent? Well, the parent is
array.prototype.
Then does the prototype array.prototype
has the property key constructor? Yes.
Now what is the value of that? Well,
that is array. Okay, then the uh and it
is also equals to array uh a dot
constructor. Okay, if you evaluate this,
it's all true. So you see it's all true.
Now close that. So you can see this part
is verifying the array object and this
section verifies the date object. you
know we create a date object. This
section verifies a function object. So
now you run it. It's all true now. But
let's change them to uh assert. Okay. So
press press. That's my own command. Uh
so let's do press press. Now repeat last
command. Do do it. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it do it. Do do it do
it do it do it do it do it. Evaluate the
whole thing. No output. Fantastic. It
means all the assertion came out true.
Okay, now put it back. Syntax color the
whole page. Search for log. There's no
more occurrence. Okay, now show the
whole thing in browser. So we finished
it. We finished updating all console.log
to console.assert
for this page on constructor property.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Um,
so hi. Hey dude. Hey dude. Alex dude the
informat informaticist.
You should write some modes for zero ad.
Just for fun. People would like it. Now
what is zero ad? I don't know exactly
what is zero ad.
Uh, ha. I noticed you stopped using the
Kinesis today. How come you switched for
fun or freshness? Yeah, you haven't
watched my videos for a long time.
I stopped using Kinesis like
two three years ago. Okay. I started to
use Glove 80. Perhaps that's what you
meant. So I used the glove 80 in the
past two or three years. Okay. Then for
all my live stream then about two month
ago two or three I started to using the
ultimate hacking keyboard 80 UHK80.
Why? Because they sent it to me. It's
new. So I'm doing uh kind of a plugin,
you know, review for them. It's very
good. I enjoy it very much. I like them
both very much. Okay. So I think that's
it for today. So uh you know you guys uh
can you know if you don't know about the
keyboard stuff let me go to it. Go to
kasadi. So go to kasardi.info
http nos. Okay search for it uh for
kasar code you'll find it. Okay then you
first of all go all the way down but to
the bottom you pay me donate to me.
Okay. If you like my stuff you go down
here. PayPal me, Patreon, Amazon gift
card or PayPal. Okay, fantastic. If you
do $100, if you have a job
now, so here then you go to uh si.info,
you go to a keyboard section. So that's
there are uh 1,000 over 1,000 articles
on keyboard on
um on keyboard on keyboard layout on
ergonomic keyboard on keyboard history
on typewriters on key caps on key switch
mechanisms you know everything. Uh for
example track balls uh tracks video
reviews. So some of these are some of my
best videos. Okay. uh talk show on
keyboard videos. Okay, the collection of
my kind of my best uh each one of these
is one hour. Okay, so that's Kinesis
360. This is glove 80. Fantastic. This
is fantastic. This is suave board.
Okay, swabboard. Fantastic. Okay,
I haven't used it yet. I will. Okay. So
then then Kinesis 360 then then expose
also another fantastic and this is
ultimate hacking keyboard 60. This
before my current 80. Okay. Now look at
me. That's Beethoven here.
Okay. So um Okay. So I I So that's about
the keyboards. Okay. So uh if you guys
haven't It looks like it's a cool thumb
cluster. Yeah. So yeah. So three month
ago they you know they have you know
they sent me Wait, don't I have a UHK80
here?
Oh, I don't.
So that's a fantastic mouse. A friend,
one one of you guys a friend sent it to
me from China. Uh I I should actually
take it out, use it because this mouse
got uh buttons. Okay, because this this
mouse um
This mouse got buttons because now I
wanted to use button anyway.
So, so, so, uh, yeah. So, Ultimate
Hacking Keyboard 80. I should put the,
you know, I got to link.
Yeah. Interesting. Yeah, I should. So,
anyway, but you go to my keyboard blog,
you'll see it linked right there. Okay.
So,
uh, okay. That's it. Bye, guys.
Yeah, checking them out. Check them out.
Uh,
I need to have Bluetooth. Okay, so
Swabboard, they do have like Bluetooth
feature. I mean, not so you need to
check out, you know, contact them. They
they got a website. They also got a
Discord. Tell them sent you. Okay. So,
yeah, Bluetooth is required. I don't
know what's the current state but the
way it was that you you can they I
forgot what's the thing they um you can
like install Bluetooth module
um yeah I forgot what's the thing but
the guy is using it they he showed me if
you want so um so anyway you go to the
his discord his website you you'll find
information about that
string on finger joint. Yeah, I don't
know yet. Okay, so bye guys.