good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of XR talk show I just woke up
about three hours ago
four hours ago 6 o clock p.m. that's
when I woke up and today is Friday
Friday is supposed to be the boogie
night where people you know yuppies go
out and have fun watch movies have
dinner or whatever go to parties dance
clubs whatever
oh and [ __ ] I forgot this let's see ok
I'm not sure this is going to be
successful
it's kind of hard today
ok yeah yeah I'm going good
zero watching now let's do some
preparation let's pop this window out
and
so what we gonna do today well we gonna
I'm going to do some Emacs demo I'm
going to show a max demo 2019 April
April 12 that's today honk-honk Pepe
Pepe you know Pepe is is is quite
fascinating you know the internet
phenomenon the internet you know history
and phenomenon and all sort of
happenings so that's a page so let's go
- let's go - where shall we go hard slog
what the odds okay show it in browser
and I'm gonna show you not what I blog
okay but anyway so here is the Thai
women Thai woman in in Yunnan China okay
this is a Chinese ethnicity you know I
don't know nothing about it but I just
read from Twitter so so apparently
there's this Chinese ethnicity called
die which is kind of like they are
people in the region of you know in the
region of Vietnam in the which region of
Thai in a retile and you know in the
region of liao kind of that region and
in southern China so you know people in
that region I don't know anything about
this ethnicity but anyways that's a
photo of that so not so let's go to now
this is this is my word e block which is
literature writing linguistics but now
let's go to some arts blog now some arts
block you can see this is Pepe this is
Pepe the clown this is honk honk Pepe
which is kind of a new meme and they are
fascinating he's you know fascinating
is to it let me show you first of all
let's go to croissants my website so you
can see there it is salads my arts blog
website you know and let's go to my blog
you know history of art you know it's
serious stuff history in the whole
history of art but anyway so pepe
history of paper ok his tremendous
talent you know like the fortune and the
reddit the mean the memes and you know
so code means that would came up since
about like 10 years ago which I thought
was very idiotic you know memes these
people anyway
the but you can see that this this this
is like what you would call a pop art or
pop culture okay you know I mean a
culture it doesn't really have you know
these different types but you know
academics assign certain aspect of
culture is pop culture that's that's
what it is
so you know the internet lots of things
phenomenons on internet we you call it
pop culture and mean meme is one of them
you know like anyway so okay we gonna
talk about you know we might talk about
yeah let's talk about paper a little bit
then I'm going to show you a MX demo but
actually let me show you just a you max
demo so for those of you watching my
videos you know you just want the
technique because stuff you don't want
you know no nonsense well for that if
you really into that the best thing to
do is just read my blog okay my Emacs
blog you know it's all written so you
don't waste no time but okay so let's
what so first of all let's just do Emacs
demo so you see I okay so this this is a
blog right you got a video you got a
image here and you got this break the
internet Pepe
so this is actually this
deal it's it's got 1 million views but
it's very well made it because it
because it's it's a it's a history of
Pepe okay how it evolved over the past
ten years since 2000 you know for
something that's about history Pepe so
in the first video I'm not gonna play it
if you want to watch it you know where
to go you know good just go to my
website okay my website it's the center
of the universe and so if you are here
say hi okay let's see where are we okay
here Pepe yeah so I just created you
know I just saw this today and I found I
found it amazing so I'm going to blog it
I put it on my Arts blog but you know I
want to create a new page for it so a
page just containing this this subject
Pepe and history of Pepe and okay so
let's do so this is a Emacs demo and
it's going to be about ten minutes okay
you can see my commands on my right on
the left so first of all go here and you
see normally what I do I show you what
normally I do so I normally I would go
to the directory diet you can see every
command I go is showing on the left
window okay so go to the directory oops
I got the directory diet let's say AI
and chess mark song okay this is quite
interesting page by the way it so so
there is this there is this novelist
okay who create so here is a short
fiction science fiction of an AI so this
guy scientist he created a chess playing
other visual intelligence chess playing
machine okay
however the guy beats the machine you
know the machine cannot win so the
machine killed him and this is an
illustration
you know by by an artist Japanese artist
Tatsuya Marino okay so this is it's
great art and great story you know it's
sad these days you know when I found
these things it's really great you know
this is this is good art you know this
is great artwork and and the story is
also fascinating you know the theme at
least the theme then you know you a
scientist created a I invented AI yet
the AI cannot beat the guy however the
AI kill the guy you know so it you know
this did this this so it actually
although it the AI cannot play chess but
however it actually has intelligence for
more than just playing chess so but you
these days you know you post to online
forums like you get nothing
nobody he's almost like nobody sees you
know nobody liked it you know nobody
thumbs up nobody is somewhat you know
and and it's almost like nobody has seen
it and you know and also Twitter you
know they they got all these algorithms
so they control you know your followers
like I have like 2,000 more than 2,000
followers but they your posts they don't
see it the only way to see people you
follow is that you have to constantly
interact with them like like their stuff
chat with them you know on Twitter for
example then their posts will begin to
show in your stream otherwise it you
know because twitter twitter you know
control information flow man in the mass
massive scale this is part of the reason
why society America USA for example is
going downhill very fast you know I look
at China they have incredible I mean I'm
just you know so amazed by it you know
every day the China you know official
sites they post photos and stuff
technology you know you don't see it in
USA all you see every day is social
justice
you know who writes this and that and
violence and fighting so anyway yeah one
of the sad phenomenon is that you post
things you know you thought it's you
know it's it used to be you know this
kind of you know you it's a good thing
you post good content but you don't you
get no no response what kind of response
gets content it gets you know spread you
know the anger you know angry stuff
shouting brainless you know attacking
people you know you you know like that
anger and and thoughtless things so
that's the reason this happens is
because Twitter and Facebook and others
including Google they what they want is
they want to make money and the one way
to do that is to get more posts more
post and and show things you know only
you like don't show things you don't
like
so you get bubbles and you get you know
and Twitter has like char limit and you
know so so today you go to youtube or
reddit or Twitter or you know almost any
on my website all you see is a bunch of
you know no you know memes so you know
like brainless things means angry shouts
no nothing nothing is thinking you know
nothing is made of like thoughtful you
know you thought for one hour about
something then you reply you know you
know discussion or something nothing
like that everything is like one second
you know sentence you know you know
that's that's what happened to Internet
and Society is getting very bad as you
you you know if you are following me you
probably agree so okay let's get back to
Emacs then it's okay we digressed and
let's get back to you max so I want to
create a new page right you know new
page for this pep article so nobody
hears what I normally do go to arts blog
so
I go to diet directory and pick pick
just pick any article opening it copy
the content close it close it
create a new buffer paste the content
save it as what I want to name it pep
dot HTML okay save it show in browser
now that's a copy of the other page
right now I just now look at the command
I call this command io signa this
command
cuz I shan't tml update title and I type
a new title pep and it's it's history
okay title case it enter that's done
showing browser what what it does is
that it will the command the command saw
update title what it does is is that it
will change automatically find the title
section and change it and automatically
find the h1 element and change the title
so I don't have to you know such the
buffer go to the title type it then such
the buffer go to h1 and type it you know
I just call this command for example I
do it again
cut TD T you know you see they are
changed so that is size t ml what what
is the command it let's do it again
HTML update title so let's change it
back okay paper and history now showing
browser now then another command I'm
going to Co is update a date you see
previously you have 2018 now I just type
a command I type a key now look at the
command on the Left panel okay now I got
a new
you know update date 2019 April 12 but
usually I have to do these so rid of
that so you see now the date is correct
then I just delete that part delete that
part show it it's empty
that's good then I close that oh wait
then copy the file path close it paste
the file path link if I make a paragraph
showing browser there it is
pep and its history you know now it's
empty now I just go back now dddd dddd
TV that's TV and coffee okay you can see
the command here and now actually this
part itv now open that file pasty here
showing browser you see that's good then
I just sync to my website you know
housing however let me show you another
command I just I have so first of all
let's copy this out
sure okay close it put it here okay I
have my block back to the way it is okay
now let me show you some other commands
I'm going to show you okay open the pet
file and I'm going to I don't want I
want to delete this page okay so I press
one key and that page is done now I try
to open it it says the file doesn't
exist because I just delete it so that
command delete is delete current file
you can use you know all these commands
on on my website most of them are if
they are not on my website then they are
on my github website site so anyway so I
just deleted this I want to copy the
title so paste it here close it okay
so now let's so I'm going to do this
over again create a new page and put
these contents there okay so like before
I go to diet and I pick one file such
for chess okay let's say this one
you know I why do I want to pick the
file because I want to clone the page
why do I want to clone the page because
in each of my website and in each
directory there are certain structures I
need to keep you know for example in
this directory in this art website and
and in this arts directory all the files
HTML files they have certain structure
like normally you would call that
template now since I'm not using a
template system you know so I don't
actually have a template but however the
the the template kind of existing all
these files so since I don't use a
template so what I do when I want to
create a new page is actually a chrome
one existing page and you know and put
the content layer so anyway so let's
copy the path of this file close it
paste it here blink of eye okay now I
want oh okay wait let me show you this
is a command I want so I want to create
a new file right and like like I said
before I need to clone a page but I have
written a command
that's called let me just show you it's
called let me magnify it's called a new
page so first of all I type the title I
want the page to be let's just say paper
okay and I call this command watch MX
saw new page okay do it now it's done
and I if I press ENTER to of an eye file
it opens now showing browser you can see
it automatically created the page you
know using a template actually it's not
using a template you actually just
behind the scenes in it actually just
copy it just Chrome one of the files in
the directory and remove all the content
part leaving only the structure so what
that's what that Sonia page does you
know it works so if you are you know
different
my others side like sorry Darlene Fogo
gimmicks I can also call that command
then you were based on whatever files in
that directory so essentially it comes
the file of that directory so close the
Pepe page okay so we got this new page
ready to ready to add content so I all
we have to do is copy the title go here
paste it and go back here open it call
the title command call the title command
new title pep and its history okay it's
done close it save now now we put the
content cut cut cut cut cut
okay go back here open the page go down
paste showing browser there it is now I
have I just created this new page
hilarious yeah pif stuff and now it's
done and close it now this now the block
show the blog in browser you see it's
there but now let me do one more thing I
want the icon you know like this entries
there's an icon so you can get an idea
what they are then you go to the page
then you see it you know this is math
geometry architecture they are extremely
beautiful
you know architecture the beautiful
architecture they are a phenomenon they
are essentially a practical exhibition
of geometry
yeah most most of it you know because
you know for the Asian was these are
agent like 2000 years old also they are
extremely beautiful but most okay and
this is cathedral right 1500 year 1500
or something look at this this window
that's geometry you know this in fact
actually if you study math you know wow
I have studied a lot math and what one
okay one kind of recreational part of
math is pattern you know patterns and
tidings like decorate that decorative
patterns such as these you know it's
actually kind of a I mean it's not
exactly a branch of math but it's a
community decorated pattern you know
yeah you know less in the in previous
talk show we have a episode where I talk
about the math topic tidings and
patterns so you might check it out so
tidings and patterns is actually a
entire branch of math I mean it's not
just art it's it's actually like serious
math you know you know there's a entire
branch but it's not mainstream math you
know it's not mainstream mainstream math
is like algebra analysis you know the
mainstream math typically requires you
to have like undergraduate degree
background in math like you have to
spend four years to study math then you
can possibly appreciate you know what
they are talking about you know but
so that's mainstream math but however
there are lots of math Liz logic logic
is actually not mainstream proof systems
is not mainstream discrete math is not
mainstream whatever computer science
math that's not mainstream okay math
mathematicians consider them inferior
like you programmers I mean you
computers
you know kind of yeah the mathematicians
they are like high up they are linked
they are doing you know topology
topology is mainstream like when you
when you are doing topology oh we see
here this is mathematician when you are
doing proof systems even you know that's
it's kind of like that you know this
prejudice and evie to the you know it
happens in all fields
good morning brick and good evenin break
the loop have you ever read iron Rand's
The Fountainhead it's about an architect
yeah I heard of that but I never read
any any work by her I heard you know I
looked into her a bit you know quite a
bit she is some people a lot of people
consider hook a kind kind of a nut job
you know kind of a young kind of a nutty
you know crackpot on a job or extreme
you know somewhere along there she is in
America she's considered as a
philosopher and her thing is basically
capitalism she praises capitalism which
I which I actually agree because
capitalism you know forget about
academic jack joggins capitalism you
know what the [ __ ] does in capitalism
versus communism as the if you know the
word is just that you know and also the
Eastern versus Western I thought you
know I fell into that mistake you know
then the Israel reminded me so what
about what about Middle East what about
Israel you know so and what about Russia
are they eastern or western no it's not
Eastern he of course the word is not
just eastern and western philosophies is
you know quite quite a lot but however
we kind of you know that we often
thought of Eastern versus Western
because you know because easy on you
know China was you know the big culture
in western society today in modern times
the Western you know Europe and us
imperio imperialism you know the powers
of the 1900s you know that's why you
have the Western you know but however
Western civilization doesn't did a no
engine from you know America America is
only 200 years old the Western
civilization our engine aided from you
know Greek area around you know or and
and and actually and I don't know much
about Middle East but Greek is around
there you know some might say it's it's
in Egypt or you know they are all Soviet
Air Asia you know like I could act
emissions say you know the they are like
five ancient civilizations you know so
anyways so Eastern back east and back to
Oak ok back to Iran Sochi in America she
was considered as a philosopher but I
read that elsewhere they don't really
consider her anything she you know she
other philosophers might consider her as
a peddler of cattle ISM you know okay
yeah so I was talking about capitalism
versus communism these are you know
academia jargons okay so what do you
mean exactly capitalism well you know
it's you know you can think of it's a
economic theory or kind of a category
utilization of economic practice but
anyway avoid jargons usually is the best
thing because they because they just
becomes a you know something Oh
capitalism you you attach all kind of
thought to it you know even though you
may not know anything about it but
anyway I I like I think capitalism is
fundamentally good because my view of
the world and society and history the
whole thing okay is the universe is that
what was I going to say because I want
you look at just human you know basic
human nature
okay anyway that's not getting into that
because what what do you mean human
nature like you know so anyway so so
okay in short I like you know the
capital is an idea of free market it's
actually I think it's a good because
because if you just look at yourself
you know you survive you thrive only for
yourself basically yeah you know people
say you you know people you know you
might help others or stuff but actually
no human just like other animals we
survive we thrive for ourselves that's
what make us have more children that
that's what make us thrive you know if
you are that the type who only care
about the others like the Jedi the Jedi
only cares about others they don't
consider for themselves you die out you
know you don't get to survive you know
so that's a human nature so yeah and you
know when you do when you have that you
cannot help it you know just like you
know they are all kind of philosophy you
know you cannot help it without eating
you know what what if you know eating is
the most evil thing I mean you know what
if you cannot do it I mean you cannot
what if you can only obtain truth if you
stop eating what if that's you know what
if that you can't do it you know then
forget about truth I have to eat because
the moment I don't eat I cease to exist
then there is no philosophy no nothing
you know so I mean it's so human you
know we have to you know you throw away
all morality or ethics or ethics or
philosophy or God you know you throw
that away you look at human animal if if
you look at human animal scientifically
then what you get is just like when you
observe other animals or the creatures
you know organisms you know cats dogs
you know you know tigers lions dolphins
or sharks you know
oh and Spees was any any creature you
study them just as is then you then
human animal is actually not much
different from you know other mammals
you know wolves
you know lions yeah in some way we are
different in some but before see not you
know we we survive whoever you know we
survive by you know being selfish
we thrive by being selfish selfish okay
that's basically as a scientific view
okay there's no God okay I mean if you
believe in religion that's fine that's
you know that's religion is is a kind of
way that help us you know help us
society bind together you know it's
ancient
but I mean from scientific view you know
you can throw I mean unless you're
talking about social interactions but
from a scientific view if you look at
human animals it's just animals you know
whoever has power whoever two things
wins there is this know God is going to
help you there's no God is going to do
justice for you okay if there's a bad
guy you know if if I'm the bad guy okay
I kill you all
I have the power you know I have you
know I have the power like I'm a
Superman and I'm also you know makeup
billionaire you know I can kill you all
then what happens nothing nothing I
thrive because I have the power so
that's what happens in society in
general there is no justice basically
that's why you know throughout history
stories in fictions you see all these
injustice you know they tell the story
because they want to pass on you know so
anyway I also so and Rand okay so that
so okay so given given that if you take
the scientific view about humanity okay
then free market the idea of free market
meaning you freely exchanged you know
trade with other people you money
you know whatever or even helper that
give out things for free that's that's
basically essentially what capitalism is
okay that's the heart that of capitalism
that's the jist of cod kappa reason you
know that's you know and so it's good
the the opposite you know simplified
version of the opposite is communism or
socialism where you don't freely do
things you actually you actually live
under certain moral precept you know
more of a kind of occasion where you are
not allowed to you know to to be selfish
to do things just for yourself you are
not allowed you act rather you are
prepared to always think of others like
help others it's kind of like that okay
that's kind of you know so-called
communism or socialism and you I mean of
course it doesn't you know it doesn't
really work today you know today's
people today young young people they are
very ignorant they are extremely because
they the education system is doing
nothing you know people graduate from
Harvard these so-called
Ivy League's they know nothing they
don't know history they don't know you
don't even know how to write they know
nothing and you know and that's the way
you know and then you use we see all
these stories of you know rich people
paying their kids got to go to Harvard
and and you know and you know the the
the affirmative action you know so
getting so so you ignore hard-working
you know like the Harvard you know they
kick out it they they they have quotas
like what kind of race can give you know
getting if you have your AC on if you
have high school okay but we can only
take so much of you you know the rest of
you go home we have to take black people
yeah like we have to regard as their
their score because you know of
you know affirmative actions and so on
so they are you know they so so
basically they are corrupt basically our
situation our society today in
especially especially among a powerful
like the you know yeah so they are the
word is corruption that's why you know a
lot of people don't like capitalism
because when they think of capitalism
they see these giant corporations you
know corporations they do you know giant
corporations and you know they do bad
things and they attribute these people
you know attributed as a problem of
capitalism but actually that's I don't
think that's main issue the main issue
is corruption not not the nature of
capitalism okay I'm just of course you
know you ask different people
these are controversial topics you ask
different people nobody can agree on
anything but that's my take so and so so
okay back to Ayn Rand so she so she is
kind of a nutcase you know in the sense
that she is not simply you know academia
or philosopher but she's such a person
she has a zeal and she do things to push
her idea
you know actually I've seen a comic that
gives a short biography of Ayn Rand Rand
anyway she is popular because in certain
circles in certain people amongst other
antiques because she she sells
capitalism you know that's her story
although I haven't read it though like
the Atlas Shrugged have you read it
break the loop good morning MOOC depth
and mock didn't hello comrade break the
loop say she is a controversial
controversial figure but Fonda but The
Fountainhead is a great book oh is it
okay you know these days I
you know I don't think I'm going to read
any novels anymore because I'm getting
like halfway integrate I give myself
five more years to to still be able to
actually do programming or mathematics
in a way that's you know I can still do
it you know when people get old you
really lose things so I have you know
five more years so you know you know
it's not like me likely for me to read
any novels you know good morning Isaac
yes I did one this morning but you know
I just woke up so another one why not
you know because the other thing is
because yeah I don't have a normal
schedule you know because you know so
you know if I live a normal schedule
then when I wake up or before I go to
bed I'd do a video then it's like within
24 hours you know each date you have one
video but because my schedule is kind of
you know sometimes sleep in two cycles
per day you know so you know that's kind
of chaotic
okay so what should add to bannerghatta
steeps okay well Isaac
okay maybe okay good night as I I slack
religion give hope for weak people yeah
well that's what I thought as well but
but I don't think that's you know the
you know I don't think you know in the
past five or ten years I kind of have
second thoughts you know I still you
know I don't believe in God and I don't
believe in religion so I'm like atheist
but then after you know in the past 10
years you know after seeing the rise of
social justice and they became
essentially they became religion
themselves you know you know
so-called and secular religion so before
that you know I don't believe in
religion because they are just you know
region is not scientific you know I want
to believe scientific things but however
as you know scientific being a
scientific is a methodology and if you
throw away beliefs then you are left
with essentially Cornelissen okay that's
what I believe okay that's what I kind
of believe nearly zhim which is by the
way if you like ten years ago you know
by the way nearly some sometimes people
get confused what it means like some
people want to think of neol ism as as
you know associated with vandals and
destruction okay that's that's not neat
what nyan nyan ism is okay it's like
many of these philosophical
terminologies they they have become
corrupted by you know by political act
activists or by some people who want to
push you know like you know for example
the misogyny okay the word missile it
massagin misogyny okay what does it mean
you know hate a woman hate the hatred of
women actually that's not what it means
okay if it's just a hatred woman then
it's just you know you don't need a word
for it okay it's not just it's not that
but you know I'm not going to go into it
but anyway respect to near neo lism so
what does neo listen mean basically neo
neo Lisa mean it's kind of it's it's
like when you take the pure scientific
stance okay
pure scientific stance then you then you
are forced into this logical conclusion
okay god it does not exist
okay nothing you can understand you
become AB not igniting you know agnostic
means agnosticism means unknowable like
the universe the God where the guardians
is unknowable not you know it's
impossible to know okay that's
not obnoxious season Sony ilysm when you
take everything in a scientific way then
okay God doesn't exist nothing is
knowable and you came into this you are
forcing to the logical conclusion of
kind of like absurdism like why do we
exist what's the purpose of life nothing
you know so we don't know the end
nothing nothing is knowable and you
can't know and so what so you can so so
you can start to destroy you know
destroy things you know kill things you
know so what what what what about that
that okay then not nothing you know so
near ISM is like nothing of nothing it's
like there's nothing because you cannot
this it becomes the conclusion is the
word is just absurd you just you are
just here do whatever you want you can
say whatever you want there is no
morality okay that's all so you know
there's no because morality is you know
it's not scientific any moral concept
the very concept of moral morality okay
presupposes that there is certain
purpose or goal you know if there's no
goal no purpose you don't have morality
you know so where does this purpose come
from you have to suppose that you know
maybe it's from God you know God is good
yes you want us so that's the purpose
you know the the goal is like we want to
live in peace and harmony or something
else you know then you have morality
okay then you have different
philosophies of morality like you know
utilitarianism and you know you know you
have different schools of thought about
what is being moral well anyway the very
concept of morality requires a
presupposes some kind of higher you know
dear to your goal you know but if you
are if you are taking if you take the
scientific approach to the hilt
you cannot presuppose that we would
that supposition come from there's none
so the the word is like just just
whatever you know just whatever is
whatever do whatever so that that is the
essence that you know the the a sense
the essence of you know meaning of
Neolithic fee and I was you know I'm
still I'm still kind of analyst okay so
but if you are near near list then you
have to think about okay so nothing
exists you know you know nothing makes
sense so what what I do what am I here
for that's a big question you know so
that that becomes a problem it kind of
became a practical problem because you
no longer believes in God you know like
most people they believe in God
even though it's illogical or whatever
you know they don't they don't care they
don't care they were taught to believe
in God so they have to you know follow
the Bible the teachings of you know
Islam or whatever or Buddhism you know
they follow it then they have they have
a family you and you go out you know you
have society you go on but if you are a
pure scientist type near list then then
you don't believe nothing so what do you
do for you know what you don't go to
church
then what's your life you your life
becomes like mine okay so that's that is
a practical problem okay so a practical
problem with nihilism so you know for
example the atheist ham Cyrus you know
he said you know he proposed
you know he put pounds that okay once
you throw away religion then what do you
do well you have certain I don't know I
don't remember exactly what what is he
steal but basically basically you want
to believe in good for Humanity you know
you want to you know well personally for
example the way I I would say is that
okay so there's no you know logically
there's no God no morality nothing no
nothing so what I do well you know I I
like I enjoy you know good food I enjoy
Tisa I enjoy I enjoy to have money I
enjoy to have happiness you know there
are certain things I enjoy and southern
things I don't want I don't want hunger
I don't want pain
I don't want violence done to me okay
and same thing logically you can infer
same thing for other people most most
almost all human animals you know we
kind of like you know we want the same
thing good things happiness you know
prosperity and you know once you do
violence so so so you so logically you
can kind of so you did use you know so
what is good good is you know let's you
know what to get together and you know
we can prosper together you know that
that's that is kind of what you latch
onto if you are near least okay but the
problem I think I think there is a still
kind of a problem because because I
don't know why and I don't know the
answer but basically because you don't
have it's not like religion okay for the
religious people they believe in God
okay
Oh Buddhists okay they basically they
don't think you are not supposed to
think okay it's just like God is there
God tells you you have to do this this
then you follow you confirm then you
have you know society thrives your
society okay but if you are the nearest
or atheist type then you know you have
to rely on logic to have kind of a good
community but logic is like then you can
you know you can start to question you
know then then you argue then you're
maybe oh you know God you know actually
your logic is wrong my logic is better
no there's no overpowering you know
ruler kind of you know even even
fictional you know that imposes things
onto you so you have this care you you I
think you know I don't know for sure
but I'm guessing so that I mean that's a
problem with atheism and nearly
something you kind of you kind of get
into this you are prone to have these
issues you know once you are without you
know a certain you know absolute you
know power or fictional power or rule
that tells you what to do and you know
also a lot of people most people they
are not you know they are not you know
educated you know you know that's a
matter of fact they are not magicians
you only they are not interested in
thinking about Oh logic and whatnot like
many many of us are so you know you know
so actually so that's about an R and I
don't know if I pronounce her name
correctly but I was going to back to was
I talking about architecture yeah yeah
back to Emacs but anyway so anyway
there's one more thing I want to do
there about you know creating an icon
for it but I'm gonna read the comments
but let me just finish finish this or
actually maybe I because we've been
talking about something else okay so now
this will be done in two minutes so I
opened this so here's an image so I call
this command
this command is what's with my here I'll
create some nail image so I put my
cursor on the image link and I just
called a command and it asked me what
weight side do I want so 250 is good so
you see it creates this it actually
creates a file like this let me open it
see it creates a thumbnail close it so
now I link if I actually I don't want
you you know I just copy it you know cut
it close it
they put here pace-it link if I remove
the paragraph and then put a dive
paragraph put a dive on it
so now viewing browser that's what I
want I and I want a break so you see now
okay that is stunt for the Emacs now
let's go back to so that that is done so
let's go back to the what whatever I was
talking about yeah so we were talking
about iron Rand capitalism philosophy
near lism you know communism stuff so
region gives hope so weak people
yeah capitalism is capitalism is natural
selection so break the loop says
Fountainhead is one of my favorite books
oh I challenge you to read it without
preconceptions of the author it's an
inspiring book with heroic
characteristics in ideas ok
amazon.com let's go to Fountainhead now
is it thick actually you know seriously
I don't think I'm going to read a book
you know I don't I don't have you know
I'm I'm living on a time you know I my
life is in you know is using problem so
fountain fountain
have you ever UN ta I and head
let's see the cover because okay so font
Fountainhead does not okay how big is
the book thick yeah it's not likely I'm
gonna read it because I can't you know
like I got so many things to do and I
have to like somehow so larry allison is
odd but sharp steel so larry Allison so
who is Larry Allison if there is a God
don't you think there is a big chance
that he has a preserved message to share
with clear answers for important
questions it will be terrible in hard to
live all your life having to force
yourself to believe a lot of things but
because you believe in a God just
because you believe in God I will be
like you said living without thinking
but there is an answer for that maybe
you don't know what it is but there is
one clear one what do you mean
mariya was said so what yeah you know so
what I'm not sure what do you mean so
break the loop says fountain fountain
head is a long book yeah like I guess
you know his/her books is like big you
know Atlas Shrugged that's okay I
understand I'm having the time to read a
novel I never read fiction these days
anymore neither
so Mario says it will be really hard
okay actually I don't have much comments
[Music]
so what are you saying
if there is a god don't you think there
is a big chance that he has a preserved
message to share yeah but I'm not
getting what you are saying Mario's are
you saying something or well yeah if you
you know you you know if you want to you
know clarify what you mean I'm not sure
what you saying
okay actually what else to talk about
we've been talking for four hour so
quick the loop says have you ever looked
into Saturn ism yes what's the
philosophy yes Saten ism yes I looked
into it's actually you know a certain
ISM I would characterize as actually you
know it's just numb believers okay wait
let me okay
let me read it
Saten ISM is a group of ideological and
philosophical beliefs based on Saturn
contemporary religious practice of
Saturn ISM began with the founding of
the Church of Saturn in 1966 although a
few historical precedents exist prior to
the public practice Saturn ISM existed
primarily as an accusation of various
Christian groups towards perceived
ideological opponents okay anyway so
okay I don't know about satin ism but
there is a church of satin I think
that's from it or yeah that one laveyan
satanism yes that I was thinking I went
as well yeah so this guy you know by the
way this guy you know he he's got a
daughter
and so she Church of Saturn yeah
so he's got a daughter and her he
started you know he died I think he died
like a few decades ago and in the 1980s
or something kotas yeah religious a new
religious movement I think it's this guy
yeah this guy so he died in 1997
so it Saturn is Emir peers to me it's
basically the they had Saturn ISM is
just well the love love aliens Saturn
ISM is basically who do not believe in
God like like some Harris okay he's a
theist who strongly you know do not
believe in any of the mono Li you know
monotheism the God and you know o Allah
so he want to oppose you know the
Christian ality or you know oh is Islam
and so but however you know it's that's
odd news you know a lot of people don't
believe in Christianity and they are
they are deemed as pagans you know or
heretics but so he so this is my
perspective so he came up with a way to
fight you know this Christianity okay so
instead of just you P instead of just
saying oh we don't believe in God
because of logic or this or that he
created you know he's also he created
his own religion and he caused its
atomism now I am not sure what's the
base of his naming of Saturn ISM but I'm
guessing you know I'm guessing actually
is just you know echoed that name just
for dramatic reasons because Saturn you
know in the Bible was the devil you know
it's something like a representation of
the of what you know again is Scott you
know I think he picked the name Saturn
isn't just for dramatic reasons like is
because maybe it began as a semi joke or
something okay let me see the very
established laveyan satanism in the US
state of California through the founding
of the
through the founding of his Church of
Saturn were pergi snatch of 1966 which
he proclaimed to be the year one analyst
Atanas the first year of the age of
Saturn his ideas were heavily influenced
by the ideas in writings of Frederick
initiate and an Ryan oh okay yeah so you
know he's a he's a pagan and he you know
he is atheist he wants to fight Chris
that's what I see you know he wants to
fight Christianity but instead of James
just you know the normal way the old you
know way saying you know it doesn't
exist he he created a movement you know
kind of and as a religion you know you
know like to basically again is you know
the Christianity and I've read I
remember I read their rules and
principles it just you know like
rationalism you know it is really this
is nothing like nobody when we see the
words that Saturn knows satanic it's
like we think of rituals or blood and
evil like like this you know the dog oh
they use but I think you know he is
doing that it's like he's doing that
it's almost like say my joke but taken
seriously you know he's you know he's
creating a movement you know religion
that's what well it's made it basically
died off today I think but I remember
reading that he started you know so he
died and his daughter came up and you
know talk [ __ ] about him so she because
I think there is a struggle of maybe
power with when he died so there's a
leader in the group in and they fight
you know it's like a lot you know rich
famous Hollywood stars
you know when they die then their family
start to fight you know a legal fight
about inheritance
money so I think yeah so is easy not
shirk the daughter you are talking about
yeah I think so I think that yes yes
that yeah
that sounds familiar I agree that Saturn
name choice seems like marketing
generates easy controversy by the name
yeah yes I think your analysis on
Saturday
Saturn ISM is accurate okay what else
what you up to break the loop so it's
your mo card so what are you doing these
days how many people are watching I
think that's about it for today and
after this I got we got seven people so
people who are you people
come come out and say something okay
let's see if I can actually see who is
here okay let's see participants okay so
yeah it only shows people who are
talking so if you want to you know if
you want to show you are watching that's
fine but you know hey Aaron Aaron Dodd
we from Aaron like what country so I'm
going to drink this this is a energy
drink sugar free so I've been drinking
this like every day for like four years
now five years even
and my thing is to mix it with fruit
juice so this hundred hundred percent
pineapple juice okay so that I don't end
up drinking the you know the condensed
coffee all the time you know actually I
drink fruit juice like water like this
thing like I've been doing this like all
my life you know for past thirty years
instead of drinking water I have always
been drinking 100% juice instead you
know when when I have money I would buy
those freshly squeezed juice but now I
don't have money I drink the you know
concentrate or whatever
so break the loop says I came home late
Saturday I came home late today about a
p.m. hello scene to Hayes scene to come
on in sin to sin - are you in China so
Aaron is from UK great United Kingdom
you know you know and we have United
States you know when I first came to us
you know that back in 1980
you know 1980s so when I first see the
u.s. you know the u.s. states you know
California New York you know Wyoming
Ohta you know you call them States but
however it's not called provinces like
in China you have different regions they
are called province and same thing in
Canada you have different provinces and
when I heard the states you know one way
you call it States you know it's like
almost you know a person me back then
you know I you know I don't know much
about literature or history or English
you know like 30 years ago
so no no I know of course but I was
puzzled why you go a state but finally I
realized okay United States there are
states actually because because in
something in some sense it's a it's not
one country you know actually you have
States States meaning you know state
means you know it's it's one political
entity you know so you have these
different states each one of them is a
political entity you know then you have
the then it so happens you know his
history
it so happens these different political
entities unite you know they decided to
they want to be together like a joint
like European Union okay but you know
they decide to join together so they
become the United States you know of
America you know America refers to the
you know so it's United States so that's
why it's you know each California is a
state it's not a province you know so
there's a technical difference in
meaning although in practice it's it's
basically the same thing but you know
you know so it's actually a federation
you know you so like you have to pay
federal tax then you have to pay state
tax you know state is you're you know
you is a political entity it's it's like
a country okay so California is one
entity but then because you are united
with other states then you have the
federal like the government you know the
the Star Trek Federation Enterprise you
know so you have this but actually in
practice you know it's not really you
know the state's the u.s. even though in
some historical sense there are
different states but in practice they
are not really they are just like one
country you know we are one country USA
you cannot you know decide you're gonna
leave the Union you know people have
been talking about that but it's not
likely your thing and that something
serious happens scene two is from
Southern California
great so actually we are about done so
if you have anything interesting or come
and just say it and we're gonna say
goodbye so break the loop says lady I've
been reading a computer science book by
Robert Sedgwick and doing the problems
chapter by chapter oh so who is Roberts
age week I email the professor in got a
reply so he's a professor
computer science scientists Robert
Sedgwick okay
so robust edge week for 1946
oh so he's pretty old 70-72 is an
American computer science professor at
Princeton University and a member of the
board of directors of Adobe Systems okay
founding Sedgwick was the founding
chairman of department of computer
science and so on okay but what what
does he do what is he known for so
Roberts edge with your but Rob Robert
Roberts Sedgwick is the author of a
well-known book series algorithms oh
okay oh yeah I remember that book cover
you know it's got it's a white cover
with a kind of balanced thing yeah I
remembered the first edition of the book
was published in 1983 okay
okay he said that she did he write a
novel I mean it's it does not mention
here but actually is he also the author
of the compiler book let's see
okay so wait something is wrong here
okay so let's go here
yeah okay so I was thinking he's was he
was one of them never mind
oh you're a computer science book okay I
missed I misread that to be a fiction
okay so break the loop okay so Mario
says I think Mario says Mario says I
think it's true that a lot of people
that believe in a god live without
thinking okay it will be hard to force
yourself to believe in everything that a
book like the Bible said yes yeah
okay good night good night break the
loop samaria says not yet okay so so
mario says it will be hard to live that
kind of life we need evidence in
certainty but there is an answer for
that the answer is you only have to
believe once one time in just a clear
message God has if you do believe in
that message you will have evidence for
your whole life after that in conclusion
you just need one deeper faith for for
believing God
oh okay so yeah oh okay so I see I was
mistaken so Robert Sedgwick book
oh okay so oh so I guess this is a new
book yeah I didn't I didn't know about
that interesting
yeah that algorithm book although I
haven't read it though you know actually
was a programmer I mean even even back
in Nets Abe back in mm okay
I started industrial programming in 1998
with Perl okay you don't you don't
really need to know algorithms because
everything is you know either in a
language you just have a function you
know salt for example and and today you
need even less like you don't need to
almost never unless unless you are the
principal program the lead programmer
you know that the beginner the the you
know of software that is extremely
complex such as you know Google search
engine if you do that you become a
billionaire you know if you can do that
but anyways yeah unless you actually
write something very serious you know in
big you know several maybe one year two
years project you have no need for
algorithms so like whatsoever it's like
you know nothing you don't have to know
nothing about it
how refresh on Java oh yeah oh yeah okay
that I think that's
okay Mario if you have the you know if
you have the link feel free to post it
the Bible way to heaven
okay so anyways that's it for today
thank you guys for coming
good night break the loop and good eye
guys yep
we will see you for sure the tomorrow
and so