good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sun talk
show
today is 2020 august 12th
12th 2 o'clock in the afternoon san
francisco time
and today we are going to talk about
emacs we are going to talk about
the just released emacs 27
uh there's a lot of things going on this
is fantastic
just released uh yesterday also emacs
version 27 grew emacs and first of all
let me tell you about the background
image
so this is a pumpkin uh carved in emacs
logo
this is back in um 2013
so seven years ago ever since i haven't
seen a good
you know uh pumpkin logo of emacs or
lisp
uh you know someone should do at least
one lisp logo like
like you know do a pumpkin this year
okay
uh in october someone should do that
okay so that's a pumpkin and let's talk
about emacs okay uh
okay so here is game of thrones game of
thrones is
epic fantastic okay uh go watch it
let's move it somewhere so we don't
always see that
usb speakers okay so let's talk about
emacs
good morning cortes so let me check
if i'm alive and everything is good we
don't have many people here today
uh okay voice check check
okay so let's talk about emacs so i mean
the new version of emacs so emacs 27 has
just been released
i'm going to go over i'm going to
download it install it
run it and tell you go over through some
of the features
my impressions and you know in real time
so first of all let's go to
i go to my emacs blog
i go to my emacs blog let's go to um
yeah emacs tutorial this is how i
download
it myself so emacs tutorial the first
item
where to download emacs for windows
for mac and for linux typically on linux
you just compile compile it yourself
yourself you know i have instructions on
how to compile
uh emacs on linux pretty easy
uh in five minutes you'll be done
but for macs and windows typically they
are pre-compiled version
it's more problematic to compile them so
you click on that
and download e-max version 27.1
fantastic okay yes say okay
and now we go to go to
okay it's downloading
sally fan club
wait let's wait for it to download
opening emacs 27.1 universal okay drag
to install
so let's drag it so on mac the
installation is
all very easy instead on windows you
have like
the installer you know then you run the
installer on the mac you just drag it
so it's copying to my applications
folder you don't have to
if you don't want to
so i'm actually excited about this emacs
27 release
every time there's a emacs release i'm
excited of course
they release about every two or three
years
but 27 i've seen several features
those are fantastic
so i'm going to tell you how do i
you know you know you can watch me how i
learn about
new features in emacs
like typically in unlike
other software the emacs you know they
they've been around for 30 years they
have a tradition of their own
how they release and their release notes
you know typically
today's software you have released new
notes you know what's new
but in emacs you don't have that
instead they say they have news you know
news
there's a news file which is basically
uh new features you know what's
being updated and that news file every
time there's a major
you know major version 27 26 25
release of emacs that news file is huge
like 50 pages and it's very esoteric
technical very technical they describe
features in terms of
it's it's basically incomprehensible
unless you have uh you know many years
of
experience of with emacs or emac beast
i mean even me reading that half of it
is like
incomprehensible you have to like dig
okay so it's copying to applications
okay it's done
now so here is the application i'm going
to rename it okay
hold on a second let me magnify uh
so you see my previous version is 26.3
so the 20 so this this is the latest
version i'm going to
rename it 27 27.1
okay there it is
okay now i'm going to start it now
now look at my emacs okay this is my od
max let me start a new
um so i go to terminal
i press up arrow so this is my previous
it will run my previous version of emacs
but let's change that
okay 27.1 launch it
okay now it's verifying emacs 27.1
app you know this this is the latest
version of mac os
and they started to have this annoying
thing like every time you use a
application
that's not sanctioned by apple you know
they have to
put a stamp of approval you have to i
i'm not sure you have to pay but
basically you have to be your apple
developer and so on and you know
but if you download some app on the from
the internet and you run it
the mac os will start to do some kind of
checking
so for example it says emacs 27.1
app can be open because app cannot check
it for
malicious software you know apple you
know
they started to have this tight control
of what can run on your machine
what the hell can be open because apple
cannot check it for malicious software
the software needs to be updated contact
the developer
okay now this is a problem
what okay i'm actually running into an
issue
uh mac os one let me open this
application [ __ ] let me try it again
god this is a problem
okay i don't know how to solve this
usually
usually there is a preference setting
let's go to preference okay
security and privacy i guess
good morning jack davidson hey what are
your opinion on veeam
hello not sure about microwave software
but for ios development you have to pay
99 every year for your app to stay in
the store yeah
yeah the apple you know they have wood
garden and they are apple has become
very evil you know they make your
they make your iphone slower whenever
there
is a new iphone coming out you know they
they use software to make your iphone
intentionally slower
and the apple has been sued for that
so let's go to security and privacy i
think there's a check box
somewhere there let's try it again
this is a problem my friend this is a
problem
i just want to run emacs
uh
uh maybe we have to search the internet
general okay
a login password has been set for this
computer
okay yeah here emacs 27 app was blocked
from use because it's not from an
identified developer
that means you didn't pay [ __ ] apple
open anyway
okay now we finally passed that
so it tells me there's already a process
id running because i already have a
emacs running do i want to
use that desktop file appear to be used
by that
uh use it anyway yeah
okay so this is my um
let's see wait which version is what
so this is actually new version
and let's close the close this window
let's quit let's create my old version
of emacs okay
actually let's start again let's make
everything don't save
close that close that
okay close that back to terminal
start emax 27.1
fantastic now it's running
first of all let's do a version okay
meta x
version you see it says emacs 27
now it's too small for you to see this
magnify okay
so you switch to messages buffer so you
can see
in this line emacs 27
now when when you download when you uh
how do you so that's how you check uh
version number okay meta x version let's
go to my talk show page
show in browser let's go here go to
browser close it
close that go back to go back to browser
copy the url back to my talk show page
paste it here linkify show in browser
so we have download emacs for windows
and mac that's the location to download
then we are going to okay let me tell
you so meta x
mx m let me magnify okay
and let me start my key command log okay
so you can see
all my command i code so
so let's call command xr start command
log mod
okay so now you can see all my
keystrokes on the pink window
okay and now mxh
meta x version
to see the version number
showing browser there it is so that's uh
that's how you look at
emacs version now so when you want to
see so that's how you see the version
number now
but if you want to see what's new what's
the new feature in the current version
what you do is you call this command
uh news okay meta x
news
uh i i forgot what's the command name
but let's
you what you can do is uh ctrl h okay
press
ctrl h
then question mark okay then it'll tell
you
which one to see the news and i believe
it's n
yeah so n there it is
so what you do is you let's try it again
okay
control h n that's how you see it
so here is actually the command view
emacs news
so now it will open a file that's
gnu emacs news you can see on the top
let me magnify
okay so this is the new emacs news it's
actually just a file so you can go to
a directory you go to the directory you
can see
this is a file these these new
files are basically new features of
emacs they
you know um
news update i mean the the features
change log basically essentially like a
change log
change log okay so
so close that so we
are going to let me tell you some of the
features okay so so
this news file usually they open in a
outline mod
okay uh let's open a new window okay so
we okay let's go back to my talk
show talk show um
what what do i want to do let me just
explain instead of writing it so this
news file when you open it
ctrl will open this news file
and this will open in a mod called
outline mod you can see
in the mod line it says online that you
know you can invoke that that command
and let's try let's write it down online
mod okay
mh meta x online mod
and the outline mod you know online mod
is is is like org now if you are
if you use oak you are familiar you see
these outlines
online mod is the daddy of oak mod you
know oak mod is created by this uh
finnish guy uh northern european uh the
professor
he was a student of astronomy and
about 20 years ago he's taking notes
with outline mod
and he found that the outline mod the
keys
are cumbersome so he started to
improve it eventually that became oak
mod
so oakmod outline mod is the granddaddy
of oakmod
mod is basically a derivative
i mean with much much more features
after 20 years
so online mod you can let me try yeah
the so the outline mod the keys for
online mod
and oak mod are rather completely
different
you know online mod keys is very so it's
cumbersome control c
control something something that's why
oak mod you know he created oak mod
now when you are in a new mod you can
see the documentation of the mod what
you do is you call describe
mod okay let me try it
oh the shortcut is ctrl h
m okay control h m
you see it pops up a window this this
command is called
uh describe mod you can see here
describe mod
so uh so there you have the
documentation for the online mod you can
see
you can see these uh shortcuts you know
control c
control a outline show all you know for
headings and stuff so anyway
close that uh let me go
uh let me let me tell you uh describe
mod okay
i mean i'm i'm i'm also giving you some
of the emacs list
tutorials um okay show in browser you
can you can you can use describe mod
it's
very useful uh
so let's go back to the news file
so once you you are in news file just
change it to
uh you can just change it to uh org mod
because org mod is much more powerful
and it's
basically compatible with outline mods
so let's go to old mod
co oak mod okay
now we are in oak mod magnify now in oak
mod you can press
tab key to to collapse the outline
so uh what's the let's see
shift tab there it is you see you press
shift tab you you see the entire outline
let's let's try it again
shift tab shift tab okay shift tab
shift tab they cycle between collapsing
and stuff so anyways
so here is the list of features of emacs
27 lots of them
so if you let's try shift tab again
shift tab
lots of things you know it takes days to
go through them
and it's usually esoteric for example
uh if i'm going to start to read it for
example installation changes
emacs now uses gmp the gnu multiple
precision library okay that's
that's esoteric unless you code c you
wouldn't know what that is
then emacs can now use half bus
as its shaping engine i have no idea
what that
is uh then the new configuration option
with json
adds native support for json okay that's
fantastic
then it says the configuration option
with carrio
is no longer experimental okay
so there's a lot of to go through now as
a user
you know if you are just a normal emacs
user usually you go through these
it's not helpful i mean the ratio of
information you get and the time spent
to read it
is not usually not worthy because
there's tons of
stuff because you you don't you are not
you know
developing emacs for example this
so let's shift tab again let's see the
outline
so editing so for example editing
changes in imax27 that would be
interesting so let's expand that
so this is typically the part you want
to read
because that's relates to editing but
again
usually they are esoteric
like is of no concern to you most of
them
but anyway let's so but someone this
uh super thank you super in discord if
you haven't already joined our discord
okay
so so you are watching sally kung
you know i announced that i'm going to
do a live stream and cortez
posted that
so anyway so so thanks to super he
he he give us some of the uh
very fantastic features of emacs 27
so let's let me go through them okay
common and questions posted okay let me
read the comments
and then i'm going to go through i'm
going to give you my
i'm going to read the fantastic new
features i'm
going to tell you what i think about
them i'm going to try them
um and i'm going to uh valid you know
try them and validate verify it
and i'm going to give you my impressions
in real time
so let's see what you guys are saying
how long have i been talking i've been
talking for
22 minutes so time goes fast so
okay so they make you go to another menu
where you can just run it okay it fakes
security okay windows uac is the same
exactly yeah
hello mac os still allow um
hey scott good morning scott uh
good evening good evening scott has been
um
uh scott has been using emacs since 1990
right yeah 10 years earlier than me
[Laughter]
good evening uh uh
what uh so good idea can you can you
compare oakmod to html to be more
readable
can you good idea and you can compile
oakmod to html
right i mean you you can export ht okama
to html yeah let's try that okay
so ctrl h m
uh wait uh control h n
shows the news file and now
let's copy the whole thing close it
create a new buffer
paste it here actually let's close it go
to my emacs uh blog showing browser
then i'm going to create a new file here
so open a new buffer
paste the entire news file here you can
see the scroll bar that's
uh that's like you can you can see the
scoreboard that's like
three thousand two hundred lines three
thousand two hundred lines now save it
uh save it as um i want to save it in
miscellaneous emacs news
emacs 27 27 okay
dot h dot org
okay does not
exist uh wait uh [ __ ]
i want to save it in
wait uh i want to save it in
miscellaneous okay save in that
directory
okay now go to the go to my go to the
directory you can see i have a space
i have a space in that file name i want
to change that so
so go to top dial toggle read only
and just change the name ctrl c ctrl c
to finalize it so i change the name with
a underscore instead of space
open it copy the file path close it
close it back to my that's in my emacs
that's my emacs blog open a new
section paste the link linkify
make a paragraph show in browser
so here is the emax27 oak file
now let's export it so open it
uh meta x org export
yeah okay oh i don't use org mod much so
i don't remember the keys
so let's just try oak export
what's the keys again for export org
export dispatch okay yeah so that
then then h html file
there it is uh wait
yeah [ __ ]
the og mod where are we
i i hate you know ogmod has their
own uh esoteric files i mean not files
so let's do control hm describe
mod okay so that will tell me what the
keys
so ctrl h m
magnify search for
um wait this is our line wait
i need to switch oh yeah i need to
switch to oakmod so
um open
okay this is uh oh yeah so
close it reopen it
it's in online mod why is it yeah it's
stupid
[ __ ] okay so you see i i created this
file and this file is named oak
you know emacs27.org so if a file name
ends in org
it should open in oak mod but it's not
you can see the mod line says online why
is that
because you see at the end of the file
they have local variables
it says smart outline you don't want
that it's stupid
so delete that line save it
close it reopen it magnify it now you
can see
in the mod line it says oak mod right
now now we are good to go now let's do
uh
describe mod ctrl h
m okay now we see the ogma documentation
magnify now let's search for export
there it is so here is the here's the
key stroke you want to
call ctrl c ctrl e okay close it
ctrl c ctrl e
then h
then edge
edge okay you have to type h twice
yeah that's done so now go back to diet
you can see it created a new file update
you can see it created new file open it
okay so this is the html exported
showing browser
so there it is the oak mod
you know the news for the
emacs 27 huge you can see the scroll bar
it's a huge document
in this okay but okay so let's forget
that
open it copy the file path close close
close uh let's put it here
uh wait what's going on
yeah the stupid title wait
i'm i'm just going to do some thing
quickly so
the title is incorrect well rather my
my my
yeah the title is incorrect you see the
title it becomes
uh
the title becomes
i'm not sure what character that is
uh anyway the that's uh that's because
of the org
export the title is incorrect
so anyway let's go through let's go
through the interesting things okay
uh let's go to the interesting things
let's close close okay so emacs 27
let's see what's the interesting things
uh go back to my
talk page so building support for
arbitrary size integers
that's fantastic um you know why uh
you know why because
emacs in emacs buffer you have
uh whenever your cursor
cursor has a cruiser position in in the
beginning of a buffer
the position is one always so you can
see the cruiser position by calling this
command
uh the command is called describe
wait
uh describe char okay so the
command name is called describe char so
so you call describe char i have a
keyboard shortcut in soft like keys
which is
uh space hc okay so you can see
i'm my my cruiser my cruiser is right
here
and it says and if you go to the pop-up
window it says
uh you see the first line position 168.
so so cruz you know kusa has a position
and at the end of the cruiser position
you have
um you know
at the end right now i'm at position
now there's a problem so so if you have
a huge
file let's say two gigabyte file so
the cruiser position will be a huge
number
in the previous e-max version that
number will be
beyond the maximal integer
that e-max have you know beyond the
maximum integer
so so that effectively
creates a limit of how large a file you
can open
in emacs so that has been a problem for
you know
for for 10 years because file gets
larger and larger so now
finally they have a built-in support for
arbitrary size integers
so that is that is actually one of the
item we see
uh am i going too slow like i think i'm
going to
too finely detailed uh let's go to
okay control h n
let's go back to the news file so
magnify
so you see this this section emacs now
uses gmp the glue multiple precision
library
so basically that you know from what i
understand that
that multiple precision
you know is it essentially gives you
infinite
uh infinite uh integer size
something like that
okay so so so now you can open large
files i suppose
so that's a great thing uh text
shaping with heartburst i don't know
what they what is that
uh let me let me go to the discord and
go to here and copy the text
so uh super gave us
these news so let's copy that
copy go back to talk show and let's
paste it
make a list make a list and uh
showing browser so now it's easier to
see
native support for json parsing i i want
to um
okay portable done being used instead of
on hex okay i can tell you what that is
uh support for xdg conventions for init
file yeah
um additional early you need early
innate initialization file
lexical binding is used by default
that's fantastic
building support for tab bar and top tab
line
now that that is the most useful this is
the this one is the most easy to
understand and useful let's see if i can
try it you know many of these other
items it takes
a lot of time to explain you know take
five or a minute five minutes you know
several minutes to explain each one of
them
uh but let's try the tab bar support i
always i want i've been wanting to see
that for a long time
so ctrl h n go to the news file
search for tab
tab bar okay so
let's see if i can try the tab bar
what's uh you know i want to know the
command name okay so here it is
type bar mod so the new command tab
bar mod enables the tab by the top of
each frame
including text terminal frames wow
that's amazing amazing we're gonna try
that
where you can use tabs to switch between
name
named persistent window configurations
you know the [ __ ] emacs
the new you know people they use these
jargons nobody
nobody can understand what the [ __ ] they
are talking about
so they so this so there's a new type of
mod okay enables the tab by the top of
each frame
e-max frame just means window okay
stupid emacs people
it just means a window okay like window
window
window but but emacs call those frames
then it says including tty frames go
[ __ ]
[ __ ] yourself the [ __ ] nuts e-max
green
green max idiots that is why e-max never
becomes popular okay that's that is why
so many other reasons but that this is
why and these nerds refuse they don't
understand they refuse to change they
think oh
this is technically correct you know so
tty frame what does that mean it just
means
it runs in text terminal when you start
emacs in terminal
this feature will also work in terminal
that's what it means
so then it says where you can use tabs
to switch between named persistent
window configurations
[ __ ] this you know they are saying you
can use your tabs
so what does that mean it just means
tabs just like a browser okay you have
tabs just like a browser you can switch
tabs between
windows but these nodes don't understand
for
you know they are like that
so type mod we're gonna try okay so
let's see what else um
let's just try it so meta x
tab bar mod let's see what we got
what the [ __ ] it says tab bar mod
enabled but i don't see
it okay oh god
they should say you know they this emacs
people they are just incomprehensible
facts you know that's that is why every
time
with when whenever there's a new emacs
release
then you have a you know a couple of
bloggers including myself
we write your blog tells
tells you you know the emacs new
features
which you can actually understand okay
which command to call
and how do you configure it you know
but the gnu emacs people they can do
that you know
they'll say oh no resources no that's
not true because they
they they really wanted to stick to this
nerd
talk and they part of the reason
is that they are actually incapable just
like the linux people they are
incapable of of of writing technical
writing
and in a way that other people can
understand
and also partly because they refuse why
they refuse they because they
you know in the programming community
they have the this mentality real
men you know real men's editor emacs
real
men men's programming language c you
know they want things to be as
difficult as possible because they it
functions
as a filter filter out those
uh stupid people or newbies they you
know they
they kind they have some kind of elite
mentality that's what these
nerd tech gigging [ __ ] are you know
including the
unix people linux people 3bs people
it's you know in a lot of people in in
it's it's part of their mindset
you know so so some partly because they
are incapable of technical writing
great great lucid technical writing they
are incapable of
they they tend to write dribbles or dry
stuff you know
then they then partly because they don't
want to because they have a
elite mentality they they want things to
be like
esoteric so that for example if you are
you
uh emax phonetics i know many of you are
you know and
and vim people when when you read it you
you get excited oh my god
oh my god taps you know these esoteric
terminologies
is [ __ ] stupid people
uh then then then okay so so i just
tried tap mod and it's not working
so what's what's going on i i i can you
know i have some guesses
because possibly because i turned off
the
um you know the gui so let's go to my
emacs gui okay emacs go to my
bookmark style open fast um
start open file fast open a bookmark of
my
a brief file then go to the directory so
here is my
all my emacs in it then go to the file
settings
search for settings okay so this is all
my
uh the settings file is all the basic
the most
fundamental emacs in it without
requiring
any uh modules or packages you download
so this is the most
fundamental so i have here
somewhere that prevents uh the two bar
lines
maybe that's that's the one that's the
bar that says copy paste
open file things like that so let's
remove that line
okay so remove that line save it
quit emacs let's restart emax
emacs 27 okay let's restart i want i
just want to try the tab bar mod
tap boss
okay warning warning okay this is a new
feature warning a necessary call to
package in use
initialize in init file okay that that
must be another new change now it's not
necessary to call package initialize
probably because it's already built in
it's already you know
okay let's ignore that for now wait
let's
verify okay control h n go to the news
file
and search for package initialize search
for
okay there it is magnify uh
magnify magnify so it says
installed packages are now activated
before
loading the init file okay
installed packages are now activated
before loading the init file
oh that's interesting huh
before loading the init file okay so it
actually
essentially it so it when emacs starts
it will load
your lpar directory you know you have
the lp directory that's the
let me show you okay emacs init
let's go to um so you go to your emacs
dot d directory lp directory
go to the directory so here is
where your packages are installed when
if you are installing them from melpa or
elpa so so so apparently now emacs will
load this these packages
before reading your init file
so okay that's a nice feature so that
means i have to go to my
emacs init i have to close that
go to my emacs init file and
remove the line here you see
i probably have to remove this line
and maybe remove that line as well you
have to try you have to
do trial and error and restart and see
or you have to read this you know this
news file carefully
yeah they actually give you a code
example this
this is good now this is a good you know
this code example is good so anyway
let's start the tab bar mod
okay meta x wait let's start
my command first uh exhaust start
command log
okay so now you can see my command again
on the pink window now let's uh meta x
tab bar mod please
wait wait wait hold on a second uh i'm
still
not seeing the bar wait new oh they okay
so
okay you know what's going on now we
have a bar
but why is my other windows doesn't have
the bar because
every time you quit emacs will remember
your windows
configuration so that's why so let's
close this window
close this window open a new window so
you can see
those things now let's try tap our mod
again
type bar mod i don't see tabs
what the [ __ ] okay that means i need to
read
the news file so control h n
search for tab
bar
okay so let's see what what do we have
to do
here
so go to the top search for tab bar
go to the top search for tab
bar
so let's see what it says the new uh
wait
um
so new the new command tab tab enables
the tab bar at top of each frame
uh control xt
sequence is the new prefix key for tab
related commands okay control x t2
creates a new tab
okay blah blah blah tab related commands
are availa available
even when tab bar mod is disabled okay
the x resource tab bar class tab bar
enables the tab
bar blah blah blah the user option tab
bar position specifies where to show the
tab bar
wait what what emacs version am i using
version 27 yeah so where's my tab bar
okay so it says read the new
info not emacs top tab box to
for full description of all related
feature
what what the [ __ ] why you would
you know i've been using emacs for 20
years i cannot you know i have no i
i spent 10 minutes i cannot get the tap
bar to show
what does that mean for other emacs
users this is so
[ __ ]
okay so uh so do you guys know
just tried it in in linux and it works
both in x windows mod
and within a terminal okay so
so okay so apparently it worked for
scott
okay try making a new tab bar okay ctrl
x wait ctrl
x t 2.
i'm not seeing any tabs
okay now let's try one more one more
time one last time quit emacs
quit the [ __ ] now let's start emacs
again this time
this time with a option uh
dash queue dash q means download your
unique files so we are running a plane
gnu emacs 27 27.1
okay so now i ha now
you know this is playing gnu e max 27 i
don't have my keys
so i have to use the default emacs keys
i don't remember
all the keys so now meta x
meta x wait
uh meta is this key meta x
tab bar
mod no no no
no no [ __ ] tabs
[ __ ]
okay it says maybe hello says maybe it's
not ported to mac os yet
okay screws you know the the glue emacs
people they intentionally by purpose
intentionally by richard stowman they
want to prevent
any feature in mac or windows that's
that
that might be better than linux so
whenever something works on mac
they i mean this is intentional explicit
you know
you can go to this happened many times
controversy giant controversy
they in richard stoneman himself not
others usually not others not the
not the current maintainer richard
stoneman
even though he's not technically the
maintainer the leader of the emacs you
know
he but however he sit he sit in the
emacs grenoble imax dev mailing this
background and he just wrote his
opinions these [ __ ]
richard stowman he said oh we should
remove that you know
even though technically he's not the
leader he's he's supposed to
support you know by by their explicit
statement
he has no right to to give the direction
of emacs in any technical sense
except when it comes to political issues
such as licensing such as any packages
that relates to
politics then he can say you know what
we should do
but however in the past 10 years he has
voiced opinions that
that that are purely technical opinions
and
and uh you know tell others what to do
this this richard stowman scum bag
so let's try one more time to get the
tapas
mod run okay so now no init file
and dash nw nw means no windows system
so we are going to run emacs
in pure terminal let's see maybe if that
feature is in terminal
okay run it okay so we are in terminal
so let's
meter x
tap bar mod
oh there it is there it is tab bar mod
so you can see a tab there now
control x control x
control f that's for opening a new file
uh wait cancel ctrl
g let's open a new buffer so i want to
see more tabs okay
so control control
x control b
okay that's list buffers control x b
okay switch to a new buffer now type a
random name
that's how you open a new buffer
okay now we have a new buffer now i want
to unsplit ctrl x
1 i have a new buffer but i don't see
the tabs so can let's try again ctrl
x t 2.
oh so new tab so so you know
at this point i have to play around
exactly to see what the
what what they mean by tab
so so far it does not looks like
browsers tab
or maybe i don't know for sure you see
because right now
the buffer honute is
having two tabs now let's switch buffer
okay
ctrl ctrl x control
wait uh ctrl x b
let's go to scratch okay now you see the
tab it says
honute and scratch
and of course you can click on that no
you cannot click on that
anyway so that's that's a tab bar so i
have to look into
but you know i need to run emacs in gui
because in g so what's the difference
which one is better
running e-max in group in terminal text
terminal or gui gui is better okay
because in gui
e-max will be able to detect much more
keys key you know key binding why
because for example
in terminal it is impossible
to distinguish
control
it's for example it's impossible to
distinguish
the enter key versus control
m okay for example for example like i
can press ctrl
m right now control m is the same as uh
let me let me type it okay
control plus m
is the same as the enter key and
in terminal there is
no way to distinguish
them that's because the technology of
terminal you send in key sequences
there's no way to distinguish them but
on the other hand on the
on the gui terminal on a gui e-max
you can distribute distinguish that and
also there's another
more important difference for example in
terminal
it's impossible to distinguish control
capital letter versus control lower
later they will be the same
so it so in terminal it reduces lots of
your
key binding possibilities
and again i have a um
you know i have a tutorial you know the
i tell you everything about emacs keys
you just go to my emacs website
uh emacs keys overview emacs key
overview
now go to how to define keys so i have
all this
information detailed there you know
which key to use
if you want the new keybinding which to
use how do you choose them
which key to avoid why you should avoid
them things like that
so if you know just by just buy my emacs
tutorial okay if you like it
buy it
okay so how long have i been talking i
think i'm gonna gonna read
the uh comments and that'll be it for
today i've been talking for long
so emacs 27 is out is fantastic i've
been talking for 54 minutes it's
fantastic
um i so i was thinking of going through
the features
but each one of them will actually take
five or ten minutes to explain uh
but all these are great features you
know the
the the one feature that's really useful
to the user
is the tab bar mod why because
you know a lot of emacs nerds like you
people
you don't want it because a lot of emacs
people they
they don't want to use the mouse they
don't want anything gui
they are extremely [ __ ] idiots okay
let me tell you why
this e-max nuts people on one hand let
me explain okay let's quit
let me explain this thing ctrl
x c okay exit emacs and go back to my
gui version
let me explain the e-max nerds these
idiots these
idiots you know on one hand
you know they don't like this uh gui you
see this uh
the thing and also you see my scoreboard
you see my scroll bar you know uh here
you see on one hand they don't like that
because they they think it's
necessary they they prefer efficiency
okay they
e-max people you you hear them talk all
the time they prefer
uh atmos most efficiency they want they
don't like they don't want to use the
mouse at all
but they are [ __ ] idiots they are the
mo they are in many ways they are
inefficient for example
the emax key binding system that's the
most [ __ ]
inefficient system on earth the most
inefficient you can
you can count by create you know install
a key lock you know i talked about this
many kinds sometimes
there's a package key frequency you can
compute you can count your keystrokes
using the default emax keybinding system
is the
the utmost [ __ ] inefficient [ __ ] in
the universe
but this imax knows people you know on
one hand they say oh you must
use the glue default emacs keybinding
system because it's efficient it's well
designed
you can see it's well designed they're a
[ __ ] ass
meanwhile meanwhile they want to you
know they
you know if you read a lot reddit or
emacs bloggers they tell you about
remove the you know the remove the
scroll bar
you know for example i can remove it
right now so
hold on a second wait where's my keys
uh do you want to enable dictation what
the [ __ ]
no i don't know
did i change my key or something no okay
so
wait my key is not working
okay somehow i got caps lock on
what the [ __ ]
uh what
okay i got the
yeah what the [ __ ]
what the [ __ ] okay now i'm back to
normal okay
so uh so let me tell you let me explain
okay you see the scroll bar you know
usually they don't want it so
you know i can show you you know i
so first of all there's a toolbar on top
now that
is not useful because i can tell you
that it's not useful so i removed it
in my in my default so let's go back to
my uh
settings so go to settings you see this
line
you know toolbar i removed it because
it's it's
not useful technically but sometimes
they remove the scoreboard
you know you can technomancy for example
technomancy is a guy who created the
um you know these nuts okay i can i
cannot stand them this unix
philosophy [ __ ] you know let me
show you this
this guy okay i mean he's a great guy
okay and he's a
very intelligent guy he created this
keyboard okay
he created this keyboard atrius okay a
lot
you know again atreus is a one of the
thing that these
nerds love uh you know he created these
atrias not just that he is also a
closure
master he he created the closure many
fundamental uh the closure the the the
i have articles on that okay you just go
to closure um
okay let me show you okay so let me take
some few minutes to show you
i'm talking about this guy okay so uh
you go to my tutorial you go to closure
not
not chinese chess you go to um
programming language tutorial you go to
crochet i started i have a
kind of a tutorial on closure begin
beginners
so then then you have on enclosure
because it's
java you have these
you have this this oh yeah here so so
right uh so you have this um leonard
leonard gun [ __ ]
which is a command line utility very
complex
it's just like the javascript npm you
know npm you run this command too
very complex but anyway it's very useful
it's very
actually extremely important uh tool
you it's almost necessary if you are a
closure developer
and it's not easy to write of course and
this lender gun is written by
this guy technomancy this guy this guy
is
you know very smart he's a far better
programmer than me
i can say that for sure and he's also
uh you know but you know but these
people these idiots these people
he's one of them okay they're not very
very extreme hacker types this
he's one of them he i remember
reading you know his blog or somewhere
you know he's one of those guy
who tells you to remove this
scroll bar you know the visual scroll
bar the idiots why
because they think you know you see at
the bottom
you see that 58 percent you know it
might be too small but in the mod line
is you can see
there's a 15 you know 71 that thing
that since things tells you where your
cursor is
related to the buffer it's function you
know is same serves the same purpose of
as the visual scroll bar so according to
these people meanwhile they want
efficiency you know they they tell you
to remove they don't like the mouse
they don't like the gui they tell you to
use the glue default keybinding which is
the most inefficient
[ __ ] you know they're loved by these
people
but they also tell you to remove the
scroll bar but
the scroll bar is actually the most
efficient way
to tell where your cursor is related to
the buffer
because right now i can you know even
i'm not looking at my screen
directly i can by my peripheral region
vision
the scroll by speak i can tell right
away where relatively where my
scoreboard
where my cruiser is relative to the
buffer
but with these hacker nuts they tell you
they want to remove the scroll bar
they tell you to use they tell you to
look at that you know 60
uh you know that percentage uh
you know the the text on the my life
what the
what the [ __ ] are these people thinking
do they have a brain
you know you know again i can tell you
why they think that way because
that thing you know 60 percent that's
esoteric okay nobody understand what
that is
you need it's a require you you need to
learn it
this it makes things difficult that's
why these people love it so
it makes it difficult they have a
mentality of being a
real man you know but but these days the
social justice scan
prevents that you know you cannot say
real name anymore but they
it's like that so they are kind of elite
you know they like
they are you know let me put this way
if you are concerned about efficiency
and now we have the question whether the
scoreboard the visual scroll bar is
efficient more efficient for e
for which way is faster to tell
where is your cruiser position relative
to the whole buffer
the scroll bar or that or that
you know percentage uh notification you
know
and if you if you are a scientist or
anything you know you you know for sure
the scoreboard is more efficient
but this these notes you know this e-max
phonetics
they won't have it lots of other
examples
lots of other examples let me let me
tell you scroll bar
the tab bar we are just trying to show
that is one
giant example too because you know
the tab bar mod okay i have articles on
that okay uh let me let me
let me show you so this is becoming a
giant rant
again it's these emacs notes
so you search for exactly type bar okay
actually
yeah let's search for let's search the
web
i know where the article is but let's
search the web so you can
uh um
emacs top bar okay let's search the web
you you'll find my articles
uh where is it no here
so anyway what i'm saying is that that
there is
a uh there is a
package that does the tap bar like 10
years ago
10 [ __ ] years ago
it exists uh you have to install it
you know it's a third-party package
where is it i
uh i have article on that i i i tell you
uh 10 years ago where is it
let's go to okay so this this is my
website let's go to emacs init
uh let's search for tab
okay it's not here you know anyway so
this
you know i wrote about it 10 years ago
it's part of ergo emacs it's from you
know it shows tabs just like a browser
so why tabs because tabs provide a
visual clue
of what what files buffers you have you
know
it's not necessary but it's it's often
useful because
especially for beginners you know emacs
people complain
there are not many emacs people anymore
it's reducing
less and less people using emacs why
because it's difficult
in every way it's unnecessarily
difficult
i'm not talking you know i don't want to
remove any efficiency part of emacs i
love emacs i love you know i love
living it but we but meanwhile if you
can do something
that has no that doesn't take away
anything of emacs but
also make it more friendly to beginners
why not
tap out is one of the thing so it
existed 10 years ago but it's not good
because
it makes emacs very slow why because
it's an external package
it's it's hard to implement that feature
because the emacs
this infrastructure doesn't have that
you know
the emac list infrastructure the emacs
um infrastructure is doesn't have a
uh modern gui uh framework
put it that way yeah so it's
it's kind of difficult to for
for external packages emac these
packages to
add features such as um
such as you know the tap bar it it went
through
extreme hacks to create that so but the
result is not so good
uh because it makes emacs very slow
actually i do have a
i do have a picture i can
i can find it okay i can find it let me
just
try to find it
okay search for tab bar
okay this this is becoming a giant
rant and are you guys still here
[Laughter]
what is your opinion about emacs native
uh comp branch for emacs 28
what is that i don't know
okay let's search for god so this
is um
so let's look at my emacs blog archive
2000 year 2010
so you see year 2010 december
2nd ergo emacs package version 1.91
is released this is essentially just
1.91
fixed fixed a zip package packaging
problem and loading problem
of tab bar mod and tweet
mod okay so you know google code google
code is closed we are seeing history
here
but i i have a picture okay what i want
to show you is the picture so
let's magnify let's go to so let's go to
e-shell
and find dash now let's run unix
commands
the things that tickles these notes uh
find name tab okay let's uh tab bar mod
okay let's
let's search for bar
okay oh wait not html png
there it is tab bar so
okay not that there it is okay
okay that's one of the picture let's
show in the preview
so you see this is the um
magnum file okay so this is this is the
emacs tab
the package it's not so good because it
slows down your
emacs but anyway what i want to say
actually there's more than that emacs
tab bar problem wait
um another screenshot okay here's
another
another screenshot okay so actually
you can okay anyway anyway so
so here is tab bar okay this is 10 years
ago
so but when this happens you know the
gnu people they don't want that you know
if you ask you know
if you read the emacs new menus they
they are like oh we don't want to talk
about that that's not us you know
emacs people has been that like that for
30 years
basically every new feature useful
feature such as syntax highlighting okay
syntax coloring you know coloring
keywords
and any feature like that it exists in
the industry you know in in the industry
emacs people will refuse to do it
until like five or ten years later
tab bar mod is one of the example tabs
has
been existing in browsers since like 20
years now
now the [ __ ] emacs [ __ ] these
nerds
they are thinking oh we oh no it's time
we you know we should
we oh fantastic we are going to have a
table
where are they what are they thinking 20
years ago why don't they do that
if they do that 20 years ago emacs today
might be just like
just like a browser use it by everyone
but these people refuse you know they
don't understand just like the linux
people they don't they don't
understand how things work how society
how
how you know the average people and
meanwhile they are not they
they are nurse they want to create a
certain elite community that's what they
are that's what they do
what so what is my perspective you know
i'm a efficiency i'm a nerd too i'm a
nerd too
and i'm a efficiency extreme efficiency
nerd
i don't [ __ ] care about user
interface
you look at my emacs i don't use themes
thing my ass okay i don't i don't want
any coloring
[ __ ] but i do want syntax coloring
because that
actually is efficient that actually
visually it's the most efficient way to
to find the code okay so i'm a i'm a
i'm a nerd i'm a of and i'm also a
efficiency nerd
i i care about functionality
hundred percent functionality the most
ugly the user interface the best it is
okay
somewhat okay but but i want the scroll
bar because scroll by is the most
efficient
okay and i want i want the tab bar
because it it actually helps and i also
want the menu for example
many emacs people for example you see
the menu here
uh wait show menu
okay you see the menu many emacs notes
they remove the menu
the [ __ ] idiots i want the menu why
because if you only are only concerned
about
efficiency extreme functionality nothing
else
you want the menu why because menu in
many cases when for example when you are
trying a new mod menu is the most
efficient way
to tell you what are the important
commands
better than describe mod okay better
than for example i'm doing describe mod
this
this bunch of text you know for example
if you are in oak mod you have
let's close that okay close that close
that let's go to org
uh for example let's go to uh emacs blog
let's go to the oak oakmod file
and let's go to describe mod
you see this is another way to see what
commands are there you know you see you
got
you got you know hundreds of them and
it's incomprehensible
because every esoteric less used command
is also
all shows are there you know you don't
know which one to use
use but on the other hand if you go to
the
menu now there's something screwed up in
my menu because some menus are not
showing
um you know usually there's a oak mod
when you
when you turn on augma there's the oak
mod menu
mod specific menu that menu will show
you tell you which command is the most
useful but you know you can look it
so that so so i'm an efficiency nerd i'm
a nerd and i'm
also i'm also i'm interested in
functionality hundred percent
but so but meanwhile looking at these
other nodes you know these emacs people
you know you know this unix philosophy
or these typical
programming language notes they they are
thinking is actually
oftentimes they insist on something
that's just bad
okay that's just inefficient such as
removing the
the scroll bar or removing the menu
that's just
idiot okay that's just idiot and also
the default
the default guru emax key binding what
is that
that's not efficiency that's idiot to
the extreme
and these people they like to insist on
that
i you know that's why sometimes i don't
get i cannot you know for 20 years they
call me a troll
i don't get what the [ __ ] they are
thinking and the way they write
this documentation this incomprehensible
[ __ ]
okay that's that's the um that's today's
uh rant okay i hope
msu on okay
uh one hour and 15 minutes okay we
i'm going to shut down and i'm going to
okay now i have 14 14 viewers
the more random the more viewers people
want to see drama i'm going to sip
my energy drink then i'm going to sip
tea
then we shut down in maybe three or five
minutes
okay then i'm going to read the comments
so comments right now
i'll answer questions
and now this is tea
okay i'm going to read comments and that
that'll be it for today which we should
now in three minutes um
hello says i once emailed
richard storman he said he couldn't see
the website
fine yeah he see the article he he
requested i described the picture
yes exactly that's him i i wrote to him
too
like in 2008
you know in 2008 i proposed to him
because the emacs manual the emacs
manual
is [ __ ] idiotic okay
so i i was trying to you know i talked
to the emacs dev you know they know me
right yeah you know they know me i know
them
most of them uh they i want to you know
i
i'm thinking we should rewrite the emacs
manual
you know in emacs manual you have 900
pages
and the the it's it's it's
incomprehensible and also
idiotic you know it spends one chapter
to tell you to tell you what is the
cruiser you know
or or what is the copy paste you know
they they spend several
uh pages to tell you what what is a copy
paste
the [ __ ] idiots you know in 1980s
yeah you tell people what is copy paste
not today you know you don't waste time
to read a manual of an editor that
spends two pages three pages telling you
what is the copy and paste
you know this you might say just one
sentence
you know but the emacs menu is like that
i can show you right now
the the [ __ ] emacs menu control h i
okay control h i gets you to this page
then you go to um the the here
okay the emacs menu okay let's go there
then you have like now this is this is
literally 900 pages okay
now you can uh for example copy and
paste and
emacs refuse to use that term they have
their own term for example they call it
yank and uh let me show you okay kill
yeah
you know mark okay mark
let's open that so the mark and the
region that's
what is that that's text selection okay
that's guys let's just text selection
well the only special thing emacs is is
you have a mark
that means use the start the command to
start the text selection without using
the mouse which is great which
which is actually very efficient uh
so anyway so so mark in the region the
[ __ ] emacs [ __ ]
you know they tell you about marx and
region then you you know
then you read it then then there's face
custom
customization what the [ __ ] is a face
that just means font okay
font but they they have to say face
customization
so let's go back the marketing region
then you then you spend
you know they so so you have you know
then then setting the mark
setting the mark you know and and then
this command
that you know that's why nobody nobody
actually [ __ ] reads the emacs manual
these [ __ ] and the marking object
using region markering okay
many of these are great emacs features
for example global marketing
local marketing you know i if you read
my tutorials over there
i give you the most easy to understand
you know
you spend five you know you you spend to
read this
we will take you an hour or two about
the
about the mark uh about this you know
market region on the other hand on my
tutorial you can see on my tutorial i
have like three pages about that
you spend 10 minutes 10 minutes you can
understand the whole thing
but so in 2008 i wrote to richard
stoneman i talked to the emacs dev they
don't listen of course they they they
are
incorrigible impossible to communicate
with them
and pretty soon it's going to become a
flame war
or someone will start to say why don't
you use
why don't you use a microsoft notepad
the [ __ ] the [ __ ] them
you know anything anything different
from emacs they will just say
why don't you use uh microsoft notepad
we are not microsoft notepad why don't
you go
use windows so [ __ ] them
or sometimes they will become oh vi
versus vim
every time you talk about emacs you know
this is
intimidating you'll become oh vi let's
talk about vi versus vim
the the idiots so i so in 2008 i wrote
two you just stole my i say okay i can
improve
you know all polite you know i don't do
i don't do rant when i talk to
when i mean emacs dev or talk to other
people
or polite and i'm suggesting you know i
can i could
because i've been writing i've been
reading and writing uh manuals for
for all my life 30 years so i suggested
you know i can
rewrite the emacs manual i tell you i
tell him what's you know what the
problems i see
you know what's his response very
typical just like uh hello
you know he he says oh why don't you
um you know why don't you work on that
and send me the result
uh and i'll look it you know so
so what he's saying you know in practice
what that means
i spent three months to re to try to
rewrite it the emacs manual
send it back to him having me review and
say whether it's a goal or not
and and and and that's what he suggests
you know
that it's like the great spirit of the
free software
communism you know we help each other
oh yeah you know [ __ ] him
and i know what the result will be if i
spend three months to rewrite the
entirety of the emacs manual or send it
to him
basically back and forth and the
you know three-month dedicated you know
full-time work
how how much that how much you get paid
at google
if it's facebook or microsoft or any
tech company
meanwhile i if i do that i contribute i
get nothing
and even barely barely almost no mention
in the emacs
um acknowledgement you know
when people you know let me ask you guys
who country who who made all this work
in past 10 years in emacs
oh most of you i mean
great most people will say oh richard
stowman nobody else
the [ __ ] [ __ ] richard stolman
he takes all the credit he becomes and
in the past years he
you know in 1980s and 1990s he's a
and even in in early 2000s he's a great
guy with a vision you know free software
you know the and
open source they they are valid opinions
you know as far as licensing goes you
know it's a
valid alternative to the commercial uh
system but in the past 10 years
he has become no good
and also the open source has become
an ideology that created the monster
facebook google controls everything
every aspect
and if you are a programmer you have no
power at all you have nothing no power
at
all the open source roughed all your
power
the only thing you can do is go work for
google and they can fire you
fire you anytime you want anytime you
say same something they don't like
such as men are different from women
they
they fire you at at will that's what the
open source done to us
and many of you people many my you know
my followers
even my followers they they they still
open source phonetics
like every time you use something
they'll tell you oh you need to open
those use this
[ __ ] head anyway so
so hello says back to hello's comments
yeah so richard snowman requested you
know you describe the picture to him
instead of sending the screenshot
reading how he used the internet on his
website made me
yeah facepalm yeah richard snowman
um
goes from zero to one hundred and two
seconds when you attack
geekers okay hello uh long time without
come to this channel
attached hey um you know you guys
you know i'd like to uh know you guys or
meet you guys
uh but after a while i forgot you know i
cannot keep up so
so if you join the discord you know i
have a discord you know
you you chat there every day then we can
this is better way to know each other
because you are there you post
opinions on different things so uh
you know i have a hard time remembering
where you guys are i used to ask you
where you guys are and you know showing
that but
um
okay that's it it's that's a long talk i
think that's a
big long talk let me finish
okay so earlier you had the path to your
oak file
inside your html right yeah so that's my
emacs blog
so let's um go to my emacs blog
magnify so here's the oak file
and you open the file just like that oh
i can you know so there's a command
let me show you okay so you look at the
pink window oh the pink window is good
so let's start command log mod okay
so here's the pink window you can see
all my commands
uh wait so let me move around so you see
my commands there let me shrink it
okay so if i want to open this file i
just put a cursor here
then ctrl c i mean space cu
space cu you open the file so the
command is
open file at kuza and you can look it up
that's on my website you can see the
source code
and that's that is basically a improved
version
of the find file at point that's a bod
command
find file at point it's an improved
version because when you call find file
a point it will
it will prompt asking you to confirm
very annoying so with the open file
acoustic you don't have to confirm you
don't have to are you really sure
are you sure you want to open this is
the file you want to open this
idiotic so you you know you
you know so so that's uh so that's that
command
uh looking into something like his hello
the most efficient keybinding on the
planet i don't think
it's a soft light key so it's another
function
okay he didn't even even have the file
selected i thought it was
cool okay paul it was in the in the
previous video
shows his knowledge and shows the
function going between the web page and
source
thank you guys thank you bye my
tutorials okay you you can
if you like my stuff if you like my buy
my
uh donate paypal and stuff you know
where to go
buy my emacs tutorial emac list tutorial
and
also javascript in depth thank you guys
bye
okay so thank you guys bye
super from discord so hello you are
super
you