good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show
today we are going to do
coding okay lots of coding we are going
to do
find and replace or unix grip and set in
wolfram language emac bisp golden python
pearl and powershell so i'm going to
demonstrate a find and replace code in
all these languages but mostly i'm going
to code we are going to code wufam
language uh live to write a find and
replace
script
so uh video check audio check so let's
get ready and ready to go so good
morning alan alan is back
and uh good morning huang so let's so if
you have questions ask me okay uh tag me
and ask me so
let's begin um
yeah let's um so today's i think it's
pretty fairly technical ff stray
good morning so okay so we are let's do
this um
but good morning but
finally you back
okay so we are going to you know let's
do quick uh quick let's do technical
okay so on the pink window i'm using
stuff like keys and this is my keyboard
cone this is advantage too and ultimate
hacking and you can see
uh you just go search for exactly
keyboard blog and you can see the
reviews and names of all my keywords
okay you go then buy it from my amazon i
highly recommend
okay so
so that's my keyboard um
[Music]
so yeah so we are going to do coding so
let's let's start now okay
no nonsense no nonsense coding so this
is a contin continuation of yesterday's
video yesterday we started to talk about
uh find and replace and grab you know
so okay so first of all let me show you
so let's demo okay so go so go to emacs
blog
i mean go to my emac emacs blog you can
see in this directory
logo emacs okay
let's turn on global highline mod so you
can see where is my cursor okay and on
the pink window you can see all my emacs
command cores
aside you know for example i move cursor
you can see all the commands and
keystrokes
uh it'll show up there in the pink
window and also
i'm using a vorack
keyboard layout okay so in this
directory you can see in this directory
uh web logo emacs there is there are
so we did part of this yesterday but
let's uh let's
you know you'll get interesting okay so
here is um
the
powershell
recurse
include let's see how many html files
are there okay so here is all the html
files in this directory and now
let's count
pipe it to measure so there are 200
uh html files in this directory okay so
now let's uh start to do find and
replace so first first stop i'm going to
show you emaclis so this is the emaclist
package so i'm just gonna do it okay so
call the command okay the command name
is called xsa find
uh
okay exa find replace text we are not
going to use regular expression in this
case there is also a regular expression
version but let's just do this because i
find replace okay correct let's replace
all the word haskell
by
the word emac these you can see at the
bottom okay
and it asks you which directory so ogo
emacs directory that's correct
and it asks you a regular expression for
file path to filter file path
so you want to say dot html dollar sign
that's all html files file names ending
html
okay so it asks you a the depth
so something this emac list command has
a feature
that lets you do find and replace only
on a specific
depth of directory a range of it so
starting from zero and you know all the
way to depth nine okay
and right change to file no fixed case
in search yes fixed casing replacement
yes
make backup yes okay now it's running
it's uh you know the most time spent is
actually the disk disk speed is the
bottleneck bottle neck and i have a um
flash drive you know i have a you know
how they call it solid state drive so
it's much faster than before so anyway
so here is the result you can see
you can see
the pink lines are files
that contains the word haskell and each
of the yellow highlight is the
occurrence so we can enter and jump to
the file so you can see
so let's jump to let's jump to the first
one okay
so
press press arrow key or tab to go to
you know you you can press arrow arrow
or
i prefer uh red arrow uh previous arrow
left arrow to jump among the
occurrences so the first occurrence is
this one
under this file so okay so you can you
just press enter it will jump to the
file so
so here's the file showing browser you
can see there is a word haskell there so
that's one occurrence now this is the
file in browser then let's just search
for
john so there it is so that's the
currents of haskell
and remember we want to replace all the
word haskar with the word emac lisp
so
it didn't happen because we said you
know right to file no we just want to
see what happens so you see so here is
uh you know
so that's a demonstration of the emac
list
uh version code for find and replace
very powerful very convenient fantastic
i recommend you if you like it
buy my software okay so let me let me
show you where that is
uh describe key press the key
so here is the source code for soft fine
in emac list
so
there is 700 lines of code
and
here is a home page so go to it show in
browser so this is the emacs find
replace in pure emac list okay so you
like it pay me okay i send it to you so
let's e-mac this version now let's
demonstrate some other versions
but so far we can see you know you can
see what um
you know what files it found and you
know let's so let's use this example to
demonstrate
per version golden version python
version powershell version okay so first
so yeah okay let's do that so close that
close that close that close that let's
go to uh
today's talk show open so here's a
today's talk show we demonstrated find
replacing emac lisp now let's
demonstrate powershell okay so go to
powershell
so current directory um
the you know
if you want to know the current
directory the keyword is pwd it's a 80s
with a unix convention but you can also
um
current location i believe the full um
i forgot what's the full command name
but you what you can do is uh help pwd
that that will tell you the full command
name so the foot connect command name is
get location so you see so
clear pwd shows you the current path
which is you know ergo emacs so you can
see you oh you can
say
get
location
oh get local get location get
and
location
you see it's the same thing and if you
want to find all the aliases of this
command cam complete that's what it
called you do get ads
or gl
then
definition
then you say get location okay
then it will tell you all the aliases
for this command get location which you
have gl and pwd so you see gl pwd they
are the same thing
okay so anyway that's a digression so we
are in this directory that's what i'm
trying to say so we are in this
directory now we let's use powershell to
do find and replace
for
for the 2500 files in this directory
recursively okay so how do you do that
okay the
recurse
and like before we want include
star html that's a
glob
match that means all files ending in the
name html
and we want to
um
pipe it to okay so um
we did this yesterday but i'm still
pretty newish to powershell
so let's uh let's let's code it here
in e-max so powershell
okay
put it here so start this is xr
powershell mod so it lets you um
edit powershot code very nice convenient
and you can of course
powershot mod you can buy you can find
it on the web
support me
okay so and it's open open source by the
way okay so
now let's do the so find replace code in
powershell how do you do it so you pipe
it to
uh for each okay the percentage sign
means it's a shortcut for four each okay
so for example let me show you gl get
ideas gl is the edius for get alias so
you say definition then you say uh for
each
object then you can see you see
percentage sign is alias for for each
object it's a very convenient short so
that's what that is
so let's magnify so that's um
so now you pipe it for each for each of
the you know html file you want to gc
um wait gc gc means get content okay the
full name is get content i'm just going
to use abbreviations because it's more
convenient so get content
dollar sign underscore that means the
current you know the current file so get
content dollar sign underscore let's put
them in a parenthesis then you say
replace replace this operator for string
so then this is a fine string
and
you put
replace
string here okay so the fine string is
going to be
uh haskell
okay the replace string is gonna be
emaclis okay so get content all the
content and do a replace operation
replace haskell by
okay then
then you need to so once you get the
content you did you do the replacement
you need to write back to the file so
so now we
pipe it to out file
out file is a command that writes to
file so out file
uh
so
help of file so powershell has you know
just like man
just like in unix you man something
you know there's a online documentation
so here's online documentation for our
file
you press enter so
magnify
let's go back so
so out file
sends output to file um
uh you we want you utf-8 encoding we
want let's let me just do it okay let me
just do it quickly
no new lines and
confirm with okay with this one of the
important thing i guess okay that
doesn't matter let's do this okay
so write output to file and what's the
file path so you do make me so you do um
dollar sign underscore that's a current
file
and you want to dot
full name so powershell they work by
object everything in powershell is a net
object
you see when you do
you know when you do um
when you do this kind of thing you know
it shows at least all the files it's
actually object but when it displays it
it turns them into a string that's why
you
that's how
it becomes like string like that so this
is unlike unix where everything is just
string so in powershell everything is
actually.net object so so right now we
output to file we want to write to file
the current file name then dot full name
what's a dot phone name because remember
because it's object so object has
methods and properties okay so full name
is one of the property okay i'm not
going to go into details but if you
if you want to know i have a full
powershell tutorial you can learn all
about
for example object type what's the
object what's the object type how do you
find the properties how do you find the
methods okay so just search for
the powershell tutorial you'll learn the
details okay so back to here find
replace code so
so i believe that's it okay so
so but i'm not sure
because once you run this command you
it's actually going to do the find
replace and write to file so but i want
this is my website so i want to be
careful so i want to say dash what if
okay so so the what if thing
the what if thing
means don't do it just show what happens
okay so this is the code copy it back to
powershell paste it
now pray to god this works
do it
okay fantastic seems like it's working
okay
[Music]
okay so actually so it's actually
doing the find and replace on all files
out there
you can see
so you see it's actually trying to do
the find replace on
2500 files
you see what if performing the operation
output to file on target this path you
know it's doing fine replacing all these
files
and uh
yeah so if i remove the what if it's
going to actually do it
uh but this is not a good we uh
we need you know if we are actually
going to write a find and replace script
this is not
this script needs modification because
you don't want to actually
do the replacement on every file you
only want to
do it on the on those files that
actually contains the word haskell
okay
but this would work because this would
work also because
you know if the file doesn't contain
haskell it's just the same you just
writing the same file to itself but it's
inefficient so if we really want to
improve it we need to
um
let's think about how we're going to
improve it so
so we
if we really want to improve it let's um
let me try a little bit today mostly we
are going to try uh we are going to code
wufang language so it's gonna take a
while so let's put so let's
don't spend too much time here
comments oh z trunk crazy good morning
so many
so questions ask me okay tag me
so disney's how do you force yourself to
do stuff when you don't feel like doing
it do you have some secret technique
that helps you focus on the current task
even if you don't feel like working on
it
okay that's uh that's a different topic
okay that's not programming but that's
about that's a that's essentially about
personality which is uh
okay we are digressing but basically it
that's about
a very general topic of how do you you
know focus your personality and habits
okay
basically mostly
mostly interest is the most important
thing okay if you have an interest or
desire
for certain things you will always just
do it you don't need someone to tell you
oh you gotta do you gotta study you
gotta you know do something you don't
need because there's a
strong interest
so
for nuts for many of us it's programming
we just have to you know do programming
for me you know for me there was also
mathematics
and uh
sex okay pornography
okay so anyway
so but you know then you read about
business people you know seven habits
for successful people
most you know
yeah you can try to read those but i'm
old you know i'm 202
so anyway so interest is the most
interesting thing but the then you have
the question how do you get the interest
how do you that depends on you that
depends on lots of reasons depending on
your personality even depends on your
dna depends on your
your environment your parents what you
know how you grew up
for example a lot
mathematicians
engineers physicists
or programmers their dad is also some
kind of programmer or engineer so
you have your family so anyway so
so interest
how do you
get those interests and also depends on
what you want to do do you really you
know for example lawyers many successful
people lawyers businessmen politicians
you know
politicians
they don't want they they have no
interest they have no desire they don't
want
you know had to have an interest in
programming you know if their son is
learning programming they they're gonna
stop it they're gonna try
so
so there's also depending on what you
actually desire but then then you have
the issue of
then then there's a question so if you
are interested in particular
but right now
for whatever reasons you don't have you
know you don't you don't
you you don't seem to be able to get
yourself into you know to do that every
day how do you
solve the problem well you
social engineer so yeah okay social yeah
so you you try to hang around with
people you you know who
who
you think you like you know who are your
idols so like me okay you watch my
videos
will learn more about coding your your
maybe start to get interested in
you fascinating okay anyway digression
okay so let's back to the
to this uh so
so we are going to we are we are writing
a uh find and replace script in
powershell and right now we are
successful but the curve is not
efficient so we want to modify it by
by first of all doing a grep
so you want to find the files that
contains the word first then do the find
replace on those files then write to
file okay so anyway i'm gonna i'm not
going to write it
because today we i want to write a
wolfram language code so
so um so
show today's talk show okay that's
powershell code
so we demonstrated emaclis we
demonstrated powershell let's let me
demonstrate golan okay so i'm just
trying to quickly demonstrate some of
the
uh
okay
so here is a script
what's going on it takes so long so here
is a script in golan
this script is
lines of code this is golan and this
will do finally replace so how does it
work
so i wrote this in 2009 2019 wow okay
uh i'm thinking it's must be early oh
this is a 2019 version i must have
written this earlier so if you want the
code you can go to my website just
search for saudi golan finance replace
so here's a code okay
and i tell you what's a few so let's
demonstrate let's shut up and
demonstrate okay so
so here is the input so what directory
you want to do find replace that one
what kind of file name okay dot html
download sign that's a html file right
to file uh true okay let's change it to
force i don't want to write to file
because this is my website backup true
backup suffix okay that that
and the to skip so of course you can
skip certain directories so you can you
have this feature in this
in in this code so there are certain
directories you can for example dot git
if a directory path match is not get
that means skip you can add you know you
can add more here
so and this so here is a list of files i
mean sometimes you want to do find
replace only on very specific set of
files not the whole directory so you can
put that here if you put that here you
can you know you can
for example let's let me show you okay
so emac leaves let's say i want to find
replace these files only okay not any
other so copy the file path that's the
emac list command
uh you can see copy current um
you see that's my command copy console
copy file path you can find the code on
my website so suppose you only want to
find those files okay so let's paste the
path here
and look and watch this powerful command
okay i press the three keys
and it becomes that each one becomes a
string and with a comma at the end so so
this is the
goal line syntax for a list of strings
okay in a slice you know array okay so
now
for example let's format it okay
uh so again i'm okay so let's go format
okay go format it
okay now it looks you got indentation so
yeah okay so you got these files but
actually in this
you know we want to do the find replace
on all directories so here is the find
replace pair you have the find string
and replace string okay
and then rest of it is the actual code
so let's run it
okay so let's okay write to file force
okay run it and that command is solvent
current file okay that's the emax
command so here is the output so it
so this
version in gold line is simpler you know
remember in the emac list version
it also prints out the actual currencies
but for the golden version i only print
out the
changed files so there are these files
that changed
so um
you know so you can but actually right
to file is false so anyway that's a
demonstration of the golan
script for find replace okay so close it
uh let's change it back to true okay
close it close it so we demonstrated
powershell go lan let's do a python one
okay
so
so python okay so i have returned
because you know i do find replays for
the past like 20 years every day on
thousands of files so over the 20 years
over the past 20 years i've written many
find with replace scripts in different
languages
so here is a here is a python 3 okay
there's a regular expression version and
there's a plain text version so let's
open the plain text version so this is a
python 3 code for find and replace
so again
you can specify a list of files
and directory okay so the directory
needs to change okay so
the directory needs to be
that that okay so here is the you know
that's a directory so comment that out
input
okay then
and again in the python version you can
specify a level the depth of the
directory okay so let's say just leave
it so regular expressions for the file
name okay print file name with no change
force
backup file name extension okay
do backup true okay
then what do you want to find okay we
want to find
pascal the word pascal by
elise okay
make sure
make sure the write to file is false
okay so
because i don't want
screw up my
website
uh where is the right to file
option
do back up back of print file name with
no change file name wait wait
i don't have a write to file option
okay uh
yeah so if we comment this out then it
will not write to file
so this script began in 2006 around
there okay so this python script because
in 2006 that's the that's where i
started to learn python
so output file open so wait and let me
make sure i haven't i haven't coded
python for a long time
you know once i started to use emacly
spangolan i don't use the python script
anymore
so let's check file name request print
file when no change backup file name
backup this order so there's no
right to file option
so okay so you just need to change the
code so this function
replace string in file
number okay first of all you replace
them you get the content and do the
replacement then you write to file so um
let's just comment them all out okay
that should be it let's just run it
run it
okay there is there it is your results
so python you see it tells you how many
occurrences for each file so there's
three occurrences in this file
okay
so this is a python
3 version of find and replace again you
can find the code by
there okay
now let's revert this and
okay so
find and replace in python
okay now i have also a version in perl
so
um in perl yeah so but hold on a second
let's go back to talk show because i
want to
create the links here
so here's a python version
and
here's the golan version copy it
so golen python
powershell
and we are going to demon
demonstrate pearl okay so
so pearl version
dot pl so there it is this is a pearl
version of find replace
is it getting boring so pearl find
replace so it's also on my website copy
the
file path
paste it here
there it is go go land python pearl okay
so let's
now let's
run the code
okay so here is the pearl code pearl is
the earliest i wrote it this in 2000
year 2000 okay
so
uh directory so let's find the directory
copy the file path
so here's the file path
so we need to
modify this
okay so comment that out input the path
uh
backup
okay the this you know so this script is
20 years old i have not used this script
for
15 years
uh so now
it says backup to this directory
so it actually you know back then i have
a different concept of where do you put
the backup
so no you know normally you create a
backup in the same directory of
the file but here the idea is that you
create the backup in a separate
directory or in an entirely new
directory
um
so i'm not sure um
let's see so
so let's say xy backup you know i want
to be careful because otherwise it's
going to override lots of my files
can
okay so also i'm not sure
oh if it doesn't exist it will be
created okay this is a good quality of
code
you see you can you can just type any
director you if it doesn't exist even
nested okay even nested
so let's try nested
you'll just create it okay so
now here's the find and replace string
okay again you can have multiple find
replace string so we want to find
haskell we want to replace by elisp okay
then you can have another pair and
another so
you know that's all
golan python they all you know my script
will support that
so okay so this is a find and replace
pairs
then
do i want to use regular expression no
okay so you just say zero
uh and skip large file size so if you
have you know some files that
a few hundred megabytes you can skip it
okay that's uh that's it i haven't run
perl code for you know for 10 years so
this this is gonna be interesting let's
see
wait
where does it say i don't want to
actually write to file
you know i i don't want actually to
write to file so there's again there's
no option that says don't write to file
um
so that means i have to comment out the
right to file part
do i make sense
so let me read the comments i think we i
you know
is it good is it
am i doing good you know i've been
talking a lot but today
i want to code wufang language
so okay 12 38 i already talked for
40 minutes and we haven't begun to code
wufang language yet
okay so anyways it doesn't matter so
interesting question okay i'm curious
about these two politicians one of
program society social engineers
switched to goal line recently never
used python again indeed that's that's
my sentiment as well golan is a better
language in
python it's superior in
many ways in almost every way the only
exception is that golan
golan
writing the same program
in golan it would be
about
1.5
about 0.
0.5
more number of lines so for example in
gold in in python something is 100 lines
in gold land it will be 150 or 130
something somewhere around there okay so
the factor the multiplication factor is
1.5 so goal line is more
you have you need more code
mostly template code especially you know
golden because
you need to write lots of this error
checking code that you know you have to
because the language enforce it you know
usually it's annoying so python is
actually slightly higher level
but however every other aspect gold line
is better than python golin is
golan's libraries is far better than
python the building libraries
golan's documentation
for the language and for the library is
far better than python the python
okay they refuse to change the python
people you know
the golan okay golan is also easier to
learn than python easier because the
syntax the grammar is actually much uh
fewer okay simple goal line is very
simple easier to learn than python
goal line is also faster than python
because skolan is
considered low level kind of low level
in in the class of cc plus plus okay
it's that's that's their that's what
they are designed for golan
while python is more or less considered
a scripting language you know python
pearl ruby bash you know it's a high
level scripting but go so goal line is
much faster you know
two times three times faster than python
and go line can be run as a script as
well so for example we just we just did
you know goal line find replacing go lan
you know but not like c or c plus plus
or java or c sharp you have to compile
it you have to compile it get a binary
code then you execute that and that's
you know i don't like i don't like
low-level languages so golan support uh
you know you can just run the code
directly so it's like us
it's like a scripting language okay so
so golan
faster than python also um
you can use it like a scripting language
no compile you don't need to compile it
and golan just like cc and c plus plus
golan
you can if you want to you can compile
your code
get a binary block your software and you
can sell it okay you can you can send it
to your friends and your your friends
can run the code
not for python not for python pro
on
ruby you know
for python your friends you send him
your script your friend needs to install
python you need the python your engine
but not golden golem can just like c can
compile into a you know a
binary blot and blob and your friend can
run so golan in my opinion is
superior than python in
you know in almost every way so
anyway so okay so uh this is uh
typescript let's go back to golan okay
we were talking about
pearl yeah okay so you know pearl is
kind of dead now
okay so let's comment out the right to
script part
i don't i don't remember pearl
um
so um
so process file so actually the
indentation is too long
and this is you know this is 20 years
old code
uh so what i want to do is
the opening file and write to file so
so here is
the opening file part right right out
right output to file
uh
if not open
die error you know pearl has these
characteristics you know they like to
say die you know they are the unix
phonetics idiots they are the you know
they are into the unix philosophy
with lots of puns and you know they
think it's fun so they say die
you know if
you know something something if it
doesn't work then die error opening file
so i guess i
comment this up make a backup
comment this out comment this out
comment this out
okay i'm not even sure this will work
because
this is very old
code
let's just run it okay let's just
let's hope it will not screw up my
website
but before we do that
let's go to um
um
okay let's let's let's git commit okay
so we can kind of
get status okay get
add
can we do that yeah do that
do it
git commit
okay so we have i have commented my
website
so in case we the pearl screwed up my
website i can revert
okay back to the perl script
let's run the code shall we
so logo emac directory
replace haskell by emac let's run it
let's see what happens there it is
processing oh uh there it is
so the pearl output let's see
okay so it actually you see
so the power output is processing for
each file it's reading you know
it you know processing processing you
know 2
500 files okay processing and go let's
go down
okay then
okay then it says to replacement made
for this file okay then processing
processing then one replace
replacement made for this file okay this
is
okay
okay so yeah so there's lots of you know
intermix so then at the end it says
total files changed
the following large files are skipped
okay there are several okay
mp4 you know
movie files okay richard stowman
videos
so this anyway
so that's a demonstration of find
replace code in perl
okay
so let's remove let's comment you know
remove our changes to the file so
okay that's uh
that's demonstration of pearl code
close it
okay now we are going to now we are the
main topic
how do you write a faint replace in
wolfen language the main topic let's go
to talk show
wait my
syntax coloring is screwed up
why is that
oh i missed you i up yeah
let's see
okay
yeah
so now
the main show
writing
a find replace script in wufam language
okay
okay so how many people do i have
the paucity of my youtube watchers
so let's see how many people do i have
watching
we need to go to um
concurrent viewers three
okay so now golan wufang language okay
you know i have the wolfram language
here
okay so what do you need to do in order
to write a find and
find and replace script okay
let's uh let me show you
the main things you need to do
for writing a find replace
script okay
the okay first of all you need to
walk
a directory okay
you need to you know go through a
directory and find recursively
basically we we want to order
subdirectories so that's
that's what you need to know how to do
in a
language okay
then
open file
get content of the file okay that's the
second thing you need to do
let's make them a list okay
then the third thing
to find and replace a given
big string okay that's what you need to
do
then you need to know
how to write to a file okay
that's the
showing browser that's the four things
you need to know in order to write a
find and replace script
okay now let's see
let's you know i haven't done any text
you know i haven't done any text
processing type of programming in wufang
language
you know i've been coding wufang
language for about 20 years you know
mostly 1990s
1993 to 19 1993 to 2005 every day so
over 10 years
but
mostly it's
you know it's mathematics visualization
geometry
it's not text processing like the
javascripts
so this is the first time
i'm going to do
text processing muffin language it would
be interesting uh that's why
so
let's begin three plus two
okay let's magnify
okay so
so first of all so you need to walk a
directory um
you know i'm thinking i don't know if i
can finish this it will take me
30 minutes to one hour
i mean also because i'm doing you know
because i have to talk and explain
uh
so i don't know if i can actually finish
it
but um
so but anyway these are the things we
need to find out how to do walker
directory recursively open file get file
content
to find new face of a given big string
okay string okay so let's see string
first of all let's see interesting
things string functions
um let's see
what
wait i don't i don't get why is that
do i like cats what kind of question is
that
all right
so let's list all the string functions
first of all
so we need
so first of all let's do
let's find out how do you replace a
string in language
so here is all the string functions
ah okay i'm not sure
i'm doing well am i
where is my drink i need to get a drink
uh
forgot to bring my drink
uh i need to finish this because i know
other people you know
after
the live stream other people will you
know there are few hundred people will
find it interesting they actually
okay then i need to uh focus on what are
we what am i going to do so
i'm going to write the wolfram language
find string am i going to do it
yes okay let's do it
it might take 30 minutes or an hour okay
but let's do it i need to get my drink
i need to okay let's
let me get a drink and let's do it okay
i'll be back in one minute
comments guys comments chat
if you haven't already join
xl discord
interesting people okay
and on the keyboard front this is
uh wait can you see that oh yeah so this
is uh exposed this is fantastic i'm
going to review
i'm going to do a review of the xposed
natural i mean the exposed knight
keyboard
xpose is one of my favorite keyboard you
know it's fantastic
and i'm also going to do a review of the
new kinesis that's coming up
okay back to code i think uh
back to code let's see what this is
discord
turn it off
um
okay woofing language
okay wolfen language now first of all
let's see how do you to find and replace
strings
there it is string replace okay
string replace so here's the
documentation and string replace um
let's see there are three related
functions okay string replace string
replace okay let me let's let's do this
okay
so here are the functions we need let's
see
okay so street okay so let's let me do
okay so let's go to emacs
so let's start showing browser
let's start a multi-language mod
okay
and so you are looking at
you are looking at xsa
the ufam language mod so i can code
wufang language in
emacs
you can get the mod
okay so
pay me okay buy it go buy it so
right now we are trying to find um
okay
let's let's copy so we know what we're
talking about so wufang language
so so this is
okay
we need to do these things
okay so first of all the replace string
functions okay so uh we compute so like
uh
the wolfram language okay i'm not going
to explain what these
these things are but
but these are the functions that it's
relevant okay
so these are the functions that's
relevant so press the key to go to the
wolfram documentation
turn on javascript
okay so let's see do i need to mark
magnets magnify okay so
string repeat
or we don't need to repeat so string
repeat we don't need
string replace
replace okay so
um
string replace string then
then a replacement pair replace the
string expression
whenever it appears okay that's what we
need to do so
the syntax
is
big
big string
then
you need a bunch of rules let's say
big
small okay let's try that if that work
do it
fantastic you see
so that is a function we need but there
are you know there's a lot of features
let's keep reading
so you go you you can also have a list
of rules list of replacement pairs okay
then you can have okay then you can
specify just do the first n replacement
then you can specify
okay then you can apply this to a list
of strings you know like thousands of
files you can do them in one shot this
is you know we are getting into the
power of wufam language i'm gonna tell
you i'm telling you you know i've been
talking about how wufang language is a
magnitude superior than all
out there including any of these closure
commonly skim this including pearl
python ruby including haskell whatever
erlang you know
golan you know c sharp c plus first java
you know
wolfen language is the magnitude
beyond them
as far as the high levelness
because so we are we are talking about
doing a find replace script okay now i
haven't coded text processing in
language before but
however i can tell you it's going to be
one single line okay one single line
not not super long you know it's just
one single line of uh let's say within
200 characters
okay
because you can already see it you see
you can have a list of you know a pair
you know list of pairs for find and
replace just like my code you know these
are pairs you can do them in one shot
but however this one single function
you can also specify a list of sources
you know so
here the first element will be 1000
files content okay
yeah okay so
okay so that's one function now there's
another function let's see how this one
how is this one different
string replace list
okay give a list of the string obtained
by replacing each
okay so it's this one is basically
what does this string replace return
okay so let's see
okay i think it just returns a bunch of
history okay let me show you okay so i'm
okay so
the goal here i mean i'm i'm trying to
write a find replay script in unfamiliar
language but meanwhile
let me just
you know kind of tutorial teach you
about wufang language you know
constructs okay so
so right now we want to know what's the
difference between string replace and
this string replace list okay so in
general string replace this is just a
give you a history of the replacement
let me see
i think so but um
okay so you can have a list of rules
okay so wait let's copy
so
big
replace small and let's see
let's say g let's
let's say um
b
to c
and let's say
to d let's see what happens okay
okay replace all b by c
then replace or c by d okay so you can
see it does not do them in kind of
repetitive way because if
if i mean it does not do them in a
sequential way because if you do them
which is not desired okay so you see you
want to replace all b by c
you also want to replace all c by d
now there are two this is very
interesting about find and replace okay
because it happened to my code as well
you see so if you give this replacement
you want to or occurrence of c
replaced by d
however
if you run them c you see the original
screen does not contain any
c
let's magnify okay
so you see the big string it doesn't
contain c
so
so you see
this is a result which is the desired
result but however if you do a typical
english you know if you code it in
typical way you tends to do finding
and replace sequentially you know for
each pair of the find and replace but if
you do that b becomes c
then c changed to d
so you we you we are actually um
so let me show you what what's going on
okay so maybe i can
do i make sense okay so
let me know do i
so what
what
the other way is uh you know recursion
basically that's not desired okay
so essentially what this is what you
have okay so first of all you do b2c
then
the result you do a c2d okay so for
example let's run this hopefully it runs
you see it becomes dig string which is
usually not what you want
okay so that's a little bit um
you know this this is a very nice touch
you know wuffing language is fantastic
in this kind of ways in many these kind
of ways you know it does what you
actually
want
so anyway so
so we let's go back to what's the
difference okay i can explain okay so
what's the difference between the least
this this one just give you a
um
what
okay for example let's run them
together uh
it returns at least okay uh is that all
okay i think let's go let's move on okay
because we need we have still a lot to
do justin hey justin
scafi we are doing wufan language now
you know which is a language for
mathematics but however it's not but
today we are doing uh text processing
programming text processing
in language
you would be interested in in math okay
and you know so much i can learn from
you
okay f says you know i can already see
the appeal of a language but say but but
uh say the mathematician is hard to get
into that's false okay uh language you
don't have to use it for math it's not
in you know it's actually i would
actually claim it's the easiest
because there's no
irregularity okay you just learn a few
just like lisp okay wolfen language is a
branch
you could say it's a branch of lisp and
apl so
there's no
irregularity you know you just learn a
simple few handful principles and you
know the entire language
you know like we talked about before
python versus pearl you know which one
is easier to learn
go
i mean python versus skull line which
one is easier to learn gold line is much
easier why because it's very simple
there's only few
you know 10 20 constructs then you know
the entirety of the older language
meanwhile python you have lots of
exceptions i mean irregularities like
list comprehension then it's a new
syntax you know a little language within
least comprehension you know then some
of them are then in python some are
functions some are methods then you have
to learn objects you know
there's a lot
inconsistency okay yeah i mean they you
know they don't call it that you know in
inconsistency as well as irregularity in
vast majority of industrial languages
it's
their syntax in semantics is
ad hoc and irregular for example c
c plus plus
java including java c c plus first java
javascript c sharp
uh all these you know essentially pearl
especially pro they you know the syntax
is irregular like there's no one single
principle
you have to learn you know for loop for
loop while loop they are different they
have different syntax then
then then you have four each iterators
which is another syntax you know it's
like that print print you know this is
like the whole syntax you know you have
to each every
construct in a language is a new kind of
a new syntax okay if statement
versus if expression you know entirely
new yeah it's like you know so you have
to learn each one and everyone but
on the other hand this okay this
family of languages closure
scheme racket emac lisp including
mathematica it's one syntax for all for
example in this parenthesis that's all
that's all you need to know a function
parenthesis function argument every code
every code source code in this is like
that okay you don't have to learn
spatial syntax so that's
one of the attraction
of lisp you know very simple syntax same
what's another example of search
language apl okay apl
uh just look up okay uh so apl and uh
tcl maybe okay i'm not too familiar with
tcr but anyway my point is that
in
the syntax design of programming
languages
there is a
you know you could say there is one
philosophy where
you
only have
a handful of very simple constructs the
entire language syntax is based on that
you don't have to learn extra okay
so this
mathematica wufan language apl is like
that okay
on the other hand you have
you know syntax design you have like c c
style c style c java c plus plus java
javascript pearl python yeah including
python
they
almost every construct is a is a you
know it has its own syntax you know so
so about wufam language i would say you
know it's actually
uh
easy to learn
however you have the perception it's
hard well only because you are familiar
you know with c
style because c you know sees the virus
it spread and spread to all languages to
go land to rust you know it's basically
the it's kind of the
conventional syntax so everyone get used
to it
that's what that's why i call that's why
that's that's why i say unix and c
is the m is a like a criminal in
programming industry they they are like
viruses they spread bad ideas over
because they are free because they are
the fastest okay that you know they they
they use these kind of tactics you know
have intentionally have you know
innocently you know like
so basically they have these qualities
they they push they spread like like
drugs like a virus to all the entire
programming industry so today for most
people when they see languages you know
c c plus plus c sharp java python ruby
uh pearl you know they think oh that's
normal that's that's that's how things
should be
then when they see mathematica wufang
language you know uh these they think oh
that's weird that's difficult actually
that's a it's a reverse
you know
you you you think it's weird only
because you you know all the people get
used to the bad concept of c okay see
that's why i
truly despise the c and unix
uh okay so back to wufang language so we
um
i need to finish uh so we are continue
coding the
find and replace script
talk guys are you still here how many
people four people
all right talk say something
so let's
let's let's let's continue let's push on
let's finish the find use and replace uh
script in wufang language
okay and okay so we know how to do find
string
find and replace string now
but however does the find replace string
do regular expressions that's what i
want to know but anyway that's not
important today it
um
what is string expression
so where is the
regular expression you know there is
regular expression but i
i don't know it's one of these
let's let's go to um
let's search the web okay wufang
language uh regular expressions okay
so that's what you have to do
yeah
so
xsa
language mods so you have uh you know
press the tab
uh iegu okay okay press tab you have
completion okay regular expression um
okay so here is a regular expression
from language
okay that's how you do it okay so here
this represents rejects for example dot
html for example the file path ending in
html would be that
okay
so that's a regular expression in from
language
now
now we need to know
how do you traverse the directory okay
let's see
okay let's try the find and replace
string let's try the regular expression
let's remove the
remove the complexity okay
let's do this so now let's
let's use a regular expression here
so
okay so there's some let's say
filename.html
now we want to use regular expression to
replace it by okay let's let's get fancy
with the
rejects okay so
anything
anything not
a literal dot one or more
so that represent the file name
oh actually let's let's just do
uh a2 z okay
a to z with underscore and dash okay
so one or more then dot html
not a plus okay then replace it by
we replace it by
the last
capture
dot
w-w-l move and language okay we'll find
language actually let's start m okay
so let's try this okay so you see
i think it'll work
do it
okay so
yeah so this needs to be slash slash i
think
okay that doesn't work so the capture
pattern
so you need to find out how do you
represent the capture
so you see the regular expression in
wufang language is actually
generalized okay
so it's not just uh you know it's
actually more powerful
so how do you do capture
how do you represent the captured
pattern okay oh g there
within a regular expression string
backslash gn represent the substring
matched by the nth parenthesis okay so
okay so
so here it is so let me show you
so we want to replace by another regular
expression let me copy it so you can see
what we are changing
okay
so we use stream replace
on the on this screen filename.html
and use regular expression that and to
replace by that okay let's see how if
that works
okay
not
incorrect so it's it's not correct so
uh how do you
stream match how do you replace string
with regular expressions string replace
so string replace
so easier example where they use regular
expressions
oh there it is so here is the example of
string replace with regular expressions
but however the replacement string
[Music]
we need to capture we need an example
where the replace string
contains a captured pattern
[Music]
let's see
see
let's try that
oh
double sash i think
what's wrong click
string expression regular expression
okay so this is
okay i don't know
so let's let's go to tutorials
okay we are kind of staggering
stagnate
we stuck here character range
regular expression oh there it is
string cases wait okay so
backslash backslash one
right okay so backslash backslash yeah
you need i think i think you need to
backslash
why is it
no
oh dollar sign oh yeah okay dollar sign
that's right
so we this should be a dollar sign
instead
okay so i think i think i know what's
going on so
there it is that worked okay so let's
modify this so
okay so let me show you what's the
proper
so here is the proper code
so you just you know you have a big text
here
then you use a regular expression then
you the replace string is just a simple
string with dollar sign representing the
capture fantastic
okay
fantastic so that's how you do regular
expression in um
okay so we got that
okay so regular expression
okay
next
we want to know
so now we know
now we know how to do find and replace
next we need to know
how do you open the file okay
so let's let's go wufang language open
file okay
okay so here is the wolfram language
help documentation
read stream
read string
write string read line
okay so
files okay
restring right string
okay restring
restring and file name okay let's try
that
okay restrain a file path okay
okay that's a long file path let's see
if that works
fantastic
okay so this is the file content this is
how you read a string in wufang language
read string
but now you can see there's some unicode
problem because i have a unicode so you
need to specify
the file content is encoded in unicode
so let's see if the these are options
for read stream
okay it's kind of long so let's say
options
read string
time constraints infinity okay there's
no
there's no option about reading them as
unicode utf-8
that's okay so
that's a issue we need to actually it's
critical we need to solve
you know we can kind of skip this
because you know you might think oh most
of the files source code is just asking
not today you know not today today you
have lots of emojis you know in common
in any way or arrows you know
emojis or arrows um
you know
anywhere in your source code
so
you want to make sure
that when you open a file you are using
the correct encoding
otherwise chinese characters russian
characters they all got screwed up
so
so here is how you write to file
okay let's copy that right to file
okay so here's how you write to file
file path and string
but how do you deal with encoding
so
okay file
file function is a symbolic
representation of a location in a local
file system okay
now does this have
encoding option
creation date last access date
by account rob raw raw by account
permission device uid gi dsid owner name
so it represents a file
in the unix tradition of metadata
okay these are the unix tradition of
metadata
but i don't see any encoding yeah you
know we need to
uh
okay file operations
and see file operations copy file
rename file delete convert
file format file byte count
okay
so
we don't know how to you know
how to make sure the encoding is correct
okay but
let's worry about that later
now we run into directory which is what
we one of the things we need to do we
need to know how do you traverse the
directory okay so here are
uh i think here we are leaders to it
directory so
how to traverse a directory
so directory
queue is true or false
okay
directory uh wait
directory operational file names file
operations
directories and directory operations
okay
so
current kernel directory notebook
directory reset directory
parent directory
print out the directory part of the full
name okay directory part of the name
file name join file name split
okay so
we need to know given a directory we
need to it to list all the
subdirectories in it
set directory okay so
create rename copy delete
so manipulate manipulating files and
directories
got the you know ufm language has 6000
functions
copy file rename delete file by account
file date
create directory rename directory
maybe you could use file name something
oh yeah okay so that's a good idea file
names
great great suggestion but
yeah let me look around a little bit
more
so read this
read list
byte
record list
word separator
uh
you know so
i'm sure your idea works
so let's see
file name okay
file name okay so let's say
let's let's give her the emac path okay
so emacs so just like before
then we use a
asterisk okay that will work i think
oh okay so actually
list of files in the current working
directory
uh
at least all files in your directory
okay that's how that's the syntax okay
so you need to say
okay i hope i think that's
what
why is it
so you need to look at examples and
documentation file names can be given as
literal strings
or
regular expression or string expression
okay let's try this
you know what what what is the
directories actually you know i don't
want it to list all of a sudden all my
you know
all the files on my disk
oh okay i forgot the s okay so yeah
that's right
now fantastic fantastic
there we have it so there it is
2500 files
okay
um
well
1 000 files there in this directory so
yeah fantastic
so file names oh so this gives you at
least let's let's see let's see if it
does actually recursive okay i think it
does
no okay it actually does not recurse
wait but if you put a asterisk does it
then it recurses okay then then okay
fantastic this is yeah so you include
the emacs directory you include also the
you know the miscellaneous yeah you
include all so this is fantastic this is
what we want
okay
you see um okay so
let's write it down okay
this is how you
list all files in the
including subdues okay now there are
probably there are maybe better ways i
mean
you know usually when you code you want
to find the best way i mean you you know
the idiom or whatever you call it you
know the proper way to do it but anyway
anyway we know this works for our
purposes okay let's you know we want to
get this to work so
this works
this will list all directories and
subdirectories you know return a list
you know one of the great things about
wolfram language is that
just like this everything is based on
list
okay so it just returns a whole list
then you can use any of the map function
to just apply functions to everything
so let's put this together okay we will
we are close close uh closer okay
so
so this is how you read the file
then write file let's put it uh down
okay so
and this is how you do find replace and
this is how you do find replace with a
regular expression
and
and you want to do how do you do um
write to fire okay so we need to yeah
right to file
but um
[Music]
let's okay let's skip that first let's
try to put this together let's see if we
can
whoops
let's see if we can put these together
okay so um
yeah this is city
wait uh
so we want to so we got these uh file
names we got all files for each file we
want to read the string okay so read the
string
so each one so we want to map okay so
i'm gonna write this quickly
so function
so that means a pure function okay
so you want to read string of whatever
argument there and you want to map
you want to map this into
all file names okay
so for each file name so this this
return this
you want to read the string
then so you got a list of all the
contents okay so hold on a second so
actually
let's let's say
you know i'm thinking i'm wondering you
know i'm detailing whether i should do
it in a short
syntax
which is
idiomatic which is you know the
more efficient way to coding uh language
or should i use a more
uh standard notation so that everyone
can actually understand what we are
doing
yeah so the best thing is actually use
the standard notation so everyone
understand what we are doing so okay so
it's let's let's
okay so
so let's do this okay file name okay
let's write them in full
so you
so here's a function and takes one
argument file name and here's the
expression
the expression will be
uh read stream okay
restring
the file name
and remove that okay so this is easy to
understand this is we are writing this
is a this is a lambda okay this is what
you call lambda you know in python in
other languages so function
one argument file name and the file and
you read the string okay actually it
should return two things okay i want to
i want it to return two things
one thing is the file name
and the list return a list okay the
first part is the file name the second
part is the actual content okay
um
let's say content okay let's
let's um yeah let's do this okay
ct just means a content function i mean
it doesn't mean anything it just wraps a
ct
word around it
why why do i want to do that because
later on it's easier to
anyway so
so you so you want to map this function
to this so how do you do that the the
normal ways you do this way okay so here
is your function
map takes
two arguments okay three arguments so
this is the first argument the second
argument is the list here
uh
let's
[Music]
god i'm i'm going all over the place so
let me do this okay
read it
okay here's a function okay that's
easier
so files okay
uh files equals to
okay so that's easier so read it it's a
function
then we can
so read it
files
and we don't okay so that's what we do
we
okay so we read the file so we then we
need to do replacement okay so actually
there's a lot more to do so we read it
you know we are i'm writing it right now
in a very verbal sway you know that's
not normally how you how how
i do it but uh
but we you know this is better for
explanation okay so now you have you
assigned to a variable file name and and
content which is a list
each element
is a list of two things the first part
is the file name the second part is the
content of the file okay then
then again you want to map again okay so
um
let's let's do this okay so let's so
this is uh let's say two okay file name
and contents too
so what you do is you
again you map to that
and this this time you want to do a
replacement okay let's let's write
to replace
okay do replace is a function
okay that's right
okay two replacement is a function
the function takes one argument content
okay so
okay and what you do to the content you
replace the content okay so like that
um
so
this time you want to replace um
okay so here here's a content
let's say big text okay
let's yeah well content okay content
then you want to replace the word
haskell
by elise okay is that clear
so here is another function to replace
it takes a
giant text and replace haskell by emac
beast okay
then
then you got the new content okay new
file name and content so we map
we map the do replace command
so actually you need to so here is how
you write it okay you need another
function let me write this in the most
clear way so
people
can understand but you know i i want to
say you know because
it looks
you know uh big because but
normally if i code it you don't have all
these code you know it's it's very
compact but however um
it takes a lot of time to explain what
they are
so
so let's do in the in the most
verbose way
so so again you do you call a map to and
return a new content and this time
the function takes
one argument okay the function takes one
argument
right the argument is the
um
oops
path
and content right the argument is
basically this a list of two items the
first part is the file path the second
part is the content of it
okay so you write a function that takes
that argument
then
then you here you can create a module
which is a local function
uh let me show you what how we are what
we are doing okay so
so
so the first part again remember so
so let me show you okay
so here's the file path
file path will be that
one okay so that means remember the
okay so
do i make sense okay so let me let me do
this
so remember
we are
we are calling the function map okay the
map takes two argument
and this is our first argument which
should be a function
the second argument is a list okay so
that's what it is doing now this
function we are creating it will take
one argument remember each each of the
file name and content is a element is a
list of two things the first part is the
file path second part is the content so
this function takes one argument at
least
now we want to now in inside here we use
a module module is like this sled it's a
local variable it's it's like let okay
so the
module uh whoops what
okay the the module will um
you know let me
the the module okay so we need we need
some kind of a
formatting to make this easy to see
but i hope you are seeing it so the
module the let you know local variable
the path and content okay so the content
will be
you see
the path will be the first element the
content will be second element okay
and now
now we call the do replace function
so we call it do replace function on it
and
we
and it should be content right
so we call it do replace and give it the
argument of the content right so it
returns the new content
so however
the whole re
hold return we want to return like this
okay
so here this is the return value
the return value we actually want
so do i make sense
yeah so the heart of the this function
is just this part it returns a new to it
you know element the first part is the
same path the second part is the new
content okay
okay so that gives us the file name and
content now
we
now we just need to write them back to
write the new content back to the file
path
do i make sense guys
okay this this is uh
close to two hours let's run it okay
let's just run the code
um
okay this is too long i don't want
that okay so
so let's do that let's do that
let's do that
and let's let's just make them one line
you know let me show you okay so
okay ufam language
read it is a function
files it's a list of all files 2500
files file name and content so it's
going to return a giant list
and with every content
of the file
okay some error
cannot open that
because
restring file name
i finally found a
restrict file name
then
files okay then
file name and content read it
function applied to files
so open read cannot open
okay let's do some modification it's
um
let's just say path okay
path
and let's
let's remove that
okay
so read stream file names and this
directory too big let's make let's
try some other smaller directory
that doesn't have
one medium files
okay okay you can see data files excel
go
okay ux keywinding
okay let's try this file this this
directory okay
so in this directory so let's
okay so actually let's show the
empty what
is it empty
but
that works but why is that the other one
empty
show all files wait wait why is that
healthy i don't get it
that also works
but then
all right
okay now it works
uh turns out you don't actually need the
asterisk okay
so you don't need asterisk
so you see this this works okay so this
works now
let's try the need those code
okay so first of all you list the files
then
[Music]
file name and content map read it in
files
oh oh there's a mistake uh
yeah restream path
okay start over
there is the content okay these are
image files that's why okay so yeah
yeah this so these are image files
that's why you get this uh huge thing
okay so
we don't want that
um
you know those are png files
so
so now i want to only limit to html so
let's do this maybe your work
no the asterisk doesn't work
yeah so right now we need to again
filter
okay this is getting um
and i'm getting tired
uh i need to filter so that also
let's look at file names okay file name
there must be some way to filter it form
form one form two
okay form okay so final name let's try
form
there it is okay that's how you do it
form okay so that's
that's how you do it
uh
this is how you read the file so
so that's how you read all html files
only okay
yeah so here
let's
never mind what i'm doing okay i'm just
doing some cleanup
so here so here is the um so here we got
the html files only it turns out there's
only one html file in that directory
which is good
then we map it okay let's try it again
fantastic it contains the content of
that file you know let me show you what
that file is okay so we open the
directory so this is the this this is
the html file we open it you can see
that's a content show in browser this is
a very old article 2005
when i was trying to do unicode in emacs
so this is unicode in mac mac emacs and
text editor year 2005.
okay so that's the that's that
so in language you know it's actually
showing the content that's what exactly
what we want
so each you see each element is the
first element is the
file path the second element is the
entire content of the
file okay
now
now let's replace the word uh let's
replace the word year 2005 by year you
know let's say replaced by something
else so
so now we need to
so do replace is a file name is a so we
replace that word by
um
by year to uh today okay
by that
by year 2021 so here is a function
so let's
let's do this
so those are functions
yeah so the first two are functions then
this this is a list of files in this
file and contents
then new file and contents
let's see
yeah so this is uh i believe our content
is spelled incorrectly so let's fix that
is it
okay so
let's just say big text
so path and big text
okay so
uh write file we don't
we don't care we don't know how to write
file yet so
that
okay so here is the code
let's see if we can make it pretty no
no
okay so we
do it
so did did it actually make the change
let's look at the year 2000 in the title
so
year 2005
no the title wait
yeah so here's a new there it is it
changed you see
year 2021
year 2021 you know the title the you
know the html title
and the html h1
you know so we
so so far the code here
worked okay so the you know this
these few lines of code
now the next step to do is to actually
write to the file okay
but i think i'm you know i'm tired and
let's let's
let's it be that today we we did this
for two hours now
okay
yeah okay so
yeah
okay so
so the next step we have to do is to
write the file basically we are almost
done but so here is uh the woofing code
is basically
uh this okay and plus plus the right
file step
so if we so basically the wolfram code
let's delete that is
is this part okay just how you write to
how you do find and replace to a file
now again like i said before i wrote
this in the most you know beginner way
so you can easily see
you know all the code is of the function
and format so
but there's much better you know
shortcuts which is typically after a
while that's how you code with a
language so let me show you that version
okay
so let's copy it let's do it here
so uh so let me show you how you do that
so instead of this okay let me show you
one by one so you don't do you don't do
that you write
okay uh path okay read string
you'll see in a moment okay
okay that's it so this line is
equivalent to that line okay
now this line is equivalent to um
let me write it okay so
again the function
remove that
so just string replace okay
okay
so this line
is equivalent to this line okay you know
much much more easier to read so
so let's remove the top one remove that
one okay so here we have two functions
okay that's how you write you know
that's the
how you do it
and this line
again uh this time file file names okay
this line no change
uh this line oops
this line okay can be written
okay like that okay so these two lines
are equivalent okay
uh shortcuts so remove that
and this line very long okay so now this
line how do you how do you rewrite it
let me let me show you okay so
uh you don't need all these you know
too long
okay
so
so this line
is equivalent to
this line okay so you know that's how i
mean that's the
power of what's so called
in this
this is called
meta expression okay in this you have
symbolic expression which is s e x p
you know that's a short initial symbolic
expression which is full parenthesis
then you have what's called meta
expression which in this almost never
happened
but it was in the
the concept of the original this
inventor mccarthy
so but in in wufang language it actually
happened implemented that so here
you might call this
symbolic expression but here is the what
this would call
uh
meta expression
now in language
this you don't call that you you kind of
call them full form in the standard you
know standard form anyway
so my point what you know what i'm
showing is that you see okay so let me
comp let's compare okay so let me make
sure it's let's compare before and after
okay
so before
your code
looks like that okay that's before and
after your code looks like that okay and
we can we can try it let's let's try it
and make sure we are correct yeah yeah
so it's correct it returns the it did
the find replace on the new content
uh and uh okay so like i said before
this actually should be one single line
how do you do that let me let me do let
me show you okay
single line it should be just one single
line you don't need all these
you know i'm assigning them to variables
and so on so that it's easier to uh for
beginners to understand
so for example this is a read it
function
uh we don't
you know it happened once so we don't
wait
so just put it here
and this finding replace function
we
don't need it we because we only use it
once
so
remove it
put it here okay
and this this the file function only we
use it once so we don't need the whole
thing there
delete that these two files put it here
okay so now we just now two lines okay
uh you don't need two lines okay because
this is only used once okay so because
yeah so we just
remove that put it here
okay so now it's just single line now
this single line you don't need to you
know what do you need to assign to a
variable so you don't need even need to
assign a variable so this one
single line okay that's wufam language i
don't know if you can see that's move on
language mathematical code let's try it
okay let's try it
do it
uh okay i got the function wrong in my
editing process somewhere
okay so let's fix that
what is going on string
replace oh okay so we um
yeah this is
you know this is bad for my
demonstration because now you got an
error
what is the error part part
specification is longer than depth of
object okay part specification which is
here
which is longer in the depth okay so
okay so
so you need to separate them
so again the map takes two functions so
here is our first function
[Music]
which is
which is this whole thing
and here is our second function okay
uh read string so you don't even need
that so read string
restring
oh okay so i got yeah so i know what you
got what's going on so
yeah so you got you got a mistake i
somehow made a mistake um
okay so that should be the code let's do
it again
fantastic you see it works
and you see in language it has the
feature of auto format so you don't need
to you know press tab or whatever you
make them in generally you make them
into one line okay then you paste it
here ufam will
uh automatically format it in a smart
way for example you can see
a new shrink you know let's highlight
let's highlight this as you shrink
they the code
focus on this okay so let's make a copy
so remember i copy this code go to fram
notebook new notebook
paste it you know one single line now if
your window is wide then it's one single
line if your window is small
it formats in a
sensible way you see
you see it with indent
indentation and all that automatically
you see you can you can widen you know
you see
in a
semantic sensible way okay so it's not
you know random placement of
breaking lines or indentation
okay so here is the entire code for find
and replace in wolfram language okay
just just this line uh except we we
didn't um
write to file so we need actually
how do we
we need to write to file right so we
yeah so we need to actually add another
function so it actually rectifies okay
but that's it for today
maybe it could be shorter yeah you know
there's more ways to make it shorter
because because right now
let's see where is our powershell okay
so let's see you know the powershell is
this but it's not efficient okay let's
compare okay let's let's do you know
wufang language versus powershell which
is shorter okay so let me let me do okay
so this is powershell okay wait
open it uh make it
uh make it powershell mod
yeah okay so powershell mod this is
powershell now wufang language so you
want to be shorter okay so let's um
let me do it okay
so let me do it so
so yeah so so this whole thing you know
so this is just one this single line
okay so
yeah we need the right file somewhere
so let's um okay so the map first of all
you don't need a map okay so you can
let's see where i want it so
yeah so
yeah so you don't need map
all you have to do is that so
yeah read of the map so now we read of
the
so that so that's what it looks like and
also
also um
also this this function you know our
algorithm is actually very redundant
because
you know you we actually created a list
of
each
and every file content you don't need to
do that okay you know
you know we we created at least the
final content
as a inter ring result you don't need
that
it's very inefficient you know so
so uh so remove that okay so
yeah so um
yeah so we don't actually need a map so
we just remove we just place the read
function let me see how you do it okay
yeah so here is a read function
[Music]
yeah so
restream is going to be
removed okay
just read string and
you see we don't need that entire thing
so we
restrain of a file path then do the
replacement okay
so we
we already
okay so
we don't need that we don't need that
and
okay now it's much more simpler okay we
don't we don't need this either so
restream of a file path then do the
replacement
for uh then you yeah you map it to
yeah it's so simple now okay it's just
now it's becoming very simple
so yeah then you yeah so you map that
yes you have to map it then but um
right string okay let's let's put the
right let's yeah actually let's fix the
script so it actually works
uh
also you know right to string so write
to string here
so that's what we need
the file path that's right the file path
there it is
uh the right string so this is a
function
okay so that's that's it
uh that's that
okay
so this
this is the final complete
code for finding and replacing from
language can we try it yeah let's try it
now okay before we try it let me just go
over make sure it's uh correct okay so
the argument the right string restring
takes a path that's right
that's right okay so i i'm fairly
certain this is correct okay so let's
copy that let's paste it here
if we run it that file will be changed
okay in fact all html files but
but however we limit it to this
directory so there's only one html file
there i don't want to change my whole
directory
so you know just so okay so if you read
that file will be changed so let's run
done okay so now let's open that file
unicode
there it is showing browser unicode emax
and emax takes edit year 2021 so we did
change
so success
so
so now you see now you compare okay
now you compare okay so so we are
comparing you know which one is the
longer okay so
yeah so the power shell okay so let's do
the comparison
now the power shell here is not fair
because you don't actually contain the
full path you need the full path so
let's change it
so uh yeah so you need a full path there
it is
uh then
let's
okay then then let's say haskell to emac
these okay so let's change this to
haskell and emac this
okay so how many characters in wufang
language
uh
it's i need to compact okay so hold on a
second
compact code remove white spaces and so
on okay there it is
now okay so uh
uh
wait where's the powershell
oh the powershell is on top
right okay so now how many characters
are there
count words
142 characters okay 142. now how many
powershell is there you don't need a
file
you don't need that oh wait
you forgot the path
133 characters so powershell is 10
characters less
but but but
let me reduce it further
okay you don't you don't need um
i can how do i
can see if i can reduce it further okay
so
yeah the problem with uh wufang language
is that you have these long
names you know
right string
string replace
read string those are long name oh you
know in powershell you know
the full name is get chart item so get
you know instead of the
the proper name is get child items so
let's if we write this properly you know
if we write this in a way you you need
to
you know uh send it to your work you
know so you have to write properly
okay still
so how many how many characters are
there
so compared to the wolfram code
142.
code is one character less
okay so powershell you can you can also
remove the redundant um
spaces
okay anyway so
in the end so you have the powershell
code
then you have the wolfram language code
okay they are kind of
similar
yeah exactly you know count symbols but
that gets you know that that's that's a
proper way to
to judge how short is a programming code
but however that's not popular because
then then you got the issue of you know
you you have to write a script to
replace all the long you know function
names and so on that gets fairly complex
and non-trivial i mean it's it's it's
it's trivial but it's actually tedious
to do because
language has 6000 functions you know so
anyway
yeah a draw okay
now
i'm not satisfied with a draw so i'm
thinking is here
you can actually make this simpler um
[Music]
you know let's see file names um
yeah i think it's a i think that's about
the best you can do okay okay that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
uh it's a two hours
if you like my stuff okay donate paypal
me patreon paypal patreon buy my emacs
mods you know wufam language mod
powershell language mod it's all on my
emacs website
uh by my emacs this tutorial
and i have n wolfen language is free
okay i mentioned this many times just
search for wufang script okay you can
you can actually run it let's see if i
can actually run it
i don't i i don't have it installed i
have the you know but it's you can
download it for free just search for
uh okay uh
so i have a tutorial i did several
videos okay so uh language tutorial
several past videos and this one we did
you know last week it's uh very good
okay it's fantastic you teach you would
language doing geometry which is the
main
use for wufam language not for shell
scripting i mean this is you know i'm
this is the first time i'm doing text
processing in wufang language that's why
i'm not familiar with this
but but the traditional use of
language is engineering physics
mathematics you know sciences chemistry
you know so i did a video last week
and saber okay and the wolfram language
for free you can download it i show you
how you know several ways uh if you buy
raspberry pi it's also free it's come
with it bundled or you can just download
wufang engine or film script
okay thank you guys bye
fantastic okay all right we close we
shut down in one minute and now i'm just
cleaning up my code okay so copy that
go to talk show
uh today's talk show
powershell
paste it
okay then wufang language yeah so after
all this trouble
you know after all this trouble we
reduced it to this final and correct
version one single line
fantastic thing and thank you guys for
the for the you know
for telling me to do it
you know i wasn't sure we gonna okay so
yeah so
um
so do i um
so okay so first of all copy that
go to talk show put it on my bye guys
bye
um
put it here
so you can see
this is the
syntax coloring added so you can see
this is the final wolfram language code
uh in powershell okay so the powershell
let's remove the first one
okay show it
okay
add syntax coloring show it then go back
to the wolfram language
now the wolfram language
we add some tutorials so we can people
can see how to read string
um
okay so for example
this is how you read the string
read the file how do you do find replace
how do you do regular expression
and how do you
that covers
it okay so so so this
this is how you
how you um
do that okay
and replace string okay
we don't need that we don't need that
that
that that that that
search failed okay wait
search failed
bye guys bye bye
no this this idiot
of course
okay this is the final page for today's
talk show and uh
show the video part
you know i'm gonna upload it to my
website you can so today's today's talk
show notes
we demonstrated
how to find replacing e-mag list
powershell golan python pearl and here's
a powershell code and here's how to do
it in wufang language and finally here's
one single line
fantastic part
good night