foreign
welcome to another episode of Casino
talk show
so today we are going to code emac bisp
and some randomish okay randomish so I'd
love to see your comments and questions
hey Huang
Huang uh Chinese blood full channel from
Germany
so I like I'm going to coat my uh just
I'm gonna work on my uh emac Beast
coding uh it's probably going to be
boring for you because I'm going to
continue uh what we did last time that
we didn't finish and we got distracted
into talking some other subject
so emacs coding and then I'm gonna talk
some random maybe some randomish uh
things okay and by the way right now
there's a emacs online conference going
on so if you just go to search for emacs
conference uh so there are a lot emacs
experts and emac this experts they are
you know talking about emac stuff so go
watch them okay if you are emacs user
and interested in himac Beast go watch
them
a view emacs fans you know many of you
emacs fans hello Tito emacs fam and
hello names uh nimsu names who are you
so anyway so
so yeah emacs conference is going on so
you can go watch just uh search for it
you know and I uh
I did a Twitter let me show you okay so
this is interesting so uh twitter.com
I mean I'm going to show you one of the
link one of the Articles okay uh and I'm
gonna
you know I'm gonna talk random a little
bit random today so I'm gonna you know
first of all emac stuff let me show you
I'm gonna talk about that later okay
that is uh okay hold on a second
uh so where is the emacs conference
thing so that's Richard Stroman but hold
on a second
uh
yeah okay okay so emacs conference is
going on in emacs 29 is upcoming
fantastic okay so let me mention a few
things random things
uh
and trees yeah let me talk about these
things three-seater is a new password
for editors uh kind of similar for in
purpose for the language protocol
language server protocol okay so first
of all so check out this emacs talk okay
uh I know this guy a little bit
um
10 reasons why you should use eshow emac
Beast shell okay so that's Isha and you
have seen me see you have seen me using
Esha before for example get uh status
you know I can do the git status
written in emac bisp purely e-mac this
written so there is a video God you know
this open source phonetics free software
Foundation phonetics you can their
website is hard to see you know there is
a video
uh what
the [ __ ] is the video did we have a
JavaScript on
pack two talks uh 10 top 10 reasons why
you should use should be using Isha this
guy is Abraham Howard Abraham okay
Howard Abraham and Howard Abrams and he
has been coding uh emac this
I think yeah I think so well you know at
least he's been using emacs for 10 20
years 20 years or something or even more
so
where is where is the
video Let's Open that one okay
God this you know free software
Foundation website they they this is one
of the problem this phonetics problem
find out how to watch and participate oh
find out how to watch and participate
there you go and this is one thing good
about them so because all the videos you
can just
play and download a card
refresh
ah God you know this is a free software
Foundation website problematic am I
doing good talk a video check audio
check okay so anyway so
this guy you know so so emacs conference
okay if you want to learn it in like
this you can learn from them you know
besides me
okay that's one thing let me talk about
so this let me talk about uh this fun
thing okay uh
this one fun thing you are watching
hello everyone great gun
dark
so you know I would Proclaim that the
real artificial intelligence
year 2023 is the year of the Rio the
starting of the Rio artificial
intelligence is getting amazing okay so
you are looking at right now is this
China you know this China's AI bot that
does drawing so basically what you do is
you post an image or picture or photo or
drawing whatever and it returns a
beautified version of it okay you know
in the beginning I think this is lousy
because this this image for example yeah
it's beautiful but it you know someone
someone did this I'm gonna show you more
so this image is beautiful but it
doesn't capture the essence of the
character you know it this this this
beautiful dude doesn't look like me at
all you can tell if you just see that
you know this is sorry
so
so you know like a caricature you know
have you seen uh
career culture let me explain this
career card
okay so you'll see some examples that's
the essence of a correct caricature okay
JavaScript
by the way uh Brave browser
I'm using right now you are looking at
Brave browser I recommend it okay I
recommend web browser it's Bill is
started by the guy who created
JavaScript once you know after he got
kicked out by the social justice scan
you know so great browser is great I
recommend it I'm also using Firefox by
the way I'm using also using you know I
use multiple browsers
so very browser the brave company now
they have a search
you know so that's what I'm using it
just I think it just started so this
search engine is different from Earth
from others because this search engine
it's not just a wrapper to Google or
Microsoft Bing or Yahoo or whatever they
are independent so this is uh very good
okay so I'm trying it out so almost all
the others you know Echo ecosia search
Styx search they are paid or based on
you know Google search engine and all
others they kind of they are just a
wrapper so this is an independent search
engine I recommend it okay Brave search
you can just search search it and you'll
find it okay so actually I'm starting to
talk about lots of things but so let's
write it down so we have a topic okay
three-seater
emacs conference okay
uh that's we that we already talked
about talked about emacs conference and
uh
uh Brave browser
Brave search okay those are fantastic
and uh
and we are talking about character we'll
come back to it okay
so in the show in browser okay
that's today's talk show uh and let's go
to my programming blog showing browser
so
so you know Brandon Ike the guy created
JavaScript and he created web browser
and now there's a brave search engine so
and what about DuckDuckGo you should not
use the go because you know I I tried it
I've been using I tried it since 2018.
uh it's got problems uh but the
the most serious problem
is this one the girl started to censor
because of the Ukraine war you know he
started he think that
you know he he started to sense the
information so from this guy Gabriel
Weinberg I suppose that's uh he's a boss
who created DuckDuckGo but anyway now he
started to censor you know since the
ship is like when opinions is like
opinions you like yeah you know we we
are doctor girl we don't do we you know
we don't uh get your private information
but when when the information is really
something you don't like like really
really something you hate like each one
of us have something we really hate you
know maybe Religion different religion
or or politics you know
daddy that you know then he says he's
gonna sense
so Duck Duck Go it's no good okay
uh and there are not many choices today
okay so that's one thing Duck Duck Go so
let's let's go back to what we want to
talk about so so yeah so go uh let me
copy this okay so copy it so we have a
um record of the links we talked about
so later on people can go through my
page and
see the links okay now yeah back to the
QQ AI drawing bar so we were talking
about
you know this this strong I'm gonna show
you a lot okay so first of all you have
creature you know you know if you know
what creature is you know essentially
you know they look cartoonish but the
essence of caricature is that you take a
look at them you immediately know
who are they you know what what you know
who are they because they capture the
characteristics of the person
you know he is he is uh Obama for
example uh who is this the Zuckerberg I
think this is the movie star Leonardo
dicapio you know anyway you get you get
point you know so character so at first
why when I saw this uh
Chinese AI drawing but you know I think
this is no good because it doesn't
capture the essence but actually
actually it's amazing okay I find it
amazing because
what essentially you do is it let me
show you some more okay so that's me
someone did it
uh you know so I I was saying my first
impression no it's not good because it
does you know the drawing it generates
does not capture the essence of the
original but
but that's actually not not not its
purpose it has something else very very
I'm very impressed you know today and
you know in the past week there's also
the open AI chat GPT it's quite amazing
okay quite amazing the artificial
intelligence is
is becoming uh is becoming human-like
now these days and and by the way this
QQ drawing is this is the first time you
know I have seen artificial generated
drawings before they suck you know they
they usually sucks very bad you know
they try to draw in the you know and
also you have
they they are creepy you know artificial
you know AI generated drawing they are
very creepy and but this is the first
time I'm fairly impressed okay so so
look at this you know this is the chat
you know this is a meme
so it becomes that okay but but let me
show you but but you see if you give it
a drawing like that some kind of cartoon
and it it changes into these things
okay that's another example okay
but then if you give it a drawing you
know some fuzzy photo it transforms you
know into this beautiful
guy you know you so
so I mean if you are a iPod what what
what are you supposed to do you know so
it's very creative you know it's
creativity it you know it has a license
you know it takes the license of
creativity and transform that's a that's
a purpose of this drawing but not to
replicate
in in a drawing form of the original but
rather it's kind of transformed beautify
it beautify it into uh
kind of this style of uh drawing this is
not exactly anime okay you know you know
if you know you could call it anime but
it's not exactly anime for example this
one
but look there's some some so many more
okay so let me show you some of the
amazing ones okay
so so here we have a fat you know woman
and notice that the face is not shown
but however it came out with this
beautiful image with the face you know
and with the elaborate necklace you see
that that choker
it's a women's thing you know it's like
you are like a dog you know
uh and that's another thing that's
that's the phenomenon of sexuality you
know how
you know you can see a lot of that in
women's stress that of their own choice
you know they put something on their
neck that seems like they you know it's
gonna choke them or it's like a dog dog
leash but however women do that you know
that's so that's
thousands or millions of years of human
sexuality okay so anyway that's another
thing so anyway this drawing you see
that it transforms these faceless image
into this beautiful uh drawing so that's
amazing
foreign
and also look at the pattern you know
look at the pattern on her bra
you know so this so this is a drone by
AI you know artificial intelligence they
they create the drawing but also the
patterns on the brothers and which you
don't see you know in general photos is
quite amazing
so I'm I'm very fairly impressed for the
first time uh by other visual artificial
intelligence generated drawing okay
uh no I haven't tried it myself but
apparently you can go and try it and you
know someone tried it you know I if I
really want to try I have to I don't
know exactly what is what what is this
AI bot you know I have two I haven't
looked yet so you I need to talk to my
China friends programmers and they they
all know
but if you search it you'll probably
probably find it okay so this is a
Chinese website apparently so let's go
let's let's go next Okay so
and and look at this one you know
a photo of two
beautiful girls and and what's that
that's a guy or something and it
transformed it just by cutting off that
guy he changed it and put a girl there
quite amazing
uh again so and another thing cultural
thing you are seeing here is that you
see that those uh patterns those are uh
logos of the gaming
keyboard and mouse company called
what's the name guys
if you are watching guys say something
okay comment
so uh
this brand okay so let's go to my
keyboard blog blog let me just tell you
random things okay my keyboard blog and
you can find the name of that brand
called
um
razor you know never you know never buy
Razer keyboard okay raise the product
Razer product is no good
and in fact I think Razer product
happened to be founded by a Chinese guy
so don't buy razor okay so anyway that's
the logo of the razor let's show girls
that's what it is but today you don't
see this kind of thing in USA because
USA the white man culture banned it
so anyway that's that then
you have uh
then you have this
you know I I'm not you know I don't know
what that is some kind of sexual thing
okay
then you just change it to birds
so very creative okay
uh then then you have there it is Elon
Musk you know Elon Musk so the open AI
company recently uh open AI let me show
you okay so that that's another amazing
thing okay you you it generates text
okay I don't have uh let's start
JavaScript it generates text in point oh
yeah so let me show you one okay
let me show you one so open Ai and hold
on a second so I want to open that and
open Wikipedia okay
so open AI let's magnify
you know it was started by Elon Musk and
others so not by Google Okay so this one
is different from Google's AI you know
Google is most famous for lots of AI
begin it so the the right now it's
called chat GPT okay you know just go
there and try it it's amazing let me
show you
um
copy the link
it's put into my talk show
so that you can see the topics we talked
about okay
chat GPT
okay so the
um right
chat GPT open Ai and uh okay close that
and
we yeah so then then there's the emacs
uh feature let me let me write it down
emacs 29 coming that's fantastic okay
um and uh
yeah so there it is Elon Musk okay
okay about the
chat GPT let me show you okay
it it can generate poem and in fact it
generates a poem you know you just just
type Saudi generator poem for sorry and
it shows uh you know someone did it you
know a friend the William on Discord on
Sunday scored
okay so it generated you know this poem
for my website can you guys see it
yeah you can okay
so um
okay so so so
you know so it um it's magnify
you cannot
so it generates a poem you know a poem
about kasari.org
pentameter okay so it then the AI says
this is a website built by xabi a guy
who knows his stuff and wants to share
it with you the site is crammed with
info on all sorts of things from
programming to sex
there's something for everyone
so if you are looking for knowledge or
just a good laugh
you need to check out sally.org the best
website around
generated by AI how does it know how
does it know my website and in the
description you look at this poem and
it's actually young big pentameter you
know I'm not too you know that's a a
specific pattern of poem okay I don't
know exactly how it works but it's so it
knows my website and the description
given is very accurate okay and then
you know very accurate and also kind of
in my style the way I would write it you
know it's amazing then I asked the guy
will you know
a friend you know on this disco too okay
tell it to generate a poem in Limerick
okay I want I want to check if this is
real you know you know let's see
generate a study about sadi.org in
Limerick and it does
it says there was a geek named xsa who
ran a website with much Flair
he would write code all day and all
night and his site was really something
quite right you know one of the
catchphrase I use often is all day and
night and this poem just used it that
and here's another version Limerick okay
about saudi.org there was a geek named
sa who ran a website called saudi.org he
was quite the geek and knew a lot of
stuff and his website was really awesome
okay uh so yeah so this open AI is just
amazing and it can generate code you
know not always correct but you know so
right now on Twitter
uh right now Elon musk's Twitter if you
just search it you know chat gbg you'll
find a ton of amazing quite amazing you
know um
machine generated text okay and it can
also generate a story like
like I would you know it I would say
it's already past the tuning test you
know the test for artificial
intelligence I would say it's already
passed
so
you know we you know so this I would say
2023 is the year of the real AI so are
you guys still there say something okay
if you guys watch us okay so there is
you know uh
chat GPT okay quite amazing and on
Discord we talked about it and a lot of
people Dion uh friend the Dion is the
biggest sponsor of my work okay
so uh you know and you know he is the
biggest uh don't don't know and we have
you know so a lot of people we have you
know tried the opening AI chatbot quite
amazing okay lots of uh oh yeah here
uh quite a lot a lot of amazing things
the the thing
so so anyway let's go back to the this
qqai the China AI so there's Elon Musk
you know with his fire gun
flamethrower and they and there it is a
result
um you know
so let's look at the next one
the next one a pretty girl a Chinese
girl or something or something it
doesn't look like Japanese it looks like
then a pretty girl is just a pretty girl
he returns pretty girl okay
um
and also you know look at the patterns
on her clothing
you know this this is not
I you know I wouldn't say this is this
is not trivial and to create this in a
drawing style and create arbitrary
patterns on the Fly you know depending
on whatever
uh images I don't think that you know
each one is different so it's quite
amazing
so then here's the example of a guy
you know so it becomes this handsome
hunk but one issue is that his bulge is
good so that's that's a flaw okay
then so here is the Snowden famous
Snowden becomes the head
and then this is another funny one so
you know this is a famous painting that
got
damaged you know by some idiot you know
uh rework and then it becomes that girl
okay uh yeah so
so that's about this this qqai drawing
thing oh yeah so then you have this
Korean you know North Korea
King John E or something you know so it
becomes that
so again the it doesn't capture the
character but however
however it's very creative and somehow
the spirit of the image is captured
okay let me show you a lot more so then
here's the Jesus you know the
virgin virgin Mary you know with the
baby
I suppose I suppose that's what that you
know then you got that beautiful and
then
okay this is UNA Obama you know the you
know
uh
you know you so let me show you if you
guys don't know
yeah I'm not gonna show it so when Obama
is outright
and so his name you know he's in jail
because he killed people so Ted
uh Ted something okay you know so here's
a
a result of his real photo
mugshot
so so yeah so and here is another
example of extreme creativity you know
you give it this image then it returns
this with this
melancing fingers and fingernails you
know and something like with a computer
screen on the nail and also a kind of
face with some kind of mask or scar you
see
quite amazing you know it takes
some creativity to create okay
so so that then that's that's here's
another interesting one so you give it a
photo of a supposedly UFO this this is a
you know somewhat popular incident where
I you know on YouTube you can find it
where you have a USA jet fighters on a
carrier
found some unidentified flying object
you know like UFO so they this is
supposed to be the video footage of it
uh it's on YouTube over and also the Joe
Rogan idiot talks about it
so you give it that image and it returns
this
you know this
strange thing you know again I would say
it captures the kind of the
the spirit the the background the
context you know of the things so so
what is this thing you know
you know I
you can tell it's like a dish and a
needle or something but it's very
strange
yeah so
so then let's see next okay so do we
have anything else okay so you can see a
lot more and you can try it yourself
okay people generate it I uh posted the
link so there's a link to 4chan
you know so
you know yesterday I looked at all these
um
I'm I'm fairly I'm fairly impressed okay
I'm fairly uh impressed by by these uh
and there are some you know some you
know again this is another creativity so
you show this face giant phase and
become they become just Lakes
so uh so what you guys are saying
YouTube is not allowing me to write
censorship okay okay guys start AOC with
gpt3
I don't know what that means exactly
uh Anonymous says care to comment on
team pool's compound being rated in the
ensuing Eagle battle oh I didn't know
that
well that's about politics I'm not going
to talk about you know
too much about politics team pool you
know
let me just let me give you a comment
about team pool team pool I started to
follow team pool around 2006.
you know I mean 2016.
you know that's the election year
you know that's when you suddenly all of
a sudden you have all these strange
jargons you know safe space
Mains trading man spreading you know all
these strange jargons all of a sudden
you know over
then
then I started to notice this guy team
pool you know he's doing documentary on
the ground you know he's a journal
journalist independent journalist he
you know he for example back in 2008
also there's a Occupy Wall Street right
he's so he's there and he actually won
journalism Awards you know because he's
on the street document what people are
saying you know so
I didn't know who who he is you know but
you know back in 2016 then 2017 you know
the Trump years you know you have all
these you know
eventually it's called cultural War you
know social justice Warrior and so so
anyway I found this guy you know I
remember it's back in Berkeley UC
Berkeley the origin
you know UC Berkeley is our engine of
free speech you know because of the
Vietnam War remember the Vietnam War you
know UC Berkeley you have students you
know protesting
you know that that's what made Free
Speech famous UC Berkeley started and
back then USA is mostly a Christian
Nation so you cannot say [ __ ] you know
on [ __ ] or [ __ ] or swear any kind of
swear you get banned okay it's ruled by
Christians
USA so anyway you you know UC Berkeley
is famous for for Free Speech but in
2017 you know when the social justice
thing
started to appear then on UC Berkeley
you have protest that burns that burns
American flag that burns Free Speech
sign and beating people
you know bloody bloody
and you know
so that so starting in 2016 to 2019 I
started to watch a lot what's going on
you know
kind of strange okay that's anyway
so Team Four that's how I started to
know team pool the first time ever is
when he is at UC Berkeley you know
protest and he interviewed people like I
don't know who he is I just happened to
see YouTube okay but eventually I
watched then basically around 2017
through 2019 I watched team pool every
every other day okay
several hours a week and so I've been
watching Team pool a lot
so I find him I judge him to be a good
guy good person good person on the
ground doing you know documentary and
journalism
but team pool
began started to degrade starting around
2019 okay instead of going to the ground
and actually document you know things
interview people he started to just sit
on his computer like me like me right
now and just going through news You Know
Drama news oh social justice Warrior did
this today oh Trump dad oh CNN is you
know he started to do that
every and and before it was like one
video every
two days or three you know because it
takes time for him to go to places
but starting around 2019 he's churning
out two or three videos every day
team pool okay meanwhile he's getting
more and more popular his his viewers by
now it's like uh you know more than a
million two million or something maybe
and he started to have multiple channels
and it is just every day he's just
sitting there
show you new news website drama you know
talking about Drama Oh beating oh bloody
here or you know Trump or whatever Biden
Hunter Biden
and uh
and and he's like a you know alarming
you know he so he he went down you know
he he so in my mind
he's just flying drama
you know the more drama the more viewers
viewers you have like right now I'm
doing you know I'm talking about
politics a little bit
you know if I just do emac this coding
oh I got you know
200 watch per video now if I talk about
the social justice or this kind of thing
oh one thousand two thousand watches and
if I add a caption you know oh you know
AI is taking over the world oh my God
then I'm gonna have ten thousand views
drama that's what tempo is doing and
let's let's go to
um
okay I actually have a um
article about him I started to document
you know I started to clean up my
my political blog
of random thoughts
that I wrote down in the past five years
I started to kind of clean them up move
things around so they the goal is to so
they become more coherent so now I have
I have a kind of an article a page on
Temple
you know and this one is very famous you
know there it is Joe Rogan Joe Rogan
Temple Jack Dorsey and this
the Vijaya you know the Jack Dorsey and
vijayaka they are scums okay in my
opinion they are criminals of humanity
okay these are these people these two
so anyway this video is very popular
okay several million views the first day
you know
it's about you know Twitter is doing a
lot of censorship okay so team pool is
in fact expert you know so
okay I'm starting to uh getting into a
lot of other things okay team pool
so Tempo originally is a great
journalist actually deserve the word
journalist okay journalist by today it's
it's rotted you know it's rotten you
know if you hear someone is journalist
you know it's a it's [ __ ] okay so I
don't even use the word journalism like
is you know used to be like 20 years ago
journalism is like a great because
journalism report the truth you know if
you have a big organization like Google
or government or China okay China China
is another big dramatic thing
journalists reported you know if you are
corrupt if you take a lot of Vibes you
know moving millions of dollars you know
journalists report them you know that's
like the foundation of the USA principle
you know
but today journalism they work for the
they they every day what they report is
the government things you know the
government tell them and big
corporations like Google tell them what
to say
so anyway team pool was once a great
journalist and around 2019 he started to
do like cultural Wars you know like two
or three videos every day and he just
sit there and point you point you to you
know
different websites like Fox News or CNN
oh yeah and then he just babble and team
pool
also he's his IQ is low okay he said
many times that he doesn't
um
he doesn't you know he he never had a
degree in fact he's a high school
dropout
which is fine I'm also you know I never
I don't have any degree I learned math
in programming mostly by myself okay
so team pool but he but he's you know
he's he's
he walk you know he walk for whatever he
does okay I mean he worked for it you
know so
no degree that's fine but however team
pool is not very smart and then he start
you know he he started to like emphasize
oh
um
idiot basically opinions about Society
about philosophy about economics you
know he don't know any of that but when
he covered news he'll just inject his
opinions about oh I think you know blah
blah blah
so team pool is was a great journalist
but in 2019 he started to do
a cultural War you know flying drama
make himself more money
and he also started to and his IQ is
pretty low okay
low IQ
okay and and look at the way he you know
these uh clickbaits that's his you know
very popular among all YouTubers you
know USC giant title dramatic title then
some face you know some
we gotta you know this this page
deserves uh
Big Image you know German that's what
they do you know they they that's what
this kind of thing make money you know
find drama and lots of YouTube stars are
like that you know almost all of them
all of them because this this is the way
to get yourself popular okay so team
pool so
ah
okay so but there's one thing I want to
say about team pool I highly respect he
is not a bad person okay even though he
did this clickbait and talking idiotic
things you know he covers some news you
know some news that usually the
mainstream will not cover okay
so but when doing that he tends to be
alarmist you know he kept saying oh oh
Civil War is happening you know you've
been saying that for like three years at
this Civil War which in some sense is
true then you start you know
blah blah blah drama okay but there's
one thing about team pool
that he is a good person okay that is
why I still
I don't watch him anymore you know
because I got other things to do not
because
you know I got you know I'm getting old
I have like maybe five more years to
code so I got lots of math proofs Theory
type Theory differential geometry I want
to go into I want in in a lot of emac
beasts work I need to do so I don't
I haven't been watching Team pool since
in fact I haven't been watching any of
these uh various popular people Laura
and Southern Jordan Peterson Dave Rubin
uh Lindsay Shepherd these are some of
the very famous
anti-social just just to scan people but
I haven't watched them since about 2019
okay so but one thing
I want to emphasize about team poor the
person is that he
does not lie okay or at least not
intentionally I I think you know for my
own
observations of all these drama people
or you know these people cultural World
stuff Tempo is not a bad person I would
say
Jordan Peterson
is not a bad person he's he's great
Lord and certain okay let me let me let
me talk about law assistant okay all
these people are great okay lower
uncertain Lawrence southern team pool
Dave Rubin
Lindsay Shepherd are very famous for you
know I'm not going to go into because
you can talk about this for for a year
so these are good people okay good
people about that they they don't lie
maybe you know they have opinions maybe
that's
wrong or incorrect but they don't do
nasty things now especially I want to
say about Lauren Southern
okay this Stefan
he's kind of a crackpot okay he's I
don't you know I don't like him he's a
crack part sort of people
uh
but in lower and Southern it's a it's a
great fantastic
person okay
because
we
you know
I'm getting emotional because
these are about
you know what they do a lot of these
social justice uh scumbags that
beat people up or they reach you know
when I talk about social justice
Warriors I don't mean just oh some blue
hair on Twitter you know some some
activists there are top leaders that you
know those are on Twitter usually they
are just pawns Pawn pawns a chest like a
chess game in scammers they make a lot
of money
but they are top leaders in USA that are
doing these things that lead you know
that create this phenomenon
so what I want to say about Lauren
certain is that she's not she's not very
you know she's not a academic type of
person like me like I you know what I am
you know we study we talk about
philosophy or stuff she's she's not like
that she's just a
pretty girl but
from what I have seen
I judge her to be a great great person
okay lower uncertain
okay
okay so team pool so
you know I
um
okay I think maybe that's it for today
so we all uh we we talked for 15 minutes
so this um
yeah the very interesting
um
you know artificial intelligence stuff
uh and also this one if you guys you
know follow some of the drama online
this is the sister of
um sapiro you know the famous you know
another guy famous sapiro
you know this is this is her YouTube
She's beautiful you know she's singing
There's a YouTube video of her in fact I
also have I also have a Blog of her
let's go to art
so there's some odd Pages
um you know this photo I took
very beautiful
uh so let's see yeah so there it is
Abigail
Shapiro okay that's the sister of uh Ben
Shapiro so she
she's doing that her hair girl face but
there's a video you know you search you
can see her sing she sings opera so they
are kind of affluent you know upper
class people
and then you know so this drawing
becomes that it's beautiful
you know when you talk about some of
these people you know this
um you know kind of celeb celebrity
in the cultural War
um you know any of these people or a lot
more you know actually I have a Blog so
let me just show it since we are talking
about politics you know just in Trudeau
the Canadian
leader basically
you know these gender things this uh
antifa you know flying a Russian flag
beating people you know burning people
alive you know
all this happening
and but okay so all these people you
know almost any one of them
you you know when you talk about
you you'll see everyone is you know
talking about their opinions uh dramatic
different opinions attacks you know
almost like random you know it's a chaos
chaos you know like for example Jordan
Peterson which I respect you know
you know you know something he says
Jordan Peterson I don't agree but in
general I would you know I would I think
Jordan Peterson is a great person okay
a great person
and but of course what I'm trying to say
is that when you talk about these people
some people will disagree including some
of you you know they'll say oh Jordan
Peterson is actually the most evil you
know you know they'll say the same thing
about lmus about anyone you know because
this
this is politics we are talking about
politics politics you know
um
okay so that's
um so that's it you know um
that's I think that's it for today
uh let's see what else we might have to
say
uh
oh yeah so there's the chat GPT
uh so emacs 29 is coming and it has
fantastic features okay I recommend you
watch uh
this guy so this guy emacs 29 is nine
what can we expect so a lot fantastic
features
and one of the most important I mean one
of the most deep and
for me is let's go through my emacs blog
you know emacs 99 features and one of
the most
deep for me is the there's a parser
called three-seater
and emacs 29 is starting to support it I
think this is more important than the
language server protocol now if you
don't know what about you if you don't
know what that is don't worry about it
because it's a bit more complex and
advanced it's about syntax coloring it's
about
formatting code it's about the engine
you know what it is does what does it
take to do this kind of thing
so you know this one of the issue I'm
concerned with
I'm very interested in you know for the
past you know 10 or 15 years so I
started to write a page that collects
many of my articles on these things I've
written before in the past 15 years or
so so many articles for example you have
Auto formatting you know
for example in Golan there's a tool you
can press the button and have your
entire
code Auto formatted you know even if
your whole code is one you know
one single line you know so there's a
goal and auto format it's this begin
with Golan around 2008.
fantastic then it started a movement so
now you also have one for python you can
just you know I demonstrated this before
so you press the key then it auto format
the entire entire file or all files in
your directory
and then you of course you have for
JavaScript which is stay now okay and
you have also one for Powershell which
requires some code to make it work and
then you have
yeah so in this article 2007
I I wrote up the idea that you should
never
you know typically before before goal
and scope format what programmers do and
all the style guys tell programmers how
you should indent okay this line should
indent oh you know
Richie style or C style or whatever [ __ ]
you know they tell you how to manually
like you know how many space versus tabs
or whatever crap
what you should really have is just just
like the goal and auto format you know
you press the button the machine can do
it okay you have compilers you have
passes machine can do it it's just that
this programmer idiots
you know since the year 2000 Pro python
email especially insulting is the Emax
lisp people [ __ ] idiots you know
because emac this
um
because emac this code
emac lists or List syntax in general is
the most
easy to do automatic formatting but the
least first people don't they don't know
they tell you oh you should you
shouldn't have you know blah blah blah
you should put all your parents parents
together then you have the power edit
mod the most idiotic [ __ ]
that induces you to manual manually
detailing your code per edit okay if you
are in the emacs community you'll think
all the emacs phonetics they are say
part edit is the best thing it's in fact
in my opinion it's the worst idiotic
[ __ ] because with pi edit what it really
do is to induce you to manual format
your code that's what power added do
does okay
for example this code okay let's go to
emac this mod so if you I can you know I
can remove the format if I want to
format them you press one button okay
press one button format the entire block
okay that's the way to go
even better is is like the Golan python
then or JavaScript Powershell you know
you press the button format the whole
code for whole page four whole file okay
that's the way you want to go you don't
want style guide [ __ ] okay you don't
want to style guide you don't want Power
edit [ __ ] okay
and
but my point is that you see when you
are in the language you know for example
in Python in emac this all the all the
high priests they tell you that you
should follow this this that that's the
worst thing okay
what you really should is just like
write a tool like go format you know or
want any one of these that just format
it automatically so you don't have like
formatting style debates anymore okay
that's what that's how things should be
and this begin to happen with Golan by
raw Pike fantastic you know raw pack is
a Unix phonetics you know I don't like
Unix I I'm a Unix hater raw pack is a
Unix Fanatics and he is also one of the
most dramatic talkative Pro Unix people
he write a lot but he also it turns out
he's super smart and and his language go
land I very much like you know I think
it's the best language for at least you
know kind of low level thing go like
so I have a whole tutorial so so raw
Pike okay he and and other people you
know he they created uh go land with the
idea go format automatically format okay
this is a revolution this is a
revolutionary programming language let
me tell you the history you don't you
don't see this kind of History anyway on
Hacker News you don't see you just see
babbling all the time
okay so go from Oman go run a pike or
and he's and and several others I forgot
the name Thomas uh something you know
you can you can look up Wikipedia so
wrap anyway go from Golan
around 2008 is the first one
practically you know the most effect is
practically the first one to create the
phenomena the revolution the idea the
concept to spread the concept that
formatting code should be done
automatically by your password by your
password tool okay that's
that's that Golan then you started to
have
first internal I suppose and then
JavaScript and today I believe you also
have in C for C or C plus plus you know
Auto format because before this day
before this school land
people you know this [ __ ] scams they
tell you to do style guide they tell you
to like you know indentation you know
they actually manual every editor is
just all manual how many how many
characters your you know one line should
have
uh let me let me do that
you know like how many characters should
the line have you know you should you
know [ __ ] idiotic [ __ ]
and I wrote about this so I wrote about
this in 2007.
okay but nobody nobody you know they
they think I'm a troll and blah blah
blah and the power addict the power edit
author says oh what do you say you know
what what you propose is actually uh
very difficult or impossible to do
I I don't get it I have no idea why he
says that the author of pie that you
know he says he says that you know what
you are suggesting is actually
impossible
it's extremely idiotic you know
the least language syntax is the most
easy to do compared to Golan python
JavaScript you know
because because the characteristics of
the least syntax is that they are
uniform regular okay most mostly
so um
yeah so so all these articles they they
are already and also about syntax
coloring you know
so anyway so today you have three Sita
which I I'll be you know watch this
video okay three seater I think I'll be
spending a lot of time in in next year
to study and uh
do something about it in my emac
packages and also studying pasta which
is a project I kind of
stopped you know I I started to um
you know I want to write a pasta but I
kind of stopped so now I gonna start to
work on them again
okay so that's that's it for today thank
you guys for watching donate okay
now if you like my videos or some parts
you like spread it okay post your
Twitter or blog or whatever
and also comment on YouTube with the
timestamp
okay that's it
any ring
yeah that's it that's it for today
uh Zionism yeah don't you know don't
don't post those you know controversial
stuff
you know about
yeah I'm not gonna get into that topic
um and also that topic you know it's not
it's not too relevant to Chinese blood
people like you know me because to me
they are just all white people
um
okay so that's it for today
yes this this uh Abba gel Superior she
she's beautiful
that's what I see beauty
um
yeah so that's it bye guys
what else
um
that's it bye guys donate okay
go to PayPal go to patreon go to my
website you'll find those you know links
because money
you know is actually how things work you
know because you see all the all the
scams all the you know
this cultural World whatever
you know if you wonder why does it
what's the root cause for them to happen
money okay
ultimately
you know I I code open so yeah anyway
ah so let's see emacs block close close
all these today's talk show yeah
yeah so we didn't code emac this today
that's fine because I'm gonna do it
offline