good morning I am alive so are you
welcome to another episode of c talk
show uh so good morning we are going to
code emac lisp hello
timer uh let's have some wi okay can I
see it video check audio check have a
red one today's topic is emac L coding f
fantastic make America great Again by
engineering okay not by lawyers and uh
poor talkers mouths
influencers so if you want to make
America great again or whatever your
country great
again work do mathematics okay
today we're going to do for coders so
for those of you computer programmers
you will find this interesting because
we are doing emac
emac the most powerful text editor like
I'm using right now you can see these
two
windows uh check check check check okay
do I need to talk about my keyboards
like you know I talk about every video
so let's give it
today and okay so hi so if you are here
say hi comments I love your comments I
love it if you are not here play at 1.5
speed and Skip around because I
ramble fantastic you like rants of
course that is the bottom line of
humanity everyone wants gossip because
when you gossip they is drama you know
what is movie made of you know we talk
about box Offices Hollywood making big
money you go watch Star Wars or whatever
or or Twilight the women's thing
Twilight if you are a guy Star Wars or
whatever drama that's what you want
drama so okay so um so you guys how many
people are watching like three uh Jesus
three is a crowd
counting myself okay and there's no
people okay so so in that case let me uh
I want to talk about this Allan guy okay
so but we're going to also do code okay
don't worry if you are just technical
people like Asians you know if you are
Chinese you are good for math that's
it so there's this skum bag aggressive
German scum Allan Mac
Kenzie did he do any crime
no but he's aggressive guy in the emac
community that creates that insists he
insists bad things to happen to emac
because in his opinion it's better but
he makes emac a lot worse okay so this
Alan McKenzie guy he
resigned he he's old he is kind of old I
don't know how old but uh I think at
least 60 I think I I think I don't know
okay but Alan McKenzie aggressive guy
and he's been working with emac G emac
for like 20 years at least but he's he
he he he his opinions make emac very bad
so
finally he posted this
resignation letter to G IMX Dev okay he
says hello emx I'm resigning my position
as emac
contributor you know the immediate
reason is that as maintainer of CC mod
CC mod symbols its name where were taken
by emac and used for other purposes
without informing me much less
Consulting me blah blah blah you know
this you know he so so you see there are
arguments on the go emac development
mailing list of course programmers
always argue this should be designed
this way should be this way no it should
be that way the user interface of emac
no you shouldn't support Mouse no you
should you know always
arguments but he got pissed this Alan
McKenzie guy got pissed over the past
five or 10 years because people do do
not like his ideas you know he spefic
specifically point out a few people
which I like okay but Alan McKenzie he's
a so in my you know I I I I exchanged
email email and or uh News scho Post
with him back in uh 2000s let's say 2005
or you know in 2000s I've exchanged a
few emails with him now let me emphasize
again did this guy is he a criminal no
no did he do any crime no however he has
insisted on a lot opinions on emac
design which in my opinion did damage to
emac okay in particular there's one of
them let me show you okay since we I'm
talking about this let me just talk
about this okay Alam McKenzie I want to
I want to you know talk about this guy
on on YouTube because I want to
emphasize it again he
did damage to the emac okay to the emac
editor
technology huge
damage so let me show and so that's one
thing the other thing is that he's like
this kind of aggressive guy I noticed
actually German people tends to be
aggressive you know aggressive like they
insist their opinion if you don't agree
they're going to attack you okay so Alam
McKenzie is one of such guy so let me
show you the damage one of the major
damage he has done I talked about this
in past videos okay so CI quotes um so I
did a video about that S Talk Show
2021 May 29th curly quotes Unicode emac
and the crime of Richard storman okay
Richard storman is of course involved
but let's go to the C quote controversy
okay so here's article so let's copy it
so that you can uh for those of you
later on you can check it out okay well
not here uh
what so let's go toar talk show yeah
post it here and also the uh okay let me
just post the link here okay
so Alan McKenzie let's get his name
right okay showing browser there you go
Alan McKenzie guy aggressive scum two
articles emac Dev Alan McKenzie resigns
2024 November and uh the other so the
other article is iMac this dark string
cly quote controversy
2015 this is the huge damage he did Alam
McKenzie basically
single-handed
singlehandedly did it to emac a huge
damage to emac let me show you why okay
so this issue is about emac
um emac stock
string formatting conventions okay uh
you might think it's oh formatting
conventions that's no big deal it's a
big deal okay so let's start a emac this
you know let's say defund so we are
finding
function so in IMA convension so let's
say X test okay so this is a function
name so in iMac this we so this part is
a
documentation inline doc or sometimes
called doc string okay you know a
function you can have documentation now
in this documentation there are many
conventions for example if you search
for if you for example describe function
the that directory editing you know you
can see the inline doc of the ad and you
can see there are some links you click
on that it jumps through the source code
you see it jumps to the source code
which is this file right close it you
see you jump to the source code close it
so you got you see you got some links
you can tap to go to uh the links you
see then you got some of the key strokes
you see how it it is highlighted you and
then you got some other you know
highlighted and then you got links to
other
um function you see so you can you there
are links to the source code there are
you can link to other function names
when you discuss the documentation you
can you can have a keystroke markup so
all these are
markups so close that so that is what
you have to do so if for example if I
want um uh if I want to mention uh
directory uh let's
see uh you know if I want to mention so
what's a command
uh
um okay so let me just try to find a
command to link to okay so if I want to
mention the command switch to buffer
so for example
C switch to buffer okay so I need to put
this quote this tick back tick there and
a straight tick there that is a markup
so when you have that then evaluate the
buffer then describe function X test do
it then you can
see inline doc do string for for example
see switch to buffer so you can link to
another command so you press enter Then
you see the documentation for switch to
buer you see so that is done by this
markups
okay okay so let's go toar emac this
Search forar emac tutorial you'll find a
comprehensive tutorial and click
on list Basics and uh click on go down
go to the function section Define
function function parameters function
doc string so click on that so this page
tells you all about these markups in
dark string okay so you um all caps
means the parameter parameter name and
if you want to link to a function you
have to put the back tick and uh
straight single quote and if you want to
link to a variable name then you have to
put a variable in front because in iMac
this variable and function names can
sometimes be the same so you can you can
distinguish you know link to a name that
is a function or if you if that if you
want to link to the variable of that
same name so so these are markups okay
so close that uh copy the link go to the
talk show and uh let's paste the link
here so you can see it later okay so
there a documentation Stam markup
okay comments okay am I making sense so
we so we talked about the EAC lisp do
string markup okay so if you're going to
write emac LP you need to know
that now okay now let's get to the point
so so let's go so let's go to so close
that uh s talk show next what is this
emx block close uh next so back to the
code
okay so if so suppose now suppose you
want to
um uh suppose this function takes a
string
okay my string okay uh this function
takes uh this function wait this going
to be inside the string this function
takes an
AR my string okay and it by convention
you need you should capitalize
it okay so so this function takes a an
argument uh
string
um let's see um you know but basically
so
um sometimes in your doc mentation you
need to put you you you want a single
quote there
because because suppose uh suppose you
want so okay
so let me just create an example and
okay so take a AR my string my string
in must contain a
substring delimitated
by single quote okay let's for example
for example so for example
um okay
sum thing here okay
so for example if the
arc given is this string
it Returns the
returns this okay so you can see let me
show you okay so now evaluate the buffer
now describe function uh describe fun
function X test show the documentation
okay I got something wrong
here uh
wrong number of arguments what's going
on uh okay so my
string let's just print it okay
so but what is going on
here evaluate the per okay it's done now
I don't know what what is the error
before I think that's that uh uh because
I didn't use it I didn't use the
argument let's try it again evaluate the
buffer oh it
works uh I don't know what is the error
before so anyway here is a function okay
so you don't need the let remove the
let uh let's
say you know this is this is a function
evaluate the buffer describe function X
test okay so now you see the
documentation my string must contains a
sub string delim delimitated by single
quote it will return the single quote
okay so the point here is that sometimes
in the documentation you need to have
some kind of code you need to have this
um single quote there
okay so what the Alam maeni did is that
now when you have when you do this it's
emac will complain you actually what you
have to do is now you have to write this
okay so you have to write back
slash equal sign
okay this is what you have to write so
instead of that you have to write this
so [ __ ] Alan McKenzie
okay let me show you this this thing uh
let's go to diet okay so let me show
you uh describe function the add this
your documentation for the add jump to
the source code okay go to the directory
Now search search all files in the in
this directory that contains this uh
back slash equal okay search it so you
are searching all the emac this
code cheers
so timer says I don't code in
emac but I like looking at your video of
efficiency techniques thank you I'm
using keyboard
digma Dey okay that's a good one so you
are looking into you are interested in
keyboards what do you think about those
keyboard those that's a good one okay
but I don't have it
so so anyway let me let me finish
talking about this so you can see here
is all the occurrences of of of
the of
[Music]
the no okay so there's a question can
you just do tick or something no I mean
the the valid way is is you must use
this okay so here all the currencies you
can see the little score bar there are
like a thousands of them so let's show
how many of them are so wait show
them so there areh what is the uh why is
the number
what so there are
225 that contains that markup okay
220 files emac this source code now
let's let's look at the source let's
look at this okay
um let's look at all of them okay
so okay so you can see there are
3,145
occurrences so let me so let me show you
so you can see so this means it [ __ ] up
the inline documentation so every time
you need a single quote now it becomes
this back slash back slash equal sign
okay this is the
crime done by Alan McKenzie
[ __ ] okay Alan McKenzie
[ __ ] he create he made emx into this
in
2015 Alan McKenzie
[ __ ] okay so now every time you need
a single quote now you have to type back
slashback slash
quote not just single quote you you have
to do this for lots of other other kind
of quotes okay or or you you know it
madees it made
emac extremely complex the documentation
string [ __ ] the AL McKenzie [ __ ] it okay
so you can see in emac this sour there
are
3,145 occurrences just so that you know
so so you got to [ __ ] up [ __ ] like
that and when you look at into them
let's say open them open one of
them uh let's see open one of them so
here's the source code see here's the
ACT actual source code it becomes
unreadable you see in this source code
you know this one is Define Mar
Define absolute variable you know from
this spite
run. source code from building emx okay
so you can see this
function and here is the inline
documentation you know here's the inline
documentation so it's trying to explain
you know sometimes the inline
documentation must contain code so you
know it's trying to say this this is the
typical usage okay but now
you can't read it it's like like you
know back slash back slash equal full
thing back SL the [ __ ] Alam
McKenzie before 20 2025 you don't need
to do that okay so this is a crime this
is a
um this is a the the the effect the
Damage
Done by this Alan McKenzie [ __ ]
okay this Alam
McKenzie now he's complaining oh uh hi
guys I'm going to resign because I don't
feel you guys are correct that's good
thing thank you for resigning thank
you so let's look at you know let's look
at so there are 3 thousands of them
let's look at another one so here's
another one source code this is the
Define variable face up test explain so
you can see this this back slash back
slash quote you know things like
that so why did this happen so what is
the issue what why did Alan McKenzie
insisted that you need that in the
beginning he this is a indirect
consequence
because to understand that you need to
look at
um so we go to
you look at the CI quote so this article
emx this dark string CI quote
controversy
2015 basically what the Alan McKenzie
want is that he refused he do not want
people to be able to type curly
quote you see he doesn't want people to
be able to type unic code C quote for
example describe Char then you can see
what character that is so search for
name this is left double quotation mark
cly quote in short okay Alan McKenzie
[ __ ] he does not want people to type
Unicode in the dark string because why
because he thinks that oh uh programming
programming code must be asky only uh
when you have the C quote you can't type
it
[ __ ] Alam McKenzie okay that is the
reason
so so he doesn't want people to have the
curly quote in dark string so he
recommend that you don't use curly quote
but you just use like like this single
uh okay so let me try to do
it okay
because because the double straight
quote is used for string so you have to
escape it so that's why you have backs
slash quote C quote backlash so he want
people to use just asky okay so then you
need the
backslash okay he doesn't want people to
use any kind of unic code in in dark
string as the standard convention okay
so but
then people do want C quote you know
know that that's the reason you know
this this this guy Stefan Monier which
was a leader for the guu emx for about
five five or seven years he's a great
guy he implemented that so
he so instead instead of this you know
for
example see for example this this hack
you know this hack one is the back tick
character you begin it by great accent
character then you end it
by
apostrophe in order for this markup to
link to a function name command name
okay so people I suggested like 10 15
years ago I suggest you know this is a
hack this is a hack why are you using a
backtick and apostrophe you know
backtick that that's a grave Act accent
that's designed for Spanish
French okay apostrophe is apostrophe
they are not matching
pairs by the progress of Technology we
have
Unicode
okay matching pairs so you can actually
match them you know you can
actually
uh match them
by the progress of
Technology but come out this Alam
McKenzie [ __ ] and lots of American
[ __ ] okay a lot of American
[ __ ] this American just know
English monolingual they don't know
nothing else they think you know to
their opinion that programming should
not contain this this this kind of thing
I cannot type
it [ __ ] them
so that line of thought is kind of very
popular among the white you know typical
American industrial coders okay but it's
it's it's dying because you cannot
refuse the progress of Technology that's
what what it is emac is a technology
okay technology improves changes over
the years in 10 years in 20 years so we
go with it you know you don't want to
have a mentality oh but I I like the I
like you know 20 years ago uh technology
when I was a team because I'm used to
that oh what what is what what is this
Cody quote I don't know what the [ __ ] it
is the [ __ ] these people okay so this
kind of sticking to asking only I must
have asking only in programming code
that that thought was very popular in
1990s so of course because Unicode was
not you know Unicode was created in
1990s in 1989 also okay but but
beginning in 2000s it became popular so
by now it's very it's it's like standard
utf8 is a standard encoding for the
website for any programming language in
Java in Goan in Python utf8 unic code
okay so this character the matching Cod
quote is valid
okay so if you came from the 1980s 19
1980s 1990s you are a dinosaur okay so
today's people programmers The Zuma
generation they don't have a problem you
know this is this is natural which is
actually good okay especially when you
need to do a lot math for
example uh let me show you okay
for example right
arrow okay let me let me show it here
okay
so right arrow you know X to x squared
you often need that or you can even do
it this way you can can you see X tox
squ especially when you do a lot math
mathematics you need that okay so for
example let's uh give another example I
can show you
okay there function mapping this symbol
usually is known for is a convention
notation conventional notation in
mathematics
for for for example this in this case
two is mapped to four x squ okay this is
like actual map of a point you know so
many so many of the unical characters
you need it for example another
example
Alpha
Beta
gamma
and Lambda you know you need this all
the time okay so with the Zuma
generation for example in a lot
languages you have that you I mean it's
this unic code is part of the language
okay so let me show you a example
close that go to talk show close that go
to today's talk show showing browser
back to emac go to directory uh link so
I'm starting to learn this Lan proof
system fantastic okay so but let me show
you the unic code part so many languages
today especially those with to do with
with mathematics for example Lin
Julia even hascal Lin Julia hascal for
example they all like embrace the
Unicode because you have to because they
it makes a lot uh variable names or
function names easier to understand okay
so let me show you in their
documentation
okay the so these are official
documentations okay
cheers dependent type Theory okay I'm
starting to learn it it's
fantastic so let me magnify so you can
like see the full Glory of these Unicode
characters
search for Unicode you
see also known as cesium product note
that the x is a Unicode symbol the
judicious use of Unicode improves
legibility and all modern editors have
great support for it in the Lan standard
Library you often see the Greek letters
to denote types and the Unicode symbol
right arrow is a more compact version of
Dash greater than okay so you can see in
this documentation of the link proof
system unic code is um ubiquitous
ubiquitous it's part of the programming
language okay this right arrow this
multiplication sign
course and even Lambda okay and then
then and even they have built ways for
you to type it so that you know the
average programmer don't know how to
type these things but they but they
build it with the editor with the emac
mod link mod or the vs code very popular
so they show you how do you type that
for example to type lower Greek letters
like Alpha Beta gamma to range over
types you can enter this
particular characters by by back SL a
back SLB back SLG okay so you can see
this is the official documentation of
the link language you they use all these
characters including Lambda okay you see
red arrow there and the Greek
letters okay so anyway I I highly
recommend so for those of you into uh
functional programming uh you might look
into link proof system
I'm starting to learn it because this is
one of my goal for my life before I die
you know I'm 50 something I'm pushing 60
so I don't have much time in my life not
like you guys young you know young for
chan people you know mean mean this mean
that oh I have you tried this this this
this I don't have much time to for the
crap my time is limited so I need to
learn something you know that I want to
do so one of them is uh proof systems in
particular type Theory okay so I'm
reading this link I have a great time in
the past week
um okay so anyway this is one example
not just one okay this is one of the
example of a modern programming language
that they Embrace Unicode in fact you
have to use it actually I don't think
you you are forced to use it but it's
like very common in in link source code
okay other example is Julia or hascar
okay so I have article on
that so let me uh search okay so
Link Link learning notes I'm starting to
uh kind of write a tutorial I'm starting
to okay so let's copy that close close
that let's showing browser today's talk
show paste this link link show you there
there it is okay and uh and Link so let
me show you oh yeah so let's go to
search
search unic
code in programming languages
okay so there is
Fess for Fortress programming
language uh and this this article I want
to show you okay programming languages
unic code math symbols in function name
and operator so in this article I
explore what kind of support what degree
of
support of unit code in function names
and uh operator names function names
variable names and operator can you
define an operator in your favorite
programming language that this question
if you can then the next question is can
you have a Unicode math symbol as the
operator name you know some programming
language cannot do that so here is a
exploration and statistics of the
different languages support
cc++ go Java JavaScript python par Ruby
OK cam hascal imagis Julia you know and
so on okay so this this documentation I
wrote like 15 years ago
2010 okay so copy that so this is my
obsession my personal Obsession about
the unic code and you might wonder you
know you might wonder what's a big deal
you know you you you you are stupid why
should you I mean ask is fine you don't
have to use Unicode I mean to what
degree it doesn't improve readability
that
much because you are a idiot okay
Unicode in function name and especially
when you have a operator and you want it
to be Unicode like this okay so let me
increase the font so you can see the
full
Glory you see you see over
there where you have the Circle Cross as
an operator that becomes very
significant if you are doing a lot of
scientific programming okay I have
article on that
too uh so you go down this article is
quite long so what is a function what is
an operator and here this article
programing language design why do you
need operators why don't we all just use
function name and parenthesis why do you
need need like the plus you know or or
multiply the asterisk why do you need it
why don't we be consistent and uniform
always have a function name and
parentheses you know and
arguments well here is a this article
explains programming language design why
you need operators because then you can
see you can see the varieties if you
don't support operators if you don't you
know you can see
progressively how The Operators help
significantly significantly in
readability okay so you can see you know
you you have to go read the article I'm
not going to explain in detail and this
article is from 200 um this article is
from like 10 years ago okay this page is
from 202 too but it was split off from
other articles so this I've written this
like uh wait this article is um maybe
2022 okay so but anyway some article is
like split from other other articles
okay so I think that's it okay so today
we talked about basically we talked
about the Unicode issue why you need
unicode and the Alam McKenzie [ __ ]
up okay so again my point is that in
many today's programming languages
Unicode is just part of the language
okay so you need you want to have that
for example The Fortress language
Fortress language is not well known
Fortress Fortress programming language
is a concurrent programming language
designed for concurrency by the god of
lisp this guy okay guy steel who created
scheme lisp and you know guio one of the
wellknown computer scientist he designed
the Fortress language and in Fortress
language you see this this kind of weird
characters and this right arrow those
are part of the language and this Z
double stroke Z which stand for for uh
which stand for the integers okay they
are part of the language and you see
this angle
quote angle brackets you see they are
part of the Fortress language and
fortres language began in uh 2006 or
something
okay so you see so I documented fully so
let's copy that and put it
here uh
okay so you can see all the links in
today's talk show s talk show today's
talk show okay so Fortress language uh
where is it you see use all these
symbols so my my message is that if you
are a programmer you know the American
industrial programmer you are into C and
C++ and uh rust okay and you think that
oh you cannot you should not use these
weird characters uh programming source
code should be asky only okay my message
to you is go [ __ ]
yourself that's it for today thank you
guys for
watching uh we were going to do some uh
W uh emac this coding but let's forget
it okay because we uh the main topic IC
today we talked about the Unicode that's
a good
topic so let's change the let's change
the title so iMac this so let's see uh
let's change the title
to math symbols and unit code
in programming
languages why should you use use okay
capitalize the sentence and uh make the
H1 also that title showing browser there
it is that's a full title today okay if
you like my pay
me go to c. code c. info go all the way
to the bottom patreon me Amazon gift
card PayPal me if you work as a
professional coder or if you are a
lawyer or whatever uh pay me $100 okay I
need to increase this but I'm not I'm
not a money guy okay so just just send
it to me PayPal one
shot so here's some comments let me
answer the comments and that will be it
for
today youo says why not just make the
pass detect the nest double quoted
string uh well that's another question
you can't really do
that uh well I mean you got issues okay
so this is a do string and you can have
a nested so let's
see
uh you you can have a nested One n you
can you cannot you cannot really have
that wait uh
what let's magnify
okay
so not sure why it was an issue for
passing well I mean what you are saying
is that why can't the passer
automatically pass nested uh brackets
for
example uh why
can't
the pass Auto
detect let's let's say
nested quotes
well the problem is then because this
single double quote they are not
matching characters so this could be you
know so this this line for example it
contain contains a
nested straight double quote okay right
it contains the N straight double quote
so why can't the passer just
automatically detect the nesting well
the pro the issue is there are many
interpretations
so you can think of this is a nested or
you can think of this line as one quot
then one not quoted word followed by a
quoted string you see then you might say
oh well but but if if it's inside the
dark string part then you should
interpret this way or that way it gets
complex okay that's a basically bottom
line
uh this make me want to try
emac uh I've been using Vim for years
for years Vim is pretty good I mean you
don't have to change okay uh you know
you could try emac they are kind of
different because e emac is more of the
philosophy if you want to have a battle
session you want one thing to do
everything okay while vim's philosophy
is more
of just a text editor you know when you
need to do other things you dive into
the Unix sh bash and you know you can
easily switch around you know so this so
you don't have to
switch uh you know that's a long
frequently Asked flame wall between emac
and
Vim t te says you are going to reach a
100 years old and still uh teaching
efficiency and calling out scumback okay
hello Hank Uno been out for 25 years
anyone who want moveies clown that's
correct oh okay so you got that okay bye
guys thank you have a good day and uh
enjoy
your day whatever
um enjoy your day okay so let's see I'm
closing down I'm closing down in one
minute uh so search for pre so let's add
a pre uh
text okay then this code let's bring it
back let's bring it back color it
showing browser so that's what we did
today okay bye
guys pay me don't forget just Amazon
gift card or patreon PayPal okay bye