good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of SCI talk show I'm alive and
today is August 22nd so let's see what
topic we're gonna talk about August 27
20 second noon California time so let's
see what topic are we gonna talk about
so MBTI that's myers-briggs Type
Indicator it's a CD psych psychological
test
everyone loves especially especially
nerds I suppose yeah and I think I'm not
sure but particularly the INTJ you know
kind of type you know that's the type of
person who I who are for example nuts
basically you know the so called
architect type or the things like that
or designer type and I was so much into
that in in the 1990s you know it's you
know psychology test is one of those
dramatic things everyone almost everyone
loves it you know every especially when
you are young you know you always want
to check check out you know who you are
what type of person you are so anyway I
was very much into that though all these
kind of tests and so I was very much
into the you know the myers-briggs
personality test and you know your
temperament stuff and in the 1990s
so I even went and bought a book about
that it's called something it's the
title is like dramas and different
dramas but hold on a second let me let
me check what what are the other topic
suggestions greetings everyone okay so
Michael
Michael how do you what is the letter
Michael mr. Michel M I see a J okay
Michael Michael Pierrot officio okay so
good morning and topics number five and
number three so let's see what they are
topic number five so number three is to
some live coding of : okay and number
five is random okay over my keyboard
blog and stuff okay Emacs JavaScript and
so on so let's okay let's talk about
colon and the Myers Brigg thing yeah hey
hey Zee Tron crazy Z Tron crazy good
name
what but by the way is there any what
does zero mean this is at a storm or
something a gemstone okay so so so there
is this test you probably are aware of
let's see if I can find the link
programming math Emacs programming
topics keyboard topics non tech topics
so okay that's non tech my ass break oh
yeah so my my yes my ass break so what
is such any subject matter in the
universe
you just such sorry int J oh my ass
break okay my ye AR s speak and you are
bound to find it
are you Otis are you schizoid autistic
okay I'm talking about myself
that is my blog about that so I wrote
this blog blog in 2010 you know as a
young person you always have
psychological you know you a lot of
people you know I think large population
are interested in psychological tests
you know self test
and also mostly young people the younger
you are the I mean beginning starting
with thing you are interesting those
kind of things for example Scientology
one of their method of recruiting
recruiting is by giving a personality
test you know there are people on the
street and they have you know these
things personality test you can feel out
and they will send you result but
actually that's you know that's a trick
to recruit you to become a Scientologist
so anyway actually when I was young I
was twenty or something I did that
exactly that you know you know free
personality test so I just you know you
know answer the questions and send it
out and then Scientology they mailed me
contact me and yeah and actually I went
to work for them for two months and that
is actually a you know almost is almost
illegal its abusing you know you are I'm
not actually there you know officially
according to them by the legal documents
you know they have you have to sign
papers but I didn't know anything back
then that you know pretty much you just
go there and you just sign it and turns
out it's not really work actually you
are considered as a volunteer you know
yeah so I did that you know for two
months for them this is in 1991 you know
because after two months you know they
say well you know I'm asking them ways
my way am I going to paid get paid you
know I thought I was going to get paid
you know because to me was a walk you
know it's a job and so what I do for
them is mass mail you know mass mailing
you know before that you don't have
emails back then so it's a envelopes you
know you have to write the address so
I'm writing the address for them you
know the whole day you know just writing
address is you know mass mailing so
anyway it turns out so after two months
they say oh you're gonna bed not yet not
yet but after two months
eventually I got paid but it's like you
know it's it's it's not really pay it's
like $3 an hour it's like take taken if
it is a job it is under you know the
minimum wage you know it's illegal but
so it turns out it's actually not a job
technically because when I you know when
when I signed up they have me sign
papers that paper says that you know you
are volunteering for the church that's
what you know basically so anyway so I
left and I have always been very much
interested in psychology or this type of
things psychology psychology
brainwashing the marketing you know
persuasion all these kind of things are
related and coat you know how they how
can someone you know they are quite a
few coats out there and many of them are
huge you know and also when it becomes
big it's you know religion you call
religion they are of the similar similar
nature but code and religion is you know
some minor some differences but
typically code when you are small you
are code when you are really large you
you just become you just go at religion
okay so anyway code religion and so
basically you see when you are caught I
mean even in programming communities we
have like phenomenons of code Emacs is
an example I would say okay Perl
programmers back then it's a you know
it's a code and you know you pearl died
out so so anyway that's programming and
it's kind of almost you can say it's
almost harmless in me you know you
anyway so there are codes there are many
other codes some some of them have mass
suicide you know the leader can just say
okay today is today we're gonna add or
die then hold the people to it so you
see codes are codes and these are
tremendously powerful you know the you
typically code has one single leader so
this person you know
you know there are many similar act you
know actually I don't want to mention it
because you you you know Google start to
censor you things like that because some
of these are very powerful
you know they so anyway so coats yeah so
typically there's one leader and this
person has the power you know his
personality and his abilities you know
persuasion your observation and so on
charisma typically charisma is required
you have to be handsome okay that is
actually one of the main attraction for
people to listen to you to follow you
it is some somewhat fundamental in you
know among human animals you you know so
co-leader so if they have the ability to
you see to control millions of people
you know tens tens of thousands hundred
thousands of media and even tell them
you know you typically tell them to give
you money and you know they lay they
have you know so many mentions over the
you know world so yeah code so so so
this subject I'm attracted to you know
code brainwashing marketing you know
persuasions slogans they are all related
anyway part another you know the other
thing we were talking about personality
tests so I was also very much interested
in that by the way so person as I'm
mission before personality test is one
of the dramatic or cornerstone I don't I
don't know if I use that word correctly
but it's one of the thing that it's tied
to coat or or you know Hold'em what was
I saying you you could say it's one of
the method for coats to to to to grab
you something something like that I'm
nothing
King clearly I know so but anyway let's
go back to psychological test so there
are so many including this also IQ test
you know controversial acute test codes
and so you look at psychological tests
you know basically they they didn't do
much okay
for example let's talk about these Myers
Brigg thing you know so back then in
1990s I read this book please understand
me character and temperament types david
history Marilyn Bates anyway today we
are familiar with the Myers Brigg like
INTJ INTP you know like sixteen types by
the way so so there is this book this is
great book I'm gonna talk about them
okay and this video is talk about ski so
it what what it means
so anyway ski soda is one of the
personality disorder by psychiatrists
you know according to psychiatrists they
are like fifteen or you know twenty of
them called personality disorders which
means you know each of us has a
personality but when bent but when a
particular personality becomes so
extreme that you cannot function in
society for example you cannot get a job
because us screw-up of because of your
particular extreme personality so if
your personality is to such extreme that
you cannot function in society they call
it disorder you know pull so you have so
that's that's why it's personality
disorder now quite a few and I turned
out to be schizoid okay you know some
people find me weird you know a lot of
people saying I'm controversial and so
on but anyway basically I have I would
say my out schizoid personality which
basically means loners okay you prefer
to do everything along you don't make
friends yeah almost no friends in your
if you don't because you don't make them
you don't you don't you don't want to
everything is cold so basically a lot of
mathematicians and nerds you know
program Mossad like that you know to do
two different degrees so anyway back to
the so there are a lot of things to say
here and and let's talk about the miles
break so let's see so actually there are
variations you know you can go to
Wikipedia and you can read the history
of this test so so the history
temperament sorter okay this is a
different one but but basically they are
the same you see so this this is a
variation the history temperament sorter
and you know according to Wikipedia it
says it is close closely associated with
the myers-briggs Type Indicator
okay so let's look at the myers-briggs
Type Indicator so I mean if you are not
familiar you you probably are familiar
if you are on the internet you know this
so back back in 1990s I you know I've
seen this test I don't remember where I
think online I don't remember if it's
online or not yeah I think it's online
it is around 1997 now this is in the
very early days of internet you know you
don't have not like today know Wikipedia
you know nothing like that so I think I
found I think I think I first heard of
it online I am Not sure I forgot but
then then I went to the library back
back in 1990 90s I go to the library
every day you know physical libraries
and I read this book you know so so back
in 1997 I was like 28 or something
let's see 2068
so in year 2000 I am 30
let's see 32 so in year 2000 I'm 32 so
in 1997 I am like 28 or something and
when you are young you know what you
like when you are a teen or or in your
early twenties like some of you a lot
you know a lot of people following me
because you know because we have close
personalities so some of you if you are
lost you know I can give you some advice
so so when you are younger like
20-something you tends to sometimes you
know for some people you are lost you
don't know oh maybe I have you know some
sort of psychological disorder I'm just
different from other people or maybe you
have bipolar you know so they call it
bipolar disorder meaning maniac maniac
depressive and by the way also many of
these psychological terminologies they
change it over the 20 years you know 30
years because part of it has also to do
with political correctness you know part
of it has to do with that and part of it
has to do with you know psychiatry and
psychology they are not hard sciences so
they they kind of also change change
views and improve and so on so so for
example many of the personality
disorders by psychiatry state they have
a like a dictionary like a reference you
know these are the personality disorders
in their names
this this bipolar is one of them
depressed depression is one of them
depressive there's histrionic which is a
person personality type who needs to get
attention all the time like he is acting
you know you know he is loud and
shouting and all the time because he
needed you know he that's why these are
you know these are personalities you
know like extrovert so so the histrionic
type of personality is such that his
extreme extra
but to us such a degree not not just
extrovert but he has to like make noises
like you know he has to be the center of
attention at all times so yes that is
make me a maniac and you know narcissism
there's you know many quite a few so the
the the the the histrionic Personality
Disorder okay then there is also
dependent how do you go there are so
many main names okay dear actually let's
let's go to let's just look up schizoid
because I am so maybe that's interesting
schizoid personality you know on
Wikipedia you have article and I've been
checking it every two years also since
like 10 years ago
they of course they change and you know
they become larger and larger and more
complex before it's just few pages now
it's like 20 pages see when let's
magnify okay wait hold on saying 1 2 3 4
5 6 7 8 9 10 yeah now it's like 20 pages
wait this is the this is the phone
version I don't like the phone version
apparently today if you search you know
something and arrived on Wikipedia they
tends to be often they becomes the phone
mobile version so that means you know
from that fact you can see that mobile
is scanning a lot of traffic you know
it's I think it's it's already to have
taken over desktop or laptop because
most people you know foam everyone has a
phone anyway so here is the schizoid
personality disorder on Wikipedia and
and you can you can read it but
basically it's loners who doesn't who
must do everything alone because he
prefer I prefer so well it's not know
you know it's not like I insist or I
particularly want to it's just
just lets you just happens you just like
that's just you happen to be that way
that you know that's the situation so
you know I don't make friends you know a
lot in fact friends makes schizoid
personalities okay it makes you and
makes me uncomfortable like okay so this
so that's why you know I'm weird and
people like oh that's you know weird guy
you don't you know associate because
like like you guys for example you know
I you know I'd like you guys you know I
but like sometimes people my followers
reach out you know they start to hey
let's do something together or something
you know I cannot yeah I don't I just I
don't want to you know it's not like I
think about it oh I don't want it's just
like it doesn't make doesn't work
doesn't like like I if for example what
one quick way to understand it is that
you know typical normal people okay you
have like guys night out especially in
America you know something like guys
night out where a bunch of guys you know
your friends you got you go to a bar or
you you go to play polkas together you
know have fun I cannot have that fun you
know i i'm i'm i cannot i if it makes me
very nervous you know if i go to a bar
I feel nervous you know like everyone is
having fun you know logically I can
understand you know yeah just go they'll
say whatever but you cannot you know you
it's not your nature you cannot do it so
that's kind of you know the schizoid
personality disorder so and I wanted to
show you show you some of the others
just for illustration so here is a bunch
of personality disorders actually let me
go back and open a new page
you know so you get to see what are the
different personality disorders by the
way like I mentioned it's not exactly a
disorder is it's it's it's somewhat a
disorder only when you are such a - such
a extreme degree you you can never work
in a job or things like that and never
have relations things like that so
classification you know they have these
psychiatrists they have these icd-11
things like that and dsm-5 you know
those they're jargons basically those
are like a dictionary or reference book
that defines you know say oh when is it
you know what type of disorder is is
characteristics you know symptoms you
know they have the psychologist has that
so this one is you know the icd-11 is
from World Health Organization that and
that stands for international
classification of diseases okay and then
the other one dsm-5 is by American
Psychiatric Association okay so let me
give you some like some of the names
let's see I think yeah okay here is a
cluster okay so they have like clusters
cluster cluster a is odd or eccentric
disorders okay they include paranoid
personality disorder yeah you know like
especially in my group my followers and
people are paranoid all the time like
like the you know complete the hackers
the programmers the cryptography you
know those they're paranoid about good
the government about you know
persecution all the time I'm not that
much you know that so so anyway cluster
a is odd or eccentric disorders so they
include paranoid personality disorder
schizoid okay then schizotypal
personality disorder now another thing
interesting about these names is that
about the schizoid is that the schizoid
they have several derivative names for
example you have the word skis or
by the way there's a Star Trek show one
episode called the schizoid man you know
this a doctor who is old and is going to
die but he's like a genius he invented
mr. data oh no he he he taught the
inventor of mr. data anyway so that that
episode is called the schizoid man and
there's also a song called the schizoid
man you know you can look up on YouTube
so anyways the with the word schizoid
has many variations so schizoid then you
also have skis or people then Oh then
then you have the what is the disorder
that you have illusions like you
actually hear things there's a you know
that there's a movie made out of it a
beautiful mind that mathematicians got
that disorder where you actually hear
and hear things that nuts that's not
there that's kind of a biological
disorder schizophrenia yes schizophrenia
so so you see skis of skis over the
world has very several variation
schizoid schizotypal then schizophrenia
now it's critical to understand that
schizophrenia is totally different from
from the schizoid and from the schizoid
tipo schizophrenia is kind of is someone
who have did delusions like I mean you
actually see things that's not there or
you hear things that's not there you
know these it's somewhat more biological
or new new around your brain you know
something some something of that nature
ok so it's very different okay all these
other disorders they are not like that
they are not they don't have delusions
you know so so anyways schizophrenia
it's actually not listed here because
it's not schizophrenia is not a
personality disorder it's actually
something it's quite serious you don't
you don't want to have that so anyway so
back to the personality odd or eccentric
disorders so you have paranoid schizoid
schizotypal now another interesting
information that many of these are kind
of similar like like you read it and
they share many many aspects like like
you know for example depression they
happen in quite a few of them then
prefer to be along they also happen
somewhat for example paranoid if you are
a paranoid you know personality like a
social like your socio and you know you
get paranoid but you probably tends to
like to be alone I mean I'm you know
introvert you know anyway so many of
these shared things share aspects and
also let me say again you know site
psychology and psychiatry they are not
hard sciences like math or physics so
you know you can read them but you know
you'd like it's not absolute you know
you can be you know it another way
another another thing to say is that
most people you know typically they say
most people everyone we all kind of have
you know can identify with some part of
it you know and or experience some of
these disorders you know for some period
in your life so you know it's not
absolute just just remember that it's
not absolute so anyway so you have this
disorder ski so tipo is kind of weird
okay so I don't it's you know like like
some of these disorders if you are not
like that it's hard to understand so
skis OT pole you know I I'm not often
Adam I'm not quite sure exactly you know
what exactly they it's like Perry okay
so it's you know some of the symptoms
are ideas
of reference okay so he says at least
five of the following symptoms must be
present I ideas of reference I have no
idea what that is
okay strange of strange beliefs or
magical thinking okay
abnormal perceptual experiences okay
strange thinking and speech okay
paranoia okay inappropriate or
constricted effect okay
strange behavior or appearance okay lack
of close friends okay
which by the way this is shared by
schizoid personality disorder and also
another is another one is excessive
social anxiety and so on so anyway yeah
III kind of get what this personality is
the ski so tipo personality disorder is
you know sometimes you read history or
you know historical figures you might
run into
mystics mystics like like in history you
have some some people they are mistakes
like they always talk about things like
it's it's hard to understand you know
it's like very strange it's like out of
this world Cosmo you know that kind of
people those ask schizotypal personality
disorder okay so you can see strange
beliefs or magical thinking you know
abnormal perceptual experiences yeah
that that's what they are they could
what's the word mystics or I think it's
called mystics
there are several prominent very famous
historical figures who are mystics okay
there it is another psychological test
am i a mystic can telltale science you
might be a mistake
typically this this website is geared
for women I'm pretty sure mysticism okay
so see Christian mysticism you know yeah
some people are like that
but actually I'm not interested in mr.
C's Cesar Marco actually I want to find
some examples of famous people who are
considered mistakes anyone know you know
for example there's a German I mean not
not German Russian yeah Russian guy who
is like very famous you know who is
considered a mistake you know mistakes
people I never actually understand you
know I cannot get what you know with the
very strange you know they talking about
the cosmos all the time actually I have
a friend on Twitter who is following me
now he is a transgender ok it's it's
open information so he you know I could
yeah yeah spoon yeah what Rasputin I've
came across that name a doctor he's
considered a mistake no you know you
don't know what is his story like what
what's going on yeah I like I don't I
don't understand
so what what's your impression of rest
puddings like tell tell me you know type
it like what's his story
so anyway I have a friend on you know I
met online he's very you know he's not
the average you know the normal people
like okay like me okay he's kind of
weird but I highly respect and you know
whenever I write something when he
replies there's information I especially
programming very technical topic and he
post something and that answered my
question often you know oh yeah that
answered my question typically I don't
get that because all my followers you
know when you actually have a like when
you would when you post some opinion
about Linux or programming this you know
you you have a lot you know replies and
typically you know like they say okay
have you tried this have you look at
that you know but you know you often
usually most of the time I look at them
yeah I have seen their hundred times
since 10 years ago oh you
something they are into I'm not
interested you know typically like that
but you know when I do my language
research often I have particular
specific questions and whenever I post
that nobody answered it well sometimes
they do you know so what I have a
question I really want to get answered
but you cannot find the answer on Stack
Overflow because it's not a you know no
more question but but you know I need to
know the answer but typically there are
people who know the answer typically not
just average for professor they need
they need to be kind of very specialized
and they can answer your question not
necessarily in the form that they give
you a direct answer but rather their
knowledge and you know they have this
very deep and broad knowledge you know
in some specialized and guide so they
see the question it may be the first
time this they are seeing the question
they never they never see a thought like
that before but but but however because
they know so much about in this area
they can they can tell you you know the
answer to you know to that question you
know we all you you it's a you know you
shouldn't think of that way instead of
think of this way for example that's one
of their answer and then when I read it
oh yeah that makes sense you know that
that's that's great answer but yeah so
anyway so typically I had one way I
actually have a question I don't get
answers like I hate it you know but
sometimes I do like you know once in
awhile and so that guy you know that my
friend on Twitter
I think he's somewhat mistake he often
they gave me the you know answers about
things yeah so so mystics anyway so that
there's this you know schizotypal
personality yeah that's you know very
strange so anyway back to the list of
personality personality disorders so
paranoid schizoid skills
so tipo then the cluster B which is
dramatic emotional or erratic disorders
okay then we have antisocial okay and a
social disorder borderline personality
personality disorder now let me tell you
what that is that that is someone who is
okay yeah okay let's just read Wikipedia
it's it's borderline personality
disorder is pervasive pattern or abrupt
mood swings instability in relationships
self-image identity behavior and an
effect of often leading to self-harm
yeah that's what I was going to say you
know today you if you go into the teens
community especially girls you you you
see the lot of them like to cut
themselves you know and that that is
kind of like that poor borderline
personality disorder they they need they
are unstable in relationships but they
and also they need okay anyway that's
borderline
okay that's and then there is histrionic
Personality Disorder these these are
type of people who needs to make drama
all the time you know and narcistic
okay now sis narcistic is you know
loving yourself like I'm the greatest
I'm the most beautiful you know to a
extreme degree and and that can get bad
you know aggression psychopathy and sad
ism okay then then another class Krista
see anxious or fearful disorders yeah so
that you have avoidant personality
disorder this is kind of so avoidant is
like a social you know you you you don't
do you don't you don't go to any parties
you know you want to avoid yeah so it
says pervasive feeling of social in hip
inhibition and inadequacy
extreme sensitivity to negative
evaluation and then you have dependent
personality disorder which is someone
who always needs other people's approval
like your boyfriend/girlfriend
so it says pervasive psychological need
to be cared or by other people yeah then
then there's a bit obsessive compulsive
personality disorder which is you need
to wash your hands several times a day
[Laughter]
anyway so so they are you know these are
the basic ones personality sodas you
know I read them so personality
disorders and and we were talking about
personality tests okay so let's talk
about personality test you know it so
back then I was into the myers-briggs
you know so much you know so I found out
I'm int J or int P weight you know I'm
kind of like did I say it here's let's
name is such high and he
hi and TJ okay I must I must have said
it somewhere maybe another face so maybe
he's not on my block after that but I I
was like int Jo I and he II in between I
mean here's some something like that and
I'm not sick so anyway so what I want to
say is is about okay so there are so
many personality personality disorders
so my question is you know since you
know this is I've been reading psycho
psychology books and there's actually
several interesting books you know when
you dive into psychology and psychiatry
you have you know this fluid and Jung
and you know the theories and the you
are it's kind of like you are going into
some kind of mysterious land okay they
do psychoanalysis on person you know on
your you know then then then some branch
kind of pseudoscience then you have
dreams about analysis of dreams you know
you get into all these directions so
that's kind that's kind of the
psychology is like that it's not hard
science and often it becomes
pseudoscience see often so so yeah I was
reading you know into these kind of
things psychology personality disorders
you know the mind you know the end and
persuasion you know public relations
marketing influence tact is kind of part
of it part of it also you know code so
these things
so the anyway let's go back to the
personality tests so there are many
types so the question to me is what is
their significance
okay that is a question for example the
Myers
okay you found out you are INTJ you know
and typically when you find out you are
like happy oh oh my god this this
describes me you know and all the
descriptions they read okay
you are int J or ye and TJ okay so you
Rin let's say int P oh no I was int P
naught J I I think I was I ain't int P
oh yeah some somewhere here int P E and
T P oh yeah int P or INTP that's the
closest that was me so when you when you
see these you know typically you know
I've seen a lot people you know they
they do the test and then you read the
description then oh my god I'm so happy
you know this this is me exactly I'm the
best architect so the question is and by
the way they're used
they are also formed they I'm sure they
are today but even 20 years ago there's
yahoogroups you know we're discussion
forums one of them is like int P you
know you know people get together and
also you will see our social networks
like Twitter like some people
programmers they will say I am int P you
know things like that so the question is
what is the validity of these
psychological personality tests what is
the validity I mean is they actually
does it actually is it scientific does
actually actually measure something I
mean does it actually measure something
you know oh is it just I mean what does
it yeah the validity you know what would
so so you know that is a question and I
have you know I I have thought about
this and my answer is that you know I
don't remember I don't think I've read
you know I haven't seen other people
asking that know but probably seen
articles by anyway so my answer to that
question is you know I thought about
this
personality tests you know you cannot
say they are invalid okay it's not it's
not true that they are invalid but
however you could say that they are they
are of little significance like almost
nope no practical value okay
why for example color you know what what
what is your favorite color that
question constitutes a personality test
what is your favorite color so type your
favorite color now type it you know as
lots of comments I'm going to beat them
so what is your favorite color type it
so that actually constitute that one one
of the simplest personality test
why because I mean it does tell you
something because color in different
cultures let's limit it to America
because you know I mean USA so color you
know color usually have some cultural
color has usually some kind of
association with certain meaning or
qualities in almost any culture for is
for example black is typically talk you
know like dark maybe you don't want to
be seen or you want you are into the
evil side you know you you owe you you
know or power you know that's like black
on the other hand why it is like purity
purity angel you know white you know red
is flashy you know you know flashy and
the flamboyant you know red the color
red and pink you know I guess well pink
this today a lot women you know they
like pink you know so and green for
example green we associate with trees
you know today is the green environment
the green movement the green party queen
you know it's like peace you know peace
so when you ask someone what's your
favorite
they give you answer that tells you
something okay that is a valid you know
psychological test
I mean personality test it is you know
valid you know if you like talk then I
know something about you not too much
but I kind of you know kind of added a
little piece of information you know but
on the other hand if you say your
favorite color is black is white then I
know you know you see they are different
information it does make sense it tells
you a little bit something about
yourself so anyway so this is a simple
example of a personality test
so you you cannot say it's invalid it is
married to some degree it does you know
it contains some information but it is
almost useless
you see that's that that is my answer
that is the key it's almost useless what
does it you know what am I gonna do with
that but you know what color you like
what am I gonna do with it it's almost
useless here's a here's a punch line ok
here's a punch line
when you talk to people you already for
example if I talk to you guys okay
Benjamin yeah whoever has commented
Benjamin okay if I make you face to face
then I know a lot about you a ton about
you then any of these personality tests
okay you can tell me you are int J or
whatever but if I me if I met you you
know I don't have to probe for your
preferences at you know I think you know
like you go out you meet your boss
co-workers you know you you you know
people right your schoolmates you know
your roommates you know them sometimes
you know them for just one for one hour
you made some new friends for one hour
that's it you got some impression for
some other people you met them for a
week you know them for months or years
you know your work mate or school mates
or you make when you meet people even
within our one hour you get a whole lot
of information those information is like
it's like it's
it's almost like you know you can say it
it's just like just it's just like he
said you know it's like he it's a
personality test it's a result of a
personality test you see so so so in
this way you can see so for example if
you know someone for a year he you know
you don't need to know what what is his
INTP or you know isfp you know one of
these 16 things you don't need to know
you actually know them you know he
doesn't need to give you this thing but
if you know him for for for a year
roommate or school may for example you
know far more about him than this you
know this this classification
information that is that is the thing so
you see that these all these personality
tests they actually they are kind of
valid but they actually they are not in
any way they are not that useful okay
it's it's it when you actually meet
people that that information is far
beyond you know above this these
personality tests okay that's that's
what I'm good that's that's that's not
what I'm saying about about this
question the validity the value of
personality test but there's more okay
so anyway let me also mention them the
Myers Brigg okay they are not created by
professional psychologists okay this
might break - break and variations like
the history temperament and dip they are
quite a lot like on internet you know
young people love that you know
especially girls you know you women they
have lots of more tests you know like
what dress tells you know how you dress
tells what kind of person you are though
you know women's magazine girls magazine
they have that every almost every month
you know personality tests so anyway so
I want to mention you know this history
temperament or the Maya speak they are
crack they are created by
not by professional psychiatrist or
psychologist they are just created by
someone basically the background story
is that they are they are you know some
I think it's created by mom mommy and
daughter pea want one of these okay
Catherine cook bridges and her daughter
is about Briggs Myers okay mom daughter
pea they are not professional
psychologists or anything they just
happen to create it quick
they just happen to create it you know
begin somewhere with some kind of test
then they found out it makes money for
them then it grew that's the basic story
of the history so you see it's it's
Heidi you know it's a questionable so
the next question is is is okay so but
what if you ask professional
psychologist you know who actually has
you know tries to do things
scientifically you know like I mentioned
psychology is not a hard science so
there are many even professional ones
they are kind of you know wishy-washy
but you cannot say it's totally
because they does they actually do use
scientific methods in the statistics to
gather certain information and many many
of this information is actually very
useful they have practical impact okay
so that's psychologist
so my question next question is so you
go act you know you look into the actual
professional psychologist you know with
good research you look at them what can
you what do they say what do they say
about personality tests okay they do
have one and that is called the big five
okay I learned this from Peter Jordan
Pederson let me find it okay so Jordan
mr. Peterson
he has a website understand myself you
know there's I think you have to pay I
think so anyway
this website I did you know I didn't
look into but anyway but anyway the
professional psychologist they they do
have a personality test that is called
Big Five I mean no muss Big Five okay
let's let's see if I can find it
big ok so it's not there but anyway fake
Otteson and I'm a pony autoscent test
autism test agoraphobia stuff let's see
okay so this is this book you can buy
this girl this women love Emir she
researched into the history of the
meersburg and also she went to interview
but you know today they are like a
crackpot they are like they are just
money-making organizations
she gave details she has written several
blogs about it you know several pages
you can read I read them and then and
you know which is kind of like excerpt
from her book basically so these
organizations not in the Myers Brigg you
know this organization behind it they
are just they are just like you know
they just want to make money they are
nothing scientific or anything so if you
you know you can read it check it out
and if you like it buy it so let me post
that so ok back to the topic okay the
what is the okay the big five these are
the big five okay now let's see what's
the name okay let me read it this is
from Wikipedia so that you just you can
search the Big Five personality traits
okay
so this is from professional
psychologists they you know so like him
like I said or personality or
personality test they do measure
something
but it's not necessarily useful but
however because they do actually give
you certain information so that's kind
of useful so so professional
psychologists they have designed
actually a set of tests they call these
the big five or the Big Five personality
traits that I measure kind of you know
they have all parameters so five
parameters they measure a person like
you know like the int P or whatever so
the five are openness to experience or
inventive curious versus consistent
cautious okay
conscientiousness which is that's kind
of a wrong use of the word by anyway it
means efficient organized was as easy
going in careless so I'm like careless
on the other hand for example religious
people are like probably more efficient
organized you know traditional people
then extraversion basically meaning
introvert or extrovert okay then
agreeableness basically means you are
very friendly or you are always
competitive and and neuroticism
neuroticism basically means you are
always nervous self-doubt or very
competent okay so these are the you know
from professional psychologists they
give these five variables and you know
they they think of these five as you
know the fundamental variables to
measure personality so anyway so that's
that's about that yet so that's about
what I have to say for ya for now I
guess let's see
you know autism today is become
fashionable this is especially among the
young the social justice type of people
you know this guy you know to me so
autism a lot of people you know my
followers sometimes they tell me you are
autistic you know I guess that's to some
degree true I don't know because all
these personality disorders and autism
you know it's kind of all related you
know you can't be sure exactly what you
know it's just a label you know you
label you put a label to people and but
anyway autism seems to become
fashionable also according to studies
supposedly autism autistic people have
increased in the past 10 or 20 years
among adults supposedly you don't know
for sure but but today one thing for
sure is that on Twitter you can see a
lot of people it becomes fashionable
because you know these people they like
to say oh I'm autistic
oh oh oh you need to help autistic
people I think it's just okay
for you know they you know I could say
oh I'm you know I'm sorry I'm autistic
please help me you know I I don't have a
job I give him I give me money you know
give me him PayPal me
nobody's you know this guy is a
scam you know he poses something he
people's this garbage okay he posed it's
a thread on Twitter and I looked it I
look at that you know if you actually
want to compare autism I'm more autistic
than you you know he says oh I don't
want to do laundry because I'm autistic
you know he says you know of himself you
know and he you know but to me that's
just that's you know you you are you
know you are a you know the social just
is crap you know so I answered you know
I answered you know I answered rather
without you know directory and he just
he just blocked me right away
which you know whenever people do that I
typically consider them as someone who
is not a bad person okay
anyway that's today's you know autism
becomes popular you know everyone is
autistic we need to help them every
everyone is a victim that's right
so you know and people watching and I
have been talking for an hour so now
it's questions and answers session let's
see of official word for that you know
this is that's the public relations talk
now guys now it's questions and sessions
answer session so let me read the
comments so okay let me to do let me do
this quickly so if I can so type
questions right now okay I'm gonna go
through them quickly type questions now
so with the second make the correct
pronounce a okay Michael says is the
correct pronunciation of my name
I'm a polish Xetra I came from Z Tron
and on English its lemon
oh it's wrong so Michael is the correct
pronunciation what I don't know what how
it's pronounced Mik Mik saw me Shaw I
don't know okay so bathroom you say Sam
I was always interested in these
psychological topics as well nice to see
we are very much alike in this aspect
when we says sometimes I analyze
advertisements out of interest today I
did that for the last time roast roast
Oh about programming okay today we are
supposed to do some Golan but it's too
late you
sorry guys so we have to do that
tomorrow actually that's nice because
technique or topic and non-technical
topic it's better to separate them yeah
so we do
Golan tomorrow or something : we need to
pick something to code in anyway so so
micro says so micro says I mean I know
the risk cause it is another method to
get people in communities and you never
know what the interests talking about
codes what do you think about circus
folks so what does circus folks me MSS
okay so oh that I think that is idiotic
one day you know that's from you know
that this is a popular YouTube Linux
people UNIX you know again UNIX
philosophy can his name is what's his
name did I can remember the name but
usually why I'm talking I don't Smith
okay
missing the other parts what's his name
guys the YouTube somethings Lucas Smith
you know so he's technical YouTube he
often talks about Linux linguistics
related things because I know some of my
followers tells me we share interests
and one day I watched one of his video I
think I yeah this this I think wait what
is this this is a forum actually
so they actually have a project going on
Feliz I didn't know hegemony Israel
great to see you hey what's up we are
about to end we were so today we were
talking about personality tests you know
also the personality test especially the
Mayas break
you know the intp INTJ thing and today
we were talking about personality
disorders too in psychology stuff and
right now I'm just reading the comments
so so mas says right you are in Israel
same MSS says that's a great general
generalization so I don't know what is
success people ok units philosophy sir
class is good in theory but won't go
anywhere so they actually have a group
like a project going on because I
thought it's just a website a web page
that least some I could be placement
tools that page is Christ City you know
that's it's really very City so the
people are mixed pack and one of the
reason you want go anywhere sadly the
distinct way he's a single user circus
is fun bunch of Tours okay right but I
thought it's just a list of two
replacements also so what why what's
with the name you need boomers that is
Duke Smith that's the name he call
himself that oh oh is that what's the
story
he's at a meme or what Unabomber
Oh sir class is a project okay is TP
okay I mean I keep getting int P
horoscope something to associate with
generalities Osterman is logical
Oh Ted guy let me show you something
about that Ted guy the Unabomber hey you
misspelled oh my god
Israel you miss you misspelled that word
all the time
uni bummer bo m ER not uni boomer that's
why that's how you spell it
really no I don't think so oh he's a
making a joke okay okay I get it
yeah so let me tell you because I
actually read the whole thing and I
annotated that whole thing only bummer
manifesto okay I guess YouTube is going
to censor me now I cannot I cannot turn
on to make money anymore so oh god I'd
so you know we live in this situation so
anyway so here it is
una palma manifesto okay uyuni boomer I
bet it you know the whole thing and I
annotated it for example you go to
sections and actually I have a list of
arrows he you know I correction to his
oh I moved them to the pages anyway so
corrections to miss misspelled in so any
you know any errors so anyway for for
example so you know section 38 surrogate
surrogate activities
you know that's my annotation you know
for example heroes sheet oh who is he
you know I I have they I explained he is
Japanese Emperor and so on and let's see
the power process over socialization you
know I have lots of so I did with the
whole thing and have lots of annotations
and back then I thought you know I
thought this guy is a nut job because
mode because the first half of the
manifesto is
criticism of the left in USA then the
second part the second half of the
article of the manifesto is basically
extreme views about he wants to ban
technology basically he wants to he want
us to go back to the you know basics
like you know living in living huts
things like that
yeah tape Carrie Davis had schizophrenia
you know that's kind of that's a
debilitating thing to have to
schizophrenia let me finish reading the
comments here so anyway back to the
manifesto basically the first part part
the first half criticizes American left
the second part is the extreme view
about he wants to ban technology he want
you know no almost like going back to I
don't know I am age or something but so
back then when I read this in in
nineteen in year 2000 something 2004
around there 2005 my opinion is that the
criticism on the left is is very is
correct but however I was complaining
because there is no criticism of
American right you know the Hawks you
know George W Bush was ruling then you
know the Iraq war which is like totally
for fake reasons Iraq war that you you
know you killed with you know American
we killed thousands you know five to six
thousands of severe civilians all this
was you know Iraq war so in this
manifesto there's no criticism zero of
the American right it's so oh just
criticism of the left so that was my
criticism of it you know I was thinking
yeah you know it's been the second part
about going backwards you know no
technology he wants to ban technology
that's really bad you know I saw
so my view back then is no technology
actually will help us you know solve
some of these problems that's back then
okay but today my god you know so today
as we know since you know since the past
four years there is a rise of certain
you know society America totally changed
and he's criticism on the left or have
came true you know I was surprised that
you know really because you know it's
this article has been mentioned now and
then today and I read it as you know
it's just amazing all these criticisms
has come true and you know also some of
the his reasons to ban technology you
see so as today we have seen all the
giant corporations you know they are
they are doing censorship they are going
into the direction of dictatorship you
know what what what can you say so
it's pretty you know so you know for my
point of view at least it's free it's
pretty bad it's getting pretty bad so a
lot more comments okay so hold on a
second let me read okay I need I need to
get a drink now so let's have my apple
juice
as usual I'm gonna show you my drink
apple juice so we're gonna finish about
five more minutes five more minutes and
we are done okay so five more minutes
and view out there if you like my stuff
put money in my pockets okay PayPal
whatever you know where to find the
links on my website so I'm gonna you
know just finish reading the comments
comments and
yeah I gotta stop maybe I should skip
them because boys coming
okay so Rasputin is a is this Russian
mistake so X Dark Prince says SK x-cart
X a cart is a hack who copied Buddha
ratones also copied Buddha I don't know
who that is the West oriented the West
Orion oriental Isis the SS mystic I
don't think so yeah Dark Prince you are
kind of you know you are often kind of
like extreme you know you don't say it's
not like that
it's not like you know it's like Oh
wholesale this group did something to
that group so doctrine says Russian
mysticism is due to deep Iranian
influence and they are real mistakes in
the past
aesthetics okay yeah you know and also
when you study these things they take
yeah they become you know they are used
so you also dragon Buddhism in Hindu you
know region kind of getting very complex
man black yellow purple so so you guys
favorite color flag okay
black black z trunk yellow and purple
okay that's that's why it's lemons it
wrong and Nicholas says cien cien that's
okay that's a opportunity to show my CSS
website let's see see on where is young
OC yeah okay because dark indigo okay
this match is now off of you Japan white
is associated with death okay what if
one has no favorite color if I find it
hard to quantify how good colors
compared to them you just have to pick
one you know it's like you know that's
the that's that's the thing that's the
thing about psychological tests
personality tests you just have to pick
one
well message you know helpful review I
don't know you know avoid if you want to
post something avoid you know swear
words of that okay don't don't type the
sensitive words okay so okay so I got a
I got can't finish this person intestine
okay so are there new questions no new
comments so okay I'm gonna read the
questions to address to me okay Benjamin
says sorry how do you get your website
ranked so high D on such ancients I want
to make a popular website - oh because I
do underhand tactics you know it's
called it's called black hat is SEO okay
well I do rank I don't well I don't know
because I read a lot you know Emacs
basically nobody else does eMac this
part in particular in Unicode you know
and otherwise you know a lot programmers
they also like me they write a lot but
typically in a blog format that's not
good okay if you want some article to
persist you don't want to writing a blog
in style you want to don't you know
rather you want to try to write in a
Wikipedia style which is like everything
is independent and fully explained and
you know in you know independent
articles article by article not blogging
not oh today I feel like Oh today today
I run into this problem and this is
here's how you solve it no let's blog
and that's also how to you know if you
want write or how to how to is also good
but you write it and by the way my
website is actually not popular it it
seems too popular to you because you are
a nerd it's not popular at all and you
don't make money out of it okay you
cannot make enough living for for living
you know basically each 1000 page view
you get one dollar okay same thing for
YouTube you know if they are you know if
YouTube says 1000 views you get one
dollar so if you have you know 1 million
views you get $1,000
roughly ok you don't make money so any
any way so a short advice is that if you
are going to blog about programming
languages you know programming
stuff and you are thinking oh maybe you
can make money or even if you are
thinking maybe you can become somewhat
popular forget it you will not become
popular and oh and even among
programmers at all because the popular
sites are those fried up by corporations
you know like basically for example
w3schools
spammy spammy sites with very bad
information incorrect information those
are popular those are like 10,000 times
you know more popular than my website
okay and also you forget it you know if
you are you know programmers if you are
going to write you know it's thinking
you're gonna be popular for writing
technical topics such as math
programming forget it totally you know
they are there are hundreds spammy
websites they are far more popular than
you for anything related to JavaScript
and because in order to do to get
popular somewhat because the the web you
know it's fiercely competitive and and
also you have bag' of spammers you have
ten million hundred thousands you know
black hat SEO so-called black hat Isis
is using more where various distributors
they are all trying to put ads they have
they offer it they dedicate their life
and they don't care about nothing like
for example me I study golem for example
or JavaScript I spent a year you know
you spent ten hours to write one
sentence essentially that's what you do
you you spend ten hours to just create
one centers you know but meanwhile they
are not like that you know they you know
those people they also write : like a
tutorial but they are only interested
how can I make the maximize money
maximize viewers so they target the
beginners theta you know a lot of people
want to you know get into programming
they heard that it makes money so so
those so there are all these old type of
people you know it literally it so in
those industry it's a hundred thousands
people in India in China maybe not China
because the inter
at blocking but in India lots of
countries you know this little places
they all do that
you know SSC CEO you know they they have
you know they did do that you cannot win
there unless you are one of them unless
you forget about quality I just am here
just I just want to make money Mac how
can I copy everything from Casal you
know like how can I possibly copy
everything sauce is rewarded and create
a page you know so create ten pages a
day then then try to market you know you
need you know PR skills and never swear
you know remove whatever swearing words
in sauce I just remove it it happens
like you search my name every day they
are like tens of domains copying in my
websites you know I I have talked about
it in past videos for an hour you just
for example go go to google.com such
folks Rd okay sorry and such for past
hour okay search for okay this one this
one is a scam you know it's scam or more
where it's like a random domain name I
can yeah I know I know because I've seen
those for year for for ten years but for
20 years
okay in past 24 hours I can tell you
okay this is kind of okay they are not
actually this is a spam website this is
a spam website the rest of the ten pages
are spam this is a spam they all have my
name you know pike sorry this is spam
pike sorry this is autohotkey dependence
by cassadee's spam website
this is patreon that's not my website
uses a scam website they want to
probably I'm not sure because sometimes
Google you know anyway so this is a scam
website doctor keyboard scam
side back sorry you know basically
hungry everyday you know this is like in
past 24 hours you do it every day you
see every day that's what they they
actually do make money that's you know
if you are want to be popular that's
what you do you actually make money if
you want to honestly right programming
opinions and become popular forget it
and useless you don't pay nobody pay you
and you know I I get people saying oh
thank you so much it's good you know I
like it thank you you know I really
appreciate but no money basically
open-source okay I gotta stop you know
I'm just going to answer some questions
addressed to me
Israel Tech should probably adopted more
cautiously sorry how do you get your
YouTube comments in emacs
how do you get your YouTube comments
what do you mean like which YouTube
comments in emacs what do you mean I
don't I don't know anyway so Michael my
show me show or something says I know it
is a bit of topic but what are your
thoughts on Buddhism
maybe the Mahayana variety of course the
topic is larger not okay I'll talk you
know at Buddhism you know so I was born
in Taiwan you know which we are Chinese
so Buddhism is the most popular region
in Asia in China in Japan in Taiwan
almost every everywhere like you go up
to the street you see Buddha you go to
your friend's home you will see several
Buddhism's you know statues almost yeah
every frame every you know every you
have of your friend's home you have some
kind of incense burning or and you go
out to the street you know every few
blocks you'll see incense burning or
Buddha or Buddhism and then every
holiday you have to burn paper money
things like that Buddhism you know
indeed so Taiwan is you know is
years of heavy heavily Buddhist country
and Buddhism is unlike Christianity or
Islam is it's rather it's kind of it's
it's kind of also mixed in with Asian
Confucian philosophy Buddhism I I can't
say it's a big topic okay so if you have
specific things then we can talk about
it it's it's very big topic and and and
also Buddhism in Taiwan for example it's
also they have a large superstitions for
example in Western countries you have
astrology and oftentimes girls you know
women's magazines they they want to look
at you know they are obsessed with it
astrology you know but in Buddhism is
much more it's not astrology though it's
palmistry you know quite a few these
kind of things you know you read your
palms that's you know that's very
popular or sense or phones way phone
phones way okay in Chinese we say phones
way in English you pronounce phone
straight which is kind of which is you
can tell the fortune by looking at the
arrangements of your house your garden
your tree where is the location of the
tree with Ray you know where and how
your house is facing then you can devise
omens like okay you need to place the
furniture here otherwise it's blocking
your money you know things like that
lots of superstitions
you know they talk on TV every day and
people generally believe it you know
that's Buddhism in this in Taiwan okay
and so I wasn't exactly I don't you know
I don't believe I you know I'm not into
Buddhism actually anyway anyway that's a
big topic so maybe next day let's see
how many thirteen watching yeah I'm
getting longer and longer every day now
it's like nineteen
every day so Benjamin look at Saudi
screen and see what I wrote YouTube
seems to be prejudiced against me Mac so
do you mean well yeah I don't see what
you mean
so isn't that buffer you have open of
YouTube comments oh I just copied it you
didn't see it you see okay Cece I go
here select or copy go back to Emacs new
buffer paste that is so yeah I'm getting
longer and longer I should stop now so
okay yeah thank you guys for watching
I'll see you next day I mean I missed
some comments maybe uh maybe your answer
in the youtube comment section you know
when I watch and I read them later bye