good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sound talk show
today we are going to do
uh continue from yesterday we are going
to code python emac beast and wufem
language we are going to write a script
in each of this language to do find and
replace
of all text files in a directory and
we are going to compare their speed so
yesterday we did emac bisp in wufem
language and today we're gonna add
python first of all we're gonna modify
yesterday's emac this man Wolfram
language because to make it to make them
more efficient okay
so I so let's let's begin uh let's begin
this so if you have comments and
questions post it okay
pop out chat uh okay so here we go
okay so let's begin so I'm going to yeah
so let's go to talk show
this is my talk show index page and
let's go to yesterday because we need
some of the code
okay so here is yesterday
um
we did e-maglis and uh and Wolfram
language okay so let's copy all their
code
okay so
um
starting here
copy your code from yesterday
copy close and we're gonna modify it
okay
so okay show it in browser so for the
first thing we are going to do is we're
gonna write this Powershell script so
that it can copy all the files into the
test directory and we are using the emac
beasts manual as an example so
so let's remove the syntax coloring HTML
and let's do the Powershell okay so the
Powershell pop it out
so we are going to
copy let me show you the emac this uh
emac this manual you can download from
you know search the web you'll find it
emacs manual there are 1000 pages okay
and we're gonna copy to this directory
this my home directory okay so start
Powershell
uh okay so let's
magnify Okay so
copy it
do it do it
done fantastic now we open this
directory you can see emac these files
they are fantastic okay and now next
next we is
um yeah so we uh
we're gonna write this script okay let's
pop this back Powershell now let's
go to the emac this script okay so here
is the emac this script we did now
remember the the words we want we have
four pairs of find replace strings so we
replace previous to previous something
something replace that to that something
something so four pairs of them so in
this emac this code
uh you know that's all there it is okay
just 40 lines so we can see this for
each find replace pair we have this
block of code
so in this block of code is repeated the
only change is the actual string
you know so this is
um
you know this is easy to understand but
too much bloat maybe so we can make it
better
we can
put this find replace pairs into a list
of list or a vector of leg vectors then
just Loop over so we just have one block
of code so let's modify let's do that
okay
uh you know if you I'm not going to
explain how the code works if you want
to you can watch yesterday okay so we're
just gonna clean this up so so this
thing
okay this thing is gonna be we I wanna I
wanna use a vector okay so a vector in
emac is square bracket a vector vectors
so in fact this can be just done by
uh let me show my uh key Magic
uh
Okay so
square bracket and no comma okay so we
did that that that that
that that
and the whole thing is a vector that and
oh no comma I forgot
because emac this you don't need you use
space as separator no comma so here is
these pairs okay
find uh
replace
okay
so you are in emac list so set a
variable that variable
and the value of that variable is that
predefy the code okay
now too many uh too much intent I don't
like that this okay so here
so let's find replace pairs Let's uh put
at the top as the input
so the input are this is also wrong uh
the input directory so because today we
are using a new better input directory
so input directory should be that
just that okay
yeah let's open it you see good close it
okay
so that's the input directory and
and these are the pairs we want to
replace and and over here what we have
to do is you know these repetitions we
don't need anymore
and the last one
yeah so we just this this part we want
to what we want to do is we want to map
map means for each okay and map a
function over at least so the the list
is going to be uh find replace pairs
okay and what is a function okay the
function will be
the function body will be something like
that over there so copy it
put it here make it pretty okay so
here's the function
okay uh wait what
yeah so uh what did I do
what is that
anyway so
yeah here's a function body so go to the
beginning then search for word and here
we will be
yeah so before we actually do anything
let's put the let
okay and then let's put all this into it
there okay make it pretty now let's it's
gonna be some variables the it's gonna
be fine and replace pairs so
the fine pair is gonna be
fine okay let's say dollar sign find
equals to
a ref
array
X is array
then the index is zero okay that's the
let's set the value for find and for the
replace
is
unref the second pair so you see
Visa pairs okay so find this is the fine
string and this is a replace string okay
now here what we have to do is just say
find
okay same thing here
find and here
replace string
replace string okay so we map we map a
function this function to this
uh array of arrays or vector vectors
each Vector is a
find and replace pair so this will work
now however let's I want to do something
to make this code more efficient okay
so
so let me explain you know yesterday we
you see these two lines of code I mean
these two blocks of code are very
similar we are first of all trying to
search for word
you know a string if we found it
we replace it okay then we set change to
true
we want to know that because if the file
if there's actually something we changed
then
you know then we write to file if
there's no change don't write to file
because otherwise it will be very
inefficient it's redundant
so the way we solve that is we first of
all find find you know the string then
modify the variable then we continue to
do the search and replace for that same
string
okay but however notice there's a
redundancy happening well this
is not really redundancy I mean I mean
the code is somewhat duplicated you see
this this block and this part but
algorithmically there is no redundancy
because every time you do find emacs
will move the point to the end of the
place it found so when you do while loop
to find it again it doesn't start from
the beginning so there's no inefficiency
here but however however the code is
repeated
we can make it better by yesterday I
discovered you know after the live
stream I thought about it we can make it
better to detect the change we can I
mean one simple way is to check the
um
the total size
of the Stream
you know that will not work if the find
replace pairs have the same size you
know same length
but in our case it will
uh so there are quite a few ways to do
this
but in fact
you see
this current way
you know although it's efficient but
however this set changed is repeated
what I mean is that suppose you have a
medium pairs you know let's say you have
a medium pairs now as soon as you found
a string
that's in the text
so you do the replacement and you set
change to True let's say that happens in
the first pair you know you found it you
made a change therefore change is true
however
but you have a million other pairs so
each time you are you know you are
setting this variable a million times
which you don't need so you'll be better
if you say if change is nil
then set it to true
but the problem is if you add as if
statement the if statement is
plus setting is probably taking
equivalent time then just set the
variable
so we are getting into uh the
nitty-gritty details about efficiency
this is when you know when you go to a
lower level language it you have so many
more ways to do it
the higher level of the language
where one line can do lots of things but
it's often not optimal so
so when you go down lower level
languages such as C
or assembly
the more low level the more multiple
ways you have
kind of to do the same thing
I learned that when I was doing the
homework of someone's brain
language there's a you know language
brain hello guys
let's you know not brand brain
b-r-a-i-n okay so for example you know
about five years ago I was doing
homework for someone College computer
science homework brain so brain
fact is you know artificial
uh
obfuscated language you only have a few
operations
and I never had experience in low-level
languages such as assembly or C you know
I never really ever experience but brain
kind of opened my eyes so I I started to
see there just yeah you know usually for
example in Python
or in many languages the design of the
language usually you want to have only
one way to do it to do something
but actually from a algorithmic point of
view point of view that is basically
impossible you can never have just one
way to do it
you might have one way to do it that's
most you know intuitive you know with
respect to the language but actually
this you always have so many ways to do
it and some ways will be more efficient
so anyway
uh the equation so you know we are
talking about how do you um
so let me so let's uh hello guys Greg
and Doc and hello uh German if you see
insert file content path with the T you
can use buffer modified
uh both for modified P yeah that's true
but actually doesn't apply here because
we are you know we talked about this
yesterday we are using with 10 buffer so
you know that both a modified P only
work if the file is associated if the
buffer is associated with the file
in our case we don't we are not
uh copperstein says I think that said
changed P May many times it's okay for
performance yeah you are right yeah
yeah you are right so the Nitty Gritty
details
um
yeah you should you know in practice it
it doesn't matter it doesn't really
matter okay so let's just go with this
thing
let's just go with this
um okay so you know let's stop wasting
time on this you know so okay so here is
essentially
um
our code
we don't need the comments okay so so
yeah so that's
let's make it
um
you know
compact okay so here is the you should
work so let's uh check one more like one
more time
so you
go to this directory
uh this is find replace speakers you
list the directory or HTML files and you
do this yeah should then you know you
define this function that process each
file path then you map this function to
the digital files okay that should work
now
copy pop it back to HTML now we want to
create
that file here so
yeah okay so let's open that path not
exist do I are you sure create yes paste
it here save close open again it's there
okay so we can run it in Shell now
and the same thing we want to do with
wufam land but let's let's run the emac
this first okay so let's this is
Powershell let's try to run it
uh double check yeah
okay measure command measure the time it
takes
it's Powershell run it
okay there is the error yeah we know
this from yesterday there's a run type
of argument stream p
uh debugger entered this very wrong type
of argument
a stream P so he wants a string
okay so okay
so there's the arrow so let's look at
what is the error so
something with our map C something went
wrong there so
each time you get this pair oh there it
is that that right arrow is incorrect so
yeah so you you don't want that
there okay now go back to Shell
run the last command to it
should be five seconds yeah okay four
seconds first time
do it again
two seconds 1.7 yeah 1.7 seconds Okay
the reason the second time is faster
there's a little complexity let me
explain again
when you do a fine replace on thousands
of files like we are doing now you know
there's 1000 files
the bottleneck is the disc accessing the
loading the file from the disk or even
from flash drive right now I have flash
drive
you know if if you have a spinning disc
that's even 10 times slower so the
bottleneck is loading the fire from the
drive okay
so let's say if you are doing grip not
find replace simply find string
the first time you do it on a thousand
files let me show you okay let me show
you let's go to uh
so here is my Golan script
uh you can you can find the
you know you can find the code here
Golan
is simply find by regular acceleration
some file so this is equivalent to Unix
scrap or rip grab or whatever you know I
I like um I I did one video where I
looked in depth into rip grab rib grab
is faster than this script uh yeah so
okay so the point so here's a script so
when you want to find some string in
thousands of files the first time is
super slow for example this this this uh
this script will find
about 7000 HTML files you try to search
seven seven thousand HTML files in my
directory
and thus you know Skip get and Skip some
documentation directory so let's see the
find string uh let's say we want to find
the string Rhino okay there's a book
JavaScript right now okay so I run it
the first time you'll take two or three
seconds
okay it's still running still running
this is written in go fast fastest uh
faster than humanities
okay it's still running
I found one instance
he found a few instances wait okay wait
the first time is slow because it's
going through
it's going through like 20 000 files
among which seven thousand are HTML
files so you have to first of all you
know dive into the directory and
subdirectories filter out the files you
want HTML files then open each HTML okay
it's done okay it's that's probably
seven seconds okay now you
mods so you can you can have this nice
interface you can jump to any one of the
file
showing browser you know so this is one
of the article Rhino you know JavaScript
the Gradebook okay this is one of the
best book JavaScript the Rhino book The
Definitive guide so okay
so you can see now close it okay wait
back here close it okay so you can see
is it found about 10 instant you know
one two three four five six seven eight
seven instances okay took about seven
seconds uh close it now if I run this
again it's instantaneous okay let me
show you because now all the 7000 HTML
files they are in memory okay let me run
it
then you see
then and now put in the casa find March
C
you see so that's the point when you do
find when you try to you know the
bottleneck is loading the file into
memory that is a big bottleneck we this
is important because we are trying to
test the speed
of of these scripts so we have two so if
all you are doing is fine you know is
grab then
you want to run a script the first time
then join it one more time the second
time is the actual speed of of the of
the of the grab in that particular
language okay the first time is is just
loading the files okay so that's one
thing to know very critical
loading files from the disk is the
bottleneck okay
but now we are not doing grip we are
doing find and replace okay so let me so
there's a intricate intricacy we need to
know
uh to make sense of our speed comparison
and that is let me explain okay
so that is you know first of all same
thing happens when you do this for the
first time it has to uh it has to load
you know these 1000 files from disk so
very slow so the first time when we run
it this 4.3 seconds includes those times
to load this
but however here's the thing
the second time we do it
still have to load all these files why I
mean
because the file has changed you see the
file has changed because we are doing
fine replace so some of the files have
changed some of them not
so we run into a situation where the
second speed
you know we don't know exactly which
file are already loaded in memory memory
which one one or not
so you know we don't know exactly
we can find out of course because we we
know exactly which string we we changed
but the generally speaking you know some
files are still in memory some not
and and why is it 1.7 times faster I
mean what why is this the second time
faster well part of the reason is that
possibly that some of the files are
still in memory
but the other reason is that
you know when you do the second time you
no longer have this word in those 1000
vowels because they all become that you
know
how so same thing with Lambda you know
you don't no longer have the word Lambda
you no longer have the word number but
however this
this exists this let that you know that
becomes that something so that is still
there so the second time is faster
for two reasons one is that your the the
string you need to find is is much less
the occurrence therefore the time you
have to write to this is much less far
fewer files you have to write to this
right to this is another major
uh cost in you know bottleneck right to
disk
so one reason is that there's less
number of pairs you are actually writing
to disk changing the second reason is
that
some of these files are still in memory
Okay so
so that's that's a conclusion okay if we
do it again it's basically it's 1.72 you
see 1.8
we do it again 1.8 something 1.7 okay so
basically each time it's going to do
that let's go there and let's show you
let's show it so for example if you open
that search for that you see
you know because we did one two three
four four times
and you can search that again
you know that you know that is one of
the most frequently words so let's
highlight this
okay so you can see all that occurrences
you see
that that you see
okay
so that's emac lease okay let's close
that close that that's emac bisp okay we
are ready to move on to wufam language
then we're gonna do python okay
now a little one more one last check is
there anything new efficient here
uh I don't think so
um
yeah this change to we can we can change
it by
just compare just check the length of
the buffer you know the point Max
if the point Max is different from the
original you know that's another way to
do it but anyway so
this should be fine so emac this code is
complete okay backup close okay we got
that now let's work on Wolf Hamlet any
questions comments
the worst bottleneck is human yes and
that's when Wolfram language shines you
know
so in Wu family let's let me show you
okay so let's go to Fan language okay
so this so
um
this emac this code we deleted we don't
care anymore
okay now let's start the Wolfram
language okay now cut
probably a bag we don't want now let's
go to open this here
yes create paste it save okay here's the
Wolfram language let's remove that that
comment
find replace multiple pairs inverter
okay now the
input okay the input also changed so the
input is now
here that's right
okay input and here's a bunch of replace
Pairs and there's the arrow here that
should be let's look
that should be that
okay
okay and very simple you see we just
apply this function process file is
defined as a function we
um
you know different language we the
function file path is the variable the
argument so you read string get the
files content as a string then you just
call replace string replace and stream
replace can take a multiple pair you can
see
you see
so you don't even have to either you
know that's the power of Wolfram
language you want to replace multiple
pairs one function call
you know you and and each one part of
this can be a regular expression
so you don't have to uh you know worry
about anything
okay then you do scan scan is like for
each okay so you map the process file
function to you know this part is just
gets to all the file names it returns a
list of files name very similar to uh
this you know if we compare
emac this code you see this part file
list
is equivalent to
um
that you see the directory files
in Wolfram language is just file names
then you map you know the scan the scan
is like Wolfram language is map C
so actually so you don't so these files
you actually just put it here so you
don't need the
the variables
you see
so
okay
now
now let's work on the Wolfram language
okay let's make sure the emac this is
not
yeah so so that's good emac this file is
good
okay now let's work on Wolfram language
uh and this part this process file you
can actually just grab the whole thing
and put it here so it's one single line
let's even remove the done
you don't need the process fast so let
me show you okay let me show you some
tricks in Wolfram language
uh
so we're gonna rewrite this this two
into one single line okay
so first of all this process file can be
written by
this function
can be written by you don't need the
final pass
stream
and actually I'm thinking
okay so so this block is equivalent to
this one okay in fact you can shorten it
much more
yeah so they are the same okay so
this block is equivalent to this one and
since now we just have one line we don't
even need that anymore so just put this
line here
so compare
these two lines now it's just this
single line okay
now
[Music]
um
now
it's um
let's not worry about that let's work
with the more readable version
currently this will find script is not
efficient
because
you read the whole file then you do the
stream replace
if there is no change you don't want to
write stream you don't want to write to
file okay so we need to be able to tell
whether there's a change or not
so
um how do you do that
so the German says okay so during the
second run the files are already in
memory not all of them because remember
we did already we are replacing some
strings
so during the second run
those files are not not changed
eye memory but those files where we did
the string replacement or not in memory
because the operating system will
we'll detect you know the files is
different
okay so does e magnet support
multi-threading no or a single weight no
okay that's one of the major complaint
of emac this it doesn't support that
there are tricks there are ways to do
but not really
okay so now
yeah let's fix let's make this wolf I'm
script efficient because
you know that's our goal to compare the
speed of each language
but we cannot be but if our code is
inefficient then it's not fair Okay so
we want to be able to find out if
something changed okay so one trick is
by
checking the okay so let's let me write
this
one trick is by
uh
oops Yeah
what
my command log buffer broke
don't know what I did
yeah
so let's start
a new one let's see now I move
yeah
stupid
let's let's start a new one
and command log mod work okay close it
okay so we
let's do with
okay so width is basically declare a
local constants so this is like emacslet
but however all the variables are
constant okay so here we will just put
the
um
we'll do the file content okay
let's file content and the expression
whatever okay so
um
yeah so this so this with
okay put here
then put this inside okay
uh so
so here is the final content so you
don't need this part anymore so file
content
so read stream and uh
then you want
the length
okay
okay in content length equals to
right
I don't have a shortcut
okay uh
yeah
okay so content length will be the
be the length of the original content
okay
now
now you do
screen replace
so let's have a new variable new content
okay
new content equals to
string replace okay
content in finally paste pairs that's
right
then
if
we can do a equality comparison you know
we can do
you know we can do that but that's
probably slow or we can just compare the
length Okay so basically if
if
they are equal
then do nothing
otherwise
try to file okay
so this is one way to do it and another
way is that more efficient is if
ah
if content length is equals to
new content length okay
then
don't do nothing otherwise right to
string okay so no should be
um
in wufan language no is do nothing yeah
it should be capital
okay
so that's our function so this should be
more efficient so let's double check
read content content length
and new content
okay so content length is a con is
equals to X content okay the new content
is the replace string okay
yeah replace string friend replace pairs
and if content is equals to new content
okay this
this is uh more accurate I mean this is
the correct version you compare the full
string content if they are the same
don't do anything okay otherwise
right to file that's right so let's
um
okay that's coming this up
this function will return no okay so
let's put a semicolon okay that's the
with statement and here is the function
okay
so now this should work this should this
is the correct way your work okay let's
try it
so make backup let's run the Wolfram
script
close it
go back to talk show
open it correct close it copy the line
back to terminal
paste it
okay remember right now the files are
already changed by emacs okay so Wolfram
is
you know so we need to refresh the files
so we need to remove
you know let's do a refresh let's see
how much open language takes now emacs
time is remember
is four seconds okay yeah Emax is four
seconds
then 1.7
you know
okay now let's see wolfam language
first of all you need to
remove it
okay
copy it
wolfam language run it
1.3 did we make a mistake this is
significantly faster than
then then emac this
and let's try it again
1.3 so okay now let's look at the
look at the let's verify it actually
made appropriate changes
it's incorrect you see that previous is
still there
so we made the arrow somewhere
the wufam language is not working
correctly
open it
so this should be the third right
all right
oh
right
oh wait
copied it wrong okay we got some problem
x x so we don't need the least part
that's right
yeah so this is
wait what's our copy command
parallel second
let's see copy oh yeah just copy to XX
there's no Edis so let's double check
yeah
okay now let's do it again
remove the files
copy them
code
1.4 seconds
significantly faster than
e-mac lisp
let's double check did it work
No it didn't
search for that
no it didn't work
something wrong with our code okay
double check the code
so here is a list of pairs
that's right
now what is the let's copy these two of
them notebook because ruframe notebook
will
uh you know sometimes show you syntax
errors or something
paste it
and smack the file
okay so Wolfram notebook displays it
very well
and let's copy it let's see if we can
make it into nice no it's the same okay
so anyway
so did we make any error
if content is equals to that don't do
anything no otherwise otherwise right
string
file path
new contents
so why is it wrong
I don't know
yeah I don't know why is it
so we can
not play
print
if we print final path and see what
happens when you if we print file path
okay
it's not printing file path
I told it to a print file path
God what's going on
hmm
oh
let's move that
foreign
comments any comments
now if you run this in Wolfram language
you see it's printing those files
yeah but the idiotic
okay
the final path
looks funny
the final path looks funny because very
annoying
this is a very annoying issue of the
final path separators
but Wolfram language did did open the
file did it I think so
so let's double check
hex contents
read stream file path
and new content equals true
and let's go to the directory did did it
make any change no
did not make any change what's the uh
input the
so first of all it did
go through all these files because the
print is there
then
then we can say okay let's try something
else
let's say print the first
five characters also
okay string substring
string pots okay
so you want the functions
okay let's see that's how you get
substring okay give the nth character so
give a list of in uh so
how do you get substring
string take that's how you get substring
keeps a string containing the first n
characters Okay so so not stream part
strain
take
okay
that let's say
20 okay print the first 20.
um
print the first 20
characters
okay
copy the whole
copy the whole let's just run this in
Wolfram notebook
yeah select no paste
learn it
variable X new content is local variable
specification okay
oh obviously how idiotic because with
means local constant
I mean yeah local
constant so when you have a local
constant with using with you you must
have a value so you cannot do like this
okay so therefore we change the width to
module
you know I was trying to use width to
maybe save some fractions of second so
module is like lisp slit so that way you
can you know have this variable and uh
you know in the assign a value by the
way why don't we assign the value over
there
well because
the
wolfen language module is like lisp slat
the latter ones do not know the value of
the previous variable so you cannot say
new content equals to something X
content
you have to do it in the body
and in this you can say let as the risk
that will do that but not in woven
language
so this okay so now let's try to run
this in Shell let's remove all the print
statement
Okay so
do it
it's taking so long six seconds okay
this seems proper now it's probably
working let's double check let's go
check the file check
you see changed now this matching lines
that
you see each one has got changed
okay
yeah so that's good
now let's so
six seconds that's one second slower
then move then e-mac please let's do it
again
2.7 again one second slower than e-mac
this do it again
2.7 so remember the the metric is
six
then 2.7 okay six first time 2.7 second
time it's wolfam language now let's see
if we can improve the speed
by
so we don't need the print anymore so
you can improve the speed by
e
by replacing
that test with um
with with testing the length
but this would be cheating though
because this is not
really that correct this is kind of a
hack it works in our context
do we have a Content length now
so this will be
okay now we just compare the length
now I'm curious does this actually work
can you I mean I mean let's let's check
okay
some let's say ABC okay
I think you should
yeah so string you know the triple equal
works on a string
so that should be fast enough though
so if we do this way
I don't think it will improve the speed
let's do it again
it did actually you see
saved almost one second
yeah it did
yeah but this is a hack we can do this
we can compare the length to know if the
fire modified is because we know that
the fine replace pairs will change the
file length
but in general if you have arbitrary you
know business pairs you cannot read
rely on these
yeah but that's that's okay now let's
redo from fresh remove the directory
get a fresh copy of the directory
now Run Run Wolf and language
five seconds
you're in the second time
two seconds now what is the e-mac this
speed
let's see
e-mac this speed is 4.3 and 1.7
okay let's let's write it down
let's write it down in our talk show
okay that's e-magli speed
now Wolfram land speed
who found land speed is
5.3
and 1.9
okay do it again
1.9 do it again 1.9
yes
okay so you can see emac this is
slightly faster fascinating
fascinating now shall we do python now
okay but one last check is is there
something we can speed up the woo family
because I really
you know
when Wu family is slower it really bugs
me
what
all right why is this common uncommon
not work
my code is up my wolf I'm
language mod
there okay
so let me let me try to think of way to
speed this up okay
because I want
so this assignment is really making it
slow this you see you assign a huge
string into that
so rather
yeah so rather we want to do let me let
me just start to do
Advanced Warframe language coding okay
okay so
hello
Omega
so Advanced roof and language coding so
we are going to have a function next
step function uh you know partial
application and so on
so we have we want a function here
that
okay so the function will basically do
this let's let's write it
Okay so
this new so the function will be applied
an argument
and the argument will be
that okay and uh
so this will be the new content okay
okay so this is our function
so this so we yeah we do this
this way we save the step of assigning a
huge string to a variable
by this code very Advanced
you know so it's not hard to understand
so this part is a function
and this function is given this argument
string replace so it gets the new
content this is computed only once then
the argument is feed to the function at
the Palm side locations so if old
content is equals to the new
then do nothing otherwise find our path
and return that so this is
this would be
efficient okay so with this
with this we don't need
we don't need the new content and we
don't need this
we don't need a new content variable
we don't need that we don't need that
only okay in fact this can be further
simplified uh I will do that but first
of all before we do that let's just run
this
I want to make sure that
language is fast okay
2.8 what the
two seconds becomes 2.8 what
wait are you are you sure
1.9 it was 1.9 now it becomes two it
becomes much more slower what
okay
yeah God what am I doing Jesus
Jesus this is no good
okay let's let's get back to this
okay is there a way to know if
if
is there a way to know if string replays
actually
made some changes or not let's see
so string replace does only the first in
replacement give the list of results for
each of the
has one
okay it's really place okay
I'm saying expression
you know when we do this we we do we
want to know if there's any change
happened
because if there's a change we don't
want to write to file
I mean if there's no change we don't
want to write fire
okay
I don't think you can do that here
so how do I how do you make this faster
find our names process fire scan process
file
as Inspire function file path
function therapists file path is used
in two places
this part
of your pass
uh
I don't know why that's
Okay so
we we I want to make this faster so
new content equals to string replace
find replace pairs
that's right
and
if the content did not change
do nothing otherwise we want to write
file so right string let's look at the
live stream
to file
Channel expression when expression 2.
text string give a human readable string
representation of expression
keeps a human readable string
representation of expression okay
so that turns any movement language
expression to
human readable string text
yeah kind of
so examples here
becomes that you know
[Music]
okay that's that's too fancy
so
I'm trying to find a way to make Wolfram
language faster
and right now we failed
huh
now how do you make this even faster
you could replace the function file path
by a
H stop using
stop using a module
next content
thanks content and new content okay
let's look up documentation for read
stream
Okay so
you know I think this part is taking the
most time this comparison
let's remove that let's see if we just
always right to file
will that work now you want
I mean it might be faster but it's a
huge hack because if your file is one
gigabyte
then
then you know this you know right to
every file is not going to save time
but let's just see
let's see if we do this
do it
three seconds do it
2.8 you know three seconds but if you
compare it you know before we write to
file then
2.8 he's almost the same why is that
2.7
okay I think that's it for Wolfram
language we cannot
yeah I don't know how to make this
that's it okay that's the code for
Wolfram language
now let's
um
what is this
okay that's all
okay let's start over
remove all the files
copy over
then
when the Wolfram language
the first time is six seconds
the second time is 2.7 so they are about
one second slower each time okay
stop that now let's go to talk show
okay
[Music]
2.7
yeah this should be 2.7
it should be six
so that's wolfam language speed okay
let's move on to python
what about the difference between the
first and second run does the language
take longer to load the files
well I just we I just explained that he
explained that
like 10 10 minutes ago
uh
right when you hear 10 minutes ago
so the second the second one is faster
because because
the computer already have main some of
the files those unchanged files in
memory so when you read it doesn't have
to access the disk the second reason the
second time is faster in any language is
because
the second time
we don't we no longer have the string
like that and that that you know the
only string that's still in the files is
this that
so you have much less files to change
and this files to to write to file to
so that's why the second time is always
faster doesn't matter what language just
because
the way we have set up the replacement
pairs
okay so let's do python okay let's move
on maybe you know this so
so we already did almost 90 minutes wow
okay let's let's move to python quickly
okay let's go to python it's actually so
I already have the code you know since
I've been doing fine replace for 20
years
so Python 3
so we don't want the regular expression
version we want this version okay this
version does a bunch of things
fancy so and it's on my website you can
go there and get the code okay
so but now copy it close close
close Okay we want to have a python
version so new buffer
the here copy this line This will be X
python 3 of course
uh
X python p y okay
X Python 3 okay so open it yes cut paste
and uh
save okay so here is the python code now
let's
let's clean this up so that so that we
don't have this
lots of features and just say find
replace
multiple pairs
in order
okay
and we don't want uh file list we don't
need input that's what we need and input
is just
that okay
level we don't care about level max
level uh file name rejects we need print
file name change Backup backup don't
care replace these two you don't care
reject string directory to skip we don't
care code begin yes encoding
okay this is a python educ we don't care
because we are not printing anything
okay dates daytime string input
duh
normalized path we don't care
okay so for X in find replace list okay
we don't care because there is
not in search list
yeah so
so and what
wait where is the pairs oh
what yeah let's go to our original again
finally slow replace pair at least this
somehow we skipped
close close close okay
yeah this replacement this we need
and they will be
okay so let's get that to the python
um
syntax
the python syntax is like that okay
so it's going to be
parent and comma okay
and let's just do that
and this Arrow will be just a comma okay
okay
okay yeah
now format the code and see can we
format the code
what
Excel format python
uh
it's a python format
some python format buffer
haven't do it
okay
okay so that's fine replace pay at least
find replace list okay now replace
string this is the process file
oh God python Jesus I hate
python
do backup
and do backup we don't care
and trained a bunch we don't care
and print the find replace this we don't
care
print that we don't care wait why is so
many
so this so find replace open the file
input path open read encoding
uh God file content input file read
okay yeah file content then Unicode
decoding error
idiotic and close the file
and global data and string we don't care
number replace we don't care
for pair in find replace list
uh
content uh
number replaced
file content.com
yeah this is very inefficient
okay we don't care about number we place
that's about making a report
and it's actually inefficient because
this count and this replace they are
doing kind of the same thing redundant
so let's just say file content equals to
file content E equals to dot replace
pair
find string replace by replace string
so for each pair we do that okay then
then this part we don't care again
so output file
oh then we um
what sweet
oh then yeah so we have the same problem
how do you tell if the file changed
yeah same problem so actually we do
we don't want this number replaced
you see
change it only if it you know we have to
write to file only when there is some
change otherwise we don't want to write
file because otherwise it's very uh
costy
so
so the problem now just like in Wolfram
language how do you
determine the file changed well
I I really truly despise the Python
language and this syntax this this
variable name convention
if I can think so
so for each pair so this is original
content then you are basically
overwriting it here
and
so you can do that
number replaced equals to wait where's
number replaced
they must be initialized to zero okay
now open the original
okay yeah so there they initialize to
zero you forgot
so initialize to zero then then but look
look at the syntax coloring of the
Python mod idiotic
okay number replace equals to zero then
you for each pair you increment that
doesn't take much time
wait uh it does take much time because
you are doing a count here
so
okay so you well
yes
so as soon as we find yeah you are you
this is you know this is inefficient
because this line is taking a lot of
time it's actually trying to count how
many occurrences
then you do The Replacements okay does
the replacement return
final content replaced does it tell you
there's any change or not
ah python you know python when you want
to look at documentation
it's hard so this is The Final Countdown
is a string so he faces a method
so let's open let's see my let's open my
old Python tutorial
stream methods
so substring length join repeat
substitute search social string
find replace okay replace the currencies
of substring
only first count number of these okay so
it will replace occurrences
okay this is a bad documentation
okay it's not too bad so anyway so we
yeah replace old by new
and uh
and uh is it in line
when you replace do you have to reset it
back to content it didn't say so this
documentation my is not very good
so we need to look up so we want to know
does it replace the string
to the new result or not
uh
and I think so you know by the way the
python usually you know the oop python
so does anyone know
certainly two people are watching
nobody's watching so
python string method replace okay
python stream replace metal we want to
see the documentation
I don't want these
idiots you know tutorial let's go to
uh python
documentation it's Building open that
okay python on Windows comes with this
building documentation okay
so
so now you all you have to do is to find
the string Methods okay
Python tutorial setup and usage
God pythons truly
idiotic
the Python language now is it here or is
it
expressions
simple statements no it's not here the
python standard Library
okay building types
building types
sequence types idiot you know
they don't they don't have a just say
string
but string is part of sequence type I
suppose
okay pretentious
immutable immutable sequence types every
time I I code python it's
uh very uh annoying extremely in every
way
you know now now this is a huge page
building types
right now I just want to know if the
string method replace does the
replacement in line
okay so you go to the official Doc it's
a library section and see there's no you
know building types you cannot there's
no one section that says string
you are assumed to know that in Python
the computer science are us
that string is uh you know is a sequence
type I suppose
there are three basic sequence types
these tuples and range objects
okay so it's not a sequence type it's a
what the
text sequence type there it is
python
pretentious text sequence
they don't call it string they call it
text sequence type textual data in
Python is handled with string objects or
strings the pretentious
you know they have to make a distinction
between string object or just strings oh
by the way string is just a short name
you know you know it's not an official
formal name but it's a you know
convenient short name for a string
object python
strings are immutable sequences of
Unicode code points
string details are written in a variety
of ways like a bunch of incomprehensive
tensible jargons like
pretentious
you know immutable sequences you know do
you mean sequence according to your
language or do you mean in general they
are core sequences like what what the
you mean
Unicode code points what the is
Unicode co-points go yourself
biggest programming language design
idiots
pretentious string literals are
written in a variety of ways variety of
ways you I just just
say you know string Detroit is this this
this
but you have to say string details are
written in a variety of us of ways as
opposed to it can be something else in
variety of ways
you know the the beach
okay so anyways so this screen you know
so it's they they want to call it text
sequence type what is the significance
of the text sequence type what do I
you know
why do I have to know that where does it
matter that whether it's called string
or text sequence type the python
okay stream methods we are getting uh we
are getting there hey rat
we are getting the string Methods okay
so text sequence type Guido vandrosums s
in this variety of written in variety of
ways string literals
python Guido van Rossum
immutable it
sequence of Unicode
string Methods we're getting there so
there it is uh stream dot replace okay
you know it takes my anger
on the pythons okay Street you know
there it is you know
string dot replace oh new and you know
this incomprehensible returns a
copy of the string
okay it returns a copy it doesn't
replace in line
returns a copy of the string with all
occurrences of substring all replaced by
Nu okay if the options are given Okay
blah blah blah so it returns a copy
okay so my code here is correct you have
to assign it
yeah this my documentation needs to be
improved
okay
so it returns a copy uh so
yeah it so I so to be efficient we
these two lines should be you know we
should
assigned the old file content
you know then compare the new file
content for example here should be
new content Okay so
yeah so we can do that
this new variable then we just we remove
this number replaced counts because this
is very inefficient you are counting
every pair a refined string
so we remove this line and just compare
the file content with the new content if
they are different then we write to
files something like that
okay but for now let's don't do anything
let's try the old way see the speed
okay
so if if number replace greater than
zero then blah blah blah blah blah then
right to file basically
so
so we have to write two file here what
is this it's trying to print the other
report
uh
so don't print so output file equals to
open for right encoding utf-8
yeah our profile
right and because otherwise the
python
a friend found them with no change
okay so when when that's otherwise
there's no change
uh
you don't you don't care about that
okay so here is the you know look at
look at python you know
more lines than even him like
this and the indentation
okay so so now
what is this the final list uh okay we
don't care
so
this part we don't care
we want to Traverse that okay now the
whole thing needs to be indented back
um
yeah
the python indent shift rates
okay let's I believe that's what we want
yeah okay
so now to Traverse the directory
current level we don't care can the
level we remove that feature
okay
and uh the so if the current level is
less than minimum level and less than
max level
something something and Skip with
something something you don't care
so this step this if statement is always
true
python okay
so and here the let's indent left
again we don't need if
okay so for file name in file list
uh regular expression
what
the about
okay let's just
it's just just put it hard coat it there
okay
I'll call it there okay
so now we search for HTML files
file name and the regular expression
unicode
and uh
and what
and if the file name does not begin with
a
does not contain the Palm side
that's for prevention of emacs
to Peter T the Emax generates those file
names with pound sign okay so remove
that
remove that so
simplify
so if the file is HTML file
and then you replace string file
which is that okay
the path always separated blah blah blah
and the print we don't care
okay printed okay
so Python scripts and
down script it seems even
longer than necessary
this
this should work okay so
don't try we don't want the try
okay we just simplify the whole
okay so let's test check if this works
and if it does let's try to change this
algorithm to to the compare file
contents to see if it's faster okay so
let's check one more so this is python
36 months
and we probably don't need the the OS
the cisfaq the short fact
python
you know I I haven't been it's been
acquired I don't remember which is what
you need daytime you don't need
anymore for sure
OS you don't need
uh what about open
yeah I don't remember which one is it
it's uh it's critical because you we do
want to
you know we don't want to load libraries
that we don't use
so
so let's yeah you know we remove them
one by one or something then we'll find
out
or let's look at my Python tutorial
let's see open file which Library do you
need
so miscellaneous web text processing
daytime module uh
crochet type of functioning class module
miscellaneous
where is the read file okay so read file
okay so read file you need sis
impulses
so you don't need OS you don't need that
I'm pretty sure
that will work
okay so make a backup
go to the diet directory so this is a
file path close because
close close
yeah so here is the python open yeah
close copy
finally back to our
back to our terminal is our terminal
yeah
paste the python
run the python
oh wait the Wolfram script oh fam script
is learning python
yeah so this will be python now now what
the is the
pay that I executable then you know the
Guido wonders and refused to have
py.py3 as the extension and also on
different operating systems
some of the Python is python 3. you know
some some Linux some distro or on
Windows or a Mac
python May mean python 2 May mean Python
3 you know and on some distro or up when
you see some some if you want Python 3
you have to say explicitly Python 3
because the pyth because the gido van
Rossum you know he think he's
the best designer he don't want he don't
want the situation where you have python
2 or python 3.
you know he wanted he want the future to
be like just one python let's all forget
about python 2 existed you know so he
doesn't want you know like if you have
like py.3 he doesn't want that and that
creates a lot problem because this you
know you have to there's no way to you
know it's a problem to
expect Python 3 or python 2 but you are
actually running the other
you know so that kid online wasn't
okay so suppose this will be it
okay when the pylon code do it uh
something is wrong okay I think
oh yeah so here yeah python right yeah
python um
yeah you don't you don't say file you
you know python is just file directly
do it no something is wrong most recent
call Fire online 32
always walk OS is not defined that's
right so you need the OS yes that's
right yeah OS library for the walk
okay so does that actually work seems
very fast
but did it actually work
okay so let's try again
remove all the data
copy it
okay now run the python code
then python code
seems It's Working 3.7
wow
wow python code this means it's faster
than emac this
okay so this is faster than emac this
now let's check if it's actually working
Check Yes these matching lines that
that yes it's working now let's do it
again
3.7 why why is python the second time it
doesn't save
time
you know nowadays if we refresh we all
see that this
you know it should have two occurrence
of that okay
close we open
this matching lines yeah so it is
working
okay so but for some reason each time
python runs the second time is still
you see
it doesn't save time every time you run
so the the speed here is getting a bit
complicated
that's document okay let's document the
python speed
basically it's 3.7 for each
okay something like that
something like that I'm surprised I'm a
little surprised
now the Wolfram line is pretty bad
the
hmm
anyway that I think that's um
we we kind of did what we wanted today
we commission accomplished we did python
emac this blue fam language and we
compare the speed so far here's the
result python
python one
even though the python code can be
improved
a lot
but there is a puzzle why why is each
time python doesn't
speed up significantly
so if the number replace is greater than
zero you write to file otherwise you
don't right
so why is the patterns always taking
this much time
so the second run python is losing out
actually
you know the first run python is great
but the second run in Python is losing
to emac this and the Wolfram language so
that means there is something wrong here
can we compact the code somehow we don't
want so many
so you guys python experts
say something maybe we can we uh you
know improve the code
the first question is that why python on
second run doesn't
uh doesn't reduce time like the others
so that is likely because python is
still writing to fire all the time so
let's print let's put a print statement
let's print what do we print from our
path
okay
maybe that will show
and wait it doesn't print
did we why is it not printing
if number replaced
what
it's not printing anything
is it because the major command
suppressed it
yeah is it because the major commands
suppress any printing yeah so
indeed the major command is suppressing
all the print printing okay but here is
the python output okay that's expected
all right wait
okay so the python output
printing the path
okay so let's do it again
no no it's not printing we do want it to
print the path
and uh we also want to print the pair
okay so let's see
okay this is wrong because this means
you see it is indeed
trying to write to the file
um
for any for every file
because this is a file name and this is
a current pair so number let's see go up
number
wait down
they are all printing number
nothing else why is that
oh yeah the pair is always the last one
that's right that's right so the
printing the pair doesn't make sense
ah
okay so we can do this
else
okay
okay so now
so let's check those two files the mark
and outside context
okay
so go to the files
open it
the mark
okay so the mark
then let's search for
search for that indeed there are so many
occurrences of that okay so that is a
file that changed
correct
and the second file there's no change
search for that
no occurrence
so this is correct
so in fact
almost all files contains the the word
that
so we actually may need to modify our
list of words to change
because let's see let's put make this
more prominent
so we can actually see
what kind of percentage of files that
does not change
okay so for about every
every 10 files every seven files there's
a file no change
okay every five
so they are significant number of files
that's no change
okay this significant number of files
yeah so that still makes
a difference
so for this files that doesn't change
don't do anything but for files changed
we
do something
but the
you know so let's do again remove
copy the directory
then run the measure of the Python code
now this time don't
don't
print nothing
okay
don't say nothing
let's check the speed one more time
okay do it
four seconds
do it again
3.7 seconds do it again
3.4 seconds do it again
3.4 so it stays with 3.4
yeah then 3.5 so the first time is
three the first time is four point four
seconds Okay so
so let's modify okay so but let's do it
again
remove everything
copy
run the python code
first time
3.8
do it again
3.7
3.4 do it again
3.4
so we can kind of assume 3.7 and 3.4
that's the python speed
okay
so we we kind of had the result uh okay
so that's it for today we did uh
two hours now
uh so here is our results
and uh
very interesting so python is the
fastest
and python
we haven't even you know we have some
actually we have some inefficiencies we
actually haven't really tried to make it
faster there is some inefficiencies
because
we are doing a
you know yeah I'm pretty sure I can
improve the speed we do have some
inefficiencies but anyway here's a
python code
and it's fastest
okay and
for Wolfram language it's you know
I don't think there's much I can do
although it's the shortest
but
not sure how much I can do to to make it
faster
it is possible but you will be like much
more involved I mean you have to
consider you know the
the normal you know suppose you have
been coding each language for two years
so
you know so the Wolfram language this is
pretty much that how you do it okay if
you want to make it
faster you are kind of going beyond the
normal wolf and language way okay
and for emac this
can we make this faster anyhow I don't
think so
so compile it yeah we can buy it
compiling
and let's see let's see maybe maybe
maybe that makes a difference okay
it's
removed them copy the files over
and let's try
let's try the byte compiled version okay
drop down to the directory capital B but
compare it
there's some error warning assignment
two three variables we don't care
yeah reference to free variable yeah we
don't care because this is a script
so now
so let's
um
let's ERC okay
so e l c there are two
uh
okay first of all let's try e l
let's watch
now there's the arrow
what
oh this
yeah okay so my God
okay
do it again
removal
copy over
render Emax this script
five seconds okay
okay
then the second time
one second 1.7
yeah so e-max this has an advantage such
that
very interesting you know
for the second time emac is somehow
beats them all
I mean for the Wolfram language it even
beats python 2 for the second time for
for reasons I don't
right now
for the emac this for the second time it
beats them all
okay but now let's try to do it again
now let's write let's try the compiled
version okay
compiled version of easy so that
let's see if there's significant change
by the way this is byte compiled this is
not
um
natively compiled
in Emax 28 you started to have natively
compiled emac this
so we okay the speed is about the same I
expected 5.9
yeah back compile doesn't do you much
yeah
okay so that's the conclusion so here is
our conclusion for today
and there's some things to dig into that
is why is this result this way and
right now I don't know
uh the python figures appears
questionable I mean
it means there's something probably we
need to optimize in Python anyway that's
it for today
okay bye guys two people watching bye
if you like my stuff pay me okay go
through my website sorry.info and uh
is PayPal and patreon there
okay thank you guys bye
very interesting result okay and
clean up and put a code
Rats You by
so we're gonna have python wufam land
Evis you know so fantastic
okay so first of all let's get the Edis
code copy
okay because
uh
paste it there
then
move from then
open copy close back here paste then
painting python open copy paste
codify them all show in browser
today's talk show fantastic
you got Powershell you got
find replace pairs you got tiny results
you got
email address source code you got
wufam lens source code the shortest you
got python source code the longest
[Laughter]
okay bye