hello guys welcome to another episode of
SAR talk
show so it's been a while so how are you
today so so here's my keyboard This is
glove 80 fantastic this is Ultimate
hacking keyboard too fantastic okay and
this is s board data hand which I did
the review I did a I have a review of
all of these keyboards dat hand SW V
okay magnetic switch so I switched from
my kesis 360 to the G of 80 uh and it's
a great experience you know because I
have isi I typed so much in the past
week so it's getting the pain is getting
back coming back so this scub 0 you know
both of them are 35 G switch but this
one glove 80 is um is a uh them profile
you know thing profile so that makes it
much more lighter so it's fantastic so
and the SW board if you look back a
month ago you will see my uh video so
I'm going to start to learn this uh data
hand SP
board okay now that's about keyboard now
let's go back so if you are here say say
hi finally I'm here hello hang uh and uh
let me just talk about what I have been
doing in the past uh week or two past
week so you know I coded so much emac
this and the wolam language stuff so let
me start to show you so glove 0 keyboard
fantastic okay check into uh I recommend
okay and I have also been writing this
SAS guide on programming the kesis 360
keyboard okay so you know this is my
guide you can read their tutorials I
mean you can read their manual you know
check their manual or you can you know
my quick guide so I've been writing
it so so that's the S guide on
programing the kesis
360 and if you guys are thinking of
buying one of them here is my glove 80
versus Kinesis 360 I give you pros and
cons uh so you know between the two they
are both great I don't want to say you
know which I which one I prefer because
I'm a keyboard reviewer you know it's
not good if you just say oh I prefer
this one or I prefer that one uh
but you know but you know well actually
I slight I I I slightly prefer the gra8
okay but they are are many aspects for
example do you want it portable do you
want it Wireless do you want it
Bluetooth how you know um programability
do you prefer easy extremely easy to
program or do you prefer the most
powerful you have to compile or you know
you have to use the open source you know
the qmk and stuff so do you want it
portable so there are several issues and
how much the cost does it matter to you
so I have a table that compares so I
looked I have seen many other people's
reviews I mean as a keyboard reviewer I
sometimes also check out other people so
some people um you know I will I'll say
that some
people it's not always one-sided so some
some people prefer the glove 80 they
think it's much better you know some
people but some people prefer there are
some people prefer the kesis 360 they
think it's more professional so you know
so I give you PR and cons on this page
you can you can check it out okay now
the clesis advantage too I no longer
recommend because one of the biggest
reason reason is that because it doesn't
have um light linear switches the lowest
you can go is Cherry MX red uh Cherry MX
red silent something like that so I no
longer recommend it so either glove 80
or kesis 360 okay
so you know you can check out each one
of the aspect you know typ in Comfort
which one I prefer price which one I
prefer you know full size function keys
the gl80 has it you know but F F1 to F10
there's no F1 12 but you can set up keys
but so that's a detail you know full
function uh uh fulls size function keys
and wired or versus Wireless which one I
prefer you know one piece or two pieces
you know uh things like that which one
is most post portable so uh you guys
check that out so let me if you have a
questions post it now okay I'm going to
answer so swab board I really love it so
but you know I'm haven't been uh I've
been coding busy so but now I've set it
up you know I'm starting to learn it um
daily so you can see yeah so you can see
sof Smartboard hand you can see my
screen yes okay so I'm going to uh you
know start to learn it learn it every
day for half an hour
also okay so now let's talk about code
I've been coding a lot wam language wam
mod so let me so wam language you know
if you have haven't seen you can see
lots of my videos but
um uh what did I do okay
so let's let me show you so wam language
okay so let me just uh there's a update
on wam language mod so it's here so let
me just do a demo insert wam language
code okay so this is a blank new buffer
can you guys see it let's
[Music]
see
yeah okay so table table is like range
in Python uh can you see
it there's always some
issue yeah okay so let me move this over
here okay so table let's say x x from
one to9 so I want to evaluate it so you
can
press uh let's see hold on second so
control hm so you can see all the keys
you know all the new commands supported
so I just want to run it so you have Eva
region that's new and uh let's
see Eva eval region is New eval current
line is new and uh and the Run script
print last is also new run script that's
old so lots of update so so let's see
eval current line so I'm running I want
to eval the current line
and
uh there it is okay so here is the
result uh and uh let's let me show Eva
region okay so X so um x = 2 3 and
x + y okay so I want to evaluate these
two parts
so uh that would be tab
R uh wait what is tab R tab uh uh run
script okay so eval Regin is tab
e you see here's a result 3 + one so
that's uh you know that's San mod uh let
me show you the website so you can
download okay here's a source code
3,000 lines about and here's the URL
check it so if you just search the web
you'll find it woi mod and uh it's on
GitHub you can download okay so next so
questions okay post questions and I'll
answer
it close that close that okay put it
back now let's let me talk about the
next topic you know today I was I
upgraded the
OBS then when I started to live stream
it says oh you know your driver needs
your your graphics card driver is
incompatible because this is try to
update the graphic card driver so I have
to update the
Nvidia you know the the driver thing on
Windows sucks extremely extreme
incompetent you know uh extreme
incompetent let me show
you you know last time I tried to you
know about last year update you know
The Saga of updating Nvidia driver
fantastically incompetent [ __ ] you know
incredible and also the gamers The
Gamers the American Gamers they are
idiots you know when you install you
know when when you have a for example
let's look at the you know MV driver the
whatever this software is called okay
you look at the in interface first of
all it's tiny but the gamers don't care
the gamer thinks this is great you know
why usually when a software sucks and
yet it's very popular that means the
users are idiots okay so the gamer
Community created this situation so
first of all this you know Nvidia
control panel everything is Tiny you
know even I have my windows font size
magnified but it doesn't you know it
doesn't support it doesn't support it so
it's tiny I cannot
see then then one bunch of you know
techno garbage you know that let like
this kind of in this you know this tiny
thing this interface is like 30 years
old you know and then you know like for
example when I try to update I try to
see uh you know version of my
own uh you know and it's tiny I cannot
copy this you see this text I cannot
copy it you know driver version very
complex let me read it you see driver
version driver type direct 3D Feature
Feature level Cuda course graphic boot
boost doc you know [ __ ] crap you know
the gamma idiots they made it this this
way it's like you know when why flame
The Gamers it's like the Linux idiots
when I Flame the Linux idiot they don't
they don't they don't agree they say oh
no because you don't know the kernel and
stuff but when I flame Windows the the
Linux people oh yeah yeah that's right
you know they they don't see for
themselves the situation so in general
when when a software that's very popular
but it sucks but still very popular that
usually means the users it's got a
problem that's part of the reason there
are other reasons for example for
Windows part of the reason is the users
are idiots okay but but for Windows
specifically there are other reasons
because they already you know they
already saturated the markets you know
they have no competition basically you
know like like the Linux idiots why why
why is Linux not competition to
Microsoft Windows because Linux people
are idiots the Linux oh where are you
are still you know when I flame Linux
the Linux idiots they watch my show
they'll say oh look at this you are
still on windows so therefore what you
said doesn't apply this for Chan type of
idiots you know so if Linux is free and
open source you know 20 years ago 25
years ago by now you know we hoped like
we are imagining we are thinking in year
2000 that in 10 years Microsoft will
beun but that didn't happen you know now
after 25 years Microsoft is far more
powerful you know and Linux is like no
user and then the Linux idiots they will
say oh look at Google This Server is all
Linux you know extreme idiots so anyway
back to this so you see the user
interface you cannot copy the text and
you click about then you know it gives
you the about Box about this system info
what the [ __ ] is that the [ __ ]
extremely idiotic you know HDMI is logo
is a registered trademark you know PCI
Express is a tradem mark what the [ __ ]
you telling me this about for you know
then then the idiots you know they'll
say oh but that is actually legally
necessary to say that no okay look at
Apple Mac OS beautiful
it it's another issue okay it's World
Garden you know they make a lot of money
but however look when you look use apple
stuff you don't have this [ __ ]
okay so you cannot copy this then you
have to save and then it pops up you
know it was it pops up pop up pop up
this where do you want to save but it
defaults to system 32 something
[ __ ] you know in idiocy okay that that's
incompetent
[ __ ] okay and but Nvidia is like so it's
kind of corrupt you know because they
are saturated you know they don't need
to change you know we are just this way
so what so you know don't don't use it
yeah but the gamer keep will keep using
it so so they don't
complain so that's that's why you get
this situation and Nvidia is becoming so
rich and Powerful because of the AI I
you know so you know in the past year uh
you know open Ai and GP chat chat GPT
and all that
wave okay so you know so I have you know
but last year you know this so two years
ago 2021 I have to update it so I wrote
the entire Saga you know first of all
where do I find the device you know like
how do you upgrade a driver right so you
you you know you think you know
technology so on Windows that's device
manager you know you go
there and you check you know Nvidia Jos
you know driver properties and that's
not that's that's wrong okay it's got a
version here but it's got 10,000
different versions of of different
components okay and so there's a update
driver there you know you think you are
windows master so this is the proper way
you know you go to the device manager
and no that doesn't work if you do that
you know you [ __ ] up your system
then then then you know you click update
driver do you want to search for drivers
you know this this generic template the
windows idiot you know Microsoft Windows
then you know the nvdia control panel
[ __ ] then you click on that you know to
get a version then detailed information
about your Nvidia hardware and the
system it runs on you know the dll and
[ __ ] then then eventually you go to the
Nvidia website there's like 10,000 of
them download the
driver half of them are scams you
know you know the Nvidia might say oh
yeah but that's not them that's not us
you know it's them they did it no you
know be you know part of it because you
guys you know Nvidia did
it and then you go to the website then
then they have this product type let me
show you okay Nvidia I I still have
the okay so let me go back and uh you
see you go to product type GeForce Titan
Nvidia blah blah grid networking and
product
series you know it's like incredible you
don't know you don't know which one is
it so
anyway so that's about you know so you
know I wrote this article I documented
the full detail and and then you know
when you update you know they use this
opportunity to make more money so when
you don't try to update a driver that
you have the besides the all the
versions after finally you downloaded
the version then when you try to install
they'll tell you you know which one you
want do you want the GeForce
experience you know a little bit Tech te
tech tech tip okay whenever you see you
know something experien you don't want
it okay they try to install trash to
your computer to monitor your stuff and
stuff make your computer slow so you
don't want the gForce experience
[ __ ] it's there because the game are
idiots you
know and
then then Express okay so that's the
Saga of updating Nvidia driver okay let
me go back to what I want to talk about
um so there are some questions let me
answer the questions so we demonstrated
wolam update okay two more things let me
show you guys two more things okay wam
language this uh package for
doing Tidings this is the best package
for doing tiing okay wfam language plain
Tiding Mathematica package I talked
about in my past few videos uh real time
demo so now it's free and it's on GitHub
okay so you can you know you can
generate any uh plan tiing periodic
patterns so if you are a designer maybe
interior designer or architecture or you
are designing your garden or you are
designing a wallpaper or cloth clothing
patterns you can use this um package
okay you need the wam language you can
download it for free and for the
graphics you need to install Julia you
know it's also on the wolam language
GitHub
site so you can generate any possible uh
per periodic Tidings plus you have you
have variety of techniques using this
package to generate Tidings for example
this is uh recursive tiling okay so you
can also get patterns like
that okay and uh you know line transform
and so so so you can download it on
GitHub let's
see okay
there okay that's so that's on GitHub
and also this package plan tiing uh
plane curve plot okay it's also on G
GitHub I talked about in my video past
few videos many interesting
uh PL curve patterns okay so it's also
on GitHub
there okay that's about that so let me
answer the questions and then we go to
the next
one Juan says have you ever made a
desktop application I understand how
electron got so popular your only
alternatives for crossplatform desktop
are gtk and QT yes but they are asked to
deploy yes so on that question so have I
ever done a desktop application no the
answer is simply no okay uh and
uh about which is the best for
crossplatform application today the
answer is basically just uh electron
okay there's article on
that uh maybe I have a Blog I don't I
don't uh okay that's uh fancy keyboard
so let's go to my blog let's
see if I can find
it okay let me get
coffee
coffee so it's talking about electronic
I don't want electronic I want electrons
so let's
delete electronic
okay
uh oh there it is there it is the
article gtk
so so this is s program blog archive
August
gtk so there it is so this guy wrote an
article this guy has coded you know all
these different uh crossplatform
widget you know the Frameworks so you
know he wrote a detailed article about
that so I don't know about it so but
this guy I can trust he knows so who is
this guy uh what's his name
but anyway you can read this article
okay so according to him today it turns
out electron okay you know like the
typically the programmer will say oh
electron is just a
browser the idiots okay yeah but it
turns out today that is the best okay
and gtk is a circus you know typically
the goo open source stuff is the worst
so in Java FX it's part of java
basically you use you know basically you
create the application in Java style in
Java's GUI
style um so anyway I so electron is
probably the best the second best is QT
because I even I don't write desktop
I've never done a desktop application
but I've looked into like GT is used for
example Google Earth is written in GT
and quite a lot others GDK no G ddk is
for just G Des desktop you know just for
that okay QT is uh more popular but
today you probably want to write it in
electron the real course platform uh and
uh Discord for example let's open Kar
Discord no let's
notar Discord because if I open it now
it's going to show my friend stuff I
have to
click so Discord is also written in
electron VSS code is also return
electron for for example let me show
that
again so I have a emac command open in
vs code so we're going to open this
current page in vs code fantastic vs
code and whenever you know so okay so
you going to switch so this is my page
now I need to show control shift
Escape so you can see Visual Studio code
just one
page
what V Visual Studio code 50 megabyte
and
100 50 megabyte okay there it is
what you know it's incredible it used
used to be like 600 megabyte did they
fix it or what no they just separated
it and
see visual Visual Studio code wait did
they actually improve
memory
because because a year ago when you
start Visual Studio vs
code it's going to eat like 600
megabytes of
memory but now I guess they fix it
amazing that's interesting
finding so you know anyway so
emac emac use use is very extremely link
okay 72 megabytes of memory so
anyway so visual studio code is also
written in electron okay that's that
question I have not yet seen a package
for it but it exists I would use it so
much okay let
me half tab
oh you wish a wolam language in emac
well yeah that will take 10
years
uh okay anything else maybe that's it
for today okay I mean there is something
I want to let's
see there then there's a emac stuff I
want to talk about but I talked about
emac all the time so in the past week
I've done massive update on on my on
coding emac this okay massive you can
read my blog emac blog and in part
particular I worked
on I worked on uh lots of my packages
okay so let me let me show you
soar emac tutorial table of contents
packages you know I worked windows on
those and uh and then in the past few
days I updated
um my
emac lisp tutorial okay so you have you
can see the panel you have quick start
that gets you started coding emac lisp
you learn the lisp Basics okay so you
have comments you how to do comments you
have print you have string strange
section you have number section you have
buing section you have variables and
conditionals and loop and then data
structure list Vector sequence and how
do you define a function and more
advanced list symbols and uh and the
regular expression and and so on okay so
if you like my stuff buy it okay so you
can just go
to emac and pay me you get the whole
thing uh in a zip file so you have
instantaneous access and also use a
reference what are your thoughts about
rust is that is that are you trolling
rust is
[ __ ] okay so how long have I been so
maybe that's it for
today so if you have questions say
it
how come do you have tabs displaying
vertically and horizontally well that's
because in Firefox you don't have
vertical tabs okay so in Firefox if you
want tabs you have to install this
um Siberia uh what let's
see you know so let me show you
okay uh let me just show you okay some
wind
Windows tips okay you just search forar
Windows Microsoft Window
tips okay then you have everything about
Windows learn entire Powers shell and uh
learn about the full detail about
environment variables how do you set it
up and so on and how do you use
Powershell to do it to create
environment environment variables or
delete them or use the command EX see so
you have registry which is a big thing
in Windows you can also learn about it
all the details you need to know in the
most condensed and easy to understand
manner
okay and uh
then okay so the question your question
is about yeah okay about Firefox
so
uh good browser extensions so have some
notes about that you want to install U
block or engine okay that's a good one
and I also use duplicate tab closer okay
these are good ones because every time I
install browser extension I don't
install them in general okay I don't
install them any extraneous crap okay if
I do install I spend one hour to look
into who wrote it what what is this
guy's nature where is there a source
code you know so this one if if I put it
here you can be sure you can trust it
okay so these are open
source so one of them is you know
there's a GitHub old redit redirect so
cber okay cber is the one I use
I
so but they do not remove the horizontal
tabs that's kind of a technical
issue
okay that's it
maybe so
yeah
oh John Kitchen SX so you have a
question about John Kitchen simax I can
recommend
it okay John Kitchen I met him a great
guy I met him in 2018 2017 okay so
simax there it is okay and he's also on
YouTube he does you know he you know so
here is this guy John Kitchen he's a
professor in chemistry
okay so you can you know I can recommend
simax you know I don't use it of course
because I mean because I've been coding
emac for 20 years so everything I only
use my own stuff but John K you know he
has demonstrated you know this to me
before and I think it's uh very good
especially good if if you are academics
writing papers like if you are maybe a
PhD students or if you are Professor you
know you have to write about science you
know scientific publishing all the time
this is a good uh
emac distribution okay it's like the
whole thing simax
okay
YouTube does not allow links okay
YouTube chat never allow
links so there's a suggestion saying
that you can remove the horizontal tabs
with use chrome. CSS in Firefox
n just for your information okay that's
good information yeah but I'm not going
to bother I spend already too much time
you know dealing with the you know
software issues like setting the
preference I mean the biggest thing is
emac you know the emac you know I spent
10 20 years to set up
emx okay that's that's that's it I think
anything else how many people do I have
18 wow relatively high
today any question we're going to close
it down otherwise so I've been talking
for 40 minutes about
so let me so keys if you have not you
know you should try it so I did
tremendous tremendous update so much on
you know emac uh in P week and and even
continuously I mean you can this is my
blog they this is my emac blog they just
go endless endless for like 20 years and
the for CH people elevated me with this
meme okay and okay
so so s like Keys there's a new feature
so two days ago I worked on this run
current file so let me Demo okay so let
me Demo a few so let's see what I want
to do so let's say python okay
python so python print three okay
evaluated so you got three
instantaneously okay okay pop it back
let's do a Goan let me show the pink
window the pink window shows all my
command Calles and the key strokes on
the left okay so let's start a emac list
okay so
messages
High three
okay
evaluated you can see uh okay
evaluated okay
so I mean if you evaluate it you'll see
the uh you'll see the result in the
message buffer okay so let me show you
again evaluate the code so you can see I
just called sarun file go to the
messages buffer you can see there high
three okay so that's emac LP now python
let's do
JavaScript JavaScript okay pop it out so
it's all my mods you see this is
Javascript mod so let me go to so let's
just do this first okay constant no
console log three okay
evaluated three fantastic and what are
you what is this you are using I'm
using JavaScript mod go to it okay there
it
is600 lines so you can see all my
packages here so you see all the these
are backups so because I every time I
modify I make a backup so let's delete
all the
backup press a few keys are you sure yes
okay so you can see these are all my
packages you can get them all for about
$100 okay then you get a full Kar system
Kar emac okay you can just search forx
you'll see you know I listed there you
pay me $100 you get the whole so CSS
mod the mod emac list mod emac list find
S Keys s Keys is on GitHub it's free FSH
mod FSH is fantastic okay I started to
learn so I started to write a mod for
it goand mod oh let's demonstrate goand
okay so let's demonstrate go land okay
new
buffer uh meta X go Land mod okay then
actually you need to save it so let's
say
XX go okay uh go line is go
okay now type go press you got the
template okay now run
it okay when you run go first first time
it have to kind of do a warmup so you
can seear run current file and you can
see the answer is 33 because we printed
33 go Land mod okay now what is what
what uh what's the next okay so Goan mod
HTML mod which I use every day which you
have just seen uh let's see
what uh so HTML JavaScript mod we just
demonstrate Linden Script Mod Lindon
script language mod that's Second Life
okay math input uh that's good PHP mod
that's kind of old pow shell mod okay
let's do pow shell mod save it
XX do PS1 power shell extension name is
PS1 so if you type the it becomes get
children and runet you see this is the
output you see let's see let's say uh
okay you can run you know this is Powers
shell
this is Powershell so okay so close
Powershell save it close python we did
uh and wolam language mod we demo today
so anyway that's
it okay so what
else see exan JavaScript mod uhan talk
show
yeah pop it back sh
browser
oh
so so in emac this this is a bit
technical they started to have this
function set Q sequence set Q okay this
is fantastic this is basically pattern
matching or in other words it's called D
structure assignment okay so finally
it's in emac lisp but let me show you
JavaScript let me let me show you okay
um
D structure okay so you know D structure
binding so let me show you
um yeah okay so let's go go here go here
go here s code that's my homepage S
search
info D structure so you have that in
closure you have that in emac dis which
which is that sequence set C
you have that in JavaScript you have
that what is it self-destruct keyboard
in movie Alien okay that's
interesting and you also have that in
wolam language but I don't have a page
for it and you
also do you have that in goand I
forgot and do you have that in
Python uh I think
so I think these it's a new feature
anyway so you can see you know
inclosure uh yeah is in interesting okay
I'm kind of going nowhere so I think
that's it for today only 100 where do
you buy deprecated so you just search
forar Emax okay just search for Kar emx
okay karx okay package
uh emac
packages there it is ah stupid Brave
still shows the uro emac page but there
it is Kar emx packages so you can see
Kar emx right here so this is a
collection of all my packages you can
just PayPal me
or you can actually do it in Amazon gift
cards1
$110 but yeah I don't have Amazon get
just PayPal okay just use PayPal make it
simpler because if you use Amazon some
you know in the past some people have
sent me Amazon from Germany from Japan
that won't work you know you send $100
or $30 from Amazon Germany you pay to
Amazon but I cannot get the money you
know I need to open account of the
Amazon Germany or whatever so you know
it's basically Amazon just a your money
so just use PayPal okay use uh PayPal
this
address so the question is Lis was worth
learning in current year which one if
so and okay that's a frequently Asked
question that's so frequently that's
frequently fre the most frequently Asked
question
okay which language should you learn is
it worth
it okay let me show you some videos
because I'm not going to talk about that
because I talk about that tomorrow
somebody you ask again usually because
that's a that's a question you know
that's that's a bike shade
question you you know because there's
you don't really have if you already
have a goal you know which one is worth
it because but you don't have a goal and
you are young and you you know so you
want to watch I I recommend a few videos
to watch okay so you go to kali.org I
mean cali. info C code then you scroll
down then you have a
um programing language tutorials okay
then then you
have
um there is comp plan perving okay so
you open
that watch this video okay this is
actually
2021 very old where I talk about the
characteristics of hasal pearl Ruby
python closure Java JavaScript this wam
language you can you know so it's like 1
hour you know so you can listen to it
you can see you can kind of see a
summary kind of you know a summary of
the characteristics of the different
languages you know the very different
from typical
take uh then you know then there's
another video 2020 which programming
language is worth
learning so that's there's two of them
okay uh but that's not all because I've
been talking about this for 30 minutes
every every few
month so the other way is you go to k
talk show okay you just go to k talk
show homepage then you go down s talk
show clips so I started to collect kind
of
snippet information because I got
frequently asked questions all the time
so I but I forgot which video is it you
know because I by now I have like
700 uh videos and each one is 1 hour
long you know I should like you know
like those Joe Rogan and and uh Jordan
Peterson they have assistance so they
make clips and The Lex Freeman idiots
Lex Lex
fredman kind
of kind of he's a extremely idiot okay
Lex fman you know so they have assistant
they make Clips they have a dedicated
Channel just like five minutes Clips oh
drama you know click clickbait title
tiger versus lion which one is more
which one is
better in the [ __ ] idiots these
idiots so you have that you know so you
know you have lots of little Clips so
people and with with wild you know um
thumbnail pictures so that gets you
popular
I should have that but it takes a lot of
time to do it you know I and I do live
so anyway so I start to do to uh collect
some kind of things
um for example plain curves this is
mathematics okay and Unix programmer
idsy on ask key Obsession and the Damage
it has done so this are you know some of
the better Parts like 10 minutes or so
Auto form formatting automatic
formatting demonstration okay now this
one is it possible to create 3D game in
wolam language Okay naming Convention of
variable and functions okay that's
related to your question if you you know
want to know which language to learn a
shallow question programmers don't touch
type that's another big topic there's
like
a stigma attached you know if you are a
programmer but you don't touch type you
kind of oh you know you don't want to
tell people but it's rampant you know
most programmers they don't touch
type and the Pearl on the survival
strategies of Larry wall and uh Richard
strowman okay and here's his parents ask
for girlfriend that's Juan's question
what to do if my parents ask me do I you
know I have a girlfriend or not yet
yet and here's emac V evil mod versus
Stu like Keys okay and this one lature
the most idiotic thing in Western
culture lature
okay uh the cppo sign okay this one is
about political correctness the cppo
sign and this one why can't we prove why
can't we prove everything in C++ Java
python this one mathematicians versus
coding monkeys this one common lisp with
versus wolam language okay this one pow
Shell versus bash related to your
question which one which language to
learn which one is worth it you
know uh this one why Mozilla MD and
JavaScript tutorial
Su this one on Pascal Creator Nicholas
worth is he worth reading you know he's
a creator of the Pascal programming
language okay that's also related to
your question
this one why chat GPT so bad at math
okay that's a demonstration in real time
this one mathematicians hacker B gospel
okay that reminds me I need to work on
uh B bog gospel stuff
mathematician okay so and uh here's
about El musk and there's quite a few
more okay
so okay that's it for today bye guys pay
me okay go to PayPal you know you you
you go to Sali doino so actually I need
to show it because I realized I need to
do some marketing for myself okay you
can buy you know if you work at Google
or whatever you can donate $1,000 to me
I give you my entire website that's
about 2 gigabyte of s. info okay and
then you go to the bottom you can
patreon me you can Amazon GI card here's
a link for Amazon gift card okay then
you know and PayPal if you want to
donate or if you want to buy uh my
stuff that's
it
tomoko TOMCO is that the anime character
right I learned about you know I don't
know what is this anime character
so
apparently wait yeah it's this
one yeah Pinterest Pinterest is a
scum I don't want
Pinterest you know the brave browser is
got issues it's not so good I mean the
brave search it's better than Google
because it doesn't track you stuff
but uh but it does not always give you
the best answer so let's look up let's
use
lookup look up
Google there it is let's look at image
there it is so Google is kind of better
so this character you know this anime
character I'm not sure it looks like
she's autistic something like that oh
there's a
cosplay okay yeah but I don't
know exactly what why are they using
that character as a
me in stream