Hello guys, good morning. Welcome to
another episode of talk show. We are
going to code wam language. I'm going to
show you some interesting things about
wuam language. Let's see uh mathematics,
geometry and wam language. So uh it's
not technical. So uh uh any person can
kind of enjoy it. So here is wuam. So
here is some famous uh mathematical
geometry objects. Uh these are well
known. You probably have seen it. Okay,
I'm just going to go through and they
are uh they are in wam language
function. So you can plot them very
interesting and there's quite a few
more. So I'm going to add uh so wam
language.
Then there's a new ultimate hacking
keyboard. If you are here say hi. If you
are watching this offline pay at 1.5
speed. Okay. So, let's see. Am I like
live? Check. Double check. Check. Okay.
Low lower the volume a little bit. Uh
check. Double check. Okay. Good.
Keyboard uh video check. Okay. So, so
Wuan language and there's a news about
ultimate hacking keyboard. That's this
one. So, let me show you my keyboards.
Okay. So, there's some news. I'm going
to review them. So, the here I have
bunch of keyboards. So this is this is
glove 80 keyboard. Fantastic is my main
for the past like 3 years.
And uh this is ultimate hacking 60 or
also known as auto ultimate hacking
keyboard too. I use it as a micro
keypad. So you can see I can switch to
last uh application or uh or in browser
I can switch to previous uh tab next
tab. Okay you cannot see my screen. So
anyway, glove 80. This one ultimate
hacking keyboard 60C. Uh this is newly
attractable and this is Logitech G502.
Yeah, it's got a spin wheel. That spin
wheel. That's the best thing. Okay. So
there is a new ultimate hacking keyboard
can coming out. So the one I have
Ultimate Hacking 60 uh it's wired. Okay.
But the new one, so you can see I have a
review for each one of them, okay, on
YouTube.
In fact, more than one for each more
more than one video, like one hour alone
for each one of these keyboards. So you
can see this is my last written review
for automat hacking keyboard. And this
is the first version back in almost 10
years ago. The first version is oh 2018.
Okay, 2018 they came out with this
ultimate hacking keyboard. Now let me
tell you about ultimate hacking
keyboard. They are the highest quality.
Okay. Now in many many uh keyboards okay
if you are here say hi okay love to see
your comments. In many keyboards uh you
know they all have high quality. So for
example I can tell you uh I can tell you
like the highest quality ones that I
have. Um,
okay. This this and you know, uh, I'm
only talking about the ones I actually
have. Like usually they gave it to me
and I used it for many months or years.
So this one is glove 80 is highest
quality. Okay. Uh, and this this sturdy
metal like very heavy kinesis 360
keyboard is also highest quality. But
here's the thing. They are high quality
in different ways. Okay, the glove 80
it's it's meticulous design but however
the overall the the overall thing. So
let me show you. So um can you like see
uh let's see the video. So you see the
overall is kind of like plastic and you
know uh
but there's extreme uh meticulous design
engineering when doing into it because
this this uh glove 80 many many too many
aspect so you can go watch my video I
talked about them. So, for example, this
one, the GL, they designed it so they
want the key to be as low as possible on
the table, you know, like usually if you
put like especially like the G like the
um Oh, god. So, switch.
So, especially like switch. Okay. Uh
let's see. Switch. Uh switch. Yeah.
Especially like the Kinesis 360, you
know, they are if you put on the desk
like they're they're very heavy like
they are this high and and then your
hand will be raised up like one inch uh
from the keyboard. But the glove 80 they
want the lowest possible. So there's
there's extreme engineering uh design
went into it. And that's just one of it
one one aspect of the glove at what I
mean by quality. Okay. Quality design.
Okay. So, so there many aspect of
quality. That's what I'm talking about.
So, okay. So, that's the uh Can you see
it? Yeah. So, that's a G 80. Okay. Now,
on the other hand, the Kinesis 360
keyboard, they are built like a tank
like like a like a tank, you know, heavy
metal like they weigh a kilogram or
something. 1.5 kilograms. Uh what both?
Yeah both of them together. So this is
also high quality but different and also
so so there are pros and cons. Okay. So
right now my main is the glove 80 but
there are pros and cons. For some people
you might like prefer the Kinesis 360
built like a tank and also on the fly
programmability. You can program the
keys by just pressing a few keys on the
Kissics 360.
That you cannot do on glove 80. Like on
glove at if I want to change, for
example, the the right thumb key to be
uh escape tab, I have to go to the
website, log in, you know, uh drag the
key to create a key map, download a key
map, then flash the firmware, which
means you have to like
plug it in, plug it in or something.
Yeah, you uh I think so. Plug it in and
flash firmware and you know, so it's
tedious. So usually you program it once
and you never like usually you don't
bother with it. So that's one aspect I
don't like about the uh glove 80 but but
of course it's got other advantages.
That's why this is my main now. So on
the other hand the Kinesis 360 is
dynamically programmable. If you just
want, you know, let's say experiment,
you want the right hand control to be
escape or whatever, you press three keys
and it's done. It's it's burned into the
firmware, you know, programmable on the
fly. But that only applies to wired
version. Typically for wireless that's
like uh impossible. Usually they don't
have that feature. So anyway, so so what
I'm saying is the quality there are
different uh meaning of quality. Each
one of these went into of course there
are some others they some other keyboard
that is not high quality but I'm talking
about the high quality ones. Okay. So
then you got this. This is one of my
favorite like the expose. It's extremely
simple.
Hold on a second.
Extremely simple. Cheap one piece. And
uh every time I use it, it's a joy. Like
you don't have to fiddle like you don't
have to typically like the two-piece
keyboards you have to like remap your
keys and you know you find that con
inconvenient you want to change it or
something but the but the expose is just
simple it's it's one always been one of
my favorite every time I use it it's a
joy okay so the quality is you know in
different aspect and it's also uh very
sturdy it's uh this version expose night
is
build out of metal. It's so it's also
metal. Okay. So then the ultimate
hacking keyboard is also of highest
quality. Okay. Now in part in particular
about the ultimate hacking keyboard I I
have been using for like uh by now seven
years two different versions. Okay. So
for example right now I have the mouse
you can you see this is a score ball uh
score uh track ball. Okay. And you know
there's a add-on modules I can show you.
So I have everything written out on my
website. You can see there's a separate
page for
uh add-on modules you know. So anyway so
the on the ultimate hacking keyboard
what they have
in it's high quality every you know for
example I can tell you that one of the
highest quality. Okay. Uh my my desk is
all messy, so I can't
I can't just show you without
up my wires. But um but you see
the feet, the snap on feet. It you can,
you know, you can just snap on the the
design. Uh
wait,
I don't want to break it. Of course,
you know, the the feed you can snap on
and off so extremely easily, but uh god.
Okay, now this is embarrassing. So why
can't So there it is. It come off. It
should, you know. So it's
um well, I cannot show you the details.
Can you see it? But anyway, in my video,
you you'll see the full demonstration.
So, just snap it in, twist it, and it's
there. Okay? And you can pop up the
feet. So, that is a design element, you
know, you can you can take it off. You
don't need screws or whatever.
But one thing particular about the about
the ultimate hacking keyboard is that
the guy I be I believe they are like
original they are in Ukraine. And I
believe they are building Ukraine or
something around there around Eastern
Europe somewhere. I I don't remember.
But one particular quality is about
software. They update their software
like every every year. Okay. So let's
see. Ultimate hacking uh keyboard agent.
That's the software. And by the way,
it's also open source. So you see
there's a update firmware. I don't want
to do it now because you know I'm middle
in the middle of a live stream. But but
can I show you? Yes. Key cluster. Track
ball. So, uh let's see. Yeah. Here's the
track ball. Key cluster. Uh what is my
normal? Yeah. So, here's my normal
setup.
The one particular quality about the
ultimate hacking keyboard is that the
software is superb. Okay. Now unlike the
Kinesis 360 where you can just press a
few keys without ever launching any
software
but the ultimate hacking keyboard you
have to launch the software. Okay.
However, it it is just extremely easy.
You don't need like you don't have to
read any manual like you have to usually
you know configuring keyboard you have
to read the manual or how do you do
that? But but the auto hacking keyboard
software is just fantastic. never has a
problem, you know, everything just
works, okay? And they update it like
like every year, you know, you know,
every time you launch it, they tell you
there's a firmware update. So, if I say,
for example, say update, it'll just
update after like about a minute. I
don't have to like unplug, replug,
double check, you know, nothing. So,
it's superb. Okay, this and and also the
the keyboard build quality, I'm not
going to show it today. watch my old
videos, okay? The build quality is just
superb. Okay, like superb.
Now, the the news is that so I have
reviews, you know, I was I I used to be
a big keyboard re reviewer for the past
15, 20 years, but I I kind of stopped
doing it because there's new keyboard
every every year. So anyway, so
so out of the um so let's let's let's
let's close that. So you can read, you
know, there are 1,000 articles about
keyboard, mouse, trackboard, everything.
Okay.
So there's a news about ultimate hacking
keyboard. So let's go to uh go to kasar
code.info
my homepage.
Then uh keyboard blog. Then there is
news ultimate hacking keyboard 80 came
out. Okay, this is fantastic upgrade.
This is their website. So go to it. So
this is the one UHK80. So there's quite
a few uh significant features addition.
Okay. So first of all you got the
function keys now which is kind of
necessary for a lot of people for me
too. Um but then you got now four extra
or uh yeah four extra thumb keys. Okay,
that's fantastic. This you know can you
see it? That is that is almost that's
significant. That's very significant for
ergonomics. And also on the side they
now they have dedicated arrow keys and
page up page down home and that is also
absolutely necessary. So, I didn't like,
you know, the ultimate hacking before.
It was kind of, you know, it's like it's
one of those six keys. So, you don't
have dedicated arrow keys. You don't
have dedicated page up and down, you
know. That's that's
especially about arrow keys. That's a
major issue for me.
Uh, so now that's fixed in the Ultimate
Hacking Keyboard 80. So, that's
fantastic. But plus you got page up and
down home end and function keys. So that
would be fantastic. And plus it's
wireless
finally.
You know a lot of people need wireless
these days. So it's two is USB wireless
with the dongle. Plus it's also
Bluetooth wireless and it can also be
used plugged in while it's plugged in.
So it's fantastic. So when you buy it
actually you can buy without the option
of batteries. So meaning that you're
gonna always use it wired. So you don't
you don't add the batteries, but it's
still the same keyboard. Okay. So that
is coming. They are sending me uh you
know a a unit uh with all the add-ons I
believe. So I'm going to demonstrate
that
uh and probably I will be using it for
like a year or two or three.
Okay. So that's the news. Ultimate
hacking keyboard. So anyone here three
people. Okay. Say hi.
So that's a news about automatic hacking
keyboard. Okay. And it's got tenting.
Fantastic. Okay. So that let's uh that's
about that about keyboard. Let's see.
Now let's talk about math then. Okay.
Uh yeah. So wam language for
programmers. If you don't know yet, you
can use that's the best programming
language by a magnitude and you can
download it for free. Just go to
kasali.info my website this page search
for uh kasaw language tutorial for
programmers. Okay, kasali.info
and click on download. Be sure to follow
these links specifically because if you
search the web, you'll be misled into
some, you know, other random pages. If
you go to Wuam Language website,
wufam.com,
they have like literally like I believe
they have like like a million pages on
their website and there's lots of
marketing material. So you you have no
idea where to find the download you know
you you go like introduction or or why
language is the best you you know or
other things but if you want just to get
a download and start it you know easiest
way is just go to my website or the the
URL is woofam.com/developer
okay so you can download it okay and you
can you know I have like
over 100 Wam language tutorials in the
past. Okay, video tutorials. Each one is
1 hour. Okay, without further ado, let's
let's start to uh do today's uh what I
want to do today. Mesh region. Mesh
region is incredible. Okay, mesh region
they started to uh they added this
feature about 10 years ago in 2014. Wuam
language 10. Okay. So, and I've been
studying it. I find it's not it's not so
simple. Okay, it's not so trivial. So,
I've been spending quite a few times in
the past few months trying to read it,
you know, because there are there are
about like over 100 functions related to
this mesh thing. Okay, what is the mesh
thing? You know, I con conceptually it's
very simple. You guys all have seen it.
Just like a little triangles, mini
triangles, they make a a patch of a
surface or something, you know, for
example. Let's see. You know, something
like, you know, tetrahedrin, you know,
this blob,
you know, or or like, you know, a sphere
or this, you know, it's a mesh like you
often see it in the design of a car
engine or shuttle, space shuttle and and
so on, jet fighters and so on. But it's
actually
so you know there's a lot to it. There's
a huge amount of u computational
geometry. So you know I've been reading
it it's complicated. So I started to
realize they were designed 10 years ago
you know like 100 functions about this
mesh. So what you so I was a bit
confused why are they doing it you know
what's it like what what what is the
design principle? Why do the why why we
have 100 things about the mesh? I mean
after all it's like a bunch of
triangles, right?
So so I traced it to you know Wuam
language version 10 2014. So Stephan
Wuam has an article
um
you know he introduces the Wufam
language version 14. So I read it and I
get I got an insight. Okay. So you can
see my inside actually I posted it on
Twitter. Uh but Twitter my Twitter is
got lots of things.
Uh let's see if I can find it. So basic
yeah well I posted yesterday. So Twitter
is kind of um
yeah let let me show you his article
then. Let's see. Stefan Wuan.
Okay. Stefan Wolf from
uh latest writings or writings.
So 2014. So you go back 10 years ago.
Each one of his articles takes many
hours to read. Each one of his article
is actually a book length. And in fact,
some of them are published as mini books
like you know uh so each one of them
takes several hours to just have a
glance.
That's the way he writing style. I mean
he's Yeah. So 2025 2024.
Uh
so you got computational knowledge and
future of pure mathematic pure
mathematics. Okay. So there is Wuang
programming cloud is live launching
Mathematica 10 with 700 plus new
functions and a crazy amount of research
and development there. So in this
article he detailed
he detailed about the reason for this
mesh
uh like there's a lot this is the
beginning of the machine learning uh
era. Okay, like remember this is 2014.
2014 is around the time when the machine
learning craze came up. So they started
to have like machine learning functions
built in. You know you can simply just
say classify it'll just uh you know tell
you a element from data from massive
data of your own.
So, so here is that's when they started
to talk about the additions they have in
geometry. Okay. So, it turns out the
mesh is complex. Simply put is because
they are trying to merge the concepts of
the mesh in from mathematics, the field
of mathematics and the field of 3D CAD
design like for engineers designing car
engines. um
uh jet engines and so on CAT systems. So
merge mathematics and CAT systems and
computer graphics. So for example, so
let me quickly let's see if I can um
show you some example.
So in so for for example this Taurus
that's a typical computer graphics,
right? You might see it in game game
engine too. uh or or in game engine
anything you see is kind of like
computer graphics. Okay. So computer
graphics there's you know so in there
you have the concept of points line
triangle or a patch depending on you
know yeah you know you have like do they
call it a patch I don't know but anyway
you have these
concepts point triangles lines and so on
or to or maybe Taurus so that's computer
graphics but in mathematics you also
have these concepts line point uh plane
Taurus
or triangle. But the the the ideas in
mathematics this triangle line point is
very different from computer graphics.
Okay. Like in computer graphics a point
like a two dimensional point is just two
numbers. Okay. In mathematics that's not
just two numbers. That's that's like
that's the coordinate that like that's
you know they call it coordinate space
two dimensional of
real coordinate space real means real
numbers okay which you cannot represent
all real numbers in computer graphics
but anyway math math you know
mathematics point is very different is
slightly different from computer
graphics okay and then you have the CAD
system
um CAD engine okay Let's see I can show
some pictures
you know for example design of a car
engine. Okay that's from CAD system. Now
in the CAT system you also have the
concepts like point line triangle but
but those those those concepts are very
different from from computer graphics in
let's say in your typical 3D uh game
engine. Okay, very different because in
CAD system they need to be very precise
and they you know they have different
needs. Okay. So basically mathematics,
CAD system and uh computer graphics they
all kind of share they all have this
concept of line point plane or dimension
or triangle a patch or a surface or or a
nerve or a spline or spline curve or
parametric curve but they don't share
that but you know many of them are
different for each one. So but in wuam
language what they do is they unify it.
Okay. So so it's kind of you know
so I read it you know I realized and
that's actually the design that's kind
of the fundamental design principle of
wam language. Okay. So basically you
want to take the approach that you look
at the word doesn't matter what it is
history programming mathematics or
whatever or esoterica or or you know any
anything
human ever did in in the world that we
know of. Okay. And you want to create a
a whole map of them a consistent way in
a consistent way. That is what wuam
language is. Okay. So of course wam
language is a programming language. So
it it focus on you know things related
to programming language. So now you have
so now back to our mesh thing. Why is
the wam language mesh like fairly
complex? Because it's generalized. It's
for computer graphics
uh such as such as you know we are you
know plotting this Taurus or sphere.
It is also for
CAD.
Okay. And it is also for mathematics.
Okay. So that is that's so that's quite
that's why. Okay. So let me show let me
start to show you a example. Okay. So
uh so example so mesh region. So let's
see. Uh okay. So so you got this mesh.
So let's say mesh region examples. Okay.
Now that's what I want to show today. So
these things. So for example this one uh
spice
spinski
this this is typically called spur
pinsky triangle. Okay. So select or
paste evaluate. Okay. So you can see
uh you know this this is one of the
first fractals you break a equal angular
triangle
uh into four. So uh for each side at the
midpoint you mark it and the three
midpoints of each sides forms a smaller
equal angular triangle in the middle. So
the triangle becomes four of them. Okay.
Then you repeat the process. So you take
the top one as a triangle. You repeat
it. So you got you got this sequence of
triangles. So this process can be re
repeated to infinity. So you got kind of
like kind of this fractal structure.
Okay. And this concept span Spaniski
triangle can be extended to
three-dimensional.
So here is a three-dimensional version.
For example, let's enlarge this one.
Okay.
Okay. So here here here is the uh Okay.
So uh first of all let me just show you
the Wikipedia article. So there is
Wikipedia article. Now this this um
let's see do they have a pronunciation
section? No. Okay. But anyway let's say
sepinski
seapinski triangle. Okay. So this
triangle this kind of fractal thing they
they are a concept in mathematics. Okay.
This is very important. You know this is
about why we were talking about the CAD
systems versus the computer graphics
systems versus the math. Okay. So in in
CAT system
you will never have this this
you know this fractal thing that's just
like that's for you know in in in 3D cut
system maybe for visualization
maybe for toy or for drawing ones you
have that but for for the ones that
builds engine you never have that you
never need it you don't want you know
you don't you don't need it because you
are never going to build actual fractal
that goes to infinity
Right. So this this you know this um
wait so uh where is it? Um
this sepinsky triangle they are a
concept in mathematics only okay and in
mathematics then you have limits you
have you can find their area you can
find the length of the triangle and so
on. Okay. But that doesn't exist in in
uh CAT systems. Um and and for computer
graphics, yeah, you can do this. It
would be very interesting if you guys
try to draw this in Python or whatever
JavaScript. Uh of course with Wuang
language, it's much easier. Okay. So
that's one of them. So let's go to the
next one. So um yeah, so there it is
that. Okay. So there now here is another
one. This this one is called the manga
manga uh sponge usually. Okay. So let's
paste the code here. Evaluate it. There
you are. Uh the idea is pretty similar.
Okay.
Uh kind of you factor. Okay. So let's go
to the next one. This one is canered. Uh
traditionally it's called caner dust.
Okay. So you can the idea is kind of
pretty similar. So you start with a a
whole square then you divide the square
into nice smaller squares. Okay? Then
you keep the ones at the corner
but in the middle you remove them. So
one big square becomes four smaller
squares. Okay? Then you repeat it. It
becomes you know 16 smaller squares. You
repeat it and so on. And this thing this
can dust originally it was uh applied to
a line. So a line you you know you cut
the line into three parts three equal
parts. You delete the one in the middle.
Then you got two lines you know on each
side. Right? So for each one of those
lines you repeat the process. So you got
that then you got that you know you got
smaller and smaller segment of lines. So
this process should repeat to infinity
you know do this infinite number of
times the result is called
canerd dust. Okay so let's say caner
dust you'll find it or it's also known
as caner set.
So Kender does you don't you don't you
know by the way you don't want to use uh
wolf math word that that website sucks
usually is wrong too. Uh so you want to
uh caner dust. So it it used to be known
as caner dust but today it's more like
caner set.
Okay. Can where is it? Uh Wikipedia.
Uh, Wikipedia does Wikipedia caner
physical road. Now, what the is
that?
Okay, let's search for Caner set.
Caner does let's say type math
George Caner. Okay, so George Caner is
one of the great mathematician that's
him. Uh
there can counter set. Okay. So
Wikipedia will describe it. Uh let's
see. Uh stupid formatting. So let's
let's just make it
okay. They so there. So they show you
this they they show this. So this is one
dimension. you know, counterdust was
originally, you know, it's it's it's one
of the first exploration of the concept
of uh like
uh
continuity or density of a space or
something in topology. Okay. So, you got
this weird space, you know, like you can
it's not continuous. I mean, is it
anyway that's that's that's one of the
first study. Okay.
And so it can be general generalized
into two dimensional. So in two
dimensional you got this you got this
thing and in and also in three
dimension. So you got this thing. Okay.
So that's called caner set. Now in now
now remember in wam language they all
end with the word mesh
you know. So like again in mathematics
they are not called mesh they are a set.
But but why in wuam language they all
became mesh like you know in mathematics
that doesn't make sense that's not a
mesh that's a set so it's a mesh because
remember you wam language unifies this
concept in mathematics
computer graphics and 3D cat systems so
you you because you know because this
this thing yeah it's it's a you know
spin Inski triangle it's a it's a
topology uh space it's a uh set in
mathematics however in computer graphics
it's a bunch of triangles you can you
can you can plot them and in cat systems
you you can actually build these two
like especially when you are doing 3D
printing you know just for toy so the
the idea exist in all these fields but
but you you need a data structure that
kind of can unify all of
So that's why you got this mesh thing.
So in wam language these things are
called mesh because they are basically
the definition is basically a u the it's
very interesting. Okay actually the
definition is called also exist in math.
It's called
simplicial complex.
Okay, there
simplicio complex
that is kind of fairly advanced. Okay,
so a complex a a complex is basically a
like a point, a line segment, a triangle
or a tetrahedrin or in higher dimensions
or higher you know. So basically they
are the minimum um kind of elements that
occupy the dimension. Okay. So,
uh they're simplex, you know. So, like
these are simplexes. In in zero
dimension, it's a point. In one
dimension, it's a line segment. In two
dimension, it's a triangle. In three
dimension, it's a tetrahedrin.
In four dimension, it's uh it's a how do
you call it? I don't know. But it's like
you know in four dimension you got an
one you know then you you got in five
six seven and higher dimensions. So so
all these things in general you call
them simplex.
Okay in any dimension. So that's
simplex.
Now what what is a now then what is a
simplicial complex? That's that's
basically a set of simplexes. Okay. a
set of simplexes that may be connected
together like this. Okay. So this apply
this idea applies in any dimension.
So so this is a math idea and and that
that idea is basically the fundamental
unifying idea of the wam languages what
they call mesh region. Okay do you guys
understand like maybe not I don't know.
Okay. So anyway, so all these meshes we
are seeing uh you know SPinsky
triangle mesh or the um Morgan sponge
you know they call it mesh or the caner
mesh they actually all return this they
all return this mesh region. So for
example I can show you. So for example
this um
okay so let's say paste that there x uh
okay so x equals to can mesh
uh oh uh counter mesh so you want to
nest three times in dimension two uh
let's say dimension three okay there you
go there you go so let's not nest too
many times let's nest it um just two
times. So nest it just two times.
Okay, you got this thing. Uh okay, let's
say two, three, four times.
Okay, that's interesting. And you can
now say
um
you see it returned this huge list.
There are 32,000 stuff points in it. So
but the whole thing is a mesh region. So
all these their return value is this
mesh region.
Okay. That is that interesting. Hello
simple postman. Let me get my coffee.
And maybe that's it for today.
Simple postman says
let's magnify.
So control uh and I assume that in
practice if
uh
yeah this is annoying. I assume that in
practice a fullscale cat system written
in wuam language would be very slow. So
even though it's admirable that the
concept of line actual unified
application is doubtful that's not
that's not correct. Okay but let me let
me answer that. I mean let me tell you
so how detailed and precise can a 3D
image being woofam? I never used it
beyond math homework. Okay. Then he
says, "I have just got Google Wam system
modeler." So probably I'm wrong. That
That's right. That's right. And there
are real world system for 3D simulations
and CAD wam language. Yes, that's true.
So what that's what I'm saying. So
if your job is a professional let's say
uh drafter you know or you know like
there's a job you know all this computer
cat used to be draw by by hand you know
like back in 1990s when I was at Dansza
community college there's a course
there's actually a major I think yeah
actually a major to be a drafter and I
was very much interested I was you about
to become a drafter because I was
fascinated by these you know uh drawing
of engines or space shuttles. Okay. So
um for example
CAD space
you know AutoCAD you know there are
many. So, so before before computers all
these are actually done by hand but
maybe not as detailed as this one but
you but you got to do this for gears you
know symbol or bicycles you know lots of
things. So I was um
yeah so so what what was I going to say?
Yeah. Um yeah so what I what I was
saying is that so if your job is like
professionally creating these things
then obviously you you you need a prof
dedicated CAD software such as AutoCAD
there there's quite a few uh I have
actually a lot articles about that so
let's search um let's say CAD
uh
let's see computer uh CAD systems. Okay,
so 3D CAD uh no math models and 3D
input. Okay, so these are my very old
articles. Mathematica graphics with live
graphics 3D that's like 20 years old. Uh
relies on Java that no longer works.
Okay, because Java plugin on the browser
that's gone. So let's see 3D
visualization design. Wait, what? Uh
okay let me just find the article 3D
visualization design okay that's uh like
this is old article requirement for a
visualization system 2010 outline
rendering 3D models what is technical
drawing descripted descriptive geometry
and project geometry and linear algebra
what are the differences
uh uh math models of 3D input control.
Okay. So let's go back
mathematical optimization problem. Okay.
So let's see. So here is another
interesting thing like usually when we
see cartoon they are drawn like that or
or this or these image they they
actually they are not
uh it's very interesting because in
order to draw this you cannot just rely
on a 3D model. You need
to have a 3D model. Then you need to
have a 2D projection like you you need
to project it on a plane then figure out
find find the like convex hole.
So anyway so it's not a pure 3D thing.
So very interesting. So you know also
for example this thing you see that's a
screenshot in Second Life. So it's
showing showing this cartoon character.
This this is a uh Monopoly uh boss, you
know, the the character, but it's in 3D
because in Second Life it, you know, the
guy actually moves, but actually but but
the way you see it is only 2D, you see.
So, what they what's happening in this
kind of thing is that you got a 3D thing
like that, you know. For example, we we
we did this uh live
um
and uh so for example, I can show you.
So paste it. There it is. There it is.
Go down.
It's computing. So go down. Go down.
Wait, what? Okay.
Okay. I did. Okay. That that is
incorrect because I defined the X.
That's what screwed it up.
So I need to undefine X. Okay.
Clear
X. Okay. Then let's run this.
Okay. So you see you got that. You got
that.
And then you got that.
Then you got that. Then you make it
thicker. Then you got that. So this is a
computer graphics 3D thing. Then once
you have this, then you need to project
the whole thing into a 2D plane. Then
you take the outline. So in this case,
the outline is like some of something
like that. Okay. So in fact let me show
you something interesting. So for
example let's um
I'll get back to your question but
actually you you already you know you
already know the answer. You got the
answer but so let me let's capture this
image.
So we got a 2D image. Now how do you
import a 2D image? Can you uh drag it?
Let's see.
There it is. So there it is. Okay. Now
uh shift enter. So wait. So now let's
say x image equals to there. Okay. So x
image is now a raster raster image.
Okay. Now let's use that one of the mesh
um uh to turn that into a mesh that like
the thing we are talking about today. Um
god do you guys are still following me?
like we we can turn an image into this
uh which is let's see
because I was trying to do this
subdivision mesh okay the looney mesh
that's very interesting thing we haven't
done yet veron mesh uh convex whole mesh
array mesh we haven't done yet image
mesh okay I was wondering you know it's
turning a image into this
assume you know I assume it's a 3D thing
so I have no idea so now it's a good
time to try so let's see
image mesh uh not muted pie image mesh
okay now x image let's see what it
returns there it is so it you see it
returns the outline
fantastic it you see it takes a image
The image is basically a 2D pro
projection of this. You see this is 3D
but once we take a screenshot it becomes
a 2D image basically a projection. Then
you say image mesh that turns it into a
a kind of outline. Okay. So, which
brings up what we were talking about
about the um
can we go back about this you know
outline rendering of 3D models
anyway we digressed so basically what
I'm saying about that you know can wolf
language do cat is that if you are a
professional programmer
I mean if you are a professional cat you
know designer then you use dedicated
CAD. But for engineering if you are
designing a uh car engine and you know
something often times you need to solve
equations you need to output models then
you then you export you know you see
this idiotic website anis space claim.
So you you you can design in wam
language with very precise you know CAD
specification then you output to you
know one of the 10 uh CAD system formats
then you import into the cast system
then you can further do whatever uh you
want to do with it. Okay. So what is
this website? So let's refresh. That's
one of the problem of modern websites.
Uh when when you don't have JavaScript
it's still stupid. Okay, doesn't work.
But you know the graphics become fuzzy
because maybe because I don't have V uh
cookie on. Anyway, so all these are CAD
stuff. There are so many.
So So what I'm saying, yeah, if you are
professional cat, you know, maybe you
use a CAD software, but often times you
you need to do a lot of equation solving
stuff, you know, to get it right. Then
you can do it in Wuam language. Then
eventually you get some kind of thing
like that. Then you can export it, you
know. Okay. Now, now the website looks
good. Accept all cookies. Oh
I'm going to every every time I quit
you'll delete all cookies. So this is
another 3D modeling software. Okay.
Okay. So that's what I'm kind of what we
are talking about.
So but if you are you know if you are a
Photoshop you know professional designer
for website that applies too like
typically you use Photoshop right but in
Wuam language you can do a basically
anything you can do with image
processing so for example image you know
there's like whole ton of image
processing functionalities
um so let me let me go to it Okay.
So if you go to the wolf um
documentation.
Okay. So graphics images. Okay. So image
computation overview you can do like
just about anything everything Photoshop
needs to do or and NASA they need to
process you know photos taken from Mars
or whatever.
Okay. So you know
so so what I'm saying yeah so you can do
just like anything anything that is
possible with a computer for for me
programmers you know I'm into geometry
so that I do a lot of these uh kind of
thing and and also do lots of like text
processing things like that so you know
anyway Okay.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Thank
you guys for watching.
Yeah, actually I actually there there is
something I need to do. Okay. So, let me
let me finish them. Okay. Save this.
Save this today.
Okay. And uh there is more things I want
to do. Okay. So, mesh regions. Did we
finish demo? No, not yet. For example,
this uh the looney mesh we haven't
demoed yet. That is very interesting
because what it does is uh why can't I
paste
Oh, because I got function key in. Okay,
now paste shift enter.
That's so you give it like 50 random
numbers.
Okay, this so this part return uh let's
say five random numbers. So this this
means give me a random number between
zero negative 10 to 10
and give me five of them but in in group
of two. Okay. So shift enter. There you
are. So now do the same. Let's say give
me 10 of them. But however feed the
input into the delun uh the lun mesh.
Okay. So do that it generates a mesh.
Now this so you basically you got a
random bunch of numbers and it create
triangles
among them uh in a particular way uh
that and that is related to
vol noise triangle. Okay, let me show
you that. But anyway, but but here you
can also do it in three dimension. So
this time we got a bunch of random
numbers 50 of them in groups of three.
So each three points is each three
numbers is a point in space. So that's
that's this input. Then create uh the
lun mesh then highlight some part of it.
So let's run it.
So there you have it. So the the vertex
are colored red,
the line segments are colored blue and
the faces are colored you know light
blue and transparent. So you can see
semi-transparent.
So let's say change opacity to
uh opacity to two. So much much more
transparent.
And let's change too many points. Let's
change it to just 10 point. Shift enter.
So there you have it. Okay. And this uh
there's a lot more. So I wanted to do
I wanted to demo
boron noi mesh. That's very interesting.
Okay. So
uh
so let's go to
Okay. So,
let me just do a few more. Okay. So, you
go to uh geometry
and meshbased geometric regions. So what
I have been reading is all this geometry
in the past uh month especially
basically
this and this and this this these three
uh these two meshbased geometric regions
regions and derived geometric regions
this like there are 100 functions just
in those two fun uh two sections. So
this here we covered most of it
already. Let's magnify
mesh region. Then we cover that. So
let's do this one.
Okay. Uh veronoi mesh.
Um
and uh you can have it in one dimension
or two dimension. Okay, let's just copy
it.
Okay, you you have to copy it. Uh
so show in browser. So that is what I'm
doing. And now so now a new section
Okay. And what is the thing we are
doing? This is called
uh
veronoi
mesh.
Okay. And the function is that
make a wolf language
reference link
and uh start a
wra language code. Pop it out and that
returns a list of random numbers 25 of
them.
Okay. And then what you want to say is
just that random numbers. Okay. So
remove that. So ellipses,
we don't want the ellipses.
Uh yeah. So
so actually we don't want that. Just put
it here. Okay. So that will do it. So
this is a two-dimensional version. Okay.
And we can also have a one-dimensional
version. So here you don't say that.
Okay, that's one-dimensional version. So
let me show you. So go to back to wra
language, paste, run it. Uh, no, that
didn't work. Oh yeah, because you forgot
to say how many. Uh, so you want, let's
say, 20 of them.
Okay.
Uh, no, that didn't work. Maybe you need
do that. There it is. Okay. So, each
each time it generates a different
different one.
Uh, and so that's one dimensional case.
And so, let's do that one. And here is
two dimensional case.
Okay, fantastic. Okay, now it's, you
know, it's like missing something
because usually this diagram is shown
with a dot in the middle. Uh because
Okay, so that's easy uh easy to do. So
let's just Yeah, that's why it says
points equals true. So those are my
points. And uh then
mesh equals to that. Then what we going
to show is we're going to show
uh
show
show the mesh. Plus we want also to show
uh points. Okay. So what we can do is
okay. So it should be just
uh wait. So, let's make it red.
Yeah, let's see.
Okay, that's not right because you are
missing graphics.
There it is. So the red dots are the
original random points and the ver V ver
Veronoi
uh the veronoi mesh is created that it
creates a line between any two dots such
that the line is like in the middle of
them. So that's how this um this is
formed. Okay. So if you want to know the
details,
you can just search for it. Veronoi
diagram. Okay. And there's a JavaScript.
This is very interesting. There's a
JavaScript application out there that
allows you to, you know, click on
several to create to to create random
dots and move the drag the mouse and
they'll show you change in real time.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Um,
working on cast system, you know, that's
difficult. You know, you've been working
on a 3D game engine in list, that's very
difficult. 3D game engine and you also
been working on CAD system. So that's
also very difficult.
Okay, bye guys.
Interesting stuff. Thank you. Yeah,
that's it. Bye. So we shut down in one
minute.
So this is working code. Yes. Uh so put
it back
and uh and syntax collect show in
browser then we're going to add
so we need to add the graphics add this
graphics there
and I myself need to uh spend many hours
or days to study
uh many of these but for example this
one this one you know the um
the veronoi diagram I never actually
read
you know the algorithm how do you
actually do it you you know because it's
this is not easy not trivial okay
because you need to create this
this dividing lines in order to create
the dividing lines basically you need to
find these other points you see so given
a bunch of random points in a plane
By the way, this also can be in three
3D. Uh we we didn't show, but you can do
it in 3D just just like just like this
this just like this um this the looney
triangles. Okay. In fact, they are they
are the opposite of each other. They are
the what they call dual. Okay. So,
Veronoi triangle
stew is the Doneyi mesh. Okay. So in
other words this given a random bunch of
points in the plane you want to find
another bunch of dots in the plane such
that when you connect the dots they
divide any two neighbor random points in
the middle. Okay. So and those new
points you created those are actually
the
the this this
looney mesh points. Okay. So they are
dual. So but given I mean given a random
random list of points how do you find
the other points that's not trivial
because then
for each point you have kind of check
all the other points you know then you
compute their distance like you compare
you compute their distance divided by
half then you compare you compute the
vector so you get the the midpoint
between them then you so this is a huge
amount of computation.
So what is efficient algorithm? I so I
never actually thought about it. I got a
book like 30 years ago but I never
actually read. Uh so
so I'm going to you know today I'm going
to you know today this week next week
I'm going to start to like look into
these algorithms how they do it. Um very
interesting and and very beautiful.
Okay. So, so you see the dual graph of
veronoi diagram blah blah blah blah
corresponds to the the lun triangulation
form for the same set of points. So it
mentioned there so you can see their
relationship.
Okay. Bye.
Oh, but you know besides studying this,
so there's a lot a lot more because this
because because of Wuam language you can
you can see I started I already spent
like
you know several days to read so to read
about this whole mesh thing you know why
is it called mesh then then many of
these for example this can mesh we
showed they are mathematical ideas in
topology ology. So you want to so so
then you stop computer graphics stop
programming you go into mathematics
which is pure mathematics then you learn
about you know about this you know for
example I don't exactly know why is
caner dust created in the first place
you know I know it's related to study
um like the the density of the space or
something like point set topology G uh
oh yeah yeah so density so Caner
mentioned this tonary construction
only passing only in passing as an
example of a perfect set that is nowhere
dense okay so so this this can dust
thing
you know in in the case they are talking
about that's a one-dimensional version
okay so just one-dimensional so line
segment so this this that is such that
it's no way a dense.
So that's pure ma pure mathematics. Very
interesting.
Okay. So yeah. So you know so this these
kind of things the wuam language you
know when you study them they they
there's like huge amount of things you
uh you can study. And also another thing
interesting we talked about is that you
see how exactly do they mesh do they
merge the concept of mathematics the
concept of computer graphics such as
computational geometry such such as this
the looney mesh Veroni mesh convex hole
you know they merge with mathematics and
then um like did they do it right you
know like how do to look at all these
topics in a in a kind of unified hole.
So that's what I've been uh been doing.
Bye.