check okay so my audio is off again what
a idiot oh my god I should have I should
have double-checked
so today's captain's log September
eighteenth 2019 Wednesday two o'clock
p.m. San Francisco time hello guys
good morning Kat 44 good morning
climate crime and 99 or did I pronounce
it correctly so what is the topic today
so if you guys you know ask me questions
or pick a topic you know from the from
from from the list here so I was talking
about you know what we did yesterday we
talked about Jaron Lanier
a very interesting guy kind of like
Richard Stallman ish but they have
slightly different ideas we talked about
that yesterday and no donation to
Wikipedia and no you Millennials
you know the younger generation since
about late I will say late 2000s you
know late 2000 like truth out study
let's say starting from 2005 that's when
you know we're talking about the history
of a culture so for you his historians
out there you know you better you better
listen closely Lockleys okay so around
2005 or later this is when Kimmy Kimmy
start you know gaming culture you began
to have lots of gamers and this is also
when you start to have gaming
competitions like like the cameras you
know Jemma typically looks idiotic you
know they are nerds they look ugly they
are ting you know 15 you know teenagers
and they kind of idiotic okay they are
good at nothing you know but they just
fair games all day but now since about
2005 now they have a career they have
they become professional gamer you have
all these scheming competitions you win
if you are a champion you win million
dollars you know so you know you you
have these gamers you know
and and other and it's a industry you
know it's not easy
he became a industry you have cameras
you have teams corporate sponsors you
have game shows you know and billions
people watch around the world and many
of them are Korean or other countries
you know they especially Korean they you
know they are very you know they they
play that a lot of people play games you
know all day so - good morning or - good
morning - Chile talk about ten goal and
write a script in validate okay let's do
that okay so let me let me take two more
minutes to finish about the gaming stuff
so gaming culture starts around 2000
after 2005 then you also start to have
the cosplay culture now Kosrae is kind
of related to gaming and also related to
Japanese comics because Kosrae you know
and and and lots of girls okay this is
also the beginning where girls women
they got involved
actually the yeah that is true but they
are no you know women began to get
involved in lots of things like like for
example today we have a large female
programmers hello castle long time no
see
must massage how do you pronounce the
your name my god that's polish name I
suppose massage you know I I don't know
but I just I you know the from the look
of it I would say much mass ma she
watched always I don't know how to even
ask your name
so anyway so let's get on let's start to
talk about that goal and stuff : and
Emacs validate bracket so let's let's
try let me show you the Emacs version
first racket
seek a change bracket pairs so what we
want to do is we want to have a command
that validate brackets but first of all
I need to show you that commands and you
know I'm going to demonstrate that then
then maybe we'll do a goal and you know
I you know that that would be a okay so
let's so let's go to my Emacs init file
go to the directory and search for
search for bracket search for validate
okay none okay then search again for
validate match what
oh we went to such eld affair files not
dot HTML so such again validate reddit
it doesn't automatically pop up let me
let me let's do this again so you are
right polish I'm working and working
with engineers for many countries and
could hear ten thousand versions of my
name so tuna okay Marcy okay so for now
I just say mushy must must must see okay
so it's such for valid okay it's such in
this directory in oal files okay and
that's such for bracket so minor mod for
highlighting matching brackets or well
validate them okay so that's actually
sub right bracket mod that's not public
yet
I wrote that a while ago so I'm trying
to find my Emacs command I have a
command that validate brackets so okay
that's let's do it again
so that's such again let's call repeat
complex command it's such full match
then you get all stream match okay
that's too many that's not good okay so
let's go to the directory and it's just
let's go to miscellaneous so hold on a
second magnify
okay so such for miscellaneous so I have
this miscellaneous file that contains
all miscellaneous commands and least
matching lines lists or different okay
then search for validate okay
search for bracket okay it's not there
we can we can find it because last time
so go back to the directory let's see a
brief ok let's try this
a brief alias Adam is a sprog utility
tired commands not tired commands fire
association not that font Google Earth
Google Emacs HTML this is all HTML
related commands now let's lease
matching lines defend ok and let's see
in update syntax color hex Python ref
linker Phi YouTube insert date copy
remove Wikipedia links ok not here
back to diet link of Phi innate key
binding key binding key binding key mark
well miscellaneous mouse commands math
commands Microsoft Windows reference
link of I replace quotes no settings
were the southside movie image and
listening matching lines least non
matching lines ok add ok so maybe it's
some bracket mod now I don't think it's
here this is a bracket mod I started
these few years ago but I actually I
think it works but this is not what we
want it this one is written in 2013
yeah about five years ago
I want to I need to find the Emax
validate bracket command so that I can
show a demo what do I mean by that and
but now we are having problem finding
that command missing your smoke well
fire association let's just just try MX
okay first of all saw start command log
mod okay so oh my MX command is going to
show on the left window
okay so mouseka met where's my validate
brackets commence croissant corner
bracket to HTML mod overlay Emacs
overlay and chopped-up ities Emacs
syntax pause its search for bracket
again bracket such such in Oriel files
so you can all break it bracket move
bracket bracket minor mod for minam are
to highlight matching bracket no bracket
or quote by syntax table no Emacs brief
no Emacs key bindings no parentheses
quote I think that is it Oh God
I named this SAR check / impact balance
okay let's go there open open
okay here is the function now to region
okay so here is the function that's 60
lines
Sarek parentheses balance I don't like
that term you know I you know I know you
know I used to name this as okay there's
a Emacs there's a page on my website so
if you search this page sorry
Emacs check parentheses balance you will
find the code here and you can use it so
let me just show you how to use it first
of all but hold on before we do that
let's open any comments opinions
questions interesting things just post
it okay I like that so let's go to this
our talk show
santosh chokes on top show today today's
state had a today state saw new page
create a new HTML page make it Li cut it
put it here okay
then go to the page go to the page
showing browser back to Emacs paste
paste again paste previous okay make a
make a list
okay that is you know a log of today's
topic so we talked about that page and
so I'm going to right now I'm going to
demonstrate this command no yes
so close that close that close that okay
so actually close that back to talk show
open that and this is the command okay
and what does that mean for example I'm
just going to call it actually describe
function let's see the let's see the
function documentation so describe
function the name and so it says check
if there are unbalanced parentheses
bracket quotes in current buffer or
selection okay if so place cursor there
green arrow to message before okay that
is what it does so let's call it so meta
X check for imbalance enter it says o
brackets quotes match you see you see
that mini buffer head but but at the
bottom so that's fantastic
not so so this page is all valid but
let's try for example now I start a
parenthesis it's let's call the command
again oh so then the now says mismatch
found the char that has no matching pair
okay let's open a new buffer let's
switch it to message buffer okay message
is perfect
so every message is Emacs lock them to
the message buffer so you know if
there's some message in the mini buffer
you it will go away after a while after
after you do something else but you can
always see them in the message buffer
the message before is named you know
star messages star asterisk so it says
let's see what does it say oh oh oh
there mismatch found the cha 4209 one
has no matching pair now forty is let's
see what is forty I forgot
so let's call it again let's put the
cursor here let's call it again okay
same arrow
so the cha 42 zero and I want it doesn't
it should move the cursor tool to to the
mismatch face but it's not doing that I
haven't used this command for a long
time but so let's go to let's go to the
source code describe cha go to the
source code and let's look at the file
so the last time I added tit is 2018
okay last year so you check these
brackets first of all let's find out
what are the area what does the arrow
mean so this needs improvement because
it you know the documentation does not
explain what are the 40 and end stuff
but actually and I kind of know what it
what they mean for example he says it
says 40 mm 91 has no matching pair so if
act we can do what we can do now is go
to code a command go to cha okay
then type 40
okay that's not right it's not that
so let's go go to cha again type type
tou0 or 91 there it is so you see so 2 0
91 the second number is the position
where the error occurs but for example
let's let's just complete it for now so
so now we have a good racket pair now
let's call the command again
check check pair imbalance good whole
thing's match and now now let me show
you a different parent let's say you see
this is curry Kuo
you see we can put it inside actually we
can do a lot quotes let me show you okay
so we have all kind of quotes oops okay
now we don't want that okay we have
several kind of quotes okay let's call
the command again cuz I'll check param
balance he's so good
Oh match but now if we say for example
if we move this one to there then we got
a problem you see you see this you see
we got a problem
so now let's call the command such
aquarium balance all quotes match that's
a mistake
so let's go back to the code what's
going on
oh this is this is embarrassing but why
is it okay I know what's going on
because it's actually not you see we got
a total racket here so let me show you
so this bracket here if you could
describe cha you can see the name is
opening Toto is shell bracket in that
bracket okay now close that that bracket
is actually not one of the bracket we
are checking so let's add it you know
this is the power of Emacs let's just
add it add that bracket okay let's hold
on a second so we want to select this
line narrow to region and replace any of
that by that okay now we want to make it
like that so widen so now you see so now
it's small clear so you see we do we
have the turtle Toto is bracket no we
don't have the total is package so let's
add it copy the line paste it here and
modify it so we got a turtle is bracket
yeah
magnify so you see not that the turtles
bracket is here now we even change the
date version date and now avow function
oh it cannot evolve
it you know here here's a bug in Emacs
you see you have the you have the
function let me show you what's a
function the function is called avout
the fun okay that's the name you see
Avada fun so what this function does is
that when you call that it will evaluate
the current function your crews are
using so my cursor is inside the
function I call the function it should
evaluate this from
but right now if we do it if we do it I
call the shortcode okay look at the left
left window you'll see the command now I
call avati fun you see you see here
Avada fun but actually a mask it gives
me a error because it gives me a some
kind of passing arrow okay why this is a
bug in emag list this is very annoying
because I've talked to the you know many
many Emacs fanatics they don't be they
don't believe it anyway so let me
explain okay so this is a bug this when
your emag list code is not wear
formatted what do you mean like where
formatter like that when they are not
well formatted I mean not that's not the
right word when they are not yeah the
line formatting yeah the line formatting
is not well formatted such as for
example like that okay then that without
the phone function will break you will
not walk for example let's try it again
let's try it again okay call it oh no it
works wait no it's no actually it
evaluated saw you are our file path you
see the mini buffer at the bottom so now
it actually evaluated the next function
in a up even you know Emacs
up like so so you know I mean
Emacs for 20 years so I know a lot of
people meaning our friends and even
friends you know some I know you know
some friends will say Oh George always
use even if an avowed defend and they
always say oh use parent you know par
edit you know which is a which is a
package that helps you format your IDs
those are all garbage it is because
those that you have this bug and they
don't know the the reason they don't
know about this bug is because they are
so used to they are
so used to prettyprint the Emacs Lisp
code like using PI edit or using other
means
you know this basically what they do is
that they manually format emag based
code all the time like every life like
many many packages when you press ENTER
you'll try to format that that line
so in essence they are actually manually
formatting every single line with the
help of the editor you know something
for example in Python you see you know
you press you know right now I'm using
saw eel emag be smart when I press tab
it it it pretty print it formats the
entire function okay so that's why you
see when I have several places that's
not correctly formatted but I can press
ENTER a formats the whole function this
is what you want now if I switch to
let's undo if I switch to let's undo
okay did I make a mistake here somewhere
let's undo and do and do and do okay so
if I switch to let's switch to Emacs Lee
smart okay this is the default Emacs mod
okay now if I press ENTER nothing
happens now I have to move here press
ENTER that's how you format you know
basically each line and you see now I
press ENTER a formula that lie what if
my cursor is here I press ENTER it
doesn't work because the formatting is
based on previous line so it's you know
this is true for almost every major body
in Emacs
when you format it is based on the
previous line you know so so when you
press ENTER nothing happens but if you
your cursor is here then you press ENTER
then that works so in order to fix this
you have to call you have to call it's
very complicated there's there are many
commands for example there is a command
called indentation intend for tab
command
you have to select it okay let's try it
okay now it works you see it's no good
okay so what you want is okay what you
want is for example close this reopen
magnify now we are inside this mod sorry
Lee smart so what do you want is pre
press one single button right now see it
formats the whole thing so now it's
formatted now let's try to run the avada
fun okay now we run it it worked you see
the mini profile says subject for
imbalance it means this function is now
evaluated okay so now now let's go back
to the to the to to this page remember
we have a mismatched friend here now
let's try to let's now let's call start
check for imbalance there it is mismatch
found you see you see this error here is
here is the error let's magnify this
okay so mismatch found the cha the cha
that okay now I understand the message
so it gives a bunch of pairs the first
pair I mean the first number is the
Unicode number for the character I think
yeah anyway so now know it's got a
problem you see now it actually found a
mismatch parent now let's fix it okay
let's fix it cut that and put it back
here okay now let's call it save it code
up function enter now a bracket match
that's good okay now so that is the that
is a demo that is what we want to do so
I want to write a version or similar
version in :
I'm not sure I can do it in half an hour
but I we we could we could try
so let me check out the comments so
Tigers also helps us also meow says
factoring use indentation this person's
friend if everyone is pretty printing
already there's no more point for
brackets felt some mini Karen what is
meaning Karen yeah I don't know what is
mini Karen so okay we know let's let's
write that in go lines so let's see how
long I've been talking and let's see
let's do this quickly see if I can make
it so okay 20 minutes now let's see what
we have in another 20 minutes so first
of all go to let's copy this okay
create a new buffer paste it save it
xxxx
today's date yeah because we need to
reference this code now actually let's
do this cut make a Elise code here color
Phi T that showing browser that's good
we have the code here now
d-dad buffer now now let's go to : okay
goal and so here is my goal and tutorial
we we all need to reference this
frequency because I haven't caught coded
: for like a month
so we have : and now let's create let's
start to code : yes
what we do is we create a new buffer
save it okay I want to say what's this
name okay let me show you go to tired
copy the file name now switch to to this
buffer save it paste the file name and
and endian go okay so now we got the new
name now close that so go line now go
okay now let's begin that's the here's a
template for : every basically every
goal and file will be like this we have
this template package main import format
and function main that's yo is needed us
every goal and file need the package man
and every goal and fire every package
every goal and package needs a main
function a function named me okay
by the way let me mention this quickly
so I have a goal and tutorial so if you
never program : before this is a good
Chidori okay check out you know support
me check out my tutorial and share it
with friends
I love : : is my favorite industrial
programming language so I spend a lot of
time you know I because I love it so if
this is like this is one of my good
tutorials for good for beginners at
least I there are some topics I did not
cover for example some of the topics the
dramatic topics that gets nerds excited
is co-routine that is for parallel
programming co-routine and also
interface co interface which which is
more less about Opie yeah so goal
routing I did not cover go interface I
did not cover and that that's basically
the two major parts I did not cover okay
you know some people read my tutorial
and then then they complain you know
those are actually advanced you know for
beginners my is good you know good for
you know for for the first three months
at least
codeine Golan so much message says I
have a question have you had a chance to
test key Mouse device yes know you
mentioned this device in your webpage
yeah I have not I have never tested I
have never tried that
Chema's so attach everything so so far
so good
the the speed of tutorial is so far so
good I want to focus on a goal and oh so
so so but let me quickly mention the key
Mouse
so you go to casali keyboard block and
key Mouse is in the yeah cool cool
attached so key mouse is in the
do-it-yourself section key Mouse this is
the device okay so this device someone
sells it actually it's a kind of a small
company that sells it so this is a mouse
and keyboard combined now they have a
trackball on the keyboard so and also
that I think the keyboard right that I
think the keyboard also functions the
mouse there's a video here yeah if you
go to my website okay so let me show you
so let's see Paisley is link get the
link and go to the chrome of a new
buffer new new tab go there so key Mouse
device this is my keyboard website so
there are few videos you can watch and
there are you know this guy this stupid
guy Venus he you know he he he did a
review of that and this guy also did a
review but anyway the point so this
whole thing can walk that Mouse like you
move the whole keyboard and also it has
a trackball it's kind of its kind of
like
it's kind of do it yourself but it's
made by a company you can buy it's
expensive like how much was it $300 or
something or more and my so I have never
tried it I have never seen it I mean
I've never touched it but but based on
my impression I I'm not too I do not
think this is that good okay I mean it's
better than normal keyboards but I
rather prefer you know just you know I
just prefer my you know the the
so-called typical kind of you know my
Kinesis or go dogs or a bunch of others
so I think because because because I
think the keymod is kind of too
cumbersome I mean you got a when you
when you want to move the mouse you got
a drag you have to drag the whole thing
you know it's kind you know I prefer
things that are mobile and small this is
kind of too too too big to come crunky
okay so copy that close it back to Emacs
back to Emacs okay link of ISO okay
that's about chemos so much it says I've
been using this device for eight months
now okay that's great
took me about one month to beam a bit to
make make two to make it a maxi for
Emacs I can give you more user
experience details if you are interested
oh yeah say okay by all means to do I
love these kind of comments because
there's actual information you know
since you're you actually have used it
you know yeah so do you have a blog I
suppose not I mean if you have a blog
posted okay otherwise just type it well
but let me go back to the colon because
we need to finish that that they'll take
some time let's go back to : we can talk
about the key mouse you know another day
in more detail so let's go back to Golan
and we want to write we want to write
the command that that validate brackets
so let's make it simple so all the
brackets we we want to check is let's
just say two of them so paren and that
perennial square bracket okay so this is
all the brackets we want to check we
ignore or the other kind of bracket so
you know I haven't looked at this code
for a while so I actually had should
have done some kind of preparation
because first of all you need to know
the what what is the algorithm to use
yeah so but let's just move along let's
try what we can do so first of all you
need an algorithm so what algorithm to
to do this task so basically so yeah so
you got a buffer basically you got a
bunch of text you got a big string you
want to go through every string from the
beginning okay so then wherever you see
a bracket so for example when so for our
purposes we are going to check these
four characters square brackets and
parentheses so whenever you see any of
those characters okay you you push that
character to a stack okay then you keep
going then when you see another
character you push it to a stack okay
now every time you push to a stack you
check you check if if the current stack
matches the previous stack I mean if
they are a pair if so you remove those
too you know you remove those too so
that's what you do right so you go
through the text file go to go through
the huge text big string from in the
beginning every time you see a
bracket you push to a stack whenever you
push the stack you check you check if
that bracket if the the previous stack
matches it if it does then you remove
both okay then you continue okay and yes
until you reach the end of buffer that's
done now once you reach to the end of
buffer you look at the stacks if the
stack is empty everything is good if
it's not empty then you have mismatched
brackets okay does that make sense so
that's what we that's that's algorithm
okay so so let's look at my did I do
explanation here no I didn't do
explanation here so actually yeah so
that's about it actually I have a
website I have an essay talking about
that let's look that sorry
check brackets
okay so actually I have an essay so this
is actually almost this is 2011
so Lisp Python Perl Ruby code to
validate matching brackets so I posted
this as a programming problem so you
know I encourage people to to submit
their solutions so my solution is for
Emacs you know I wrote this in 2011 and
and this can can be applied to all files
in the directory so it can can work
hundreds of files and then someone have
provided oh this is me actually
wait wait some someone this guy Raymond
Hettinger he's provided a Python 3
solution ok so I'm glad we look at this
because now we can we can just trust
translate this Python code to Golan and
actually there are several other
solutions there are three more Python
solutions there are two to ruby
solutions let's look at them it's there
are two ruby solutions when I try to
open it the browser start to launch some
other editor I guess I don't know so
let's look at the let's look at it so
here's a file let's open it locally
showing browser so they are Python
versions ruby versions there are
perversions there's this one power
version okay there it is
there is this Perl version there is this
ruby version
oh this ruby version is very short now I
have not verified them so sometimes they
are wrong you know like when you post a
problem to the programming forum you got
a lot answers but many of them are just
wrong or very bad quality so this Ruby
code is
very short it's only like 15 lines but
ice I haven't checked I don't know if
it's you know it works well I can be
sure that my email is called work well
okay my my eMac beast version so anyway
and there's even a a common dispersion
so here's a common dist version so
anyway we're gonna do it in :
so okay so then it's it's okay so let's
do it
this is going to actually be a
exploration and you are exploring with
me okay so where do we begin so so first
of all you need to read the file so
let's write out right write down what we
need to do so open a file given a file
path you need to open the file read the
file as a string okay anyway so attach a
youth you already know some : or are you
completely new because if you are
completely new then this might be useful
I mean I suppose it may be maybe you
already know some : but probably you are
not expert yet but yeah I mean if you
are expert then this you are wasting
time here but if you are you know :
beginner you know you you might you know
we could learn how to read the file and
things like that I'm not sure I can
finish it today because I haven't coded
: for a month for two months so we need
to okay open the file read the file as a
string then go through the string
whenever a bracket is
encountered push it to a stack when
pushing to stack also check if previous
how do you say so we have a stack which
is a data structure but how do you say
each level I mean to you let's just go a
level check if previous level match
matches the current level if so remove
both okay then continue to go through
the string till end of string okay then
now if stack has nothing or is good no
mismatched brackets
if stack has something then we have
mismatched packet okay
let's just do it very simply so first of
all open the file so let's read some
comments
good morning Kathy great to see you join
in hello to London so message have say
module says in short you have right-hand
mouse if you if if quite heavy ok quite
heavy yeah that's a issue I'm thinking
so but if you can get used to okay
typing performance is for the for me
similar as for Canisius great I'm happy
to share more details data yeah yeah
yeah even you know either feel free to
type type type it because I'm sure a lot
of people watching my videos are
interested in that and also yeah that's
a great great feedback and also you use
Kinesis that's great yeah but it it it
being too heavy is a issue yeah I don't
like Mouse to have you at all in fact
even the Gaming Mouse is too heavy any
wireless mouse with batteries is too
heavy I mean it's not ideal
I like the mouse to be as light as
possible you know so I can actually just
nudge it yeah so I so I I don't think I
like the the key Mouse so anyway maokai
says mini quran' is a proof sabha based
on scheme implemented using Petrie's oh
that's interesting
mini korean let's let's see such tuk-tuk
go for mini korean
okay mini Korean Wikipedia let's see
what it says mini Korean is a family of
programming languages for relational
programming Oh relational that's a fancy
word I actually don't know what that is
relational logic for grabbing why
they say relational I know what logic
programming is but they could they say
relational for me anyway
it's a minicar a means of priming
language poimen language is a family of
programming languages Oh a family for
relational programming as relations are
bi-directional if mini Korean is given
an expression and a desired output
meaning Korean can run the expression
backward finding all possible inputs to
the expression that produce the desired
output okay so I think as so I I think
this is a logic you know in a category
of logic programming or constraint
programming and it's good for I suppose
this is this language is good for back
backtracking algorithms and so on and by
the way yesterday I was you know
yesterday I was reading about goose and
goose has this thing called algorithm X
actually we should go back to focus on
the wait where did my
where did my chat box go did I just
close it
okay so back back in here so myths
now I'm not using Evo guys Louise I'm
not using Evo I'm using soft like keys
okay hold on they mean we finish the
comments and let's go yeah we should
actually focus on the Golan because I'm
not sure I can actually finish it but
let me finish the comments so anyway
there there is mini current okay mini
Corinne so that's interesting
thanks mail oh god I need to magnify the
text you when you get when you are 50
you cannot read mini Corinne
okay the author wins a show like you on
YouTube he's really nice
oh okay so well I didn't know so much
each says moving hand back and forth was
was issue for me for years
okay let's go back to let's go back to
goal and focus so first so we have the
our line of algorithm first of all we
need to open fire how do you do that
I don't remember so I haven't got you
know I haven't coded go line for a month
Oh - two months actually so open the
file I have a tutorial here so just go
here attach okay so so go here and open
a file there is read file that's what we
want so read whole file read first X
bytes so we want to read whole file so
here's what we do
we just copy and paste copy paste copy
and paste is the most powerful paradigm
in programming and you need also the IO
uto package so so there it is
io uto package and read the whole file
yes now before we now before we read the
fire we need a fire path so let's define
file path okay and what file path okay
so let's open a new buffer save this as
X X date
xx date bracket dot text okay
let's save this file as that by that
name okay so here's the file and let's
give it some paren so we can gonna check
this file and I know I'm gonna go you
know a bunch bunch of brackets and
arrange so you know just some random
file we're gonna check this is our input
file copy the file path copy the file
path paste the file path here that's
what we want
yes fire path we have that then go read
file so the the the way you read file is
this okay
io u T or read file and it returns the
text so this is a function returns two
things the first thing is a text of the
file a string and the second thing is
arrow okay and then you check arrow okay
then you print text okay so so far so
good now we can actually run this file
so run this file good you know it it
read the file you see it reads the file
and it just printed here so now it
actually just print betweens the file
content that's good so so far so good
and let's see
okay goal and this function actually
returns a it returns a a slice of bytes
yeah it actually returns a slice of
bytes so that's why you need to convert
it to stream
so let me mention you know let me
mention you know in : you have this is
you have a string string is actually a
sequence of bytes so you : for example
we have a let's say go phone manner
let's go go phone man okay format the
code you see you see this line is not
intended so let's go go format to format
the whole code you know go go : has this
great solution about formatting code
which I actually agree let's see for
example let's destroy the format now
let's say let's destroy the format and
you know let's make it almost like
random you know let's see you see so
this is not formatted now I just go go
format it whom has the whole file or
supposed to typically in Emacs in Python
in Perl
in this you know this idiocy the
programmers they format line by line
you know they well you do have a to that
format at the whole but that's kind of
not normal I mean that's normally you
just format lamb lamb bell line by line
that's not the case in colon colon has
to has this tool called go from go
format building for example let's undo
let's go to tired this is the file copy
the file name copy it or copy the file
name go to issue there is a format
called Co that that is a net go format
okay then you just type the file name
enter o then then it outputs okay so you
need to format it in place I forgot what
you need to format it you see it output
the formatted code so okay so go format
help
so if you want to okay so you need to
say - W that will format the code in
place so let's switch back each oh
that's so look at the bottom buffer here
magnify okay go format go format we need
to give a - W okay
enter you see you see this buffer it's
all formatted
okay so close that so that's about go
format no I of course I have a Emacs
command that caused that so I don't
actually go to Asia oh oh I do is I just
press CC control C control C and you can
see I'm calling go format and you're
just format the buffer so go format we
chose so now we have read the file and
into a string now we want to go through
the string one character by one
character so we are we are going through
the bite slice okay
so comments questions post okay bite
size so we want to go through the bite
size because this my text is a pie slice
so how do you go through a pie slice
I don't remember let's look into pie
slice here now slice is just like a ray
in goal and slices just like a ray
accept that array you cannot change the
length but slice is this is basically
your wrapper on top of array and you can
change the length in fact it
automatically increases the length
wherever you add more elements okay so
if I'm going to I guess if if I'm going
too slow just say ok but I guess most
people don't know this I'll just assume
you guys are new to
okay I mean otherwise you know keep
typing comments so I know
so in : you have a slice slice is like a
ray
it's a wrapper to array it it it had it
can change length so right now this this
my text is a size we want to go through
it so how do you do that
let's see syntax of size little
expression of size print size print size
by line by line creates ice with make
length capacity slice of slice nested
isopentyl size cut slice copy size
criticize nested size loop through slice
this is what we want copy it this is
what happens if you forgot you know if
you have haven't been code in the
language for a while so okay so here's
what we do we go through I 4i v equals
through range size weight so what does I
mean loop through size where I is the
current index and V is the value okay I
so current index so we do want the index
and we do want the value okay first of
all first of all there's one thing we
need to do before we go through we loop
through it because now my string my text
now this i/o uto
read file function returns a it returns
a slice of bytes okay so this my text
the type of my text is actually a slice
and each element is a byte not character
this is important not character but a
bite this is important because if you're
if your stream I mean if your file
contains a character that's not a ski
for example emoji or
you know Chinese rackets those are not
back you know if you contain any non
ASCII characters then each of those
characters are actually two or more
bytes for example if you have an emoji
that's actually two or three bytes you
know if you have a Chinese bracket such
as such as for example the total is
bracket here or the corner bracket like
that you know that character is actually
2 bytes two or three bytes know for you
know to do 4 bytes so but for any ASCII
character ASCII character is basically
all the characters you can type on a
keyboard
so for ASCII characters each character
is one byte for example F is 1 byte is 1
by 2 L is 1 byte ok so what what is my
point so my point is this bit file this
3 file function it its return value the
type of the return value is a slice of
bytes you know bites not character so so
what that means is that whenever you
have an emoji it will become 2 elements
you know it will become 2 fights you
know and that's not not what you want
because because because then because
then you have if when you have a Chinese
bracket it becomes 2 bytes you cannot
check you know because we are checking
the brackets so we want the character
not bytes so how do you do this how do
you solve this because so so my text is
a slice of bytes and if we go through
the slice of bytes that doesn't work
because each element is a byte we want
that we want the actual character so we
we start to get into many tedious
details of you know of doing this task
you know it looks simple you know you
look simple by this
on line but actually when you actually
code there are a lot of details so so
right now we have this problem this is a
slice of bytes we wanted to be there are
several ways to solve it so one way I
mean the simplest way conceptually
simplest is to convert the whole thing
to slice of unicode characters in golden
it's called run you know you know so we
want to convert it from slice of bytes
to slice of run that's one way to solve
it let's just do that
you know let's this straight you know
let's just try to get a prototype going
instead of you know bogging down with
all the details yeah so so we want to
convert this slice of bytes to slice of
run am i doing good
let's see
okay I'm not sure we can finish this so
let me show you i oh okay I owe you to
read file so I owe you to your file so
here is the goal and documentation and
actually let's go to Chrome so we have
JavaScript okay and let's magnify this
magnify and we want there is the beat
file that's a function we are calling
and you can see it you know Cola and
here's the : documentation so it says
read file is a function and it tells you
what's the input type the input is a
string which is a file path the output
here's output it returned two values the
first one you know the square bracket
byte that means it's a byte slice a
slice of bytes oh you know so it's like
a ray of each element is about the
second return value is ever so so we
verified that slice of bytes now we want
we need to convert it to slice of run so
what what does I mean name in explain
okay actually let me just do it because
every time then I try to explain let me
just try to do it run so we need to look
into run so here is run now run is :
invented the term run its colons jargon
what it basically what it means is just
a code point in unicode basically just
means a character okay purpose okay so
we so we want to convert it to run yeah
let's do it
so how do you do that actually I have a
article about that
now this article this is actually very
important this article if you are new to
go and read this article okay : string
by size run size because again : string
is a sequence of bytes now if you have a
sequence of bytes what's the difference
between string and by size
I mean bytes slice is also a sequence of
bytes why do you have you know both well
the thing with string is that string is
a sequence of bytes remember bytes not
characters bytes so string is a sequence
of a bytes but however string in golden
is immutable
that means string cannot be changed if
any time you change your string colon
has basically creates a new string and
we can discard the old one so so that is
very expensive because especially when
strains law like a file so string string
datatype is not mutable so if you want
to change your character in in a string
or if you want to do find replace then
the string data type is not not good
you want to use space size instead so by
slice is kind of like array array of
bytes and you can change any element you
know so so that is why you have the
string datatype then you also have the
page size little datatype depending on
whether you want to change them okay if
you don't want to change them then
strange good now you also have run slice
so like I said run is run just means
character so so one slice is just as
like a array of characters an array but
each element is a character not bite a
character may be more than one bite okay
so so so what we want here is a run
slice so we want to change a page slice
to run size
let's see how to do that by size two
string string to run slice one slice to
string by size to run size
yeah here's what I want to do by size to
run size so here's a code let me show
you what that means so first of all
create a new variable my choice okay
that's characters sequence of characters
char slice
okay slice let's just say char slice
okay
character slice and it's equal to these
okay so first of all we convert the page
slice to string then we convert it to
run size this is how you convert forced
conversion things in goal add basically
what you do is you you type I mean you
you type the type the type name in front
as a function then you just call it so
this is what you want to change and here
is the type you want to result in so
strange the type so you just say string
that that returns a string now you feed
that to to to this function
so because run you know this square
bracket run that that is the syntax to
represent one size so when you do that
then you put a parenthesis parenthesis
behind that becomes a function that just
converted to run size so that's how we
do it
okay so format it and we can actually
print it okay so let's let's print it
okay so print it here and run it oh okay
so now you see it works but however it
prints this it prints this I believe
those are Unicode code point for each
character for example let's go back to
the input character I mean let's go back
to the input file so I know a is 97 or
96 okay so let's run it again oh yeah a
is 65 that's right
so let's small a is 97 or 96 so let's
run a run it again oh there it is 65
what happened to the big a so wait
so let's go describe cha so capital a is
65 there it is capital a is 65 small a
is 97 there right so 65 so you see that
this is correct 6532 e space 97 is the
small a you see they so we are printing
each character let's put an emoji okay
cat face
okay so let's so let's put an emoji so
so let's go describe cha so this this
character is named grinning cat face
with smiling eyes and the Unicode code
point is here it's 128 568 one two eight
five six eight okay and now save it now
let's run the : code again let's run it
there it is one two eight five six eight
that's correct but actually fold for now
we we want to print it as a string not
not a size so let's convert it back
string run it okay now that's good so
now we actually got a slice now the next
thing we want to do we want to go
through the slice okay
go through the slice so so I is the
index we this is a char and let's say
range slice
yeah that's how you do it so the code is
gonna be here okay so here is how you go
through a slice so here's our slice and
I is the index choice the actual
character so for example let's remove
the print here let's print here print i
n print cha okay let's just say C let's
say Xin chào okay we want to print okay
let's run it good okay so so we got
index and we got the character in your
in Unicode in fact actually this is
actually let's do it this way yeah yeah
yeah there it is
so we are printing the index and we are
printing a character so 0 1 2 that's
correct okay so we we are going through
the size the next then then we want to
check if cha equals to if cha equals to
if cha equals through any of our
premiere characters any of those okay
that's more code okay so how am i doing
attached guys oh my god we are I'm stuck
okay let me just finish it then let's
just go slow however let's just finish
it so we need a list of characters but
how do we need to do it how do we do it
I mean the easiest way is to specify
brackets or brackets okay one of the
easiest way is simply just to make it a
string but but this is not we want we
actually want we want it to be a slice
okay so we want to be a slice of runs
okay so actually we need to convert
these two slice so let's do that
okay something like that right this is
easy way to write it hole brackets so
here we have basically we have a slice
of four elements you can see the length
is four let's run it
length is six that's not right
let's remove this print statement
okay let's comment this out for now
why is this not printed let's run it
chastise declared and not used chastise
declare not used voice is not printing
so slice let's go back to slice
so we want to find the length of size
yeah Lane Lane is right but why is it
not
it's land not links
oh yeah it's refusing to run because
it's refusing to run because I've been
using those variables and I'm not using
them okay so let's do this again : is
very annoying because of these Oh now
finally so it's correct
it says length is four yeah so what is
trouble
okay now we are back here Janet I owe
you tea Oh Janet
Oh bracket declare not used copy yet so
so we are going through the file and we
are checking if the character for each
character we want to check if if it
matches one of the brackets so we need
to do a loop again
yeah so we need to do a loop so for
range okay that's a loop and for range
of brackets okay okay you for all
brackets
check if check if the character equals
to
equals two Wow
okay and if so
print I and
train kusa position and print
cha okay
okay like that so we go through the file
each character then for each character
we also go through all brackets to see
that character that character matches
one of the bracket character if so let's
just print it okay
comment this out let's run it key
declare they're not used this is one of
the very annoying things about : because
every time you declare something you do
not use it : will refuse to compile very
annoying this is annoying because when
you are doing debugging or prototype
sometimes you want to comment lots of
things out just to experiment but then
go long we all complain you know you
didn't use those whatever packages or
variables you declared so you have to
comment all of them out this is very
this is a major problem let's run it
okay now it runs so actually we did file
this is good so you see we let's train
again again it's not ok so we here as a
result this is good so it found several
brackets the found a bracket could you
know found the parentheses at kusa
position seven found a square bracket
includes a position ten okay yeah so
this lets see describe char
who's the position eight correct because
in Emacs the kusa position counting
start at one so the first character is
one but in : we are dealing with slice
you know slice of characters so i start
at
zero that is why you know in Emacs Emacs
says this character is kusa position
eight here but in : it says it is seven
you know it off by one
maybe there's a yeah okay so anyway so
let me just finish this so is is it okay
at attach and attach and Kathy so far so
good
are you guys still watching let me just
finish it then you know say it say so
you know good or something you know so I
you know that's better for me so let me
finish so okay so far so good we are
making a Qui you know this is actually
normal
I mean you know if I'm coding myself
this is about the right speed because I
haven't been coding : for the past 2
month and we are actually indeed making
progress so we went through so we
succeed in going through each character
in the you know in a file and we are
able to match you know whenever we see a
bracket we know so now instead of print
we will actually need to push it into a
stack ok so next thing to do is we need
to create a stack data type so to create
a stack data type
let's save our stack okay let's just say
stack okay so what here is another
decision to make what data structure of
Golan to use to implement a stack data
structure of computer science okay so
for that question for Golan pretty much
you use least Golan doesn't really have
something called at least but rather is
just
slice so let me double check yes slice
right so you want to create a slice so
so stack we are beginning as a empty
size okay so let's review slice here
let's use make to create a slice there
here's the syntax here it is let's print
it let's put it here begin 0 okay
capacity let's say 300
okay now capacities for optimization
purposes because you know it tells :
what is the potential number of items in
a slice why do you need to tell :
because so it can reserve enough memory
you know it mostly it's for the purpose
of speed because you don't really need
it because every time when you have more
elements when you add another element to
the sights : will automatically you know
increase it you you know but however to
implement that : has to every time you
know when there is more number of items
it needs to create a new kind of memory
management like create a new you know
space memory space for it and it's that
that is slow so if you just tell it
directly how many items you're gonna use
then : is more prepared so it is faster
so that's what this argument is for
capacity so anyway we have a stack
okay no no we have a stack now whenever
we whenever this happens we want to push
to stack so basically add add add a tool
to the slice so how do we do that let's
seek Prince lash size literal expression
twin size creates lies with make length
size of size a pen - sighs okay so here
is the oh my god I remember this is
problematic a pen to slice this is how
you add a new element to size
okay a pen to size so yep Kathy thank
you so here we are going to append to
slice so our slice name is stack so
let's see so here's how we do it this is
how we do it okay let's say 1,000 ok so
right now we are trying to so wherever
we run into a character that is one of
the bracket we need to push it to stack
so that is what this line does so we so
we push it to stack this line and
what's the syntax error here oh we need
to this this this slice declaration is
wrong actually here it needs to be run
run is a run means Unicode characters it
is a jargon invented by :
it just means Unicode characters
technically it means Unicode code point
and run is also a type in :
and that type is basically 32 bits bite
32 bits yeah 32 bits that's what one
type is so if you don't know what I'm
talking about you know you go through go
through my tutorial it's it's explained
everything here you have run you have
types you know so anyway so stack is a
slice of characters that's right we
potentially 1000 of them okay now here
we add a slice a paint stack new item
okay here is a new item so we need to
add a new item what that item will be it
will be it will be a pair of things well
not you know I was thinking it's gonna
be to a pair of things the first item is
the position of the character so when
you have a mismatch bracket you can
print out you know you can tell the user
where the position is you know it's we
we all need that because you know then
the second argument I mean the second
element is going to be the character
the-the-the the bracket that's
mismatched but for now let's just just
use a bracket forget about position
because we are out of time so this
program will just tell you if there's a
mismatch or not you know without without
telling you and we're so for now let's
just add
Chah so push it cha yep
so we don't need to print yeah but at
the end now we print now we print the
stack okay so basically now at the end
the stack will contain all bracket
characters okay run it IT Crowd and not
used okay God stupid : there it is okay
it's a bunch of numbers incomprehensible
okay we need to we need to find out the
proper way to print run so that we don't
see these you know a bunch of numbers
Unicode code points so okay how do you
print out run so let's see go to run
what's wrong purpose of run what score
point run literal print run okay here is
print one it's the is the easiest way is
actually to convert it to a string okay
run it okay so actually so I think this
is wrong you know so X okay so you see
so here's our stack right so it it found
that one then it added that one then you
know you go through the buffer then you
found more bracket than you add more so
at the end this is us what our stack
looks like that's good so actually this
print statement should actually outside
of the loop here here so let's run it
again
good so here's our stack this is what
our stack looks looks like okay we
making progress
now the next step step is that after you
add just add to the stack you need to
check if the previous level in the
current stack they are a matching pair
yeah you need to check that but how do
you do that so basically our problem
right now is suppose you have these two
characters you know this these two
bracket characters how do you find out
they are matching pairs
now that's actually a tedious problem
that by itself will take at least ten
minutes you know so you guys see what
the problem is so Cathy right Cathy do
you see the problem attached attached
are you still here
say something comment so right now oh
are you still here attached so right now
our problem is that given two characters
you know one of them may be a
parentheses bracket character you want
to check if these two characters are
actually matched pair that is a problem
you know given two characters how do you
check if they are matching pairs or in
other words given a string of two
characters you want to check you know if
the first element matches the second one
and in a correct order you know it must
be it must not be like that
it must be you know in this order that
okay that is actually so that's another
that's a tedious sub task there are many
ways to do that to approach that problem
one way is you actually manually code a
table so you manually code a table you
know you men you manually say you know
this character will match this character
so it's something like something like
that so you create you create array
something like that pairs and men you
know so you manually create this lookup
table so when you find this character
and you find a pair you know then then
you have these pairs of matching
characters then you say okay that is
matching character
if you know for example for example
let's say so something like this okay
matching pairs okay yeah so okay so in :
it's actually we need to put this in :
format but actually we probably need to
fix this
hey I can so you get the idea is you see
we need we can create I think this is
probably the easiest way you manually
create a table of matching pairs then
given any two characters you you go
through this table to see if it's you
know one of those pairs if it is then
you know they match otherwise not okay
so I guess this is what we will do now
the next step is to make sure this is a
correct goal and format it is not first
of all this matching pairs will be your
slice a slice of pairs and each pair is
again a slice okay that's one way to do
it or we could use a map let's see if a
map is appropriate
so in : a map is another data type that
is key value pairs map is a an ordered
collection of key value pairs
yeah in Python you color dictionary in
Ruby you called hash table okay so so
map is a database in : you could use we
could use and here is the syntax for map
a key type a do type key value key value
but
so we could use Matt for sure but
alternatively we can just use nested
slices which one is better I have to
think about which one is better
hi okay what's up I can actually I'm
kind of having kind of I want to stop 1
1 hour and 40 minutes we still have 6
people watching oh god I need to so this
is like torture I need to complete this
so so one way is to use map
another way is you slice you know I'm
thinking because which data structure
you choose or which data type of Golan
you choose they they impact what you're
gonna do because you you have to think
about which one is easier down the road
you know because we need to go through
this so that's why you have to think
about a lot of these but this is
actually real life coding I mean you
know this is real life coding is like
that 10 minutes thinking 1 minutes
typing so Kathy says interesting I
config show per a mod to locate
parentheses okay I never really think
about how it works in black in black and
in backend yeah yeah show pyramid yeah
I'm using that as well yeah it kind of
yeah yeah man behind the scenes it
actually does something similar because
for example if you have you know for
example you know it will highlight the
matching one not just the first one you
see so you see so in a background it
it's doing similar actually it has to go
everything we are going through you know
so actually actually thinking about that
since you mentioned that actually so
Emacs has this building so if we are
coding this in Emacs we could look at
the Emacs code and kind of utilize it
but you but but from experience I know
that that may not be easy
rather it's easier if you just write
completely new because Emacs pack and I
mean the Emacs internals they it's
rather very complicated and and besides
this is not difficult to write like like
we are almost done almost we are almost
done here so and also that you know the
the reason we are writing this so we can
do it massively like one on one thousand
files that is what why I want to do it
because I used I mean in HTML and I use
all kind of brackets so I want to make
sure all the brackets are valid you know
they don't have mismatched or missing
brackets or in wrong order things like
that so we can you know once I have this
sinkhole and I can run it on you know
ten thousand files within few seconds so
that is why I'm doing this you know I I
have a version in a Mac list I showed
you know I showed before but colon is
like five times faster than many Mac
this and the other reason I want to do
in colon is that I want to you know like
a practice this is how you practice
learning a new language so that's that's
what I'm doing okay so I need to finish
this matching pairs so so do we need do
we use do we use map or not
I don't know so this is just let's just
push on with a map okay so let's
so if we use map then how do we check so
you see we need you know late later on
we need to go through this and we need
to check
not just the first element we also need
to check the second element you know for
example we want to check we want to
compare a character with the first
element you know this element but we
also need to check the second element so
in other words it's not just checking
with all keys we also need to go through
every value I'm like I'm right now I'm
thinking whether should I use map or
slice of size okay so let's go with map
let's just let's just try to go with the
map okay
so let's copy the pastry here so so map
syntax is going to be type key type key
type is going to be run value type is
also run and then we type the key and
value okay okay now the way you
represent run is by single quote in goal
and so let's let's show you how let's
see narrow to buffer switch or double
quote to single quote yeah so there so
expand again
and switch so this should be a comma
instead I mean :
right so I think that's that okay I
think that's like that so this is no
good
probably let's make it okay so wrong
oh yeah so this is wrong we don't we
don't need that go format
okay now good coding go format
okay now good so we have matching pairs
as a map each key is the opening bracket
okay value is the ending bracket okay so
matching pairs okay now since we have
this structure we actually don't need
need this anymore you see this whole
packet it should be generated from this
you know but that's optimization we do
that later
so anyway matching because otherwise
otherwise we have repetition we have
redundancy you see because the brackets
are declared in both phases you know in
in both forms we we rather just want to
have this but anyway so matching pairs
now we have now we need to check this is
another yeah this this and I don't think
I can finish this you know this is gonna
be another 20 minutes minimum even if we
can do that so let's let's do this okay
let's open a new buffer Pastis save it
as X X dot go magnify insert a colon
template let's just write a simple code
that solves a problem of checking if two
characters matches is a matching pair so
we are doing we are studying a subtask
here okay so far
cha one ok cha 1 equals to a let's say
Chawla in quotes through that la cha 2
equals to that ok and matching pair put
it on top and so given to Charles we
want to know if Chauhan and cha to our
matching pairs okay so so first of all
we need to go through the matching pairs
here so go
so for range okay so here's how we go
through matching pairs go through
matching pairs key value okay if key
equals to cha what now
now Java and chart who should be run
remember red means the character so they
should be single quote okay
let's double check
then right so you see run in Cola and
run is a data type that means a Unicode
character and it the syntax is single
quote so that's how you define here so
so Chawan charter so if key equals to
char one then
now there's a lot to do here actually
first of all okay so if ki was to Chawan
okay and I think end is like that in
Golan and he equals - cha - wait that's
not right
okay I think map is the wrong format
okay so so wait so if T equals to cha
one then if
if Val equals to char - yeah that's
that's it that's it
okay return true that's it I think
otherwise return force oh my god we are
we are good
wait where do we return force so
matching pairs that I don't know let's
just run it and see what happens
import not used format to many argument
to return what yeah you should you know
I just try to run it it doesn't work
usually when you you know sometimes you
try to escape thinking and just try to
see if it works
usually that's a bad thing to do because
that happens usually why when you are
very tired you know you just want to
skip thinking and you just want to try
to see something works but usually that
ends up very bad because you usually
ends up you trying 10 times 20 times
something Co doesn't work so when you
program at least for me the the way that
works best is always just to think
through what's going on so here we want
to char it's probably sunshine in my
eyes or not yeah okay so here what we
what's going on is key equals to Chawan
so if key equals to char one then we
want to check if value equals to chart -
that's right now if that's true
if that's true we want to exit the loop
and return true now when you return to
the yeah it also exit loop I think so it
just returned true
it's just it's just paint matched okay
yes it is just try that okay yeah what
yeah so so this is how we found out if
if two characters are matching
characters but but let's try something
else let's see okay that that seems to
work
okay we added a else here
okay yeah so this seems to work let's we
need more tests here what if they are
reversed direction like that no good
what if they are
let's try paren okay Janet no and yes
wait something is wrong here
oh you need to exit them you need to
exit so how do you exit the loop so
let's look at loop look a wire loop
infinite loop break loop yeah break okay
you say break here so once you found
this and you say break okay
okay let's let's do result
so if cha
yeah I think this is better so print
okay run it matched true that's right
okay so now we can change let's go back
this case run it matched force correct
let's try that run it match true okay
let's try another thing run it
Oh declared twice problem with : okay
unit force that's correct so we can
assume that this code is correct now we
can make this into a function we can
make this into a function then use back
in our code here let's let's try it then
maybe we should maybe we should stop
because today is two hours yeah watching
what all the people are gone so I don't
know who is here now Kathy you are here
so that's it for today thank you guys
for watching bye
yeah Kathy you are the only one by Oh
bathroom you is online now oh my god
battle me you are you even keeping quiet
today anyway I'll see you guys next time