good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sod talk show now let me get
prepared go live and if you are new here
just go to this website Sal talks your
website which is over here and you will
see a list of topics and find the one
that interests you then type in the
comment box then we will talk about that
so you know type the comment in real
time comment box so let me get something
to drink this is my power drink Rockstar
this is basically condensed while some
kind of coffee condensed coffee essence
you know like Red Bull ok
energize and now here is prune juice
100% prune juice $1 each cheap so we're
gonna talk about you know let me know
what you want to what we're gonna talk
about we can talk about in general
there's two divisions tech technical or
non tech tech is like Emacs programming
programming languages user interface
design programming language design
JavaScript programming : and so on
that's tech technical non tech is you
know anything on technical you know
interesting things happening so let me
just begin by non-technical things okay
so you know again you know what the top
is going to be is going to depend on
depends on what you know what you guys
want what do you got you know you guys
take the direction like we have a chat
and I'll be fun okay we have one guy
here and say something you know just
type in the chat bar box and today is
the 16th and let me get the talk okay
and let's see let's put this here copy
the path new buffer paste make it into a
link shrink make it one line pick a
topic and post in comment okay okay wait
not here wait well okay paste it there
and actually I need to paste it here so
what so yesterday we did the talk show
where I talked about does well the
social justice people and that's kind of
sad you know I but I was afraid Google
is
- Pammy and okay since nobody's here yet
let me go - okay so here is a page
google - evo you can just search focus
on equal to evo and you'll find it you
know google so this page I start - I
begin to dark document of the many
things that evil things Google is doing
for example this this article is from
today former mozilla execute former
mozilla executed
google has sabotage firefox for years
you know so google is doing you know
google chrome team is doing evil things
you know it to to make firefox you know
like underhand tactics to make firefox
look bad so that's one example you know
you can go read read the article then
here's another article from two days ago
google a MP lowered our page speed and
there is no choice but to use it so yeah
google has been doing a lot of you know
really bad evil things so and i have
been working on my JavaScript tutorial
in the past month so let me show you
let's go to Emacs okay close that
bookmark jump to javascript website
showing browser so this is my local copy
of my javascript in-depth web site so i
have been working on this in the past
week
you know updating it I added the side
panel here this is a great tutorial it's
the best tutorial on the web okay you
know one of the best among the top three
I would say you know the Amun that one
of the top three of or JavaScript
tutorials book in existence doesn't
matter its online or offline okay
including Microsoft's including mozi
you know JavaScript reference including
whatever printed books okay of all of
them I would claim that my is the best
among the top three okay so if you like
it
you know check it out jump just search
for javascript in depth sorry and you
know try to learn it and if you like it
put money in my pocket okay put to my
patreon PayPal and so on and you can
also buy the whole tutorial offline you
know you can read it offline without any
ads so this is kind of comprehensive and
I've read you know all the JavaScript
specs and so actually so since there's
you know nobody is here yet one person
you know let me know what you want to
you know type a question or anything
comment so you know say hi so since no
is your hi let me work on something then
maybe so you can see this is a SVG
tutorial now if I go to my SVG tutorial
hold on a second it's copy that go to
Emacs
copy that go to Emacs open the file and
ensuring browser okay
now you see this one doesn't have the
side box however if you go to my SVG
tutorial here it is and you can see on
the side panel you have the index you
have SVG basics you have path SVG path
and other topics so for some reason that
Arco article didn't have that so we
gonna I'm going to need to add it so
let's see SVG animate tank okay so first
of all I need to you know go to the
tired directory and find out of all
files in this directory I want to find
out
which fire does not have the the side
panel so let's do that so first of all
go to JavaScript in depth which is this
one wait I need to go to SVG SVG open in
browser so so the panel is go is this
one is this part so I'm going to search
let me go show that so I'm going to
search wait a minute I'm going to search
this text for all files in this
directory okay
MX find count okay what such string so
paste the search string enter and what
do I want to show so I want to show
anything that is not one not equal to
one okay show it
so I got all these files quite a lot
files oh that's actually too many
because most of them are actually
JavaScript so my task is to find so I
copy everything new buffer paste select
all sewed it compact the empty space see
that then go down all the way down okay
copy this line go to the top query
replace paste the line replaced by
nothing for all okay then compact the
line then we don't need this part we
don't need that so now we have all the
files basically now select Oh
salt okay and now this Oh line is that
whose file name contains SVG at least
matching lines
SVG Oh so only actually three of them
okay that's good copy it close close we
don't need to save it close that now
actually okay so new buffer paste it I'm
gonna open these files so open it show
in browser ok browser in line is the
image hate Wade scale vs. quad browser
inline SVG image okay I haven't seen
this article for a long time this is
very old article 2012
okay that's actually this is not part of
the SVG tutorial so I'm not going to add
SVG panels on the left so this is
browser inline SVG image hate weight
scale scale versus quad okay I think it
was a bug
ie night yeah it's kind of a bugging I
you know so you ignore this page now
let's open this one show in browser
canvas is versus SVG so this page is
comparison of these two technologies now
why why was it not okay for some reason
I don't have the panel so okay anyway
copy the panel here copy go here go to
the bottom then we want to replace this
block by that now showing browser now we
have the SVG navigation panel on the
left that's good okay now one more file
SVG animate tag so do the same thing
let's go here go to the bottom select it
paste that's good showing browser that's
good and now we just upload to my
browser go to each shell okay wait
close it close it we don't need it no
save go to issue a brief Interactive a
brief okay our sink yes then it's
uploaded to my browser I mean to my
server okay so that's one task done
that's about Emacs I'm using Emacs
okay what else
so it's Chloe the open SVG crows crows
crows okay back to a talk show now let's
go back to SVG tutorial yeah okay
what else to talk we got two person
watching um okay what else to talk about
okay let's talk about random then you
know if you have a question comment post
it you know I'd like to see your
comments and I'm gonna talk about I'm
gonna talk random okay so SVG basic
examples close it
let's see truncation lines Google to Evo
okay we talked about that that's start
to read that's the things I have to read
okay saw talk show actually there's a
there's a case I want to talk about
I'm not sure I want to talk about that
it's it's basically about you know
social issues anyway
so I don't know what to talk about let's
go - lets go - kasam programming block
okay let's see what's interesting like
programming blog so Firefox you know
Firefox just removed shift F to feature
basically Firefox remove the removed
this feature code okay let's go here
full-page screenshot in browser so here
here this page is tells you how to do
full-page screenshot of a browser page
for example this page is very long you
know it's got many pages you know it's
and you want to do a screenshot you know
creating a big long image you know
capturing the whole page you can do that
with browsers so in Firefox you just go
to web dev console command option K
let's try it command option K let's do
that command option K then you just type
you just type these one second
let's bring the panel down then you just
type : screenshot - - full page then
file name whatever file name you want to
save it as let's try it why not
so you go to console then screenshot
okay - - full page and let's name it e
okay okay the screenshot is done now I
can just go to this is going to be a
trick okay I create a new section and
just call this commands are new images
okay save it now if I view this in
browser
you can see you see this is a screenshot
you know it's it's more than one page
but it captured the whole thing so
that's good you know that's just the
example now we don't want actually want
it so open that deleted did it V DD DD
okay so that's five that's Firefox
screenshot now however it used to be
they have this feature
it's called developer toolbar or also
known as G LCI you know kind of a
toolbar at the bottom you you can type
commands that feature has been around
around for like three or four years in
and it's good you know what happened is
that since about ten years ago
browsers start to have features that
comes and go you know it's you cannot
rely on it you know this year is here
next year it's gone and Firefox used to
have like a 3d feature where you can see
your page rendered in 3d I mean it's
it's hard to let me show you
Firefox sorry Firefox 3d feature I
blogged about it
then you know and and then that feature
is removed it's pretty cool though but I
guess nobody uses it not this one you
know sure yeah so you know the browser
it changes every year you know oh every
month this trend began with Google
Chrome about 10 years ago so you know it
just changes and everything becomes a
history Firefox 3d view yeah that's
called Firefox 3d view
let's see if I can you know so they'd
remove that they removed it okay I'm
trying to find you know I'm trying to
find my blog but apparently but
hopefully I can show you some pictures
yeah it looks like that you see this
this is pretty fancy you know any
webpage you can go into a 3d view and
you can see they you see these stacked
up things
looks like buildings the the hate I mean
each HTML tag creates a hate so when
they are high you see them as they are
nest nested when when there's many
nesting they become higher so that's how
it looks you can actually rotate the
thing you know it's three dimensional
but they remove that you know because
they they were trying yeah you see it
looks like this I like it very much I
mean it's very good let's open let's try
to yeah they removed it
so someone is asking why is it removed
so the answer is chosen answer hello 3d
view shield isn't compatible with the
multi-process version of firefox as it
stands at the moment if you disable
attention you'll still be available so
it says it's not compatible with the
multi-process version okay you know
sometimes in the past few years Firefox
finally switched to the multi-process
version like multi-process feature what
that means is that you used to be when
used when you run an app each app runs
one process you know in in programming
terms it's one process but beginning but
but starting with Google Chrome browser
they began to have instead of each you
know application runs one process you
have each tab is one process so you know
like this is one process this is one
process this is one process and you can
see that in Activity Monitor you see it
okay process name
you see Google Chrome help I think on
the Mac I think these are you know these
are you know each one is a process
that's the what they call Google Chrome
help but on Linux you can just you can
see you know just Google Chrome
processes let's go to so I have this
Linux tutorial you might check out Linux
basic shell command practical Linux
tutorial so you go here and it's
practical Linux tutorial where I show
you all the most practical and commonly
used commands commands that are used
everyday you know it's all pure commands
you run them on terminal and one of the
command is top you know top top and edge
top top is the traditional unix tool to
show which process is running so i have
a tutorial here but however there's a
better better tool which is h top the
major difference is that in etch top you
can actually show all processes you know
you can page down in page up and show
all the processes but with the
traditional unix top tool you can only
see the you know the top 20 most cpu
heavy processes you cannot see the rest
of it there's no page down you know
that's why that's why it's it's code top
you know it just lets you to let you see
you know monitor the top cpu heavy
processes so h top is a better version
much improved and it also shows you
the memory usage in a sensible graph
sensible way okay you get you can see
actually see here you see all these
qualms chrome chrome yeah that's that's
chrome that's you know because each tab
is running a process the reason they
want to do that chrome started to do
that is because it supposedly have
better security
you know because different websites you
know each tab is only one process if you
have a virus on this web page it won't
crash or your other tabs things like
that so Google you know did that then
Firefox try to do that but it's not easy
to do because you have to you have to
kind of rewrite the whole thing so it
took Firefox several years to do that
and now they are suppose they are doing
it let's see if I can actually see it in
Firefox let's let me switch to several
browsers and go back here and it's such
Firefox yeah so he only shows four so
I'm actually I'm not sure Firefox is
actually using more type processes
so how many people are watching out to
people okay no but nobody is watching
today okay that's too bad
so today today is Tuesday so right now
it's like 3 o clock so maybe this time
you know they are not many people but
also because I just announced it one
hour ago
so anyway I'm using Emacs version 26 you
can see let me do this control u MX
version so you can see I'm using the
guna Emacs
26.2 which is the latest version they
just released this version yesterday two
days ago actually but it's not very good
because every now and then you will see
the hope of a flash it becomes blank for
half a second so that's not very good
and also they have you see my title bar
is like you see this this is a normal
title bar you can see your power there
but on this window you don't have that
this window you don't have that that's a
bug you know it's that's not something I
created it's just that every time I have
desktop mod on and every time I restart
Emacs you know it reopens all the
windows you had and they appear like
that so it's so if I can close this
window yeah so that's a bug I'm not sure
what's the deal
so what what else to talk about so I'm
looking at yeah so you know if you have
a question just type it okay just just
type anything say hi so I'm looking at
my programming blog you know if no one
is asking no one is here and you know no
one is you know talking they I'm just
going to talk random you know about my
website and stuff so this is my website
and you know code this is sorry dot info
okay you can see the URL at top and this
is my local page so on this side I have
like close to 4,000 files HTML files I
have written men manually by hand you
know with the help of Emacs but okay so
there's an interesting thing let's show
that so let's go to Saudi Don info and I
added this Chinese chess sprain Chinese
chess
good morning sound toxin random talk is
fine with me
that's great where are you from where
are you from
sound toxin what country so I got this
Chinese chess it's written in JavaScript
I didn't write it but it's a like a open
source somewhere so you know you can
play with computers so let me try to
play it do you know how to play chinese
chess so let me let me play a quick game
okay I'm going to lose for sure Midwest
area central line cool central time
that's cool so Chinese chess so Chinese
chess is basically a variant of chess
you know so you know it's like you know
international chess kind of similar but
but you know but it's slightly slightly
different you know the rule you know the
but the nature is the same nature and
and this is actually one of my most
popular pages okay he's coming up good
morning tom thomas thomas whoa
good morning wench then when san I know
you I know you from I think Twitter I
think you are my longtime follower so
Winston are you in Taiwan or are you in
US and the UK Chinese oh you learned it
when you were small so me - yeah I
learned it when I was a kid and I I am
pretty good at Chinese chess but however
is I cannot beat the computer you know
because computer chess computers today
they beat any chess champion you know
since like 10 years ago like for sure
almost you know for sure if you play you
know ten games you know the computer
will win you know most of the games even
for word world champions so anyway
that's Chinese chess you know now and
then I play it you know because you know
I am used to the game so I play it but
but I always lose when sin is immobile
Australia oh wow
mobilis Australia followed you on
Twitter for a long time yeah that's
great good to know
so when sand yeah I don't remember
what's your Twitter handle though I
think it's the same name but I don't
think I've seen you treat for a while so
let's see Chinese chess so anyway that's
Chinese chess so if you you know if you
are into test you guys might be
interested you can you can learn how to
play it
Wikipedia you know we hate PDS has tell
you rules so anyway back to my website
so so what do you guys what what do you
guys program programming languages so I
got you know so mostly the things I'm
sorry website is programming programming
stuff technical stuff and math so yeah
let me show you what's what they are so
okay there's a chess there's a Unicode
Unicode is one of the things I love
because you can see okay there are
emojis you know also love emojis and and
then there are symbols
so sound toxin says I can't program very
much yet but I like scheme and Ruby
those are elegant languages and Thomas
says I'm learning to program in C sharp
why C sharp okay so this page is unicode
stars you can you can see all the
unicode star variations so unicode is
very interesting let me show you
so there's also cross you know all these
are crosses you know unicode they
contain all the worlds characters and
and you see many characters they are
agent for example you know you have east
sirak cross you have cause of jerusalem
you have also darks cross you have cross
of Lorraine you have zero you have
dotted course you have UNK
you know so many of these symbols are
Asian this tank for example it's it's at
least I think maybe 3000 years old you
know because it's used in its Egyptian
and also these characters is also it's
ancient Buddhism symbol but you if you
are a westerner and you met you may not
know but the these are all these
actually you know you can see the names
this these two are actually Chinese
characters I mean you know it may looks
like a symbol but actually they are
Chinese characters they are variations
of the you know it's a hindu buddhism
symbol it means it means like luck
prosperity you know along that line
so oh yeah so let me talk about this
symbol this symbol Hank it's for it's in
a heliograph for example let me show you
so here is the Egyptian hero graph and
you can see you know it's Egyptian hero
graph is kind of interesting it's funny
you have these characters and you will
find a symbol you have eyes you have
teeth you have mouth you have this as I
suppose those are tits which is you know
fundamental and natural you know one of
the you know the most phenomenal most
basic of human animals in all animals
you have to you know so let's see where
can i I saw that symbol just a few days
ago yesterday
so anyway so Thomas says Thomas is my
first strongly typed language
okay that's tsipras a nice eShop and
Hamas says I'm not a fan of PHP but I'm
hoping to land a job as a web developer
oh that's that's cool and Thomas were
you from and Hamas is a big fan of Ruby
yeah Ruby's very good elegant Ruby and
scheme so wench wench sand wench and let
me ask you so do you have a question for
me for Emacs
and Winston Winston what are you doing
like what do you you you work as a
programmer right so anyway so I have
this unicode pages they are fascinating
and let's go back to my website
sorry oke back to unicode back to sorry
dot info
Oh Thomas is in England
when Sun is doing not J as dev cool so
solid our info you have chest
you have Unicode then you have keyboard
a lot of you know so I have like few
hundred keyboard pages like reviews and
introduction to keyboard or and
everything anything about keyboard so
you have economic keyboards I give you a
list of all the bass essentially all the
ergonomic keyboards you can buy if you
are a programmer it's a good investment
you know you should buy up them one of
them you know buy them for my website
you know pick what you want if you have
a question about keyboards you know I
asked me so you have you know ergonomic
keyboards in some people a lot of people
don't like economic keyboards because
usually almost always because they don't
touch type if you look if you do not
touch type then economic keyboard is
really actually not useful to you I mean
it's actually because you don't touch
type then you know you know you you
wouldn't find a Bonomi keyboard
advantage advantages you know you it's
is rather useless so you people like PC
keyboards so I have a select selection
of the best mechanical PC keyboards and
many of them are programmable for
example this one is programmable vortex
race and also this vortex gear cipher
and also see a master key and also this
one not all of them though and this one
to this one booting but this one booting
is very special I think it it's like
three hundred dollars
because it has I mean instead of being
just a mechanical keyboard like digital
like switch on and off on and off this
wooden keyboard is actually analog
mechanical switch meaning that when you
press a key the key functions almost
like a joystick so it's not just on and
off it's actually like some kind of a
continuous signal you know so you can so
so it will send a signal when you know
like at what level your key is pressed
you know so what what is the purpose of
that well the point of that is then this
keyboard becomes each key becomes like
you have fine control for example they
are not many applications for this yet
but basically you can think of each key
as a analog like a joystick you know so
so there's many signals levels at
different levels so for you for example
you can kind of use this to drive a car
like video game a car or fly a plane
like you know how how fast you go
depends on how how much you are holding
down a key something like that
so this this is definitely a new
technology so I think it's already on
sale I'm not sure you might check the
website where to buy the wooden keyboard
let's see
oh it's it's 8 a.m. in Australia cool so
Thomas says I use a USB touchscreen
keyboard i bought from japan USB
touchscreen keyboard that's interesting
really for programming thats would be i
cannot imagine that would be good a
touch swing keyboard i mean it's a
screen like a grass yeah i cannot
imagine you know using a one of those
touchscreen keyboards it's like do you
have a name or a picture or something
you can show us so anyway there is a
wooden keyboard okay pre-order now
apparently it's not for prime time yet
so anyway so so let's go back to my
keyboard page yeah so I got PC keyboard
reviews then then I got some lots of
articles about keyboard design for
example for example keyboard design for
example you might wonder how you know
the arrangement of keys like on your
keyboard you have qwe R and asdf and so
on you know where does that came from
why do they arrange it that way so I
have explanations for that here you know
and lots of other things you know for
example why why are the keys
slanted you know or sometimes it's
called staggered who's you know like
like these staggered why because
actually because from mechanical
typewriters you see the bass underneath
they need to keep those bars aligned and
straight
thus why the keys become slanted in a
strange way
in a rather irregular way because you
can see it's not it's not exactly
diagonal and it's you know you know it's
from top right to lower top left to
lower right you know the all kind of
weird things going on with the keyboard
and that's the history of it and why for
example why is a space bar so huge well
that is because one day you know the
typewriters the mechanical typewriters
here here is okay
typewriter spacebar history here is a
history and this is this is from a book
and I was told of this story by by this
guy let me show you by massing why curry
massing why curry okay he said he's a
keyboard history keyboard historian okay
he's he's writing a book on keyboard I'm
not sure it's out or not yet anyway so
here is a page about why the space spa
is huge
actually you don't need it you know you
don't really need huge your spacebar the
it's it's that way just because one day
you know you know one of the guys who
who you know the people who are making
typewriters just thought of it you know
hey hey why not then you know let's make
it you know why so maybe it's more
convenient and and then oh yeah and it's
this chart and you know then it's just
there and it's stuck so
so this Japanese keyboard touchscreen
keyboard is called cool leaf so let's
see if we can find it cool Eve keyboard
it's such images oh that's interesting
so we got this touchscreen keyboard from
Japan I cannot possibly imagine that
you're going to be typing on this and
you like it this so this is actually
this is your main keyboard it's
basically just like a grass and to me I
feel that it will be the most painful to
type because because you don't get you
know the tactile sensation you don't
have any yield like you are just
touching grass all day so how much is it
though
okay you don't always use it it's quite
interesting though so I'm going to look
into it yeah cool
you know this interesting keyboard so
let's go back to my keyboard page yeah
so here is a typewriter spacebar history
there is no like rationale yeah like
sometimes when you look at things almost
anything you know like the why the
keyboard is the way they are why we have
the caps lock key you know why anything
if you just look at in detail and think
of why they oftentimes they have you
know history but usually I mean we might
think we we usually think you know there
must be a logical rational reason like
someone think you know for some reason
then they decided to design it that way
because of something something you
should put often that's not the case you
the way things are often depending on
what things but anyway for keyboards a
lot of things just they don't have like
a rational reason it's like not for good
reason so the reason that the spacebar
is really long it's not because you know
people have you know tried all possible
ways and turns out you know a long
spacebar is good no it just so happens
that someone designed it that way and
the brand is popular you know it's like
used by everyone and everyone just get
used to it we just got people just got
used to it and when they when people see
a new keyboard you know with a small
space bar they don't like it because
there's a habit you know you are you
already are used to the long space bar
so so one day you see a short space
value you might your reaction would be
this is strange you know this is strange
you know you don't want it because yeah
that's that's that's
that's what happens to lots of things so
oftentimes similarly to programming
languages you know like there are people
who studied programming languages you
know the history usually you know it's
the programmers who refuse innovation
like if we look at the programming
languages in the past you know five
years you know C and Lisp and you know
full try and whatever they are a lot you
know you don't hear about them you know
it's a PR and you know all the
programming histories we can see your
progress you know from assembly language
to higher-level language to to you know
machine language assembly language
Fortran COBOL see this you know forth
you know and and APL and you know and so
on if you look at them you can see
progress you know today like today we
have Perl you know that there was pearl
in this Python Ruby then we have : you
know for example photo for the C C we
have C C++ Java C sharp and D you know C
C C++ C Java C sharp right it's kind of
like a progression and we have : and we
have lost this these are all kind of
like low-level C kind of family anyway
so there are many of them you know
there's scripting languages there's blue
one
you know lure Python and Judea and so on
and you can kind of see progress because
many features we don't have before and
we have today for example lamb lambda is
one of the thing enclosure you know is
also another feature and also automatic
memory management and many you know
almost every feature you can see is over
the years then gradually almost all
programming languages have those
features but however if you look back in
history usually it's a case that when
that feature
I introduced the programmers at the time
they they rejected like they don't want
it they think it's stupid it's like this
happens decade after decade it's
somewhat almost like that so you know
today we take things for granted
absolutely you know why you know we
might think some programming feature in
every language with to to us it seems
obvious you know obvious we obviously
which we should have that but if you
look back then when that feature is
introduced the programmers at the time
they they are almost saying I know
that's the most stupid feature we don't
want that why is that it's because of
habit so in the same way today there are
lots of new things we refuse like today
we we as programmers we think you know
that's stupid but actually it's it's
only because we are not used to it
because we are used to whatever you know
programming languages we have today we
are a customer to it so so sound Thaksin
says I got to borrow an ogre Docs
keyboard for a couple of months and I
liked that the keys were in a grid
instead of staggered layout yeah that's
what I use you know I showed my keyboard
many times in the past let's see you
know so I'm using truly ergonomic
keyboard you know so the keys are or
straight you see it's straight uptown
you know uptown it's like there's a line
so and it's it's like that it's curved
you know it's like it's like a it's like
a pole you know so I my fingers rest on
it and I think that's my favorite
keyboard now I mean you can see on my
website so anyway back on this website
page you can see many of the old
typewriters
they used to have different space bars
that's not just bad you see this one
doesn't you see this this keyboard the
spacebar is just one single key over
here so that's a history of the spacebar
and this one is fun funky one and look
and look at this one the spacebar is
that these two things on the side I
think they are yeah
space space you know so so my keyboard
now is this auger docks so you might
check it out so so Toma says have you
came across crystal for any language
yeah I haven't looked into it though I
think it's good but you know there are
so many languages today crystal language
I think it's supposed to be its space
sound Ruby so it has the same syntax as
Ruby but it has the speed of C so it's
kind of a modern version of Ruby you
might say you know so yeah crystal I
think it's good you know as far as
programming language language goes you
know it's basically every ten years you
know for each decade the newer the
better in general you know there's no
doubt about that because that's you know
because that's called progress you know
because you know programming that kind
of applies to any technology as far as
long as it's a technology its technology
then usually the newer the better you
know
so Christo's so I mean there are so many
languages is today it's not like you
know 20 years ago so so today there are
so many languages new ones it's like you
you can
you don't have the time to learn all of
them you know all of them are very good
I mean I I suppose you know I'm guessing
Christo you know it's very good it has
you know Ruby syntax and those fast as C
it's very good so Golan is good Julia is
good you know a lot a lot of them
actually I have an article see
proliferation of programming languages
proliferation of computing languages so
on this page I list you know many new
languages this is written in 2008 and I
began to update them but I can't kind of
stopped because there's just too many
languages you know you don't even have
time to add them to add to the list
okay so there's pure pure is a pattern
matching language let's see if they are
still around they used to have a
Wikipedia page but it got deleted a
while back it seems you know
oh it's still there okay so you got this
pure
so this is the repository for oh wait
the repository is good I guess they must
have moved away from bitbucket yeah must
be so anyway I got the list of lots of
languages here Julia Oh meta or meta is
a old one Elm so anyway so any anything
else I think that's it for today
I kind of you know one hour okay so you
know I kind of just random swift is from
Apple hack plan is from Facebook
a gerson how a Gerson is a pattern
matching language I forgot about it
hoechlin I know actually I don't know
how I don't know anything about Hakluyt
hoechlin is you know you know PHP is
designed you know PHP is extremely
popular you know back in 2000 it's the
most popular language basically or the
top three you know if you can't see C++
PHP Java that's the most popular but PHP
is still one of the most popular among
top five you know it's used everywhere
it's Wikipedia is written in PHP
Facebook is written in PHP so so you
know so Facebook you know but PHP is a
compiler
I mean so it's it's not a fast language
so but people becomes huge you know
becomes one of the most powerful you
know in popular website so they they
have the money so they basically they
they create they want to improve PHP in
who improve the speed so they created
this hacklin back in I think back in
even 2009 I forgot what's the date they
created it back in 2010 something like
that but I haven't heard of it much you
know basically hacklin is just like PHP
is basically PHP with optional type
system and type inference but I never
actually looked into it
I programmed in PHP for like for a few
years and I read the PHP documentation
almost cover back cover to cover you
know anyway hacklin yeah I don't know
much about hacklin why are you let's see
are you interested too
yeah that's p-type into a PHP so you you
program PHP yeah so and I you know it
seems I don't hear people talking about
Hekla and much yeah but also since then
PHP as far as I know the it has also
improved a lot I mean a new competitor
has came out you know the compiler has
been rewritten again you know it's been
rewritten several times you know every
few years you know we as we know more
compiler technology so I mean PHP is
very popular right so a lot of people
companies have the resources you know
they so they write a better compiler
every few years so last I heard it's you
know it's very you know it's very good
you know some of these languages it is
very good today I that's what I heard
yeah the problem with PHP is you know
the naming is inconsistent
Oh Flo type okay so when Stan says I'm
doing Winston says I'm doing JavaScript
and there is flow type from Facebook
which I think might be a similar thing
as what hacklin to PHP so flow type how
is that it's let's search flow type
let's see a static type checker for
JavaScript oh I'm not sure about that
because because you know there's a
typescript right have you used
typescript I'm using typescript it's
pretty good but so flow is a static type
checker for JavaScript yeah time check I
don't have that I'm not sure I like it
yeah it's a type checker so so basically
I said I suppose it adds types to
JavaScript and it compiles to JavaScript
I mean that's what typescript do I mean
that's what typescript does and as far
as that goes types typescript is pretty
good
but overall it's no good because because
JavaScript I talked about this in in one
of the videos you know last week also
JavaScript the syntax is extremely
complicated okay because javascript is
you know a language that's designed and
written implemented in ten days ten days
you know the whole thing design and
implementation the whole thing is
created in ten days so there's a lot of
problems and over the past twenty years
they changed lots of things but however
they made they tried to make it backward
compatible so all the bad things in
JavaScript is still there
so today the JavaScript you know you
have this extremely messy you know
basically it's an extremely messy
language the syntax is fairly
complicated so given that then you have
typescript which is 100% compatible with
JavaScript except that they added types
you know static optional types you can
add it if you want so you know so it's
supposed to help programmers but anyway
so what so what you got is this
extremely complicated syntax first more
even more complicated syntax for the
type you know for you know the type
annotation syntax so it's it's not good
I mean and and also if you code in
typescript you know I have a you know
for example let me show you my
typescript go-to sorry the info Saad row
index open that okay copy that
so I go here you can see this this is my
project to draw to draw curves
these are Chavez this is our JavaScript
app script and you can see the code
[Music]
you can see the code here this this one
so it's all typescript and you know so
you can see for example this is a
function and these are type annotations
this is you know so anyway
typescript companion oh you got this
complicated syntax inconsistent and then
it compares to JavaScript so it adds
more complications you know it's not
it's not a bad a dong as far as Adam
goes but compared to for example golden
or Judea or even say crystal or name you
know some of the new languages it's it's
no good because you have you have so
many so much complications
you know you compile you add types you
compare to JavaScript and JavaScript is
like 30 years old pile a pile of you
know bags packages you know so you know
so compared to the newer languages like
completely new : Swift maybe hoechlin
elixir you know many of name also name
you know many of these you know if you
compare to them then the typescript is
plus Java Scooby is not good
Oh Winston says flow flow does not
compile building it just strips of or
typing annotations okay yeah still you
know I don't like those you know like
today's languages today is today's
development especially in the JavaScript
front-end you know the the thing becomes
extremely complicated because you have
the you have so many tools like NPM you
have like hundred libraries you download
one run library that library uses you
know 100 other libraries you have in
dependencies you know then you have the
config files then you have the
transpilers you know javascript es2015
transpilers and you have you know a
bunch of crap then you have tools to to
dynamically update your page and and
then then you have tools to combine
libraries and stuff so it's one huge bag
of mess then okay then you have you know
the typescript which compares to
javascript then you have you need to use
Pablo or whatever or maybe you use flow
then so this whole package you know so
so then you have then you have the build
step like when you build you run the
tool then the tools means a bunch of
libraries you know complicated things to
combine libraries or whatever then you
have to deploy you know it's it's very
it's it's very bad it's a mess
you know as compared to in the old days
for example Python you write a program
you just write it all you know even
anyways
javascript is our hike oh hi
so Thomas says JavaScript is how I got
into programming I always thought it was
very minimal JavaScript
is not really minimal I mean depending
on what do you mean of course I can see
what you know what do you mean by
minimum you know JavaScript you know if
you compare the language okay JavaScript
the language you know just the language
itself it's pretty small but it's not
really minimal because when you compare
to Ruby or what when you compare
compared to a scheme for example scheme
is you know actually the the really
truly minimal language but javascript
you know you don't have lots of
libraries building so you actually need
all the libraries you know elsewhere hey
good morning Isaak you how late you are
early actually I think we are done today
you know 17 minutes so what's up Isaac
anything anything interesting anything
else so I've been talking for one hour
you know it's kind of yeah yeah so I
think I'm gonna shut down so I talked
about I didn't talk much about much
today I kind of just random you know the
random stuff he just finished class okay
okay have a good day guys I hope to see
you next time bye