good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sound talk show
how are you guys
so we are going to do wufang language
coding we are going to continue from
yesterday's uh george's wolfram language
code that does unix script that is find
text in all files in a directory
recursively
including subdirectories
so
video check and audio check let's see uh
video check audio check am i streaming
yes
okay let's go uh we are ready to go good
morning andrew
so wu from language coding so i'm going
to go through george
wufan language code
uh and i'm going to
optimize it
now
you know it's easy when you have already
a code you are just going to modify it
you know george so let's give you know
so george did great you know he wrote
this he's new to wolfram language and he
wrote this
find string uh
script
but
because i've been coding wufang language
for 10 years so i can optimize it you
know make it idiomatic you know and
improve it so
so i think there's a lot to do today and
so i'm going to like teach you wufam
language uh some of the tips in wufang
language about efficiency and all that
efficiency i'm gonna
okay so so let me tell you what the
steps we are going to go through today
so first of all um
i'm going to
uh
go through
the syntax change the syn
change the syntax to a
better faster form okay then
the second thing i'm going to do
change is to change the algorithm so so
the result should be a magnitude faster
so the result should be a
magnitude faster okay
so
so here's a script
okay so let's actually so let's begin so
today today is 2021
november
9th okay
if you have a common questions good
morning alan
good morning ellen andrew so common and
questions posted love to see them okay
so so yeah so let's do
a language okay so uh let me start with
let me start the wolfram code i mean the
wolfram
uh desktop the mathematica so a new one
and one plus
one plus two
evaluate three that's good let's put
this window here
now so you can also see my keyboard
this is i mean so this video this is
kinesis advantage two red switches this
is ultimate hacking you go to search for
saudi keyboard and go buy it i have full
reviews and video and all that
uh and okay so that's so
how i operate a computer you see oh you
see i don't press any keys but i can
switch windows i talked about this many
times this is the very efficient way as
opposed to the
control tab you know wait where is the
control uh
wait alt tab you know the old tab
oops which one which one is it you know
that's silly so
so you see mouse operation now can i see
myself yes you see yeah you can see my
mouse so now
let's read up that
and let's
read of that let's begin okay let's
begin to the the code okay
so
uh
i'm using stuff like keys in emacs and
i'm using varia keyboard so you can see
here's a code now let's go to let's
change the file name okay so
um
let's change the file name so
let's say
wgrep okay
okay that's a file name w grab its
magnify and hide the you know and delete
the temp files so here's a file and open
it make a backup go to directory refresh
you see this is a backup file and now
let's change it
w grab one uh w grab two okay let's name
it that that
so right now these two are identical
files now
so the original i'm going to modify the
original and uh and
you know and you know i'm going to
modify the w grab 2.
so but first of all okay open this and
go to the powershell one key press we
are to the powershot windows powershell
and
first of all we want to test the script
works okay so
let's um
so we'll find script
file
wgrep one
and you need to give a pattern so what i
do we want to find uh let's let's say we
want to find haskar okay and what
directory the current directory okay
enter
so that prints
that prints let me magnify so that
prints every occurrence
of lines that contains the word haskell
so this is george's script so you can
see
here's the word haskell first of all it
prints the file name so in the file
topic nodes.html
so you have this one occurrence has got
syntax sucks why has got syntax sucks
and
so each line when it occurs you print it
but before you print the line number so
for example if we go to topic notes the
file and line 41401
we can we should see it so let's go to
open topic notes
and go to line four zero one
so four zero one
uh
wait so what oh four four zero one not
four one zero so four zero one so there
it is
so you can see
land design formal languages
complexities of grammar syntax algebra
why has got length syntax sucks so there
it is indeed it found it close it so you
see for each occurrence i mean for if it
occurs in a file first of all print the
file name then for each line it occurs
print the line and also print the line
number and repeat for every file so this
is the you know
what the script does okay
now let's begin the modification okay
let's so let's open the w grip two we um
we're gonna start to modify it
okay now the first line is sheban you
know shebang is a traditional unix um
way
to
to run a program without typing the
interpreter for example we
we typed woofam script that's a that's a
that's a
application that runs wolfram language
then we give option file then this is a
script then the argument to the script
but
alternatively you don't have to um
you know because if you have the sheep
ban line you can just say you know this
becomes like a unix program you don't
have to let's let's try it
yeah
okay so hold on a second so i think i
got a space inside right
yeah
okay so wait oh yeah so the the you see
this line needs to be the first line if
it's on the second line it doesn't work
it's called she ban okay look
look it up she ban this is a classic
unix stuff
okay so now let's save the file you see
i don't even i don't ever press save in
emacs because for example i change
something you can see the asterisk here
that means the file has been changed but
however when i whenever i switch window
you see it automatically saves so i
never press save so that's a another
efficient efficiency tip and you can
find the code in emacs by just searching
uh auto save xrd emacs autosave you can
find out how to do that
so that's the emacs tip okay so anyway
so back to the uh script let's do the
sheban
hey wait why is it um
the shebang is not working uh oh yeah
that's why that's the reason the shiban
line is not working because i'm not on
unix
i'm on windows with windows doesn't know
what the is the shebang
so
so you have to do it this way okay which
i which i prefer you know the shiban
line
is uh
it is a crime
you know it's it's it's not a good
design the unique they they
you know they love this slant you know
it's it's it's a hack okay it's a
extreme hack i would recommend if you
called in pearl ruby python never use
the shi line you know always
have the full interpreter in front okay
because that's a more functional there's
no implicit crap
you know what you you know you know
exactly what you are running not by
magic you know the magic line you know
magic line and magic characters by the
way the first two characters those are
called magic characters okay
uh okay i'm ready to digress okay not
not that so i'm ready to digress but i
want to show you quickly you know so you
can see the uni the wikipedia they talk
about sheban okay no good don't use that
okay so anyway
so back to powershell uh so i have two
instances of powershell running close
that one so
okay so you can see now the um script
works wait what happened okay enter
yeah so the script works so now we
modify it okay so i'm going to modify it
now
so on the pink window on the left you
can see all the commands i call in emacs
and all the keystrokes that corresponds
to it so for example moving cursor and
so on so you can you know once you know
the function name you can look it up
most of my functions is on my website
just search for it you'll find it
okay so the sheban line we don't need
okay so um well let's leave it okay so
so first of all uh it assigns the
executable so
okay this is gonna be
a long session because if i going i'm
going to explain everything then it's
gonna take a while uh one hour
let's see how long i've been 16 16
minutes already
i'm okay i'm going to try to do it fast
okay so
first of all
we are going to optimize these programs
but kind of
by trivial syntax syntactical way then
we are going to change the algorithm so
the whole thing right now you see it's
like uh 20 lines also the whole thing
should be one single line one single
line and the result should be much
faster so but first of all let's go
through a syntactical kind of the make
it faster by saying tactical means okay
so here you have the um
so the dollar sign something wufang
language every building symbol begin
with a capital letter okay and
or it begins with a dollar sign so this
is a building symbol and we can look it
up
so you can see script cannot script
command line
uh let's turn javascript so so we can
see the details okay
comments comments
hey hey diong
so
so you can see now you can see uh you
know this is the uh the documentation so
every building
symbol in wufang language either start
with a capital letter or start with a
dollar sign and by the way there's no
any other punctuation symbols it's just
pure english letters except you know the
dollar sign in front
so this is a building you know whenever
it's a dollar sign dollar sign something
that means it's a built-in variable or
in powershell the terminology is
automatic variable you know it's just a
variable predefined it has a meaning so
dollar script command line which returns
a list okay i can i can just tell you
what it returns it returns a list of
three things okay the first thing is the
uh program name the second string okay
the second thing is uh
uh okay it mod uh arc one okay the
second thing is arc one the third thing
is r2 and so on so it returns a list of
you know you know just like unix
dollar sign zero you know bash dollar
sign zero dollar sign one dollar sign
two in pearl and and also ruby because
this
pearl
bash pearl ruby they have the same
lineage
so anyway so so that's that so that's
what this returns okay so so command
line script command line that returns
you know the command name and arguments
then what is this um
okay
this is gonna take a long time if i keep
doing this uh so
so this part this part the double square
brackets
that's a shorthand syntax for
uh okay so let me explain expression
and when whenever you see this that's a
shorthand syntax for
n okay so these two things are
equivalent
syntactically equivalent that means
wufam language whenever c you know
before it runs does anything it changes
all your uh the whole source code it
transforms everything into a functional
form so this is a shorthand this is the
equivalent
100 percent equivalent
syntax okay so because
language it just transform everything
like that or the equal sign
uh or everything so basically in wolfen
language it's just like a lisp okay
everything should have this form
if let's magnify okay everything should
be
a
b
c
everything in the language is should be
this form and only there's no equal sign
there's no band there's no plus sign
there's no minus sign nothing okay
this is this is important because um
you know as you learn more wufam
language you are this is a a very
important thing i have a tutorial here
ufo language syntax i explained
so anyway just uh
everything should be this form any of
the a b c or f should be nested you know
arbitrary nested just like just like
lisp you know except least use
parentheses and uh in this you put the f
inside the parenthesis but in frame
language this is the form everything
there's no plus sign there's nothing
else so when we but there are many
shortcuts to film language syntactical
shortcuts building called meta
expression so
so whenever wu from language before it
compiles it transform everything like
that for example the
for example this equal sign so for
example let me give you an example this
line
let me copy it that line can be written
as
set okay
set executable to
part
okay
part then okay then
that
and one okay
so this line
let me turn on the global uh highlight
mod so this line is 100 equivalent to
that one you see so the the second one
is completely nested uh you know syntax
okay i actually i'm digressing i don't
want to talk about this so today i'm
just trying to uh
you know uh make this optimize this code
so let's do it again okay so so so
executable he he assigns the
you know
the executable file name which is the
this file you know w grab two that's
what it returns the first element of
that which is uh this this uh command uh
this script's name so this executable
variable is used only once once you see
so you don't you don't you so we don't
we don't we don't need it okay so since
it's only used one once let's just put
here
so
so and this part
so if so we have a if expression if if
expression takes three arguments the
first argument is a test so it tests if
the length of uh you know the arguments
pressure script is not equal to three
then print the usage okay that that's
you know what george says but you okay
so
so if takes three arguments so actually
uh the proper code you should have a
semi semicolon um
so if takes three argument the first
argument is a test if it's you know less
than three argument if it's not exactly
three arguments then print the usage
uh then it runs the second argument i
mean the oh wait um
yeah okay so
so so the first argument is that the
second argument is these three lines
together so you know if the if the test
is false if i mean if the test is not
equal to true to three it is true
then you print usage
so okay so let me show you an example so
let's call this again
let's magnify
okay so
let's say let's omit the directory
path okay you run it it says usage you
know
script name pattern path
so you know this part is called so
that's what that is doing
uh okay so i need to go actually faster
so so here the pattern so this program
takes a pattern you know has got what
you want to search so that that is what
this line does then this the third
argument is the file path so we which is
uh you know dot which is the current
directory
okay
then okay so those are lines are fine
because uh pattern you know we it's used
multiple times and okay
and okay so so now let's do this one
okay so here this one
uh this one is more complex
so let's so this line so what
okay so this line is actually defining a
function okay so it defines the function
at index
add indices
uh the argument is a list
and the function is this map index
function okay so you can see the
documentation map indexed
by the way i'm using you know i'm coding
wolfen language inside emacs and
because i'm using you know some woofer
mod so if you like my stuff buy it okay
so let me show you quick quickly
uh press the key so wait press the key
uh
okay so here's the source code here is
the documentation for woof and mod open
it
and you can see
about two thousand
something lines
in emac this and here is the beginning
of the file and you go to the url
showing browser so this is woof and mod
if you like it if you you know
interested in coding wufang language in
emacs
uh pay me okay i you know paypal me i i
tell you you know pay by me and i send
you
okay that's a woofham language mod okay
so close that so close that yeah close
that
close that okay so back to this line
this is a function uh and
and uh oh my god to explain the whole
thing will take an hour
so basically you know here is a defining
function named add indices and what it
does is that um
it takes a
list argument and uh
okay
well the easiest way let me explain the
easiest way is just actually run the
code okay so let's say x
abc okay a b
c so you can see what it's doing
so i paste so you see
this is a list abc and map index is just
like map in normal languages except you
also give the indices as the second
argument
so let's just run that so you can see
now abc becomes 1a 2b 3c so those
numbers are the position or index of you
know index of the each element so that's
what the map index do and this part is
just a shortcut for this is a shortcut
syntax for function so this is a
function
that
that you know the the the pound
one
symbol means the first argument
the pound two symbol means the second
argument so it returns at least you can
see it returns this
list where the first
argument i mean the first element of the
list
is this thing
so that means take the first
element of the
second part
which is the index number so you know um
oh my god it should explain the whole
thing it's gonna take one more day it's
gonna take an hour i
uh so any any comments uh so is script
command line one indexed
uh
no
well well yes yes you know you know
basically in wolfram language everything
is one indexed but it's it's a bit
tricky okay so
it's a bit tricky but you can see okay
so let's do this okay so let's say
so here we want to write a function okay
so map index the first argument is a
function so
let's say so the function and let's say
two arguments okay so x and y okay then
let's just say return themselves x and y
so you run it so you can see
the map index map this function to that
the list abc and the result is this each
one is um
you know a then bracket one
why bracket because um
because in ufam language usually a list
is usually arbitrarily nested unlike
most other languages ruby python perl
javascript typically
even in lisp typically the list is just
flat you know but in wufang language is
like almost every every expression is
like arbitrary
arbitrary really nested list so how do
you give a index to arbitrary element in
a nested list well you
you give a list
a list of indices so
so if you have you know if you have a
flat
list then
you just you just need an integer you
know one is the first element two is the
second element and so on but if you have
a nested list then you say
you give several indices you know the
first index is the first level then
you know the for example the first
element
then the second element of that result
then the seventh element of that result
so several indices you know which means
take take the element consecutively
so in general
any element in a
tree you know in arbitrary net
arbitrarily nested list
you can they each each element has a
specific
position you don't call them index
anymore a position so the position is a
list of in list of integers just like
this
so because now abc is a flat tree that's
why you have you know just
you know one two three but otherwise so
so
so okay so that's about the position of
a list okay so but um
but so the question whether wufang
language is zero index or one indexed
it's a bit
in general it's just one index okay one
index unlike other languages just like
all mathematical languages they are all
one index however the zeroth index
refers to the head of expression okay
i'm digressing a big time so so let me
show you okay so
uh so okay hold on a second let me let
me show you what the whole deal is about
the position about the zero index or the
first index uh so we don't want to take
take we don't we we
we want um
[Music]
okay let's let's use this position okay
so i'm going to show you
x equals to
uh a b
c okay except b is nested okay b1 b2
okay so here we have a list okay x is
that kind of nested list so now we use
the function position
okay position
then you want to say position
x okay and what element you want to find
you want to find the element b1 i want
to know what is the position of let's
say a okay show it so that is the
position of a which is the first element
okay what about the position of b1 how
do you what you know you do that so
here's the position so that means it's a
second element then the first element of
that so you see the second element
then the first element of that
okay so
so
this is very interesting okay okay yeah
but we're gonna continue so
so but what about zero so so what about
um
what about um part okay so let me show
you another thing okay so
let's say i want to take the part the
first element
of the
of the expression x okay
so that gives you a as expected what if
i say second element that gives you b1
and b2 as expected
third element is c of course now what if
you say zero
that's interesting so when you say 0 it
will actually return this these whole
things ahead which means list okay so
you see because
why is that because
because let me show you the full form of
x
so you see the expression we typed here
this list you know you know a b 1 b 1 c
there's the full syntax is actually this
so
this is a this is a general um form of
any expression in wufang language any
just like i mentioned before
so
when you have this expression
a
the index the position of a is one
the position of
of the second element is this thing list
b1 b2
the and the third one is c what about
the index zero so the index zero refers
to you see the whole the head
which is this list okay now this is very
this is kind of advanced but it's very
fundamental you know if you program you
know with language seriously you have to
know this
so that's about the index issue in
general you don't you know
unless you become very advanced you
don't use the index zero so like it's
very rare
it's very rare
uh to have the need to extract the you
know zeroth element
okay so okay okay
i i digress all the time that's the
nature of structure so let's go back to
so i want so so we showed the map
indexed
so okay i want to explain so here so you
know
so here is a function
that
that basically take the list as argument
and
create
returns at least with the index in front
why we need to why do we need to that do
that because we are going to read the
file and split a lot
split or lines into a list
when we print lines of occurrence we
need to know the line number so that's
why you know
this is doing you know add indices
uh you know the
yeah so okay so
so this function this is definition of a
function but there's a much better way
to do it so what this function does
actually
you are looking at you are actually
looking
at symbolic pattern matching
so this is this is a very common way to
define a function but actually the full
form let me let me show you what this
actually is
so when you have x
when you have something okay let's say
two so what that means the full form of
that is actually this okay set
delayed okay so let me type it x two
so
so this line is actually 100
equivalent to this this line
syntactically
so now
with the full function name you can
actually now understand what it is doing
it's actually
when you do this x colon equals to
something it's actually creating a rule
it's telling mathematica it's telling
wufam language that whenever
whenever the expression on the left hand
side occurs
replace it with the one on the right
hand side you see we are we are defining
a rule to uh language
so the left hand side can be not just a
symbol it can be arbitrary expression
you know it can be like
arbitrary the right hand side again can
be arbitrary so once you tell wufam
language to set up this rule set delay
then when whenever it runs computation
whenever it sees the left hand side
pattern it will just replace it by right
hand side so this is very interesting
because you know you are looking at you
are seeing the
the wolfram engine how it does
computation the a big part of it that
that is symbolic pattern matching
so on on a surface on a surface this
looks like oh you are just defining a
function that's correct
but however however the way the way the
function works is very different from
typical languages
you know it's it's actually defining a
rule replacement rule you know symbolic
pattern replacement rule so
so so here i explained this you know x
equals to 2.
so what about what about this what is
this doing so it this is telling wufam
language that whenever you see something
you know
that says add indices you know a symbol
add indices followed by a bracket
then
whatever inside so that's a you know
underscore that means a blank that means
whatever
so add indexes bracket whatever you know
what you know can be one thousand
characters long whatever you know
pattern or list or whatever
so whenever it's telling from language
whenever you see that replace it by that
okay that's so that's what it doing
now but
but
using pattern matching is in general a
lot slower you know
patent imaging is very powerful uh when
especially when you do graphics it's
very powerful because without pattern
matching
you know this is one single line but
sometimes with for for some occasions
for some tasks
without using pad imaging you you're
gonna require a hundred lines or more
you know
so pattern matching is extremely
powerful but usually it's ten times
slower very slow so alternatively
we can define this function at indices
without using pattern matching so let me
show you how to do that okay
so instead of doing that um
so we
okay so let's do that okay so let's
let's uh let's write this without
pattern matching okay so
so let me write it function
um
function uh list okay so
so this is how you do it without pattern
matching
you see that underscore that means
pattern matching but here we don't have
patterns at all
so what this one does
in fact we can actually uh
clarify this part too so let's
not use the shorthand function i mean
let's not use the shorthand
let's write um
let's write this way okay x y
okay returns a list of two things the
first thing is
y
and the second things
is x okay so this part and this part are
exactly the same well not exactly but
it's getting details but anyway they are
the same okay so
so but the second part you see the first
part the this line is kind of a
shorthand so we the first time you
called wufang language you know what the
is that you don't know but the
second the second one full
full form syntax you know it's easy to
see what's doing so it's a function you
know this function is just like lisps
lambda okay so it's basically lambda so
it takes two arguments x y x and y
and the second argument is is what it
returns the body of the lambda so it
returns at least
the first element is the first part of y
the second element is x
so that's what that is so now we can
compact the whole thing so this
so this uh this line
becomes uh
that okay the add indices so it's a
function so
now we can comment out the first one
now we can comment out the first one and
go back to shell and let's run it to
check if it runs okay so we are coding
wgrep2 the new version
so it still works so you can see
these two are equivalent
okay
so now
we did this okay so actually so so you
see in this code there's a lot pattern
matching going on so actually
um
so you can see and you know this
underscore whenever you see underscore
you know that's a pattern matching
this is again pattern matching and this
is more complicated pattern matching so
this one for example
this line is telling with a language
that remember the colon equal that says
you know create a pattern create a rule
such that whenever wolfen language sees
the left hand side
replace it by the right hand side you
know so in a sense in essence it defines
a function but it needs not to be that
way so let me let me do another example
of rewriting this without pattern
matching okay
so you just uh
so so so you just say that okay so again
you say function here
function
function takes two arguments the first
argument is uh parent parameters the
second argument is body okay so the
first argument is number and contents
okay so
okay so this is how you do
so this function and this function are
kind of
semantically equivalent except this way
of implementation does not require
pattern matching okay so let's comment
out this
let's um
let's
let's comment out that line
and run the code again
uh you see it runs actually we screwed
up something because the output is
is different
uh what did i
oh yeah so uh wait
okay so yeah i made a mistake oops so
you see this pattern this is actually
this function actually only have one
argument
you see that list number content that's
actually one argument it's not two
arguments so here our function is wrong
so
it should be let's just say x okay so x
is the argument so
and the print the
x okay the argument
then the first part of the argument okay
then x the argument
okay the second part of the argument
okay now
coming out this line let's run it again
you see now it works like before
so
so what i showed is that you know you
can see let's shrink a little bit
let's shrink
so you can see
these two lines are equivalent
semantically the same
is a different way to implement same
thing without pattern magic okay now
let's delete the first one
now likewise we can rewrite each
and every of these functions uh but we
are not going to i'm not going to
because um it takes
you know
because i we have a lot of things to do
okay so we already
oh we already it's 44 minutes 40
minutes already
we have a lot to do um actually
um
wow uh so let's see what are we saying
so uh it's a good question yeah so
should sell video course
uh true so listen to dion
video course well uh
well
you know thank you guys for donation but
that's kind of what i'm doing now um you
know so
and other people who are not you know
who are watching my youtube offline
can donate
and also woof and lang you know woofam
uh incorporated they are sponsored you
know they are
uh they are sponsored by my videos so i
should say that
okay so let's continue so let's continue
um so what so what is a plan so i'm
going to
yeah we would we we do want to optimize
the code so let me just do quickly okay
i did some i did the explanation now
let's let me just rewrite these lines of
code so that it does not use pattern
matching because path imagine makes your
code 10 times slower
so once we do that
then
i'm going to rewrite the whole thing
i mean you know improve the whole code
by using a different algorithm because
the whole
thing you know grab grip a bunch of
files only it should be one single line
okay so but let me quickly rewrite the
patterns okay so
uh
so so here we have uh text so text um
add indices so
so again let me use the function form
uh i want to so okay so let me quickly
rewrite this lines function by uh
without pattern matching okay so wait uh
so add indices now this add indices is
actually just a function so add index is
a function
so let's actually
put that
so wait what is this doing add indices
so okay so let me explain what is this
um
slash slash okay so slash slash whenever
you have something like this a slash
slash b
where a and b can be any expression okay
so that means
that just means
ba okay
so this is a
so the slash so the slash slash b a
slash b is a shorthand for this so it
just means
call the function b with ao's argument
so this is a postfix
notation just like the unix pipe okay
the unix vertical line that's that's
what this slash slash is
okay so um
so uh so let me yeah i want to quickly
uh finish uh
rewriting this
so we can move on
okay so so um you know this is one way
to do it okay but that's kind of uh
verbose
um
wait okay so wait that's not that's not
right
i think this is okay
what are we doing split string
springs split string okay so let's
[Music]
so
so this function mostly is going to
split string
then
so split string given a text
a giant string you want to split by
returns or you know line return or the
you know windows convention or unix
convention
uh it it returns a list
then once you have a list you
okay let's just do it then let's just do
it in this this way
uh there there's a lot of ways to make
this much shorter but let's not worry
about that let's just do it okay
so comment this out let's
test it see if it still works
i know it
where did i up
god what what did i
add in this is
uh which one is this what what is the
operator precedence i need to know
yeah okay so the right hand side stays
on the right hand side
uh
okay so let's just do this
this is
argument what
no um okay so i can actually
oh yeah text that's why text not lines
yeah so i got the
i got the weight
so function
one argument function of one argument
you
and the body is split string okay so
yeah
then you want to add indices so yeah so
this this will be
applied to the second part okay so
it's gonna be like that
yeah
so there
shrink
so
delete so this line and this line are
the same
and further we can you know you see this
function you see
let me explain this okay so whenever you
have function
x
body
whenever you have something like that
there's a shorthand but by the way the
full form is actually
so this is a function so this is how you
write a function okay so the function
the first takes two argument the first
argument is at least the parameters so
you say a list and it can be x y if you
have two arguments or z three arguments
or a one you know four arguments and so
on
the second part is body in the body
whatever is the first part will be
replaced in the body
once you give it give it a argument such
as three okay now
so this is the full form to define a
function now there's a shortcut so
because the list whenever you have a
list
there's a
shorthand syntax which is with the
uh
curly braces that's a shorthand so this
line
is exact exactly the same as this line
but however we can we can shorten it
further by
by by hold on second let me
by shortening it further by um
by
by by by just by just this okay
by just that ampersand
sign how this works in the body
for every argument to represent the
first argument you say part one one okay
to represent the second argument you say
pound one two
so
okay so
so we are going to rewrite this function
by by a shorthand so let's see
so first of all
remove that okay so we're gonna rewrite
this function by a shorthand we don't
need the argument text anymore so just
say pound pound means
the first argument and at add a
ampersand
so
so these two lines are again the same
okay now if you're just a beginning
wufang language user you don't have to
worry about you know because of this
shorthand syntax is kind of
cryptic you know so
if you just begin you can just write
everything in the full you know full
symbol name and square bracket that
makes it much easier to understand
but as you go on the shorthand is
extremely powerful because it compact
your code
so what i'm saying so so you are seeing
you know these two lines are identical
okay so these two lines are identical
uh and
and
and now we
you know since all these lines are then
identical let's comment that out
and comment
so so we can see
how the progression of
of of you know simply
find the code so this line becomes this
line
you know this line pattern matching
pattern matching becomes this line
without pattern matching and becomes
this line more approached
so we can comment out the first one
back to powershell run the code run it
works as before
so now remove that okay so now we also
need to uh do this again so this one
how long have i been talking is it
boring a structured course like the
stuff on ken academy
we have time carry on okay so so so
right now it's uh
one hour already
okay so now i'm going to rewrite this
line without pattern matching okay so
let me just go faster
so uh let's rewrite that line with
without pad imagine so
so text is the argument where does text
occur so text occurs there so
so what this does is um
so it's calling select select text two
arguments
so select text two arguments select
basically select
the first argument is whatever
expression you want to select for it's a
list okay the second argument is
is a function
that whenever the function returns true
then return it so the select
function in language is like filter in
python or other languages okay
so it takes a list and a function it
returns
it it kind of reduces the list only when
the function returns true so you can you
can see here is using the shorthand for
the function
so again the full uh the full form for
the function would be
would be like this okay the full form
for the function would be
actually x
the full form for the function would be
that okay so these two are kind of the
same
but um
[Music]
what am i doing i'm kind of like
wasting um so let's
okay let's finish this
so you want to
select us a function so yeah um okay the
easiest way is actually just
okay i actually i'm kind of um
actually this will just work okay so
let's just put here um and text okay so
function two argument the easiest way to
transform is this okay so that will work
so
this line
these two lines are equivalent okay
semantically
not syntactically but semantically the
first one is using pattern matching the
second is without using pattern matching
okay so let's come in now the first one
and let's go back to
uh
to the console and see if it works
yeah it works
okay so so far we have removed and okay
one more so here again it's a pattern
matching so let's okay let me do this
real quick so let's just uh you know now
we just do this
so the file okay so the file yeah so
okay that's it
so now you don't use pattern matching uh
so
oh but i forgot the original so where is
the original so you can see
here's the original okay so this you
know this part
with pattern matching with that file we
don't have it here now we just change it
to
a function here
okay and one another thing interesting
about wufang language is that you see
typically in programming languages you
have like the indentation right this is
typical you know very typical how you do
programming you know you need to indent
you know you need to indent correctly in
order to see that's not
idiom that's not how you do things in
ufam language you know actually uh you
need a semicolon here okay so you need a
semicolon
that's necessary okay so the way you do
typically you do in wolfram language is
like this one single line okay now
if you copy this in wolfram notebook
it format for you automatically so if
your window is wide it's one you know
you know if it
is
it format
for you automatically
you know if your window is short it
format this way with indentation or that
if you
your window is wide it should format
this way and it adds a line break here
why because the semicolon okay
there's another thing interesting what
what is the thing with semicolon let me
explain remember wolfram language
everything is this form okay everything
every expression is purely this form
nothing else
comma square brackets and english
letters
so
what the is semicolon let me
explain so whenever you have semicolon
a b or c okay whenever you have that
let's simplify it let's just say a and b
okay a semicolon b whenever that occurs
where a and b is any arbitrary long
expression can be 1 000 lines okay so
whenever you have that the that's a
short syntax for this okay
um
that's the short syntax for these okay
so you see a semicolon b that is
actually
the short syntax for
for this function compound expression
and what does that mean
that is the same as
uh as lisps
prog
progn
that means just you know that means okay
evaluate all the arguments okay so let
me show this here okay so if you have a
b and c
so if you have a b and c that just means
that okay
so whenever you have a compound
expression that means evaluate each of
the argument
but return
return only the last argument
okay that's what it means so semicolon a
you know a7 column b just means evaluate
both but return only b do not return you
know
uh do not return anything you know about
a
so
so if we if we look at the expression
here the if uh what
okay so
you know just like this is often used in
if
okay
so for example this uh this is too long
okay so
anyway so so so what i my point is if
you have a b c right this is a if
expression
a is test b is what you return if true c
is what you return it force so
but what if your b is a lot of complex
complicated things so that's when you do
b1 semicolon b2 semicolon b3 and so on
so in same you know same thing with this
you know same thing with uh one
for example uh equal
3 4
you see that progn
that means if you do
you know if you need let's say message
print this
and if you have more than one message
print that
make it pretty fine so you see the
product is like it's like c
curly braces it
groups a bunch of expressions into one
and returns only the value of the last
expression so
you know so in wufang language it's the
same
it's almost exactly the same you see
that's why i say wu family you know
wufam language is uh based on lisp and
apl it's essentially a lisp
with you know with a different syntax
and uh
and meta expression
so okay so let's go back to so so that's
about this if so that's about the
semicolon you know again the semicolon
is you know just compound expression now
another thing interesting to notice is
that you know in the woof in lisp for
example
you know you have you know you
now we are looking at the naming of
functions you know different philosophy
of how you name functions so in
in this in general in this they usually
name their functions fully
but still in some cases you have like
like uh
mysterious function names like p r p r o
g n you know that kind of stands for
program
you know like program and and
n programs you know
but in wolfram language they also fully
name their function but
but actually more expressive so by
looking at the thing the function name
compound expression you know what it
does
you know
so this
so it goes uphill language goes one step
beyond
beyond the uh full you know full naming
the fully you know full naming of
function names even beyond this this
this is pretty you know pretty full name
as compared to for example uh python or
c c the worst
c is what's the unix you know like
cryptic names like you don't know what
they're doing but by in foreign language
if you know the function name you know
what it does
almost
okay so that's the digestion about the
shorthand syntax which is very uh
important okay so let's remove that
remove that remove that okay so now we
back to the code
the whole thing so now we don't have uh
we don't have pattern matching anymore
uh let's remove that so we have
rewritten the whole code without any
panda matching so let's run it one last
time to see if it works it works
so okay but how does this code work
you know we haven't explained uh the
whole thing but how does it work let me
explain okay
given
a
the path
and a string pattern
print
open every file in the the
if
the file
content contains the pattern
print
the line
that
occurs and print a line number in front
okay that's essentially what the whole
program does
so
first of all you have the you know the
pattern which is the argument the path
the directory root path then
this add indices function
[Music]
add the line number basically first of
all you know it add line number to a
list
then here is the lines you know um
you given the text file you split it
into a list of lines so that's what this
function does lines
the match lines is another function
given a giant string which is the
content of the text file it selects
certain lines
okay then here's a print lines function
then the whole thing then
print if match then basically at the end
you have
file system so let's press one key and
see you know the documentation profile
system scan file system scan is
basically a map okay see takes two
arguments the first argument is a
function the second argument is a file
path so it will apply the function to
every file in the file path so that's
what it does so it applies the print
match function to every file in the in
the you know
given path
then
what does printmatch do printmatch uses
all the functions before to basically
print lines
with the line number okay but the whole
thing
can be done in just
two lines okay
except you know with this you know the
the help documentation that's one line
then basically the rest is one single
line uh and it would be much more
efficient you know we can you know we
can actually test the efficiency by
measuring the time uh by trying a
different directory with thousands of
files but
we are not going to do that so it's now
seven minutes um okay
so now what we're gonna do so
i'm going to
we can either stop now
or
i can try to um
you know create the optimized version
um
so let's see what's the comments
i
want you in
uh
coffee so i'm going um
yeah i'm drinking power drink energy
drink
uh
so dion says
is it realistic to have e-list functions
run wolfram
programs
that depends on what you mean but right
now i'm
this is the emac this function that runs
this program so for example
if you look at the um
you know the ping window so i'm going to
call the command okay yeah let me show
you how how this works
let's show let's open a new file okay so
new file save it
let's save it okay save it xx dot wl
okay
so
now let's say uh one plus three plus
two okay
so
let's let's do something more fancy okay
abc okay let's say
um
let's say map
so i'm going i'm gonna do something
fancy okay so
that i'm gonna write a lambda at one
then map that lambda to this list okay
so this should return at least a plus
one b plus one c plus one symbolically
that's a point that's another uh very
unusual characteristics of wufam
language
so we are applying a function
which add one to the argument
to and we map that function to a list
abc symbols they are not numbers so we
should get the result a plus one b plus
one c plus one is at least okay so now
we run the code
so now this is um invalid syntax in
order in what
oh yeah so so that typo okay so this
should be a add sign
slash ad yeah so run it
so this is all in emacs so you can see
the output at the bottom
can you magnify the output okay so what
okay so we need to
show the output so you can see the
output is here
so you can see
this this is interesting okay so let's
show this in the wolfram notebook
because uh
so you see in other languages you cannot
do this
by the way let me just show you the full
form okay so
this full form and meta syntax meta
meta expression is very interesting so
we i explained that throughout this
video but let me do it one more time
okay so the full form for the above is
like this okay map two arguments the
second argument is a function i mean
it's a list okay so list
okay so this part this abc is equivalent
to that
that thing okay so now the first part is
the function
uh function okay so the function again
at least one argument x
and here you just say x uh plus that's a
full form for the plus sign uh x
one so you see this line is one hundred
percent syntactically equivalent to the
first line because when wu fan language
sees the first line
the first thing it does is it to
transform it to the to the full form
which is what you see here
so you can now you can understand the
whole thing very clear so map takes two
from uh wait map takes two functions
you know the first function is the first
i mean takes two arguments the first one
is a function the second one is a list
okay so now if we run the code you'll
compute it twice okay so you can see
uh you see it returns that twice
uh and if you if we change this to uh
three four five
and run it
you can see the answer four five six
okay so that's the power of symbolic
computation now in
most languages you can you can you can
add you cannot add one to a b c you'll
say oh a is not defined arrow b is not
defined c is not defined
so this is symbolic so let me now let me
show you the power of pattern matching
so let's see so let's say i have this
expression i want
i want to replace a by a by
1 b by 2 c by 3 let's say okay so what
how you do that you can do it this way
okay so a so this is a by 1
b by 2
c
by 3 okay let's say let's replace c by
pi over
four okay
run it
fantastic
the power of symbolic
computation
now it's pretty you know you know you
see wufang language and this this is
also symbolic but can this do this no
this
um
you know that's that's one of my
complaints about dispersed these
phonetics
they could easily do all these but they
you know they they you know they don't
they don't listen first of all uufam
language is not open source
so that immediately shut off
what you know shut off fulfillment
language in front of these open source
phonetics eyes like they don't see it
they are they are blind to it because
they only stick with the open source
they heard oh wufang language because i
say super language is fantastic oh but
it's not open source oh they are
not gonna you know they don't want to
hear anything about it so they close
that they close their they probably they
put a blindfold to your their eyes they
don't they don't no no they don't know
nothing
they stick with linux linux and bash
so
now you get you see you got this
symbolic expression and also you see
let's uh
and also let's uh let's actually
now let's replace let's do again replace
pi
by
by pi squared okay i mean by square root
of pi okay
okay
do it you see now you are seeing
type setting
not the tech and latex
you know backslash slash quality quotes
you know
crap it's automated
automated type setting you as you are
looking at now if you want the numerical
result
uh the by the way the
the percentage sign is a shorthand for
okay let me show you what that another
shortcut okay
so percentage sign
percentage
sign
one is shorthand syntax shorthand for
output one okay so these two are exactly
identical okay that means the last
output you know the you know so let me
run it okay percentage one or percentage
is the same thing so so that means the
last output
now we apply again a shortcut we talked
about slash slash n
so what does slash slash means that's a
postfix notation that's just the same
same like the unix
uh pipe okay n means numerical give a
numerical result so that so you got that
so the full form if you want to run the
full thing
you what you can do is this
okay so that that's what you do so let
me
copy
let me run it
run it
so
run it same thing okay oh yeah what why
do i run it twice because i wanted to
show you
the input form so you can type that and
look at oh yeah you can see my press a
button
you have the standard phone press the
button you have the input form
well actually input from yeah and let me
show you another form okay
so you have that expression you want to
say hold then you want to say uh full
form
so we've been talking full form all this
while so
so now you can actually see the full
form you see
the purely nested syntax
uh
you know you don't have like what is a
slash what is this slash slash what is
this
plus sign you know that's not
that's not
the you know fully nested brackets so
but you say full form
you get these
fully completely nested brackets just
you know
um
okay
i think i i'm gonna stop now
there's no
if uh fifa so emacs and wufang language
can only communicate
via share process okay so the way how
okay back to that question so
so you see i can run this
i can run this by pressing two keys so
the actual command is this one
run wolfram script print all so
okay so let's uh in emacs let's say
describe key
and let's show the function so here is a
function the documentation for the
console run
wolfram script.o so it's in
ufo mod let's go to the definition so
here is the definition of
of sardine wolfram script print all
and it basically called sao from script
you know it
it just called the function cassandra
frame script the emax function with the
argument print o
okay printer is feed to the wolfram
script script
because when you run a file in a console
sometimes you want to print other
results sometimes you don't so
so anyway so this it's not real woofing
script print all is a wrapper to someone
from script with the additional option
you know print print print or
expressions in the in the file so so but
so okay so if we go back if we go to the
wolfram script definition
here is a code
uh you know just like 20 lines of emac
bisp so basically it's calling a share
command
uh not very
not complicated so it's it's at the end
this is uh the gist okay so emax
function shell command then gives the
command string
which is
you know which is exactly um you know
basically like this wefan script then
dash file then whatever the script name
in the buffer
then
uh possibly options actually i don't
support options anyway
so this is how
emacs can call
wufan language uh in via xiao
and you can also get output of course
for example if i do
i don't have it well i don't have it
written that way but you can
you can have emacs return the output
like print you know paste it here if you
want to
so
one way to communicate with with wolfram
language in emacs is via shell you know
and and then you call from script
basically no that's not the only way the
the way wufang language works is that
whenever it doesn't matter it's a
mathematica or firm script or wolfram
engine doesn't matter what
it
basically there's an engine called
kernel with a
mathematical kernel or wolfram engine
that actually does the computation then
you have things such as wolfram script
or front end that talks to it even in a
notebook so the notebook for example
when i run some expression
it's actually sending the input to the
wolfram engine
in the case in this case it's woofam
kernel
so
anyway so the way wufang language works
is that you have the engine or kernel
and you have the front end the front end
can be a notebook or the other you know
offense script whatever so
whenever you do computation it
sends the input to the wolfram kernel
then the kernel responds like a server
okay so the kernel can be remote or
local in in my case it's local but it
can be remote for example you can see
here start kernel local or um it can be
remote you know if you buy wolfram cloud
uh
you know and you can also create kernel
you can also connect to multiple kernels
like cannot connect to like parallel
computation like ufam
has that you know if you are you know a
scientist you know if you are nasa
designing rockets you can have things
run in one 1000 kernels
things like that okay so the way wufram
language works is that there's a kernel
there's a front end or whatever you know
the interface so they talk via a
protocol called
uh used to called math link but now it's
called wufam language protocol or
something
so
if if i want to i can make my emacs
you know you you know like i can call
from language functions within emacs
without
without using the shell without going
through the shower or frame script i can
you know talk to the wolfram kernel
directly so that's um so let me let's
show uh okay
so it the old man the old name is math
link okay so but now
um
okay the old name is math link but now
they call wolfram language protocol i
think
that's the protocol for yeah there wstp
wufan symbolic transfer protocol very
marketing friendly
firm symbolic
transfer protocol so you can see it
supports c
c plus plus
it supports you know java
dot net
microsoft.net you know so you can
i can do that you know if but
you know if i want to if i really want a
nice robust interface i can
do that but xiao is good enough
um you know so you they also have uh wsp
services in clients you know woofing
engine wolfram server will find desktop
notebook uh
you know and ufm cloud and so on
okay i think that's it um yeah
so
i think we talked actually we talked
long we can actually
yeah the whole thing this script can be
made into
george is gonna pissed georgie is gonna
be pissed tomorrow he says that's how
you did one hour the video you got you
did two hours but you didn't improve my
program
[Laughter]
but yeah but okay
you know you know yeah next time you
know
but tomorrow i think i'm gonna try to do
something else some emac this because
yesterday it's also ufam language you
know in the past few videos it's open
language so
tomorrow or
um i'm gonna try to do something emacs
let's go back to emac this
so
some another day i'm gonna you know try
to do this but um
yeah maybe you know i'm just doing this
for fun
so thank you guys for watching any more
questions two more minutes we shut down
yeah so
you know if i'm you know to write a you
know emac this if i if i try to write
communication with you know wolfram
symbolic transfer protocol
you'll be involved you know it's not
gonna be trivial you
know
it's not gonna you know i need to
you know maybe if they
i don't know well
i'm not gonna do it you know right now
it works with uh you know why
why do i have you know i don't need it i
don't need it right now
uh
but yeah but this is the real i mean if
you really want to do something serious
for example if some company out there
want to hire me give me a you know give
me a
few thousand dollars you know i i'll
write this you know i'll write this in
emac this well by the way in python for
the for
you people who are using python or ruby
this is already uh written okay so
for example python um
julia or you know this already people
have written you know using the
to allow python ruby or c to communicate
with wolfram language this already you
know for example what's a notebook
what's uh
julia right julia notebook let's see
confusing with the language julia
uh not julia what's uh what what's the
pluto no not pluto what's um
[Music]
did i miss any questions
yeah that's it for today so bye guys
if you like my stuff okay
you can donate uh
buy my emacs tutorial buy my wolfram
cassava mod for emacs and uh
uh you know other things you know paypal
or patreon
jupiter okay jupiter there it is so
j-u-p-y-t-e-r
so jupiter notebook uh actually we want
we want the jupiter and the mathematica
interface
yeah so there you go so you go to the
this is wufam research
github
so wolfen language kernel for jupiter
notebooks so
so let me mention one more time okay so
you go to um you go to sardi
you know star code you know saudi.info
you go to
ufam language
then
you you know this is my past videos then
you go to you download wufam language
for free
then you can learn about the difference
between wufam language mathematica or
from engine what frame script you know
kind of confusing you can learn what
they
are then
you know if you download from engine you
know it's a freebie it comes with
wolfram script
like you know like this what we have
been using today
but it does not supports graphics i i
didn't show any graphics today but it
doesn't you know it doesn't
yeah let me show you one more thing okay
about wolfram script
so wufram script you can say integrate
okay so
integrate x over 2 x okay
so enter
so you can see it
supports
type setting but in a cd ascii way so
let's do something more complex expand
so this is
right now we are doing mathematics
x squared y third power
okay so you expand the whole thing to
three
let's run it
you see so actually so can we do this uh
yeah let's do some let's add some pie
and fancy stuff
let's square root pie let's see what we
got
so you got this fancy you know
kind of silly ascii type setting but if
you do you know but if you have this in
wolfram notebook
then it's pretty you know let's let's
shrink
so you see you got this pretty uh again
it's automatic for automatic formatting
you see depending on window width and
it's it's fantastic okay it beats the
tech and la tech the
you know the tech geekers of the unix
um
school
and you don't have to learn all the
syntax you know the backslash whatever
and
so what what is my point so yeah so you
yeah so you download wolfram engine
it comes with wolfram script then you
get this you know you get this
which is not so nice but you can install
you go install julia
uh where yeah you go install julia
notebook then you install you know the
you know you you know you look around
they have documentation you install the
you know the the interface then then you
can display graphics
in
julia notebook yeah
okay bye guys