hello hello good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of EX talk
show today we are going to uh do emac we
are going to demo we are going to beat
Vim emac versus Vim we are going to demo
a keyboard markal that uh moreo
challenged me okay so let me show you so
here's me here's my keyboard gl8
ultimate hacking keyboard NLEA track
ball
uh and uh you can check out my website I
have reviews on them and video reviews
and now let's go let's do let's do the
emac mar okay so the problem so here is
Moo so he's a Vim user you know he
challenges me to create let me show you
the problem okay copy uh if if you are
here say hi love to see your comments if
you are watching offline
uh skip around and play at
1.2 uh you know 1.5 speed okay so make
sure you can see my screen so here are
the um you know here are the my text so
this is emac and the pink window shows
all all my command Calles and the key
strokes for example you can see the
command name on the right side and the
key stroke on the left side okay I don't
press control keys I'm using sunfly keys
uh and I'm using for example cut that
block of text undo it you can see the
command name on the right and the key
stroke on the left and then UND do I'm
using Sly keys and I'm using uh a verac
layout okay so let me show you my sof FL
keys so here's a source code go to the
top go here and open it and show in
browser Sly Keys the most efficient key
binding system for emac
uh and here's a video demo and I'm going
to use C keys to beat Vim okay in cly
Keys when you use S keys for with emac
you have less key strokes and you do
more and we're going to show
that hello Mo so here's the chall Here
Comes The
Challenger okay so so s keys and I'm
using a v keyboard Okay so remember now
actually so let me magnify this um this
window so we have because we're going to
count keystrokes we're going to do this
task and we're going to count keystrokes
and to see who uh who can you know like
do the most uh let's move this window to
here shall
we uh okay hold on a second let's do
preparation so again if you are watching
this offline uh skip around okay okay so
let's put this
here what keyboard do you recommend
under 100 uh that would be expose okay
let me answer that
question uh yeah under 100 that would be
Expos the most F fantastic okay so you
just search for S keyboard blog and you
go to the ergonomic section so you see
this collection of ergonomic keyboards
and Expos this is what I
recommend uh they have different
versions okay so depending on you have
to check with uh their website to see
which one is available but one of them
was the uh light is
9900 exactly so you
know uh so I recommend this one uh and
uh yeah I'd recommend that one the most
okay about
$100 okay so let's show the problem
let's get down to the uh let's see uh
where do I put
the you see I need to show the key
strokes as I as I solve this
problem uh okay so let's just let's just
put this narrow in
uh okay where do I put uh let's see
because if it's like that then you
cannot
[Music]
see
um okay
I what to do here okay let's just let's
just put it there okay let's just put it
there like that okay so the problem uh
the problem is you have lines like that
1 two 3 uh up to up to 1 1,000 okay you
have uh lines like that up to 1,000 you
have to create these lines okay you have
to create this text once you created
that then you you want to swap the lines
swap every two lines so instead of one
two you're going to be 21 then instead
of 3 four you got be 43 and up to you
know 1,000 and uh then
999 so first of all you have to do
whatever you can to create these lines
you know originally the problem was just
swap the lines but Mo thought that you
know he's going to create it more
difficult so that I cannot do it in emx
but I can do it with less key strokes
than beam okay and no control keys okay
no press control
keys No meta no like hold this and do
that you know so let's begin okay so let
me start okay let me just do it quickly
so okay so let's begin now let's start
to count okay uh switch 1 two 3 4 line
and uh okay then you need the number
okay
um okay that okay and and and do that
and that okay I made a mistake [ __ ] okay
Enter
CLE
then um then actually I [ __ ] up okay
then let's say command
V 1,000 okay
1,000 then let's try paste it there it
is okay and uh okay then
you so that's how many what seven key
strokes something like that then you um
then you want to add the line numbers
okay so there are many ways to do that
so one okay so let's one key strokes
okay two
keystrokes three four
keystrokes five keystrokes okay then
we're going to five okay then we're
going to add the numbers so that would
be uh let's see if I remember my keys
correctly one
two
three uh that's the wrong key okay don't
count that let's do it again uh 1 two
3 okay there it is actually it's a
mistake because well anyway so you got
the line numbers and
uh okay that's that's how many that's
four key strokes
okay but but this's this you know this
this extra space well okay let's fix
that okay so do
it uh wait cancel uh do it again okay so
one two 3 query replace regular
expression space space then plus okay
let's hope this is a uh correct key plus
okay Enter then just
space enter Then type exclamation okay
we got fixed uh that you know okay so
far so good uh now we just want to swap
lines okay now go to the
top okay we we made a mistake we we
should have done the first one as well
but let's just manually fix it okay so
now we want to swap the lines now that
this is the important part okay so start
record a keyboard
marro okay then we um then let's see
what to do
uh okay we are starting recording
keyboard marker then cut the line
go down paste it okay done okay now stop
record keyboard Marco you can see on the
pink window that's the command name okay
now we just call last keyboard
markco one two three do it you see done
now we need to continue that for the
next you know 900 something times but
instead I I'm going to do this okay I'm
going to call repeat last command and
just hold the key and you'll just do
them all okay so one two three okay you
see it repeats I just hold the
key uh then you'll do the whole
thing so I'm just holding one key down
right there it is done
so how is that is that good how many key
strokes I don't know you know we have to
kind of
like
uh you know like when you re okay when
you hold it it actually you know repeats
so so it's hard to count from from this
pink
window but if you don't want you know we
can do it all over again now let's do it
again just for fun let's write the emac
this command to do it okay
default def okay so uh switch
to this mod okay default defund actually
we don't need defund let's just write a
y Loop okay set x equals to one
1,000 1,000 okay
then evaluate that then
while okay
while less than
while X is less than 1,000 actually uh X
should be one okay while is um let's say
less than or
equal uh okay well it's less than 1,000
and we need to uh increase the X
so increment + One X uh you need to set
x equals to x + 1 okay now what you do
for each time you do that you want to
insert uh insert you want to insert the
string
line uh then space then with the X okay
so X you need to X is a number you need
to convert to string so string uh number
to
string X okay now we don't need the rest
okay that's
it so evaluate this x now go here now if
I evaluate that you'll just do it okay
let's do it now let's double check one
last time to make
sure it's correct yeah it's correct so
let's do it there it is so we we forgot
the um line return so we just need to
have a line return there let's do it
again evaluate
it uh wait oh we we need to reset it's
going to infinite n Loop we need to uh
set the x to one again so evaluate that
put a curer here evaluate the last
expression there it is okay there's
something wrong again uh line number oh
line number needs to go at the end not
there
so there okay let's do it again
evaluate that evaluate that there it is
oh we have to then we need to swap it so
let's do the swap again uh so we can
actually
call you see we still have the markall
do it do it do it do it do it do it do
it I cannot hold the key or let's see if
I can um you know call like do it 800
times let's see if that works okay
so 800 you know it's got to be n wait uh
let's do it again okay so Universal
command then 900 900 uh
980 times
okay then we're going to call last keyw
Mark there it is one shot you see this
time I don't have to hold a key it does
it so that's that I think I is it
satisfactory
Mo now let's show most uh you know most
also recorded in Vim so let's let's
watch his solution okay so here's small
solution so let's begin uh you know mo
your phone is too small people cannot
see it
wait
uh yeah well anyway you cannot see the
left hand
side wait let's redo this because you
cannot see the left side with my face
and all
that um so temporarily let's move this
here oh [ __ ] I don't want to show
that you know whatever possibly things I
don't want to
show
uh and yeah let's play most video so
that's on
Discord start
over stop start
over magnify okay let's watch
can you guys see it can you guys see it
well you know some Vim magic you know V
Vim is pretty good okay now it's
swapping the lines let's see uh QQ DD DD
is cut line QQ is what uh
pqi
KKK
2635 okay that's what repeating I
guess g
JJJ okay that okay that's s okay
okay let's see the comment but I think R
is massive yes indeed of course very
good uh What keyboard do you recommend
okay under 100 you seem to be a keyboard
expert uh yes yeah yes I'm kind of you
know I've been studying math you know
keyboards um I'm just starting emac and
saw your website just two two chapters
in and I like it's uh I like it very
it's not very verbos thank you my emac
tutorial uh that's part of what I'm
known for emac and the
keyboards that's what I'm mostly known
for uh and I've been blogging since
1997 so I'm an
Oldtimer he long time no see Zero I
don't remember who you are uh you know
so yeah that's you know that's what
happens to
streamers uh yeah I don't Sero I don't
remember where are you from and palash
says what is the exact wording of the
problem
again uh okay let me let me show that
again so you got a bunch of lines you
have to generate yourself each line is
the text line followed by a number so it
goes from 1 to 1,000 okay now part of
the problem is that you have to create
the Alli yourself programmatically or by
key Mar or whatever means okay uh you
know I wonder if they can you know the
VSS code people I wonder if they can do
that V
code uh they can probably do it too you
know with you know they drop into Power
shell you know like uh let's see we can
uh let's see I can show
that so you need to have this bunch of
lines okay then you have to to swap
every two lines you have to swap their
order so that's it so you know that's a
problem now Exel open vs
code oh I think Mo also mentioned uh
let's see so vs code you know we started
to run vs code whatever update [ __ ] so
there's VSS code you
know I you know they can you know so you
have to open a terminal in vs code I
actually never
I don't use vs code actually so which
one new terminal you see so in vs code
the terminal pops down at the bottom so
let's
see uh CD let's I want to magnify okay
control scroll doesn't work stupid vs
code Control Plus okay where's my plus
let's see magnify okay Control
Plus so in vs code so
cd2 uh to web and uh wait I forgot my
key info okay that's good then then talk
show something like
that what is
this
draw uh
turn on the sticky key okay Exel talk
show I think H where's my where's my
talk show
located no it doesn't you know I'm
trying to complete but it's not cycling
um so what is this talk show okay okay
so it's t k yeah so we go down that
directory duh so this directory you know
so you can start to code but I don't
know how to insert you know the output
into the bu into the
anyway that's a that's a problem okay so
let's see what are we doing
uh where is the comment
looks really good but still I think Vim
is massive I used to show up like almost
a year
ago code one gamma a year ago I look
forward to more stream thank you okay I
think you know that's one task you know
that's like demo of the keyboard marro
of emac so let
me
um so where are the windows so let me
redo my keyboard move to where they
were okay so and this massive pink
window uh let's put it
back so that's a record of all my key
strokes and
commands and the vs code we don't care
uh okay so what what else we going to do
so you know that that's interesting
thing um I think Mo actually mentioned
that he wants the comma you know you
know he like he wants to make it more
difficult he wants to have a comma I
think at the end something but let me
show you how to add a comma okay so in S
likees I have my own custom command so
you cannot do it in emx but if you are
using softw keys let me look look okay
let me I'm just going to show you okay
press press press double quote yes
separator comma there you have it this
is extremely useful especially if you
are coding goand Java or pow shell you
know whenever you need a array you know
you need a comma and also usually you
need uh you know quot so if you don't
want to quote let's undo okay so if you
don't want to quote you call the command
again which is s quote lines then you
say none okay no qu now do you want the
end of line separated yes comma okay
there there you have it okay now you see
they got a space in front so let's
undo now show show the white spaces you
can see you got the extra space at the
end of every line so you just call
command
uh not that one call what is a key no uh
uh wait this key okay so that's s clean
white space that's a command that
removes all the um extra white spaces
and now you do s quote Lines no quote
and comma then you can see a comma Now
turn off y space so there you
are uh and this
s quot lines you don't have that in emac
but you can do it easily so you know so
let's say again by a keyboard marro so
let's record a keyboard marro okay so
start
recording uh okay
so um well you can do many ways so let's
select the
line now let's
type okay let's type a quote then emac
Auto automatically put them in front and
back and
[Music]
then and and then let's say if you want
a comma okay let's add a comma then stop
recording okay that's what you want to
do for this line and but you want to do
for all the lines so all you have to do
is select all the lines go
down select all the lines and call apply
last Mark to
all lines okay watch the pink window the
command name will show okay I press B
bam bam there it is you see
the the command I called is uh did it
say here oh it
didn't uh well the command is let's
show this command apply marro to region
lines that's part of emac
okay so that you know so that's some
emac
demo uh hey why are you using multip
multiple browsers that's a good question
and that's been asked a few times in the
past three years uh because I've been
using multiple browsers all my life
since 1990s I always use multiple
browsers why for example the okay so let
me show you so this fir Fox so let me
just switch around so you know one key
press to wait what uh are you guys
seeing me yeah okay so so one key press
to to switch next tab previous tab you
know previous next next uh previous this
is one of the oh that that's my that's
my
keyboards this is uh Kar battle station
so next tab so Firefox right now is used
for my uh for Dev of my own website so
all these URL are local URL you know
right now there are 1,00 1,5 tabs they
are all my website pages so so I work on
them when I'm ready I go to terminal and
I uh aring to my web server so I work
them locally so that's five box now the
bra browser okay actually actually I
turned it off uh because I want to clear
memory oh
[ __ ] JavaScript not available turn on
JavaScript to let Google know where you
live so there it is my Twitter follow me
on my Twitter and follow me on Discord
you can find my Discord ons.info my
website
so so uh so the bra browser I use for
Twitter basically Twitter or you know
usually just Twitter and then I got a
Chrome browser Google Chrome which I
only use for Google stuff like Gmail
whatever Google Google requiring a
login so right now this that's how I use
the different browsers they
are they all have JavaScript off by
default you know Brave has JavaScript
off by default when whenever I visit
some website if I you know you know if
it required then I turn it on same thing
in Firefox by default it's
off and exception is Google Chrome uh
because Google Chrome I uh use for Gmail
and Google stuff so I never visit any
website in the Google Chrome Google go
be you know Google has become very nasty
uh
they they they can can do a lot of
things very very extremely nasty okay
related to
politics uh you know so you don't want
basically you don't want to use Google
browsers at
all not not even you know not at all
even they do a lot of nasty things so
yeah actually I can I can try not to use
Google Chrome at
all so anyway that's the reason why I
use multiple browsers um and there are
you know so I have you know in the past
30 years since I've been
blogging I have for example tons of
blogs about browser you know I you know
I've used all browser that exist over
the past 30 years so you can see so many
articles unic code character equivalence
support in web
browsers and and okay that's one of the
reason I use different browsers for
different purposes because I do really a
lot of websites browsing websites
reading documentation is almost what all
I do uh you know you know reading
reading websites but also I'm a web dev
so since 1990s I'm a web dev so when you
are web dev you need a lot
browsers so by the way this picture
today's thumbnail is generated by Gro
okay so we about a month ago we did a
video like live stream talking about
artificial intelligence image
generation so let me show you some
articles about browsers because when you
look back you know when you don't
realize you've been you've been uh
writing blogs for 30 years like more
than half of your life but then you look
back you actually see history you know
you kind of see record history you know
here's conqueror browser SE SE sty ass
conqueror is one of the
Linux Linux thing and the Y Opera
browser se you know web browser market
share
2010 uh browser inline SVG image height
and weight scale versus cop you know
lots of and Google Chrome spdy protocol
browser world to that's around
2010 and
spdy protocol that's Google's protocol
became
http2 and now it's part of the standard
you know currently in use so Google
Chrome browser special URL you know
that's uh like settings and stuff so you
know like okay 32 um
blocks whose title contains the World
Browser but but here's this one what is
a browser browser this is very
interesting especially For You ner Tech
nerds okay what is a browser let's go
there browser market share 2010 okay so
browser inline sving image you know
browser has bugs and so on you see so
here's the example in ie9 where they CRA
an SVG image for some reason possibly
because the SVG is not valid or
incorrect in some way so when you show
it in I9 it became
CED uh and by the way this SVG is
xfce desktop environment that's the
Linux thing which I was using uh I was
using Linux for like six
years uh okay Google Chrome browser
special URL so here's interesting what
is a browser so Google
back in when Google is still good you
know 2009 they have people went to New
York and ask people on the street what
is a
browser and guess what's the result
people have no idea what is a browser
like they don't know like it's this is
funny you know so search for what is a
browser G Le okay so you can watch it
you see the people vast majority of
people like programmers don't know like
especially the Nerds like the Linux VI
Vim emac users you know they think they
know so much about Society they tell
every other people what to do you know
how you should design user interface
that like extreme
idiots but the average people on a
street they they don't even know what
the [ __ ] is a browser like oh it's you
mean search
engines they know what is a search
engine because they have to search
things but they they have no idea what
is a
browser uh so this is interesting
because when you hear when you talk
among the program like us you know we
sometimes argue about user interface
about online Forum what it should be how
most people are idiots you know you
should you know like you try to tell
people you should spend time to learn
about the tool and blah blah blah that
dribbles like incredible because they
these people these Tech NS have no idea
of reality we think we know because we
code you know you know you should you
you know tell your mom to use Linux it's
so easy it's easy my ass Linux is worst
[ __ ] okay so uh what is the some other
topic so that answer I think that
answers a question what why do I use
several browsers because I'm a web dev
so I use a lot of browsers because you
know when you are actually working you
need to test different browsers and
check behaviors I haven't been working a
corporation for you know for 15 20 years
okay but but I still do but it's just
because but I still
write tremendous uh JavaScript tutorial
for example today we have update and and
in the past two days we have a huge
argument you know we've been arguing
onar Discord for for three
days about a very esoteric technical
detail in
JavaScript about whether the JavaScript
object is faster or the JavaScript map
object okay so let's go there JavaScript
reference okay you just search for
JavaScript in depth okay that's my one
of my best tutorial pay me okay I send
you the whole thing no framework you
don't need any framework no react [ __ ]
no angular no view [ __ ] crap [ __ ] okay
you don't need any of that all my
website you know I have demoed before
but I'm not not going to do it today but
you know there's interactivity and you
don't need any of I don't use any of
that you don't need mpm zero like every
time you use mpm you
know mpm you know uh mpm install like
1,000 libraries like 1,000 [ __ ] comes
into your
computer the [ __ ] extreme edsy of the
industry you know they become and in npm
there's a library
that just one lines of code is this a
even
number or trim trim trim stream trim the
white spaces of line the [ __ ] one
line or five lines of code is the
library that's a state of the idy
extreme so anyway so JavaScript tutorial
JavaScript in depth you can pay me okay
so you go there and you know somewhere
at the
bottom uh buy JavaScript you know pay me
I sent you the zip file so you can read
offline uh including all the references
so let's go to a JavaScript reference
all the objects let's go to map so
JavaScript you have this map object
which is created in 2016 2015 okay
that's a major upgrade of JavaScript
2015 major like major revision you know
um you know that 2016 JavaScript made
2015 made
JavaScript respectable language because
before it's like total [ __ ] but still
right now it's still lots of crap
because they don't they Tred to be
Backward Compatible so all the problems
of JavaScript is still there you know
they just covered it up with new things
so you avoid you don't use you know you
so you use the new things instead of the
old thing but all the crap all the Watts
all the problem still is still there
JavaScript but it's reasonable I mean I
mean you can code you know just a script
or even better in some cases than python
or Ruby and I wouldn't say so anyway so
JavaScript you have the map object which
is just a hash table okay JavaScript
doesn't have a hash table or called
dictionary in Python you know
dictionary JavaScript don't have it but
they have a object which is kind of like
a dictionary but but not really because
that's the nature of jav JavaScript you
have lots of
complexities for example you cannot get
you know typically if you have a
dictionary you can know how many entries
are there you know is it 100 1,000 or
998 you know how many how many entries
are there you cannot do that with
JavaScript
object so in 2015 JavaScript created you
know this map object this is the proper
hash table and the key of the hash table
can be any uh object can be a string can
be a number can be a floating Point
number can be other objects too you know
so it's a proper properly welld designed
dictionary or has table that's you know
that's this map object you see but but
there's a problem you see because this
is new and this is a bit Advanced
because you know most you know vast
majority program of programers they
don't know they don't know about these
new things and they just they are happy
with the JavaScript you know the
JavaScript object which is kind of like
hashtable but not really got lots of
problems because you know JavaScript
object so let's see let's go to
JavaScript in depth and go to object
overview so object object JavaScript
object is a collection of pairs okay
each pair is a key and value called
properties so JavaScript object is a
collection by definition by the
specification is a collection of pairs
each pair is a key and value this pair
thing is called a property okay uh but
then each object may have a parent may
have
Associated object which is called the
parent of the object and that object may
also have a parent so you have an object
may have a parent and that parent have
parent and so on this is called
prototype chain okay so whenever you
look up a property let's say you know
you look up a property it checks the if
the object has that property key if not
it will look at the parent object to see
if that parent object has a property of
that key if it does it returns it you
see this so this is what inheritance
means okay JavaScript inheritance okay
uh you know somewhere um you know so
anyway that's that's inheritance okay so
when you use JavaScript object as a some
kind of hash table or dictionary you got
a problem because it has to check the
parent object you know which you don't
want because the parent and parent of
parent or parent they can have like
1,000 properties you don't know what the
[ __ ] is there so usually you don't want
to do
that but people you know people do
anyway
because it still works most of the time
because when you create an
object um you know so let me let me let
me talk about JavaScript okay so when
you create an object like using the
object literal
expression uh okay so this is object
literal expression so let's
magnify uh so today we just G to talk
random okay so this is a object Okay so
so when you create an object by this
literal
expression it will create a object with
a parent the parent will point to um
point to this object okay point to this
uh
object dot
um where is it uh let's go there okay so
JavaScript object Let's uh create object
okay let's click create object go there
um typee parent wait not here create
object so you can create by literal
expression or you can create by object
create or you can create by other ways
so let's go to literal expression okay
so when you create object by this
literal expression like that it will
create object but and the parent will be
um what is the parent the parent will be
um object. prototype okay so that's
another object building so that would be
the parent and this
object has these properties okay one two
3 four five six seven eight about eight
properties okay not too many one of the
most important is two string because if
you call JavaScript then you know you
know you can call two string where it
came from every object has it it came
from this object. prototype okay so but
you see but when you are using a
JavaScript object as a hash table you
just create it you know so the parent is
this one so magically you got this two
string key so that's not what you want
because your dictionary have this you
know all these properties that's not
what you want but however you see it's
rare for the for the property Collision
because usually your dictionary is like
list of names or whatever you know
rarely you have your key to be like
JavaScript keywords so so normally
that's not a problem so people just use
object as a hash
table why because JavaScript do not have
a hash table you know before 2015 that's
you know using the object is actually
the only way but now they do but you
know for one thing people are not
familiar you know most people still
don't know about the new stuff and and
for the other reason people are already
used to how to you know just use the
object as hash table like there's like
million billions of projects or doing
that so people are habituated they just
use the object for hash table so Ching
Hank thank you
Hank uh okay let me answer that question
in a bit so that's why so that's you
know so that's why a lot of people use
the JavaScript object object as for
hashtable
and we started to have a huge debate for
three days you know since 3 days ago
starting uh here which George George is
a George is one of the top expert of
JavaScript I would say but his coding
style we have different coding
Styles and he's he's saying you know
using object as a hash table is
faster than if you actually use map at
this disagree so we started to you know
show code and compare speed and went
into a huge argument for three days uh
and with other also lots of other people
joined in you know Dion and and and you
know Dion and
Steve uh yeah but it's an interesting
thing and you see JavaScript is such a
mess because
different you know it's such a huge mess
that's why each engine they imp
they all try to be very fast it's also
extremely competitive because each one
of these scums the Microsoft the
Google and Apple Apple Safari you know
they they they you know winning the
browser war is very important because
that means a lot money a lot Power a lot
influence uh let's see you see Opera
browser Opera is basically dead Opera is
created by Scutt by a scum from the
northern Europe who also created CSS
okay Opera he he his name is like uh you
know why is he scum he's a huge
Microsoft
hater hate this Microsoft I mean this
this uh this this Opera browser Opera
Opera browser was one of the best
browser for about 10 years from from
1990s to let's say to
2010 best one of the best U but you know
today is like dead nobody you know like
today's generation I'm not sure they
even know they heard of it oh yeah this
guy evangelist hackam Willam
lie okay he's a in my opinion he's not a
good person he's a extreme Microsoft ha
hater what does that mean what do I mean
you know that means like often you'll
see a us you know in the Linux community
in the Unix community in the emac
community in the v VM Community you'll
see and python Community for example
you'll see Microsoft hatred every minute
like the Microsoft the you know like you
know you know you know what I mean like
even today one bunch of people will ask
me why are you on Windows oh my God K
why are you on
Windows they think I should be on
Linux so anyway I digressed random you
know so micros you know the Opera
browser is one of the best it's created
by this
guy hacken William LI or hacken William
Lee whatever he's
from uh you
know Finland something like that you
know the the the northern
Europe you know so Norway or Finland
something and he is he also created C
CSS okay CSS was kind of created by Him
actually let me make sure okay CSS
Creator let's
see uh no not generator let's say CSS
inventor let's say let's try bot who
invented
CSS wait do I have the bot on oh uh
because the let's see turn JavaScript
there it is yeah that's him hackam
William
Lee okay this guy he also created CSS in
my opinion in my opinion this guy is a
scum a scum bag of humanity okay now you
might be
wondering why can you how can you pass
can how can you say that that's so
disrespectful no you know in this world
doesn't matter you are technology leader
or whatever there's a lots of scums you
know right in politics you know you know
this you know po
politicians they do things to get money
big money big huge
money uh so in my
opinion this guy is not a good guy okay
not maybe not a scum scum is too strong
a word but he's a not a good person he's
a huge Microsoft hater just for the hate
purposes
okay so that's you know and you know
okay that's a digression so we talked
about JavaScript uh map versus object
then what else uh keyboards okay so back
to
uh how many people watching 10 fantastic
comments okay I think that's it for
today so let me answer the
question so so let's see the web browser
thing
uh yeah so we had a huge argument about
object speed range function for array
yeah what is a browser watch this video
what is a browser very interesting by G
Le 15 years ago so 2009 April
30s then what is the browser then Google
Chrome browser special URL so Google
Chrome spdy protocol browser world I in
0 uh so when you look back you know like
by now this is 15 years old but to the
writer to you to me this is like
yesterday because you remember writing
it you know and also you know you
remember you know you see there's a fral
viewer so when when Google created this
spdy protocol you know back then it's
over on the news Hacker News every nerd
is talking about it oh Google created a
new protocol you know it's is shiny this
you know why how does it work you know
everyone is talking about it a
fat Google also you know when Google
created that they also created a fractal
viewer to show
the
um okay it's not it's not actually
related but it's it was to show the
JavaScript work workers technology
JavaScript has this workers which allows
you to have uh like multi comput
concurrent
computation
not you know multi-threaded computation
workers so Google created a facto viewer
you know a website that draw draw factos
because facto is supposed to be very
computational uh expensive so they
Google created that using the new
technology JavaScript workers to
demonstrate the speed so you can do you
know concurrent comp computation it's
not concurrent it's uh what's it called
it's a parallel you know more it's more
like parallel computation but now but
now the website is dead you see the
website is dead since few years ago
because I checked so what I'm saying is
that so when you write a blog after you
know 15 years you can see a lot history
um like you can read you can remember
what you you know what happened at the
time what you were doing and you kind of
partially recorded history uh for
example today for example if you want to
know who who would know that this Julia
map. Google labs.com existed like today
you ask the zoom they don't know they
they don't know can you actually search
for it actually you will be you know
let's search for this thing okay first
of all okay it's not the website is dead
so you got so you go here okay type
something you know so like things you
don't know they become history and uh
you see you click on that it's dead uh
then Julia programming okay you cannot
even find it no mention at all uh
discontinuation okay it's mentioned
in did Wikipedia mention it let's
see so search for
Julia no Wikipedia didn't mention it on
this page Google labs Google Labs itself
is dead let's
see yeah in 2023 Google revived Labs at
the anual oh it revived so it's still
alive it's mostly
dead so anyway so let's see the question
and let's uh what is the sociology
behind the split between r
dbms and l d a
directories nobody seems to want to
system accounts against
Rd BMS okay I don't know that question
at all yeah that's totally unfamiliar to
me in fact I don't
know like I don't really know what is Rd
relational database oh that's relational
database rdbm okay so
wait I think that's
oh relational database I know but this
ldap that's some kind of directory
service I never got I never know exactly
what they do lightweight directory
access protocol okay yeah that this this
is like one of the Class A old Asian
protocol popular in
1990s but I never
actually you know know exactly what it
does you know I got nothing to do with
it but but the relational database of
course you know anyone works with the
web or you know you know about it
um you know it's a essential technology
for for big scale you know this
relational database is only for big St
big scale usage for example you have
like hundreds of millions of data for
each person and things like hundreds of
millions at least you know if you just
have 10,000 you know you don't use this
so rational database for example Amazon
eBay Apple they have to use it every
every
major Bank you know bank or
transactional website involving a lot of
people you need to use uh relational
database such as mysq my M you know
MySQL is with uh most popular or Oracle
database I was a master of my SQL you
know I read the entirety of 1,000 pages
of their documentation
twice uh you know uh the last time but
the last time is in 2006 I read the
entirety of my SQL
database okay and the creator of MySQL
is also a scum in my opinion okay there
it is the MySQL the creator of my you
know I I don't think you know yeah I I I
I don't like like the guy you know
create the creator of
MySQL he's like he's like that creator
of CSS he's kind of like they are
Microsoft
haters they they Pro you know like a
typical Unix or Linux nerd they
promote they you know they they they
care about nothing they they promote
their own views about things like like
really push it in in at the cost of any
other people's opinion and
they they have no idea about the reality
of the world like the you know like what
is a browser like the average people
what's their needs and so on you know
they just push their views you know that
like like the Richard soulman similar
thing with the Richard soulman you know
everything must be software must be free
software otherwise you should die you
know that's that's that's that's this
people so anyway my MyQ is you know the
one of the huge database and I as a
master B but I haven't used for 20 years
so today I don't
know so I think that's it 7 o' exactly 1
hour I think that's it for my talk show
today um anything else yeah tech tech
Noob okay so well half of the people
half about half on my on my C Discord
are programmers okay you know maybe half
and the other half are not so you know
so you are uh you know you have you have
company uh yeah I think that's it for
today anything
else let's see emx okay I think that's
it for
today oh the from Brazil there's the
news from Brazil the politics you see
Brazil
uh maybe I shouldn't you know I don't
know if I should talk about it because I
started to talk about it Google is going
to Bam
me but bra Brazil is got this corrupt
guy a corrupt judge very corrupt you
know he's going to ban he you know he's
Banning Twitter
x.com why because he he request Elam
musk to ban certain accounts who are
talking about politics you know so like
in Brazil there are some Brazilians they
want talk about politics you know
because they think maybe they have
corrupt leaders or whatever you know but
the leader this corrupt judge says no
you cannot do that he tells El musk the
owner of ttor to ban
them but the El musk says no elus says
[ __ ] you you know elamus you are says to
the jurge you know you are a corrupt
[ __ ] you should go to jail you know El
mus is El musk today is challenging many
of the very corrupt people the top
politicians and he he can do it because
he's got you know one of the
richest so El must tell the Brazil judge
go [ __ ] yourself you know this this this
this issue is not just about these two
people it involves the entire USA and
Military okay very deep very deep it's
not just about one you know one crazy
not job judge or one crazy Element no it
the entire USA and Military are involved
because who runs who become the
president in Brazil has a lot to do with
USA and the whole world you know who
like who can buy o your from what
country you know resource control and
who will be on whose side you know right
now there are two Wars going on and this
nukes you
know he did you know so very involved
thing so alen must told him to [ __ ]
himself but then something happened okay
exactly what happened we don't know Elam
musk gave up Elam musk then quietly
without you know mentioning talking you
know because you he was talking about
every day [ __ ] this church you should go
to jail every day like broadly to his
like 2 million or something 20 million
whatever followers but curretly El you
know the ex in Brazil they followed all
the rules from of that church they
banned the people they want to ban you
know the jurge so they followed all the
rules and they also paid the fines like
some millions of millions of dollars
right so now X should be back in Brazil
right no why this more twist let me let
me find today's treat okay because I
just saw a news about it from Glen
greenw okay then that's it for this
today so let me show you the people I
follow okay I mostly follow just the um
you know like wait is it working yeah
okay elus okay actually I want to go to
the Glen guy
uh search for search
for green
Greenwood where is
it right and let's just scroll down
scroll
down yeah one of one of the problem is
that
you
um emx versus Vim Okay so
so Glen is usually here so these are the
people I read every day okay lots of you
know lots of death going
on uh of course depending on your point
of view in politics you know some of
this you'll never see instead you'll see
your things the things you
like uh but I need to go to the Glen guy
okay
so there it is okay so this guy so you
go to Glenn Greenwood which is a
renowned journalist he re resides in
Brazil okay and uh then just today there
it is this one okay one point about
today's election you see Brazil is
holding its midterm elections today
after its USA supported dictation
dictatorship ended voting became
mandatory okay I don't want to read it
because Google is going to ban
me um but anyway
so the the the the the bottom line is X
followed all the rules however X is
still banned because they put a they
they made a Twist so that X will not be
banned X will come back to Brazil only
after the election not before the
election you know they make a complaint
oh yeah but you PID to you paid your f
to the wrong guy okay so there's a delay
until we are done with the election then
X can be back on Brazil you see that's
what's going
on yeah it's incredible I read that
$9,000 fee per day was it per day for
average citizen in Brazil who tries to
sneak into x.com using vpm
you know what what kind you have to
think about this
$99,000 right yeah something you know is
that brailon dollar but it's a lot money
like I read you know the in US US
Dollars like a lot money a day per day
if you use VPN to read like you cannot
read you cannot read x.com they're going
to B in Brazil but you know maybe I know
technology yet so I can you know use vpm
to read it no
that is also illegal that's so is
incredible so that means you don't have
you don't have freedom you cannot read
what you want you know so what kind of
what kind of law is
that I mean you know
you yeah average salary is
230 that's not even a day right that's
that's what for a a month no wait
that's a day okay yeah so anyway that's
it for today um yeah that that's it we
closing down thank you guys for watching
Pretty corrupt okay lots of corruption
you know and why does this happen in
Brazil now here's a a bit more
things how do I know because I read my
information you know I don't follow
memes for example these are the people
like what you see here are the people I
have have turned on alert so basically
every day I only these people I follow
but they are also on alert so every time
they post I see so I only read these
people basically I have I follow other
people but I rarely read them so I don't
read any memes I don't enjoy you know
funny crap Trump memes or whatever Pepe
you know I don't follow any of that or
ma what whatever [ __ ] I only follow
people who actually post
critical important information for
example this guy American first legal
they are they are doing lawsuits every
day okay
lawsuits uh and El mus okay I kind of
follow because you know he he you know
musk he post a lot memes too this girl
is about um election okay wait uh it's
about uh what is it about it's about no
it's about how how difficult is to
change opinion political opinion he's
supposedly a neurosurgeon you know so
he's going to talk about why people why
is it hard for people to change their
opinion for example if you are trying if
you are Trump supporter or if you are
beaten supporter you try to talk the to
the other side you know you're gonna be
beat up you know they're going to beat
you up so so she's talking about it but
anyway so these people
I follow usually they just have they
post important information no memes no
like random joke no like sarcastic [ __ ]
I don't like any of those I only you
know just follow like dense critical
stuff so that is so if I may say so I
know about some of these issues um you
know a lot of it is of of course secret
but but today it's very hard to hide
information because of the internet
precisely if you really want to know
what is actually true regardless what
event may be this war or that war or the
Brazil Banning this thing who is
actually good person who is actually you
know what kind of things they did in the
past you can find out if you really want
to and if you have enough time you just
have to spend time read and read
research you know use use whatever
search engine you know this like like
you just spend your time you'll know the
truth okay that's it bye