hello guys good morning welcome to
another episode of sound talk show
today is 2021 november 23rd
and we don't have a topic yet
so
in the first five minutes you are here
uh post the topic you know refresh
refresh your youtube and in the
description you can see
there are two links
and those two links are let me show you
so one of them is some toxic topic notes
the other one is
it's not to do okay so
uh
pick a topic in the first five minutes
and i'll talk about that today okay
otherwise
uh let me just start to uh work random
on my website okay so you are looking at
my emacs and uh i'm using soft light
keys
and uh i'm using vera keyboard and the
pink window you can see all my emacs
command cores and the keystroke
and this is kinesis advantage keyboard
and this is ultimate hacking keyboard
okay you can search for xrd
keyboard and find my reviews on them
okay so uh no topics yet and so i'm just
going to
uh start working on my website kind of
random okay
so there you have wufang language
fantastic
in no other language you can see this
okay this is a nested
array
and you can specify a level when you map
to it okay so let's see video check
audio check fantastic
uh so i want to do yeah let's do some
okay so
see
go to talk show
go to notes
uh javascript so i have this page
history of the javascript script tag
you know so you know javascript script
tag
you know this is a history of web
technology
so you see usually you say type equals
to
text slash javascript
um
yeah so this article is written around
so in the past 30 years there's a lot of
changes about using how you use the
javascript tag script tag
back then in the beginning you say
there is this language equals to
javascript
because
in the 1990s
in the 19 late 1990s there javascript
there's also jscript and microsoft
that's from microsoft jscript
which is a reverse engineering of
javascript the language you know
javascript was invented by mozilla the
netscape browser you know which became
firefox
and microsoft created their own version
of javascript by just looking at the you
know looking at what the behavior so
they called it
jscript
so big history of javascript so and
mozilla submitted their javascript
language
to a standard organization called ecma
okay so
there are quite a few things i want to
do about this uh no comments comments
okay comments guys
so
if you go to javascript in depth this is
my tutorial about javascript
and you can see
at the bottom
there is the javascript reference so
this is ecmascript
specification
you know so javascript is quite
[ __ ] up so
let me summarize
in 1996
mozilla you know not you are an escape
the company was called netscape they
created
what's up alan so in 1996 netscape
which became mozilla firefox netscape
created javascript the language the idea
is
dynamic website because before 1996
all website is just static you know just
like text or images there's no
interaction you cannot
you know there's no interaction so 1996
mozilla netscape created javascript
then netscape submitted their javascript
language to this organization ecma okay
this organization is called ecma
international
so that the idea is that to standardize
the language i mean
they don't really want to you see
netscape is a commercial entity all they
really want is to create
to make money for themselves so they
invented javascript but
you know back then open source is
beginning to go around the idea so
people want
it to be a not proprietary language so
if it's proprietary language then people
you know don't like it they don't use it
then you don't have market you know you
don't have users
so
netscape by this pressure
they
they um
you know they put their javascript
submit their javascript language into
this ecma standard organization this is
not too well known the ecma you know so
ekma
so then ekma created the standard
documentation for javascript so the very
first one is here this one
javascript you know
so this this is the very first
javascript specification
june 1997 standard ecma 262 okay
so ecmascript a general purpose
cross-platform programming language yeah
right
you remember this is 1996 1997.
so netscape you know try to standardize
their language to this ecma organization
and this economic
ecommerce august organization
named the language ekma script okay
that's how
things are so
why do they name it ecmascript and not
javascript well i guess because
javascript was trademarked by netscape
you know
so there is a lot um
you know selfish reasons you know if
you know nate escape you know if they
really want to you know benefit humanity
and all that they should you know just
i mean why is there all these complex
why do you why do you have javascript
jscrip ecmascript you know it's like all
confusing and javascript has nothing to
do with java the language
but why is it named javascript well
because again commercial purposes
selfish reasons you know all these
cell self-motivated
motivations you know selfish reasons
created all these confusion on the
surface they will tell you you know
they're gonna help the world just like
google and microsoft you know that's on
the surface but behind behind that's why
behind it all there's all these selfish
reasons that created all these
complexity and uh [ __ ] up
so um
including microsoft you know microsoft
you guys know you guys hate microsoft
most of you and including unix you know
unix with their irc complete [ __ ] up so
anyway
so netscape
created javascript they submit submit
the language to this ecma standard
standard organization to create a
standardized language
and out of selfish reasons by pressure
and so ecma created this you know ecma
script they call it xmas script it's
just javascript
so
then microsoft around 1998 1999
you know netscape created javascript so
that you can have interactive web pages
so microsoft saw that you know microsoft
is not a internet company you know
microsoft is just focused on setting
operating systems
but then the next you know the we talked
about in last video the history of the
web okay
you know the modem and all that so
so the internet became a thing you know
1995 you know
you have cyberspace you have hyperlinks
you know it's like new era like today's
metaverse
okay so
so it became a thing so everyone you
know so microsoft thinking is thinking
oh oh next you know the browser so we
need to do something so like microsoft
created internet explorer
why is my pages why is my key not
working
what's going on
okay
so let's uh so i have a collection of
articles about the history of web
technology html validation history and
politics so
this is the reason today's web
technology is one extreme [ __ ] up
you know this is even before today's web
frameworks you know uh
complexity you know all the react and
view and uh
and and so on
so this escape created javascript then
then
you know then you have the html tag to
specify the language you know
interactive website
um
then in the beginning it's like that
you know today you just do this script
you know with no attributes
uh
javascript won't
okay
and and yeah so so so um
so but in the beginning it's like that
then around 2006 i guess yeah
2006 they changed it
around year 2000 you know the
ww3 standard organization which is
another standard organization that's
responsible
responsible for html for css you know
they say
okay this is not good okay you shouldn't
have you know language equals javascript
you should have you know type equals to
application slash javascript
because back then the idea is that
you know the embedded object you know
javascript is you can
in a general sense you can think of it
as some kind of embedded object you know
there are a lot embedded objects back
then for example uh vr ml uh virtual
reality ml okay
in year 2000
and other and adobe you know the
adobe flash you know back then it's
called a
macro media flash okay marco media flash
which kind of works like javascript and
svg you know it's so this is a history
around year 2000
so back then you have all these kind of
embedded things so they the thinking was
that
you know you should generalize so the
tag should be type equals to application
slash javascript now this is called a
mind type
but
okay let me show you so some history
okay my mind type
uh i wanna go to wikipedia okay so
mining uh
common mind types okay they don't call
it my mind types anymore you see now you
you you can see some of the mind types
but now it's called um
okay let's
mine type wikipedia so
yeah so this is the history of the
m-i-n-e-m-m-i-m-e which stands for
multi-purpose internet mail extensions
yeah
because originally originally they came
from email you know email
like if you want to attach an image you
cannot do it you cannot do that
in 1990s late 1990s you know we have
email throughout 1990s but you cannot
attach images it's just pure text you
know that's the way unix philosophy
unix people the unix [ __ ] they like
it that way no images
then but people need it you know average
people need attached images
the but the unix people precisely the
unix and c packets they refuse
you know like like many of you guys okay
like today's new generation about the
linux you know uh
uh you know tiny window system you know
these type of people elite kind of
hacker guy they refuse they think oh no
communication should not include you
know pictures you should be able to you
should learn to write you know
communication english so they don't want
images but eventually of course that
um
that's
you know that's incompatible with
reality
image most people do want images you
know they want to attach image send
images to friends in email so
the unix people the unix that's why you
know in my video i talked about i
despise the unix people because you know
remember back then they they don't want
they don't want
to uh to let email have images you know
because they think that's a proper way
okay so eventually they they failed of
course so they create so the you know
the so we have you know we created you
know
um the technology to attach images to a
email and that technology is called
multi-purpose internet mail extensions
okay because you have to change the mail
protocol in order you know for it to
work
so
multi-purpose internet
mail
extensions that's mine and that event
that then evolved into
um
into attaching images or
um other things into website so anyway
that that became the mind type okay so
so let me go back to what i'm talking
about so um so history of javascript
script tag in html so
around year 2000 you have type equals to
application slash javascript that's what
you're supposed to
say when you have a you know script tag
to embed javascript
then
okay let me let me regroup okay in the
beginning
it's this script languages
script language equals to javascript
then
the mind
type happened then you know the w3c
tells us that the proper way should be
type equals to application slash
javascript because this is more general
you know
so this is the application and it's a
specific is javascript so it could be
others for example um let's go to
wikipedia my mind type
there are quite a few others do they
have a list
um
they probably have a list somewhere here
so but you can see several uh different
mind types you know you know multi part
slash mixed okay content type
uh text slash plane content type
application
octet string so you see now it says
content type that's a that's a later
thing
you know originally it's uh called mind
type okay so anyway uh wait
so do they have a list of mind types you
know so this you are looking at rfc
now ifc is the standard
uh
organization you know the
publishing standards in a unix era you
know in 1980s
in 1990s just just like
the incomprehensible
uh
ecmascript okay so
so i've been going over the ecmascript
let me let me show you the
the the
the page again ecmascript
incomprehensible okay that's a unix rfc
so yeah we are talking about the history
of the javascript tag
okay so you have type equals to
something then
then
a few years later they decided the
standard organizations and all the you
know elite hacker types they tell us
that
it should be type equals to text slash
javascript
instead of the application because the
thinking changed again because they
think okay javascript is just a text
file so it should be text javascript so
that's a
little history of the
of the javascript tag so this article is
written in
in 2006 so back then you can see here
what does other popular sites use
so for example amazon
uses both type equals to and language
equals to
javascript or something and and they
sometimes also use just um
language equals to
okay so apple apple.com uses language
equals true this is old school okay
language equals three is the very first
way yahoo uses language equals to occur
dot com uses type equals to now you may
not know what is awkward okay is the
google's very first
uh
social network so that's around the year
2004 oakwood it became very popular
so popular and it became so popular in
brazil they google google moved their
oakland headquarters to brazil
that's another big chapter of history
you know
oak could lasted for like 10 years and
google eventually shut it down
they still have a lot users but for i
suppose business reasons google says
okay or code is not making money for us
so they shut it down they shut it down
around
sometimes 2012 or something
but
okay okay
dot com for like
it was very popular okay that's that's
google's first social network then after
that then you have google plus
uh so that's also history you know
google plus from 2010 or something uh
for
for six or seven years also shut down
so all could use type equals to so then
msn.com which is microsoft's uses both
okay so this is an ebay
then google.com
so we have some you know history of the
javascript tag okay that's a little bit
talk about this
now what i want to do is you see there's
this back button
so you go back to the
uh
this index page
uh you know this icon used to be
extremely popular you will usually see
this i icon
where do they
at at where do you see them at the home
page of the elite hackers
for example the linux users
the unix
you know phonetics linux phonetics e-max
phonetics vi phonetics or these type of
people they they will put this
badge on their website
because back then so this is around the
year 2000 okay
basically throughout 2000 people are you
know these type of people are upset
obsessed about this because they say
your html must be valid you know and and
you should be conformed to the w3c
standard organization like every node
every hacker will tell you that if you
don't do that they they you know they
don't like you they disagree
you know if you dare to disagree they
ban you you know they don't like you
they call you a troll you know but today
this this this idea is kind of gone in
fact google
google and html5 people you know what
the [ __ ] group you know that created
html5 they eliminated basically they
don't
they do
not um
they do not um
[Music]
they do not push for the idea of html
correctness you know
yeah and uh also xml diet anyway so that
icon used to be everywhere as you know
among us like
we uh
our type of people
so this page is the index of several
articles about web history
okay so what i want to do i want to
i want to first of all
make this uh back button okay so make
this back button into just
web tech history okay this is too long
html validation history and politics too
long i just want that i just want to say
web history okay so let's start to do
work
um
okay nobody's here comments okay
comments guys
so first of all let me put some of the
link here
that the things we talked about
mind type
mind
type close that
ecmascript okay ecmascript javascript
um
ecmascript
the job javascript specification
uh and
and that that that make a link
showing browser so that is what we
talked about today okay so actually so
this one
make a link
show in browser okay that's what we
talked about
today
okay now i want to do some
some work okay so first of all we
rename that okay
copy that
open it
so you can see the navigation bar is
this one so let's change the name okay
uh
let's see what directory is this okay
now i'm going to call xa
find replace text you can see in the
pink window
so this is the text i want to replace
okay
then replace it by
just say web tech history
okay do it
do it all for all um
[Music]
pages yeah
uh
yeah
do it
level directory level zero two nine
that's fine right changes to file yes
yes yes yes yes
okay so you can see the currencies and
uh the pages they occur for example
let's open this one showing browser so
this is another history page html style
1999 hacker news
this is also interesting because when
you go to hacker news
uh
so this one is written in 2013.
i believe it's still the case if you go
to hackernews.com
you look at their source code for html
their html is written in a style of 1999
so uh you know let's let's check for fun
okay let's go see uh
hackernews.com
let's see you know
whether they have updated modernize
their um
html so
ctrl c uh wait no not windows um control
u to see the source code okay select or
copy close shrink back to emacs
open a new page paste it here uh into
html mod magnify let's let's go top
magnify so let's see the html what
yep this is um
you see they are still using table tags
table the whole thing is a table
uh table tags tr
okay it's a bit better than the
then
than the 2013
because they
they no longer use you know back then if
you if we look at my screenshot here
still the same thing yeah okay oh yeah
so you see
what's uh in particular what stand out
is you see this font size
tag
that is very
much 1999. html font you know you use
the font tag to change the font size and
font color you see they use the font tag
but let's see if they still use that
search for font
okay
they no longer use that
okay finally uh hacker news
do not use the 1999
html style
you know why do they use that because
paul graham he's a old school you know
when you get old you tend to
uh not
not picking up new technology so paul
graham just like me grew up with html
you know html back in the 1990s you know
he just used the fun tag and
yeah that's funny
so but now finally they um
they changed um
so
comments the sound of the keyboard is
soothing my mac is so crappy okay
hello from programming topics
constructed human languages programming
languages and regularity of syntax okay
that topic um
that topic i can talk for long
for long but we already kind of um
how long have i been talking i already
talked for 40
30 minutes so
i guess let's continue today with um
web technology history okay yeah i guess
let's continue with web technology
history
uh then maybe we talk about that
so anyway the source code of hacker news
let's look a little bit more so
you see 26 points
let's see
and i don't want that okay so
okay you see they still use center tag
that's interesting center tag is also
kind of obsolete tag
yeah center tag is 1999.
nobody uses that i i'm not sure even i
think it's
the tag is actually obsolete you know
like it's illegal let's see what version
of html they use
html um
yeah yeah i mean they
let's see uh go to one of my of my page
doc type that
yeah they don't you know they are not
you know the hacker news website is not
it you know html conformant
uh so when you
you know they
they they are not qualified to put this
even html 4.0
it's just a syntax soup tech soup
the hacker news
you can check by the way you know today
okay so a lot of people may not know
there's a
html
validator
created by you know validator h
by the w3c
uh group validation service you know you
you're pasting hacker news and it's it's
trying to do it
hackanews.com are we sure that's his
correct address
uh
yeah okay hackernews.com i'm pretty sure
yeah okay
check
it's gonna light up like a christmas
tree you see
errol start texting without seeing a
doctype first exactly you see it it
needs to have be that
you know this is just a tax loop
there's no you know there's no such uh
that
you know so arrow arrow you know it it
you know it lights up like a christmas
tree
so you know back then
in year 2000s
the hacker types
in particular like just like hacker news
the people who go through hacker news
they all
wanna you know they all like push for
uh they are all fanatical about
html
uh
correctness
but
i guess not paul graham you know
so anyway so that's hacker news website
that's hacker news uh html okay so
uh that topic you know you know yeah
yeah so so like i said like i said you
know you guys you know
uh watch my video um you go early you
you know you coming here early in the
first five minutes you say that i'll
talk about that because there's a lot to
say about that
about the language syntax regularity of
programming language syntax simplicity
and regularity of programming syntax and
related to
human language syntax regularity of
human language syntax such as english
french chinese japanese and so on
there's a kind of a sharp contrast a
very interesting topic
okay so um so anyway so hacker news okay
so
we just changed the
uh back to web tech
history correctness and html correctness
and validators okay some of the pages
not changed let's do that again
close that
open this page
copy that
do replacement okay
then you want to say
web
tech history okay
do it
okay
all these files change to the browser
refresh
fantastic
web tech history
okay so several articles now there's one
more thing i want to do
i want to move all these into a
uh
left panel can i do that let's see let's
open that
so
you can see
yeah you can do that but um
multi-dimensional arrays what's the
topic of day
you guys you know you gotta come early
so
when i begin so
okay so i kind of um
what
what do we do now what do we do next
we already talked for 40 minutes um
so we have 20 minutes left so
let's see what's this page close that
what is this page html correctness in
validate validators
uh close that
close that
programming block closed that
html style 1999 hacker news
yeah you know it's interesting that paul
graham his website is still using image
map
you know image map is a technology
that
you know it's that's this is
you know this panel on the left side
that's that's not text that's an image
map
it's funny
uh i i'm gonna show you what they are
okay um
open image you see so
you see this is paul graham's
this old hacker's website and the left
panel is using a image tag
so what is a what image map so what is
the image map so you go to html you go
to the html tutorial
and here
this
you know this old school teach you what
is image map you you probably you won't
find a tutorial about that anymore i
don't think so not much so image map is
that you see this image
now if i move the cursor watch my cursor
into the big eye
oh i need javascript on or is it
wait
here example sometimes you want a image
to have sensitive areas that will have
different behavior this is done with
html image map okay
so move your mouse over the big eye then
a alert box will pop up
you know it's not popping up [ __ ]
okay
i screwed up my website uh
oh or is it because image maps are not
supported anymore oh yeah what's what's
going on
so go to this go to my site uh go to
this url let's
there it is okay it's not working in
varvardi because
because
image maps okay so this is a new thing
image map does not work when you have a
local file i suppose that's what happens
but anyway
image map you see i move my mouse over
to the eye and and something will happen
you know so that's what image map you
know
so you can see this is the image
uh and how do you do it you know you
specify
okay uh you
wait
okay so use this is how you do an image
map you use this map tag
now let's see the map tab
tag is it still supported i think it is
it's not obsolete so how do i know you
go here
html tag complete list
then search for
map yeah image map is still supported
because
it's used a lot in you know in 1990s and
early 2000s so
100 you know tens of thousand or 100 000
websites still use that so you cannot
make it obsolete
so that so program is using image map so
you you so so you see you move
your mouse to different area
you know let's let's look at the
you can see control control u to see his
um
his source code
and
search for
map
okay there it is you see this line
map name something something it's a it's
a long line so let's copy the whole
source code shrink the window
and go to emacs open a new buffer paste
it
so here you can see his image map let's
magnify
so you see
this part okay so wait
this part okay so let's
let's make it
like that okay so
magnify magnify so this image map
so we can
we can clean it a little bit so to see
yeah so
so you see those area let's replace area
by a line area so
do that
so now you can
it's easy to see
this section image map
so this is very tedious you know for you
you d you have to find the coordinate in
the image you know the pixel the
position then you say so on that
position if the mouse is on that
position then it's a link to this
article if the mouse is in this position
it's linked to amazon that's uh paul
graham's um
ancient
programs ancient website did i just
close it yeah
um
okay so the program is website let's
open it
there
so what's new with paul graham what's
his latest article good taste beyond
smart weird languages okay weird
languages that's what we are interested
program mxi
mxi the roman numerals very old school
you know today's you know the malaysian
don't know what that is
roman numerals
2021 pg okay
let's see weird languages click on that
august 2021 okay he's still going he's
still writing essays so this is very
short
uh
real languages uh let's read a little
bit when people say that their
experience or they
when people say that in their experience
all programming languages are basically
equivalent
they are making a statement not about
languages but about the kind of
programming they've done
okay that's his
claim
99.5 percent of programming consists of
growing together calls to library
functions all popular languages are
equally good at this
so
one can easily spend one's whole career
operating in the intersection of popular
programming languages
okay that's his claim
then he says but the other point
five percent of programming is
disproportionately interesting
interesting if you want to learn what it
consists of
the weirdness of the weird languages is
a good crew to follow
okay real languages aren't
weird by accident
not the good ones at least the weirdness
of the good ones usually implies the
existence of some form of programming
that's not just the usual green together
of library course
whatever
i don't think this is a
great
opinion i think it's true okay it's true
but it's not uh
uh program it's not a
significant opinion okay so what he's
saying you know weird language yeah of
course i mean this is kind of like a pop
pop
um what do you say
pop scholarship you know it's not even
scholarship it's a
pop
analysis okay that's
you know that's if you are beyond
kindergarten then everyone knows this so
he's saying that you know the typical
languages c plus plus pearl java
javascript you know uh
golan they are all kind of
similar
uh but then he says that but there are
some
languages usually you'll find them weird
okay such as this maybe he probably he
probably has this in his mind you know
at least
uh
ufam language uh
brain [ __ ] for example
uh
and then lots of you know uh
uh apl
um
[Music]
prologue you know
that's what he's talking about i'm
pretty sure because you know
you know because i he's you know we are
in the same generation so he's saying
that these weird languages
happened
um usually they are weird usually
because of design and they
they are interesting because they
solve some problems you've never seen
before basically that's what he's saying
and here comes here comes let me read
this okay
okay he weird languages aren't weird but
excellent blah blah blah okay then he
says a concrete example lisp markers
these markers seem
weird even to many of these programmers
[Laughter]
so this guy
so in my opinion he's getting old he's
he's getting old he's
you know and his essay is out of um
other force you know there's no you know
other force so using these markers you
know today's programmers you guys marine
jeans most of them are familiar with
macros okay not necessarily lisp but
they are they know about marcos okay but
but to him he's still
you know he's still living in the in his
younger days in in 1990s or 2000s
that
that regards this macro or some sort of
weird and fantastic you know that's
cd
and then he says so if you want to
expand your concept of what programming
can be one way to do it is by learning
weird languages yeah idiotic you know
this thought
was popular in 1990s
but after two years he's still basically
writing the same thing you know and this
very short
uh well
poor groundhog that's what happened when
you get old like me
and i suppose nobody you know not many
people read paul graham's website
much anymore i mean most people don't
even know who he is most young people
you know that's what happens to the
generation so if you want to check
you can go
to uh
what's a top what's the website to top
website
this uh one of the amazons
one of the amazon's website
alexa okay alexa
so you go to alexa
turn on javascript so alexa is part of
amazon since 10 10 plus years ago 15
years ago or so they
they um they rank the popularity of
websites you know you may not know
you may not know it but it was
a lot nerds no back then
so um
so
so for example right now the top one is
google youtube tmail timor is china
facebook qq china baidu china sohu china
taobao china
cn china jd.com china
amazon you know the top 10 sites half of
them is all china this
it's amazing because this thing happened
you know i've i've been observing this
uh
this since 10 years ago because i have
articles on that
and i you know all of a sudden you know
like all of them are become china
it's amazing china is doing
so
so okay so you know so we want to see
then then you know like top 100 websites
it's it's like half of them all china
so 11th amazon 12th yahoo 13th wikipedia
or wikipedia fail
you know wikipedia used to be the top
five
beginning about two years ago
google started to remove you know like
used to be
[Music]
two years ago
almost everything you search
um at on google.com wikipedia will be
one of the top results
but two years ago since about 2000 year
2000 they started to change that and
i've noticed that happening across the
web
wikipedia because wikipedia is
part of the reason is because there's so
many so much propaganda you know the
anyway anyway so
14th weibo weibo china 15th saint cena
china 16th
uh
xinhua net china 17th
zoom zoom okay
18th live.com that's microsoft and 19th
netflix
threaded okay
so you want to type program here so can
you can i still type um
what
by country by category okay
you know my website is probably is you
know i'm pretty sure it's more popular
than
than programs
but not not hacker news
uh so where do i
okay click on google okay
yeah so here you can type program okay
so program.com
you can see his ranking
so this site ranks
29 000 okay this site
rents 29 000
000.
wow that's pretty high
wait so i'm not sure my website will
beat it now
so let's see sardi dot info
oh [ __ ] now i'm
121. wait
poorgrandham.com
what
yeah let's open the new
window here [ __ ]
make sure this is program are we
correct because
okay that is the site
this site ranking
29th
wow so he's actually
going up
because for many years you know even my
website is more popular than program
[ __ ]
okay
uh
this is the past
three months
okay so i think that's it for today so
what else uh simono man says i wanted to
ask about how you taught yourself to
write articles
the way you do
i want to start writing two but find it
difficult
how to articulate your ideas well you
know so my answer would be passion okay
so how did i begin
so you know for for example i you know i
wasn't born in usa so i wasn't a native
speaker
body english okay so worthy english
so you can see my blog
you can see my kind of blog about
um
you know now i moved my domain so you go
to
xari.info now it's along saudi.info back
to worthy english
back to
saudi.org
saudi.org then you go to worthy english
here is my
blog about my diary about all things
related to writing to literature to
linguistics okay
so
so let me get just focus on the topic so
so i learned english starting when i was
okay
in
in in montreal in canada okay so
then i'm obsessed i want to
i really want to master the language
well
and the way i began is because you know
for example i have articles about how to
increase your vocabulary i bought this
thing three hundred dollars back then so
this is 1988 i bought this electronic
dish dictionary 199 1988. now remember
the back then so this is like 300 or 500
fairly expensive
of course you know so it's just a
dictionary okay but today's phone is
like 100 times more powerful than
whatever that is
but i bought this because i i look up
words like literally literally more than
100 times every day every single day for
like over ten for more than ten years
that's my obsession right my habit
because the way i thought i'm going to
learn english is by just knowing all the
words you know i'm like a nerd i'm a
nerd i'm a
naive okay it's pretty naive this
because this way of learning english is
very inefficient but
i was just naive and i was like brute
force i'm gonna brute force the [ __ ]
[ __ ] it i'm gonna be the master of
english but no i i would know english
better than all the english professors
and how am i going to do that
just read in read you know look up words
every day
that's that was my obsession okay
so i started to you know i bought this
dictionary then this is my original
dictionary
english to chinese
you know so
you know i so in the beginning i don't
know english right so i you know english
on i i look at the chinese definition to
learn it then eventually i switched to
all english dictionary so i mean so why
am i doing this it's a passion okay
it i just want to i just
i just want to i think i can you know
that's a
passion
so even you know so
um
okay so that's one part of the story
okay then i have you know i'm obsessed
about dictionaries so back then for you
know for more than 10 years for 20 years
not so much today
i'm getting old you know i'm about to
die soon
you won't see me doing youtube much
anymore but for 20 years in my in my 20s
to 30s
i you know i i look up dictionary like
more literally more than 100 times a day
i can you know this thick this thick
dictionary
let's open that okay
this
this thick dictionary this that's about
this thick this is the biggest
chinese
the biggest english chinese dictionary
at the time okay there's no bigger
there's no bigger i wanted the biggest
one so that again
every word i can find the definition so
i had my father about this in taiwan i
think it's brought from taiwan so send
me you know i got this dictionary stick
i looked at them so much to the point
that given any word i can open it one
shot and and and arrive at the correct
page just
because you do it so much you know you
just open in one shot that's the correct
page okay
so
that was my obsession
on vocabulary by the way which is a very
inefficient way to learn english
you know this so
um
so perhaps part you can still see part
of that
trait in my writing yeah you can't you
so it's not
okay so so when it comes to writing
there are many things to this okay so
i just described
uh kind of my history of learning
english you know focusing on vocabulary
vocabulary
but then
i also got interested in writing english
why because back then in the 1990s i was
very into mathematics so i go to online
forum you know i talked about yesterday
you know compuserve so there's a
forum just like you know analogous to
today's discord you go there you
have you know
back then i go there ask math questions
debate you know argue also a lot of
argument because math just like any
subject you you can
you know like what's what's the best way
to learn calculus what's your favorite
calculus book you know some people post
opinions then i would say oh i read that
but i don't i don't like that one
because you know blah blah blah
so back then 1990s you know i my english
it was not just so good but i wanted to
you know i got into you know
talking with people you know i want to
tell them what i think or what or learn
from them you know you know so there's a
lot argument which is still going on
today like among us you know we argue
about things over especially politics
you know so
so
so you i just type a lot you know a lot
you go you know you wake up you you you
dial up to the computer then you see
what's going what people say did
did they reply to my to my uh to my
opinion there you know you want to know
so also you make friends
so i started to do that just
you know typing uh learning math and
typing and that
turns out to be very significant
in
improving your english writing skills
very significant like today we have
nimshiku okay
we have this china room
and here is all politics usually very
you know we argue a lot okay
i have two enemies here whose opinion i
disagree okay but so we argue a lot
but ninjiku from my what i know you know
he doesn't
so he so
he i don't think he's writing skill is
that great okay he usually does not
you know you you want to be able to
express precisely
what it is that you want to say
and when you do a lot writing it also
hones your
thinking abilities your logic your
analysis abilities so
this kind of is connected okay writing
writing
and analysis you know logic you know
kind of abilities
and
so writing
thinking and
knowledge okay knowledge is also a
fundamental part of it because if you
don't know things you don't have content
you don't if you don't have opinion like
today's malenchen okay today's [ __ ]
millennial generations they don't have
opinion
they don't know they don't know nothing
they don't have opinion they go they
just blah mean they just know about
means put it
me me me mean [ __ ]
[ __ ] the male engine that's
that's and the zoomers today that's what
they do uh over reddit on hacker news
at best they can they can they they
might write one paragraph of something
you know because in twitter you know
because they grew up that way twitter
enforce
character limits oh jesus you cannot
even even type more than 24 50
characters you know twitter
so they these people grew up that way
you know they they lost the ability to
write think or even form opinions they
don't they don't have none
so in order to write i would claim okay
so i mean yeah so i would claim in order
you you want to learn to
write well there are
kind of three related things i mean
first i mean the the most first of all
you need to have a desire a passion okay
do you really want to uh
yes i think so you do so you want so
desire that's a passion that's the first
the most important passion
not just writing or study math or
programming or anything or being a great
lawyer bringing being a great you know
doctor or doing good in school or
whatever whatever is your life goal i
mean if you even if you don't have a
life goal that's fine too you know you
can um as long as you have money that's
it that's fine but anyway passion is the
most important thing okay passion
then
you need to exercise you know you need
to practice okay
so okay let me let me write write kind
of a summary uh um
so we we have um
we have a coherent um
kind of thing
how to learn writing
or writing well okay
history of how i learn
english okay
that's
my personal history focusing on studying
reading dictionaries
how to learn right how to learn writing
well okay
then
foremost
desire
passion okay
then
practice practice practice practice once
you have a passion you tend to do it all
the time like in our forum we have
people into guitar or bass you know the
russian guy link he plays so much he
you know he grew characters hurts his
hands you know but he still wants to do
it you know you wake up tomorrow you
still want to do it this is a strong
desire you just want to you love it okay
passion they end practice they usually
go
hand in hand you know once you love
something you're gonna keep doing it
keep doing it
then you will improve okay then
the three elements
three elements about writing well
thinking
analysis abilities
content
knowledge
opinions okay
you know if you don't have opinion on
something
there's nothing you're gonna write okay
you gotta have opinion where do you get
opinion you get an opinion from
experience knowledge learning okay
for example programming you know we like
to debate a lot of us which programming
is best you know some people say rust
i say wufang language then
a hot dog
is an idiot
he thinks wufang language is gonna
write linux by itself you know so we
have opinions where do we where's
opinion because
i'm passionate about programming i've
done a lot i've read a lot
that's what i say what i say and he's
got opinions about you know he also done
a lot so opinions you're gonna have them
from knowledge and learning that's your
that's the content of your writing okay
without you know without opinion you
don't have content doesn't matter how
well how how many words you know you
know how many
you know you know shakes three awards
doesn't
does nothing you don't have content you
gotta have opinion
um then okay so that's
then the third most important is the
the actual
writing
skill so this part involves you have to
know vocabulary you have to know the new
nuances of the words you have to know
the grammar you know you have to know
the grammar well you have to know idioms
you know for example
vocabulary grammar
idioms
writing style then you get into writing
style because even
great writers they have different styles
of expressing the same thing some is
like more fluid some is more logical
some is uh concise or something is so
simple
uh and some is you know some is just a
joy to read and while some is like
more scholarly very difficult to read
but but but they use the word correctly
you know so there's so dense content you
know many different styles they are and
for example programming documentation
that belongs to technical writing that's
a particular style
so so okay so so
so here
uh i say
let's okay that's kind of uh what we
talked about how to uh right where okay
i think that's it today
uh we talked for
over an hour now
uh
okay thank you guys no pay me okay
if you like my stuff donate okay paypal
patreon
you know amazon gift card or
you can buy
you know my tutorials on emacs on emac
list
on javascript you know i have you know
just go to my website sally.org
uh you'll find lots of my patreon and so
on links
okay that's it i think that's it for
today so one hour it's good so i'm gonna
shut down any further questions
yeah so your question i wanted to ask
you about how do you
teach yourself uh
you know to write articles i want to
start writing too but find it difficult
so how do you articulate your idea well
yeah so
so this
on that specific question how do you
articulate your idea well
so that part that part will be practice
practice
and no grammar no vocabulary and
you know
that helps and how do you know
vocabulary how do you learn grammar well
this you can you can of course read the
grammar in basic english grammar or
style guides there are a lot of them but
mostly you get them from reading so you
read novels you read you read
works
written by
a great english writer so novelist you
know in the past you know classic novels
you pick up you know then you can pick
up their style how they express things
you know
so that that is how
to improve your articulation and most
importantly practice you just need to
write okay you can you know
yeah
um
okay that that's it so i'm just gonna
copy some of my
things i talked about and paste it on
sas talk show
page so
uh we can reference to it later for
other people so
vocabulary okay so very interesting
english vocabulary so we talked about
paul graham
program the classic nerd
um and this this is surprising his
website is becoming very popular now
[ __ ] you know i'm very competitive now
his website is more popular than me i
want to know why though
because i don't
you know i don't imagine
that his website
yeah thank you welcome you're welcome
uh
you know it's funny when i was in school
in taiwan i am the worst
writer i mean not you know like in
school when you are in uh high school
okay
you know in chinese i mean in taiwan
okay they also have
they also have you know classes you know
course in chinese just like uh you know
writing in in in usa you know so you
every week that you got a homework
you're supposed to write an essay okay
i don't know how to i have no like like
that is the biggest problem
like
my score in high school i was kicked out
kind of
because my
you know in taiwan
each class you know each class
in high school we have like about 50
people
and every month or every week every
every time there's an exam
we rank
the scores of all students
and i'm always in the last five okay
that's how bad i was in school
you know things change yeah yeah i mean
that's why you don't have to like stick
to school you know just a great if you
graduate from harvard [ __ ] harvard you
know that
especially today they don't know they
don't know things they don't know
nothing
meanwhile you have dropouts like like
you know like bill gates steve jobs they
are college dropouts but they
they know much they know you [ __ ]
business you know mba whatever
phd or whatever you know
so you don't have to
you know like follow the establishment
you know the formal education or
whatever what whatever so anyway when i
was in high school i was always the last
five my school is always last five and
to the degree so that i didn't graduate
because i
i failed everything i failed in
i i think i passed in math everything
else i failed
so i that's that was middle school i
didn't you know they they cannot give me
a graduation
uh certificate so they gave me a
kind of like like you you attended this
middle school certificate
instead
you know so when so when i was that age
when there's a homework essay i don't
know what to write like i
what do i write there you know like
today's topic like or even diary you
know i can i can write a diary you know
today is saturday okay today is 2021
november
23rd and the weather is nice
um the weather is very very nice
you know you want to add more words you
know so the very is very the weather is
very nice and the weather is
very nice uh
anything i don't know what to say
anymore like
yeah it's very interesting
so we talked about image tag so that's
it today we closing down
image map
okay and here close that
close that paul graham's website close
that yeah paul graham's website funny
programs web
web style 19.99
yeah i already did that okay
go
history of javascript tag
mind type
mind type ecmascript history of
javascript
uh about math
i kind of talked about that before but
you know i don't have a set schedule but
do come in if you see my video do come
in early and say that because that will
be better i can talk about that topic in
the beginning
and you know follow on discord you can i
usually announce it two or three hours
before
bye guys