hello good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of s talk show today is
advent of a code day two okay we are
going to get right onto it uh let's
see that advent of code day two in wolam
language okay so check out yesterday
that's day one okay so let's start
coding W fam if you are here say hi
okay so Advent of two uh day two so
let's just get straight to
it uh so day two uh that's the right
answer okay that's day one return to a
vent of code calendar let's say day
two and uh move here so you can see oh
yeah so switch screen so there it is the
day two problem
okay uh
okay you are launched High into the
atmosphere the Apex of your trajectory
just barely reaches the surface of a
large island floating in the
sky hello hello guys starting to come in
so this is my keyboard kesis 360 okay
search s kinesis 360 keyboard you'll
find my YouTube review and my website
and this is timate hacking keyboard both
are great okay so day two Cube conundrum
Sol in wolen language you are launched
High into the atmosphere the aex of your
trajectory just barely reaches the
surface of a large island floating in
the sky okay so you gently gently land
land in a fluffy pile of leaves it is
quite cold but you don't see much snow
an elf runs over to greet you okay so
the elf explains that you arrived at
Snow Island and apologizes for the lack
of snow you'll be happy to explain the
situation but it's a bit of a walk so
you have
to so you so you have some
time they don't get many visitors up
here would you like to play a game in
the meantime as you walk as you walk the
elf shows you a small bag and some cubes
which are either red green or blue okay
a bag of red green or
blue each time you play this game he
will hide a secret number of cubes of
each color in the bag okay and your goal
is to figure out information about the
number of Cubes so he's going to hide
some of the cubes some some red some
blue some green red green blue right you
you you need to figure out how many are
each so to get information once the bag
has been loaded with cubes the elf will
reach into the bag grab a handful of
random cubes show them to you and then
put them back in the bag put them back
in the bag he'll do this a few times per
game okay for each game is a bag of
cubes of different color he's going to
grab some show it to you put it back
okay now you play several games and
record the information from each game
your personal input okay so each time he
show you you record it that's your input
each game is listed with its ID number
like the like the ll in game LL game 11
what what what is game
incomprehensible okay each game is
listed with its ID number followed by a
semicolon separated list of subsets of
Cubes that were revealed from the
bag okay each game is listed with its ID
number okay uh followed by a semicolon
separated list of
subsets list of subsets separated by
semicolon of Cubes that were revealed
from the back like three red five green
four blue okay but he uses coma that's
not
semicolon uh so for example the record
of few games might look like this okay
that's like like that's like your input
so let's write it
down uh for example showing browser so
this is uh today's Talk Show YouTube
link let's link it showing browser okay
so that's your uh so let's look at the
input game one okay that 1 two 3 4
that's the ID number idiotic so game one
three blue four
red oh
okay so in each game he does this the
elf does this a few times each time
shows you some cube with their color how
many are there so first time four red
four blue
uh three blue three blue four red second
time one red two green third time six
blue two green that's the first game he
showed he showed it you three times okay
so game two uh same thing
okay okay so each game he show you
several times each time is uh how many
blue how many red how many green okay in
game one three sets of cubes are
revealed from the back
three sets of Cubes reveal from the back
then put back again right okay the first
set is three blue cube uh cubes and four
red three blue four red that's
right okay and uh the second set is one
red two green check uh and six
blue check okay the third set is only
two green okay check understand the
problem okay the elf would first like to
know which game would have been possible
if the bag contains only 12 red cubes 13
red 13 green and 14 blue okay let's see
the elf would
like would first like to know implying
this more than one question maybe the
the elf would first like to know which
games would have been
possible if the bag contains only 12 red
13 green and 14
blue which games would have been
possible okay so you require some
thinking here so if the bag
contains 12 red 13 blue I mean 12 red 13
green 14
blue that is the whole set of Cubes okay
that's a whole complete total so each
time he's going to grab some show it to
you put it back mix grab some show it to
you put it back do it a few times now
the the elf would like first to know
which games would have been
possible
so what does possible mean well
obviously for one case is that if he
showed you 100 blue
then then you know the if the bag only
uh contains 12 blue then that's not
possible right
so so in each so given this information
that there are a total of 12 red 13
green 14 blue
you you can
eliminate any of the game and any of the
draw if there's more color than in the
back then that is obviously not possible
now there's a question once he draw it
does it put it back I think he does
let's see let's double check okay so to
get uh to get information once the back
has been loaded with Cube the elf will
reach into the bag grab a handful of
random cubes show them to you and put
them back in the bag he'll do this a few
times per game right so he will'll put
it
back so okay so I have a clue what is
the first thing he wanted to know so
it's just basically counting uh let's
see yeah so for example let's take game
one the first Str is three blue four red
now if any of this number is more than
the color in the back then that's not a
possible game right so you check that
one game one for each game there are
several draws so for each
draw of a game you
check if it's you know if if if there's
more than color in the back then that
means this whole game is not possible so
you you don't have to continue with the
other draws as you find as as soon as
you found one game one draw that has
more color than is possible then
eliminate that game okay that's all
probably what he's asking so in the
example above game 125 would have been
possible if the back had been loaded
with that
configuration what
however however game three would have
been
impossible because at one point the elf
showed you 20 red cubes let's check game
three there is 20 red however it says
there are only 12 red okay check so
obviously game three is not possible
okay uh if you add up the IDS of the
game that would have been possible you
get eight Okay so basically the question
is which game is not possible okay this
suing Edy you know this Advent of
uh Advent of code likes to get the
answer by some name you know it's one
kind of way to verify so it's this is
like a uh uh binary um bit checking it's
uh correction code you know so you sum
them up if the number matches matches
then you kind of know you are you got
the correct answer but this is
not the perfect perfect way to validate
correct answer for example in this
question you could
ask the person the person server to list
all the games that's not possible you
know just a list of numbers that's one
way to verify it but you know as I as
far as I learned this ADV EV of code has
a habit always like just sum sum it up
get a number so well maybe because
that's easier to check because then you
have to do the website you have to
validate the answer if it's just a
number it's
easier yeah but with a number you have
you you you it's possible to have
ambiguities so for example let's say
the you see for this test input the
correct answer is eight it say right but
how many possible ways for a bunch of
integers that sums to eight you can have
17 you can have 2 six you can have 44
right you can have three five right so
there are many possible ways to sum up
to eight so even so you might get it
wrong and but you still get the right
answer so this is ambiguity in the
design of the puzzle that's a criticism
of the puzzle okay so
anyway uh so let me read the comment in
a bit okay so first question determine
which games would have been
possible if the B had been loaded with
only 12 red 13 green and
14 blue okay now there is another issue
with the per with the personal
representation because now this sentence
12 red 13 green 14 blue is
repeated you know once it repeats then
you have to double check is that is that
the same thing are you are you
just are you just repeating for emphasiz
or just reminding us or or is it some
new
value okay criticism of the about the
writing of the person and design of the
person okay but
anyway so you need to find what is uh
what would have been possible okay so
find the possible games sum their ID up
that's should be the answer what is the
sum of the ID of those
games okay so basically for the test
input it's
eight now you need to get your personal
input okay let's get our personal input
okay select all now we did this
yesterday we know um let's open a new
file let's save it to a file because oh
it's actually not too big
uh only 100 okay that's in that case we
don't need to
um okay so let's just input equals
to that okay so it's just uh 100 lines
okay again one okay so that's wam code
let's put a semi semicolon so it
suppresses the suppress is printing the
this expression close
that okay determine which game okay we
know the uh what is a person now the
problem is to let's write
code take off your
clothes so let's read the comment a bit
I also have Logitech yeah Logitech 502
is fantastic I recommend it go to my
keyboard blog and uh go to uh Mouse and
uh here is my recommendation of mouse
expired from Amazon from my affiliate
link okay let's
see I don't want to interrupt your flow
or thought process with uh with uh what
is
this while solving the problem for the
first time okay yeah you probably solved
it already I uh
assume okay let's let's let's get back
to the code okay
so so let's close that okay copy let's
put the link
here okay so back to the code
now close that now
okay so now you got a bunch of
lines okay you first of all you want to
pass out the game
ID uh well so you
see let's start code okay first of all
split split
lines split the input then you got a
list okay so the length of the list is a
number of lines okay
so just print it let's run
it okay so you got a long list right so
uh okay put a semicolon and you can say
length Okay print
it so you can see
what 2352 we split it wrong so string
split you need to have you by default is
split by y space so now you need to tell
it to split by um by
the by the new line character okay run
it 100 so that's correct game 100 so
once you split then you take out so you
don't need the game ID because it's just
a
index Okay so so you take out the you
know remove the game ID then you then
you split again you split by the semi
colon
okay
uh let's see let's see stream part
stream part is like taking the substring
in most programming languages they call
substring okay so let's turn on
JavaScript let's look at the
documentation so string string part okay
string part takes a
substring via the position of the string
via the index of the string which is not
what we want because we want some kind
of pattern to remove because game one
and game 100 they have different um
length so so we want string
uh uh string
take uh let's see string take does it
take a regular expression
no we want uh stream drop stream
position string starts string partition
let's see string
drop no those are all go by position so
now go to S wam tutorial let me
introduce you again my wam tutorial you
can click on this link to download wam
engine for free so you can run it just
like I do and learn it for my uh wolam
Language tutorial okay this is kind of
complete for programmers and unique you
won't find that because you usually
other wam tutorials Mathematica is like
teaching you math calculus solving
equations or do uh uh physics or
chemistry and you know so the my
tutorial is for programmers for the
hardcore programmers C Java python uh
goand uh
people so anyway so so you go to string
so let's see string functions uh string
uh string replace string pattern uh test
sub string get substring okay so string
take is take by position string cases
return a uh pass a string by regular
expression we want string replace okay
that's what we want string replace part
okay okay we want string replace which
which replace a string by a pattern okay
so actually we can use
that so so the pattern is like this okay
so let's search for now we want to make
sure is there always a space after semi
code col yes there
is you see there's always a space after
semicolon so we can just all we can do a
trim after but anyway
so uh
so so we have something like that game
100 replace it by empty string and uh
then the um so for each of the line so
first of all we split by line
so map okay map
[Music]
to X list and by a function so just like
yesterday let's write a
function
uh let's use the full syntax so people
understand what we are doing so function
so you map a function to this x list
which is each line and the function will
the argument is X then the function body
we will
[Music]
be X okay stream replace uh stream
replace replace that game thing okay so
we don't care about efficiency let's
just run
it okay so here is the huge thing now we
still have the world game one uh what's
going
on no we did remove it uh did we let's
say game
no we didn't remove it something
something is wrong oh yeah we say 100
that's again you know we need a pattern
so a pattern uh you need a regular
expression here so let's do it regular
expression okay so replace this string
by uh
regular okay so in instead of the game
100 you say regular expression the full
word okay in wam language everything is
every computation is done by a function
so a function name uh full name not not
slash slash or whatever you know crypted
cryptic crap okay so the game 100 so
what to represent a sequence of Digit
is uh back slash D or is it slash D back
slash d so you add a plus uh Sign Plus
sign means one or more okay so one or
more digit followed by a colon and space
okay so let's uh let's
R uh syntax unknown string Escape okay
this is wrong unknown string
Escape why why is it uh is is it double
slash then oh God this
is yeah it's double slash just like Emax
okay here's the interesting part just in
in emac disp and in general in disp emac
disp scheme disp common disp they don't
have a special you know when you use a
regular expression
pattern in other languages that pattern
is a special string have a special
meaning okay but in L in wolam language
you don't have such thing a string is
always a string so in a
string if you want back slash D you have
to put a back slash in front in in front
of the backs slash so back slashback
slash D that means matching any digit
okay so this is how it is so for example
we can now it works so we can take the
first line okay run it you it'll show
the first line right so you can see the
game is good okay so once you do that
you remove the games now let's see go
back you remove the games then you split
by semicolon again okay it's then you
split by semicolon so once you have this
then
you split by semicolon okay so
again string split
uh first of all is a string second
argument is what you want to split by in
this case semicolon and uh usually we
should put the space because all the
input have a space just but in case they
don't have it let's use trim instead so
check the documentation for split string
and uh uh check if there's option that
automatic removes y
space yeah or we can use regular
expression again okay so let's do
it okay regular
expression then
semicolon space one or more zero or more
so zero or more is that okay so split
string by that
then the string will be this expression
okay so wam language again it's all
nested functions just like Lis okay so
uh and we can show the first line result
run
it
incorrect it should return it should
return the list oh it
did fantastic you see it returned the
list but
but you see one of the issue is that
wolam doesn't print the quotes so that's
why you got
them uh okay so but so if you want to
show the quotes let's see let me try to
Let's print it okay so there's a print
function you
actually uh print it
explicitly run
it oh yeah now now it's printing
okay now wait so you have to say input
form okay so actually let's remove that
so let's here use a postfix not postfix
notation that's like Unix pipe SL slash
okay now you say input
form input form is is a function that
takes a whatever expression and print
them print them in a input you know the
way you type them in so uh run
it imal syntax okay so yeah this needs
to be go into one line so in normally in
Wu Lang language code you don't
arbitrarily add a new line okay you
cannot do that okay typically a new
line implies is a implicit
multiplication okay however in in places
that Mak sense such as you know this is
a function so uh wait so you can add a
new line here okay so if you not run it
that
work okay wait the input form doesn't
work uh well that's because
um well okay so let's run this in wam
language in the notebook let
start
shiko shiko says stream position okay
shiko is a wolam language programmer
fantastic that's a alternative way so
there is wolam language I mean the wolam
notebook let's let's move it here and
let's
magnify okay and
let's Okay so so first of all we have
100 lines of
input then we have you know then we run
this okay so now notice very nice
formatting automatic you see you see
this double
brackets right here
that's when you paste it in it become
this this thing so it's very nice uh
Auto formatting okay and also when you
shrink the
window you can see H okay let's let's
put it apart
so delete that put it here so now when
you shrink the window I got the too many
input
above yeah so I cannot show this
properly but when you you see they
automatically format in a nice way so
why don't we open a new window let me
just show you
here you see you see the indentation you
see that's why in wam language you you
you don't manually add line you know
line return like the edotic coding
industry C Java python you know all the
whole thing uh style guide you should
not have longer lines than 80 characters
the extreme idiocy now look at
so when you have that style guide and
that Concept in your mind that tradition
that formatting you will never develop
this technology okay I talked about this
many times to programmers for wolam had
this for for for for 20 years 25 years
by now the the average industrial
programmers don't know they don't know
they don't know what you're talking
about I did a video about this line you
know um
you know I I red about this and I did
two live streams at least and the
industrial coders including some in our
s Forum they they don't know what you're
talking about this anyway so this is
interesting okay so let's back to uh so
let's evaluate this okay shift enter so
evaluated now let's run this code shift
enter there it is now you can see the
you see it's a list but it now it prints
the quote quotation sign so you have a
list of three things that's the first
line okay so but in the if you are
running wam script in the you know
in let's run
it so you see if you are running wam
script it doesn't understand the input
form uh so this is a reason you want to
pay to buy w language okay uh you know
get the
harist version which is Discount okay so
so we got that part so we we now we
split the lines now we just
check H God now we need to extract
numbers okay so question are the Leist
numbers always in particular order so we
have blue red green blue red green but
here is red green okay so the so you you
cannot rely on Old because sometimes
it's just one color
okay
so I'm thinking so you can use a hash
table a dictionary to to store how many
is green you know Green the color is a
key the value is a
number yeah that's a easiest way okay so
let's go back to the problem so what is
our problems yeah so we just need to
know we just need to
know if any of this number is greater
than yeah okay so here is the here is
also the essential input so we need also
essential input let's
see now let's see the what's the actual
input because so far
as far as I know you need two input one
is the game record the other one is how
many things in the back so let's get uh
oh wait oh wait this is already the real
input okay but the for for the to input
do we have the to input yeah okay so
let's copy the to input as
well so here is the to
input and let's just make it
okay so for the total input the solution
is
eight okay but now you also need
this so again the Advent of a code they
do not have a very specific requirement
for input so you can you can encode this
input any way you like so let's directly
put into a hash
table okay in wolam language a hash
table is
Association uh actually Association is
pretty new I haven't used that
much
yeah
Association or hashtable or associative
list is added to wfam language
around uh
2015 or something after 2010 so it's
added pretty late because wolam language
doesn't you know but anyway that's
another story so let's add Association
okay so
red 12
basically uh let's just uh let's just do
this
okay 30
green 14 blue
okay okay that's
the total bag
okay let's let's say big
bag run
it good that tells us at least our
syntax is correct so now we have the
association now we can check if the
let's check okay so if I have let's say
I want Association now I I haven't
worked with Association much but let's
just solve this problem okay uh let's go
to I have some tutorial about
Association I started to
write assoc Association key value pairs
okay so now we want how do you get value
okay
so there are so many ways okay I'm not
too familiar with this
okay look up look up is what you
do let's just say back okay so look up
in the back and the key let's say red uh
uh if it doesn't exist let's
say let's just say 01 okay wait let's
just
say if it doesn't exist let's say false
okay now run
it
12 that's correct because we have 12 red
okay so this is how you get value okay
so so far so now becoming very simple so
here
is um so this is a lookup code now
we so far we have a list of colors now
we want to turn this list of colors
into uh
into into a Association into a
dictionary Okay so
so so we have a list of
colors now we need to turn that
into Association now there are many ways
to do it okay I'm not sure which one
because I'm not too familiar with
Association so how do you turn this you
know usually very easy so let's try
let's
just okay let me let me just try some
something
here okay so suppose this is your thing
and
uh okay so this is our real code now
before that is testing code
okay this is just just our toy like
testing some uh wfam language stuff so
now we want to turn
this okay how do you do that uh and this
is look
up okay so here is a lookup dick and now
we want to turn this into a dick how do
you do that so you
can string split
by regular
expression comma space one or more okay
get rid of the
space okay
so so you got a list then for each so
you
okay here is what we can
do create
Association I should have a
shortcut but anyway create a Association
inside again remember the argument
should have be a list of rules like this
okay so here is a list of rules so what
you do is you put this inside you split
them first so the first element is like
that a
string then
you you can probably do it easier
because but let's just push on okay
so you split
again and this time you split by a space
you
split by a space okay
so you split by a space then you reverse
the
items look up documentation reverse
reverse the order that's right
then you reverse then you add
um then you can just add uh once you
reverse and change the head to rule okay
so okay this is getting
complex uh that you change the head to
rules uh yeah
yes uh change the head to rules
so okay this is probably not
comprehensible to you guys
but so change the head to rules that's
that should be
it
okay so this will turn
turn a string like that into
a dictionary okay so we can run it run
it okay syntax rule okay so we got a
problem uh rule code with three
arguments okay uh rule code with three
arguments let's
see
why is it three arguments oh you need to
map not not right
so so you need
to okay so you need
[Music]
to
yeah okay I I don't think you guys can
understand but it will take a while to
explain okay so actually you just need a
third
arguments uh one okay
so there okay run
it there it is so you you can see this
second
line that's
the that is the
um dictionary but however we got
the we got the order incorrect why is
the order
incorrect we split
by let's see four red three blue right
so we need to reverse
it so we got so which Lin this four blue
seven red five green four blue seven red
white
green which line is that came
from first line okay first line in the
real input
okay
so
so right so why is it not reversed I we
just applied
reverse
run
it yeah it should be rever why why is
the reverse not work remove
it
oh okay
so let's try
this okay so let's try
this okay so actually level two I
think
okay this is the real
Association I
mean you know so if you
say yeah not
associate so the the the the printed
representation of this dictionary is
that so you see red 12 green 13 now
however this is what we get for this
part which is wrong that's that is
because uh we can try this okay
so okay this is getting
incomprehensible I get I I think for you
guys toos been programming for a long
time hi how do you become this good at
everything I'm not good at everything
I'm not good
in lots of things okay
so let's get back to this okay so now
let's replace
that okay now let's see now if we take
that and
uh okay
actually okay
so okay
so so if we have a list like that then
[Music]
we
apply then we say level one
that will get you what do you want to
apply
uh what is the function you want to
apply the function we want to apply is
Rule okay let's see what you
get you see we get
that which is
correct okay then uh but then you what
you want to do is
[Music]
you you want to attach Association to
it okay do
that you see so the purpose of this
block of
code is just to show that how do you
turn a list of this thing into a
Association like that okay so
so which is what we are trying to do
with the
um uh but there is
something so this reverse needs to map
map it okay so you guys probably don't
understand
but there it is you
see this is this is the the first draw
of game one the line one okay so we got
Association so anyway we got a code so
let's just move on okay so so here is
how you turn it so let's so the real
code here string
split okay so string split
[Music]
then
then you need
to split again
okay then you need
to
apply
okay apply a
rule then
Association okay that's how that's how
it is H you probably you know this code
is getting complex I don't think
you understand what I'm doing
but again something is wrong
oh yeah you split you forgot to give the
second arguments okay so yeah second
argument here is regular
expression so again if you write
everything in the fully nested
functional form it's just like lisp it's
kind of hard to understand run it
again uh still wrong
this is when it's helpful if you code in
the
wam notebook because now you can see it
auto automatically format and you can
click and it will expand by syntactical
unit so you can see where it goes where
uh
so this is first
string
split then we split
Again by the first time is by semicolon
the second time is by space that's right
then
then okay so actually you didn't copy
the whole thing yeah that's why
it's you
see so that's one expression that's one
expression that's one
expression then you reverse so but
um yeah so where is my
error let's see
Association is the Arrow coming out here
or
what yes the arrow came out from
here
but
how did you become good okay so what
else can you uh can you move your emac
window higher on
screen oh okay good good
uh okay let me just concentrate
something this oh God 25 minutes this
should be easy
problem uh
oh I got the plate I place it in a wrong
place I
think so first string
replace wait is here should be
correct then
apply you know I'm just goingon to
I'm thinking of using a shortcut
notation because if you use a full
notation then it's going to like you
know it's like
lisp you know it's like lisp fully
nested uh and hard to understand but
it's worse because it's not everything
inside parentheses the function name is
outside the bracket so if you write the
everything in this full way it's harder
to understand so you can write in a
shorter way let's why don't we
just so for example instead of
apply oh you're missing I know what's
going on I I just you missed apply level
right apply
takes two arguments with the third
argument optional you say one okay so
run
it
what
attributes attention n f one is not a
known
attribute what when did we add
attributes so here is the problem rule
add
what is that
error commutative is not a known
attribute okay okay the error
is
is extra new line that's probably run it
no okay this is not good
uh okay I'm just going to start
[Music]
to
okay I'm going to start to write a
different way okay so first of all start
uh string replace okay string
replace I'm going to okay so I'm going
to write it here so you can kind of see
the above you know the original so I'm
going to rewrite this
by by rewriting this
this string replace okay so
replace
uh X okay so this needs to be a
function so here is a Lambda function
okay so the Lambda
function
then then then you
split by this expression okay so let's
again make it a
Lambda and here is
your here's your
syntax um this is not so
good
then you can just
add okay so this is a prefix notation so
you apply this function to this
function okay
then so Things become easier that
way then you
do again another
function
at this function okay so apply this you
know this function output feed it to
this function output feed it to this
function so it the code becomes linear
so you don't have a huge amount of
nesting so now apply rule oh yeah I got
the problem is I got this this one
should be inside here that is the
problem and okay tic so again take it
out again a
function
uh okay so another Lambda
add okay then the whole thing map okay
now you can put the whole thing map
uh
so uh so you want to map the whole
thing you can write it this
way
just okay then just take then just take
that okay actually you might need a
parent
okay so here is a bunch of
functions
you now well
the I think you
work okay but first of all you need to
comment out this actually you just move
this inside now work
yeah so test this one
first
what okay you cannot have the
stupid h
i
what the why is it make it one
line no something is wrong now what
about our
new ah
God
okay this is not
good stream
replace
so that's one thing string replace then
replace again okay that's a second thing
then you split stream
again that's
right
H indentation
issues this is this is wrong okay so
this definitely need to go
inside that's
right then a function okay so map
function let's do
it why is that
rule code with six argument oh okay so
you need to
map rule code with six
arguments let's look up the
documentation for apply let spec oh okay
yeah so I knew this should be actually
that okay
uh so this should be actually that that
means just level one
not not zero to
one okay so let's R
it still
wrong okay so what
I
that's
right okay that that apply is correct
you turn a list of pairs into a
dictionary and here here we work on the
real input so you should get a
dictionary of blue red green run
it that's right blue four red seven five
green okay
now why is this we are just basically
copying this
Association
to here and uh somewhere went
wrong so
apply there's
apply rule there is a rule
check uh rule check then
reverse
um
then reverse string split
reverse map at string split
okay
then then you string split again inside
it
oh okay okay I think I know what's going
on this is this is easier problem
than yesterday but we got it's already
minutes I know what's going on
because we are mapping to the different
levels because for each line first of
all you split into each line from the
input then you have to map to each
line you have to split each line so it
become a Leist then you map a function
to the list then you have to then you
have to split
again you know each of the four red or
five
green into a list of two things then
yeah so you are somewhere you are
mapping it
wrong that's why uh
so let's let's do this okay let's let's
just input okay so
input let's just simplify The Code
by
by rewriting the input so the input
now uh
no okay so line list okay so line list
equals
to
uh where where is our X list defined oh
okay oh we already have a XD
yeah okay
so what
the what are we doing so X list is a
list of
lines so let's change
name so when it get complicated the name
helps so X line list is a list of lines
then you want
to Let's uh let's do this okay so you
want to
map you want to map this
function
to remove the game remove the game uh
extra thing so we usually I don't like
to do that because now you are modifying
the variable which is not functional
programming but then you can put this
into inside here so that makes it better
[Laughter]
yeah okay so now line list
now we don't need this part line
list okay simplify it now it's just
X okay now let's comment out that
so so we got a list line
list okay now let's rename it just
lines okay now it's just a bunch of
lines okay
then then
you then you
um then for each line
you
split by
a semi my
colon you get each draw so here
is each
draw that's right so that is each draw
so let's let's let's just
um okay let's let's let's let's um let's
do this so
it's so that makes our code
easier
X draws is is a list of draws of a line
okay uh and
uh okay and here is body
so
getting very
complex I want to write this so everyone
understand what I'm doing because
otherwise there no point
of
no point of do doing a
video because I can just code it offline
then it's much
faster
uh
so
pairs that should give you
pairs which which is like four which
which is like a list of two things red
four green seven things like
that pairs okay
then hello very strange language I have
never seen this W language yeah uh then
then what
uh yeah then you
apply
actually then
Association so what the rule does is
actually the what the rule does is that
so for example you have
a a21 that's a rule which you can think
of it as a pair in a dictionary or a
hash map you know one element in a hash
map so in W from language that is
written like that okay so for
example
uh
okay so you have a list you know each
one of these is a rule which is
basically a pair uh and alternative
Syntax for this is just um so you don't
write it that way you write it this
[Music]
way so you know Al alternative syntax so
so this two is exactly the same so but
what we are doing is we have to turn a
list
of
pairs like that into that okay so that's
what is this part is doing then we add a
dictionary to the whole
thing uh okay
so so apply rule uh that should be it
pairs that that's right so what is this
so need go to
inside so this
modu so first of all is each draw this
is applied to X X is one single
line so let's make it
clear so this is one single line of
string then you split them it becomes a
list of draws then
you you need to map this
okay Association thread yeah you see I'm
not too familiar with
the yeah I think that's you are
right
Association thread you know these are
new functions since 2015
also uh associate yeah that's what uh
key value key value oh okay okay well if
you do this way then you have to
transpose the you know you have to put
the color names in One in least the
value names in another Leist so I don't
think this um I mean you could do it
that way
but uh
but I hate it that I'm stuck here but
basically we are mapping to the wrong uh
because there are
several map okay so any anyway so X
draws is a list of draws so now you
actually need to map to the to list of
draws okay so that's why this is what we
are
missing okay so map to level one by
default
then you map to
each draw the the draw are strings okay
so
actually uh
getting more and more elaborate so
you map a function to each
draw yeah so you right so you you each
draw string you split the draw string
uh
then you got the list of draw you split
them so
each
draw is several colors and number color
number color number color number then
you right each each draw string then you
split it by space
is what
uh you don't SP split by space you split
by coma you forgot the comma where is a
split by comma oh God that's why we
missing a split by
comma
comma draw a
string
split by comma okay so what do you
get okay so that's
Lambda you take the draw string then you
split by comma then what you get is what
you get
is what you get
is
colors colors in number okay so
actually getting very complicated I mean
this is not complicated but it's
just um so now you got color a color is
colors is is a list of strings each
string is like three blue four
red okay then you map on to Colors
okay right so then you
you map to the Colors by a
function uh and
uh so in order to do that you have to
split string okay split
string that's right that's that part
part map to the color
string this is not a good name because
color people think it's just color but
actually it's a color and a
number num color
pair so colors should be
num color
string okay
idiotic
now now it becomes elaborate with
documentation so draw string
example uh that example
then num color string then you get
pairs uh draw
string then you get
pairs naming issue naming gets very
complex okay so you got pairs equals
to okay re reverse that then
you create Association okay something
like
that something like that I hope it work
getting very
complicated
run
it ah
oh this is not good
man can you move your em okay very
strange language maybe Association
thread okay Advent of code is very nice
for learning new language this year I'm
trying rust seems very popular now right
hello I have a woolam language question
I wanted to read data from a yo file and
it seems that wolam can only read Jason
even though the conversion is usually
simple uh yammo file is at indentation
based well then in that case you have to
write it or look at the wam library to
see if someone already write it wrote it
otherwise you have to to passing
yourself but maybe the best thing is
first to convert the yo to Jason by some
other
tool yeah because there are so many of
these formats I don't I don't think wolf
I'm supposed yamama I'm I'm not
sure but I doubt it if it's a image
format there are tens of image format
wam supported all and also animation
codep you know movie video codc supports
tens of them or 3D formats you know Cat
3D different movie 3D format but for
yamo and those I don't
think yeah you better just convert it to
Json first or just write your own passor
but with the indentation based notation
that's that sucks it it's you know it's
not trivial to write a pass for
that so let's get back oh God this is
this is not good now it's one hour and
we stuck on this like no problem problem
and I really like to take a break I need
to take a
walk the problem happens in part is
because I'm just coding and coding I'm
not thinking you know usually you take
five minutes don't talk just think you
find the problem then you you know you
you you you you can code it like you can
fix it you can find out where you got
wrong
but uh but you know but um so that is
why so and now the code becomes so comp
so complicated like I don't you know if
you are not familiar with wame language
you don't know what I'm doing uh so it
lost the value of of live demo um and oh
this there shouldn't be a semicolon
there let's run
it yeah something wrong rule syntax rule
code with three argument yeah that's not
good so why is Rule code three arguments
uh uh let's just not instead of apply
rule let's just rule
map to this is such simple
okay maybe we should do this long
ago yeah we call with ar where is the
problem coming
from stop that
wait let's Comon out comment out that
com out that yeah come out
that R
it comma
encountered okay here I think I got a
problem with running long code in emac
because you don't know what line or
stuff uh error came from comma
encountered with no adjacent expression
okay the expression will be treated SN
don't no something is wrong so it says
comma incountered okay where is
that yeah because I'm just talking too
much
what to do
so module here module is just like Lis
let it just let you declare local
variables so we declared you know so
here's a
module you know if we we can delete the
whole thing so we basically just want to
map this function to a list of lines
okay and what's inside the function so
the function takes one argument x one
line that's one single line of string
okay
then then the function body is this
thing okay so the function body is a
module which is like a block of code
like the
C's uh braces okay and in in the the
first argument of module is a list of
variables you want to declare locally so
that's why we have this draw string so
the and let's double okay let's go over
so so draw
string is is a
string that is like three blue four red
each draw okay
so uh so we uh what you do is you take
the X1 line is a
string of a line like that which
contains many draws you split
by by semicolon then you get a list of
draws okay so that's why it's a string
uh better name it draw
okay well it is a string so draw is a
string okay so anyway
then so you got a string like three red
four three blue four red then
you
you you you split string you map split
string to the draw
string wait draw string is that just one
or many it's
many yeah so draw string is many that's
why you need to map it so it should be
draw
strings right draw strings at least wait
so it's not a string what what are we
God this is so
confusing draw string is a list of draws
so each element is a string but the
whole thing is a list so it's a list of
string
and each element is like three blue four
red okay something like that so the name
is incorrect so it should be just draws
okay so let's rename
it
okay
then then we work on the draws which is
a list so we map some function to it and
this function again split string by
comma so
that so that you got a list of each
color and
number and uh so this value this
variable should be a list it is a list
and each element is a string and that
string has a value of something like
number and color Okay so this number
color string is not a string it's a list
okay it's a list of
strings
uh okay so let's rename
it pay
us okay so number pairs is at least each
one is a string such as three blue
that's right okay now this is a list so
now we again map to the list okay okay
we map to the list here and we map it by
this function again split string now
this times split on space so we got a
pair three and blue or four and red a
least of two
things again they are strings the first
element is a number in a string the
second element is a
color okay you map that that then oh
reverse is wrong uh then actually you
can put the reverse inside the
map so you reverse
it then actually you just put a rule in
front then actually yeah you don't know
what I'm doing you you replace the head
by rule so
then then you just say Association pirs
okay
okay let's see let's copy that in W
language paste it let's see where does
the yeah
so so reverse and that are connected
syntactically then the rule add add
means replace the head replace the list
by the rule so you so
anyway run
it
God something something is wrong in my
code and I don't know
where yeah this is
very
bad this is this is really bad
so let's run in wam language okay let's
see what
happens run
it okay then
xag do you have
it run it
okay now x lines oh there that's
up the thing why do we have that
there yeah so
wait
minute
still not wrong still not
correct string
split expected so we missing an argument
basically our um our comma is placed in
the wrong place or things like
that let's
see let's R name one by one in wam
language
okay so this lines
works so each so this is a line that's
right this this is a line This is a
line x lines okay so
then
what
okay that shows you the lines okay table
formam
lines yeah
God
okay then what you do here is you have
this
thing you want to
map oh the map wait it's a function
right yeah it's a function why is it
not
it's much nicer looking there
so string or list of strings expected at
position
one okay I know what
so
so where does this one came from spit
string
okay I think I know what's going on so
you need to move this
inside okay and
it
no
for
this this is very
bad
uh
for
let's see what this
returns okay so now so you can see this
is what we
get the pairs
so so this is the first
input okay so now we have going
somewhere so this is actually the first
input like
that four blue four blue seven
red four blue seven red five five green
okay let's copy it here so we can
see okay so that represent the first
line four blue seven red five green okay
check okay
then right
so we want
to map rules at that and
uh
let's see so this is
output so each one is each element is a
draw so can
we
ha H this is too bad now
it's 70
minutes so
[Music]
we
thank you for document documenting Oro
keyboards I bought glove 80 great thank
you
and
so you know so this is not good I don't
know you know maybe another 10 minutes
we'll probably finish the part one then
there's part
two uh so it takes few hours that's not
good because now this day two the
problem is still pretty
simple pretty easy I remember last year
you know I I kind of stopped I stopped
at day six because then it took two
three hours and stuck in the
middle uh but I presume that's actually
is that's actually normal because you
know I looked at other people doing this
event of
code uh even if you are a professional
programmer taking a few hours is
normal
so unless you are the competitive you
know the gaming I mean the competit
competitive speed coders those people
are no good actually so but basically
for those people they they focus on
getting the Cod out the fastest way
possible you know I think in the past 10
years they started to have that kind of
competition you know let's see who can
write the code the fastest um but I
think the you
know that's some skill but that's
not that's not a typical skill for
profession
coders uh especially if you are great
you know writing great architecture for
great giant software such as Google
search engine or spaceship software
things like that and you know if you are
winner of those speed coding compet
competition that's some skill but that's
not a typical
um skill
for for writing uh
great huge
software uh I think the situation is can
be comparable to their are math
calculators human calculators
or you know they
can they can do incredible Feast of
mental calculation
like 20 digit number more multiply or
square root or 10th root and you know
they
can but typically those people are never
great mathematicians like if you look at
history of
mathematics those great mathematicians
usually are unable to do that except a
few you know a few are both they can do
mental calculations and they can also do
uh they became great mathematicians so
similarly for program I
mean anyway I'm digressing so you know
so anyway so I think few hours is common
but but uh so what am I going to do the
you know the day of
code you know the give giving up is the
easiest answer and let's do something
else yeah but I think we are going to
continue
uh Advent of code for for for a few days
uh but for
today let's see should we continue uh
what do you guys think I think not many
people watching four four people or
something uh we can either continue
night people
okay so what about this let me finish
doing the part one at least you know
that's so then because it's almost done
so then we move on to then we take a
then I'm going to stop then maybe
tonight we continue I do another video
maybe to continue part two you know I
want to finish it so let's do finish
it so okay so
now now we know where we are we got this
thing we
um and my code so far is not looking
good it's not it seems fairly complex
it's
uh okay so we got
that pairs this is still for one line so
you want
so yeah the problem is we got a nested
list of this things
so so what do you do with pairs okay
so so this is actually the whole thing
is just the first line remember the
first the whole thing is actually just
the first
line okay one line you have several
draws uh and uh we the way we are doing
it
is okay let's push on
so so the
pairs pairs is a list of pairs but
also
inside a list of draws so that is a
problem that's that's
where and uh reverse does not seems to
work number pairs X number
pairs let's commment this out let's run
it
five five green seven
red
for
I think I should start again current
code is too confusing oh God I'm going
to
stop I'm going
up yeah I don't think you guys can read
this but it's really simple though I
mean it's really simple but I this is
not a good
um and maybe if I do it in Notebook W
from notebook it will be
clear it will be clear more
clear well it's 190 minutes
uh
f it f
it okay here's what I uh do okay we're
going to come back in 3 hours
okay yeah let's do it
in 7:00 so now it's
230 3 4 5 5
3 4 five 6 7 in 4 and 1 half hours we
come
back okay so when we come back we can
actually I'm going to finish it offline
I'm going to do it Part Two too offline
then come back I might you know start
over and it should be pretty you know
once you go you you do it then you
explain it's it's easy it's like you
know so let's do
that yeah but right now the problem is
like the the nesting is
becoming annoying okay okay that's it
guys thank you for watching so we come
back at uh I'm going to post uh uh 4 and
five 4 and a half hours
can you put the current state in the
blog page okay yeah
so uh so if if I put in the current
state the current state is basically we
this the it's basically the nesting you
know it's kind of confusing so you got a
line a
line is made of several drawers okay and
the draw is is made of several pairs of
number and color okay then each pair of
number of color you want to process this
you you want to process it you want to
reverse it and put it into a dictionary
so anyway a line is several
draws uh and you want to eventually you
want to go through each
drawer to see if any of the number
is smaller I mean to see if any of the
number is greater than the given number
of Cubes okay so for example if there
are 12 red so if any of the draw you got
13 red then immediately that whole line
so C called game is
eliminated
right so my problem right now is just I
got confused with you know the which
part is a draw then which pair which is
the pair is is a list or did we reverse
it I mean so that's where we stuck okay
so so if we put this code back okay in
browser let's just do it yeah you know
actually we in the beginning code I
think actually I'm I'm somewhere I just
then we started to
clarify in in either case it's not going
to be clear because you have several
levels of nested map okay this is the
issue you have uh with functional
programming and wam
language if you do it you know if you do
a loop instead which is typical in CE or
Java kind of then you
use variables to annotate each line what
you do then you know you do it
procedurally uh but Aron code even you
know the it's kind of complicated and I
try to anyway so I'm going to put this
up okay
yeah let me say let me put
here start again at 7
PM San
Francis uh San Francisco time okay so
let me put that into my blog so you guys
can see and I'll upload it in 10 minutes
but for now bye guys thank you guys
sorry about
that okay I'm going to upload it bye