good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santos show today right now
is July 6 2000 2019 it's midnight here 2
minutes after midnight so today we're
gonna do sundry things let's see so
we're gonna talk about I'm just going to
I'm going to go over you know what
what's happening in the past few days
you know what's interesting things so
yeah so let's see that's random
programming Unicode keyboard stuff and
what's new okay let's begin it's so
let's go to my website and in the
keyboard Department so I just discovered
this new new 3d figuring you know it's
in USA so you know this is figure action
figure you know you know in USA it's
code typically you know the toys action
figure but in Japan this thing figuring
you know they are extremely exquisite
exquisite you know a delicate and very
expensive some of these costs $100 or
$200 or more and you know Japanese they
love these things they are you know
extremely well made so I discovered this
one let me show you some some some of
these you know in Japan I'm not sure how
they call it but sometimes in English
it's called PVC figures so let me show
you some of them okay hot blog let's go
to my art blog so we're going to talk
about PVC Vee
and these Kira Krita this this girl this
she's a mascot is she a squirrel or
something she's the mascot for this
painting software you know you use it
with the pen you know with a digital pen
to draw in you know art stuff so she is
you know so this software has a mascot
critter that's her name
and this mascot is created by a Chinese
guy do I say it here somewhere anyway
yeah she's created this mascot is is by
a Chinese artist so anyway and you know
I found this very beautiful pretty so
let me show you about talk about action
figures and what you know what I let me
show you some of them so if you are here
say hi any comments questions post it
post it okay so let's see yeah action
figures
the Japanese action figures they are
incredible fantastic they have mecha
they have you know extremely delicate so
here we have katana here we have katana
this is an American
you know version figurine this is
actually this is this this one is Welton
but you rarely see it you must you must
almost never see at katana you know she
is hot and katana is interests there
they are quite a few things interesting
about this this relates to artificial
intelligence you know the gaming
community computer graphics and also the
the design of decorations on clothing on
women's clothing you see so we cannot
talk about that but you know so many
topics let me let me finish one by one
okay so
so this this girl is her name is then we
have this her name is cortana and she
came from the video game hello
she is a some kind of artificial
intelligence hologram something like
that you know from the then she became
the she became the you know the the the
assistant the voice assistants of
microsoft operating system cortana
you know like like Apple's Siri and ok
Google so let me show you yeah let me
show you some of the first of all let's
talk about the figurines
ok let me talk about Cortana
ok so so yeah so what's interesting is
one thing interesting about this figure
this girl now look you see notice the
patterns on her body you know it's it's
or sci-fi you know sci-fi and it's it's
well done it's beautiful but notice the
patterns you know I was wondering how
does the pattern forms
I mean is it random like how do you like
when you for example if you are the
artist you know you want to design the
patterns on her body what do you you
know what what kind of what do you do
you know so that's one question but the
question I'm wondering is is how does
the pattern you know her body form
seemed like easier way
algorithm you know you know what what
makes them this way I mean why not for
example black over here or you know some
other pattern so after after a bit of
thought it's easy to understand the
pattern on her body reflects basically
reflects clothes clothing like lingerie
lingerie like women's you know sexy
lingerie so basically the pattern forms
you know it's like a pic bikini like a
swimsuit you know covering the you know
sexual parts then over here is like a
garter belt
you know so the pattern reflects you
know actually reflects kind of the
clothing of women and that you know and
also look here you know they started to
have some pattern here so it's like you
know the long-sleeved gloves sometimes
women wear so this choice of hat and
that's that's interesting at the hand
you know you look at let's magnify okay
you see you see the hand the pattern on
the hand here is like some kind of
triangle so it's similar to you know
sometimes you have these gloves women
where where you have to keep the sleeves
pulled up or something like that so you
have a string you know to attach to the
finger middle finger so that kind of
like looks like that so in anyway so the
pattern reflects women's clothing and
this choice this particular choice is
interesting because I think so you know
because it provides a familiarity you
know you know if you have other kind of
patterns that might might be as
attractive as well and interesting as
well but in in any case if you design
the pattern according to you know
clothing you have the you have the
advantage of familiarity which you know
family familiarity is one of the element
important element for attraction like
when you see something what makes it
attractive you know what what makes it
not attractive so one of the criteria
one of the important reason is familiar
familiarity you know so if you are in
Western culture or Chinese culture or
Japanese culture if you see things you
know you know you see every day you
tends to find it more attractive
things you've never seen before so yeah
so so you know like so that's why we say
usually firing things so alien things we
don't find attractive you know we like
we like Chan in general we like you know
human likes things that are familiar so
this choice you know you know creating
the pattern based on clothing is you
know has this familiarity advantage so
that's you know that's the interesting
thing then okay Americans do they have
this stupid dog is stupid dog
you know this agree you can still buy
this on Amazon I think I'm not sure how
where do you buy this though this this
one so any of you gamers out there you
know like where do you buy this it's
probably not available anymore but
anyway so that's Cortana and let's let
me show you some of the other figurines
okay in general you know it's called
figurines but you know sometimes it's
called action figures in USA and
sometimes it's called PVC figures so let
me show you some of the extremely
beautiful Japanese PVC figures for for
example this one this one you know in
Japan they have like hundreds of them
not not hundred you know it's like
thousand undred thousands of them each
one costs near like one hundred two
hundred dollars USD and in fact today
you can buy a lot of them on Amazon they
are you know imported from Japan and let
me actually I want to find let me find
you some of that okay so I have a
collection here usually these are sexy
okay this is the one I want to find this
these are extremely sexy okay
so here here is another some of the
action figures of American superheroes
they are made in Japan so you have
Batman you have you know Wonder Woman
I am N and Captain America so this these
are well made you know this so you know
this this thing I want to say you know
American you know u.s. culture you don't
have these things like they thrive in
Japan but in America you go to a toy
store even adults you know gamers store
you know game shops you know there are
action figures like idiotic there they
are for kids
you know like five dollars each you know
you know so but Japan they have you know
they have they appreciate these kind of
things so they companies you know in
technology they create these things you
know it's like a very extreme sculpture
so if you like them you know you can
check check them out on my website this
is let me show you the URL so basically
just go to solid start oke you know just
such for my name Saudi action figure and
you'll find them and you know and buy
them for my website I would like that
thank you so you have these action
figures from Japan and let me show you
the others okay and okay the Star Wars
it's fantastic this is the Darth Maul
there's another interesting interesting
thing about the naming of these
characters
now that relates to linguistics the
naming of the characters for example
this this character darth vader darth
vader in this character that does more
you know you see their names they cannot
to to rather negative or dark
you know colors you know like more what
do you think of a more you know more
it's like you know tearing things apart
I guess more let's let's look up yeah
not not Wikipedia let's go to dictionary
so more a heavy long handed hammer used
especially to drive stakes piles or
always wedges
okay heavy hammer to injure or motivate
us by scratching or beatings
so you see their names came you know
when you choose a name for character
this details went into the Oh this kind
of you know fictional let's go back to
Dartmoor you know so so this guy's stars
more and Vader you know Veda what what
does it remind you remind you we might
you you know in Veda
you know invasion vetoes something like
that and das you know it reminds you of
talk darkness so there's interesting
name naming of things involved so anyway
so these are you know Japanese action
figures sometimes it's called PVC
figures PVC PVC is the part is it it
turns out it's a particular plastic name
you know the technology used to create
this this material for these figurines
so we here we have Snow White and
another American character you know so
so in Japan they make these characters
you know they they have a figurine for
basically every you know every comics
every anime you know a Japanese anime
there are thousands of them or they also
make for example American superheroes or
American fairy tale so you know you know
characters scheming characters or
whatever so here we have snow white and
is
she's voluptuous you know and you know
nuts you know young people you know I
love it of course it's female
you know girls so the so that's Raven
now what does is that a raven or just a
bird
what does a raven has to do with Snow
White
does anyone know he is there Raven is
Snow White
anyway so so that's so that's the
Chinese for Snow White
by chickens ooh so anyways Snow White so
you have Snow White so if anyone knows
what's a raven doing here let me know
type in the comments okay so if you see
this offline you know type in a youtube
comment and okay so I was saying in
Japan they have these they have tens of
hundreds of thousands of these figure
rings okay and there are people collect
them collects them you know there is
this guy this guy who collects literally
few thousands of them I don't know if
it's tens of thousands you know and he
is rich you know like each one of these
especially this set okay each one of
these costs you know like hundred or two
hundred US dollars so this guy has I
think at least you know a few thousands
of them I think it's more more than a
few thousand so they cost you know he
spent millions of dollars on these
things you know a few million dollars so
anyway here is a photo of his collection
and these characters these are the
characters of the Japanese anime called
one piece you know in English is called
one piece in Chinese it's called hi Jay
Wong hi Jay Wong literally means you
know the king of pirates now this one
piece anime
you know story these comics you can you
can find it on Wikipedia for example
just search for one piece and there's
also its dedicated wiki this this is
incredible comics it turns out this is
the most you know of all anime in Japan
you know from history to today one piece
is the the most popular the most in
terms of you know number of books sold
or things like that it's the most
successful so of all the different types
of Japanese anime this one piece is the
most most successful and I've checked
out you know some of the comics it's
really good you know in the Japanese
comics one one characteristics about
their story different from America is
that they are their stories are very
diverse you know they they touch upon
all facets of human humanity okay
different you have different characters
you have you know good people bad people
I mean not just good back but different
personalities and humor humor aspect you
know sexy sexy ass aspect you know so
that it's encompassing Japanese you know
the Japanese comic stories are
encompassing in that way they touch on
all aspects of humanity and their story
is very creative including you know also
including some of their science fiction
comics as opposed to American now
American comics is like extremely boring
you know like superheroes all these
superheroes the Marvel Universe the
x-men the Superman Batman they are you
know they are essentially boys down to
one thing good versus evil
you know they simplify humanity they
simplify like there's nothing else
except good you are good I'm evil okay
good versus evil
you know Batman
you know so Batman is a bit complex is
because it's he's a psychotic
you know Batman you know and you know
they all have mental problems
psychological problems
Batman anyways Superman you know
Wolverine what is the American comics
spider-man you know they are basically
idiotic you know extreme idiotic and of
course they try to they they try to
breed in some of the you know practical
everyday life situations like you know
they like to meet typically there will
involve boyfriends you know girlfriends
you know like love interest
good morning and truly you know
boyfriend-girlfriend you know love
interest you know who is you know
idiotic American comics okay but anyway
so this one piece Japanese comics it's
is the encompassing and a fantastic now
this group of people are the you know
you might call bad guys it's but it's
more complex complicated than that each
one have you know they have different
personality now of course they are
traumatic you know they are not real
life you know but the that's a point of
stories you know stories is the drama
version of real life you know sometimes
real life real stories are very
sometimes the most stranger than fiction
so anyway so so these are kind of the
bad guys okay but they have different
characters personalities
now so this is drawing from the comics
but you can see you know for example
this girl this girl is her name is
pirate Empress power pirate Empress poor
Hancock boy Hancock okay and so in in
figurine
so this guy has to version of him so
that her my image is not too big whoops
so anyway and and you can see now this
this guy a bad guy this is called dong
dong quick saute doflamingo how do you
pronounce down quick saute that's a
Spanish from the Spanish famous classic
I suppose so
this guy flamingo it's just coughing him
flat because he's flamboyant
okay now this interesting thing about
the etymology of the word flamboyant
let's that's that's interesting another
linguistic aspect so it's etymology
flamboyant okay I have written a blog
about that okay so I guess it's linked
here
yeah the etymology of flamingo and
flamboyant now in it turns out they are
related so this character is flamingo
and you can see he you know he is a very
flamboyant character and you know you
can see his face expressions you know
that and also he's you know it's a
farming go so well I'm not going to read
it but anyway so they are like related I
mean that the etymology of the these two
words are you know have kind of the same
or injured so let's see flamingo long
leg so etymology of flamingo long-legged
long-necked long leg
not long necked brightly-colored the
pink bird of the tropical Americas from
Portuguese from ingo Spanish from
angle literally flame-coloured okay that
is the key flame-colored compare Greek
suddenly something flamingo literally
red feather okay
so anyway that's from in go and let's
see flamboyant flamboyant
flamboyant 1832 originally in reference
to a 15th century to 16th century
architectural style with wavy flame like
curves from French flamboyant flaming
wavy okay so yeah so they you know
basically they all came from the word
flame fire you know so that's
interesting flamingo and flamboyant okay
so let's go back to these so anyway so
this this is one piece you know you
might check it out
Japanese comics and these scuba people
are the good guys you know good guys
they you know you if you look at all the
stories you know movies or fictions you
know it is the bad guys die shines if
they are most colorful you know these
are the bad guys each one of them is
greatly you know its attractive but the
good guys they are you know they don't
look exotic they don't look
extraordinary usually so anyway yeah so
so this guy collected you know thousands
of these anime characters and look at
this you know chick you know they they
are so hot and sexy you know these women
women's clothing women you know women's
women's clothing you know they are a
huge part of humanity you know
throughout history they you know they
are clothing is extremely elaborate you
know except for example this clothing is
you know it shows the cleavage but then
you have this variation it shows you
know
bottom of the tits yeah and not just you
know this this happens these things you
know so why is women's so has so many
varieties of clothing designed or that
it's because and women you know it's
women he they do it they they they they
almost like needed require it what you
know you know because if women stop
spying you know wearing this lingerie
you know you have for example in modern
society you have Victoria's Secret
a huge success you know if women stops
you know liking these things then the
whole thing will stop you know this you
know women just put on t-shirts that
would be it but that's not of course
that's that's not what happens you know
and so this is not just modern society
it it turns out the same see it's with
us you know for you know thousands of
years you know women they have to do
these kind of things and why you know
because it's sexual attraction that's
what makes you know that that what you
know makes us propagate you know we have
to reproduce how do you reproduce you
have sex how do you have sex you well
you have you know men and women but you
don't just you don't just oh it's time
to have sex then you have sex this
complex things involved you know you
women women has to signify like in many
among animals they have like a maintain
seasonal you know estriol estrus you
know a period of time when a female egg
is mature then you have sex at that time
then you can you have babies okay
otherwise not but in human animals
there's no asset like like a mating
season it's but instead you have you
know women have periods
and that changes their mood and you know
they say women women you know the female
has to signify when they are ready to
have sex you know they you know it's a
it's a bio biological mechanism and how
do they signify well clothing is you
know dressing hops you know is one of
the reason anyway that's getting complex
complicated so anyway so so you have
these yeah Japanese anime and stories by
the way so you have this mermaid
character this mermaid okay you know
this so this one-piece story is very
complicated and you you also have this
this girl character you know she's
dressed like you know what Japanese
Maiko a Lolita fashion you know it's
called a little fashion it's kind of a
mix of goth you know Gothic fashion and
Victorian kind of thing so so they are
comics so you have these she's one of
the character as well and then you have
this mermaid character now now the
mermaid character came from of course
they came from Northern Europe I think
so anyway but she is huge you know so
you see so they change you know so so
what I'm saying is that the story is not
predictable you know the stories and the
characters in these Japanese comics it's
not like it's it's it's very so it's
very attractive that what makes it
interesting part of it is that it's not
predictable so so you have this mermaid
character and in this story this moment
character is like you know 50 times
larger than a normal person's you know
so so the she is holding this guy this
guy is actually the main character let
me show you so that guy is
[Music]
the main character this guy he's a hero
okay kind of he so he's the main
character of the whole story one piece
and so this mermaid
you know he's holding him you know so
you can see how small he is and then you
have these ghost characters you know
anyway so it's very interesting anime
okay so that's that's the you know PVC
figure that's the okay action figure so
let me okay so there are some other good
morning your much didn't so a PVC so any
questions comments just type it okay
because I'm you know today we just talk
random okay random things you know it
turns out Oh God it like every time I
start to talk I spend a lot of time you
know because there's so many please to
talk about and every time when I talk
about things is so many branches of hey
good morning Danielle so anything new
any comments opinions or any other
subjects you want me to talk about just
posted okay cuz you know thank you too
for you are great
like your content and well thank you so
so here's another PVC character you know
so her name is cari Cole
hitori something like that
you know it's very sexy so yeah so PVC
figures
oh by the way okay you see all these
comics or comics or movies or American
comics or Japanese anime you know or in
games you have you often have female
warriors you know you see you see you
know she's very hot and she is a warrior
you know she is using a you know some
samurai samurai
sword you know so and but although these
are fiction you know these are fantasies
these are fantasies that theses men
mostly and and female as well be you
know the reason you have all these
female you know warriors is you know you
know it's like pure fiction it doesn't
happen yeah you know it just never ever
happened even a little bit even like you
know like once in a while maybe in you
know you know hundred years you have one
in a billion you know one in ten million
women who was you know different you
know she's special she you know it's
like you know odd you know so you know
maybe whining a medium yeah you have
that female warriors but all these
comics and games you know they are just
pure fantasy and in America you have
these idiots you know social justice can
you idiots they say oh this okay let's
not get into that like you did like this
like they want to say oh so but why does
know what what female armor should be
like oh then this or that anyway so
here's another PVC figure and this is
from Fleet girls collection Philly girls
fleet Fleet girls collection is a huge
popular game online game in Japan you
know Japan is in many ways in American
eyes it's very weird and odd because
this game this game is actually you know
what is about this game is about let me
let me show you maybe you'll see some
okay here i fleet girls collection so so
this scam the theme of this you see all
these girls with you know military
warships you know
ships this game is based on World War
two [ __ ] Japanese World War you know what
war two Navy fleet so for every ship
Japanese warship there is a girl that
that represents the ship and you know
basically it's a game is kind of based
on World War two you know history you
know so so and it's extremely popular so
you see it's even painted on airplanes
you know in English it's can can collect
you know a free girls collection anyway
very popular so anyway so so you have
you can buy you know figurines you can
buy you know it's lots of you know and
so these these figures came from that
you know game yeah so that's some of the
examples of the you know action figures
and PVC or PVC figures so anyway so so
let me read some comments
Danielle says I was it I was at the
music centers Dorothy Chandler Pavilion
tonight I mean la Oh Music Center
Dorothy Dorothy Chandler Pavilion
I saw the royal royal ballet ballet
ballet [ __ ] I can't pronounce anymore
Kenneth McMillan's Mayerling opening
night but that doesn't sound interesting
okay when was the earthquake three hours
ago like four hours ago during
intermission
most interesting part of this my seat
equals row how expensive oh yeah there's
earthquake like four hours ago
anyways I was asleep I was asleep asleep
I think I just saw I don't know I woke
up like three four hours ago
yeah so as I said before a few times you
know I sleep my sleeping schedule
changes all the time like it shifts all
over the clock so right now for the past
week it the schedule is I sleep at noon
I wake up around 8 p.m. something like
that so anyway so there are PVC videos
about you know so we talked about let me
summarize because summarization is
important
well because every time I do a video I
have to like I talk about random things
so but when people go to see my YouTube
you know they don't know what's topic
but you know because each one is you
have a bag of random things so it's
usually nice if I put a table of
contents like this video will talk about
you know this these things but that's
painstaking like I have to watch my own
videos you know each video is like an
hour long I have to watch it then I have
to try to get the timestamp and stuff so
it would be nice like you every time I
talk about something people start to
type so action figures action figures
and we talked about American and
Japanese comics Japanese comics
you see the colorfulness of Japanese
comics and the ball of American comics
okay and that's more that vada the
Linguistics the naming of things okay
and action figures P PVC figures
okay the naming and all that and we
talked about one piece Pirate King okay
then we have anyway so that's PVC
figures that that is that so actually I
wanted to talk about quite a lot of
things but it turns out just on that
thing you know it's already 40 minutes
like we can call it a day
yeah ever I haven't begin oh it began it
all began with this with this critter
you know this figure I discovered this
critter this is a painting the mascot
for this painting software yeah so I was
going to okay so
so I'm typing this out you know so that
later they don't know I can you know
maybe you know and later I need to put
in a description
etymology oh yeah don't forget the
etymology of flamingo versus and you
know flamboyant they all came from the
word flame flame like yeah okay so so
seven people watching okay so let's talk
about okay so yeah so I have this you
know I bought this like have a half a
year ago and it works you know because
you know why I bought this because so I
got a you know see like Saudi keyboards
miscellaneous you know I traded my
laptop with my roommates micros
microsoft surface pro you know you can
see here and you know the surface pro
suits me because I need to ice it all
day so so with the surface book I can
just walk around when I'm reading
something I need to read some
programming documentation or something I
take the book and walk around so it's
very useful and it I it turns out I
learned about this digital pen you know
my first time using a digital pinion and
it's incredible it's fantastic because
now you can actually write down you know
notes you know I have a video here if
you go to my website you'll see the
video it's not showing here because
javascript is off in Firefox so so the
pain is incredible it's it's like a new
chapter of computing it's so extremely
convenient
every time you just do it you know you
do a screenshot and you can write notes
on it
and I do that often and you can also use
the pen to navigate for example if you
want to score the window down you just
you know you just like do like that you
know
so so I discovered you know the pink
computing the the Microsoft Surface pro
so I was thinking you know I want to get
one for my Mac too so I you know I
looked around and eventually I got this
one cheap the one I got is like $40
something you know check it out but it
had turns out on the Mac it sucks it
sucks donkey ass because on a Mac you
see what happens is that you see I have
this pain right now it's working you
know I can move my pain around but I
cannot scroll you know on the surface
book oh I have to do is like judges you
know click here you know I just click
here and I just moved my ping up and I
was your score but you want instead it
does selection instead so that means so
you cannot screw with it so that goes
away you know with use you know using it
as a mouse
so unless unless you install I suppose
it exists somewhere I haven't looked
unless you go install some software for
you know that is designed to make the
pain into a you know generic mouse but
on the Microsoft Surface book you can
just use you use your pen to navigate
and select and everything you know
instead of at the mouse but on a map you
you basically know you cannot so so
basically so that's a disappointment so
why does the Mac do not provide this you
know by default because obviously
because you see Apple makes their own
touchpad you know and also the Apple
makes their own pain pencil you know
Apple digital pain so they don't want
they don't want you to buy you know some
random you know drawing digital pens and
and you can use it instead of buying
apples tablet you know the touch tablet
so that's why you know so all these
corporations you know
all these corporations Apple and
including software you know Google
Twitter Facebook they every aspect of
their decision I mean trust me when I
say this because I've been computing for
30 years now since 1991 every day has
been that read all the news about you
know what what's the latest item you
know what features what operating system
just came out what upgrade you know I
was I was a nerd you know I read about
and also you know other version you know
since 1991 where I have a you know when
I have my first Mac Mac - si so I was a
Mac phonetic you you might go for for
most involved for night throughout 1990s
so anyway so I I'd you know I've been
observing so but especially in the past
ten years every corporation every every
one of their decisions how the pains
made including including Microsoft spin
you know Microsoft spin it's heavy
you know when I first use this it's
fantastic you just you know it's great
but after I had this and you know and
you know thinking about things you know
looking around study the technology of
the digital pen it's it's comparatively
it's no good but I know why it is that
way the Microsoft digital pen it is that
way because that way makes the most
money for them you know it's true
this pain is heavy and it's got two
batteries unnecessarily so why because
they could they could have trivially
they could have trivially that's my
roommate is after midnight and I'm too
loud so they they could have trivially
they could have trivially made the pen
you know like you can buy any digital
pen and your walk but of course that's
not you know so they decided to you know
they want you to buy
they're home you know specialized pain
and there's no good reason actually you
might think okay this is my baby there's
a technical reason they that you know
they have to have this pain like that
not really
so anyway so that's about Apple pain but
anyway so my roommate is complaining
hours too loud
so I think I you know that should be
here today I have actually I want it
there are several topics I want to go
over but it's kind of late here so that
should be here today
yeah 15 minutes so let me read the
comments okay let's not let's not talk
about that okay so yeah I know a lot of
people you know following me because um
because of the Wow you know it's said
I'm based and it seems my name is being
started to it's like it's a mission on
one of these you know there are several
of them can websites yeah that is true
anyway that that's it for today so thank
you guys for watching
of course if you like of these the stuff
I talked about buy from my website and
you know to have donation buttons and so
on you know and stuff any more questions
any questions you have ten seconds and
we will say goodbye here was the ignite
yeah okay this this quite a lot of
topics I want to talk about that we
haven't got into yeah there is something
new about keyboard yeah this this I want
to talk about and there's some
programming issues there's a Egyptian
hero guys you know they have these women
birth and breastfeeding you know
Egyptian drives and there's also web dev
yeah this friend said I want to talk
about because this it's about user
interface it's about the history is
about history of the standard it is
quite a lot aspects to go into and
anyway yeah so that might Danielle thank
you guys for watching good night