good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
show and today we going to talk about
interesting stuff the wonders of the
interesting stuff in a world and we
gonna okay you know actually Jesus
you know just how why do you need this
to be you know okay one of the topic is
about some messages watching live chat
what okay you know one of the
interesting thing is about the expected
window width of browsers you know over
the over the past 20 years you know so I
started coding HTML you know since 1995
you know since HTML began since the web
began and you know so you know in 1991
the the monitor size the width is 640
the hate is 480 that's standard you know
then in 2000 the standard is about 800
the width is 800 then then in then you
know it increases you know over the
years but anyway meanwhile do this
upload to my web site and we can see
here one guy watching hi say something
sorry window size okay so over the years
you know the past 20 years I've observed
you know what is you know when you do
web dev the web designers so you know
the web coders they they
Parko maker tutorial so windows size
DVD size screen size you know so the web
designers you have to design your
website so that you know you assume that
the the people the viewers has certain
window size so over the years there are
certain window width that's kind of
standard you know for for websites you
know you design it so that you assumed
the window is size so i have actually a
comparison here actually I have several
articles about it you know that's
interesting second life okay this page
is about using javascript to find out
your your viewport size your window size
your screen size for example my monitor
is nine 1920 by 1080 and my window size
right now on this on this window is
thirteen sixty by 920 and my viewport
you know if you do web dev you know
there's a concept concept of viewport
now the viewport is basically when a
viewport I think it's - the school by
and minus the top menu in tabs stuff and
sometimes the status bar at bottom but
anyway this page is about how to use
JavaScript to find out about your you
know all these sizes in school amount
hey Isaac good morning so how is your
class in info info matrix you know I
looked up informatics let me type it in
for matrix I look up that's not good so
what do you think do you think
did you was it good for you so
informatics it seems to me it's like
do you know a Joe and you know payer
programming and extreme programming you
know it began with extreme programming
in around year 2000 it became hugely
popular it's about principles of
software engineering ok so yeah I'm not
I still don't trust that topic whenever
they tell you that now you know so do
you like it I don't like it because you
know software software engineering ok
you don't like it you know you know
software engineering software
engineering it's you know we can compare
to mathematics it's in sharp contrast
with math you know for those initiated
you know you might think that both of
them are hard sciences you know math and
you know programming because into doing
programming everything those must be
correct you know otherwise you won't run
but I actually software engineering or
programming in general is if there's are
full of crackpots
you know cracker pottery you know fake
principals fake you know the companies
they create basically companies created
them they want to make money one good
example is at you you know I was so I
was saying you know agile it wasn't
called agile before big it began as the
extreme programming was extremely
popular you know and many you know this
is so many books you know they want to
sell you books name and corporations you
know they like you have a disco
operation they claim that they're gonna
help your company improve your software
they charge you millions of dollars or
10,000 you know things like that that's
how they develop basically they're
basically often organizations or
corporations money is behind it
basically they want to make money in
order to do that just like politics just
like politicians they you know they do
all possible ways but meanwhile they of
course they don't tell you oh I say this
because I want to make
money of course they don't say that any
in fact it's just like an individual
like me for example if I want you money
you know you like okay like any person
when they want to make to get money from
you they don't say that like salesman
you know they say the good things you
know they try to convince you it's a big
market but anyway so so it began with
extreme programming then part of it is
pair programming let's see actually
let's go to back to dome scripting back
to web tutorials and back to what is my
opinion of our actually I never used are
let me get to that but let me first of
all get to the software quackery so
here's my website design Python oh you
need to go to a hacker code a code
here's a collection of the hacker stuff
you see this is a typical of the agile
or extreme programming know okay I this
is a big topic of mine so I can talk
about this for the whole day okay so
free who do voodoo of software
engineering now look check out this
graph you know this graph is at your
extreme okay
now you see so you have code then you
have pair programming
they have unit test then you have payer
negotiation then stand-up meeting then
acceptance test iteration plan then
release pen and you know there's a cycle
of periods like release plan is every
month iteration plan is like every week
acceptance test is every day standard
meeting is like every day you know
acceptance test is every few days and so
on
you know unit test minutes favor gram in
seconds
like you you've had my back I scratch
your back let's sit together in chat you
know this so this this these are
Bhutto's these are basically they the
reason they are popular and it's because
they are organized organizations and
corporations they want to make money
they want to they - what are they what
they can you know possible ways they can
to squeeze money but they cannot just
say you know they have to come up with
ways right so this these are these are
their ways you know like I'm a company
okay
you are Google okay I tell you okay
Google you know we've we specialize in
agile you know extreme and we can help
your company maybe not Google because
Google is too big you know you know
small companies or midsize companies you
know we I can help you you know I you
know it's the only charge you know
hundred thousand dollars a week then you
can increase your company's productivity
and so on less bugs and so on so that's
how this organization these schemes with
these these things spread that's how
they spread so it began in a year 2000
it was extreme programming now I don't
remember who's who began it you know you
can look up Wikipedia USA but then it
became the extreme programming didn't it
was extremely popular but it evolved
into this agile agile they are no good
okay
basically any as far as software goes
you know when they talk about principles
okay also this crack potteries they
always almost always just like a code
they always almost always have a bunch
of jargons like fixed you know like
agile you know agile extreme programming
pair programming
you know you unit test pair negotiation
and stand up meeting you know what the
[ __ ] is that standard meeting you know
the
it encroaches your mind is that you know
you're working a company you get bored
in meetings right because because this
you know especially when the company
becomes big then you in general when you
are bigger than this lot of inefficiency
and the bureaucracy bureaucracy you know
that's just natural when your
organization you speak it become this
efficient so of course you know
companies like you know you get tired of
meetings and stuff so they invented so
that created this stand-up meeting so
that instead of sitting down you stand
up so what why because you know supposed
to you know of course when you stand up
you have to like you know it's not
sitting sitting me you know maybe make
you want to go to sleep you know so his
stand-up meeting so they got these all
these scraps of course they always
appear you know seems oh this that's
novel you know you know you know and
part of the reason and also this agile
and extreme programming thing they
always appeal to the managers especially
those managers who never coded one line
in their life okay because suppose I'm a
manager I never coded before you know
you know I just manage you guys okay you
guys are the programmer I don't know
nothing about programming that's not my
background maybe I came from this
business you know business background
like this business what they have a
degree or something you know
so I manage you guys yeah I don't know
about programming so when you have when
you have a task okay we need this
project and you are assigned you know a
particular task and you say you can do
it or you say you know how do I know I
wouldn't know one way okay so do I know
so one way to know is to get other
programmers to watch you you know so
other you know other programmers and
under me can tell me if you did good or
you did bad like he checks your code and
you know stuff and of course get you to
look at his code
that is the fundamental attraction of
pair programming okay
that is key because III don't know
nothing about coding I'm a manager I
need you know I need you guys to walk
but you tell me oh this cannot be done
or that is impossible you know how do I
know so I get you guys to talk about you
know so you got this pair programming
you know that's one of the thing that
that's that's how it grows and basically
even the founders you know the other day
I was last year half a year ago I was
watching a video actually what some of
the founders of agile programming they
they have a videos you know they was
invited to some conference okay they
giving a talk so actually one of them
said that yeah a Joe you know originally
it mean means something okay then
it became something else it got robbed
off by by the by corporations who wants
to make money you know push it
commercial corporations become something
else so he is you know no longer you
know it's supporting it you know like
one of the edge of guy said that so yeah
that's about extreme you know extreme
programming and you know so ever that
collection of articles extreme
programming and agile you do they are
quite quite a lot you know some famous
programmers has written again is dead
you know okay here is another example of
the Voodoo diagram you see now remember
these things always have lots of jargons
just like just like code one of the
hallmark of code okay is that they have
they have lots of jargons in fact I
claim this is so for the UNIX philosophy
kind of people to UNIX philosophy
joggins and and poor people of course
probably most famous for it okay so look
at this this agile you know so it's a
working software continuous integration
daily iteration iteration plan review
iteration retrospective okay then
release backlog release play you know it
looks so nice Wow you know vision the
strategy then strategy mission cause
charter funding adaptability
transparency simplicity unity this
accelerate delivery yeah so agile you
know it's no good so what I'm saying
okay back to the informatics I don't
actually know what it is but I looked up
Wikipedia yesterday
apparently it's some things perhaps it's
the next wave of the agile that's how
agile evolved to you know they like
every every every 10 years you know
people got tired of you say also you
created a new thing no it's normal
agile now its informatics informatics ok
so what I'm saying I was going to say ok
let's see informatics let's go to
Wikipedia I Rico there is a Wikipedia
article so guys you know if you have
some questions comment opinions type it
keep typing okay I'm gonna talk about it
if you don't type if you don't type
anything that means I'm doing good I'm
talking great talk
break the loop hey good morning
so let me let me get Wikipedia let me
get it now if I forgot your question
just type it again because sometimes I
you know see many comments sometimes I I
noticed I I may
some questions when I was watching my
video again in from informatics wait
there is a informatics no info mat ticks
X oh I thought I I think I saw Wikipedia
article yesterday but but anyway let's
just look at the let's look at this
website so it says yeah recognize the
leader of fully integrated IT and
business solution for public agencies
and private organizations informatics
continues to build upon excellent
reputation for delivering end-to-end
technology and project management
solutions in today's fast blah blah blah
ok is this by the way by the way Isaac
is this something like the course you
studied or something else but anyway I'm
saying ok any when when you when you
when you hear anything like principles
related to to software engineering ok
you know don't pay much attention to it
it's like almost ignored anything about
principle now when you want to know so
so if you throw away principles or agile
or these things so what's good about
software what makes great software I
mean what kind of strategy or
methodology to create great software ok
my opinion is is it's very simple you
know you you have knowledge you are
knowledgeable you work hard and you have
great skills and you understand the you
are knowledgeable about the area of your
field for example ecommerce or you know
what what whatever you are coding
website for you know traveling business
or whatever so knowledgeable about your
tools about the protocols about
technology
okay but about programming languages
know it very well that's good
you walk hard of course that's good you
know if you are lazy if your company is
full of lazy people you know that's not
good you know you work hard
knowledgeable about you know computer
science you know programming computer
science protocols foreign languages you
know work hard knowledge of about about
your field you know like what whatever
you know you are in the gaming industry
business industry financial industry you
know you you need to be somewhat
knowledgeable about that or aerospace or
education or whatever that's it
you know that's very simple qualities
you know you know it's very general
proven true but these are boring
qualities you know nobody's gonna want
you you know because you cannot make
money out of these qualities therefore
you need at you you know let's add sure
we let's do pair programming you know
and also programmers you know who wants
to hear that you need to want our
knowledge of course you need knowledge
but you know nobody wants to hear you
know knowledge means you have to study
you have to learn the programming
language inside out you know you have to
learn IT protocols tcp/ip protocols you
know all the things you need to you need
to [ __ ] you need to sweat and you know
to get those things so that's not you
know attractive attractive is oh we just
do you know if we just you know we if we
just have like continuous integration
you know we have this pair programming
unit test and and stand up meeting
everything will be great
yeah that's quackery that's a general
you know cracker is like Oh code you
know this is kind of like that I was
also also let me show you an article
sorry why software sucks
okay this Affco got me bad or hacker
news
wait Sophia sex okay and let me talk
about PDF sucks too by the way and let
me talk about Saudi bank sorry yeah yeah
let's Bank sorry yay okay there is y mx
people yep let's say pan Saudi hacker
news they mention how hacker news sorry
dog and what is politics so one day you
know I never joined hacker news I
despise these online websites you know
look at how they became today you know
Twitter that's how they evolved into I
despise these hacker news reddit you
know read it began in 2003 or 2005
something similar for a canoes they you
know because you you go there you got
you got this bunch of elite hacker geeks
you know they control it if you say
something they don't like they ban you
okay so snotty oak you know I never been
to hacker news before okay up to 2010 I
mean I've been to you know I have read
there but I never registered I never you
know register new account I never you
know
therefore I never post comments or stuff
I don't like I don't want to get
involved no reddit you know read it
became 2003 I witnessed you know in the
beginning reddit is written in Lisp
so it's this Emacs and Common Lisp is
one of the first you know reddit rooms
you know stash on you know then they
switch to Python and you know over the
years lots of controversy so you know
come and go and you don't know you know
you
so anyway reddit but I never joined you
know
because because I yeah I know what they
are like you know just a bunch of you
know hack it it is this this this smoke
group they want to tell everybody what
to do what you know if you agree if your
opinion for example if your opinion is
again it's open source they don't like
you they pain you you know this it's
it's not a matter of how you express it
I mean even you are nice polite you just
you know you give complete you know
thoughtful opinions about open source
that's that is contrary to their
opinions they don't like you
eventually they're gonna kick you out
you know that's what they are we you
know but okay so I never have a car I
never had a hacker news in one day in
2010 i disc so some you know someone
posted my my website article to hacker
news not the first time it's not the
first time but someone posted this
particular article to hacker news and
that article is this one so for your
sucks okay and there I then then then
they I don't know who it is you know a
canoe Snape and they banned solid oak
okay so from that day on anything on
solid oak domain cannot be posted to a
canoes by the way I never of course I
don't have a count at least I never
posted anything to a canoes it's other
people right other people who you know
think my you know the article may be
interesting or controversial they
posited so anyway one day this Arco is
posted on Hacker News and then they
banned me they found solid oak and and
by the way back then in 2010 I don't
have sorry info yet I don't have a go
Emax dog you know I don't have the other
domains the only one I have everything
is I'm sorry dot org
III separated them because Google banned
Google also bank sorry dog so I you know
then I don't have money to live so I
started to separate the programming and
math stuff technical stuff took sorry
dot info and the Emacs that stuff to ago
Emacs start oh okay that that's how I
start to have you know several domains
but I rather have just one sorry dog you
know because I'm a opinion that you know
you are you as a person you you know
personable with opinions in life you
know you have you know you should be not
be afraid you know you should show them
he expressed them you know everything
you are you are programmer but you also
have opinions about you know all the
things including you know any and all
controversial stuff you know you should
say it you know that's good for society
you know that that's good for society
but anyway so hacker news so so imposed
is my article and and today Bank sorry
dog yeah that's what happened so so this
article is kind of detail of that
incidence oh so how do I know it's been
because some other day someone posts on
Hacker News asking them what website are
banned and why are they banned you know
someone post is on Hacker News and you
know I I run into this article so then
they then they give they list a bunch of
website and sorry that is one of them
that's how I noticed and this is around
2010 and since then you know I've also
used blogger so you know people and I
also split my website not because of the
hacker news but because Google I wanted
to you know make money by ads that's why
I sprayed them so anyway this this our
code details some of
incidents you know like I make a record
of it you know these these these these
[ __ ] and they also like to erase
history you know for example I was
banned you know you have probably run
into this article before okay this this
this article is originally on Emacs wiki
they talk about penny me but one day
they erased it like they erase the whole
page you know let's not accept
acceptable to me okay it's like a coat
you know even encoding improper law like
us at least us us is or was good you
know a system governed by law you know
you cannot if you capture is if someone
is broke the law you have cops capture
the guy and everything is record you
have trial okay then then you have a
record record of it what crime did he
commit you know what what did he do
what's his defense is he okay if he is
good defense and everything no evidence
then he's free to go you know but if
there's evidence you know he did bad
this record of it you know and this this
Emacs scumbags okay so they discuss this
about penny me and I put my opinions
there you know one day they erase the
page is gone
so I captured it you know I save it as a
record so this this has come back you
know you don't want to erase history on
it okay and today today Google is doing
that Google is erasing all the websites
you know you know he like for example
Google elimin well that's another topic
you know the erase history like all the
you know it like what happens you know
it makes they make it hard to find okay
it's harder to find but okay so many
topics let me get back to this one more
thing I want to mention
canoes let me go
sorry max I'm just about done here
and then I'll read the comments so if
you go to my Emacs website and if you go
to Emacs miscellaneous then let's see
let's search folk song so okay here the
item number 8 here free not IRC
immigrant channel 10 I'm sorry then I
give a detail why am i bad okay
I mean you can see that then you click
on where do you click
oh here this link you click on that link
that's how you get to this page you know
it's a no-go Emacs you know you know you
know also I want to mention it's not
like I'm not you know I swear a lot and
sometimes insulting you know
intentionally insulting to these people
because I don't like them so it's not
like I'm I have you know it's not like
you know I'm perfect or anything you see
you know it's not like I'm a saint
okay I understand you know I have some
issues you know I you know but still
but although I don't you know I I think
they are bad yeah if you ask my opinion
so anyway so that's the Emacs pan that's
a how can you expand this one
what is this one Keaney
Hilton this is some Larry would look at
this you know remember you see back then
okay
even in 2000's almost every post you
have this quote this part is called
signature okay where you contains your
name maybe contact information and some
smarty you know smartass quotes and you
know you can see back in Poe it's very
popular you know so this guy says polio
or what poor will always provide the no
okay so this is 2009 so people are
talking about pammi
I think this this is a complan Lisp okay
many of these people's name I remember
this guy Kenneth Hilton he's old common
lisp ER he's he's on Twitter by the way
this is like 2009 so it's like 10 years
ago
Kenneth Chilton D herrings yes many of
the names I remember yeah but this is
this is like history let me see if I can
some interesting guys like a mission
Island this guy's is very bad Adam
Atkinson Mackenzie
he is the maintainer of C C++ mods in
Emacs so he is one of the Emacs Emacs
dev okay
he is also one of the person who who
prevented progress let's for this way
one of he is one of the person who did
the most preventing modernization of
Emacs because every time there is some
change you know to Emacs that improves
it he opposes he opposes and he is very
loud he insist you know his view of
Emacs is like 1980s way he want to use
Emacs the way people use Emacs in 1980s
so multiple times whenever there is
something you know he opposed it he
wanted you know Emacs to be his stay in
the 1980s way and also for example what
one of the thing he hate is Unicode okay
Unicode like today is so popular you
know you have you almost you know you
have emoji you have arrows you know math
symbols its and in fact today Unicode
you know is in in a lot of programming
languages documentation for example it's
in :
it's in JavaScript wait well I'm not
going to be exact because I can give you
a lot of examples like show you the page
right now but but that's gonna go into
another topic but anyway so he is a guy
Alan McKenzie he's a guy he's a guy who
organist
he don't like unicode his idea is like
every text you type in email
everything building must be pure ASCII
okay
he very bad I mean up to like two years
ago he killed a one major improvement in
emacs which is well that's another topic
you know if you guys like me to talk
about that I can't go into that but you
know because i I've got so many topics
then you know then you know if you want
me to talk about that I'm going to show
you the detail the articles what exactly
what's the situation you know what's the
incident you know I can show you lots of
that but anyway I don't so let's see
what okay so this page we talked about
why Sophie okay why software sucks this
is back okay we get him back to the
software voodoo thing so this is my
opinion about why software suck back in
2001 I pretty much still hold the same
opinion and actually I've talked about
I've kind of gave an overview about my
opinion already like like what are the
Voodoo was like coat
you know UNIX philosophy and this agile
extreme programming and pattern software
patterns pattern my ass you know
patterns was like hugely wildly popular
in the year 2000 then you have anti
patterns but today you don't hear it
much anymore it's like almost gun you
know so this kind of code you know this
this fad code or voodoo they change they
change every like 10 years they come and
go but when they are there that it's
like every programmer is insist that is
the only way if you disagree they they
say you are true okay so hi Aaron oh hi
Aaron yeah yeah I know you are
recognize you but let me go back okay
I'm almost done here so um okay I think
I should read some
because it's being a while okay yeah
okay let's let me read the comments
break the loop okay good morning good
morning
so informatics yeah so hexa I just to
play devil's advocate on agile doesn't
some kind of process when working a
group is necessary yeah of course
whether it's top down waterfall yeah of
course yes some kind of process is as
yeah it's necessary like doesn't matter
what you know in company in running a
company or in software development or
let's say on a road to be a
mathematician or any collaborate
collaborative project
yeah there is usually some you know some
process and there are many right and
yeah so so how does that yeah there is
some process so is an agile so obviously
the implication is that so is an agile
you know one of these process which may
be good or maybe you know which which
has advantages and disadvantages yeah
that's that that's true
I mean that's that's a good perspective
you know as far as my opinions opinion
goes okay but however I think you know I
think agile and the extreme extreme
programming they are not I mean you
could say they are you know just one of
the methodology or principle in in this
this in Teva you know so for engineering
but you know I would I would correct I
would call them actually voodoo I mean
okay let me put this
it's correct I mean it's true that in
many endeavors
especially collaborations you have
methodologies you know principles
process a procedure you know you
developed or plan you know but however
it is also true in all kind of plans or
you know or in any area politics you
know in Sciences mathematicians you have
kind of the crackpot you know crackpot
or you know slime or scum smirks you
know some bad people okay let's call
them scumbags they they sell you fake
things you know like fake news you know
there are some people who create a
website that's intentionally or just
fake news no basis you know but they try
to sell it they they make money so this
is also true so what I'm saying is that
agile and extreme programming of that
type in that direction okay to to you
know to you know to what degree is well
it's up to you to church okay but I'm
saying agile and in extreme programming
they are like that why because they to
me they they they they have many
characteristics of code or you know this
snake snake or you know they have a
bunch of dragons then and then then also
okay one of the most important thing you
can kind of test test is to be money
money because they always come down to
money you know like this the
corporation's whatever they they propose
agile they're at the end they are making
money you know they want you to adapt
them to you know they charge you or
books you know agile books like ten
thousand agile books extreme programming
books you know it's money so that's
that's that's my opinion that's
so big the loop says I'm not a fan of
agile but seems to me that a group of
people working together on software I
have to work yeah so I covered that and
I chose with Sprint's continuous
integration is just a way okay there are
some you know I think some of the ideas
is good now I I'm not too familiar with
Sprint's like I'm not too sure what that
is kind of a branch of agile I guess
French like religion you know you have
you have Christian ality then you have
Catholics then you have more moments you
have you have Islamics
these are called apple hammock religions
okay well of course miss the Buddhism a
no that's then you have different sex
you know sex sex
you know they fight each other so I want
anyway no so continuous so okay some
some ideas I would say it's it's
reasonably good for example unit testing
so the unit your idea of unit testing is
basically you you write programs to test
the correctness of software obviously
that's a good idea but you know for
example Wolfram research ok I know back
in 1995 before there's a there's a
phrase unit testing okay they tested
their software of course autumn as much
as auto automated in an automated way
like millions of lines you know they
test those Mathematica you know wolf and
research Mathematica that's before unit
test the the word ever come up let's
give you I mean let me give you another
example open source free software
foundation free software ideology you
know good for Humanity sharing helping
people my ass the [ __ ] about them selves
okay before this exist free software
foundation before open source exists
there is a good they already exist it's
called good
person good man okay before you know I
read programming Mathematica I share you
know feel free you know this like what's
copyright the copyright phrases feel
free to use this software okay if you if
you use it please give me credit that's
it that's in my mathematical software
you can still find online you can find
it if you search okay but this is back
in 1995 of course it's not me it's not
just me or the other other scientists
and programmers they and also even the
UNIX people you know many software many
programmers are like that okay we don't
need you don't need the ideology free
free software foundation the open source
to do good things to to you know to help
other people the you know being a good
person you know helping is part of the
pressure
one of the fundamental pressure you know
being a human animal okay but but what's
wrong but the open source and free
software they they have become my
ideology that's the thing bad about them
there's nothing wrong with unit test
okay until there is this kind of
ideology I mean there is like everyone
is pushing it if you don't do it you are
wrong you know you are you are a bad
person or you are just stupid you you
know you you know that's that's when
things get bad okay so that's you know
it's so you know the unit test idea you
know when you have like a like a choke
or not choke a note that's what it
became you know also applies to open
source because if you don't you know
then people start to accuse you you know
they did they disassociate oh that guy
you know I don't want to associate
because he's using Microsoft Word you
know maybe you know it's like that you
know this happens everyday you can see
what of course I know some of you of
course you know I have controversial
opinions and of course some of you
disagree that's totally fine
so let me see Yeomans owes me see the
car let me continue to answer the
comments yeah and yeah you know I don't
know who who is a guy who you know yeah
anyway I don't know who I don't I'm not
sure it's poor granham you know I
suppose he's so big you know at the top
he doesn't really I don't know if we
seem or not but I suppose it's not you
know it's probably you know they have
that's that means and I don't know you
can't keep everything oh god I'm so you
know I'm so behind in reading the
comments I forgot what's the context you
can't so Aaron says you can keep
everything forever Aaron says we get
older and mellow out
Oh disagreements can be forgotten and
maybe we can start appreciating each
other what we contribute okay that's
about open source oh oh it's about
something it's you know what okay let me
catch up with the comments how is going
how is going Aaron great to see you here
so a Zak say it's too bad I got crass
okay so EDT rate religion branching it's
how to review okay over source - okay I
guess I don't want Google supervening
okay so keep interesting about math
America doing automated unit testing
backing yeah yeah it's backing yeah I
suppose I suppose is not just to fan
research I suppose you know big
companies they you know the is
it's you know it's not the unit it's not
just you know the agile people invented
that the only thing they invented is
probably the name unit test you know
like once you give something a name then
you can think you know it's more likely
to spread you know become more popular
oh um yeah I hate UML UML is the one of
the crap one of the Voodoo created by
this Martin Fowler guy that I despise
Martin Fowler guy okay not as a person I
mean he's probably a good person okay
but I'm talking about opinions on
technology as far as you know opinions
on technology goes I think Martin Fowler
is one of the Voodoo he is one of you
like in my mahi and Larry war
okay the creative pearl is one of the
you know snake oil you know sailors
salesmen they sell snake oil Martin
Fowler right I talked about this like
for one hour in previous talk show you
know probably a few weeks ago yeah
Martin Fowler with his with his
something something injection nothing he
does I like you know Saudi okay that's
okay yeah you know I'm not gonna repeat
Oh topics hurt your leg hope you get
well yeah so Aaron Aaron is a Python
expert I met on Twitter and we had some
good grade Google Hangouts and Aaron
just taught me about Anna Kandra
that Python big Python distribution we
talked about few days ago so okay so I
think that cover the comment oh yeah the
other one the earlier there's a question
about our Mario T Mariotti you don't
have an icon for some reason for your
profile so I don't I never used ah so I
actually haven't I don't know I don't
have I don't know nothing about ah you
know I just heard that it's a it's a
language for statistics it's a math
oriented language as opposed to the
industrial languages it's a math
oriented language for doing statistics
but I heard that it's also badly
designed you know it's not something I'm
you know you know I think I'm gonna look
into yeah yeah from what I heard but I
never I don't even yeah I can't say I
even seeing one lying about I just read
it
highs for statistics yeah I don't I
don't like it for much else and Python
is great for statistics
too true so so Python well I as far as I
know you know is really good for
statistics so Python has caught up I
guess
oh yeah so I did so I didn't like reddit
hacker news I mean that's a general
sense okay I don't like yeah and so
because I didn't like them before
because you know I usually it's just
controlled you know for example you
Emacs oh oh oh programming language
group you know Perl
you know back then mm it's Emacs Perl
you know maybe Python you know I know
what's gonna happen if I join because if
I join you know I want to express my
opinions right like my opinions about
open source I have had this opinions
back in mm you know and improving in
language design you know folks you know
I hate I hate Python I hate Perl you
know I I want to express my opinions but
I know what happens you know why I
joined them you know of course I joined
there is to talk discuss and sooner or
later on some topics I will have to you
know he'll come - you know - for me to
express my opinions I know what would
happen when I do they're gonna start to
bear me so that's why I don't like them
I rather like the free kind of open
public communication group packed like
new scoops back then you have new scoops
so I use new scoops that I use i don't i
don't use groups that are you know they
have that has admins you know the the
demean soup and who are these are the
means you know they basically they are
just whoever the being the first person
created that group you become me and
your friends become odd means you know
so it's like whoever is there first you
know so anyway i didn't like them but
but i like i created account on reddit
about i don't know i don't remember when
like maybe 2010 you know I thought you
know maybe it's time you know maybe I
can maybe it's things changed
so I created and I started to it's like
on and off you know it's like all these
new social medias Google had bloggers
you know Google had Google+ which Google
just killed you know a few days ago and
you have live journal I was on
LiveJournal you know I you know so new
technology I try to sometimes yeah join
in to experiment so on reddit
I still use now you know but not much
because it's still it's it's actually
today you know as you know in today's is
different this is social justice group
they pen you know more severely on
different things so and raided you know
ready Emacs is slam information you know
and also the hacker community you know
back in 1990s or 2000's you have the
hacker kind of subculture what you might
call properly a subculture and that's
kind of going to you know also UNIX
philosophy you don't hear it much
anymore
it's replaced by today's generation
programmers I'm not sure there's a name
to it you know but lots of Millennials
Code of Conduct
you know there's evil stuff extremely
sinister you know the code of conduct
the thing they are created they are
created as a political thing whose sole
purpose is to persecute it gives them a
right to persecute anyone they don't
like that's what the code of conduct is
you know on the surface of course on the
surface they their days it's supposed to
be helped to help the minority to help
you know the week but actually they they
are helping the powerful that's what
they are so Ben Franklin on discussion
Ben Franklin our discussion or
discussing opinions said he was much
more persuasive when he did
when he did not hold his opinions very
strongly yes Oh Eddie's pretended not to
yeah that's a good point yeah I know
that you know I understand that but but
you know when people call me trolling I
know that actually I understand that but
but my intention is just to like insult
them in in so this [ __ ] [ __ ] is
okay okay I'm ready exaggerating a
little bit but it's kind of true like
you know when when I see these people
okay these people for example let's say
Emacs okay we all love Emacs okay in
there and I'm famous I suppose for you
know being a nonconformist okay
Emacs okay I still love you max I use it
every day of course i living in max
right but but I have my opinions and
that's more important you know I like I
want to say my opinions so so so my but
I know especially with you know
especially back then okay I know these
people you cannot like it has you know
you know that you know when you say this
they're gonna pain you they don't like
you okay so but basically I find their
behavior not good okay I think okay you
are the bad guy or you are the bad guy
okay and they are using Emacs right but
I I observed you know maybe through some
interactions I think you are no good you
are not good so I have opinion I'm going
to say you are the [ __ ] idiot because
you know there I post my opinion because
he so there's a bit of that you know but
you know so but I wasn't intended to
convince them no because the way I think
you know because the way I think is that
you know I wasn't there to convince you
because the way I think it's kind of
like this okay so if one plus one is two
right now if you say one plus one
three let's say Emax community everyone
is thinking one plus one equals two
three now I am going to come in
I'm gonna enjoy to just tell you you are
[ __ ] [ __ ] idiot
one plus one is two go [ __ ] yourself
okay I'm just gonna leave it there I'm
gonna insert them and and and that's
what I want to do Mike Michael that's my
intention was not to hey that's
hey guys you know hey guys maybe you
know maybe if you you know like like
like you know if I really want to change
their opinion you know yeah I could you
know that's something I could do
i-i-i-i've I'm aware of the methods to
the approach to get to that goal you
know hey guys you know you know you
start to talk about something and
intentionally maybe you touch some
subject and made them think you know
that's the way to go
but that's not what I was doing you know
back then at least least back then back
then I mean it depends on the topics you
know depends on Who am I dealing with
what's the situation for example in your
company I would never do that
you know if I'm working a company I
don't do that so I'm quite aware you
know what what what is you know I'm
doing so yeah that's also and so a lot
of you know this back then you know a
lot of my course with them is that I
just I just throw some opinions I didn't
tell them to [ __ ] themselves because
they are wrong you know like you know
sometimes I feel sad like poor people
power is dead now I want those [ __ ]
there there are hundreds of them who has
cobrahead Koro
who called me a troll who has done
things to me and in some cases League
legally harassment okay and whenever I
argue with me I never harassed them in
any legal way okay in any legally way
you call harassment no well the most I
say is go [ __ ] yourself that's that's
not that's not illegal okay because this
is this difference we
when you sum when you do something to
some someone that actually impedes their
livelihood or damage their reputation
that's legally you know that's that's
liable that's you know harassment or
what's the other would but anyway you
know but that's what I'm not what I'm
doing I mean you know so I was going to
say how many people are watching now
let's see now I'm getting good at videos
now oh one hour ten people watching okay
so I talked so much non-stop from the
beginning yeah so a lot happen a lot you
know yeah so I was talking about people
you know so I had a lot of quirós and
now people is good you know I want this
I want people to be responsible okay and
all these hackers they always almost
tends to be anonymous like they don't
like to use real names so I already
don't hacker news you got all this bunch
of facts you know padmé padmé or
whatever you know and they change their
account they post something that I did
it you know this this happened for like
20 years now that's why society gets bad
let's that's why you go to youtube or we
all or Twitter you know and you look at
the comments okay Oh anonymous and oh
like you know stupid idiotic jokes or oh
you know you know you know like content
no content
same thing with Reddit you know jokes or
mean so you know this like little
content maybe you know 5% is constant
95% is garbage why does that happen
that's because this you know that that's
because of this kick the way they they
think you know that's and this company
is trying to push their product you know
this like button the heart button and so
on this is not supposed to be that way
you know you go to youtube all the
comments it's like none not like you
know 95% of them is garbage you go to
Twitter all of them is like name-calling
and nothing else
that's who made them that's made by
these programmers these hackers who made
them us we made it who else you know you
know that's that's this you know that's
my opinion
okay so today so today's topic is is
actually so today actually we have a
topic now today's topic was about you
know yeah anyway so I was saying you
know I you know I prefer responsibility
you know if you have opinions say it you
know put put your name out there
say it you don't have to you don't have
to be extreme okay of course just you
know that's why people call me a troll
you don't have to be extreme but you
know say it's say whatever with your
opinion with your name and you know and
think before you say things you know you
know keep reasons you know that's what I
like you know that's what I like so what
I think I think maybe that's we've been
talking for hours so maybe that's that's
a good that's that's about it anything
anything else new hey Mario Mario were
you from
so yeah that's a good talk today so
break the loop I remember you were
asking me you know was it my morning or
my night yeah yeah actually shifts all
the time so today I'm going to go to bed
around maybe three or cracking I have to
know but it's kind is just like shifts
all the time wait I'm still online right
I'm still yeah
okay so say something say something guys
so let's see let's see you see something
I wanted to cover so yeah that and that
in that and why software suck yeah so so
yeah I was saying you know like all the
people like word I want to think um the
hood like especially like the pearl
people I wanted them to come back you
know come back you know like Saudis or
was I right or you you know so so
there's some validation you know so I
mean so these people would you know on
anonymous say they do whatever then they
disappeared
you know they disappear after few years
you know so in the cycle begins how to
set of ex4 scratch are you kidding me
Aaron
well how does it of Emax from scratch
you start from scratch
well I suppose you have yeah I mean you
know I I you for you already have you
know of fancy setup I bet
so okay yeah so let's wrap up in it I
think that's it for today
informatics yeah I don't know what that
is oh yeah that's about screen size
comparison yeah each year it it changes
every few years it changes window size
Twitter for notifications so Aaron says
I have space max minimal space max
config changes
oh okay so use uses space space max so
you use Python 2 code you work in a fun
financial sector financial sector right
so is any interesting things Aaron about
Python so Mario says I'm from Peru Wow
Peru great great - great to see you
yeah great to meet you
ok roots
omocha Dora's hey good morning ever
could have occurred Dora's so ever
Ghidorah says
so wait so Ericka Dora says I'll tell
you how I did it I search on YouTube
Emacs tutorial then I clicked a video
mic zamansky
I watch all his videos oh ok that's
interesting so I don't remember I don't
recall the name Mike Szymanski
so let's look it up and maybe other
people will find it interesting let's
type a max oh yeah there
oh okay hmm using Emacs using Emacs
episode 37 okay so guys check it out
avocado
Dora's have AK Edoras with the way were
you from Aaron says Aaron who says I'm a
minimalist when it comes to tricking in
Emacs you mean in Emacs oh oh oh I guess
you mean Emacs
yeah in Emacs I'm a minute minimalist
too so I guess that's it for today last
chance if you guys have any comments
type it okay Erin says everything
minimalist that's cool avocado says yes
it's avocado and parekura's oh that's
interesting
avocado first pythagoras havoc Edoras
okay that makes it easier to remember
now have a cod auras from Niagara wow
that's interesting too I I've been to
Niagara Falls
back in 1986 maybe
oh wait Niagara that's a country right
wait they're not the Niagara Falls but
Niagara is in well in Africa or South
America Central yeah a Central America
okay oh yeah there okay cool
I like dark themes backgrounds I like
clear fonts I like very standardized
ways of tricking things because I don't
like dealing with bugs
yeah hi Mario
ok I think that's it for today so so
thank you guys for coming by
great to see you Aaron see you guys next
time next time