Good morning guys. Welcome to another
episode
of Kan Talk Show.
We are going to code Emac Lisp today. So
let me show you my keyboard first.
So this is Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 80
UHK80. I did a review about two weeks
ago. Check on my YouTube. Okay.
Fantastic. Ultimate hacking keyboard.
And today we are just going into code
wam language.
Okay. So
play at 1.5 speed. I command you if you
are here say hi. Okay. We got like two
people three people say hi now. Okay.
and and we going to do wuframe language.
So let's start now. Wra language has
been you can download for free about
three or four years ago. So let's start
it.
It is the most magn magnific magnificent
programming language. Okay. A magnitude
better than all existing languages.
Uh it's a high level language. By
default, you have
7,000 functions without loading any
library. Okay. Uh and uh you can
download it by just search for
SI my name wra.
Okay. So you can see Wuang language
tutorial. go there and uh you can go
there download and download at this link
wolf language wrame research website
okay turn on JavaScript
uh the download is like five gigabytes
okay so because it's a huge it's a
artificial intelligence covers
everything so download it for free and
read my tutorial this is in uh kind of
comprehensive you know tutorial for
programmers. Okay. And uh so let's go to
move language for programmers uh
download. Okay. Uh
and uh that's a introduction. Okay. And
if you are coding, if you are a Emacs
user, which is what you are looking at,
the most powerful programmers editor,
uh much more powerful than VS Code.
You can you can you uh you can download
my karaw wam mode. Okay, the link is on
my talk show page or just search for
Emacs kasar wam mode that allows you to
code wam language in Emacs.
Hello Blair Mo. Hi Kar looking forward
to this show. Thank you. So uh intro
introduce yourself you know like where
are you from? What country are you a
student or are you uh something else?
Okay. So today we're gonna do let's go
to desktop folder because I have these
folders prepared. Now if you have any
questions about wam language this is the
time to ask me. Okay ask me any
questions about wam language. Now let's
see. Okay now there's a here is a list
of things to do. I need to do so uh as I
do them I'll explain them. Okay.
So let's begin. Okay. Any questions ask
okay so wam language tuples. So you go
to my wam let me you know basically
today we going to demonstrate some list
processing functions in wuam language.
Okay wam language for programmers. Let's
uh magnify this and uh uh list. Okay, so
you got basics, print version, show
function help, find function by name,
comment, and how to print and string and
number, how to input numbers or
hexadimals and boolean, true and false,
how to test equality and list. Okay, so
list is what we want. Go to the list
section.
Then go to um list operations. Okay,
there are so many like typically in
Python or the programming languages you
have like 20 functions or methods on
list. In wam language you have like a
okay without loading
even loading any library. So what we
want to go is list combinotaurics. So
let me show you guys what. So turppo.
Okay, let's do turbo. So copy that. Go
to the talk show page and uh list
operations. Let's paste the link there.
Show in browser. So combinatorics. Okay.
So so let's uh okay go there.
Turbo. Let me just start to demo. Okay.
So, so this turpple function what it
does is it's it returns all possible
tpples of a given list. Okay. So, let me
show you. So, what I want to do is a b.
Okay. Run it.
Cheers. Red wine and juice.
I am a professor from Oklahoma.
I have been using Emacs for five years.
Oh my god. Professor, thank you for uh
uh being here. Yeah. So thank yeah
professor that's great because uh
oftentimes my uh my audience are
students.
Uh so AB you know given a list of a and
b. So you want all possible com all
possible tpples. So you got a a ab a ba
bb. Okay. So now let's say turbo AB but
three three items per turbo. So you got
all company. So you get more complex. So
let's
uh let's format it.
Okay. So you get that
now. Now let's try to uh AB uh ABC.
Okay. AB C. And let's just two. Okay.
Two. two.
So you get you get a a ab a c ba bb bc
ca. So anyway it's all combination all
possible uh combination of two things.
Okay. So
you see what I'm doing is I'm clarifying
my tutorial. So this example I don't
need anymore. Let's delete that. So two
items and three tle. We already got
that. Okay. So now put it back syntax
color showing browser. So we we got our
turbo function return all possible
interpose. Okay, that's a demon
demonstration. Now let's check my notes.
Every hour or two I walk around for half
hour with my uh surface tablet and I
take notes. So these things I want to
do. So these things are you know my
notes. Then when I come back sit down
and I code them. So this means so what
I'm doing here these notes means that I
want to replace the one two three the
source list by symbols AB because if you
use one two three it's more confusing
because you know if you use symbols it's
more clear. Now in wam language it's
symbolic programming language like lisp.
Okay. So everything is a symbol. So you
can have AB and they'll just return you
know the value A or B or AB you know you
can have any any name you know uh in
Python for example if you do this you'll
get you know A is not defined B is not
defined things like that so you know you
can do this in w language because it's
symbolic and unlike this where you have
to quote the symbols if a symbol doesn't
have a value you have to quote it you
know like tick but in Wuan language you
don't have to because when a symbol does
not have a value it just the symbol
itself okay I think that's a actually
improvement in fact wam language is much
uh based on lisp basically this l this
and apl that's the root of wuam language
okay so so this example is done so we
want the example ABC2 then delete it. So
next uh with D. Okay. So return. So
there's some um wording issue. So
dimension
return all possible array of dimension.
Uh let's reward it. So let me show you
where that is. So this is a topo
section. So we showed this this input
but there are several variations of
input. You can you can give it two
lists.
So this will effectively do cartesium
product. Okay. Then you can have this
form. Uh let me demonstrate that. Uh
okay. But but but I but first of all I
want to fix the wording here. Okay. So
let me show you two different wording.
So this is what we want to do. array
dimension that
uh using elements in list one. Okay, so
that's a mistake. There's no list one.
So delete that.
Go back to browser. Look here. Refresh.
Okay, that's better. Uh yeah. Okay, so
let's do that.
all possible array 2 by two. Okay. So
let's start to do this example.
Okay. So comment return or possible 2x
two array. Okay, that's what this means.
Uh
yeah. So let's run it.
Okay, basically the same thing as here.
So
um what? So let's try you see the goal
is to make the tutorial as clear as
possible. So can we can we try a one one
by one array? So what does it mean one
by one? Yeah, that still makes sense. Uh
actually you can do it like that.
Yeah, that's just one item. Okay. So,
one by two.
So, this is a let's see if I can.
So, this is
one by two. Does that make sense? Uh,
I'm not sure. So, but
two by one. Let's just do some examples.
So again, they are all possible tpples.
Now,
now a tuple of one item doesn't make
sense. That's why you got these, you
know, braces single item A and B. Yeah,
that doesn't make sense. So So you don't
So you don't want um
let's see. Yeah, this doesn't I mean it
logically it still makes sense. You you
get a turbo of one by you know just one
by
dimensional one matrix basically.
Yeah. Okay. Let's remove it. Uh
because we got other things to do. So
let me think.
Does that make sense? Uh okay. So C tles
AB 2 by one. So 2 by one. No, that
doesn't make sense. Whenever you have
one,
that's not
making a lot of sense. Now this is
2x two. Yeah. So So you see, look at
this single item. That is a matrix, two
dimensional matrix. It's a 2x2 matrix.
Here's another matrix. 2x2 matrix.
Here's another one. So basically this
returns all possible 2x2 matrix of of
involving elements A, A and B. So let's
write it. Yeah. Uh
yeah. So so actually
that makes sense. Okay.
So if if we say
uh let's say
2x two by3 can you can you actually do
that?
Yes we can do that but it's going to be
long
result. Yeah.
Yeah. This is you know expon exponential
growth.
Oh my god. This is like thousands of
items.
Okay, we we don't want that.
Delete. So, what about 2x3?
Okay. Kind of hard to see. Okay. But you
can if you run this right now we are
running it in EMAC
of course you can run it in wufam
notebook shift enter to evaluate it so
you get prettier
output
see okay so let's not let's not do this
too long okay
uh delete okay put it back and put it
back syntax collect show in browser. So
you got tupose and we just demonstrated
all possible arrays. Okay.
Okay. So this one is done.
Array depth. Okay. Let me let me talk
about this. What what does it mean? What
does dimension means in array depth?
Okay. So that would be
uh let me go to it. So subset
subsequences it's fascinating. Okay. So
that's why part of the reason I
recommend wam language because in um in
python in whatever language goland or
even has f they don't have these
functions even if you
most of the time even including all the
standard libraries they don't have these
functions. So this combinatorics you
know for for example you have
permutations or possible permutations
or possible interpose then you have you
know you have several forms.
This one does cartesian
product. Okay. And uh so then you have
subsets or possible subsets of a set
and uh all or possible subsequences you
know they they they are kind of tricky
you know so these are all combinatoric
stuff and all possible groupings there's
something I need to do here so anyway
but let me go to this part I want to um
so go to list operations and go to the
list concept the array and dimension
dimenions. Okay. So here we talk about
what does dimension mean? Dimension just
means the
basically the shape of the list or the
shape of the of the n dimensional
matrix.
Okay? Like if we have a 2x two matrix
that's a two-dimensional matrix because
you you got two n by two and the shape
is two and two. You use two number. So
in the first level you got two elements.
In the in the second nested level you
got two elements each. So that's why 2x2
matrix. Then you can have 2x3 matrix or
3x2 matrix or 2x 2x two or 2x 2x3. So
this sequence of numbers is called
dimensions
uh in wam language. Okay you can see. So
you got the 2x2 matrix here. So the
dimensions is 22. Now here you got um
you got a simple flat list. The
dimension is just three because it only
have one dimension and uh it has three
elements.
So that's what dimensions means. So but
what I want to do array depth. Okay. So
ar the so what I want to do is add a
example for array depth. Array depth
just means the dimension of the array.
Okay. So if you have 3x3 matrix that's a
two-dimensional matrix because you
require two uh
numbers to specify. So if you have 3x3x2
matrix that's three-dimensional because
it requires requires three numbers.
Okay. So,
so in other words, array depth just
return the length of dimensions. But
let's add a reexample.
Uh where where is it? Uh we still on
this page. So copy the file path.
Uh close that. Okay. Paste the link
here. Go to it. Go to it. Search for
depth. Okay. Array depth. Um,
so that's dimensions. Search, search,
search. So you got to go to the depth
here. Okay. So
language make put it up. So array
depth. Okay. Then let's say AB.
So AB
and C D. Okay. that we will return two
because it's two-dimensional matrix.
Okay. So and
you can say ABC
that is uh
uh that is AB C
D
E F that's a 2x3 matrix
that dimension is still two
uh so
so what if you want a 2x you know let's
say
2x 2x2 matrix okay so let's generate it
uh
okay so
2x 2x two matrix okay let's say f uh xyz
okay x goes from 1 to two.
Y goes from 1 to two. Z goes from one to
one to two. Okay. So do it.
That will return
uh 2x two by
two. So let's
okay let's clarify
okay so you can see this is um
does that make sense?
Okay so
what are we doing? So we are doing so we
are generating a
one two
yeah 2x 2x2 matrix. So if you if you say
dimensions of this thing
at
that we will return
run it.
There it is. Okay. So,
and if you say array depth,
that will say three.
There it is. Okay. So, because there are
three numbers here. So, does that make
sense? Uh, this is a bit complicated
example. Uh I'm not happy with it
exactly but
um again the goal is to make this as
simple as possible so people can
understand.
So here we have dimension two too. Yeah
let's let's get the dimension into place
so so it's easier for people to
understand. Okay.
Dimensions to two red depth two. Okay.
And here we let's get uh dimensions.
Okay.
Dimensions
that would that would be 2 three.
Okay. and the length let's uh put a
breaker there. Okay. So dimensions 2x3
matrix is 2 three. So comment 2x3 matrix
you know when you have English comment
actually that makes it easier to
understand.
So um so you know that's one of the
problem of programmers or hackers
writing a tutorial because to me it's so
obvious you know like dimension this
this just means the dimension 2 three
but to other people not really. So but
if you say 2x3 matrix people people will
get it. Similarly for a lot other
programmers they write tutorials or
blogs about Hascal about uh you know
functional programming or about you know
or C++ first coders to them is something
is obvious but actually uh not really
uh okay so so you show the dimension 2
by 2x3 matrix the dimension is 23 it
becomes so obvious then dimension of
that is two so Um so in here let's also
add a comment two by two matrix. Okay.
Okay. So
okay so what about this one? This is
three this this is like a 3x3 matrix.
I mean 2x2x2 matrix. Okay. Uh let's see.
Let's make let's make make a comment.
Create a 2x two
by two
matrix. Uh
okay.
Okay. Then dimension 222 array dev 3.
Okay. I think that's clear. Put it back.
syntax correct show in browser.
So we explained here array depth
uh same as length. So
typically known as the
dimension
of a array. Okay,
better. Is it better? Yes, I think so.
So, okay. Now, update the updated date.
Okay, this part is done. Add example.
Close it. Now, level spec. That's
another very interesting thing.
Okay, le level spec. Okay, so let's do
level spec. So that's uh that will be
level. Okay. Now let me explain this
because this this is a very powerful and
interesting idea.
Okay. So
so if you have a nested list basically
that list can be represented as a tree.
For example, one, two, three, a flat
list. You can represent it as a tree
like that. You know where the um you
know a tree of three
leaves or three branches. Now if you
have one two then nested list AB then
you you have this tree. So whenever you
have a nested list or even any nested
expression you can view it as a tree and
once you view it as a tree you have the
concept of depth. So for example these
items one two and list they are at depth
one and this a and b they are at depth
uh two. So this the root you consider it
level zero.
So
then below it is level one. Then below
it below it is level three. And if any
item if any node they do not have any
children then you you think of them as
leaves. So this one two and a leaves.
Okay. So you have the concept of depth.
Now when you count so and and you give a
number uh to each depth in UF language
that's called level okay that's called
level
so so this concept is
very powerful because in any function
that applies to that takes an argument
of a list you can specify the level so
that function will only apply to those
nodes you know so so that's the general
idea That is why we have this level
concept in wuam language. Okay. So, so
uh for example, let me let me just run
this in wam language so you can you can
kind of see uh interactive
paste it here. Run it. So you see
so not and and in this case the list is
a is a basically a sometimes they call
jacked array. It's a nested list but in
each level they don't have the same
number of elements. If in each level
they have the same number of elements
then we call it rectangular array like
we we were doing before like the you
know dimensions and
you know but and matrix n dimensional
matrix where at each level order you
have the same number of nodes but in
this case you have a nested
list
however in each level they don't have
the same number of items so sometimes
they call jacked array in C or or Java.
So in wan language you know so here is
wo language you can see this tree
representation okay and that makes it
clear. So these things are level one
these things are level two and these
things are level three. Um okay so so
but what is it I want to do? Um
oh yeah I so here I want to so I want to
change the name. Okay. So, let's see.
Uh
they will spec
uh I think
I think by the wolf language official
documentation
do they call level spec or do they call
it level specification? Yeah, level
spec. You can see. Yeah, they just call
it level spec.
So, I'm wondering if I should call it
level specification
because
spec is really short for specification.
Nah, let's just follow their way. Okay.
So, but add uh Yeah. So add um
spec
uh
depth
uh should I say that?
So level spec level level spec is a
standard form in Wam language to specify
a specific level of an expression or a
range of levels m to n. Okay. Yeah, that
okay I'll leave that. So does that make
sense?
So
so if we run an example it'll be much
clearer. So let's do that. So but here I
want to uh yeah change wording. Okay. Uh
example. So
map with
map a function to a level. Okay.
Something like that. That's more clear.
Okay. So,
uh
does that make sense? Okay, hold on.
Map. Okay, so
uh
delete that.
Okay, I think I'll just leave it there.
So,
okay. So, but let me let me run this so
that you guys can see what's going on.
So for example um
yeah so um how do I so what should I do?
So
um
well in order to explain this
uh wait
you need to be wam language. So
wam language
confusion tree form. Okay. Tree form at.
Okay. When you see this in tree form,
it'll be much clearer.
Okay. So,
so we got a list like that. A then B
then C D. Okay. Like that. So, if you
map to level one, you it will map to A
and this list. Okay. So for example
uh so yeah so now you need to map okay
so let's
let's show this example okay
so this means map F to level one and if
you show this in tree form
slash slash
tree form slash slash is a postfix
notation. Okay, wait I didn't type it.
Run it. So you can see f f there that's
our function is applied to a and list
because they are at level one. You see
level one a and this list. So you see
f F apply to A and list then the rest
and the output looks like looks like
that.
Okay, you see F and F. Okay, so that's
idea. So I'm not going to run the rest
of it. Okay, but um but maybe I should
copy this and paste it here so it's
clear. So anyway, next
uh now pattern matching
the relation of pattern matching and
level spec. This is another very
interesting one. Okay, so let me let's
go through that.
So close that. And maybe that's about
it. How many more pages?
A few more pages. Okay. Yeah. Okay.
Uh level spec. And now I want to do
pattern matching
label spec is critical in matching
nested pattern. Yes. So here that's the
page I want to do. Okay. Close it. Uh
paste that. Go uh paste list by go to
the link and uh update the page pattern
matching and level spec. Okay. First of
all, let me let me let me just fix a few
things.
So, change the wording depth level of a
tree. uh specify depth level of
expression
for pattern matching. Okay. So what I
want to say is specify
specify depth level of expression. Okay.
Depth level of expression
for
pattern matching. Okay. So that's that's
more verbose and that's more clear
exactly what we are doing. So uh so
delete that.
Okay. So that's that.
Delete that. And uh let me change this.
So and then I'll explain it. Okay.
X
Y
Okay. So then we need
Y match 4. Okay. Copy paste. Paste. And
uh here
uh Y match
two. And uh here
and
here is Yeah. Uh
wait.
So it can match any of Yeah. Uh so here
x match one,
y matches.
Um
okay. So what what what's going on is
that when you do pattern matching you
you can specify what level to match
because if you have a pattern such as
this one
you know uh braces and x y what that
means the underscore means any
expression
and once it match you give it a name x
okay so that's what it means that you
know so basically this matches a list of
any two items. Okay. Now, however, now
if your expression is this, this will
match in several ways because the x can
match the first item one and the y can
match the second you know nested list.
Okay, but it can also you know go match
this part. If you match this part, X is
two, Y is the 3, four. And it can also
match just the innermost list, you know,
X is three, Y is four. Okay, so there's
this um so depending on what level or
what depth you want to match first, it
can match in several ways. So therefore,
Wam language provide a way in in many uh
pattern matching functions. It allows
you to say allow you to specify a level
spec just like the map we did before. So
that's what this page is about. So this
is about the importance of understanding
the level spec. Okay.
So uh so did I get this right? Uh it can
match any of
uh that X match three Y match four or
that X match two Y match three four
right or that. Yeah.
Okay. So so that's uh that's what I want
to do there. Okay. Delete that.
G that. Okay. Now here is example. Uh
let me demonstrate that example. Any
anyone else watching? Any comments?
So let me demonstrate some examples.
There are a few things I want to fix
here.
Uh
so
yeah so
okay replace or say that
important aspect of pattern matching is
at what depth. Okay, let's remove the
name tree because tree might be
confusing with a uh graph tree data
structure.
So let's just remove tree depth.
Uh
oh. And uh this specify
this means
let's remove that.
Delete that. Okay. So this is so this is
the last thing we're going to do and
that's it for today. So this is the last
thing I want to do. So, so we going to
do
move that to bottom
and show tree form. That's it.
Okay. So, let let me just prepare first
then I'm going to show you.
Okay. So,
let's
Okay. Then then then
let's do that.
Okay. And we also want to show tree
forms. So
So what we going to do? Um
so if we can run it for example, here is
a example. You got this nested
expression with kind of tails and you
give the pattern X and Y blank that
means match anything. Once it match it
matched you name it X. The match part is
XD the and the other part is named Y
arbitrary name you can say anything.
Okay. So then you replace once you match
it you replace by this symbolic
expression gxy. Okay. And and the last
argument here is the level spec. So this
uh bracket one means at level one. So,
so that means at level one you just got
you know you you got this uh you got
this thing
one and this list is level one nodes. So
so so this this pattern we will never
actually see
it will never directly match that 3.4.
So that's why so so the result is going
to be like that. You see the wait level
one.
Uh oh yeah. So level one.
Yeah. So level one is actually So level
one this this number one is on level
one. Does it does it match this pair?
No. So that's why that doesn't change.
Okay.
And let's magnify. Okay. Now
this expression is also on level one.
Does it match the XY? Yes, you got two
and uh then the three four thing.
Therefore
that becomes that. Okay. But but I want
to show example match level zero. Okay.
So match level zero.
Okay. So run it. In that case you'll
just get you see G one and that. Okay.
So that makes sense.
Match level is you know level level zero
is basically the entire thing. Okay. So
So does that make sense? Any comments?
Good so far. Fantastic.
Do you take those notes using some sort
of tablet? Yes.
Uh we we basically we are done. Okay. So
you know so this is not still not
satisfactory. Okay. But basically let
let me let me answer the question in a
bit. Okay. So basically this page what I
want to do is basically done and I mean
not done you know I wanted to generate
the tree you know I want to generate
this graph for each each example of the
level so that people can easily
understand but but for this video maybe
that's it for today. Okay. So let's see.
Uh uh yeah. So the tablet, you know, the
one I use. So you go, you search for
keyboard blog and search keyboard and
search for Surface
Microsoft Surface Pro. That's what I
have. Okay. So actually I I did a review
kind of showed it three years ago or
four years ago. Like four years ago. So
I got this
by now it's like 80 years old but it so
happens it's still useful. So I'm is you
know it's it's quite good. So Microsoft
Surface Pro 4 this is for from 2018
uh before actually 201 uh 15. So by now
it's 10 years old but it's still I still
use it every day. So I just take it walk
around and uh and write notes. So that's
what I that's that's the notes you are
seeing. Okay. And then let's see. Sorry,
I don't understand anything about Wolf
Ram. It's quite late here. I like to see
you talk someday about what you think of
creating blogs with Hugo and Emac or
mod. That's a funny question because a
lot of people try to tell me to use
that. And basically my opinion will be
disappointing to you because my opinion
is I don't use those Hugo or mod because
I code HTML raw. Actually I talked about
this many times. So if you look at my
older videos you'll see a lot.
Basically by now I have like 300 V uh
was it 300 or 400? Uh wait 700
uh today's talk show. Okay. So level
spec close show today's talk show
episode 713 so I have 700 videos and
each every one of them is you are
watching me doing raw HTML
why do I code raw HTML for example I can
delete the entire thing or delete the
entire header just one keystroke
smart delete you know undo or you know
so lot so I demonstrated lots of You
just look at my videos. Search for Emacs
HTML. Search for my name YouTube. Okay.
Uh so why do I do it raw? Because I was,
you know, I I watched the birth of HTML
in 1992.
Basically 1992 is when I began to use
it. That's basically when HTML began.
And I watched the birth of CSS. I
watched the birth of JavaScript,
you know, so CSS. So in the beginning I
I write my HTML character by character
like
you know like like press uh actually oh
wow today is so advanced you can't even
type you can't even um what you can't
even type a single um
let's see so new buffer
switch to text text mode Now you can
type. So you type HTML, close it. Then
you basically type the again, then close
it. Then you press uh you know like that
character by character in uh starting in
1995.
That's how I began. And in the beginning
I typed them in Microsoft Word using
Microsoft Word macros because back then
I read the entirety of Microsoft Word
manual and it's actually one of the best
software Microsoft Word in the 1990s.
Okay. And lots of features. So I read
the entire manual. Um so that's how I
you know began HTML. So and now by now
it's 30 years coding HTML you know I
don't you know I don't type them
character by character of course uh for
example I can just uh you know some
something you know press a key it
becomes that or just delete it or you
can move the cursor here delete that or
you can select select more select more
select more select the more and select
the entire main you see go to the bottom
them you see so and I'm using
HTML mode which what I wrote in the past
10 years so describe key press
see the documentation
HTML mode and you got this uh like 50 50
commands
so go to the source code
uh source code there's actually several
files files. So HTML. So let's highlight
all files with HTML. So there's about
seven files. Okay. Something like 10,000
lines of code.
So by now I'm you know I use you know my
own HTML mode. But basically still
everything I do is manual.
Okay. So and for those people using oak
mod I in fact I am more efficient even
when I code raw HTML because you can
count keystrokes. You count the
keystrokes right you you know when you
want a list when you want a footer or
whatever when you want the H1 uh header
or you know you can compare doing that
in oak mode the number of keystroke you
type to create the same thing. I would
say my way is actually more efficient,
less keystrokes
and then I don't have to generate it you
know like when you generate from oak mod
usually there's lots of bloat and I have
more control and I you know I also
manually code uh my CSS there's no
framework no nothing okay well because I
I watched the birth of them you know and
I'm a nerd
So, but for you, you can do the way I
do. You could, but the price you have to
pay is that you need to be really, you
need to be a nerd. You need to be
obsessive in studying um HTML and in
studying uh CSS. Okay, so let me just
show you quickly. So, um for example and
and also JavaScript. Okay. So, go to the
tutorial programming tutorial. So, you
need to be you need to learn
you need to master HTML. Okay. Master
like you can start with my tutorial and
you need to master CSS. Okay. So, you
know exactly what they are. No framework
like you like today's people they use
frameworks. They have no idea what's
going on. they just read the framework
doc framework documentation and you know
you know that's not necessarily a bad
thing but if you know this stuff raw
that that gives you the power that
actually makes you a real software
engineer because
those framework writers may be CSS or
may be HTML framework writers or may be
JavaScript framework such as React hack,
React, VU, you know, they need to know
like what I know they they need to know
the like the real fundamentals,
then they can write those frameworks. So
for you you know if you are young you
you could start with frameworks but if
eventually if you learn the raw
technology that gives you a lot of power
because then you don't need then you you
know either you can continue to use
those frameworks very useful especially
if you work in a corporation it's almost
necessary but but but but then you do
understand what's going on beneath so
that gives you a
um power that makes your craft much
better. Okay. So, so why do I not use
Hugo or Emacs Oak mod? Because I don't
need to, you know, in fact Hugo, you
know, I would tell the creator of a Hugo
to use my system. You know, it's more
efficient than Hugo.
Okay, I think that's it. Uh I I was able
to uh execute the last example in Emacs
with Kasaw Wufi mode. Thank you so much.
Fantastic. Thank you.
Uh Kasaw watched the birth of the Linux
That's true too. Linux was
born in the 1990s. You know uh it became
kind of public around 1996
something, you know. I mean even 1996
like only nerds know okay actually uh
you know it's up until 1999
with Apache they started to have some uh
public public awareness Linux okay so
anyway that's it thank you guys if you
like my stuff donate to me okay you know
just go to you know check out my
tutorial JavaScript tutorial You can buy
the whole thing on a, you know, on a f,
you know, on a zip file. I send it to
you $35 a token of donation. I don't
make money, you know. Nobody buys it.
But you, if you want it, I give you the
entire JavaScript tutorial in a zip
file. So you can read it on your
computer.
And similarly for uh my Emac list this
and Emacs tutorial and uh then I got
other lots of other tutorials you can
check out and so go to the homepage
kasali.info info
code no s in https.
Okay, then go down then you can patreon
me, Amazon gift card and PayPal me.
Okay, thank you guys. Bye.
So, we shut down in one minute. So,
yeah, I'm you know I'm just going to do
this offline. That's basically uh today.
See it.
I like simpler websites without all
those modern features, but I don't have
much time to learn HTML and CSS.
Uh, well, what do you mean? Because
looks like you are a young guy. So, if
you are a young guy, you have plenty of
time unless unless you already work for
a corporation.
Uh, I mean, but you do, you know. Okay.
So the the the bottom line is it's up to
you okay is you know it's not really
necessary for everyone to know the
details of HTML actually you need
because if you are you a web developer
are you a professional web developer
okay if you are and if you plan to be
professional web de developer for the
next let's say five years
then it is absolutely necessary to know
the full detail of all everything about
HTML and CSS. Okay, like today's Zuma
generation, I don't understand. They
they have the idea. They don't even like
they don't want to or don't have time to
learn the fundamentals of CSS. What are
you talking about? So if you plan to be
the web a web developer a good one a
professional one of course you make
money and and but you want to be a good
one
for the next five years you have to okay
know all the grey details of CSS and
HTML okay it's not optional
but however if you if you are just you
know if you are in it for the money you
know you work for a corporation so you
are a professional webdev But you don't
actually care, you know, you don't
actually care about, you know, the like
the technical details, the framework
changes every month. You don't really
care, okay? But you can make money, you
know, like those corporations, you know,
in that case, you don't really need to
know, okay? Or your heart is somewhere
else. You are into machine learning. You
are into mathematics. You are into like
to become a engineer and chemistry,
organic chemistry or inorganic or
material science or whatever.
Your heart is not doing web dev. In that
case, yeah, you don't have to spend too
much, you know, you you don't have to
framework works. It works. Okay.
So here's I need a job first. Haha. I'm
not professional, just a hobbyist. I'm
more interested in cyber security. Okay.
Well, in that case, you you you need to
know this to get a job, you know,
because the when you when you look for a
job,
you know, if you know they they care
less about, you know, you you need to
know frameworks. But when you but the
the the people who know frameworks they
are a dime a dozen okay they are cheap
like they they are like they they are u
they are not quality a dime doesn't
everyone knows frameworks you but if if
you ask them how does it work exactly
how does
uh let's say react actually work can you
write it can you can you can you try re
recreate react the fundamentals or do
you even know the basic concept how how
what what is it doing exactly
if you during your interview if you like
tell the guy
oh yeah I don't know react but I can
tell you how to write it in 10 minutes
let me demo okay they hire you they hire
you right away okay
bye Hey.