good morning welcome to another episode
of Zatoichi oh let's go - it's good
let's pop this chat out and while we
wait for people to come in and today's
topic is you know I haven't decided yet
we just thought yeah maybe we talk about
compilers because yesterday we were
going to talk about compilers an
introduction to how compiler works okay
I'm not giving you an introduction to
how to write a compiler but you know
just give you an intro to how compiler
works like what are the components in
stuff and you know just go to Microsoft
hawkship a show page and you know type
in the comment what topic you like - you
like me to talk about so let me put
today's date today date is that and that
is good good morning so by the way I
want to mention this if you go to Kesari
javascript javascript in depth now you
can see on the left side I have created
the navigation panel now let me show you
okay this is my local web page let's go
to Google here and good morning guys so
let's open the page sorry javascript in
depth now you can see I have added this
navigational panel on the left true
JavaScript true and fourth force true
and false JavaScript operators
JavaScript branch control you can see
these are navigation panels basics
variable function object property you
know so I added this navigational panel
so the top part our JavaScript the
language okay II Turbo
and miscellaneous and more more stuff
then you have JavaScript reference good
morning jack greetings a Brina Brina
Brina Brina where are you from what
country now Jack is in China
jack is in what city is that song Ching
so anyway the JavaScript in depth on the
left you have the object reference then
you have dumb dumb stuff like you know
so I just added that today so if you
haven't done already check out
javascript in depth ok that's that's one
of my best best tutorials so M is cincin
you are not in Stinson now you you or
not
well anyway Jack says so what topic to
talk about today I'm wondering if break
the loop is here break the loop if if
break the loop comes here then we're
gonna talk about introduction to
compilers okay go over here and pick a
topic let's talk about that
and so okay so a Brina Brina says from
Oslo Norway Wow
and originally from from the Gambia West
Africa amazing I have amazing followers
so are you are like are you a programmer
I mean are you okay you are a Emacs user
for sure right and are you a programmer
okay so what topics to talk about
okay guys give me a topic because if you
know otherwise I'm kind of I'm just
going to go random and random could mean
none technical you know like okay this
is yesterday so I I might be talking
about you know schizoid personality
personality disorders and autism
you know autistic you know these days
it's like a popular fashionable it's
almost like fashionable to be a autistic
person like attention deficit syndrome
Emacs Marco so what do you know what do
you want to know about you Emacs Mac
well Jack because I thought I
demonstrated that a few times
let's go to Emacs okay so UNIX and you
have read all my Emacs tutorials right
Jack I mean you told me so
so if you go to my UNIX tutorial you can
see practical Emacs that section then
there is a section of Emacs mock well
let's see go down go down right Y space
fun topic Unicode topic copy/paste topic
find/replace topic with marco okay
copy/paste topic unicode topic fun topic
whitespace topic rectangular edit topic
long rap topic shell
Oh Emacs efficiency topic then you can
see keyboard Marco yes kiba Marco
completion a brief mod use ideas so
that's in keyboard marco and on this
page near the bottom I mean on this page
I give you a tutorial it's like a
comprehensive tutorial about Emacs macro
then at the bottom you'll see five more
pages that are actual examples of Marco
so Jack do you have any specific
question about Emacs Marco's you want to
know or you want to see your demo and
good morning whet web dog good morning
crowd ohh test yeah we are autistic
persons okay which topic guys which
topic pick a topic because you know if
you don't give me a topic I'll just talk
at random then because for example I
have this website JavaScript in depth
right and today I just added the side
panel you know the side panel is kind of
convenient however actually I had that
before but then I decided to remove it
you know instead of you know that then
guys I you know the side panel looks
like that these topics but then now I
added back you know why because because
the web browser technology HTML is
pretty bad they they removed the frame
HTT HTML frames they remove the frames
feature what is the frames feature frame
set feature frame set allows you to here
let me show you example you see this is
a frame set
now French that is very convenient so
you can have a bunch of panels on the
left or near the bottom you can adjust
their size however you want and the
frameset feature is in HTTP 4 okay
I mean HTML 4 but in HTML 5 they removed
it it's very bad
so anyway come on in Duncan so actually
a few days ago I talked about FEM said
you know when I am doing a video like
when you are doing anyone ok
oftentimes the topics we Pete and that's
kind of necessarily so because you
notice that well because for me for
example I give a talk every day but not
everyone is here every day you know some
people come in and they you know they
have a question they want to ask so
usually you just answer and I notice
this is true for lecturers or senior
singers you know performance for example
pop pop singers you know Madonna
for example Prince you know it's not
necessarily Prince but for many of the
singers you know they some of them you
know you get old you know four so for
twenty years or thirty years you go
around the world you know doing concert
you know and people always want to hear
the same song you know they want to this
song because they have not been to your
concert and they really like this song
because you have a few songs that's
popular so effectively you sing the same
song you know every year you know one
hundred ten thousand times you know
literally for thirty years you really
get tired and usually what happens is
that when you go to a concert
usually when when a singer seen some
song you know popular song you know but
they change the tune like it's supposed
to go this way but they do variations
they do variations because they really
get tired of it you know seeing it tenth
out you know thousands of times
so they do variations but when you hear
the very thing you don't like it because
it's not the way you used to you know so
that's an issue for the singers you know
this repetition issue and it's the same
thing happens in in movie stars or in
lecturers for example Jordan Peterson
okay
Oh Camille Paglia now these famous
people you you can watch their YouTube's
right Hey hey David Capello we are you
the first time first time here great to
see you
David Capello is my partner in in
building a go Emacs project while ago
five years ago so he we worked together
he he basically build architecture for a
guru max so that was great
Ocoee max is a MX distribution and that
is why today you see my website is you
know sorry
Emacs that's a go Emacs name so that was
my previous project David cope hello are
you going to do a video streaming ever
are you gonna why don't you join me in a
Google hangout or something
and so David Capello you know I always
you know I is one of the nerd okay we
are all nuts okay and I always wanted
when talking to nuts I always wanted to
tell nerds
you know it's get on video because video
communication you have facial expression
it's really it's like literally ten
times more efficient than text but but
many great people okay I admire okay
such as David Clara okay and many others
over the years I've noticed I tell them
to they don't want to like no I don't
want I just want to text yeah so David
so maybe we can do a google hangout okay
you know one of these days you know
maybe next week so you know
yeah and possibly if you like you know
it would be great I would be honored if
you know if you can go on to my talk
show and you talk about something talk
about us right I'm pretty sure people
would like to hear about that
a sprite sprite is a project
David created that's for creating for
pixel art let's let's try to go to it so
yeah so this is this is a sprite which
which is basically a software
application that I guess mostly for game
creators game designers developers to
create pixel icons or animations now
correct me if I mischaracterized it okay
David so anyway yeah so so looks like
it's the business tree is doing good
right okay let's see Duncan
greetings greetings watching on phone
while making curry curry is wonderful so
so so let's go back to the topic what I
was talking about the yeah I was talking
about frames frames are really a 10
because well they cured it they they
killed the depth they they kind of
deprecated it okay david says well we
will see if we do something in the
future these days are really busy but
you always been really busy and another
thing I want to mention is that David is
an artist he has strong the
let me show you this this one this ago
Emacs mask mascot or logo I really like
it so okay so yeah frame HTML frames you
know but the HTML frames it's not going
away because Java doc because Java is
still using it you can see you know Java
Java doc you know frame is truly great
useful because you can just click on any
part and you know and you can adjust the
panel size so it's great but you know
for reasons google and the web dev
people killed it they complained that
you know it's hard for such engine to
find in stuff so so without a frame you
know if you want to use frame i have a
tutorial here you know it's called frame
set HTML frame said so but without frame
set what you do is let's get out frame
by the way frame set can be nested so
you can see here it's a heavily nested
example oh i think i think actually the
browser is preventing it to nest wait
let me try another page
okay here's another example of frameset
let's see free me free me yeah Google I
think the browser these days states they
prevent you to have too much deep nested
frames okay let's try again yeah they
they prevent yes okay so um as my
roommate roommate hey David
ko have you used rest client that year
by patchy I personally prefer it to
postman actually I don't know neither of
them what are they I don't know what's a
postman HTTP rest crying tool for Emacs
so this is a tool to manually explore
that test HTTP West Web Services runs
queries for my fan text query sheet this
very result why would you want this tool
in Emacs
Katie Bulman controversy I have no idea
what is that okay let's see
Katie Pullman Katie boom and controversy
so it's magnify magnify oh the woman
behind the first black hole image that's
I guess I suppose that's the you know
today's political feminism stuff the
women the woman who transformed our view
my ass it's all [ __ ]
so okay so let's see Catherine Lewis
woman is an how how old is she 19 19
1989 so she's 30 years old is an
American computer scientist in the field
in the field of imaging and incoming
assistant professor of computing and
mathematical sciences at California
Institute of Technology she has worked
on imaging from radio interference II
and was a member of even horizon
telescope team that captured the first
image of black hole actually I don't
know much any I mean I heard the news
that they took the photo of black hole
but to me yeah this did you see this
this media this leftist media is the
[ __ ] license comes it's like all of
a sudden Oh women women scientists all
this celebrate glorify women scientists
okay and soon Google is going to pay me
because I said my opinions but anyway
about the black hole
so yes I saw the pictures I'm not
impressed I mean what okay first of all
I don't know much about physics physics
is not my thing I don't you know it's
not my thing I'm into math
then black hole is very interesting
right black hole is one of the greatest
wonders you know of the physics you know
let's say you know because because what
happens inside black hole you could
imagine you know you know you could
imagine anything in MAGIX you know magic
happens inside back once you go in you
become whatever you know any anything
goes we don't understand it nobody
understand it but then oops I clicked by
mistake
but then ok so black hole is fascinating
and they are saying I haven't really
read the newest what's a big deal so
they are saying they took a photo of it
well normally you cannot you know black
hole sucks or light so how do you take a
photo I just about you know suppose
that's a photo of black hole and suppose
you know I suppose the middle is black
or the the others is you know horizon
ring or whatever you know I'm not very
impressed by by this photo I mean it's I
don't understand I don't really
understand it so but I don't you know
I'm not excited I mean as opposed to
like a new theory about black hole that
I would be you know I have some interest
to look into but a picture of a black
hole it doesn't seems to you know too
interesting
so oh god the black hole drama so what
he what he is a drama I suppose you know
she I suppose yeah I don't even know I
suppose a women a woman okay she a
scientist okay Caitie woman scientist
who suggested and pushed it I guess and
you know and somehow it became a drama
so david says it looks like some users
from hater from hacker news such their
github profile to check if she did the
work or if it was other user that did
walk okay so now there's actually a
question whether she actually did the
work so but but what what what is the
work involved i mean what i mean why is
this a big deal i mean yeah i don't know
the subject so let me read let's see
so katie woman led development of a
computer program that made the
breakthrough image possible okay now
first of all I'm not sure it's really a
breakthrough you know it's it's not a
black hole theory it's just the photo
the remarkable photo showing a halo of a
of dust and gas 500 million trillion
kilometres from Earth was released okay
so for dr. Bowman its creation was the
realization of an endeavor previously
thought impossible okay I'm not sure I
trust that you know these are you know
media media you know the the news fake
news websites so he says excited excited
to be bracing herself for the
groundbreaking moment that's another and
trustworthy sentence dr. Bowman was
pictured loading the image on her laptop
okay whatever
quint good morning green deck yeah I
don't know much about this you know ie
but although these you know because of
the politics on a second no this is my
tree my eyes my Isis got it because you
know because today's social justice
public you know the kind of mess so we
have all these issues women you know we
women stuff in trans stuff you know it's
every day every day there's a drama
every day there's some you know things
yeah I don't even know what someone is
going on so this is does anyone so David
do you know what's a big deal about
taking a picture of black hole I mean
what what I mean first of all so why are
you taking a me okay yeah how is it I
mean so did you do you know the
background like where do you take
pictures back of black hole and why and
how is it how is it taken why is it why
is it thought impossible or something
like that
so let's close that
yeah I don't know I don't know what's
going yeah I don't think I mean even if
she did I mean I don't think it's no
it's not a big deal it's not you know
it's not something really significant so
if people are claiming that you know she
didn't do the work or you know it's it's
not significant in the first face image
you know image computer scientists you
know whatever so so if it comes down to
programmers you know being a programmer
you know doesn't matter guy or female
okay if the black hole picture comes
down to because of some programmers you
know created something and then that's
garbage
okay don't even pay attention to [ __ ]
you stupid useless programmers I despise
programmers you know what the
programmers are programmers are that do
you know like craftsmen you know like
you know like labor workers sort of you
know you just push brick bit pushes you
know whether the jargon among hackers is
bit pushes you just push bit you you
know nothing you understand nothing you
understand no computer science you
understand no math no nothing you just
spit push bits and in the Crammer
about about patterns you know about
design patterns about unit testing and
and babbling about agile that that's
what programmers are but you make money
you know programmers what Nobel Prize so
Jesus
so david says to take a picture of a
black hole it said that the telescope
should be the size of the earth okay so
multiple color scope were used and
combined with an algorithm developed by
her and her team okay yeah about that
eMac stuff I have no idea what that is
postman so anyway I kind of just ramble
ramble today we don't have a topic is
break the loop here so I mean if he's
here then I'm gonna give a introduction
to compilers but since he's not maybe
we'll do that another day so this West
crying DL for Emacs this is a tool to
manually explore the test HTTP West Web
Services yeah I don't get it why do you
want to manually do this I mean well
yeah I don't know what you see I hate
this web site using small images okay so
anyway runs queries from a plain text
query sheet display results are pretty
printed XML JSON any and even images you
know it looks to me this kind of thing
you just do it with a script then you
call the script in Emacs you know just
run it you know it when the scripting
Emacs
then the output then the Emacs will grab
the output and codify it or whatever I
don't see why you need why do you be on
this thing in emag Lisp because Emacs
Lisp is usually pretty bad you know you
don't have libraries and tools to do
HTTP HTTP stuff but anyway I don't know
about this topic so so that's a sprite
Emacs logo frames javascript in depth
oh good good night jack hey Jack hey did
you wait a minute jack aren't we
supposed to meet up at 11 o'clock I mean
I mean after you know between us privacy
anyway you know if you have to go I'll
talk to you later
you know send me a tweet or something so
let's go back to Emacs and go back to so
actually we need a topic we got we gotta
have talked about something um I'm
thinking of some topics to cover so you
guys you know go to the we got oh wow we
got 14 people watching so just go to the
URL here and you'll see a bunch of topic
and we can talk about it because
otherwise I'm well you know do I have a
favorite artist
you mean a visual like drawing artist or
or performer like
my favorite artist I can say you know I
have a collection of artworks you know
these are dead oh yeah okay
favorite artist this guy yeah this guy
albert durer probably this guy for okay
for for dead ones for you know he's 14
71 to 15 28 he is
so this his his his drawings is he's one
of the founder of one of the first
pioneers in in using projection
techniques of project projection to draw
to create realism like you know this is
like realistic join here's another
example and you can clearly see it shows
the technique for projection and yeah
let's talk about for projective geometry
and linear algebra let me talk about
that and this this is his self-portrait
by the way he has okay yeah let's talk
about that that and what is that good
stuff door okay that's another ode no
yeah let's talk about heart a little bit
so anyway this guy so of course you know
I have several yeah I guess I suppose I
have several favorite artists you know
visual artists but he would be one of
them Albert duro I'm not sure how do you
pronounce this name but this guy and
also his work usually is tied to
associated with math for example here
you can see that's a magic square that's
so called a magic square
you know square such that all the rows
and columns adds up to the same number
and that's a big math topic magic
squares you can read you know Wikipedia
for hours about let's look for it it's
search for match it mad chick okay I got
used to the match it got confused the
Emacs match it okay there it is so magic
magic squares okay it's one of the
fascinating things about math now match
it's magic squares is part of number
theory ragged tongue let's see okay so
so here is the magic squares now you can
you know try if now if you want to if
you're a programmer and you don't know
much math this is a good topic to go
into okay this is part of number theory
which is the number theories of
foundation of cryptography okay hey so
that you may be might be interested so
magic square is you know part of number
theory and it it's it's so cold it's
so-called recreational math because it
does not require math machinery I mean
it does not require you to have you know
several years of math training to be
able to understand or appreciate what
what Magic Square is and you know so you
can study it on your own and it's
fascinating so they show history you
know and there is also extensions and
generalizations okay here's a history
history history some famous met magic
squares okay and
properties of magic squares okay you
know yeah go read it
classification of magic squares okay and
some of these actually are very deep you
know they are and and I'm pretty sure
you're see if you read a Wikipedia
article you'll see some of the problems
are not solved yet so you can actually
you can just start to work on it
seriously and you you know if you really
work hard you might after a few years
you will be remembered as the sava of
certain magic squares problems in
history UV eternal yeah so some of these
problems on Assad that I think so anyway
that's magic squares so back to the guy
so he saw this Albert how do you
pronounce his name let's see how to
pronounce his name and cause that
yes yes
you have a tongue what are you guys
talking about Danielle because he's a
huge he's a huge used youth based
cultural phenomenon who so anyway this
guy duro the duro is that Albert okay
Albert to do something like that so this
guy do anyway so this guy he's walk
usually has certain math flavors and
he's one of the first to create using
the techniques of projection to create
realistic artwork because big as as in
contrast to because before his time much
of the artwork is flat for example well
I have to find an example similar to
this
anyway anyway that's not games bad but
anyway let's look at some of his work so
okay this guy Gustav dough is another
artist so he has draw drawn this little
red riding-hood
now by the way if you have not read The
Little Red Riding Hood you should read
it here okay you know here's a UI our
goal read read this it's very short you
know it just take you a few minutes it's
kind of fun and okay after you read this
there is another version there is a
politically correct version which is
very funny okay then you should read
this one this also just a few minutes
okay oh my god Google Ads like it like
this they spam my website Jesus wait
what
okay I have to do something about this
you know Google is becoming extremely
evil eye.i what Jesus I gotta do
something about that
so anyway little writing Little Red
Riding Hood so this is by this artist
Gustav door and back to Albert duro
so here is another drawing by him now
this in destroying it illustrates the
technique of perspective drawing code
code perspective join and this article
is actually interesting this article
describes the difference between
perspective drawing wait not this
article actually I was talking about
another article but anyway this article
is talking about what is perspective we
draw perspective
join now when you study if you you know
take a class enjoying your hear this
phrase often perspect like one-point
perspective two-point perspective their
terminology is actually misleading
misleading okay so I looked into this
issue you know one day 2006 and so I
wrote up an article I explained what it
is okay so if you are interested you you
might check it out but anyway here here
is a drawing by this albert durer guy
that illustrates the technique and
principle i mean basically the heart the
gist of perspective drawing how
it's made you know it's basically the
principal's projection you know
projection yeah and the UH another
another term you'll hear often enjoying
you know classes is the vanishing point
now and and one point perspective to
point percent perspective this I
actually stupid misleading terms you
know by the drawing you know people but
mathematically there's just one thing
it's called linear projection you know
linear projection which lead us to so in
this call
oh my god what happened to Google Ads
[ __ ] why do they like one two three four
five like over let's let's to get the
here's my source code for that page
Google Ads I don't know why the how
comes this sudden II have so many I only
have one here you know I only have well
one two
three yeah three ads is maximum but here
we see one two three four five you know
it's Google is doing this kind of things
you know who is becoming evil and evil
it seem just incredible
but anyway so this page discuss you know
what is technical drawing what is
descriptive geometry and and what is
projective geometry and how they differ
from linear algebra you know I have been
fascinated by these subjects since 1990s
you know in the 1990s you have a class
called technique of drawing or drafting
that that profession kind of went away
because you know computer CAD you know
computer-aided design you know using
computers but you know back in 1991 I
remember there is still class and I was
actually thinking about you know whether
I should major in that called drafting
and what the here's are drawing you know
what do you do you know and you have the
drafters table so it's read the comments
I kind of lost you know like when I'm
talking about some subjects usually like
when you want to talk about 15 watching
when you talk about some subject like
when you when you're when you're talking
to your friends and your friends mention
the subject then it's you know you have
you have the thing going about that
topic but otherwise sometimes you know
like if all of a sudden I ask you to
talk about some topic you may not have
you know much to say about it but on a
different occasion you have a lot to say
about it be
you know the the the context and mood
changes so so right now if I'm just
going to talk about this page actually I
can talk about that kind of let's see
okay no comment so so what's up what's
up guys okay so link actually let me
talk about this topic because it's
interesting so what is what is technical
drawing what is descriptive geometry
what is projective geometry and what is
meaning algebra so I was very interested
in all these topics you know so back
then you have technical drawing or
called draft draft in your draft draft
us you know you you draw technical
pictures what are they they are like CAD
you know all these are examples you know
these she is a drafter modern draft I'd
walk okay this these days they they are
not much drafters because it's all
computerized you don't see this kind of
you know using pinyin to as much anymore
so these are examples of you know
technical drawing you know the
architecture blueprint you know in CAD
you know much machinery machinery you
have to draw this but today mostly it's
replaced by computers like like both of
these examples are drawn by computers
this this is from sketch you know it was
owned by Google you know it was created
by some company sketch 3d then Google
bought it then Google so did so many
hits it's did sketches owned by some
other company and this one is from
AutoCAD so so I was interested in
subject in these topics and there is
another topic so technical joining and
there is also descriptive geometry you
know because when I was studying
geometry so one of the thing one of the
term is
scripted geometry that's actually a
field you know it's kind of but it's
actually not math actually I'll explain
so you have descriptive geometry another
term is projective geometry okay then of
course I I learned linear algebra you
know linear algebra is you must most of
you know you know it's heavily used in
3d graphics because you need linear
algebra linear algebra is a fundamental
math the core math to create this kind
of you know 3d joins software you need
you know linear algebra so I was you
know the question to me so how are they
connected you know so you know which is
which
where are they connected huh how do they
relate ok so first of all you have
technical joining you know so before we
have computers you have technical
drawing which is you know this kind of
joint is this or you know these
blueprints you know blueprints of
machines and and this is another example
so that's before computers era that's
called technical drawing ok
then you have a subject called
descriptive geometry now you know you
can search this word on a web you'll
find you know image you can image search
you'll find books and textbooks let me
tell you what that is now this
descriptive geometry is that is
basically the technique for technical
drawing ok this is all before computer
era so for example this is a page from a
textbook on descriptive geometry
basically for example if you want to
draw this okay for example if you want
to draw a house you know in 3d like a
blueprint of a simple house let's say
your own house you know you you want to
build your house you know you want to
draw it but there you know before the
computing
you don't have software and you know and
you don't have computers but you want to
draw these how do you draw it that is
the question and the answer is called
descriptive geometry okay that's the
answer so descriptive geometry is a
bunch of techniques that is based on
geometry that tells you how to draw 3d
elements in a way that's realistic okay
my roommate my roommate brought me some
bread so so I am I like being too slow
and repetitive because I think sometimes
I am like that so if you you have to
tell me like maybe you guys see that
there's no comment coming then I know
it's like too slow like people are
falling asleep asleep or something so hi
Thomas
so Thomas Thomas whoa
ask me do I know demo scene yeah I heard
of it you know I have some when I was in
second life for four years around 1997
to 2011 they are some weird you know
there's always weird guys of all sorts
in second life so one of the real guys
telling me about demo scene demos thing
is like it's actually not my thing
yeah he's kind of seedy so they you know
if you go to youtube and you search demo
scene you will see lots of it basically
it's like programmers okay hacker type
you know hackers or programmers they
create they they they write computer
code to create create kind of a short
you know one minute or 10 second images
that it's hard to describe it's kind of
a you know there's a Wikipedia on at
demo seem so anyway they generate these
pictures and you can let's see best of
demos in 2018 okay let's try that let's
just pray a little bit you know five
seconds so
[Music]
okay so anyway let's yeah let's jump to
demo scene you know we will get back to
the descriptive geometry so demo scene
is like that I cannot play it here
because you know it's slow and stuff but
you can see this a lot on YouTube and
there's also a Wikipedia article on demo
scene but it seems like it's a very
small kind of a hacker community so they
write computer programs to create this
kind of a demo like geometric images and
usually very impressive and and also
part of the things that their code must
be very small in size for you know like
if you kilobytes or something
so it seems quite amazing yeah but I I
never find it too interesting for me you
know why because because you know first
of all I'm not too interested about this
so-called golf you know program go for
you know like very compact code where oh
where you have to know the language so
well or aspects of the language its
problems to create very small code you
know mean very minimal code you know to
more than what the code appears to be so
that's a hack that's the base that's one
of the aspect of hack I don't like hacks
I don't like anything related to hacking
kind of thing you know like I the way I
view programming the way I like I prefer
my idea is is beautiful design okay it's
like a form a computer scientist great
greatest computer scientists or greatest
mathematician they wrote the code based
on deep mathematical theorems you know
take hundred or 100 200 years to
create a theorem or takes ten years to
understand this theorem like good
theorem or or type theory you know then
if you are this mathematician oak or
great computer scientists you write the
you know 100% proof you know bullet
proof program you know great code and
it's also extremely it's the most
elegant also the most efficient possible
then that I like okay that is my ideal I
like that on the other hand many hackers
like you know this minimal code or go
for the the the you know the the the
minify what what occurred a few stock
asian kind of thing that i have like
very little intro find it interesting at
all you know it is true that those
people i mean there are competitions for
doing that you know there are some of
these great programmers you know they
really know see usually it's a language
see ok they really know see so well so
like every corner of see so they can
create this
you know like in 1k you know bytes of
code that does a lot yeah but that
doesn't interest me so what the [ __ ] you
know what not interesting that so that's
one reason I'm not really I don't see
what's the deal with the demo seeing
okay I mean it's a it's a community
right it's a subculture where people
they are very enthusiastic about that
subject so anyway the small code part I
don't find interesting but the demo I
mean they are graphics I don't really
find it interesting as well I mean it's
impressive right you know I enjoy it I
enjoy it but but again my my idea of
great computer graphics is like it's
like 3d graphics you know as you know
like for example if we can see what what
a 3d gaming graphic
is like ten hundred you know hundred
years from today that is my idea of
computer graphics where you have realism
like you know that's what I like on the
other hand that's not the core of this
demo scene kind of you know they are
creation their creation is kind of like
it's like they want to push they want to
use the minimum you know what today's
technology but they want to push it to
the maximum effect you know using with
the limits of today's you know whatever
that years technology so it's impressive
for you know for one minute so I think
yeah I'm not too much into a demo scene
type of kind of things yeah exactly I
don't like texture texture you know it's
so funny that in gaming you have texture
thing it's the the the like in computer
graphics I find you know I talked about
this last time a few days ago so in
computer graphics one of the major one
of the like almost the foundation of the
the most used and useful technique in
computer graphics like game like 3d
games you know you see is texture you
know texturing which you know that very
concept is the GUI is is one giant hack
you know you pass the images onto stuff
so so that it appears something else you
know it's have the greatest stack that's
amazing
yes good morning Pat well so yeah ray
tracing is interesting but I don't agree
ray tracing as well you know here's I
don't like every anything but anyway
yeah I can talk about why but let's let
me finish one that that descriptive
geometry topic then maybe that's it for
today let's see how long we've been
talking 13 people watching okay yeah let
me talk about finish this topic though
oh yeah
and we haven't talked about favorite
artists you know and and we have
finished talking about this Dubourg I
look at these guys and he's got long
fingers this guy yeah but he's a yeah
III so he's one of the artists I admire
very much and there are others you know
there's another one is let's go here
there is another one which is this guy I
talked about the other day as well but I
if a fascinating guy so here's some of
his drawings that that in that and
others okay and but but anyway let's go
back to the yeah technical drawing
descriptive geometry projective geometry
and linear algebra
what's the aviation so first of all you
have technique of drawing which is draft
drafters they want to before the
computer era you want to you know create
joint drawings for building for
buildings for house for machines you
know for gears you know you want to
create you want to draw it first before
you can actually make it so that's
called drafting and the technique the
technique to draw 3d you know models or
set of machines such so that they look
realistic is called descriptive geometry
okay
so together that's that that's the
discipline that's the technique it's
basically you know principles based on
geometry okay so you can draw you know
so your drawing is realistic because you
have to build it you I mean this is in
contrast to art you know it's not art
it's not like painting you can just
pinch your fantasies you have to draw
something you know for for craft you
know craftsmen to build it so that's a
descriptive geometry and typical
you know you you image such the web you
will see many pages of it look it looks
like this it tells you so for example if
you want to draw a cylinder and if you
want want to view it from certain angle
how how do you draw it you know what
should it appear things like that so
that's descriptive geometry now
projective geometry that's that's a
totally different thing
okay descriptive geometry is kind of
principles for technical draws now
projective geometry is actually a branch
of math okay a branch of abstract math
that basically that became a topic that
has nothing to do with drawing
whatsoever but it's extremely extremely
abstract okay
but however descriptive the-the-the this
now now the projective geometry is one
giant chapter in a history of math okay
it's a huge chapter you have you know
but it's it's kind of it's not
mainstream today but back in like 1500
or 1600 is it's one of the greatest
field of math projective geometry it's
kind of new and one of the big topic so
how did it arise how did projective
arise projective geometry arise because
people like like like this guy des
albert durer who wanted two ways he like
this guy who wanted to create drawings
that's realistic so in a school of art
in a philosophy of art you have realism
as one of the school okay so that kind
of begin with such project you know with
projective geometry so anyway the the
foundation that the the the beginning of
projective active geometry is from art
you know the artists when they want to
draw
they want to draw something realistic
like a photograph you know today it's so
easy for us we just take a photo and
it's you know it's really realistic why
is it realistic because actually it's
just projections you know but you know
we can use a camera to do that but back
then you know in 1500 you don't know
that because all these things we build
you know it's after generation
generation we build our knowledge we
know now today oh it's just it's just
projection and decent that but back then
people don't know so they don't know how
to draw things realistically so they
developed this you know descriptive
geometry and stuff so anyway that's a
arrangement of projective geometry
people wanted to draw you know artists
want to draw things realistic see
realistically and and they found that
it's via projection that you can do that
okay so projection is a key to make
realistic joints photo realism
okay so Alberto is one of the first yeah
you know he's 1471 to 1528 that's that's
the time when projective geometry began
okay so so but projective geometry today
or soon after it's not about drawing at
all it's let me show you what it is
project e you can see some theorem this
here's okay here's here's an example of
projective geometry but anyway let me
talk about how it became that so in the
beginning you want to draw you know
realism in joints so you tease people
discovered okay it's via projection that
you can have realistic joints then then
people and mathematicians you know back
then in 1500 you know art many artists
and mathematicians and philosophers or
scientists they are all in the same camp
you know because they are not
specialized like today like today is so
much specialized even programmers you
have game programmers you have game game
you know you have web web front-end
back in and you know whatever you know
it Network programmers you know but back
then 1500s you know scientists
philosophers artists poet you know they
are kind of often they are the same you
know Google people so anyway the
mathematicians wanted to make progress
in project understanding projection so
when people start to understand
projection you know to find principles
that's the birth of projective geometry
which is this and pretty soon projective
geometry became you know for example
here's a book for example did you know
let's see don't say that man okay so
anyway sub projective geometry they it
becomes abstract you know basically
becomes very abstract and today it has
nothing to do with with drawings here's
a for example here's a page where I it's
a introduction to real projective plane
okay so you can see you know back then I
was trying to write this oh my god
Google Ads [ __ ] I do something about
that so let's see you know let's go
through projective geometry so anyway
you can you can you can check out
Wikipedia and you know then you'll
understand what's of what projective
geometry is about it's it's it's like
when you when you read this article on
Wikipedia about projective geometry you
will see that it's all it's
like it's very abstract you may not even
understand like you don't know what it's
talking about but actually you know but
you you you might have a better
understanding now you know I've given
the background because in the beginning
its to understand
projections then it becomes very
abstract and today's is like totally
abstract like overview okay anyway so
okay let me just finish that then you
know so projective geometry okay
okay so projective geometry is developed
from understanding projection and it
becomes a branch of math by itself have
nothing to do with drawing
now what about linear algebra linear
algebra is a-okay let me explain what
how does linear algebra relates to all
that okay to technical drawing to
descriptive geometry to watch projective
geometry now the first of all understand
that projective geometry becomes very
very abstract okay for example let me
give you a theorem of projective
geometry one of the fundamental theorem
in projective geometry is called dis all
goes to triangle theorem okay let's meet
it just so you get a flavor
what projective geometry is about okay
now there are many approaches to
projective geometry but anyway here is a
classic classic classic traditional way
to describe it okay so this all goes to
triangle theorem here this is very
fundamental I mean one of the core
theory in projective geometry so it says
if two triangles have corresponding
vertices joined by Congo and
lines then the intersections of
corresponding sides are collinear okay
maybe let me just explain so if two
triangles let's see two triangles which
two if two triangles have corresponding
vertices so so for example if we have a
triangle PQR P is here okay here's the
triangle P Q ah you see that P Q R now
let's say let's draw another triangle
let's say this one P Q R you see we have
two triangles P Q R and P prime Q prime
R prime it can be anywhere okay if you
have two triangles now if you draw if
you connect the vertices of one triangle
to the other you see P connect to P R
connect to our Q connect to Q in any way
that you get three lines and the three
lines will intersect at one point now
this is a theorem okay
they were there they will have one
intersection all these three lines we
have one intersection this is a theorem
okay this is called this August -
triangle theorem and that's not all
now once you draw the three lines
P - P okay the P to P prime R to R prime
Q to P Q Prime now you take now you
p2p
okay so fast okay and then I into
extension then then the corresponding
okay I'm not sure I'm looking here take
some
you'll take some some come down to
actually explain this no I'm not okay
any anyway I'm not going to explain this
yeah you have to like be concentrated
and think about this you know to be
calming I'm kind of lost but anyway that
that that is a one of a theorem of
projective geometry so you get the
flavor of what it is like now there are
a lot others for example if you go to
this my page introduction to real
projective plane you will see lots of
theorems like you know if you I mean you
are programmer so I try to read it you
know this is math this is one of the one
of the great math okay this is one of
the huge giant giant chapter in a
history of math okay you try to you know
just for curiosity sake you try to read
this page you know you may or may not
understand it I mean if you have not
done this before you probably have no
idea like you will not see what what it
is trying to say but I mean then you can
read Wikipedia but but still if you do
this you will get a sense of it I mean
you will start to have exposure of what
abstract math is about okay you'll get
exposure and and and this by the way
projective okay let me mention this
projective geometry it's a very deep
abstract subject and many say this
cryptarch
cryptography they depends on projective
geometry okay the most advanced
cryptography they depend on projective
geometry I don't understand okay I don't
understand the details how but you know
I just you know they are related they
are you know once you go deep they are
related so that's about projective
geometry
now the reason I'm trying to give you a
flavor of projective geometry is that
you can see it's all abstract it's all
about point in lies and by the way point
in lines you know we are we are seeing a
graph of it but the actual projective
geometry there's no you don't draw you
don't draw it like in abstract math they
are all defined by logic so point points
so what is a point there's no meaning to
it okay it just says you have a point
okay there's no a point is not a point
in the plane it's just abstract thing
it's just you can replace the word point
by say a dog okay and what is a lie you
know you can just replace the word line
by cat okay so you have like so so the
this August to triangle theorem becomes
you know if you have two cats such that
dog and cat are connecting a certain way
then you know dog and cat this or that
that that's that's what it is okay it's
it has no you know it does not rely on
pictures so anyway so you can see
projective geometry it's not about
numbers you see so far we don't see any
mention of numbers at all so there's no
there's no number concept in projective
geometry okay
this is important I mean so there's no
there's no number concept whatsoever no
real number no well yeah at least in the
axiomatic sense okay because there are
many approaches to projective geometry
but anyway now what is the linear
algebra linear algebra is actually so
let yeah so there are so many approaches
to linear algebra one approach is of
act linear algebra but that but another
approach is numerical linear algebra now
as a programmer you are familiar with
numerical linear algebra which is how
you actually compute computer graphics
you know you you have matrices you
compute a bunch of numbers now so in
that sense what is linear algebra linear
algebra is a technique where you
represent all the points in a plane or
in space in 3d space you have
coordinates X Y Z okay and you know you
represent every point by numbers you
know for example a certain point in
space is just 112 zero point five you
know by by a triple by a triple of
numbers so every point in space is
represent by numbers now so for example
if you have a house you know or cube
let's say or cube all the corners
corners are just represented by numbers
just so you got a bunch of numbers now
you want to draw the tube you want to
draw the cube in a realistic way so what
do you do you do it by projection by
projection just like you know this guy
is trying to draw the Newt so you want
basically your problem the problem is
that given six points you know in in 3d
space and given a van and given another
point that's say that's that's your eye
you want to project you want to draw a
line through from the projection point
to the corners of the cube so that they
intersect the plane the planes your
canvas and you want to find the the
point on the canvas that's your problem
you know so what's the numerical points
on the canvas so that is the problem and
how do you do that the technique to do
that computation is linear algebra okay
so so that's that's that's what linear
algebra is you know from the numerical
point of view so so why is linear
algebra useful
3d graphics well because you know in 3d
graphics we it's all done by computers
so it's so you know every point is just
a bunch of numbers and you want to
calculate to find a bunch of a point on
the plane so that you show these points
on your screen that's what you see you
know basically you are doing 3d to 2d
you know you project 3d stuff to to a
screen 2d and to compute those point you
know to find out where the point should
be to compute them is the technique is
called linear algebra at least the
numerical aspect of it now in math
linear algebra is is not just that I
mean that's one application in math the
linear algebra is is again abstract you
know it's it's it does not necessarily
have to do with numbers at all so anyway
so I hope I don't know if I succeeded in
trying to explain the relations and
differences between technical drawing
descriptive geometry and projective
geometry and linear algebra I hope I did
explain something so let's see how many
people are watching 10 people okay okay
I think that's about it today do you
have good mental arithmetic tomas says
no I don't have a good mental arithmetic
Sat all you know one of the common thing
people think about mathematicians is
that they must be good at numbers
actually that's the most frequently
asked question to mathematicians most
annoying expectation because most
mathematicians they are not good with
numbers at all
well because math you know when you do
math you know like you know when you do
math real math is it's really nothing to
do with computing calculating numbers
it's all about it's about abstraction
about logic you know basically that's
kind of that
that's what mathematicians is about okay
so I've been talking for 80 minutes so
that's it for today so any questions any
comments some so let me know guys let me
know and if nothing else I'll see you
guys next time
next time bye
okay that sounds good next time if you
are learning something maybe you can
teach us what you learned in the text
video well that usually that's the thing
you know if if if I'm learning something
is kind of will take a long time to do
video like like I'm trying to explain
this thing and I kind of stuttered about
you know taking or trying for
descriptive geometry projective geometry
and linear algebra the thing about doing
a video you know I learned a lot you
know once you get more experience you
are better at lecturing or oration you
know so I'm doing better and then before
but I guess sometimes I got the steal
got stuck but anyway for this topic you
know what we just talked about this
topic is actually I'm not I'm actually
not stalking anywhere because I the the
reason I'm kind of stuck is because it's
I think it has to do with personality
like I'm not in a right set of mind like
like the the mindset you know like you
know like for example if someone is
asking me a question then I might be
more fluid but but when I'm doing this
like some time I got stuck I'm wondering
if I should continue or you know like
I'm worried about you you know if people
find this interesting so it's like
something else is is it's it's not you
know it's not making it smooth but for
some other topics for example I may not
know you know if I'm learning something
and I'm trying to teach you that I would
be stuck often because you know I forgot
a topic you know you know for example
code in JavaScript in real time yeah
because if I haven't coded for a while
then I got stuck you know I have to look
for information and the other thing is
the if I do preparation you know I don't
really like to do
raishin or scripted walk you know like I
prepare or write down what I want to say
because that's not a spontaneous and I
you know I feel like it feels like fake
okay and also I don't you know it's like
it feels like commercialize like all the
YouTube videos you see many of them they
are like they prepare them they cut and
they edit you know so they create a
final product that seems to be you know
make you happy and you know watch them I
mean nothing bad with that but but
there's one aspect of that is that you
you know it's like kind of prepared you
don't see the instantaneous facial
expressions which is you know if I'm
stuck you saw you know you see it that
I'm stuck then then that conveys some
information to you because you then you
know oh maybe this part is the most
difficult part okay you know there's
some difficulty all you can see the
character the person okay there's some
information and that's actually natural
that's that's what you get when you talk
to people you know this is kind of
natural but today we have technology you
know we have writing all the technology
and editing so sometimes in some
perspective you get fake things you know
fake news for example fake news they
wrote that you know they can spend you
know two days to write a fake news you
don't know you just read it in one
minute and you know it's it's all fake
news you see everywhere you know
thousands you know there I mean not
everything is fake right but I'm just
saying it modern technology gave us so
these kind of natural things so many of
it anyway okay thank you guys for
watching and thank you thank you Dave
and I'll see you guys next time bye