good morning everyone
you are watching Santosh oh this is the
commencement of our talk show we're
professional programmers and French
programmers we are gathered here to talk
about the words affairs and today we
have several topics we have Emacs in
email is live coding prepared for you
and we're going to talk about mouse DJ
Mouse some fantastic stuff ok DJ Mouse
Chuck wheel should Horine German
keyboard layout and German let her
frequency and HP 20 a calculator these
are fantastic things I'm going to show
you ok
let's show them the today's topic now
there are so many topics today I'm not
sure I can finish it all but let's see
where we go so we're going to talk about
first of all first stop is eMac in the
eMac this for 20 minutes we're going to
do that as promised
that's a technical topic then we're
going to talk about this DJ Mouse ok
fantastic device then we're going to
talk about this DJ DJ mouse and this the
function the functionality the purpose
of choc will ensure whole ring if you
don't know what they are I'm gonna show
you what they are and we're gonna talk
about HP 28s advanced scientific
calculator this is the first or the
second graphing calculator back in 1987
also I bought it for $250 and the
programming language is it has a
programming language which is similar to
forth the stack based programming
language okay and I programmed in that
for three years or four years that is in
fact my first programming language if
you can't add as a language and by the
way this is the Ruby creator mats also
began his programming career programming
life on a calculator okay I may show you
so let's write it down okay so some talk
show today HV 28 s okay
and Ruby creator don't ii magnify and
show the almighty max command you can
see in this pink this purple window this
is Emily's favorite color okay so we're
going to talk about Ruby creator Matz
MIT Z who started programming on a Casio
calculator okay and on YouTube in a
description box you can click a link
there's a link you go to then you will
go to my son talk show page for today
and you can and and be sure to press
refresh because I've just updated it
okay so good morning guys but good
morning you L sec salutations papa moon
loon arias and magpie good morning to
all you people in Germany in Nova Scotia
in Canada and in how do you say that
country amid in Middle America Nick
Nicaragua Nicaragua and monie in
Benjamin Raskin Benjamin Raskin is that
your real name I forgot where you from
Benjamin Raskin because that name I
remember it's also a character in a
movie and Freddy from Germany and
besides maybe I can answer a couple of
German keyboard questions what they do
rely on real-life experience okay so
let's pop this out and okay as promised
we need
begin on email is okay technical problem
technical stuff for 20 minutes okay so
on the left window you see all my Emacs
commands okay and when you see your
command you don't know you can just look
it up
search it you'll find the code so eMac
base there is this there is a fantastic
Benjamin are asking okay so there is a
fantastic command let me show you what
it does okay so I press a key now you
can see on the left window I am pressing
the key six okay that will just select
the block you see cancel let's do it
again
press press one single key press ok
press press you see this is fantastic
command now that command is let me show
you so that command is this one so
select block
so select block okay and let's look at
the keyboard okay I mean let's look at
the code so here's a code and there is a
corresponding website you go to it show
in browser and here's a code you can use
this is fantastic
this is products are fly cheese package
but there is a bug I think some
sometimes I introduce the bug so what is
a bug for example let me show you okay I
select select select select let's do it
again okay oh no so select selects like
it selects a block you know like a
paragraph then by the way Emacs also has
its built-in select paragraph but it's
no good okay I'm not going to talk about
it but if you are new to Emacs so if you
like you know some of those nerds they
will challenge they will see oh yeah but
Emacs already has it ba-ba-bam know okay
I've been doing this for 20 years like I
gotta tell you I tell you what is
correct what is not okay
so ignore the Emacs why it's no good
and I'm not going to explain well is
because it doesn't really walk it
depends on syntax table and so on so
anyway so this command this is fantastic
but but however there is a bug the bug
is for example if I have multiple let's
magnify okay hold on second so if you
see I have here a multiple empties empty
lines so suppose my cursor is over here
I select select select select now this
is incorrect it should actually select
up to here so so that's that's a bug I
introduced sometimes I forgot when so
let's fix that okay first of all go to
the go to the code so here is the code
and we are going to modify it okay so
let's see let's we can modify it right
here so make a backup first you see I
already made a backup and that command
is over there let's see magnify okay so
that is a make backup and say so we want
to modify this command and let's see
what to do so if region active search
for word okay otherwise skip sha
I made you know because you know there's
a tip in programming that is if it works
don't touch it but I think maybe last
year or sometimes this year I was
looking at the code and I thought oh
this shouldn't be you know that's
redundant let's just change it and and
now it's having this problem so so if it
works don't touch it okay
so research forward such forward new
line new line one one oh so this is a
regular expression you are looking at
you know it's tricky actually it's not
as easy as you might think because
okay so let me make work on these okay
so so if there is a region then such
forward okay otherwise okay the problem
is with the select the current rock of
texts between blank lines okay so select
block let's see if I have a backup
version here select current block so
2017 in 2017 November 1st okay wait so
why is it not working select select
so if region active we don't care
so if region is not active region active
means there is a selection
so if region is not not active then it's
that then so we first of all we skip cha
forward okay we skip space newline and
tap ok then god this is you know this
requires thinking yeah I'm doing a video
it requires thinking I cannot think
because when it requires thinking that
means I'm gonna sit here doing nothing
for two or three minutes
okay so let's add a purse there okay I
don't know if that works
oops evaluate the code okay let's try it
again so select it works okay let's just
say that okay so that's all that's all
the change we did so so you see let me
tell you let me explain okay so what
what's going on so when when there is no
when there is a region okay hold on a
second so if you see there is a if
statement then it checks if there is a
selection now if there is a selection
then you do such forward you search
forward by a new line space or tap zero
or more then another new line okay so
let's try it so there is a region let's
make a region then press okey okay so
that's no good
what we want is like that so therefore
all we have to do is add a plus here
plus means well let's first one or more
yeah so let's add a first there
so let's evaluate the code and let's try
it again so first of all make a region
then call the command that's good
that's what we want fantastic
now so when there is no region then it
says skip char forward okay that means
move the cursor to the first character
that's not space newline or tab okay so
we so when there is no region we let's
try it again do it okay that seems good
so first of all you skip cha then
you know they are you have to actually
follow the code carefully but however
what we've done right now is simply to
add a plus like multiple new lines and
it seems to work you see the problem you
see right now it appears everything is
fine
but we need to do Quality Assurance
because if you don't actually carefully
understand what these other lines are
doing then you might have other problems
it's just that you don't know right now
so this is a situation where you need
unit unit testing but to write unit
testing for this kind of thing is not
easy okay so so let's just say so that
let's just say that's it for today so we
do that change the date okay
the version date here and evaluate again
it's and save okay let's just say that
and this is supply keys let's go to the
top change the version number so let's
call command that insert the date in
this format 2019 2019 December 26 13
o'clock 21 seconds 40 seconds 21 minute
40 seconds so that's my version stamp
okay save it
let's go match it
magic is becoming so so let's go here so
these are the changes we made
okay that's good
so far so good any comments any
questions about these any questions
about Emacs about what we are doing ask
now okay then we're gonna talk about
something else
shell command open shell quote argument
okay so we meet minor fixes so okay so
I'm going to commit this so this is
magic mod okay if you guys don't know
what that is my magic mud in fact let me
copy this let me do a screenshot because
okay let me let me do a screenshot here
press okey first base to capture the
window click yes fantastic now I have a
screenshot now let's commit this thing
okay
press s to add press C to C C to commit
and we need to write what's changed
let's just say minor fixes okay
actually usually to do it properly you
need to say what what command command
are change instead of the weasel words
like minor fixes code is important okay
some change okay so well we need to do
it properly so let's do a little bit
proper comment in git commit okay so
first of all let's go back to self like
key and let's find out what the command
we just modified okay so that's the
command name so I'll select block okay
now go back here and let's say
so select blog okay and what else did we
change okay let's do it properly okay
let's let's do it properly so the other
change is this one so I'll show key or
ring okay then what's the other change
match it
okay here is another change sauce your
desktop okay that's it
so control C control C to commit then
capital P and P to push now this is
pushed to my sawfly keys master on
github
okay so let's show it oh I got 20 people
watching merry Christmas everyone
well today well Happy Holidays okay
yesterday's Christmas so now you go to
supply keys github then you can see
github stuff like he's the most
efficient Emacs key mining system if you
have not used it try it okay it's
fantastic it's more efficient than vim
or evil mod so you can see commits 6:27
commits and you can see today's commits
over here fantastic and now ml per after
a few hours or after today you'll get
the latest version or melba so that is
about that command and sawfly keys and
match it i happened just to i we just
happen to demonstrate magic magic my
friend magic is a package in Emacs for
using get okay it's it's a great package
so close sophocles close that screenshot
close back to excel talk show hold on
second
so back took saw talk show we're gonna
write down what we have done so that is
the Emacs command the code you can get
over there but we need to add today's
code change on the
space we haven't done yet we're gonna
I'm gonna do that okay so let me write
some notes first screenshot okay
thief okay
and we also showed match it okay
Emacs demo of package magic a package
for get demo of magic a package for get
okay so that is what we have done today
and hold on a second let me show you
that why are we doing a screenshot of
the gift of the DIF okay one more one
more thing actually 10,000 more things
okay let's go to so you go to you open
oh and stuff like keys okay let me show
you quite a few things I want to show
you Soph like he's okay use such soft
like he's and there's a github page and
there is stuff like his home page and
this page explains everything about what
it is what you can do how to install how
fantastic it is and including a tutorial
and how to customize it okay and this is
a French George from America he this is
his photo
so let's paste the code here okay so
stuff like he's we got that but I also
want to show you match it okay okay
sorry
Emacs magic so this is a tutorial magic
okay I got so many tutorials let me show
you all of them hold on a second go back
and if you have comments at you know
address it to me make it make it orange
okay I'm gonna answer you in a minute
so wait let's go to Emacs get where is
my magic article anyway so you go to
practical Emacs tutorial and the near
the bottom you'll have a section or
match it ok so this is my tutorial on
how to use the match it mod for Emacs
very simple okay if you have now if you
are if you are a Mac user this is a
great package to get and if you are
confused it has a lot features okay but
on this page I'm gonna show you the for
the most fundamental commands you
basically every Emacs magic user have to
use everyday okay so this is the most
practical tutorial just read it and
you'll be good ok so let me copy the URL
and put it in my talk show page okay so
that's one thing I want to show you let
me show you another thing now before we
actually just demonstrated you know
using magic
now before you use magic first of all
you have to understand kit because match
it is a package for git it's an
interfacing Emacs forget now git is of
course you know it's a version control
system very popular if you are a
professional programmer you have to know
it there's no choice okay you have to
know it and gate is extremely complex is
one of the UNIX philosophy [ __ ] okay
it's the most complex [ __ ] possible in
the tradition of Unix not just you know
it's not like necessarily compact
complex like much of mathematics they
are natural naturally complex you have
to learn mathematics deep like a black
hole or like a actual black hole it's
very deep you have to you know you study
ten you
twenty years to understand it but the
much of computing stuff like UNIX stuff
get come on like they they are
artificial complexity that is in
programming in computer science there
are a lot complexities because they are
part of mathematics the general term is
math discrete mathematics you know
computer science in general but in
programming industry what we deal with
everyday programmers we programmers you
know get UNIX command right those are
crap those are those are artificial
complexity those are created by idiots
and in the industry forces corporations
over the past you know 40 years they
arose complexity so kids is actually one
of them why why kid is like that I'm not
going to go into ok because because Unix
so anyway get so you you have to learn
it ok if you want to be a professional
programmer and if you never done before
so here is my tutorial kit basics and
like before you know they are like 10
pages ok I cover the most fundamental
basic practical command command line
examples that every good users almost
have to use every day so you know there
are tons of get tutorials online but why
you should why should you read my well
that's the reason wow you know that's my
stuff you know me so you might you know
as well check out my tutorial so get so
this is my kid tutorial you have to
learn it ok so pace it here so we have
ok so there is something wrong here so I
don't want there is a Sun you see
there's a nested list which is not we
what I want there is some Sun I'm
missing a tag somewhere that is why ok
so I think that's fixed hold on
second now it's fixed now let me show
you another command okay let me show you
another command so we go to and then I'm
going to read the comments okay so we go
to a shall another fantastic fantastic
thing in Emacs and let me show you this
command okay
this command is so interactive a brief
okay press then I got a sink press ENTER
then it's synced to my website so now if
you go to the YouTube you know in the
YouTube descriptions you click on the
link and press refresh you will see my
you know updated some talk show topics
we the things we've talked about okay so
that's about that there is one more
thing then I'm gonna answer the
questions okay I'm gonna look at the
comments one more thing so you go to
youtube and you go to exactly Linux
Tiff's we encounter another tutorial
that is teeth this is a classic UNIX
tool command-line tool that diff that
tells you that compares the differences
between two files this is essential you
know if you are a professional
programmer you need to understand this
stiff every professional programmer you
need to know okay so if you are student
if you haven't done this before
check it out okay so I'm going to put a
link here as usual after the get basics
so you can see it's there but why are we
talking about diff because remember we
did a screen shot before on my page
there is no screen shot so I I need a
screen shot so this is my process of
writing my tutorials so let's open the
diff page
first of all observe
you see there's a updated date last
updated 2019 February so we're gonna
change that okay you see it's over here
okay let me magnify you see that lines
over here so I'm just going to press one
command one key okay watch watch the
efficiency the power and efficiency of
my keys and Emacs so I press three
keystrokes okay not control something
something no such thing no control meter
nothing three single keystrokes why does
it say space you it's actually you not
why oh you okay
anyway that's that strange so I press
three keystrokes and you see the date is
updated so I go to the browser
watch the date okay refresh
you see December 26th and we're gonna
add a the screenshot we did a few
minutes ago so let me add it here okay
so let's go down here and now remember
we add we did a screenshot on a Mac and
that screenshot is saved in the test app
folder somewhere in the test test app
folder actually because we can see it do
you see there open it you see that's a
screenshot we did before close it it's
in the desktop folder but I have a
command that if I call it I just press a
few keys it will move that screenshot to
the current directory and also create a
HTML link to it so let me show you okay
so I'm gonna press three keys okay let
me show you again wait well what is the
key so okay so press two keys
he asked me what directory I want to
move to I okay and it asked me to type a
name let's say
and I type get stiff
okay there it is you see it added that
block of text with you know the image is
moved here that's an image close it and
also it created this HTML whole thing
for you just by two keystrokes show in
browser slow down
see fantastic that's so this is an
example of diff diff output with color
get stiff okay so actually I need to
move that over here because over here
it's about give now let's just leave it
there okay I'm going to think about
appropriate location position of this
image offline so but for now let's leave
it there okay so and lets you see the
the screenshot on my desktop is gone you
see because the fantastic Emacs command
did everything for me in one shot okay
and that command we just caught is over
here okay you see that that is a command
so actually so let's copy it and that is
the command and let me actually show the
code okay so here is a code and again
there is a corresponding URL over here
and showing browser this is the command
you can grab move image file so copy the
file path close it close it let's put it
here so we did a lot MX demonstration
today and UNIX stuff kids and all that
okay so that's okay then
showing browser again Sontag show
updated go to shell yow-yow is a shell
written in a Mac based entirely and and
it is what I use so it's now it's
updated to my web server so that's it
about Emacs for today so let me read the
comments and questions
oh there is a fine question
they say stub oasis
the problem with Sally's philosophy is
that once you expose a lot of interfaces
and create abstractions you risk of
making the whole thing slow and hard to
isolate to isolate errors or recover
wrong okay because my code uses the fast
is the fastest fast as possible okay my
code my email is code is faster than any
package any the most popular package ivy
helm a bunch of others you know you go
to milpa you see the top 10 the most
popular packages they usually have like
10,000 100,000 downloads you compare any
one of them very popular those are you
compare that my my my code my email list
command the user interface the code okay
the code is faster than all of them that
is my claim you can go verify it my code
is faster then let's just say the top 10
the most popular packages packages on my
path my code is faster that than them
why I can tell you why because I I call
this being a particular way I always use
the the most you know I know what I'm
doing okay
and I'm very very obsessively particular
about how my code should be so you know
a lot of people didn't like me because I
criticize reaches soman or open source I
say [ __ ] [ __ ] the UNIX you know they
don't like me so you see a lot rumors on
the web you say okay sorry doesn't know
how to code this is our leader oh he's
he's formatting is wrong this or that is
they are idiots okay so first of all my
eMac beast code the hundreds of them you
see in my packages or in my web site
they are faster then all these popular
ones okay even and I mean those popular
ones are written by the great these
programmers okay in some cases then
this better than me but still III make
the cream okay my code is faster better
than theirs that's just one thing it's
to my my eMac commands code interface
the design is better than their small
efficient you know the operation for
example I have demonstrated several of
my commands today
you know I've demonstrated several of my
Emacs command today the way they operate
the way you know for example editing
command a selection command for example
we demonstrated select selection of a
paragraph okay why do I choose this
command why should I you know maybe I
should press a button to select
something else you know anyway so what
I'm saying is that my command the user
interface the design is more efficient
than any of them I can challenge okay
this is my second clip I will challenge
of those people Emacs phonetics you know
they they they will be using you know
help they'll be using IV they'll be
using card mod [ __ ] [ __ ] the nerd
jargon card mod ok there's a key bunny
mod cod mod there's the evil mod ok
i sorry claim my commands with soft like
Esau laws or individual commands faster
than them and more efficient than them
and this can be measured scientifically
ok not what you think oh I think I think
I think the caps lock should be should
be a control [ __ ] idiots
ok these commands my command they are
not just faster faster you can measure
by time ok by a clock but they are also
they are also more efficient meaning you
use you use my system you lock your
keystrokes ok Emacs you there's a
package ok let me show you this package
you log your keystrokes ok don't don't
you know do two things scientifically so
let me show you the key log okay and I
have article on that I've article
everything key lock so ok so let me meet
IX
frequencies show now this is a package
which I kind of you know a friend began
I modified it and David Capello took
over so this package okay key frequency
okay I'm gonna so we are digressing
Casali Emacs command stud mystics okay I
have a page reporting on the statistics
of Emacs commands here
Emacs command frequency statistics and
if you know I report you know that the
which command are most often used so
this is written like 15 2007 okay so
already 13 years ago I've been
obsessively studying this kicking on
this daily more than anybody else on the
on the on on this earth okay if you
leaving Martha better bucket but on this
month my my claims about key binding in
science okay Kiki keyboarding Sciences
is better than anyone else I claim that
you can challenge me prove me wrong by
you know you can Coco and I put me wrong
don't just focus I said idiot say
something tangible say something like
because this thesis is that and most of
them did you know the opinions are no
good they don't they don't have nothing
to back up and they don't know because
they never spend much time alright so so
in so it becomes you know lots of
criticisms but I have to spend an hour
to answer each one you know is you just
watch my videos okay so anyway so this
Emacs man's command frequency statistics
report you go to the bottom there's a
link to the package so he so here's a
practical tip okay you you you get that
package isn't me oppa you download it
then you can have your key log count
just like I show here you see this is my
key log for the past I don't know have a
euro year so that so that is about key
log
okay so so let me copy this link Emacs
command frequency and put it here
this is Kassar rent none stop man I can
go on forever I can go on for a few
hours about this and I need you guys
input okay so that's that's a good
question eh-eh so you know so I'm
claiming my commands are more efficient
better you know more efficient better
design and also code is faster than
theirs okay you can believe it or not
you can you know go try it yourself you
have to spend time on it that that is
the issue so anyway let's go back to see
what the comments addressed to me okay
so so how long have I been talking 42
minutes okay so I'm in some contract
okay I'm so if you have a question for
me
put them putting my name to it so okay
so I can see easy so hey a question I
always had about you how do you spend
your day
Oh haven't you watch my videos and you
can see how I spend my day this is kind
of how I spend my day I work on all
these things you know I've been doing
video almost a year ago almost every day
about an hour a day at least half a year
ago so if you watch a few of them you
kind of know what I do every day you
know I just sitting in front of computer
I talked about these several times
before so and I get that question a lot
you know sometimes you will say oh can
you can you do a diary kind of like so
you know because I'm kind of a bit weird
and people you know they have a question
you know so what what do you do how what
what do you see what I've like what do
you do every day you know so so well so
you are watching it
somewhere it's not really so so I use VC
for version control facilities okay that
that is a building version control it
seems you are using something else match
it
yes correctly correct the VC the its
building you know there's a lot politics
in Emacs you see normally ideally in
Emacs you would like to have one package
that deals with kit or with avi or other
version control systems you know ideally
you have you you want just one building
package that's built in so everyone can
use so that that that creates you know
that makes Emacs more powerful but
that's not really the case because then
someone wrote match it ok so then then
there's politics about how do you get
your package into Emacs ok it's not it's
not ok there's a lot politics so you
know it depends on how much wheeling are
you to to talk you know a month to argue
them in the in activities I talk about
this many times so so anyway so today in
Emacs there is a beauty in command which
is vicita ok so ok I never I haven't
used it vicita ok so let's for example
let's look at the documentation so he
says vicita is an interactive auto
loaded list function ok
and it shows vc version control status
for interesting files in and below the
again things you know is the version
control and you have actually you have a
bunch of commands like 20-30 commands
for version control and this is p OD ok
remember this is important this is
building however match it you know most
people use kit today
kit you know we had a version control
war 10 years ago get wrong
basically all the others are just wiped
out kit is the kind of the de facto
standard for version control so and
someone has written this magic package
which is very good ok
the visitor also does mat get also does
get but anyway the point is this this
this situation you know it's not good so
you have these two systems you have
match it which you need to download then
you have this VC which also does skit
but also others which is speeding but
however today most people are using
magic okay very few use uses we see
there's a lot politics because match it
you know the VC Sparta is because it's
Pandora's part of new it is part of
Emacs which means they don't they don't
change easy ok they cannot evolve easy
meanwhile match it you know the things
are male power they change almost every
day you know to for whatever fixed bug
fix they change they change fast because
it's not controlled by glue by Richard
Stallman okay this is [ __ ] so so if you
are using kit I'm pretty sure match it
is better ok and also I know this VC is
written by this guy ESR ok Eric Raymond
I think mostly a large part of it
Eric s Raymond who wrote the who wrote
who wrote the but the boss ah you know
Cathedral in the buzzer okay so actually
it doesn't say women yes I so it's
actually by Dan Nicolas ooh and the
current maintainer is okay okay so it's
by this guy
Steph ammonia is the previous Emacs
maintainer four or five years also and
Tom Tommy is a guy who began he did a
lot of things you know he he he created
the new alpha guys this guy Tom Tommy
why do we have mapa why do we have male
the Alpha the Emacs package system
thanks to Tom Tommy he created it okay
thanks to Tom tremendous guy and thanks
to Steph ammonia is a great guy he he's
he led the Emax dead for four five six
years the fact Richard Stallman [ __ ]
[ __ ] Richard Stallman [ __ ] he's a
scumbag Richard Stallman is a guy who
who did the most damage to Emacs in the
past ten years more than ten years
Richard Stallman I'm not going to get
into details because I talked a lot
about this in my past videos but anyway
so the vc tool I'm pretty sure it's also
done by Eric s Raymond because I've seen
he talked about it and he don't have
time to you know actually we can do as
such yes I okay so let's do as such how
is his name spelled Eric E
our eyes see okay Eric s Raymond okay so
let's search for Eric hold on a second
no oh god those are GZ files so I don't
think my two was such GZ so it's not
search then there are other ways but
okay so anyway so gzipped
anyway I think he did some work but I
don't see it here those anyway so so we
are talking about this VC situation the
version control system in Emacs in lots
of politics okay
emacs visita command match it ALPA male
pas in Emacs dev politics okay so that's
about that so let's see
not yet I haven't turned off JavaScript
yet good morning Alan
so okay anything else address to me so
magpie says macrophage says as one as
one who's still trying to figure out
whether I want to focus on learning vim
or Emacs what's one thing Emacs can do
that VM cannot do well that's that's
kind of a complex question I mean and
that's also a frequently asked question
basically I can give you the you know
that that question has been asked for
twenty years twelve or twenty years
everyone wants to know that okay so what
what what Emacs can do that VIN cannot
wear a lot in general okay that here's a
general thing general in general VI VI
of M is focused on text editing okay
that's the primary task and in general
it relies on the the whole bag of the
UNIX system to walk so for example in
Emacs I can go to a directory okay I can
go to a direct I go to a directory and I
can split and I can go to Xiao Jie I can
go to I can go to the past yeah okay so
you see on the top is the traditional
Shou interface - and on the bottom is
the Isha okay you have lots of commands
you have like you know as they say Emacs
is the operating system technically it's
not but
Emax does like everything okay but that
is a general gist of Emax it you can do
everything you can play music you can
have you know you can show images you
can lots of things you can even write
music you know you can and see so do I
have an image here I showed it before
right so for example like open that and
you know I can show image this is the
image in Emacs I can go to the directory
and show you show you another image you
can do you know lots of things that's
the nature of Emacs as like 200s
but vim is mostly focused on text
editing and when you just need something
else you drop into the show and you use
the UNIX tools it's kind of that's the
workflow most mostly okay not this is
just a general situation so which one to
use it's really up to you of course I
like Emacs I don't like you know I don't
like I prefer Emacs okay and and in
Emacs you have a package called Evo mod
which is basically makes Emacs use
themes
clear binding so you can so if you know
him you can use Emacs almost just like a
wimp
with all the Emacs power that's that's
what you so you know like they say as
they say once you are in Emacs you live
in Emacs like I don't I don't need to go
out to Shell to do LS or whatever you
know I don't I don't need to go to
shower to do that I do everything you
max and you know I can you know I can I
can open this in a you know I can open
this in a image viewer you know in
operating system image image viewer I
can go to the diet and show in desktop I
can do a lot of things like Emacs
becomes the center you know the control
center you where
you you are in emacs you do everything
you can show everything and today you
even have people who have who moved on
Linux you move the entire x11 system
into Emacs so you don't even have the
you know you don't have like browser
windows so tests have not anymore you
you have one Emacs screen then you have
like x11 browsers or whatever terminals
inside it people are doing that I don't
like that though so that's about Emacs
versus VI okay ultimately it's like it
it's a question you have to answer so
so so waseso Emax is unnecessarily Brody
well you don't know but you have to like
you have to use it to actually know the
opinion okay that's it that's it for
Emacs and perhaps I'm thinking perhaps
that's it for today because it turns out
I talked a lot for 55 minutes so what's
the next topic guys what is the next
topic Oh Alan is mentioning Talib I'm
gonna I'm gonna [ __ ] that guy [ __ ]
that guy if I'm gonna talk about that
guy is a crackpot of our current era
so today's juice is mango juice okay
this is this is actually not pure mango
it has kind of sugar but at least it's a
cane sugar cane sugar so you know don't
don't drink sugar water but if you have
to like once in a while once in a month
can change you know can sugar can you
know sugar cane made sugar is so kind of
okay be so well okay but question these
Emacs are necessary broad it no it's not
bloated at all at all because Emacs in a
tradition of the Nerds they it's pretty
it's very efficient it's no blood at all
especially if you compare to visual
studio or any other editors they would
they will have actually you can try it
you know Emacs for example I have like I
have 20 you know I have thirties I have
60 70 you know buffers
open in Visual Studio so you know I can
show you actually so you go to process
you know you look at Emacs okay this
Emacs right now it's using what
memory who is memory okay let's go to
memory
you know as a tease 86 megabyte memory
okay MX 86 megabyte you start of Visual
Studio or visual code they are like one
Chigi bytes [ __ ] one chica by they
even if you don't have no window open
you just launch it one chica by two
chica by memory
they suck it in and this Emacs right now
it's you should almost always less than
100 megabyte mega okay not chica those V
me and whatever you know they did they
are like they upload Emacs is not and
actually we can start them let's see how
how him how much memory this would be
fun okay let's see how much memory is
vim using let's compare notes v let's
see
vim with no so now I have them can you
guys see okay this is kind of small but
so right now I have them queries beams
okay so I need to go by PID okay here's
a little tip PID is the process ID every
process in UNIX or Linux has an ID so
one way to find the process that just
you just launched you can you you can do
that by just find the ID that has the
highest number of ID most of the time
because the ID actually cycles so here
it is him okay it's using one megabyte
of memory right now okay that's that's
good because I don't have anything open
so I'm not to you know familiar with him
so I'm not going to like open lots of
fires
stuff yeah [ __ ] stupid vim okay
that's about that what else a crackpot
no I'm not quite fun I'm a good I'm a
good crackpot no I'm not a crackpot at
all but it's up to you to decide of
course so what what is the next topic
today so we talked for one minutes one
hour now so okay let's go back to
TJ mouse well actually I'm not sure
maybe that's it for today so we got DJ
mouse we got some of these interesting
things okay Chinese input system okay
wait
oh this is yeah there's a lot to talk
about about keyboard like you know like
we can start and they it will never end
once we start to talk about this Co not
end there's Chinese this HP 20s 28 s
keyboard in German okay German keyboard
layout okay so what has part can help us
with that
so I think I think I actually I mean
it's closed down for today so we focus
on Emacs in that that's good so so you
just search for you go to Saudi keyboard
and go to sake ball blog let's see what
these aren't discord what people are
saying nothing nobody is saying nothing
be your life
okay so you go to Saudi keyboard blog
you click on the layout then you see the
German I mean you see say you know about
keyboard layout then you click on German
then here we have the German keyboard
layout and you know the German language
first of all if you are not speaking
German what you have to know is that
German has these extra letters okay
a oh you with an ohm load em loud day oh
the German German people say it ohm load
day um latte I think something like that
am I correct but and this ooh ooh ooh
that's how they are pronounced I think I
think am I am I correct so but you have
to grade me ah Oh II that's what those
unloaded version of a oh you are and
this this funny be this character is
actually it kind of equipped equivalent
to SS this is interesting SS okay so
they have that character in German
language so what so these are the firing
letters in German you know you know so
I'm looking you know I'm studying
keyboard layout so so first thing you
you want to know about a keyboard layout
of another language language is that you
know what are the extra letters you know
that's the first thing you want to know
you need to know then then you need to
study the the letter frequency I have it
here you can see it so it turns out you
see those those special characters are
not used much you see you see they are
not used much
like they are the most least frequently
used so so if you are considering you
know if you are studying layout for
efficient layout you can basically
ignore all these special characters so I
have this page you click on this will
show you your frequency in real time for
example for example this is a JavaScript
code app that shows your letter
frequency in real time and this is
written by me of course and if you like
this you need to buy my JavaScript
tutorial ok so let's see let me add the
T you see if I think if adding T the T
is gonna overwrite demo and you can also
copy this entire page go here select all
and paste you see so you can copy your
source code JavaScript or whatever you
can paste it all then you and you can
see so that's about that so I want to
demonstrate that that's all and back to
the German layout where is it ok so go
back to the German layout you know so
I'm kind of studying them so but what
didn't answer okay so we're well so go
to a talk show again close that German
okay German keyboard layout and that's
it for today okay guys so have a good
day enjoy your holidays so New Year is
coming guys new year 2020 2020 this is
the end of 8
okay the beginning of a new one so
that's amazing you know 2020 so what are
you guys doing oh and also I like to
thank Kathy is Kathy here thank Kathy
for donation and you guys if you guys
yeah I'm shutting down in one minute or
two okay so many of you guys I'm not
familiar so you guys AAA joining this
code okay you can find the link on my
youtube or my exoti 13/4 website join
this code and for those are you in
discord there is a programming challenge
by George okay so so we have a solution
by Allen Allen over there who who has
who gave us a go colon solution and
George gave us a solution in Ruby and we
also have a solution another solution in
Ruby so so if you have not done that
code this programming challenge we're
going to talk about it in you know in a
few days over in a weekend I think so
that's it for today join this code okay
and thank you yeah thanks thanks to
Kathy Kathy H for for money
bye guys