hi guys so today I'm going to show you a
keyboard the ultimate hacking keyboard
which is this one who taught hacking
keyboard and that's my apple juice now
I've been trying to do this video for a
while but I really I cannot do it
because well let me show you the
keyboard because the camera is extremely
lousy you see you won't focus that is
why
you know when you're doing that when
you're doing in the camera the the
direction you move is reversed so every
time I try to move I want to move right
and it's on the left so anyway so this
is a keyboard and this is so you see the
problem is with the camera okay now it's
good but now it's not good you see you
it doesn't focus well and the camera is
this one Logitech c920 never buy this
camera it's good get you know on a way
you know it's it's it's got like 4.5
stars and if you search the web people
will say this is the this is this is the
like the best you know but it's so bad
so a Logitech c920 don't get it and also
there's a high tech scene I 20x it looks
similar it looks similar
don't don't buy that one either it's
pretty much the same so anyway let's go
back to the keyboard so you know because
the keyboard is so lousy I tried every I
tried always to set it up I tried for an
hour and another hour the other day but
I cannot do it so but I decided you know
I'm gonna just go ahead and do a video
anyway so and I decided to use a screen
you know so you can actually see my
pictures you know much better pictures
here pictures of the keyboard
so anyway so let me just show you then
let me show you so I'm gonna show you
around so this is the keyboard it's got
a wire connecting that the two pieces
and when the keyboard are connected you
don't have to you don't need them you
don't need them here walk like right now
only if you take it apart you need to
separate you need to connect them
together and this is this is like a
phone jack see
yeah anyway so let's see so that's like
a phone check
and on the on the back let me show you
the back puts him on hacking keyboard
it's got
and agent agent agent is the software to
program the keys
adaptive adaptive mod I'm not sure that
what that is this is so frustrating
because the camera won't focus in any
way so let's keep keep on so anyway so
it comes in two pieces these are
connected by magnets like you can see
this magnetic action here and they are
like that
okay this is gonna be a comical I think
that change this instead of this is
instead of keyboard review this is a
comic Center okay anyway so I'm gonna
show you this so you've seen the
keyboard now what else show backside
I've showed you that okay I wanted to I
want to take it apart so that I can type
and show key switches
well the key switches are they are just
an mechanical keys like when you buy
them you have several choices
I choose red now this is not cherry red
actually when well you can go through
their website they they actually have
red red black blue brown and green I
think available and maybe is another
let's see okay so Cherry MX screen and
clear and Kyle
red blue brown I choose red you know
kind of red is actually more resistance
than cherry MX red at first I was like
surprised but now I get I got used to it
and I love it very much so special mouse
buttons so that's that you see this this
yeah so this these are like mouse
buttons
okay anyway so these two are like mouse
buttons and you can program them just
like any other key you can see them to
be control or whatever
ohh-ho-ho special mod key or function
key or command key any any key or just
like call escape but actually I don't
like to use them much because they are
like mouse buttons and you see the light
lights up there right now this I said
this to mod so I hold on this hold on to
that my red hand become arrow keys and
actually this is mod as well so you can
see you see now my right hand becomes
arrow keys up down left right or move by
word the move my word I think I
programmed it I don't remember
anyway so special mouse buttons yeah
they can be programmed to be any key you
want discuss the led okay the lead here
they it doesn't do much I mean it looks
fancy three digits kind of led it just
show you what layout you are in like
right now I'm in Warrick I can switch it
to corty by default is 40 so you can see
it Scottie black black
then Commack then and this is quota for
Mac for Mac means that they switch the
windows and command keep the the windows
in option at the odd key they switch the
position
so anyway black quote eco Mac that's the
default key layout let me switch back to
work
and yeah and also for mac of windows so
a total of six default key sets you can
choose profiles the game is code for
profiles so okay this yeah so you need
this wire when they are apart how the
programmability of the of this keyboard
is the most advanced I've ever seen
actually I think it's I would say it's
the most of an advanced this open-source
software called qm qm o qm s something
like that and there's also another
anyway i would say this is the most real
reliable you don't have to like go
through github or compiled you don't
have to do anything like that
actually now why don't why don't I show
you the I just show you a little bit the
programming software the UK uhk ultimate
hacking keyboard agent
they named the software agent so this
software is the most intuitive and most
well most intuitive and most easy to use
software I've ever seen I didn't read
the manuals but I you know well I'm
gonna do another video to show you about
this software probably so there you have
key maps so default quote EPC code he
Mac Borak PC Borak Mac so so for example
if I go to quarry right now it means I
can change any key I want and I can you
know this this this is a base layer mud
layer function layer so anyway you know
I'm not gonna talk about the software
right now so I'm just gonna
talk about a keyboard so anyway it's the
most it's the most intuitive and easy to
use software I've ever seen and when
when you want to when you program some
keys that say base mod so so for example
I want to change let's say this key so
right now that key right now this key is
backspace but if I hold it down it's
smart if I hold it down in personal key
it's actually mod so it's dual function
and it's reliable unlike you know
operating system based key keep on in
software that's less reliable this is
completely reliable
so I click on that then I can change
yeah I'm not gonna do that now so so
what else
most intuitive software and also it's
the most advanced program ability you
can program Marcos yeah I just you know
like I said you have dual function keys
you have Marcos and it's extremely easy
to use and legs yeah so I'm using a book
like this you know I'm using a thick
book because
you can see I'm have a thick book here
if I put this down well you know they
have legs that I think I believe they go
into these schools so you can you can
put the legs on so they do pop up but
not as high as the book you know because
I typed so much I had hand injuries so I
wanted higher I'm not sure the legs
actually can go this high but anyway
even if it can I don't want to I don't I
prefer it this way you know this way you
can is simply you know you just you know
you just unplug it and carry it you know
and you don't have to
well III I don't think I like the legs
but I haven't tried it yet actually I
haven't looked into them and also
there's wrist pad you can attach I
believe it also you know going with the
schools it's it's you know I don't like
grease pads because I use towels you can
see I have basically like that powers
that's my wrist pad you know you can
just throw it away and buy a new one
like two dollars each and it's much much
more higher and more comfortable than
any respect I particularly don't like
those you know we'll put on or whatever
high-tech robot
miss fati well but when you are typing
you're not suppose to actually risk your
rest your hand on the wrist pad that's
because that's no good you you supposed
to like right now let me show you you
are you are
supposed to rest your wish on the wrist
and when you are typing yeah optional
palm rest so I don't use that but some
people like it you know and you know you
you might like it
it's very nice miss pad oh and this
optional modules they are great they are
an innovation but it's not out yet so I
think they are fantastic but they don't
have it yet it's not out yet yet and
there's more pictures you know the
people other people's pictures much more
beautiful then my you know I said that
yeah so so the lakes looks like that I
haven't I haven't put on mine but this
one is wrong they this guy attached the
lakes on the side for some reason he
shouldn't be that way should usually put
the legs in the middle if you want to
okay show some typing so show some
typing
I like this keyboard I have I have
abbreviation in Emacs you see I can go
through my brief and that's all my
abbreviations so for example yes is does
he does this let's go back to that and
and is and okay okay I think that's it
for this this video yeah so my lousy
camera I'm not sure what to do about
that I cannot get a new one but I don't
know when so anyway there you have it
thank you for watching and I'll help
I'll talk about this keyboard probably a
lot more in my Emacs and programming
tutorials and yeah thanks for watching
so if you have a questions ask me
and yeah ask me if you have a question
or what you want to see for next video
thanks bye