good morning welcome to another episode
of c talk show today we are going to
code Advent of code
2024 day four with wolam language
fantastic wolf girl generated by gr so
let's begin coding wolam language
um okay and if you don't know already
you just search my website a.info you'll
find my talk show Pages uh lots of talk
show um so now it's Episode
600 and there's aent of code 2024 index
so you can find past uh Solutions in
wolam language they are the shortest
Solution on
Earth okay because wam language is the
most high level Language by a magnitude
than them all
then lisp closure uh hascal or camo F sh
of course a lot more higher level than
python JavaScript
Ruby uh or C++ and Java those are low
level so anyway so wam language
available code yeah okay let's begin
shall we if you are here say hi if you
are not here play at 1.5 speed because I
ramble a lot 1.5 speed minimum and Skip
around okay so video check audio check
am I good to go yes and my live quality
good okay so number four Advent of code
number
four yeah okay let's see let's
begin okay so looks looks like the
chef's not here next something something
something as as the search for the Chief
continues a small elf something this
word search allows words to be
horizontal okay so wait as the search
for the chief continues a small elf who
lives on the
station who lives on the station tucks
on your on your shirt she'd like to know
oh it's a She Lovely she elf she'd like
to know if you could help her with her
word search oh yeah of course if it's a
she yes I'm going to help
you help her with her word search your
person
input okay she only has to find one word
exmas Christmas this word search allows
allows words to be horizontal vertical
diagonal written backwards or even
overlapping other words okay horizontal
vertical diagonal and also backwards
including diagonal I suppose and
vertical or even overlapping other words
it's a little unusual though as you
don't merely need to find one instance
of Xmas you need to find all of them all
of them here are a few ways xas might
appear where irrelevant characters have
been replaced with DOT okay so let's see
uh okay so you see
this so can you see yeah so you you
got xmx okay so this reversed
XM uh wait so here is a vertical One X
MX reverse vertical reverse
vertical reverse right to left and the
bottom to top and and here is uh left to
right and here
is upper left to lower right
diagonal and
uh XM okay so did we check them did we
find them or xas so starting with x so
you can start to look by just x x is the
starting
position so
so how many we have
one two three we only got three the
actual word search will be full of
letters instead okay so in this word
search xas occurred a total of 18
times okay here is the same word search
again but where letters not involved in
any X must have been replaced with DOT
okay so there are 18 occurrences in this
block of
text okay
so
xas xas up to top down bottom to
top uh xas lower right to uper left xas
lower left to upper right okay I think I
got the idea
so can there be a gap let's
see does if I mean so it can there be a
gap take a look at the little eles word
search how many times does X must
appear okay so in this so okay let's
begin coding so this is a block of
code copy
it showing browser
okay so let's
begin wolam language this is wolam
language in s wolam mod you can find it
on GitHub it's free it allows you to
code wolam language
in emac so that you can have efficient
um for example I run
it first time takes a while so you see
this this is the output this is just a
string okay so and we can do it in wfam
language notepad I already started there
it
is okay
so okay so you want to find so let's
need uh we need to start to think about
algorithm like what is the instruction
how do you solve
this
um any any anyone here yet hello hello
Dave
okay have you coded wfam language before
what uh language do you code so okay so
we got
this let's
see so the first question is can you
have a gap between words it didn't say
did it
say you don't Meely need to you need to
find all of them okay all the examples
here in this example there are three
occurrences I believe however they
didn't say so let's double
check
uh bottom to top right to left that's
two then left to right that's three then
then top left to lower right
four see one
two okay one 2 3
4 so so s High so there are four
occurrences in this example
four let's see one 2 3 4
now you see we want to check if there's
a gap if uh if if there's a gap does it
count if you see in this example it
doesn't show such occurrence so it's
ambivalent we cannot tell from this
example Xmas s okay I presume a gap does
not
count yeah because otherwise then you
could have XX m m a a SS and that would
count as two because you know you skip a
letter each time so I would I would
presume the Gap you cannot have gaps
gaps are not allowed
okay okay so you got this um 18 times so
okay let's think about the
algorithm H how do you do this then
okay this is a tedious
problem there's no uh apparent
way to solve it you see there's no
problem with horizontal or vertical
because horizontal you you can easily
check and uh and for reverse horizontal
all you have to do is just reverse each
row trivial for vertical or you you have
to do is you transpose you you turn this
into a matrix and transpose which means
flip it on a vertical on a diagonal axis
transposition of the Matrix then you can
just check horizontally like before so
vertical and horizontal there's no
problem
trivial the problem is with
diagonal so is there a so we have to
think about a way a easy way to find a
diagonal of course you can like do the
brainless brot Force by by increment of
the index horizontal in decrease by one
and uh row increase by one so you know
that that's very
tedious so so the horizontal okay so so
you need a way is there a way to turn
the diagonals into into just rows so
that become then then you become trivial
so you need
[Music]
the the back slash diagonal and you need
the reverse back slash you know the
slash inv verus back slash okay
so can you can you turn the Matrix and
extract the diagonal that's the question
yes let me write down the
algorithm uh so because when we I
mean algorithm when we do a Long Live V
uh video when you have something right
down people can see right
away for
horizontal
H H did I spell it correctly no
horizontal it's
trivial reverse row
trivial for vertical just transpose The
Matrix for
diagonal you need to turn the
diagonals into
rows can that be
done I believe
so uh in wfam language you have so
although I don't know what is so you all
you have to do just search for diagonal
okay question mark As risk d i a g o n a
l it can I believe there's a function
that gives you the diagonal matrix what
uh okay contrl
L capital
D okay there it is block di block
diagonal matrix diagonal diagonal matrix
Q diagonal matrix okay so you got
several let's look at one of them
represent uh represent the so once you
have this function building it's trivial
you see
you know without this function is
tedious the index like the C idiots c c
and C++ and Java and C this C virus
induced
idy okay so let's represent the block
diagonal matrix with diagonal blocks d
as a structure way okay you
actually keep the list of elements on
the leading diagonal of the Matrix okay
leading
diagonal uh okay Diagon Matrix
okay uh gives a matrix with the elements
of list on the leading diagonal okay so
I mean so diagonal matrix is a
mathematical Concept in
math they
um so let's see
so probably this is the one we want to
use let's
see yeah okay but uh then you need a k
give the elements on the K diagonal so
if the Matrix you
have let's see how do they count is a k
by row or
uh okay let's try this
copy that let's just play it
okay so you got that then uh let's
assign it
um XX equals
to we shift enter assign it so now
we uh I believe diagonal
yeah so diagonal and xx
then let's say one what do you get shift
enter BF okay so let's try
again let's see
Zero shift enter so zero is
AEI okay one is BF
now if you say two that's going to be
just
C
okay
fantastic
now let's see so it goes by the number
of columns starting with zero okay
so zero is the main diagonal okay so you
need to think about
um so so if you say negative
one that's going to give you D
DH shift enter that's
right so in the negative Direction you
you will have the number of rows so if
you have three rows then you have zero
negative 1 and neg -2 okay so -2 is
going to be just G
okay we got the now we understand this
diagonal
function now is it possible just
actually just give you all the
diagonals
okay let's
try uh what is this diagonal
matrix oh okay it just generates a
matrix with the certain diagonals okay
that's not what we want okay but this
diagonal is what we want
okay so once you have this it becomes
trivial uh what about what about reverse
diagonal let's
see then you just transpose right you
just transpose it then you got the
reverse diagonal okay uh so let's Okay
we almost done so we got the
diagonal from diagonal means top left to
bottom right okay once you get it you
check it then you reverse each
row then you
got lower right lower right to top left
okay
then so you checked all the you know
diagonals from you know the back slash
then you transpose The Matrix then you
do the diagonal again that's going to be
and you also reverse so yeah okay then
you know that's
the yes via the wam language
function okay
d i a g o n a l d i a g o n a l okay
that's the algorithm let's let's do it
then so that's input let's
uh so that's uh the normal way
you you want to check each row okay so
check each row so for each row what you
do is you want
to um first of all you need to turn this
into a matrix
okay let me show you how to do
that okay well first of all X input
equals to we uh first of all we turn it
into a matrix
so string
split string split by default you'll
split by white
space okay so X
input so you
got that
then then you want to
map map the characters represent a
single char character in read no
characters okay characters will turn a
string into each characters return a
list okay yeah so you want map
characters the function
to
that okay then you got
Matrix okay which let's run it
yeah so you can see you know if
we you see we got a matrix you see
cut you know beautiful
so
so yeah wait you don't you don't want to
you don't want to um because you now you
want to do regular expression on each
one you don't want you don't want the
yeah yeah okay but but if you don't turn
it into a matrix then it's hard to do
transposition so you have to turn it
into a
matrix then for each row you put them
back into a string
okay uh
yeah can let doable so now the task is
how do you have a you know a list of
strings turn them back into a
string
um okay that's
[Music]
um let's see string join let's magnify
this so it's easier to
read okay all you have to do is just uh
use string join so let's show
you string
join okay for example you have the list
AA
and uh
BB and CC and uh eval this
line there it is you got a
string so that's good so what we have to
do now is just
um h on a second
okay so what we have to do now is you
got the Matrix then you want to um what
you want to do with the Matrix map okay
so yeah so map and uh string
join then you got a string Okay so
list of string rows okay that's what it
is
um okay run
it yeah that's what you
want so now you just do a regular
expression just check
if uh yeah so you you just do a regular
expression you check so first of all
remember this is a canonical form so
every time you got you know we we begin
with this bunch of thing we turn it into
into this then we can do the check we
can find all the
xas okay yeah so so now regular
expression okay regular
expression uh
so uh string cases I
believe uh by the way uh overlap also
count remember
okay string cases let's see let's see
your example
uh let's just say x
must is it possible to overlap with that
word no xas no so so xus is just
xas if you only check for left to right
it's not possible to
overlap that will occur only if your
word contains let's
say the word has repeated letters let's
say x ma a then it's possible to overlap
so okay so string cases so string cases
take a string
uh let's say XM
tce uh yeah and then you use a regular
expression in this case
XM okay evaluate the
line right so it give you two count then
you just say
count uh uh just say length okay
uh actually string can you count
directly yep you can count directly
without you know get the cases first yes
okay so you can actually count directly
let's put this there so people
understand now I just return two
fantastic
okay so this is one row so but now you
have uh you you just need to um do this
to all
rows so you
map you map a function
to to this list of rows and uh you do
string count
okay apply map the function to that then
you just total
it okay and what we got yeah so can we
evaluate the whole thing yes so that
will give
you uh okay something is wrong oh it
requires two arcs yeah that's right so
you write a function string count and uh
here's a string and you want to count
Xmas
evaluate uh
zero uh zero is not what we
want and
[Music]
see evaluate all
output
uh string count so why is it
um let's see what is the
output list of rows okay so did we uh
what list of string
rows
what what is the value of
that yeah
it why is it zero okay I don't
know uh
uh
okay SE search for
xus so there is three Occurrence at
least okay so
actually let's highlight all the words
xmus okay so that fantastic editor
feature
um hello guys hello guys SOA hello guys
say
hi so it
occurred it occurred that many times so
what why is our
function not working because of the
capitalization I
assume
yeah you know let's try
that fantastic capitalization
issue uh yeah yeah okay
so yeah so let's just capitalize them
all
uh in fact let's just
um find and replace so that we
is okay
right then just total
okay so this is left to right there are
total of three occurrences okay then you
want to reverse okay so reverse the
rows
um so you want to map it again but
before you but you need to reverse the
string
reverse uh actually
string reverse there it is
okay so now you get
reverse two okay so let's say three
here then two
here okay so we you know so we let's see
um so what is reverse is s MX okay let's
try to highlight
it s a am
X
Sam pink okay two
occurrences nice
highlighting okay so that is the that is
all the horizontal a total of
five okay now we need to clean up the
function so then we can apply to the you
know the other directions okay now clean
up the function so
uh so uh okay
so yeah so let's clean up the function
so let's write the function
let's say horizontal did I spell that
right
horizontal horizontal stupid English
okay let's so we got we're going to
write this
function equals to a function and this
function will
[Music]
be so the function takes a matrix the x
is a matrix let's say Matrix okay and
what will the body do the body will be
something like that that uh in fact
more uh let's
see so total of that and total of that
and this of string rows so that's a
canonical form we want to feed to our
function
so uh so let's not say Matrix so this is
the this of string forms is our function
parameter okay
so so that just
plus that
okay you just plus
them that will
count you know in One Direction and
reverse okay
so that is our function and can we try
it yes so let's just try add X list of
rows so that should
work now let's double check where does
this definition okay so let's remove um
list of string
rows you it's defined
there yeah so yeah
so so you don't need that and
uh in fact move this here so it's easy
to
[Music]
see right now this is a scratch
Pad showing how it works
okay so we got the this is a matrix then
uh this is string join we don't
need uh string
join yeah okay we don't need so this is
L of string rowes which comes in this
form then then we can do string cases
and string count and we use string count
to
yeah
so yeah we don't need that yeah so now
we can try these substring rows let's
double check yeah it's
there
yes okay
okaye it should be five five correct
okay so this is our uh function now
now let's check
so horizontal equals to this
result uh vertical equals
to uh let's say total okay let's just
say
Clarity we are doing Clarity here okay
so so um so you need vertical you need
transpose okay so let's
see uh let's
see so we're going to
do uh actually not this okay so the
horizontal let you know we let's do this
manually
okay so the horizontal will be we you
know the input will be the
Matrix yeah there so you give a matrix
then you
um you know that that's the then you
join the strings then it's just a list
of strings okay it's total then vertical
total is going to
be uh the vertical total is going to be
same thing kind of the same
thing EX
except except you're going to transpose
The
Matrix
okay then
it three
fantastic um to show shall we check you
know like uh it's it's not so what about
diagonal now the
diagonal the
diagonal
uh horizontal vertical there are two
diagonals so you need a term to
distinguish so can we say slash and back
slash slash
slash and back slash actually di
actually um so
this so the backs slash direction is
properly properly called diagonal in
math okay now what about the other
diagonal what's the proper term for
that I don't know I is there a proper
term for that may maybe uh but I don't
no so but anyway diagonal means left top
left to bottom
right in math okay so diagonal total
will
be uh will be you just so you use the
diagonal function we have the
documentation here diagonal
matrix
you okay this needs some
work
so t Matrix takes two arguments the
first one is a
matrix then you need to get all the
diagonal
so so let's see we understand before so
zero so first of all you need to
know the the size of the matrix
dimensions
okay dimensions of the Matrix which is
is the row count then the column
count row and column so let's see let me
just think about this so
row row minus one okay so actually let
me just do it
range
row count minus one
to uh to the column count my uh to the
column count minus one
okay I like to name my variables
beginning with x okay so and the the row
count in
um dimensions of the Matrix okay that
gives you Row in column
okay let's see
okay it's it's um
so that's a
dimension
then first
okay second okay and what will this give
you
is for example if it's 3x three Matrix
it will give
you -2 - 1 0 1
2 uh let's run
it okay you you need to define the
Matrix okay run the whole
thing okay we got some syntax
wrong um comment that out
uh we don't know what is is yet okay so
let's
just let's just do
that
what comma encountered where where the
[ __ ] comma
encountered oh yeah this extra comma
wait wait we got it wrong
what what this is
wrong yeah this is entirely [ __ ]
up and we have to rewrite this again I'm
afraid
so there is our
Dimension then
um
then then then you di then you just do
this Dimension first okay
minus one okay then Dimension second
part minus one
then
range okay range of these two numbers
okay yeah so running
n no n is not
correct what what what what is going on
yeah let's let's use variables
okay variables make everything clear
[ __ ] this taking a
while uh this is row row count column
count
then then this range
this just
[Music]
be now it's
simpler remember you need to minus one
okay wait what what what what n
show all
results oh yeah you forgot to negative
it the row
count three 3 minus one then you just
say
negative you need to negative it yeah so
so negative is what negate
let's say negative3 let's run this line
let's see if that gives you uh
no is is there a
negate
uh what what what is the math term to
reverse
sign I
forgot so let's look up the
documentation it will tell
you negative true gives true if x is a
negative number okay so uh non positive
real sign simplify real
sign negation we want some we we want
the negation we all uh oh yeah we can
just put a minus in
front wait wait wait wait that that that
that that that that that that
that okay do it
again
beautiful now we have a 9 by9 Matrix is
that right beautiful okay so we can see
this is the output
beautiful now so what so what are we
doing uh so so but we are doing the
diagonal part so the diagonal part
let's let's do it
here vertical and horizontal is easy
here is a diagonal part so diagonal part
we need to get the diagonal matrix but
the diagonal matrix each time it just
take one so that's why you need this
range thing to get them
all um
is there way you know I want the them in
one shot easier way just to get the all
the diagonal um in one
shot uh actually this is not diagonal
matrix it should be
diagonal that
diagonal uh gives the list of elements
on the leading diagonal okay then
diagonal matrix and K gives the elements
on the K diagonal
okay uh works even m is not a square
Matrix yes uh if the K is positive
diagonal gives the diagonals above the
leading diagonal that's
right yeah but easier way to just like
get all the diagonal um like in one shot
without yeah I don't know
maybe that's too much to ask let's just
do it manually okay so you want to do it
manually you just put K here and you
just say table table is like
Python's least comprehension one idiotic
python jargon you know this these people
Python and others they think they know
math oh list comprehension which is in
fact the most idiotic
[ __ ] okay so you you you use a table now
you just say k from uh K is just from
that to that
okay so
okay let's just say kk So to avoid my
abbreviation
expansion uh
yeah that will do so
actually can we run it yes
um so you can
see this is how it works okay so give
the uh you know get the diagonal and K
and generate all of
them by this range
um
minute okay so we got the output copy it
and let's
see fantastic
beautiful we got a Christmas
tree oh oh God this fantastic so we need
to check did we is our diagonal properly
done so how how does it begin so begin
from the bottom so yeah yeah so you got
M you got mx then you got Sam then you
got Sam X that's right then all the way
then the leading diagonal is Ms
XM
a m s x m a that's correct then then the
top one the top right corner is M again
and S say
correct fantastic and
beautiful uh okay so we got all the
diagonals yeah all diagonals okay so
this is all
diagonals okay but um okay yeah we got
that that's beautiful and but uh then
you just
apply apply the same
algorithm to um you see
okay so let's let's let's abuse
variables let's just name them all all
diagonals equals to
that uh then you just count them by map
you don't need transpose you just need
uh do it all
diagonals string join correct then count
horizontal vertical diagonal let's see
five is that correct you know so let's
say xma you know there five occurrences
it's hard
to see from here but we could if we want
to
by by
by by just running this line yeah let's
try oh no but we don't have the variable
okay
but it says five okay
so run
it yeah it says five
okay uh and wait uh this is not vertical
okay so this is diagonal
okay horizontal vertical okay so this
needs to be
renamed
uh d a
g okay and what about reverse
diagonal it's the same thing except
except we just add a transpose function
here uh we just add a transpose
function there okay
so there and uh there
uh okay God this is tedious I'm already
almost an hour what the
[ __ ] blue hour says hi enjoy your
content hope to see more math videos and
live stream thank
you I find the different graph showed
very fascinating also tiing oh yeah
those are very the most fun topics hello
Hank uh
happy happy holidays Merry Christmas
Hank so
now so we got the diagonal but this code
needs to be uh compacted okay because
you can see the variables are used
several places
uh so what how shall we approach
um yeah let's let's compact this code so
that so that it becomes one single
function okay so let's do let's
begin
so count
it's a function okay equals to a
function okay now the function we are
taking a matrix okay X Matrix okay then
what does it
do it
will let's let's let's start to move in
so first of all with a width function
okay width function is
a it's a local variable okay it's like
lisl uh should I use width or uh let's
see uh width you know this width is is
like lisps let or JavaScript let it
declares local variables but both module
and width but however with width it's a
constant so once you define it you
cannot change it which is great for
functional programming however it's got
a problem because once you define a
variable you cannot Define the next
variable in terms of the previous one
like we need here you know we get a
dimension then we get you get Ro count
based on the dimension you cannot do
that
because so then so what you have to do
is you declare another width so that
it's not good so in another way is just
use module module is just like let but
you
can you can you can redefine the Val
okay let's use module okay let's not get
to so cut that put here okay in fact put
the definition here and uh
let's let's just have variables here
okay
so you got three variables then you
define each them individually in a
body you got Matrix size row count
column count then you got uh range uh
okay X range you need a
range okay the range will
[Music]
be that okay
semicolon to suppress the output okay
then okay then
you then you get all diagonals and then
count okay so we don't need this section
let's copy
that let's
see then you
just uh you have to call count
horizontal so
so all diagonals okay so let's just put
it here for clarity of
code okay then then you call this
function then it's total you don't need
that it just return the last expression
like
thisp okay so here is our function and
we can try it by
at X Matrix because we defined the
Matrix
there okay so go back here
minute what was the number three or five
okay there are five
okay then then you if you want to count
the other position of diagonal just say
transpose and not Translate
transpose
okay five
what is it also five
Jesus yeah you know this diagonal it's
hard to
debug because you cannot
uh you know so this is our
function let's
like go to w f notepad paste it it it
make it more clear you
see copy it then you can just paste here
somewhat somewhat clean
with
indentation
you yeah
okay but
um let let's double check
okay so you got the dimension you got
the row
count
Dimension raw count
column count then you get the range of
values then you get all the diagonals by
calling a table diagonal KK KK goes from
this range oh this is repeated
so this just X range
okay okay then so you got all the
diagonals then you just count horizontal
pass the value all diagonals turn them
into string turn each row into a
string then you
count
yeah is that is
that right yeah does that make sense
yeah so if
you count diagonals with the Matrix you
get
get you see this count horizontal counts
both directions okay so you can
see the count horizontal counts in both
directions you
see because we did a string reverse
there
uh it
[Music]
counts actually we don't you know
another trick is instead of you know we
just can instead of reverse the string
we just reverse the
XY yeah let's do that that's
actually
SX that's actually more efficient
yeah s MX
okay okay
[Music]
so yeah so the count horizontal is the
core function okay and you you feed it
um yeah so horizontal total is Count
horizontal string join and give it the
Matrix con vertical is
you transpose then string joint then
count horizontal then wait then
yeah then for diagonal
it's what
what uh let's see
let's
[Music]
see that should be
it but what about um
so diagonal total equals to
that what is the word for the other
diagonal of the
Matrix transverse diagonal Maybe
can you uh am I still doing good check
video
warning uh stream Health
good part one or two part one man I'm
still stuck on part
one it's getting
more difficult and more difficult
see okay it's called anti- Diagon
mathematics
fantastic you see normally top left to
bottom right is
diagonal but the other diagonal is
called anti- diagonal fantastic so let's
name it here you know the proper
terminology helps you a lot because when
you read the word you you know you you
you get the proper thinking about it so
that's why terminology is of great
importance
okay so diagonal total is that then uh
then what is
this then you want uh anti diagonal
total
okay which
is
that is that right because when you
transmit you have to think about
it when you transpose The Matrix so
normally you want
that when you transpose yeah yeah that's
right yes that's right so it so happens
it's also
five evaluated let's
see it so happens it's also five okay so
let's tab let's show all
results five and five and and uh what
five and
uh I don't know so I mean so
let's Okay so that's our code supposely
we give uh
that
wait let's do this let's add them
together
okay so
diagonal
total
plus
plus anti anti- diagonal
total plus vertical total in horizontal
total
okay 18 I think that's
right
check 18 times fantastic
beautiful okay so this is a scratch Pad
we got we got get
done fantastic now put back in um in the
browser syntax Cate showing browser this
is our today's code this is a scratch
Pad now let's make this beautiful let's
now let's actually make this beautiful
okay so don't worry about
algorithm and
uh and where is this input used okay so
this input let's clean
up you don't need
that okay so you don't need that uh list
of
rows list of strings okay list of
strings um actually change your name
list of strings yeah you can change name
just Le of
strings
okay so uh list of strings uh do you
need the Matrix do you need the Matrix
defined we are trying to reduce
variables here
so to make them all a function so it
becomes 18 okay string cases we don't
need string count we don't need
total uh what is this total
total three yeah we don't
need we don't need horizontal total
yeah count horizontal this is important
function okay this is a important
function and uh and instead of list of
strings
[Music]
we okay let's not worry about it so
least of
strings uh then count
horizontal okay so that is important
function and uh do we need
this this is important list of strings
we don't need
no okay so count horizontal is important
function remove that so this horizontal
total and uh wait how horizontal total
vertical total
then uh then we don't need this whole
thing
the then count
diagonal we
need okay so count diagonal
yeah so we can this is a function let's
put the function
here this is a function okay so con
diagonal is a function we got con
horizontal function con diagonal
function then you just count them so you
got horizontal vertical
diagonal and anti diagonal so you got
these four values
okay then you just add them evaluate
it beautiful okay so the code is just
this okay
now now you want to uh try your your
personal input so let's see get your
personal input okay so let's now we go
to um let's
save Advent of
code
Advent okay make a
[Music]
copy uh and this is State
four day for input open it delete it go
back
here copy it back to emac
paste
what did we copy it
copy
paste
what yeah paste okay so anyway so here
is
the
good save it close open it close copy
the file path
close
close and uh back to the
code right close back to the code now we
just need to read this file path
okay
uh read string I believe
yep so X input equals to read
string
of this
file
okay
now run
that
2647 okay suppose this is uh
answer for personal
input are you sure yeah I'm sure let's
submit that's not the right answer your
answer is too high
Jesus ah
[ __ ] still part of they what [ __ ] it
it's it's it's now 80 minutes almost
yeah 80 minutes you know people finish
this in two minutes those [ __ ] speed
coders
uh
God what is this
did we miss something
God uh I'm not
[Music]
happy I don't know what to do I'm not
happy no
because because then we're going to two
two concurrent viewers okay fantastic
nobody's
watching is see now we need to
um debug the code you see it's
not apparent to me where we went wrong
that's the
issue because then I need to debug the
code that just means like starting all
over and and and this is even just part
one
did I miss something is there some like
Fast trick wait did I get the input
correct you know the last thing you want
is your input is
wrong let's see get your puzal input
okay now
copy copy
new new page
copy
140 should be
right save
it hey we are not
nobody what I forgot what does that
refer to
oh oh the people the number of people
watching
so so the input there is our input let's
double check yeah you got the input
right you know this bunch of
thing Rend the
code it says no okay so remove that run
the
code
shift tab a to show
everything you see this is
a
process
2647 now what the [ __ ]
now is there some like implicit
multiplication you know let's just it's
just be sure there's no implicit
multiplication going
on what the
right 26 47 26 6
47 okay I think you see I think the
diagonal is wrong because they are equal
you know there's something fishy
okay the diagonal is wrong
transpose you have to think about the
diagonal okay input is correct now we
are in the debugging
stage input should be 140 * 140 okay so
um so thank you
yeah 140 that's
right yeah 140 by 140 did you did you
finish the
problem n
Berry uh by the way where you from
do do do I
like uh are you
Chinese because I was thinking maybe you
are one of my friends I know
okay our input is correct yeah [ __ ] I
want to finish this and uh we it's only
part one [ __ ]
it oh you don't want to transpose but
mirror in so let's think about this
again
yeah you have to think
I don't want to
think
um great tip
thanks but okay so let's
see normally it's diagonal so when it's
diagonal you take it that
way but so what happen when you
transpose oh that's right
transposition doesn't change nothing
because transposition just flip it on
the on the diagonal you know it doesn't
that's why the answer is the same that's
why we so we got we got a logical error
that is our error that is not you know
it's not a bug or something it's
our logic
error so we don't want transer we you
know to be honest we haven't thought
about it through you know we are just
like oh transpose will do
it okay so logical error so you cannot
do transpose because so what you want is
rotate
actually fantastic so is there a rotate
Matrix thing in wolam language I think
so this is the beauty of wolam language
you just search
for uh uh question mark how do you typee
question mark okay
Asterix rotate what you want is rotate
Matrix okay shift
enter image rotate rotate left rotate
right string rotate left what does that
mean string rotate left okay it
just
um rotate
represents a uh 2D Graphics primitive
okay that's about Graphics which is
fantastic wait how how is it different
from
transpose that's right transpose just
what
uh I'm pretty sure there is a function
for it but
um something about Matrix okay now you
got
like tens
of oh God you got tens of functions
about Matrix
let's think about this
transpose yeah [ __ ] you you really you
know what you really want to do is
actually just draw it without you
know because I was trying to avoid doing
this because
because this is taking time so if you
have a b
c one 2
three so when you do a transpose you
got a 1 2 3 A B C okay now let's think
about diagonal okay so uh if you think
about diagonal
you know so you got that and
here so if you think about diagonal you
see you got 1 a 2 B3 C same thing 1 a 2
B3
C so transpose is not the right answer
um but what you want
is you want some kind
of uh you know you mention flipped
mirror that's probably the
answer oh so if you want to do miror
that's so trivial you just reverse each
Matrix row so
yeah so we can we don't have to think
about this anymore
like you know we you just reverse each
row reverse the order of columns yeah
that that will work but you can easily
reverse just by map right so then yeah
let's get it to work okay let's just
so we got count diagonal then we got
anti- diagonal so it's not transpose so
you know in so we just fix this line so
instead of transpose we just
map map
um
map map a
function uh what that function is going
to be function just reverse okay
reverse let's say one
3 that that's right so all you have to
do is apply the reverse to each row uh
but you are probably right there's a
function you know but you know but I not
from so I mean I know this so we can do
this
yep so remove that so now EV about the
whole
thing
wait common that
out uh wait let's put that EV the whole
thing yeah well
what H let's put this
here EV the whole
thing
2633 fantastic
okay so I think the new answer this is
the new answer 2 three
2633 oh God
enter that's the right answer you are
one gold star thank
you and thank you
nber so okay so now we are uh going to
do part two should I continue it's 90
minutes uh you
know I want so let's do some clean up
you know so you don't need that
um actually remove that
actually
uh let's just do some clean
up toy input
is 18 and the personal input is run it
again that's right to yeah okay so now
this is our code let's put it back color
it show theow showing
browser okay uh scratch Pad then the
real code it's a bit long but uh it can
be shortened into one single line yes
and can be made a lot more efficient but
anyway so part
two uh should I continue I don't know if
it's easy you know let's
see the elf looks critically at you did
you misunderstood uh understand the
assignment no you [ __ ] yourself just I
just helped you looking for the
instructions you flipped over the word
each search to find that this isn't
actually an xus puzzle it's an X stashus
puzzle in which you are supposed to find
two masas in the shape of an
X oh
Jesus m a s m a
s okay one way to achieve that is like
this oh Jesus the nature of the puz
changed
ah [ __ ] irrelevant characters have again
been replaced with a dot in the above
diagram within the X each Mass can be
written forwards or backwards okay so
you need to find a cross here's the same
example from before but this time all of
the
xmes have been kept instead
okay so in this example xmass appears
nine times what the
[ __ ] wait
[Music]
so so it's not just horizontal so if you
have a
horizontal or a diagonal or a vertical
it doesn't count
okay actually you can forget about
horizontal and vertical you only care
about
diagonals you only care about diagonals
and
also there's a condition they must have
the
same center that is they share the
letter A that is forming across so
one course count as one not
two so let's double
check that's
one uh you know this is actually is it
easier if you show this what kind of
font are they
using actually it's easier in emx
so you got
one two
m
4 five 6 7 8 what nine times okay
actually
nine
one two
[Music]
three
5 6
78 okay there's one here so let's do it
again
one two
[Music]
three
4 five 6 7 8 9 5 6 7 8 9
so yeah okay
so I understand the
problem but
um but the L arithm
is kind of entirely
different okay because this part
two yeah yeah the the approach will be
entirely
different this is State four it's
getting difficult
already what do you guys think
yeah
so I think I close shut down this video
maybe we'll continue tonight tonight at
6:00 California
time which is
uh four more hours in four and a half
hours we'll do the part
two okay so let me think about this
again so yeah you need to find the
course so it's it is
truly entirely different
algorithm so you have to think about
that a
fresh you know it would be nice to have
some kind of pattern
matching uh algorithm yeah it's it's
entirely different okay that yeah that's
it so in summary
we did part
one and here is a
solution uh and part two will be 6:00
p.m. California time okay thank you guys
for watching that's it for today if you
have
um oh 20 minutes good for you fantastic
good work okay so yeah so bye guys if
you guys you can join s Discord you can
find
the um you can find the invitation link
ons.info
okay bye guys