good morning everyone good morning
everyone
good morning everyone so I'm alive
welcome to Santa Show today is May 24th
2019 and I'm drinking I'm 10 minutes
late I'm drinking let me show you this
so this is fresh juice this is banana
kiwi orange strawberry this is luxury
and this is energy drink just like Red
Bull but cheaper cheap is the definition
of it but actually I like it better than
Red Bull and you know and so cheers this
is fresh juice I'm kind of late today
for 10 minutes but there is one thing
going on which I like to say that is
about yesterday in my talk show there is
a incident let's go and I'm going to
talk about today JavaScript the Unicode
drun okay eunuch Unicode runic okay this
is a fantastic thing the you the runic
script okay and I'm going to show you
actually here good morning everyone
pasted into Unicode run script so you
can you can translate and you can you
can see these are run scripts so but
yesterday there is the incident yeah
there's an incident you know I'm doing
him acts a talk show and I was talking
about Casa Gong it wait kar Benjamin
also known as Sargon of Akkad now he's a
famous YouTube controversial because of
the gamergate that's how he became
popular so yesterday I was talking about
that topic that ends up me deleting the
live stream now the issue is is okay I'm
talking when you are talking about
political since sensitive topic then you
know I'm doing live stream then someone
your friend your followers okay there's
a guide Danielle
okay so he you know so someone you know
made comments they disagree and they
make comments about it you know this is
a political political topic the thing
about this is that you know they make a
comment then inevitably there will be
lots of words in the live stream and you
know he make a comment and other people
may also make a comment and it ends up
the the comments will contain lots of
taboo words meaning that words that
Google use you know Google see those
words they will bang your channel they
they will you know give you a strike
then they will kick you up you know this
censorship coming up so anyway I was
talking you know you are talking about
political topic and someone disagree
then you know almost inevitably a bunch
of words like you know I don't want to
mention them a bunch of these political
sensitive words they they will be
mentioned because these words because
they are part of the topic you cannot
talk about you know let's say terrorism
or bomb okay you can you know when
there's news about you know that you
have to you know it would be hard to
talk about that without those words you
know so in a same way there are many
other words regarding you know today's
political situation you know
so you know when I was talking about
that and someone disagree and those
words come up then what you're gonna do
normally there's no problem okay I love
to debate you know so
oh so you disagree let's see why you
know so why do you disagree and we can
use all words you want you know
including [ __ ] you know that you know
this is called this is this is this is
what free speech means offensive you
know the essence the essential meaning
of free speech is offensiveness because
if the if there if that element does not
exist
you don't need free CV speech you know
everyone is happy you know happy speech
you know pleasing speech ass-kissing
speech so essence that the defining
quality of the of the free speech
concept is offensiveness okay so anyway
the issue is you know I'm I was talking
you know about some political topics
costigan you see and if someone disagree
and quickly you know because cars are
gone you know quickly there's this bunch
of words that Google sees we as we open
you so I have so I have a problem so
what am I going to do nobody it's fine
okay normally I just you know let's talk
about it you know you disagree you know
it's let's discuss but because Google
you know because this censorship is
going on I cannot just talk about it
because I can I talk about it then
Google see those words in my stream they
you know I get banned
so that is the problem this is
essentially that is a problem that
happened yesterday and you know
yesterday you know all those words in my
live stream and you know like when you
talk about you know today so this is
really bad
you know today's political situation you
know I I blame the social justice scan
okay the social justice people so you
know this this is the issue Google is
you know this widespread censorship or
going on on Twitter on YouTube on
Facebook you know
it's it's upheaval you know political
upheaval and it's creating instability
in countries in USA in UK in Australia
you know it C is creating instabilities
instabilities means war civil war okay
you're gonna so so why does this Google
Google censorship begin you know where
are they starting to censor you know you
it used to be USA is the most you know
freedom of speech is the obsession of
every American you know we don't every
every topic whenever we talk about some
topic immediately someone will mention
you know free speech and everyone is
good you know that that was the
situation but today is somewhat you know
it's almost like made a 180-degree turn
you know they are the this is like you
know the political party they are saying
no you cannot you know this free speech
is not not allowed you know they have
you know it's hard to imagine you know
this is happening so anyway so you so
you know Google and and in censorship
you know when you look at Wikipedia okay
let's go to Wikipedia Wikipedia
censorship yeah
so that's such for you know I was amazed
I was amazed went about two years ago
2006 or 2017 2016 or 17
you know I check Wikipedia I check you
know I have like I have like eight
thousand links to Wikipedia for my
website I read it you know I read
Wikipedia for like two hours a day for
the past 10 15 years so anyway some
articles I check regularly like every
two years or so censorship article is
one of the article I check you know now
and then
so you see here is a picture of David
you know that you know that he stick his
saying you know since you used that this
kind of censorship used to be it's
typically Mary
it used to be common by the God
believers use us conserve conservatives
okay but this is then not today is
something different well anyway I want I
want to let's get back to the topic
about there is a map of censorship that
shows which country is being censored
today huh okay oh they changed oh my god
okay so this is this is this a change
here you see so in this map you know
China is big censorship you know and
pink Russia is you know some censorship
queen is no Queens no censorship and
yellow is kind of a slice and shift
someone changed this you know back in
2007 we can actually go to 2017
Wikipedia article but anyway my point is
I was surprised to see this map that
well since USA becomes kind of like pink
if I recall correctly like heavy
censorship and I think that is true but
but now they changed it again and I
think that's that's basically just the
the doings of a social justice people
you know they they they they you know
they are trying to do fake news and lie
and stuff so anyway you know good
censorship is going on like over like I
can't I cannot you know say certain
words you know Google is gonna pay me
right right now so anyway there's this
incident you know so why does censorship
happen because in my opinion because of
the social justice can okay they are
changing the USA you know the this this
great country I would say they are
changing it so that it's become you know
it's become very stable unstable and the
in fact China you know technology
engineering they are like almost like
taking over
no progress in USA but in you anyway
that's that that is my opinion that's
what I see and this is you know you
human
oh may not agree but this is like
critical issue so about this census so
in my opinion it's because the social
justice can people okay so yesterday I
was talking about car saga he's the one
he's one of those people who are again
his social justice but then this this
guy is kind of my acquaintance or
borderline acquaintance and friend okay
I don't really know him
you know maybe you Daniel you are
watching now I'm gonna talk about the
whole situation you know
so anyway III you know he's you know he
follows me since about four months ago
and you know a great guy you know of a
friend you know almost a friend except
I've never met him and I only know him
for like because you know for four
months and he contributed to Microsoft
like he's and he's using virág and using
Safari keys so it's great it's going to
be great friendship except yesterday he
and and the day before you know in the
past week he when I talk about Sargon
Akkad he expressed a he disagree okay
but he then he expressed opinions that
you know reasons for his this
disagreement and the way you know the
way I see it you know just a few
sentences IIIi cannot possibly agree
okay
you see politics often cuts friendship
you know this is serious phenomenon
politics political issues cuts family
ties cuts friendship and when civil war
happens you know there are civil wars
there are civil wars in China they are
civil civil wars in USA when civil war
happens you not just cut your friend
used you stop each other with you know
with your you know you
family your brothers your sister that's
gonna you gonna you know when we Civil
War comes we each person are forced to
do that you have to you know when that
when symbol what happens you are forced
to because it's kind of like you have to
choose a side or you die you know you
know it's kind of like that so anyway so
he he he just disagree about my opinion
about sargon of akkad and he made you
know he gave his reasons but those you
know just only a few sentences you know
online hold on a second let me close the
window so there's a garbage truck coming
in by making a lot of noises so so I'm
saying you know the civil war is
something very bad you don't want it you
know you don't want to it to happen you
don't want your country to be
politically unstable you know that that
is the thing so anyway he made a comment
and in his reason about salgaonkar
I cannot possibly agree okay you know
it's such a statement I cannot possibly
agree so you know normally I would say
no I did disagree and you know ask what
do you think that and talk about that
but I cannot because censorship because
you know he seek he gave some reasons
with these words you know google see
that those was he you know he's going
coogo is going to by my channel so what
am I gonna do i well I disagree so I I'm
you know nobody are just asking why and
this talk you know that's what talk is
about discussion o debate oh you know
and know so this is a talk show so we
talk talk but I cannot talk and because
this topic you have to you know
those words are part of the topic that
is the it's not like you can just use
some other words okay those does you
know social justice kind of things you
know they have a bunch of things you
know so like you know so that that is
kind of the problem you know so someone
disagrees who is like a friend okay and
and I and I disagree so but but but this
is a very sensitive topic and Google is
like looming over you know he's like any
moment he you know I'm gonna be banned
all right you know I I don't want to be
banned right now so anyway so the
problems that that that is the problem
so what am I supposed to do so I was
thinking you know I don't know you know
basically in general I I'm not sure what
to do about that
okay for example there are a few you
know the options for example one option
is I don't care okay you know he you
know somewhat disagree with my opinion
about some political issues I you know
pretend there's no censorship by Google
I just keep talking oh why is that oh oh
you you think that no no that that is
actually wrong because you know let me
show you this article you know which we
talked about it
then tomorrow Google been banned me
that's okay you know that's one of the
options if I don't care about Google
banning me but you know but but I'm
running Google Ads that's how I survive
I'm making $1,000 a month okay that that
is my full income you know that that you
know if you go wash dishes in a
restaurant you know you go mop floors at
McDonald's you make like three thousand
four thousand dollars a month I'm making
one thousand dollars a month so I'm on
the survival situation and how I survive
is because Google ads you know ads from
Google so if Google bad me that's that's
not going to be good okay that's that's
a problem so
I cannot just take you know like normal
people and you know treat like
pretending that Google you know you
depending does not happen you know so I
cannot do that so what are the other
option you know maybe I'm thinking you
know you think that let's show my UNIX
screen so so the other up you know the
other option is that you look at all the
YouTube youtubers you know there are
many famous ones there's Joe Rogan there
is of course Jordan Pederson
there's Camille Paglia okay there is
looping report Dave Reuben Reuben report
there's team pool or team cast you know
these are famous YouTube stars you know
they each one have I think each one has
a medium follower so close and and their
viewership is actually more than CNN CNN
is falling apart in this fake news CA by
the social just justice can [ __ ] heads
okay
CNN is falling apart they have actually
less viewers than Tim for you know just
like in a person movie before news on
YouTube anyway so you look at these
YouTube channels
you know Tim pool Joe Rogan tape you
being Jordan Pederson of course Camille
Paglia
and quite a lot you know quite a lot and
and in sargon of akkad you know the car
benjamin guy and shoe are head and you
know many speaking against the social
justice can this lying scumbags you know
typically they are very rich you know
they are celebrity so head of Google
Facebook you know or on the other hand
some of them are very poor they are like
pawns like the antiva they are homeless
you know and you know they are unhappy
and they they do violence on the street
for for the social just weak peak you
know the soldier justice tenets their
theories so anyway you look at this
youtubers you see you look at them what
they do you know first first of all of
course
any of them they don't get monetized now
YouTube has this monitor monetization
thing that is why all these people on
YouTube you know with our monetization
they wouldn't be doing much of what they
do they you know some of them I still do
it but it's because money they you know
they really put effort and you know grow
their audience by anyway all these
people so you look at them first of all
there's a monetization issue a lot of
them you can you cannot like even report
news like there's a bombing happened or
there's some I don't want to say the
word okay news you know news people get
people getting you know hurt you you go
to youtube if you are a journalist you
report it bad you got to monetize
you know because why because the social
justice can Fox they are controlling
they are lying and controlling this
information okay now if I'm going to die
because of the social tea because I
speak herbs again is the social justice
issue that's fine okay now let's get
back so I look at those so first of all
there's a D monetization issue which I'm
not making any money on YouTube why
because about two years ago Google again
because of a social justice Google they
eliminated any people who doesn't have
like 1000 followers you know they they
kicked out all you know those people
like in order to have you know to make
money on YouTube you now you have to
have at least 1000 followers or you you
must have you know the watch time of
your videos must exceed certain number
you know so you know so Google sent me
an email
okay sorry so recently we made you know
they send this to everyone this happened
about a year or two ago so they don't
they don't let anyone you know small
people that is make videos make
they you know only when you are big they
they do they let you make money anyway
so I don't you know i don't have
monetization on YouTube and I guess I
you know I I don't think I'm you know
you know I'm not hoping for that so
first of all I don't have monetization
on YouTube so that you know the
monetization doesn't matter to me for
now okay okay so but then you look at
this famous youtubers besides the
monitor demanded transition some of them
you know the yes they get they get
banned you know not not well not bad you
know YouTube has this since maybe a few
years ago strike system like you get a
strike you cannot do like livestream
anymore because you know if you talked
about some of these sensitive things and
people report you you know so so they
are the so and some people you know some
of the more extreme cases like Alex
Jones you know there's this guy Alex
Jones
infowar he is a [ __ ] okay he's a
he's a like like he said intentionally
creating this fake new this this
conspiracy theories about UFOs about
aliens okay this alex jones [ __ ] so
he got banned now he got banned that's a
big controversy because if you look at
from this free speech perspective you
know he should not be banned because
even though he talks about nonsense but
you know yeah let him talk you know you
talk to you things i talk my things you
know that people decide who is right but
anyway he got banned and
okay you aren't on YouTube a lot of
these other places Facebook and Twitter
a lot people got banned typically
conservatives including for example one
of the big in his instances is that
there is a this women this woman Megan
something okay from Canada she is as far
as I know some kind of a hardcore
feminist you know feminist feminism is
part of the social justice scan so he's
kind of the hardcore feminist but he's
anti anti the trans okay that the the
you know I I I'm starting to mention
these words you know that that these are
the words like Google is going to start
to ban you so she is anti these let's
say transformation okay let's substitute
the word she's anti transformation and
there's a word called code describe this
type of group people anyway the social
justice situation is that they they you
know they they they you know in my
opinion they are they're called what
they did they basically they just want
to [ __ ] around that that's the cool
thing you know they don't care about
anything else they want more power and
money that's what they want and they do
that to all but no means possible they
create the philosophy that what they do
their direction you know their behavior
is based on this post-modernism okay
which is kind of like the philosophy of
winning by all means possible so anyway
so big so so because they are not you
know kind of rational or logical
scientific they create this you know
what they say you know the things they
say they do is like self conflicting so
anyway the bottom line is right now they
there is a war between themselves about
you know this feminist group versus the
transformation group like you know
you know which bathroom to use and you
did but it'd be allowed or not allowed
there things like that
anyway she she got banned on Twitter
okay so so that's the thing that that
that is the thing and and a lot people
are on Twitter got banned mostly
conservatives but some of them she's not
concerned I don't think she's she's part
of the left you know so the point is
there's a lot of censorship in going on
but you YouTube I think it happens so
it's a good thing that YouTube it's not
as severe on YouTube as compared to
Facebook or Twitter but it's still it's
zero it's there so so that's what what
I'm saying so what I'm saying so back to
the previous topic so I look at this
youtubers and you know social justice is
is kind of the topic is their main topic
so you know I'd look at them what do
they do you know when when there's with
this kind of situation
mostly they you know they use this words
you know they talk you know they because
otherwise how you cannot say they you
know so you're just these issues you
know for example they are concerned
about feminism case marriage trans and
immigration and you know and you know
these these these kind of things I'd
rather not mention am bullying
harassment and and so on so they seems
to be okay
you know the for them to talk about it
although they get demonetized
you know for sure they get demonetized
but ste they are not they they are not
being banned yet okay so maybe I'm
thinking you know so there it is you
know maybe I can do that just like them
you know I okay t monetize I don't okay
I don't I'm not making money and so I
want to talk about you know car
Benjamins and there's you know social
justice things the saga of akkad I want
to talk about it if you disagree I we
can still talk about it
you know then and let's see what happens
so that's one of the option that's what
I can do yeah
so ten people watching okay so I am so
to wrap it up I think I you know I
talked about this kind of loan so this
issue about the social justice you know
my channel the reason I'm doing YouTube
videos is one as a record of myself like
a history record you know like one day
tomorrow I'll be gone any time you know
who knows I'll be going in time so when
I'm gone there's a you know this is what
sorry looks like this is what his
thoughts are you know there's a record
of it that's part of the reason the
other reason is that you know because
I'm you know I I you know I'm observing
humanity and futurology you know where
humanity human also going you know I
look at especially with respect to
technology you know because I'm a
programmer I'm a nerd so you know I
observe you know the YouTube okay
there's a YouTube this these websites
going on this AI happening
the robotics you know so I kind of
observed and one thing I observed is
that YouTube becomes video format
becomes increasingly tremendously
popular and my and also I mean
interested in from philosophical aspects
so so this is interesting because if you
look at communication between human
animals you know you have reading and
writing you know by literature you know
text you know books then you have video
video is actually the more more natural
because a lot of people actually you
know to to read and write actually takes
learning you know years think in a case
of Chinese it takes six more than six
years to learn you know write in Chinese
characters in English you know you go to
you know grade school middle school high
school
you take know six years to you know to
to be able to read you know news
journalism you know all the fancy words
but talking and speaking that that is
actually far more natural that that is
not
you know reading and writing is actually
an odd sort of artificial endeavor among
human animals it's sort of artificial
because you know if you look at
anthropology you know human history you
know in the first 10,000 years you don't
have writings you know then you started
maybe some carving you don't have
writing systems in fact a lot languages
you don't have right you don't have
writings you have talking but there's no
writing for that language you know and
then you borrow some of the you know
country's writing alphabet or writing
system for example Chinese is powered by
Japanese you know you know so so in
short we write writing and reading is
kind of kind of like this difficult
educated and esoteric kind of thing
requires learning but but talking and
looking at other people speaking you
know you watch other people that is
natural as if that is fundamental to all
animals not just human animals dogs cats
lions you know elephants they watch
other cats you know they're their king
they watch their behavior they watch
their expressions there are years there
dogs wag their tail so cats you know
what they tell us they have different
signals they have you know so what
watching and speaking you know meowing
you know that that is actually natural
so so back to YouTube so I observed you
know YouTube you know this video
technology is kind of new you know
because today due to the phone primarily
you know Allah allows everyone to make
videos and in video the format is
actually natural you know so that is the
part of the reason why there's a
tremendous tremendous growth of YouTube
not just YouTube in in China they have
for example China as China's video
platforms you know but YouTube I think
is the biggest you know worldwide is the
biggest video format video platform so
they are tremendous people watching
YouTube
and also making YouTube videos so I as a
observer you know I you know I I was a
into some way not interested in this
kind of thing and human you know future
what we're gonna be so you know so so I
think you know that's interesting you
know so I'm so that is that's this the
other reason I'm starting to make
youtube videos so I can talk to people
and you know because I'm doing
programming you know a lot of my
writings blogs about programming
tutorials Unicode you know these symbols
you know and math math symbols you know
symbology you know the oh the meaning of
the symbols or programming language
let's see
programming language tutorials or
programming language design programming
you know this this kind of thing so I
can make a video of version of them you
know I can you know teach people how to
write JavaScript or you know instead of
just instead of just my you know textual
tutorials so you know that's a good
thing and I enjoy doing them so that is
why I'm doing YouTube videos so yeah in
summary two reasons one is a record of
sorry the other reason is you know just
exploration exploration you know and
talk to people about these things
okay so let me also summarize about the
the main topic I was talking about about
how to manage the situation where when
you talk about political topics or
controversial topics that Google is
going to ban you so what am I going to
do actually I don't I don't have a video
solution but I think you know just
because just be calm you know if people
disagree with you
anyone I don't you know Daniel I don't I
don't care if you disagree that is that
is fantastic
okay that is fantastic I can see your
point of view
I don't mind you I don't easily see I
don't mind so what so so what am I gonna
do so I think what I'm going to going to
do is you know just just relax and you
know talk about it you know not try to
avoid these words that's too sensitive
and I think you know I think I should
perhaps avoid you know trying to get
angry about these social justice people
you know try to avoid you know avoid
like you know swearing at them something
something like that you know it so
instead try to try the approach of being
more let's say mellow okay you know just
okay just so about social justice I
don't think that they are right you know
I think they are just bad people you
know instead of saying oh the social
justice can the social justice [ __ ] it's
okay that's so so so I think maybe that
is what how do and I think so far if I
you know you know do that then that
would be okay for now
you know all right I hope so you know I
you know the so according to my opinion
so you know you wish you know the best
thing hope for the war
for us a for you know four other white
nations UK or you know in well actually
for the whole world you know you just
hope that let's let's say let's put it
this way you hope bad things go away you
know you hope that you know people do
not lie people do not steal people do
not you know to these things you know
things everyone would agree to be
patently bad you know and you know that
that's that's what I can you know I
guess what we can hope for you know yeah
so that that is about that social
justice thing so maybe we talk about
ruin then the the drone script
hey good morning diem how are you doing
no chatting today I was I was going on a
rant a tirade I'm not not really good
tirade but uh but anyway I was talking
about you know were you here
like all this time I was talking about
you know the incident incident yesterday
about how you know what what are you
going to do when you talk about
political topics and you know your
followers may not agree then but you
might get banned by Google you know so
what what do you do about this situation
you know that was so I was you know
talking about that on my own and you
know and other people you know because
other people all the people will be
watching you know like you know today
the social network is such that on
Twitter on Facebook you got a lot of
people following you but you don't know
you don't know almost most of the time
you don't know who they are
and you know the you know I you know it
is actually true that some of them are
your enemies you know America you you
know in American society you don't like
when you say Oh your enemy people went
nuts because they don't they typically
don't consider you know a person has
enemies you know especially today you
know they are like oh help the world my
ass you know this but anyway so so I'm
saying you know on social network you
have a lot of people you know wherever
you are on social network everything you
post is public and you you don't know
you know all the people is gonna see it
you know it's gonna go to places that
you will never imagine you know so yeah
so I'm saying you know my video and you
know so there will be a lot of people
you know I don't know who what you'll be
watching it you know today or or next
month or year after
so ago says I want to make a shirt for
myself with four run letters RT F n so
let's see what RTFM is in run so okay
let's talk about you know I'm gonna talk
maybe ten minutes about run it you know
let's see who is who might be interested
so let's see RT f RT RT F M okay so that
looks like that so so let me tell you
what run is okay actually there are a
lot of variations Deon says I heard some
of it your willingness to find a comm
perspective is admirable thank you looks
awesome man okay so so run this run
script'
okay they actually so they are used they
are used from year 150 to 1500 and they
are used for German Germanic languages
you know it's a group it's a family of
language called Germanic languages and
Germanic languages are divided two into
three groups
North Germanic West Germanic and East
Germanic so North Germanic are Danish
Norwegian Swedish Icelandic pharisee so
it's like a Scandinavia basically where
the thaw the superhero Thor came from
that's North Germanic West Germanic is
English German and Dutch so run is like
run is the writing system for English
you can say that you know that is part
of the reason I noticed a lot nerds are
fascinated by run and East Germanic is
kind of is Catholic it's it's extinct so
no language no language you know people
speak now that's you know extinct so run
is used by Germanic languages in
Germanic languages had sweet
regroups north west and east okay that's
one thing so the other thing is that
they are actually a lot variations of
the run run script so so you see these
are these are all the run characters but
actually you know there are these
different alphabets made out of run so
there's elder futhark used around year
hundred to eight hundred so this is out
of four thok then you have Englund you
then you have Anglo Saxon runs which is
basically used in England used by
English you know the Germanic people
moved to UK United Kingdom you know you
move to England and they they they
started to use you know this set called
Anglo Saxon runs let's use around for
you have four hundred to eleven hundred
then you have younger first talk runs
younger fur thugs they are there are two
variations of it one is called Long
Branch the other one is short branch you
see short branch is kind of like a
bridged you know the short and short and
the symbol you know that run the run
characters they look like you know kind
of like tree you know a tree branch so
you know so this this form is long
branch and then you have short branch
they call it short
twig then you have medieval runs which
has the most number of characters and
medieval runs is used around 1100 to
year 1500 so yeah that's runs you know
it's it's basically the writing system
for Germanic languages back then you
know but but you know you don't use runs
today because they basically run god be
praised by latin alphabets basically and
you know I read Wikipedia you know I I
don't know about this subject oh I know
it's from Wikipedia
in the past week or so - so run
disappeared because apparently because
Christian you know Christian people
moved or spread you know this Christian
people moved to Scandinavia or around
the region they spread the Latin
alphabet so run run
you know characters got replaced died
out and you know so Latin alphabet is
used instead you know which is what we
are familiar today the English ABC so
you see so there are these different run
alphabets so when you want want to write
a program that translate you know
English characters to run you have to
decide you know you have to kind of
decide you know on a table of you know
which characters map to which so I plan
to expand this application so that you
can choose you know which alphabet you
want to use you know which one of the
run of a bed out of photography and or
younger or medieval run looks awesome
it's like a writing system that was
based on placing found tricks of a
certain shape on the ground a vinta
Roman veinte what does that mean
so DeYoung are you so what's your
ancestry if I can make a head may ask
like are you so you've you know you're
your parents or parents of parents are
they from Europe are they from Germany
or are they from so in other words what
is your blood you know I I you know when
it comes to Roman and Concord you know
when it comes to like
see conviction you know the words you
use you know in the past few years I
developed thought where we should avoid
any euphemism as much as possible to
such a degree that I even started to
replace common words that's typically
not considered euphemism but we place
them by by words that small primitive
for example instead of asking you know
what's your ancestry you know ancestry
so is a word you know what it means
right like your lineage lineage family
lineage just in other words for kind of
the same thing and assess it assess
really your family lineage repress them
by what's your blood
no because you what white blood because
that is actually the more primitive
world that would you know people
understand back then you know to two
thousand years ago or more because that
is the real that match the the nature
you know the fundamental that you know
the part of human animal but as a
civilization so-called civilization as
industrial industrialization you know
modern society things gets more and more
complicated and complex like you know
today you eat you know you don't know
how your food came from you know you eat
you eat meat you know you eat cow beef
beef you know you eat cow basically you
eat pigs you know you kill you you go
out kill the pig you know blood dripping
you kill it then then you cut it up you
know and then you eat that's what bacon
is you know hamburger that's everyone
does everyday but you know a society
gets more complex we with we don't know
we forgot you like you go to hamburger
how is hamburger
made you like you don't know have you
seen how is pinky owed no I've never
seen is a big kid do you can you can you
can you cure a pig no and and even when
you say Keo a pig or Q a cow people get
like what what are you talking about you
know like like people don't don't know
what what that means they people think
that's maybe that's offensive you know
this is something like you know but
that's what you are doing that everyday
you know you have not just you have
massive slaughterhouse you know automate
it kill it Q by how many one thousand a
day no 10,000 a day no hundred thousand
a day yeah probably more you know just
in USA you know that's that that's
that's what it is you know so I like to
you know I like to stick to truth and
you know whatever is the real thing you
know so that that's kind of that's so I
kind of started to do this to me you
know you might say experiment with these
wording and phrases you know in language
so anyway so I think maybe that's it
about it today so we have so this
censorship yeah so I'm kind of sad so
apparently this map get got changed by
you know by by certain people of
yeah yeah I was actually yesterday I was
watching a video where there this there
is this woman who is a expert on
detecting lies like you look at the
person you know you're talking to
whatever your friends your family you
know you're you know co-workers if they
lie you'll be able to tell you know
you'll be able to tell by the way by you
know by observing their facial
expressions by looking at you know
noticing some kind of pattern muscle
movement you know and supposedly that's
a trend yeah supposedly you can actually
do that and oh and also it is actually
true that there are a lot of
psychologists you know there are a lot
scientific studies about how to detect
life and much of that I think it's
reasonable it's true but anyway let me
show you the YouTube video detect lie
let's see detect lies body language it
was a tech TED talk yeah uh-huh I think
that's her but it's a different video
no that's not her I was watching another
person
her how to spot a liar thumb
Pamela Mayer and she has a Wikipedia
entry so supposedly she is a expert on
these you know and it's also interesting
in science fiction's I've seen on some
science fiction TV you know YouTube
obscene that they have you know in this
supposedly you know in science fiction
you have certain aliens or human who who
was spawn or designed you know
genetically designed or some things such
that they can always tell a lie and
actually this is in plate you know
there's a movie Blade Runner yeah
there's a you know there's also you know
a thing about detecting light so that is
very interesting and yeah you know lies
but but I think there is more than that
I mean it is I think it is true that you
can you can spot lie you know you can if
you if you are well trending this if you
spend time to study this and observe you
can spot lie but the catch is that you
can spot lie of most people most
untrained Liars
but it will be difficult or impossible
to do that
for someone who are a trained liar
professional liar or or a liar who is
very good you know like you know you you
you can establish that skill that's kind
of like you know lying is just a skill
just like speaking oration you know so I
I think you know to spot lies from
common people is not difficult in fact
you are we are going in the direction
where
we are going a direction where AI is
starting to do it you know there are
cameras all over you know like today
everywhere is camera you know and I
wouldn't be surprised there's already a
company that is you know doing the
technology we're like interview
automatically if you know analyze you
know the video and and will be able to
tell here you know he's lying or she's
lying you know yeah I'm pretty sure
there's already a company doing that so
this is the thing you know it's
happening this is one of the thing
that's going on with the AAI and it has
I would say it has huge consequences but
also I like to say you know it's it is
my opinion that you cannot easily detect
lies from people who you know like you
can say professionals skilled so if that
is true you know if you agree with me on
that then basically basically the whole
the entire light detection becomes is
it's it becomes a different thing it's
not as useful as people before because
when people actually want to lie they
can and they can do it successfully you
know you you are not you know you don't
think that oh there is this you know
technology to detect lie therefore you
can always spot lies no I don't think
that that is the case so the this only
has I think limited use you know it you
know one thing
you know one thing it's easy to lie hi
I'm gonna teach you okay Casali dog show
I'm a genius you know what one thing to
lie anyone even she cannot detect it
how by lying to yourself
in fact most politicians are doing that
for example what what's the example of
doing that for example let's say you
know politician do that all the time
like some like for example gay marriage
let's say some pick some controversial
topic you know well let's pick something
else maybe something less controversial
okay let's say something like Clinton
okay you know that cream the President
Clinton he slept with a intern right
Oh Trump you know Trump you know he is
supposedly he also you know slept with
this this woman you know this
Danielle stormy stormy Danny or
something so there's a situation you
know so when the when people asks you
the with the in the journalist as you
did you did you do it did you do it
and then you have to say you know in
front of thousands of camp cameras did
you do it or not so so you want to lie
so suppose you did okay but you want to
like what to do you do that by lying to
yourself so you you want to convince
yourself you absolutely did not okay but
even if even you did but first of all
you want to convince yourself that you
know by whatever it is up to you you
know you know something you this happens
a lot issues where a morality strong
opinion about morality is concerned so
for example you can think that you know
I never did that because if I did that
that would be utterly wrong you know
that that would be something you know
something you you you you despise you
hate you you think that's the worst
possible thing to do you know like each
person is different you have you know
you have your certain things you know so
you want to you know just like think
that then you are then then you know you
like they cannot eat bacon hotel
okay that's that's it for today
woman so what anything anything else any
questions anything questions any
questions so I'm working on these let's
switch to JavaScript so on this run
script I have let's magnify let's turn
off that let's magnify so you can see I
have this run script so this is out of
stock
this is anglo-saxon and an anglo-saxon
run this is younger lone branch run and
this is younger short trick run um so
yeah I'm working on anyway
where do I live
I live in USA of course I mean Mountain
View which is what they call Silicon
Valley so Google you know Google PayPal
Netscape you know it's all apples over
here wait where are you from oh go ago
King so Dion says I need to work on
learning a better programming language
than Python I decided the day before
yesterday learning Python was a big
mistake
from Pauline oh wow
great fantastic ago is from Berlin but
blood is Russian Russian great
so Dion says I'm thinking either go or
Lisp I do mostly network programming oh
absolutely especially for network
programming go for :
absolutely why because 1 :
we all have a hundred times more jobs
than go no that's wrong
thousand times more jobs than Lisp no
that's wrong ten thousand times more
jobs than this still wrong
10,000 10,000 is about right okay so
first of all : we'll have 10,000 times
more jobs than this
meaning more options for you if you one
day want you want to make money out of
your expertise of a programming language
so first of all :
secondly : is a live company a live
language Lisp is kind of is it's
basically dead okay it's a you know you
you can do this but you will be in this
niche community where you got a bunch of
weird people like myself you know very
weird people they are they don't have a
job they they trying to do open source
or something they you know very in
general very weird people you know not
not regular and you know they don't have
a job in you know that's Lisp okay well
actually but also I mean doesn't matter
what what this right now the most
popular Lisp that has some job prospect
is closure but again you know compared
to Python : Ruby or JavaScript
you know closure is like you know you
you you you there's no you know for each
closure program you have 10,000 Java
JavaScript also 10,000 : programmers you
know it's like you know niche and you
know yeah so I absolutely do not
recommend this well also let me give you
I haven't finished so one reason is jobs
so 10,000 times more jobs for : okay the
other reason is this B's kind of dying
is it's kind of dead okay you have you
have few options you have closure which
is very alive okay closure is alive you
have racket scheme which is kind of
alive is what records scheme is academic
language okay so
you're gonna be a professor researcher
you know joining academia doing doing
you know graduate as a graduate student
you are not going and also it's kind of
dying back at this then you have scheme
this is you know that's also kind of
diet I mean okay you have common list
it's also dead common list it's dead
meaning that there are very very very
very few people actually program it and
also the common list the language is
dead like 20 years ago there is no
improvement to it whatsoever since 20
years ago the only real if if you really
want to go this knee only I will say no
I wouldn't go this at all and closure
closure is okay but closure has one
major problem that is it is married to
Java you know if so if you really want
to know closure if you really want to
master closure you actually necessarily
now don't listen to all the closure fans
what they are saying but listen to what
I am saying okay so you have to know
Java in detail the whole entirety of
Java if you really want to be expert of
closure that is that is a situation
because closure for one reason I have
articles on it closure for four reasons
they are intimately tied to Java and
also intentionally so because Java is
one of the most popular language you
know you have ten thousand jobs in Java
same same with : they are comparable :
Python Java JavaScript they all these
are you know industrial popular
languages so so so Java has lots of
programmers it's mainstream okay but
then you have closure closure want to
write on the popularity of Java that's
one of the core you know that that's one
of the tactics of growing closure
so you know you crochet says hey Java
hey Java programmers you wanna do
functional programming come over you
know we we are closer we are on top of
Java Virtual Machine so and everything
you know about Java works here too so
that's their tactics to to become
popular so you know because they you
write on the Java popularity most Java
programmers they are not you know Java
programmer Java is kind of the
enterprise language they are the Java
people they are not into functional
programming they are not into Oh monad
oh oh let's do some tail recursion they
are not interesting that okay it's Java
they are they are the kind of boring
enterprise programming and you have lots
of them using companies like with with
database backing and so on so the so one
of the tactics tactics for closure to
grow is to say is to write on a job of
Javiera T you know so that is the reason
okay the closure is like interwined with
Java
you know intentionally because every
documentation of closure you know I you
know I have two articles okay about that
so let's go to let me show you sorry
closure Java
closures popularity a tango with Java
and why Crozier is dense so I did
closure for about a year full time
around 2016 no actually around 2000 okay
2016 I was puzzled why is closure you
know why is closure kind of very much
integrated with Java I mean to me you
know I like this right so I want to you
know I like this and closure is at least
so to me is like oh let's I'm going to
learn closure this is great so I'm gonna
have another language I really love and
I can use and it's industrial - it's
great but in my journey into closure
I discovered closure is like
intentionally heavily intertwined with
Java no I despise Java okay anything
about Java IDs I hate with very much
because the language the whole package
of JVM you know many know so I don't
like Java but closure you know ok
closure is on top of JVM ok that's ok
but you know but I'm thinking but this
is a new language you know it's not Java
well you you you can use Java things if
you want within closure but you don't
have to right so I I kind of like yeah
yeah that's great I'm going to you know
learn closure it turns out you know in
the process added closure is not a inter
pendant language you know like I was
thinking you know ok yeah you can have a
language on top of JVM but the language
spec for closure is you know clean and
you know it's just like at least you
know it you can study you can master the
whole closure without actually learning
Java you know stuff that's not true in
fact it's it's the opposite closure the
language if you really try to master
them as opposed to you know just a copy
and paste code if you
really try to understand what what is
its least structure what is its you know
array structure you know its integrated
its inter wine with Java and I was you
know in unnecessarily so unnecessarily
so so I was quite puzzled eventually I
understood this is my conclusion okay
closure is that way because it's trying
to intentionally trying to write on top
of Java popularity you know to you know
to so that Java programmers can you know
easy come to closure and you know which
means you know companies with you know
big corporates this pedia million dollar
corporations they will use closure
because they are programmers you know
can easily you know start to use closure
even if they don't know because you know
that that is the reason closure is
intertwined with Java which is kind of
sad but when I talk to of course closure
programmers typically B's fans they are
they don't know they don't they don't
it's like you know that when you talk to
list fans it's typical code situation
happens they don't you know they like me
okay they want to believe they want to
you know they want to believe in closure
but instead of you know trying to like
me you know pick pick these criticisms
and attack you know and point them out
they didn't they don't do that they do
they follow the you know they want to
believe they say all closure is great
now you know the closure is great on top
of Java they don't they don't see the
problem with Java you know when I asked
them you know when they read my article
their response is typically yeah you are
right but know you don't have to know
Java stuff you know you can just do the
closure you don't really have to know
that's yeah yeah that that is if you are
you know staying at the beginner level
you know you don't intend to really
understand the language
so do you want me to tell do you want me
to tell you what you hate what do you
hate dear so that is that a trap is that
a trap because you can directly tell me
without telling me that you are going to
tell me so ergo says aha good you landed
on Emacs what do you mean I mean using
Emacs for 20 years so first name says
first name says whenever I find
difficulty I blame the lack of detailed
documentation of those inferior inferior
terrible tutorials yeah okay deal T is
going to tell us what he hate
sodium so after this I think we're gonna
shut down because it's being 68 80
minutes so Dion says I hate feeling
helpless my opinion about Python Java
and most other things is that they
faster ignorance and eventually
helplessness by providing a layer around
the thing you actually need to
understand in such a way that leaves you
ignorant okay but I don't really I mean
I don't see I kind of see the point but
I kind of see your point but not not
exactly in detail they faster ignorance
they provide a layer what like what do
you mean well because they are high
level languages right higher level
languages usually are like that so the
answer is you always have this thick
crust underneath you of something which
you have to hope of understanding
through D and you just have to give all
your power up to the programming
language or library programmers yeah I'm
not sure I understand what do you mean
you know because most you know Python at
least Python they are higher-level
languages so usually you know they are
you know usually they are so Deon says
I'm not against higher-level languages
but we have tower Babel with way too
many layers yeah okay but what do you
mean by layers like with like what in
the layers do not mesh together
okay it's not easy to describe yeah
again I can you know I can't understand
that yes yeah I mean some some of these
you know these programming concepts and
you know like you know same thing with
me that when you want to express themes
it's not easy sometimes because it's
complicated thought sometimes you have
to actually think for an hour then you
understand exactly what is the issue
then you can describe it you know and
this is actually a phenomenon in
Sciences as well in math in Sciences in
general because when you have and also
in philosophy and also it happens in
everyday life when you talk to people
like sometimes when we are talking they
when you know you want to say something
but you don't know quite the word and
you then you start to use an analogy you
know trying to like you you try to
express something by you know by analogy
or by going around but the thing is you
see when if you are interested in logic
philosophy sometimes you like Peter
jordison the way you know sometimes you
you are wondering what is the exact word
to describe sudden thinking usually the
often there's the world not always like
there's one word that captured the whole
concept or emotion for example a side
effect is one such a war that side
effect describe is a concept in
functional programming that described
the situation where a function input and
output up who does not always depend on
input you know that you know that is
what side effect is you know I remember
like 20 years 25 years ago I was trying
to describe this situation where a
function output does not depend on input
you know I was you know saying that then
Stefan Wolfe I'm says oh you mean side
effect and at the time I don't know no
computers
it's nothing you know never studied
anything you know except the
mathematical language and a side effect
yes side effect that's the first time I
heard the word side effect and you know
so that you see the the the world
captures the concept you see and this is
true for lots of things you know I you
know if you never went through the
education system or if you never studied
did something you know you don't know
the word sometimes you know the word the
word for it is you should often not
always the would then suddenly if
someone mentioned is side of a get you
know utilizable yes right side affect
how you know that word seems to describe
the whole thing inside effect and
similarly for many concept expressions
so the audiences for example Python so
Deon says bilayer
I mean code that expands into other code
in a way with unpredictable consequences
for example Python code expands into god
only knows what at the sea level with my
Kolya in between you can even have
layers that are abstract for example a
Mona doesn't correspond to any concrete
property of computers it is a
mathematical object so to implement it
on a computer you have to introduce a
concept there yeah I see what you mean
but I still don't distinguish that from
being high level language then you know
then you know I don't see the point
about okay maybe here's maybe this is
what you are saying the part I don't
like Python either because the you know
the way I you know I I also so this also
comes to me so I think the reason I
think it's because the there's a
computer language model
that's the way I put it so you know
different programming languages they
have kind of this kind of a model
internal model for the for the language
on how it works kind of you can think of
it as a machine some sort of virtual
machine that the language actually deal
with I think maybe that is what what you
might be trying to say yeah I know
so anyway by the way how old are you
deal like you know I have no idea like
in teens 20 no probably not things but
20s 30s 40s
okay that's about it twenty-nine okay
good you are on your prime okay so thank
you guys for watching goodbye
I go Jang Hye Jung so goodbye DeYoung
bye guys