Hello guys, good morning. Welcome to
another episode of Exot Talk Show. Look
at my keyboard. This is ultimate hacking
keyboard UHK80
Nia track ball logitech
mouse. Okay. And this is fantastic board
SV A L B O A R D. I have reviews on
them. Check them out on YouTube. Okay.
So now let's switch to my normal screen
and we are going to do um emac coding.
Fantastic emac this stop that okay if
you here say hi love to see your
comments. Okay okay okay need adjustment
so we're going to code emac lisp. Okay
so showing browser. So let's begin
coding emacisp. I have done enough
introduction already.
Emac disp. Okay. Can you see me? Uh yes,
check. Audio check, video check, screen
check. Okay, let's begin. Uh let's go to
my uh Goland package. So this uh let's
create a file here. Uh something save
emac disp. Okay. So wait. So close that.
Make a copy. Go here. uh rename. So this
gonna be find replace uh this is called
find uh inner
inside
text.
Okay. So, so what this will do is that
it will it will find just like the Unix
script command. It will find a text
among all files inside the directory.
But it will find the te text only if the
text happens between some other text.
For example, uh so let let me do this.
Okay. So close that. For example, let's
go to uh so the most fitting example is
HTML. Okay. So, hold on a second. Let me
go let me paste a link here. So, show in
browser today's talk show. Let's go down
section and create a new section. Paste
a link. Link by make a list. Okay. So,
the so for example, here is a HTML
section. So, sometimes you want to do
for example, let's go to my JavaScript
blog. I've been working on it so much.
So you you see you go to this binding
JavaScript block. You see there is a
code inside. So let's open that file.
Let me give you a example. What why are
we doing this? Okay. So you can see
there's a code. Now put it back. You can
see here is the JavaScript code. Now I
want to find in my JavaScript tutorial
there are about
>> [clears throat]
>> uh 1,000 pages. Okay. So in all these
files I want to find a JavaScript code
that is
you know text starting with preclass
equals to JS. Okay. So I want to find
JavaScript code that does not contain
console assert or console log. Okay. So
in these 1,00 files I want to find for
each one of them find the JavaScript
script codes snippet
if it occurs and then uh if in this
snippet it does not uh contain any
console.
Okay so that is my goal and we are going
to write a emac le script for it. Okay,
you cannot do this in Unix uh terminal
shell uh uh grab you know. Well, I mean
you have to write it.
So, okay. So, let's JavaScript this
binding. Okay, close. So, that is the
example. So, now let's go back to um to
do our our code. Okay, let's go back to
start to write this code. So, let's
start to document it. So um today's date
uh script script to find text uh in
all files in the
search
such that
with the condition the text only occur
between given text
such as HTML begin and end tag. Okay,
let's start to write that. Okay, now the
first job is traversal directory. So, uh
input. So, you need a variable. So, um
oh my god, what programming language am
I in? Oh, this is emac. So, what do I
do? uh immac define uh define define
a variable.
So input uh okay so that's the input
directory optional init value yeah I
want to okay well no optional let's just
say in input the to search okay now I
just set x input and let's give a
example let's say uh yeah javascript why
not well javascript that's a big um
let's say the talk show okay so example
Uh this talk shter
actually talk shter is got 1,00 oh god
1,600
files. Uh so
let's go to javascript. Okay.
Okay. So okay. So set set the input.
Then the first thing you want to do is
of course you want to traverse the
directory. Now in functional programming
usually that means you you call a
function that returns a list of all
files in a directory. Okay, that is how
you do it in functional programming
languages such as eag wam language and
uh I believe in most you know in
functional programming language as
opposed to in imperative you know
languages you call a walker you know the
walker hello GCS okay so so how do you
get um okay so how do you get the all
files in your directory let's go to lisp
basics okay search.info
you will find my t t t t t t t t t t t t
t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t t
t t t t t t t t tutorial of 1,00 pages
on Emac Lisp. Okay. So this basic we
want to traverse the that would be uh
that would be kind of emacisp because
the this section is about variables is
about functions it's about data types
you know that
programming language constructions about
string about number about boolean about
variable about function about
conditional if then else uh and about
loop so that's a basic fundamental
structure how do you do it in lisp
introduction Lisp basics. Now you if you
want to traverse a directory that's a
bit more
uh kind of depending on the language
usually it's in a library okay in in
Python in Ruby in Java in Goland you
know in uh NodeJS in Denojs they are
typically in a library so practical this
work directory so that's how you do it
directory files okay that is no subd uh
in our case do we want subd
Let's see. Uh
well, yes, I want subd. Okay, so you
want to call this function directory
files recursively.
Okay, now the options is a bit
complicated, but I have a example. Let's
just copy it. Okay, copy.
Okay, copy paste coding the most
powerful copy paste coding. So now you
want to say um define uh let's say
[snorts]
x file list. Okay, that's a file list.
And how do you get the file list? You
get it via list function. So this n o
subd directory or files extension.
Uh now okay. So we need to uh give
another
another option for variable definition.
I mean uh another option for user input
and assign it as a variable that would
be file name extension.
Uh
okay so that would filter it out. Okay.
So
u
well um file name extension for example
what you would do is that you want to
set it to like uel so that we only check
those files uh
you want some kind of regular expression
I mean so there's a design choice do you
want to just use a file name extension
so what this want we want to do is that
we don't want every file file in the
directory. We typically I mean the user
case the use case is that you only want
HTML files or TXT files or py files or
JS files you know you only want certain
you don't want for example JPEG files
typically and you you also want to
ignore git directory uh so there so so
that's why you need to say something
like filter file name filter um
okay so let's
Let let me let me try to copy. Um I have
written lots of code like this in the
past. So let's see if I can make use
some of my existing
uh let's make it pink. Okay. Let's go to
um
Okay. So let's see find
uh so we got
so what do we have? So define while find
text char count before uh auto save
output. Okay. So find temp path temp
path last replace record. Okay. And not
what we want. We find the ignore regular
expression list.
That's
we kind of need that. Okay. This is
getting complicated before you we even
get to the coding the hard the heart of
the problem. We got stuck with this
little trivia about filtering file
names. You see? So let's see. Is it
happened yet? Y yet yet.
Uh okay. So,
okay, let's just quick quick quickly
code them something. Okay, so you want
this. Let's see quickly. Um,
yeah, let's let's say let's say
uh X file name extension. Okay, so
that's not what we want actually. So
file name extension
uh let's say
file name
y rejects file name rejects. Okay
actually that would make much much more
sense. Okay so you just want to say that
art plus and uh backslash. So that means
back slash backslash that means anything
ending in eel. That's how you specify
uh regular expression pattern for files
ending in Excel. Okay, in EL.
So this will be rejects on file
name. Let's just
make sloppy documentation for now. We'll
improve the documentation later. Hello
archive. Hello, Skeletor. Hello,
Skeletor Delight. Skeletor delight. Are
you the skeleton?
I I know. No, I don't think so. I'm
using AI agent today to learn about API
in computer science. Item potency is a
property of a certain operation or API
request.
Uh, what do you mean?
Adam potency is one of the idiotic
almost the most extreme idiotic jargon
from the programming tech nerds. They
think you know they they think they are
talking about advanced mathematics. In
fact whenever the programmers the coders
when they use like mathematical jarans
like item potency or or directed graph
git you know oh git is a directed
directed graph. Oh um something
something uh like uh uh you know the web
um protocol that like you know the
functional like item processing whenever
you know programmers use mathematical
sounding jarens they are idiots to the
extreme they are using them in a in an
way inappropriately
useless basically mean meaningless okay
unlike mathematicians or in other fields
of science is engineering. When you use
a technical jargon, usually there's a
like it's meaningful, it's useful. You
can't, you know, if you use some other
words, it might screw up your
communication. Okay? Like as like for
for example in mathematics, okay? That's
why you you got these jarens, okay?
uh mathematics you know you got function
you got you got you got you want one one
function you got all sort of functions
you got uh group theory you got let's
see um you know lots of jarens okay in
mathematics so you have to use them
correctly that's that's when the jargon
is serves a purpose that's why there's
this these jarens hard to understand
okay but then but when when the
programmers the idiotic
programmers like the C C++ idiots and
lisp idiots. Lisp typically they
when they abuse jarens uh from people
with a code like lisp, python
uh not PHP for example these people,
Python people uh uh uh you know uh also
scheme these people uh they they tend
you know and Emacs of course they will
use jarens for for example item potent
potency. Okay. They they they they they
are the they are idiots. Okay. They
don't know what they talking about. They
like like Okay, that's a side tip. I
don't know what you're talking about.
Skeletal. Um
what keyboard are you using? What what
kind of question is that? I talk about
that in every of my video. Okay. Like
today in in introduction, I just talked
about it. Okay. You must uh this must be
the first time you watch my uh uh video.
Well, just scroll back and you'll see.
Okay, so I wanted to show you. Yeah, so
we digressed about jargon a little bit.
Okay, so let me uh just show you
uh jarens. Okay, go back to uh info. So
search for actually you don't need to
search. You you go down, go down, go
down, go down, go down. So you got all
these um
so you got uh bump land pving
this syntax soup semantic noodle
programming language jarens index. Okay.
When programmers use math jarens such as
git directed a a cyclic graph or has
monadascal monad. [laughter]
I'm having a burrito today and it's
called monad. HTTP ideal potency. Yeah,
that that's what I was thinking. HTTP
item item potency. I think I spelled it
wrong here. And and this they have a
thing about homeoiconicity.
idiots. Okay. Take my listen
now. Listen remember check again. Okay.
Uh just found my channel. Thank you.
Thank you archive. No worry you know
because you know anyway. No it's a
fantastic keyboard. Okay. Ultimate
hacking keyboard UHK80
you know you look at my YouTube you see
lots of keyboards all the fancy ones
glove 80 and you know anyway so the
these people you know then then the item
potency then they they don't know which
side is mouth which side is ass okay
these coders I despise them this
programming idiots co programmer idiots
okay
shall We go back to what we are doing.
Okay. So, now it's hot.
Oh man, this is this is uh some kind of
heavy metal.
Oh, wait. Wait. This is Mickey Mouse.
I think my wife bought me.
Okay. Busy. I've been busy for nothing.
Busy beaver. Okay. We We need to finish
this. Okay. It's quickly. So let's
quickly Did we uh digress? Did we finish
digression?
Okay, let's continue. Okay, so that's a
regular expression for file name for
filtering file name. Okay, ignore the
whose name start with dot and get. Okay.
So, and so we also need a uh variable
for ignore um
ignore
uh ignore
um
yeah let's not let's not just let's not
do that. Okay. So delete that. Okay. So
now so set file list so directory files
recursively and uh you want to go to the
input not that x input
okay then uh and here is the regular
expression pattern. So this will be file
name rejects.
Okay, fantastic. And Neo and lambda. And
actually this part should be uh
um ignored. So actually you should have
a uh another bar. So
ignore
file rejects. Okay. Something like that.
Let's say ignore file meaning both.
Okay.
Something just for now. Okay. Uh
or the name to ignore. Okay. So, copy
that and set set that to uh uh set that
to actually this. Okay. So, let me just
X ignore do it and uh cut it and uh put
it back here. Okay. Fantastic. and
beautiful the powerful efficient emac
this coding. Okay, that's what we are
doing today. Okay, so um so ignore file
out the regular expression. Okay, that
is anything beginning with a dot.
Anything well if you know if it's a path
if it's a directory name that start with
a dot ignore it such as the git
directory.
Okay. So, so that that that that that
that
pretty pitify the code. Fantastic. So,
we got a file list. Can we run this
code? Yes, we run this code and uh run
it. Done. Fantastic. And can we print
the file list? Yes. So, how do you print
messages?
Print. Run it. And now go to the
messages buffer. Can you see a bunch of
uh No.
So, did we No. So what
what uh
oh we did so so describe variables the
value is new so that means the code runs
successfully successfully but however
all the list is new for some reason it
not it's not finding any
what's oh because in JavaScript
directory tree I do not have any file
ending inel obviously so let's fix it
this not should be not eel should behml
okay now run it now go to the messages
output directory expand the window yay
fantastic is success
success by experience now next
may I help you Next. May I help you
next? Okay. Next. What we going to do
next? Okay. Next, you're going to open
each one.
Okay. So, explain. Uh, so so far is just
um
generate a list of files. Okay,
that's so far. Okay. Now, next next is
we need to uh start to write a command
to open the file.
When you see your file, open it. Search
for beginning end. Okay. God, we need to
go faster. So, open the file. So, so you
need to open file for read.
Okay. Just for read, no. Right. Okay. So
it's a bit tricky for those of you uh
seasoned programmers because it's a bit
tricky in EMAC list because in other
languages you um you know you you you
just read file or uh write file but
anyway in EMAC this let's go there in
eac this read file write file so uh so
eac this basics so string so let's see
if the read write file is Here it's a
JSON read write. No. So you actually
need to go to the EMAC list section.
Let's see this miscellaneous daytime
print date time pass day time. No,
that's not what we want. And what is
regular expression? What is this regular
expression? Okay. So we need we want to
go to the emac this section
writing a command walk directory. There
it is. Uh text processing get user input
file and buffer
read file that's what we want read file
content a string or lines open file read
okay open file read what is this
continued on the next column possibly
right okay so we can let's just click on
read file read file for open file for
read only okay um
should I uh yeah let's you know are we
going to write to file no Let's just use
that. Use that. Okay. So, we define a
function here that reads a file or a
copy paste code. Fantastic. Most
efficient because
you don't have to type anything. Insert
file content. So, first of all, so given
a path, so this is a path file path full
path. Okay. So, given the full path, you
you create a temp buffer. Then you
insert the file content into the buffer.
Then
search for um search for string. Okay.
Uh what string to search? You need to
define it here. So okay. So we didn't
define it. Okay. So we need to search.
You see we are trying to write a command
script to find text in all files in a
directory such that with the condition
the text only occur between given text
okay such as HTML begin end tag so let's
just say so how should we name the text
that we want to find as the as the as
the uh begin tag just call it begin tag
Okay, something like that. Okay, so this
is text that must occur before.
Okay, this is uh definition. Okay, uh x
x. So let's define three variables. So,
and this one is going to be X end tag
text text that must occur after and in
the middle in the middle is going to be
X
find text. This is the text we want to
find. Uh, and what we want to find uh
this is first of all doc documentation
text that we
want to
want to find. Okay. Text. Okay. So, we
defined three new variables. Va. Okay.
So, what what to do next.
Okay. Let's uh let's make them more
consistent. Okay. Three new variables.
Now, go to the bottom here. Now, we want
to search for Okay, before we search for
uh let's set them. Okay. set x begin
let's just say um
let's say pre whatever that you know and
that set x find uh let's say console
okay whatever that and here x stat x end
let's say so that part so this part is
we're going to do like that Okay, for
example. For example, for now.
Fantastic. Is this code valid? Yes. So
far so good. Okay. So now we need to
search for that. Okay. Search um search
text search, you know, search uh search
string. Uh no.
Uh what is it? What is it you're going
to do? So you want to okay you need to
think you want to search. So first of
all you need to go to the okay go to
char buffer point mean that means go to
the beginning of the buffer move the
cruiser too. Okay then you want search
forward that's right now the mentality
is right now I can think about think of
the command right away. Search for word
is a word that's e emac e in e em e em e
em e em e em e em e em e em e em e emac
this okay search for word and what do
you want to search the text that would
be that and optional bound um
okay optional so so okay so you need to
you see you need to search the for these
three um
things now you need to think about
you see You need you you need to think
about so so begin text. So you need to
find the beginning. So how you going to
do this?
You see you want to find the fine text
only if they happen between
you know the beginning text and end
text. So how do you do that? So any
comments? No comments. No comments.
Fantastic.
Do I have how many how many people? So
how many crowd? Nine. Okay.
So okay. So how do you do this? So begin
text end text. So
I mean
Okay. So you want to find obviously for
you you know you must find the beginning
text because otherwise it doesn't occur.
Okay. Then you must find
the end text.
Okay. So then you must find between.
Okay. So let me just do this quickly.
Okay. Let's you know we have to improve
it later for sure. But let's just do
this. Let's try this algorithm.
Okay. So find um
search bound no error. So actually
error. So optional bound no error
actually no error true. Let's say
no error true. Okay. Count now.
Now you need a little um
you need a little um
variables. Okay. So you need to say
begin
text per
something like that. Okay.
And text position. Okay. And uh so this
would be
set x begin.
Okay. So you do that
that uh does that return a position? No.
So okay. So you don't do that.
Uh because such text it returns true if
the text is found
otherwise it returns neo. Okay. So it
doesn't return the position. If you want
the position, you need to use the you
know you need to use get you know point.
So what you do here is you want to uh
know
so when
this is true uh okay so wait if this is
true okay now otherwise
message
not found
Okay. Otherwise you just say not found
uh something in
that not found in this file. So this
file would be file path. Okay.
It would be something like that.
Okay. So let two variables and if search
for word for the begin t text
if it's found do something this if it's
not found you know uh just
print it. Okay. And we and what we going
to do is that we going to
uh so if so
oh god this is a bit involved. So uh any
questions comments?
So search for uh okay so so so if it's
found then what you're going to do if
it's found then
set uh not spacing set
x begin tag text position
okay equals to point so that's
do you want to begin or uh actually you
want to search forward yeah so that
would be the end of the occurrence of
the beginning. Okay.
Then
Okay. So you first search that then you
search for
then you search for um
not search then then if um God this is
getting complicated.
Okay. the the uh and you want xfine
text, right? Not that that that's right.
So, okay. So, then you find the fine
text
find text optional bound bound neo no
arrow. No, not no arrow. So, if there's
arrow, you have to say error. Okay. So
again error
uh so error would be that that
okay it's probably two verb you know we
probably don't want
just point just joined so no context
okay hika why do you want to rewrite
webl like programming eag this you
missed you missed what we just head
because in this program you you want to
be able to search your text only when
they occur inside two other text such as
HTML tags. Okay. So
we just explicitly mentioned you know
grab they cannot do that you have to
write it. Okay anyway you missed it. So,
so anyway, so, so, so and uh, and by the
way, I have written this find and
replace live many times in the past five
years on my YouTube, you know, like many
times for different reasons in different
programming languages for different uh,
reasons. Okay, so anyway, but today we
we write uh writing this, okay, emac
this.
Okay. So, um,
so find text. So, so when you found the
beginning tag, then you keep going. Uh,
yes. Yes. Uh, then you keep going the
find text. If you found it, do this.
Otherwise, you know, just say not found.
And let's just make it one line. Okay.
Let's not just make it one line.
Okay. So,
so what? So, when it's found, then you
kind of do the nesting again. I I don't
like this nesting. Okay.
Uh
if so, but let's just quickly code this
to to see what happens. And we want to
run it. Okay. We want to run be able to
run this code and see what happens. So,
then the next the last search, okay,
search forward. Then this one will be
end
tag text. Okay. Optional bound. No. No
arrow. True. Uh no not we don't want no
error. So
So actually we don't want no error. So
actually just remove them because by
default they are new. Okay. So you
search the wait and t text right. So if
it's found do this. If it's not found
then you print the message that okay uh
this will be
x and t text not found in in oh we got a
mistake um xn okay so we got a mistake
here
you need okay and uh you need that
okay
and you need that. Okay.
So, end tact text. Okay. Compact the
code. Okay. So, we now we kind of get a
code. So, here's a whole code. Okay. So,
here's a whole code. Input directory.
Begin tag text. Right. Now, we set it to
pre-tag. Okay. Now, find text. This is
the text we want to find. You know, we
want to find console.
Okay.
uh you know and uh the end text
condition is end pretag for now just an
example because in other situations you
you you you you see you want to find the
text among all files in a directory such
that it occurs only when you know you
want to know if it occurs between two
other text like inside a bracket or
something you know so the most common
example is HTML you you only want to
know if occurs inside this tag something
like that. Okay, like tag with a special
ID or something. So, so, so then uh so
then we have file name regular
expression that is to filter you know uh
text file or HTML file or JavaScript
file. Okay, then we have ignore
directory such as getit you know ignore
directory regular expression pattern.
Okay, and here we started to generate
uh a list of files in functional
programming style. That's how you do it.
It just return a list of files. Okay.
Then here uh we we write a function to
process each file. So given a file path,
we insert we create a temp directory a
temp buffer. Buffer in Emacs it's called
buffer just like a temp text like
untitled
temp untitled file. the insert file
contents then go to char mean point
point mean that's go to the beginning of
the uh the buffer which is like that
okay go to the bottom go to the
beginning go to the bottom and go to
that's move that's a cursor okay that's
called point in emac jargon point okay
go to ch point mean go to the beginning
then then we create uh two local
variables beginning position and end
position okay then if search for word
begin tag tank Next,
if it's true, then you do then you do
you set the then you set the position
then then okay then you search again for
the find text if it's true.
Okay. So what are we doing here? Okay.
So if it's true then you search again
for the end text. If it's true then here
that means you all the conditions are
met.
So you must say uh like print
found
[laughter]
at file uh you know this is not good but
let's just go with it for now. Okay. F
path. So found at fp path. So right now
it just report
um
the file path it occurs and it also um
let's also report
at position
um
position. Okay, so you want to give a
position point. Okay, so that returns a
file path and position of occurrence of
of the end tag. Okay. So that's kind of
we have to refine this this script.
Okay. Because at the end we want to it
to print nicely you know like in this
file it occurred in this text block you
know show to show show it. Um but for
now it just like point out where it
occurs. Okay. So
okay found that that that. Okay. So
otherwise message not found. Okay. So,
but right now our job is just to make
sure this code runs. Okay. Like we don't
care about clarity and everything. We
just care
that the code actually runs.
Okay. You see, we got this nested thing
going on. That's usually no good. It's
better if you make them linear because
when you have lots of nesting it's like
it's it's it for humans it becomes
difficult to reference you know to
understand which which level goes to
what level
uh even though for programmers
especially lisp is all nested. Okay,
let's just run it. Okay, let's run it
and see.
Uh, you you'll get a lot found results.
Okay, because there's a lot occurrence.
Let's just run it. Now, will it destroy
my files or something? I don't think so.
There's no destructive
code. It just report. Okay.
So, so make sure. Okay. Let's run it.
Run it. Okay. Done. So let's look at the
message buffer what
nothing
okay that means our code is not running
correctly. Okay close it close it
oh because we didn't we haven't called
this function. So what you need to call
this function? You need to say
uh you need to say
map C uh
map
map a lambda or function to
x file list.
Okay. And this function will be um you
know actually you can just say that
okay you need to say that of course
because you didn't okay let's see is
that right I mean if we run this if we
run this it's going to like spit out
whole it's going to go through 1,000
files you see it's going to go through
this directory that's 1,00 files and
there's a huge uh amount of pre-tag, you
know, JavaScript code there. So, okay,
let's just run it. Okay, symbols value
as variable is void my process file
void.
Oh, because you need in this you need to
quote it. Okay, now do it again. Do it
search failed pre.
Okay, so some so search fail pre. Okay.
So where is it? Uh
oh. Okay. So yeah, I know what. So So
this search for word you need you need
to say neo
it you know bounded search. Do you want
bounded search? No. Neo. And do you want
it to report ignore error? Yes. You want
to ignore error when it's not found.
Okay. So you actually want those. So we
need to add that to all these. search
for word functions. You see you can look
at look up the documentation search for
what you can see and it will tell you
the syntax about the bound optional
bound and no error part. Okay. So now we
added bound no bound search to the end
new okay and if there's error ignore it
okay ignore the arrow because we are
doing the error catching ourself you
know if there's if it's
found I mean the error means whether
found or not okay so if it's not found
do you want to report like error out no
okay so ignore error means Not found
error means true. We we say true means
that we will handle like ignore the
arrow. Don't error out if you cannot
find the text. Okay? Because we handle
it ourself. So this is when you found it
the text and if you did not find the
text you print that. Okay? And in in our
case we don't want to do anything. Okay.
So let's think about um
not [snorts] found. Okay. So when when
it's not found because what's the point
if you just print you not found here not
found here it's not found you know it
doesn't make sense. So, so we don't need
uh this this not found Neo. Okay. Well,
now let's just say Neo.
Okay. So,
Okay. So, now let's run it.
Okay. Look, look like it's going lots of
files. Busy beaver. Busy beaver
algorithm.
Can you see? Can you guys see down
there? You know, 10,00 files BC beaver
done file. Now let's let's go to the
messages buffer. So you can see quite a
few found instances. So found at this
file at position 1886.
Okay, let's split the window. Let's uh
let's see this one. Okay, JSvar found
you know at at position 2912. Okay, now
open that file.
Now, now let's
go to char
the window. So there it is. So you can
see console log. So you can see can you
see this block of text that is actually
JavaScript code and it contains console
log exactly
what we wanted. Okay, undo. Undo. Okay,
now close it. Fantastic. So that's one
occurrence is quite a few, you know. Uh,
fantastic. I think
Okay, did we talk for how long? One
hour, I think. And I think maybe we can
like that's it. Um, so wait, put the
code back. Okay, we cannot put the code
back. So let's just copy the code. Close
it. And let's
let me just add the code here. So emac
this so people can see it. Okay, paste
the code there. And uh
and uh
and uh this hold on a second. Okay,
that's my code. Close that. Okay, close
that.
Syntax color it scan error. Wait, what?
Why can't I syntax color it?
What?
What the
Syntax error. Okay, we run into a syntax
error issue because of the pre-tag.
That's why.
Okay. So, if you do that then then Okay.
No. Still. So what the is
back? Can can can we like uh syntax
color it?
No. Because of these tag. Oh god.
Okay. Do you guys know what I mean? I
don't think you guys know. But what I'm
saying is that you see we got this pre
block of text in HTML.
So I have a EMAC command that that will
syntax color this this code
you know syntax color and make this pre
you know like make those amperanding
code but but right now that code is not
working.
Why is it not working? That is because
because you are running into a situation
where the code contains the code itself.
The you know because this command is
looking for the end of pre-tag to
determine where where does the code end
then it can syntax color you know the
selected part. But now it's having a
problem because because the code
contains this pre um that is confusing
it. So I I so I don't know um you know
so it was like that. So it's got
problem.
Um so it's you know if you show this in
browser browser will also get confused
because browser will see oh pre and oh
you know you are closing the pre so the
browser think this code closes there so
it's incorrect. So this is a issue by
the way. This is actually very
interesting issue because this occurs
whenever you have like the escape
sequence you know the backslash inside
the string escape sequence a major
headache and also occurs in HTML
whenever you have nested for example you
have HTML inside HTML you want to so you
need to encode these characters right
and it becomes very difficult to
determine whether they should be encoded
or not you you know in fact it is
impossible just like the backslash
escape sequence it's very difficult to
determine impossible in fact whether
they should be um one way or the other.
So anyway,
so if you guys have not already watched
one of my video about four month ago in
on the let's just show in browser okay
so anyway here here is today's code emac
this not syntax color okay so I mean
that does the job so let me digress a
bit so you go to talk show okay and I
think that's did for today. You go to
talk show, go to year 2025 just like a
barely a month ago and search for rock
string. Okay, rock string there.
Okay, so this episode 702
2025 September 19th the C print F crime
and new syntax for string rocks string.
So that details in depth for one hour
about the most major the the problem of
the escape sequence. Okay. And I believe
in you know this uh of all my tutorials
this is one of the best. Okay. Let's say
by now I have you know episode 700. I
have 700 videos. This I would say the
top 20 this video. Okay. In my opinion,
my own assessment, this video, episode
is
top 50 or like no top 20 of my videos in
terms of the content of computer
science. Okay, like this is my 30 years
experience
condensed into about creating a new
syntax about the problem of the C
the the the escape sequence
all sort of problems. Okay, so watch
that. Uh today for today I think we we
kind of done. So, you know, we got a
error. You know, I'm going to um
actually I can fix this easy. Just just
remove the pre just remove the HTML tag.
Okay. Uh so just for now. Okay. Now
syntax color showing browser. Now you
see now it works perfect. You see emac
code. This code is for find all files in
a directory such that all text in a
directory such that the text occur only
when they are between two other uh text.
Okay. So that's uh like elementary it
works but it needs require a lot
refinement because right now it just
like
prints the position of the files it
occur. It doesn't show actually show you
know you you it would be good if you
want you know you want it to actually
show the occurrences and also what I
what I actually want is not when they
happen what I want is actually when
when a pre-tag
does not contain any console
word. Okay. So, so we need to add
another variable option to reverse the
regular expression. So, I want only to
know of this all the 10,00 files in this
directory when when inside the pre-tag
of JavaScript code
only when the code does not contain any
console. For example, you can see it in
um in in so here's a number syntax. This
is binary int syntax. So you got console
octo syntax, binary notation, hexadimal
notation. Uh you got um
but but in some of some places um
math operate there math operators you
see there's no console log.
I want to find all snippet of this
situation. Okay, that is why we are
writing this script today. Okay, thank
you guys. Thank you. Thank you guys for
watching 12 people. Uh, any other
questions? Do you ever ride a
skateboard? No, actually I didn't. I,
you know, when I was younger, I was a
unicycle cyclist. I ride unicycles
uh for like four, five years. So I I was
I'm very fairly uh expert of unicycle.
So what trick I can do but this is long
ago. I cannot do it today. I can I can
probably still ride it but not the
tricks I do. So on on unicycle one of
the trick is that you can pedal one
foot. Okay. So you leave what one of the
foot you know not touching the pedal. So
you I can do that. You can also do that
backwards. Okay. going backward. One
foot on the pedal. And you can also
walk on the tires. So you don't you
don't put your foot on the pedal, but
you walk you you walk on the tires on
uni unicycle. Okay. So I can do that. Uh
so it's pretty advanced but I I but
there are a lot of people you know
especially today because internet you
can see all sort of like people doing
crazy uh you know advanced things like
20 years ago 30 years ago without
internet
these people exist in all sort of life
in a unicycle in bicycle in tricks in
you know for example recently this guy
climbed the Taipei 101 uh building
that's like
500 meters building. He climbed with
just hands, no ropes, no rope, you know,
he just climbed. So crazy, you right,
incredibly talented. So 30 years ago
before the internet, these type of
people still exist, you know, but you
don't you never hear them, you know.
Maybe once in a while you see oh you
know Guinness uh book of record you know
oh amazing guy this guy did that you you
know with one like black white photo
like fuzzy photo right before internet
that's the situation you don't you don't
know who you know but with internet like
you go to YouTube you see all these
incredible things uh people do and not
you know not just like in sports but
also in coding in like all sort of
things you know people
uh can can do you know so there's a lot
kind of talent that exist all over so uh
so so let me answer all the questions
one by one okay so let's see uh uh uh
just joined so what do you use to expand
template y snippet no I don't use y
snippet okay so I'm a old old Emacs user
My the first time I started to um use
Emacs is 1998.
Okay. I'm an old Asian EMAC user
and and now I'm not just Asian EMAC
user. I'm also an old guy. So I kind of
I don't you know talk to the common
people you know. So why why snip why
snippet I stopped using it in year 2010.
Okay. And I have a tutorial on Y snippet
um you know written in year 2010. So
like wait when did I stop using it? Stop
y snippet auto indent. Okay that's about
you know that's about specific feature
that I recommend not to use in ya
snippet. Okay. So anyway, the bottom
line is that YA snippet is I I you know
when it began in 2009 2010 I was using
it but I no longer use it in you know in
fact all what I use is all my packages.
Okay. It's like I
uh so I'm an oldtime eCacer. Okay. I
like this. This is what I use. All of
these is my own packages. all the
templates you see emac this mod uh eac
this that's that's part of the a brief
so in fact I explained it so many times
like you know people don't watch videos
but
so wait uh not emac this view okay so
this so emac this mode okay search for a
brief search for a brief
uh okay so you'll find it okay So there
there it is. Okay. So this is all my
Emacs abbreviations and template
expansions. You'll see it there. Okay.
So it does comp completion and and uh
you know function completion and for
basically the top 1,000 or 500 most used
emac functions. And if you go to my
e-magis website, you can find the most
frequently um
a list of the most frequent, you know,
eaglist function frequency ordered, you
know. So this I have like about 1,000 uh
eaglist tutorials in pages. Okay. So
anyway, so I so I'm a old-timer. I don't
use white snippet. Why snippet was
started like 15 years ago by a Chinese
guy who moved to MIT who went to MIT
from China and by now he graduated you
know long ago but anyway that's so so
that's why why snip it okay I don't use
it it's kind of bloated okay it's highly
bloated I don't recommend it I talked
about this before often I recommend you
just use emac a brief okay so let me let
me actually So let me start to actually
show you some of the things. Okay. So,
so the EMAC this function frequency we
talked about uh let's go back and let's
search for uh YA snippets. So what I was
was I saying about so there's a bunch of
articles I wrote 10 15 years ago about
YA snippet but I I haven't been using YA
snippet for about 10 years now. Okay. So
how to define templates in YA snippet
and and these articles I think by now
they are uh also outdated okay so don't
read my tutorials on ya snippet okay so
but but what I recommend instead of ys
snippet is just a brief okay so
emac tutorial just search for ki emac a
brief you'll find it okay so you you can
okay or you can go to it manually by go
to the Emacs tutorial. Then on the panel
you you'll see uh font split window file
and buffer copy paste find text find
replace unic code file encoding you know
uh and white space issues sort how do
you sort rectangle edit shell view
special file emac efficiency there and
there's oak mod someone was asking me
about oakmark emac efficiency okay then
a brief mode okay that's what you want
you can use a brief to type frequently
used English words like where are U, R
for R, U for you, one single letter,
things like that or how are you today?
You know like H R U Type
the full sentence. How are you today? Or
whatever you say to your friends. Howdy.
or unic code arrow or emoji or return
commonly used used in programming
language RT for return. You can just
type RT return or you can type FN that
return the function template for
whatever function in your programming
language. Okay, so lots of use for this
a brief. So here is how you do them.
Okay, uh here is how you set them up
using the uh standard Emacs way. Okay.
But I have a better way. I
uh have it here somewhere.
Uh better way. Let's see. Emacs name
confusion using a brief mode. Uh
there Emacs set up hundreds of a brief.
So go there. I show you this one file.
Put this one file in in your Emacs in it
and you can modify it and you can just
have almost all the a brief I have.
Well, except well except in each
language I have, you know, I custom
custom wrote all these hundreds of a
brief manually. Okay, so this is
manually crafted code supreme,
you know, but it takes more time. So
that that's eager
that in JavaScript in JavaScript you can
see so this is all the a brief templates
you know single letter two letters you
know you get you get date now date pass
date prototype function prototype and
there's like hundreds of them okay so so
in EMAC this in JavaScript
and also in uh well also also in HTML
and you know
in other languages.
Okay. So what uh so just join. Okay. So
templates. Okay. I use a brief. Remember
that. Okay. For ren for and I use emac a
brief. So if you watch my video today,
check out a brief that would be that's
use that's useful. Okay.
Uh so someone correct me if I'm wrong.
We are not adding these kind of
functionalities to Emacs make it slow
and crash prone. Okay. No, that depends
on what you use. Okay. If you use Y
snippet, yes, very much so. Okay. So,
Emacs takes a lot to time to master. So,
for most of you, I believe, you know,
you go you go install, you know, get um
you know, you go install like um
Malpa, right? you set up Malpa, you
install Malpa and you also, you know,
maybe you use the one of the
um
I don't even remember. It's like I'm,
you know, I'm getting old and out of
touch with the EMAC young people
community. Okay, so but you can you go
there, you go to uh Doom Emacs, for
example, Doom Emacs and what's the
other? So they usually install a lot of
packages right. So here is how you so
this is these areas packages but you can
um
okay there is uh of course there is
u emac which is very powerful uh created
by you know a great guy uh but then then
there is also that package that um
anyway so what I'm saying is that most
people like vast majority of Emacs
people they install packages those pack
like you you need to be careful like who
wrote them like most like a lot of them
in fact like most because they they they
they make your Emacs slow okay a ne in a
un a necessary way for example the best
way to illustrate this is like mpm you
know the nojs mpm the idiotic by
these zoomer idiots or late Malay genian
coders they don't know what they're
doing they don't know the details of
emacs but they want to write code you
know they don't know exactly how
JavaScript works but they write they
contribute to mpm so they have a package
of a library how to determine a number
is a even number you know I wrote this
you know how to check a number is even
npm package so that's why when you mpm
you download you know one file you have
it depends on 10 other files each one
depends on 10 other files so you you you
said you know you just want to have one
dependency 1,000 files comes in
okay so this the situation is kind of
similar in the mail git you know you
download you know because they they
don't
they don't take you know they they they
don't take the indepth you know deep
approach like the 90s of knowing emac
this you know so they have lots of like
easy code but it's inefficient so most I
would say most people when you you know
your your Emacs become slow okay your
emac like one concrete example I can
tell you is why snippet we just talked
about That package is like huge bloat.
Okay. Hu like huge huge bloat.
Ya snippet.
Um, okay. This is these are my opinions.
Okay. But you know but you know it might
be too harsh because some of the you
know if you show my clip to the these
developers they may they may say what
the this arrogant head you
know this arrogant But but I'm
right h you know at least half of the
time
you know because they you know
yeah you you could you know a lot of
these packages they can they can improve
you know they they they like they um
they are slow and they they they bog you
down especially those using the like
modern interface for this you know this
the code uh s or dash you know dash.el
E, you know, like I I said this many
times, anytime you download a EMAC
package that uses Stash,
ban it. Okay, stop using that package
right away. Anytime you you you know
this packages, okay, let me show you
guys some. Okay, so this is Melp. So you
got one, you know, you know, you got
like 10,000 more than 10,000 packages,
okay, on Melpa. Okay. So when you need
whatever you guys use, you know, like I
complete or whatever. I don't use any.
Okay. Because I've been coding eag this
for too long, 20 years. So So I So I'm
old. So I don't use any.
But but anyway, anytime you download a
package that uses uh this okay dash okay
so let's say
this
dash okay anytime you download a package
that has dashes dependency bang it okay
like stop using that package
idiots this dash is a it's kind of one
of the it so happens okay I don't want
to um
okay so so the maintainer now changed.
Okay, so it was uh by Magna Swing about
15 years ago around 2008, but now the
maint maintainer change. Okay, but
anyway, this is the most idiotic harmful
package today. Okay, the dash the idiots
and this is this one dash is the most
popular among all these 10,000 or
100,000 packages on Malpa. Okay, because
you can go to Melpa, you'll see it's the
most popular. Why? Because it's oh, it's
a modern, easy to use uh uh library for
list in Emacs. insulting and
offensive idiots. And if you use it, you
look at the code, it's like doing list,
you know, every it tries to force you
everything into list, not vectors, not
other appropriate data type, just list.
and it claims it is modern
so that it writes a wrapper calling the
list go functions. It creates a wrapper,
slow it down, create a wrapper. But the
syntax looks better because looks more
familiar to the modern Zoomer idiots who
came from closure list or whatever, you
know, they they don't want to deal with
the old, you know, the eac list, you
know, which began 40 years ago from
Macisp and so on, you know, the the the
cons or whatever. They want the modern
interface, you know, for closure API.
So, so they got rappers. So, they they
use the dash. Okay. But
the result is your code becomes slow you
know like when you use oh why is my emac
you know like you don't know because you
don't know it's caused by this dash or
whatever because that's so many layers
down you are just using whatever top
level programming language packages or
or whatever but you know
okay that answers your question
okay about whether you slow down emacs
do you even try to write some logic in C
compile so far so is people say it's
faster than this do even try
uh okay I think I think that's it for
today uh
thank you do you not use oak mod at all
no I don't use oak mod Okay. I also
that's kind of the question I answered.
A lot of people want to know. Uh
mod I don't use. It's pretty good. Well,
the reason I don't use mostly because I
grew up in with HTML. I watched the
birth of HTML in 1993.
So when HTML was born in around 1990 or
so, I was there. So I started to use it.
I started to use the internet HTML
around 1992 or three. Okay. So I watched
the birth of JavaScript. I watched the
birth of CSS. So back in 30 years ago, I
started to code HTML manually, tag by
tag. That means I t type. Okay, you
can't even uh manually type them. Okay,
so I type now they they come with a
completion. Okay. [laughter] So anyway,
I tag I Okay. So let's go to So this is
how I do.
So type the beginning uh tag. Let's say
P. Okay. Then you want to magnify this.
Okay. So can you see?
Okay. So this is how you write HTML. So
this is how I write HTML. 30 years ago
1990 I started to write HTML 1996. Okay.
So P. So, HTML. So, let's start uh HTML.
Okay. Uh stop. Okay. So, HTML start and
stop. Uh press press
press press. And you need a header.
Okay. So, you need uh copy. Convenient.
Powerful convenient. Uh copy paste.
Okay. So, then you need a body. Oh,
yeah. So, you need a body. So, this is
how I do uh wrote HTML.
Okay. Okay, so you need your backslash
and uh and then this is the important
part. H1 header. Hi mom.
Okay, you guys understand? So this is
HTML. I was literally, you know, typing
every character in in the beginning.
That's Microsoft Word. And because I'm
very studious and advanced, I read the
entire manual of Microsoft Word in 1992.
So I have created lots of a brief just
like my Emacs. So in Microsoft Word,
they have that feature allows you to
have a brief and templates and outline.
you know in Microsoft world which is one
of the most advanced robust powerful
perfect software back in 1992 from
Microsoft that is why they become very
powerful you because they create what
one of the greatest software Microsoft
world okay so I was originally using
that so so I I you know so I grew up
with HTML I watch it you know and CSS
and JavaScript
So, Oakmod was born in again Oakmod was
born if you read my tutorial Oakmod was
born in um like 2007 something search it
you'll find it okay just search for OG
mod so I have lots of tutorials about
mod soar came from this professor he
want to take notes uh when he was a
student you know but um so he created
oak mode
And after years he became a professor
you know so this is old history but I
myself I don't use old mode
okay bye.