e
e e
Audio Oh my [ __ ] that's incredible bad
experience no audio for the first five
minutes or so but hello welcome to
another episode of talk show let me
repeat the whole thing again and great
to see you Smartboard uh
VAB great to see you so I owe you a lot
so I owe you a lot so today um you know
I'm going to talk about
Smartboard if you guys haven't seen
already uh where is the camera okay so
the SW board you know this is a
fantastic input device uh you know uh a
very Advanced input device audio check
video check am I good to go hey hello
guys uh arid
duck uh Molina and small board so so
this is a you know fancy Advanced input
device magnetics which is fantastic but
I'm sorry um uh VAB I haven't been able
to um I'm not ready to demo it yet so
but yeah I wanted to mention but there's
um but but but you you're going to demo
okay so let me show you my screen okay
let me let me show you my keyboard and
then I'll show you uh my screen so this
is glove 80 fantastic this is Ultimate
hacking keyboard fantastic okay and let
me show my screen let's see audio okay
finally I have audio so the you know
because you know so I haven't done this
yet because this is kind of you know
because I'm going to I imagine I'm going
to use
this like for a year you know like
longterm my permanent keyboard so it's
so I kind of delayed um and uh you know
and I've been uh busy coding so this is
a long-term project you know so I you
know I I think I'm going to like it very
much so a lot of people I think a lot of
people are interested you know pressing
me did you use Sao yet how is it
going but but I cannot say you know I'm
ready yet and and yesterday you know I
um yeah I'm very ashamed actually so so
I think actually I need to buy a uh
cable you know uh I need to buy the you
know the standard USB to uh cable uh yet
yeah I think so because but why don't I
show you guys uh since I'm talking about
it so you know people you can see
so it's um oh wait this is USB USBC so I
wasn't I wasn't you know really focused
the other day so USBC actually why don't
we plug it in so is there people uh
um so I was planning to you know either
talk about this if you guys have
questions and or and I'm going to talk a
lot about uh wolam language and emac
lisp
you know you guys should um visit um the
small board guy oh yeah I wanted to
mention uh the you know so so um SBO got
a Discord here and cren okay cren so
he's going to
demo uh he's going to do you know
building his SW board or data hand uh a
mon Monday I yeah smbo office hours so
can you guys see
it let's uh magnify Discord so small
board uh I so C is going to demo it on
Monday
10:00 Pacific time so that's San
Francisco time California time Monday 10
so you guys can can you know go uh check
out Monday 10:00 in the morning
so I think he's going to do a live demo
I mean building or answer questions on
uh on uh on Discord yeah so you
know so I uh Monday morning 10:00 I will
be uh watching so I I'll be here too so
fantastic okay so let me show show this
again so Fant fantastic device uh I just
got busy so I haven't uh done anything
with it
yet okay so that's one thing and yes and
he uh got me all the best cables it's
truly great you know this these
expensive
cables so anyway
uh so any anything else so um yeah swab
Bo so I'm not ready to demo it so um
yeah okay so actually I
can you know I wonder if I should I
should I live and try it you know just
plug it
in uh yeah I'm in a terrible state so
you know it's been 3 month I haven't
plugged it in yet
um so let's see yeah so USB on one
side Okay so USBC on one side USBC plug
into the keyboard but the other yeah but
my computer doesn't have the
USB a I think you know the big one
so so yeah I cannot put get it in yet
I'll get the
cable so I'll get a
cable uh you know I'm doing some Amazon
shopping
store yeah so I cannot demo it um
let's
see yeah okay so Monday you know let's
go check out uh Clen is going to do a
video demo on Discord okay so uh what is
the Discord uh link let me get
it uh
invite
[Music]
people copy invite link expire in seven
days so I'm going to post the link
here Discord
live live
demo of small
board
Monday 10 a.m.
okay oh you got some magnetic too okay
uh yeah okay let me talk to you
offline uh yeah uh AR I'll definitely
like to see you trying it out yeah I'll
do that for sure because you know I
haven't done so because this is going to
be you know I imagine I'm going to be
using it for a long
time so let me give you guys some update
on uh what I've been doing so it's been
a long time I miss you guys um you know
you know because I love to talk a lot so
let me talk about you know wam language
update and uh emac list okay so today's
talk show yeah so let's
see woohoo wo F language
version
14 new logo beautiful
logo so there it is wam language uh
14 so I finally got it so let's see what
else so I've been doing WFAN language
Graphics programming so if you search
for Exile wam Language tutorial you'll
see you know the complete tutorial for
wolam language and uh the latest update
is wam language Graphics programming so
for example you can create all these for
example this one is just you know two
lines of code three lines of code so the
I have been updated the wolam language
uh Graphics programming so you you can
see the full tutorial from the groundup
this uh tutorial is for programmers so
you uh the graphics programming is kind
of advanced so you go here so all these
articles are updated and lots of them
are new so for those of you uh you know
starting to learn with language and you
can download it free of course you know
so
there okay so let's see
next okay so that's about wam language
now I think the rest of the talk is
going to be emac dis lots of emac dis
stuff okay wam language besides Graphics
there's a lot updates you know wam
language symbols they are just like imag
symbols Okay so then then go land
regular expression Parell manage manage
Parell
profile
um okay let me uh talk about the latest
things I've done with emac
LP so you just go
to c
emx tutorial or blog C emx
so you'll find c emx
tutorial and uh go down go to the
blog so there is two two major updates
in the past two or three weeks so one of
them is sequence functions
so emac started to have a set of uh
sequence functions for list list and
vector and array about 7 years ago and
now they're being very mature so it's
fantastic so you can see them
here uh update update uh so sequence
functions
so let's see lots of updates so I
updated the complete complete tutorial
on wolam language sequence functions you
see the sequence Library is a major emac
list Milestone new in
2016 so now I have a complete documented
annotated documentation for example
sequence functions you go here and you
can see all these so what is a sequence
a sequence is is basically a list or a
vector like a array so all these
functions will work on any of list or
array or string string is also a
sequence so in emac list so there's a
lot uh so all these sections are
sequence functions and they are
fantastic you know a lot people uses the
dash
Library
Maad Dash which is a third party library
for doing sequences so you can
see if we turn on
JavaScript so how many how many how many
people are watching five hi if if you
are here say hi okay so any questions
post
it uh so you can see all these uh Dash
so here is a dash function on GitHub I
mean not function the dash Library so
the dash Library really sucks you know
it's one of the huge damage to the emac
lisp you know this Dash Library began
about seven uh about 12 years ago or
something and it became hugely popular
it's created by this guy uh a great guy
but the library is not so good because
it because it focuses on list and
doesn't work on vectors and this this a
few things I consider abusive for uh uh
for example it doesn't follow the naming
conventions of EAC list
uh it doesn't follow a lot a lot of
conventions of emac disp instead it
borrows the convention the naming
convention or the
programming uh semantic you know
parameter convention from closure
lisp so anyway so I'm not a fan of this
package but because this package became
hugely popular you know got you know you
can see it's got It's one of you know
it's the most most popular use uh
popular use language you can see let's
see ma pass stable uh let's go to MAA
you can
see it's got the most download on MAA 5
million download so because it became
you know why is it created it was
created because emac list sucks you know
you don't have all you know you don't
have a function that do something with
the list so it suck so bad so this guy
created Dash so it became hugely popular
and then the G emx people saw that and
they panicked you know so and I also
made a video like two two or three years
ago you know saying how suck suck it is
then so now we have the sequence
functions Library which is fantastic so
that solves that problem so if you are
still using Dash you know if you like
almost any of these you know if you
download any emac this emac package from
from malpa you will see um you'll see
they require using Dash that's no good
so that's why I I think you know I say
it's a huge damage to the imag this
community so uh so am I interesting am I
still interesting are you guys
interested in this
topics for people Okay so
so the what is wrong with
Dash uh quite a you know quite a few
things
uh yeah quite a few things I'm not I I'm
not going to get into unless uh you guys
want uh you know want me to talk about
that so anyway so emac
sequence functions fantastic so for
example for example uh you
have sequence find so this will you know
let you find a element in a in a list or
in a vector and it can it can also
return the position of the vector and it
can
also you can find an item by a
function and you can also get the total
number of count of some criteria of in a
Leist so you know these are common you
know commonly needed
functions usually available in in goand
in other languages hascal FSH python but
they are not in emac L for a long time
so this is a great um Improvement
okay that's about the sequence functions
so I have a you know like tutorials with
the you know usage examples for
that and another major update is um if
you go to the emac this tutorial the
other major
update I spent a month Al also about it
is writing a major mod so this tutorial
tells you how to write a major mod inac
this for example if I'm creating a new
language new programming language like
that this is actually wolam language
Syntax for example you know I wanted
syntax color how do you do write how do
you do that you want write the major mod
so you can do simply by uh let's
show split the window new buffer so
that's it just five lines of
code okay so I evaluate the buffer oh
buffer is not okay so let's save
itel okay evaluate it go back here then
meta
x uh what's the name my math mod okay
meta X my math mod do it ah you can see
you got syntax coloring so that's how
simple it is
to write a major mod then then you can
read on about a lot other things you
might want to do for example you want
name completion you want type INF and
expand
to Infinity for example you want to add
that
feature so uh you can read them you know
it's all here it's pretty simple so all
these sections has been updated
okay that's
that
uh cut close back to talk show and let's
put uh code
here major mod let's
put yeah so
there showing browser
anything
else so emac major major lisp tutorial
major emac lisp tutorial update major
mod sequence functions how to write the
major mod iMac dis you uh unit testing
okay so there is a new
um new tuto tutorial on emac list unit
testing so if you just search for it
there it is so this is how
you uh write a unit test for
functions okay so
next so emac lisp you know I declare
emac lisp is the best thing today it's
the best lisp better than common lisp
and skim thisp because it is the most
practical and and it is the most
practical and it is the most widely
used said yes yes yes
what okay so emac disp then there is
this fantastic emac disp uh
article two of them actually so one of
them is the imag this spite code
manual so if you go here uh emac this B
code manual so this is uh a lot of
technical details like normally if you
are new to emac disp you don't need to
know it but if you've been coding emac
disp for for a while this this uh you
know this this article is very
interesting so this is emac this bite
code manual so that's one thing the
other thing is
the other
article is iMac history written by
Stefan monia and Michael spur uh spur
spur here so this is a fantastic article
I liked it very much evolution of emac
this this is a very technical article
going
into technical detail on emac this the
programming language of its history so
you can read about how various features
came about and uh how they are how they
were designed how they changed uh things
like that so I find this article very
very uh
interesting for example dark doc string
you know today
almost every programming language allow
you to embed a
documentation for a function for example
in
Python uh in Ruby and and you know in
lots of other languages has this feature
in wolam language
to uh but and this
feature is you know emac this is the
first one the first programming language
that creat created this this
concept okay so that's iMac this so
that's you know so I learned about this
from this from this essay so that is
Fant you know that's a example why I
think this is a great
article okay any anything else hello
hello
Leon how did you find me did you did you
did you uh came here to see keyboard or
programming or or
what so let's go to so I think you know
I'm just I'm kind of doing random and
uh today I'm kind of doing random let's
see if there's anything I wanted to talk
about emac this
P3
uh so you know I haven't been doing
video for like two weeks you know I
really want to but I I promise the next
one is going to be swb so but I just
wasn't ready yet so that kind of delayed
so that also means I didn't do you know
emac this or wam language so but but I'm
going to start to do them frequently
like every two or three days again live
stream and then and also get on to the
SW board
okay any anything else you guys ask
questions I especially like when you
call zumas yes the Zuma
idiots you know okay let me let me talk
random you know so I was looking into
the Indian God Hindu religion
because because on Twitter
I run
into Modi you know the Indian
leader so you can see he is here is his
Twitter
account or X Cod
x
uh and I I'm not logged into Twitter if
I log in and then I have to type some
code uh
[ __ ] uh
oh actually I have a Blog about it so
let me show my
blog Indian goddess Shiva actually it's
not a she but anyway so this you know
the Narendra Modi the Indian leader he's
got a Twitter and you can see he's got
this photo for his profile and that is a
commonly
seen well I don't know about you guys
but for Asian for for Chinese you seen
you have seen this before so so I but I
never knew what is this God about so I
looked into so apparently you know he
you know this is you know a guy mostly
you know because in Indian religion I
mean they sometimes they don't have a
gender but anyway this is most this is a
guy so he is one of the three most uh
worshiped God in India in
Hinduism and you know so I realized I
found out that Indian religion is quite
sexual so this
God and you know this God you know looks
like that you know you know he he's also
known as the king of dance dance
king and so this God has and has this
wife this is his wife okay and then you
can see all the sculptur you know all
these are Asian you know Asian
sculptures this this one is uh 400 years
ago uh that's his wife shiva's wife and
then they have you know one of their
their children is this elephant guy
ghisa uh you know so that's one of their
children and
uh it's very interesting because I've
seen this elephant head or or you might
you probably have seen if you live in
America in California every time you go
to Indian restaurants or have Indian
friends um so I never know anything
about it but apparently this is a child
of this Shiva and this this
um prata pravati you know each one of
these have several
names and and it you know it seem you
know apparently the history of Hinduism
is very sexual so because so let me show
you a example from Wikipedia
okay so there is
Shiva you know he you know like they
they usually comes in many
forms so there's that there that there's
that
there's that beautiful you know this
this old Asian sculptures beautiful so
here you know
thear sculpture something dep depicting
Shiva with a
goddess pavati as his equal
half okay so the icon is presented as
Half Men and half
women oh okay so the left half is Guy
the right half is women woman uh
and um and the thing so this is the you
know they they and their
children the elephant
god but the thing interesting is that if
you go here then you go to you you find
lingam okay so they have this linga
thing lingam okay you know what you know
the English
article doesn't isn't very explicit you
read it you don't know what it is but
this thing is basically a penis a
penis that's represent Shiva and this
thing is vagina that represents his wife
so and you know so that so you can see
the Asian sculptures of
them uh and there is
that um you know so the English article
is not very clear you know so you can
see here this sculpture is clearly one
giant
penis but if you read the Chinese
version so if we go back to the Shiva
article and you go read the Chinese
version then you can quickly find out
all these
things uh they'll just say it directly
there it
is so this is that Ling gam thing and in
here you can see you know the sculptures
of it it just directly tell you it's a
penis okay and also there's this you
know yesterday I read this
interesting
um do I still have collected seashells
yes I think
somewhere uh let me answer the questions
okay fantastic question I love
them so um yeah let me finish about this
Shiva
thing so you can
see so I I learned about this
yesterday oh the yeah this is the
Chinese version for the you know for the
vagina uh so this is a penis and the
vagina is called
this you know the Chinese article is
very short it just directly tell you
what it is and same thing for the Ling
gam but if you read the English article
it's like you know they are
doing they are you know writing a
esoteric way and kind of
deny you know they don't tell you what
it
is so this is very interesting because
you can see the kind of the history or
Orion of the Indian religion which I
don't know you know too much about but
you can see that it is
from you know the Indian president you
know has this Shiva sculpture then you
look at Shiva then you can you know then
you get her story his wife then you got
this thing that represent Shiva that you
know this basically a penis then you got
this thing that represent her wife
basically a
[ __ ] uh so that's
interesting okay
next uh do I still have the seashell
diag uh seashells
yes so go to Art
blog OD blog seashells yes I still have
them
somewhere uh these are beautiful the
most beautiful thing on earth
you know they are beautiful because you
know I find them extremely beautiful so
this is like 20 years ago I collected
some of them you can buy them on
eBay you know so I find them amazing
because you can see they are all Spirals
and this has to do with mathematics
let's see yeah let me show you
that so actually in one of the live
stream I we did live coding of this
thing so you can use you know
mathematically you can model them as
spirals so here is a wam language code
so actually why don't we just run
it there it is okay there it
is fantastic so you see the thing
interesting is is that then you can have
many varieties You Can Have Wrinkles and
you know all sort of varieties the way
they
trst uh yeah actually this this this is
fantastic we did this like two or three
years
ago fantastic wolam
language so you can
see the different ways they twist and
wrinkle and and and so
on uh and about the seashells so you can
see you know they can be they can also
have like needles though they can be
like that you know very little
TST this is called a Tusk
shell and you have this kind of flat
thing top
shell and then you have the patterns on
them this is supposed to be can be
generated by cellular
automat Stephan W's favorite
subject uh truly beautiful then you have
this very pointed
one and then you have this one this this
one is so beautiful this one is super
light you see this is almost transparent
very fragile you know you can just crush
it uh but it's just amazing you know
it's it's like this
big paper notus shell you can you know
many of them are cheap you know $5 $3
you can get on Amazon and and this one
for example why is it I find it
fascinating because you can see this one
showcases the patterns on it you know
amazing patterns that can be modeled
with Sil autom in fact it
is the way it is generated is is is is
by cellular
automet uh yeah so amazing yeah I have I
I I I think I still have them somewhere
in a
box thoughts on scheme shell what is the
fastest
shell so you are talking about the shell
programming
language uh there was a shell scheme
shell but it's
dead it's dead for like 15
years let's see if I can find my
article there it is UNIX pestilence
shells so this I wrote 20 years
ago and Bash is very old of course bash
is the classic bash then you have schim
shell uh but unfortunately schim shell
seems dead there's no update since 2005
also so oh look look at their website
you even you know they
got certificate
expired you know so I don't you know so
anyway this scheme sh but you know schim
shell is written by this famous guy kind
of famous uh guy o oen shivas he's now a
I believe he's a MIT
Professor uh 20 years ago I'm not sure
about
now so he's a great designer you know
he's a Unix hater like me most you know
many skin people we hate Unix and he you
know he's also famous for writing a
prologue I believe prologue to the
scheme shell you know documentation
saying that you know he did it all by
himself very
funny and
um
so but I don't think you know the lisp
syntax is really suitable for
Shell uh for example let's look at some
lisp syntax let's go to soft keys
uh so you have syntax like that full of
nested parentheses when you have nested
syntax I don't think it's suitable for
Shell you in a shell because in a shell
you need to constantly type and enter
But when you have nested syntax it's
very hard to edit for example you have
to go to all the way to the beginning to
type the you know for example let's copy
that paste it here make it long one line
uh make it syntax color so when you type
if you make a mistake you have to go you
know you have to balance the parent so I
don't think it's a good idea in a shell
language syntax design you want it to be
you want the syntax to be linear
linearized linearized
meaning that you avoid any sort of
nesting so you don't have nesting at all
at as as much as possible
so most shell languages follow kind of
Follow That Syntax for example power
shell
uh so but anyway there it is skem shell
but it's kind of
dead now your question which is uh
fastest shell I what do you mean
fastest in Shell usually you you don't
care about
speed because if you care about
speed then you need to put a lot of
things in your language for example
types C
C++
Java you know when you
have you have to De uh declare types for
the variables you are going to
use and if you do that your code becomes
more cumbersome you know one line
becomes five or
10 and so it's not suitable for Shell
because in Shell you just want to type
something for example CD
web okay uh
CD info
okay so let's see let's do the let's
magnify the
LS let's say I want to
know you know in all these directories
the total number of files so to do that
you can
do the
because
file uh yeah file I only want files I
don't want
directory and uh let's say
filter so
asterisk HTML I want all files ending in
HTML and I want Count how many of them
total so you can do
that I believe so let's try
it there it is so I have
8,600 HTML files under the.info so you
see one single line this is what you do
in sh often you know you do this all day
if you are CIS
admin so this one line if you try to
convert this in python or Ruby or even
Pearl or in any nonell language
especially lisp you're going to have
like 10 lines so this is the beauty of
the
linear linear syntax so this syntax
avoids nesting as much as possible
and also it doesn't have types if you
going to if you have a shell that
requires you know type then it's it's a
it's it's more of a problem and there's
a lot of shortcuts for example this as
risk HTML actually is a string but you
do not need to quote it it just quoted
for you so lots of this little
conveniences so when you have a sh
language with you know like that
there are some disadvantages too if you
design a programming language like that
because then when you write the long
program let's say 10,000 lines then it
becomes you know many things can mean
many
things uh so you have less control you
you have less
precision and you may have bugs that's
hard to find out what you know where the
BG come from so that's some of the
disadvantages of
linear
linearized uh how do you say it linear
so let let's see actually I think I have
an article on
that let's see magnify
wait magnify linear so linear algebra
okay we love linear Al
so
linearization okay I think that's how
you would say let's say so look up there
it is that's there is a word
linearization you want to
linear um wait
this linearize okay you want to
linearize the programming syntax so this
is very interesting and I think I have
article on that so let's try try to find
it uh
search there it is share languages and
the linearization of
syntax uh this is just a quick write up
but you'll get some idea
about you know what you need to do okay
that's about that I think that's it for
today is 1 hour
uh in my house we repeat your famous
phrase every day default emx key winding
will [ __ ] up your fingers that is true
in your house what which house is
that okay that's it for today I think um
so I'm going to start to do live stream
more
frequently about every two or three days
you know especially because I haven't
done so in the past two weeks I'm very
itchy you know to do live stream to tell
you uh guys about
things and uh let's go back to today's
talk show let's see what else uh so I'm
going to start to do live stream fre
frequently again then I'm going to you
know start to uh get onto this uh SW
board data hand SW board
anything
else oh there's another great tip for
you emac people so I found out how do
you have the mini buffer with larger
font in mini buffer so you just go
to let's go to emx blog search for mini
buffer uh mini buffer there it is emac
in it mini buffer Fone size you just put
this in your emac in file then you have
you can have bigger font whenever you
know it pops up you
know uh for you to type a command or
file
name okay that's it I think that's it
yeah then I'm going to start to do
there's a lot to do I'm going to code
you know in in the next few live stream
emac list programming wolam language
programming uh let's go to talk show
let's see what else
so don't forget on this on
Monday
Monday 10:00 in the morning San
Francisco time you go to SW board
Discord you can find the link I'll put
the link in my uhan talk show too so
there it is the
link or just you just search for swo
Discord I think you'll find it find the
invite link
uh
then let's
say yeah swo
Discord there it is the link let's
linkify it uh file not exist
what uh this
is yeah something wrong with my code
anyway so that's the link and
then Monday 10 a.m. San Francisco time
on Discord
okay oh there is a oh oh German Molina
so there's a wolam language tip so let's
see language
data let's see what that
does oh that's how you generate a
keyboard layout oh interesting
wow keyboard image entity language
Spanish wow it can generate that I
didn't know so recently someone was
asking in my YouTube comment how do you
generate a keyboard it's not you right I
don't think it's you someone was asking
that very interesting thank you bye guys
fantastic seashell I forgot about the
seashell for a
while uh oh yeah so there is the
crosssection you know someone cut it up
so you can see it's also Twisted
inside very incredible and here you know
so it's Ted
inside and there is also x-ray so you
know then you have this this shape
Thatcher shell this one is is called
Thatcher shell so you can see part of it
is flat so you can think of this one as
a triangular profile so you kind of
rotate a triangle around the spiral then
you get that
one uh then you have ribs like that and
you have this
exotic you know beautiful this is
amazing extremely beautiful exotic thing
lat laic is my way shell and then you
have other exotic shell like
that so that's
seashell uh amazingly
beautiful oh yeah so here is some x-ray
photos bye