Good morning. Good morning.
Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Xah Talk
Show.
We are going to code Wolfram Language
today. Wolfram Language. Uh so, this
today we're going to code seriously
serious
uh Wolfram Language coding.
So, this would be of interest to those
of you who are into Wolfram Language
Mathematica doing geometry plane curves.
So, we are going to write Wolfram
Language code to create
uh general purpose code to create
caustics, which is
given a plane curve and given a light
source, the light source shine rays onto
the curve and reflect off the curve. So,
this is a illustration of
caustics. It's called caustics.
Uh so, it's you know, the study of
optical properties uh called is called
caustics.
So, we are going to uh create a general
purpose code
to draw
these reflection rays or refraction rays
for any given curve.
Um so, we we started to do it last week
uh and here's a code. So, let's show the
code.
It runs, but it needs refinement, okay?
So, starting Wolfram Language, if you
don't know already, we did a lot
introduction to Wolfram Language. So,
okay. So, in case you don't know, let me
take
2 minutes to introduce you guys Wolfram
Language, okay? Wolfram Language is a um
is the most uh powerful advanced
programming system.
It was known as computer algebra system
30 years ago, but Wolfram Language
expanded, so it can do
uh today it's for you can think of it is
like 10 times more powerful than Python,
okay? Can do uh neural network, machine
learning,
uh solving equations, and derivatives,
integrals, and uh
um
number theory,
differential equations, all all
mathematics, prime numbers, crypto
uh cryptoanalysis,
uh and machine learning and graph
theory. So, it's like you can you can
kind of think of it as 10 times more
uh
powerful
than
Python, you know, the entire Python
libraries and stuff, okay?
So, and you can download, but however,
you have to pay like very expensive few
thousand dollars a year or something
like but you but today they have a uh
kind of free version you can download
for free. So,
all you have to do is just search for go
to my website xahlee.info, okay?
Uh xahlee.info.
So, you go to my website
xahlee.info, okay? Then you go to uh
go to uh Wolfram Language. So, this I
have lots of mathematics Wolfram
Language tutorial. Go there Wolfram
Language tutorial by Xah Lee, my name,
okay?
Uh you'll find it on the web and the
Wolfram Language download. So, there is
download. Go there and go to this
website wolfram.com/developer.
So, you can download the Wolfram Engine
for free.
Uh you need to turn on JavaScript. You
need to, you know, give your email and
agreement, you know, and stuff. Then you
can use it for free.
Um
or I recommend you just buy it. I bought
it like 30 years ago in beginning in
1992.
two. It is my first programming language
actually and I studied it I coded it
every day few hours a day uh for the
next, you know, for like 7 years in
1990s.
You know, af- after after 2 years it got
me a job at Wolfram Research.
So,
so I've been coding Wolfram Language for
30 years, okay?
So, um
you know, so I did a lot videos like
tons of videos. So, so you know, you
download it and also read my article,
you know, the differences and okay, you
can also get it from Raspberry Pi.
Uh differences bet- between Wolfram
Engine, Mathematica, Wolfram Language,
Wolfram Script, like what are they? Why
is so so many different names? So, you
can read about it and you also you want
to download the Jupyter
extension for Jupyter so that you can
have graphical interface, okay? Like we
do a lot of graphics.
Okay, so that's kind of so you want to
download this, okay? That's kind of the
kind of the introduction and and um
and I have done
over 100 videos on Wolfram Language. So,
some of the best ones can be seen on
this page Wolfram Language tutorial by
video Xah Lee or search on my YouTube,
okay?
So, I've done 100 videos on Wolfram
Language.
And the particularity, you know,
fascinating. I mean, the most beautiful
for example are these things, okay? For
example,
you know, here you can see the power of
Wolfram Language.
So, you see, that's a code. Shift enter.
Then here is a result.
Amazing. Is that beautiful? It's just
amazing, okay? It's control scroll to
like um
Wait, I I want to control um
shifts.
Wait.
Too many devices, trackball and mouse.
So, what is the uh
So, you can okay. So, yeah. So, you can
you see then you control um
Then you can you see? Beautiful. You can
you can magnify, you can zoom, you can
pan graphics, you see?
So, I don't want it too large. So, wait.
Yeah.
I have sticky keys on. That's why you
hear the beep. When I press control, it
held the control. That's why it seems
confusing. So, you see? Fantastic. This
is my favorite thing, geometry. This is
coding version. Uh in fact, we coded
live 3 years ago in 2023.
Uh okay. So, you see the the power of
Wolfram Language, okay? That's a short
introduction. So, shift control N to
make it typeset so you can see all these
became fractions and so on.
Okay. So, that's the introduction, okay?
But today we're going to really
I've been wanting to code this. Let's
just focus on coding this um
this
um
this caustics, okay?
Hello. If you are here, say hi. Hello.
NHQ.
Have Have you been on this channel
before? Have you used Wolfram Language
before? Are you a student? Or are you
interested in mathematics or something?
Are you learning math math? Or are you
maybe a professional?
Uh mathematician? Or are you a
carpenter? And are you in Africa? Or are
you in
Arab Middle East? Or are you in Japan?
Like
who are you?
You know, just for chat, okay? So, if
you are here, say hi. If you are not
here, play it play this video at 1.5
speed. Okay, video check, audio check,
okay? Let's start to code, okay?
So, we we we've talked about this kind
of introduction to death. So, we want to
do let's uh so, let's
start to So, from now on from this point
on, I'm going to code and this is going
to be like serious
um
Wolfram Language technicalities, okay?
Like like really uh deep. Uh so, most
people we all you we all not understand
it, okay? By the way, so this is this is
this curve is called nephroid. When you
roll a circle outside of the circle
such that the rolling circle is half the
size half the radius of the fixed
circle. Then you put a
dot on the rim of the circle a chalk or
pencil, it trace out this curve. It's
called nephroid, okay? And it can also
be formed if you shine a light parallel
rays
onto a circle, the reflection you see
this reflection will form
the nephroid.
In In other words, we say the envelope
of the reflected rays is
nephroid, okay? Is this nephroid. So,
there are so many ways to generate it.
Uh so, and today we're going to code
this, okay? Now, of course, I already
have the code. You just do that. Uh so,
so for example, uh
copy.
Go back here.
Uh let's let's run this, okay? Shift
enter. Let's uh this too huge. 125,
okay?
Okay, that's good enough.
So, you see so paste that. So, shift
enter.
So, you see beautiful you
you know, I have random color on. You
see random color. So, every time
I run this code I get a new picture of
different color. Fantastic. So, but this
code requires my package.
Search for it. You'll find it on the web
on GitHub plain curve plot by Xali.
Okay, but I don't want
packaged version. I want the gen
generate
you know, so people can
people don't have to download the
package. People can just run the code
and show the graphics. Okay, so here's
the code. So, it's going to be much
longer. You see.
But, you know, 50 lines. Okay, so you
see. So, if we run this
run it you see it's not done yet. Last
time we we started to do it it's not
done.
We're going to continue this. Okay, so
from now on it's going to be um
advanced.
This is
fantastic coffee. This is milk
and instant coffee
and honey
and some coca.
So far so good. So far so good. So far
so good.
Okay, so let's begin coding. So, let's
let's do. Okay.
So, this is for people who
who who are interesting with from
language or already know something about
it.
Um and well, we want to go to now for
it. Okay, wait.
Yes, we're going to go here.
That's the page.
Uh
so, what is this? Okay, so
make a backup. Pop this out. So, here's
a code. So,
I need to start to Okay, this is going
to be Okay, this is going to be boring.
Okay. I don't know if I can explain too
much because
you know, it's it's not
it's you know, somewhat
it's not beginners for sure.
So,
so you'll just be watching me code and
boring. Okay.
So, again we are trying to make this
uh for example, you see this shrink
thing
you can make it better by
um
by specify probably it's not anyway.
Okay, so let's focus on the code.
So, the the most important thing is this
caustic GP. Okay.
That is the usage. Okay.
Okay, let me type this out.
deep interest in Wolfram language
or car
Mathematica. Okay.
Okay, so
this
Yeah, okay. Every time I do this I
realized
if I am if I am going to explain this
then I will never code it. You know,
it's I'm just going to spend 1 hour
explaining what's it's doing.
Uh so, then we'll start again.
So, I'm not going to I I can't I can't
do explain. I just need to code this.
Okay.
Uh
because if I explain that's not going to
be finished. Okay, but anyway
So, this is
the key function. Okay, it draws the
caustic lines and it needs several
improvements.
points tangent vector ray origin
So, it takes 1 2 3 4 four parameters
list of points list of tangent vectors
and one ray origin which is a pair of
numbers
and length. Okay.
Now, I don't want length to be part of
these functions. So,
I want a new function where it doesn't
specify length, but
um
but that may create efficiency problems.
You see
you got efficiency considerations
because
So, what this function do is that you
when you call it you give a list of
points. That's the points on the curve.
For example, that that that
then you give a list of tangent vectors
at those points.
So,
So, there is a tangent vector. So, let
me show you this image. Okay.
Um well, I started to explain, but um
that means I'm never going to code
nothing.
Uh where is my plot range?
Uh there's no plot range. Okay.
So, you need to specify
graphics caustic table. What is this?
Okay, so you see it's calling the
function the caustic line list of points
on the curve
and the list of the derivatives then
then the
um
Yeah, the list of derivatives then
the origin of the light source then
length. Okay.
Then
uh you need to uh say plot
Yeah, okay. So,
let's say nine.
Nine is the length. Okay.
So, let's
Okay, let's put that there. Let's open
new one.
Paste it. Okay, let's make it 125.
150.
Yeah.
125.
Okay.
So,
yeah, shift enter.
Okay, so you can kind of see that.
That's not good.
Uh let's see you see the length is a
problem. Let's say
you kind of need a plot range. Yeah.
Yeah, okay.
then you need to say plot range.
Plot range limits the graphics to
specific region. Okay.
So, typically you can say -1 and 1
-1 and 1 multiplied by
two
that will give you a rectangular region.
Shift enter.
Okay, so that's not big enough. So,
let's say nine.
Okay, so
let's say
What?
Okay, you see?
That's what we want.
Um
God.
Okay, so by the way, I got I got a
haircut. So, my wife cut it for me.
Now, it's a bit hot.
Uh
Okay, what you going to do now? What are
you going to do with that?
So,
So, we understand the purpose of this
function.
And now, but what does this function
what it does? So, with So, it's got some
uh local variable local constants.
Then
Okay, then the major thing is a if
statement, okay? If statement.
If the origin ray origin is equals to
zero, that that is the um
uh that is kind of the um
You know, let's use you know, get the
numerical result.
So, if the ray origin is at zero, then
you do this, okay?
Otherwise, you do this. So,
So, you you need to know the ray origin.
Why? Because it saves computation, I
believe.
You see, so you got two cases. One is
that
the other one is that, okay? So, you can
see there are two cases there.
You see, this if statement.
If the ray origin is at zero,
I mean, so zero means here. So, it then
you reflect let's see.
So, norm
length greater than length two.
Yeah, you see,
this is kind of redundant,
but it's somewhat make it faster, I
believe.
You see, you are drawing a line if the
origin is the light source ray origin is
um
at zero zero. You know, the length of it
norm norm norm means the length. So, if
it's a zero vector, means it's origin,
which you know, origin means
zero zero coordinate.
Okay, then um
you know, so so if the origin is at zero
zero coordinate, then you create
a bunch of line from zero zero to
to normalize
let's see. What are you doing? You are
trying to map that map that. This is the
first argument. So, from draw draw a
line from the point
from zero zero to the
normal vector
of the curve, then multiply by length
two, okay?
Uh
So, what is the length two?
Okay, length two is equals to the
absolute value of length.
What?
Okay, that's just length.
Oh, okay, because length can be
negative. When length length is
negative, you draw the uh
refraction instead of the reflection.
That is the by design of this code.
But, I didn't document it, did we? Did
I? Each line length is X length
including the reflected portion.
Yeah, I think if you specify a negative
value, it draw refraction instead. So,
right now it's drawing
reflection, okay? Right now it's drawing
reflection.
Uh
This this is not good, okay? Let's
What this is a sign, okay? We don't want
sign, okay? So, first of all, let's go
back to fix that.
We don't want you see, this is drawing a
sign curve. X sign.
So, if you change it to
let's say three to six, let's say zero
to six.
Then plot range from
uh what?
From zero to
six.
And Y is let's say two of that, okay?
Copy all.
Go back here, select all, paste, shift
enter.
You see? Can you see it's a sign curve?
You see the sign curve goes Let's let's
do that, okay?
Uh plot.
Let's write sign. One two Not one two
nine. What stupid default?
Zero to six, okay?
You need to add that um
Okay, so you need to show
show this graphics and
that
two of them, okay?
Now,
copy all.
Select all, paste, shift enter.
Fantastic. Can you actually see the sign
curve? Actually, it looks beautiful.
I'll just leave it like that.
You see? So, now this is doing
uh reflection. The ray is coming from
above.
Now, let's make the rays
let's say three two. Let's make the ray
at three two point, okay?
>> [snorts]
>> So, let's make the ray at three two. So,
three and two, okay?
Does that make sense? Copy all.
Wait, copy all.
Select all, paste, shift enter.
Fantastic.
See?
Fantastic. Kind of beautiful.
Let's make these let's say at four four
three, okay? Let's uh
four three.
Select all.
Select all, paste, shift enter.
Fantastic.
Now, let's make the
the line color to be cyan.
So, it
looks more like light.
Okay, so you want the line color, so you
want to do it um
So, this this this return graphics.
Okay, so you can see
this part.
Okay?
That
is is cyan the color? Yes, you can see
highlight.
Okay, so select all.
Actually, we can just like copy this
part.
Paste it here, shift enter.
Fantastic and beautiful, okay?
Fantastic and beautiful.
And
So, again, if you guys are here, say hi,
okay? Love to see your comments. If you
guys are here,
uh say hi.
Uh okay.
Okay, so now let's see.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, we got the color
We got the color
We got this uh
So, this
So, this if statement
You see, it's trying to kind of save
time.
I don't think we want to do that. If ray
origin is equals to zero, okay?
So, basically, it's trying to save time.
That's why.
Okay, let's see if highlight that, okay?
So, you see
Okay, man, that's right. So, we want
this is more generalized version.
Okay, so I don't think we need this uh
remove this kind of optimization because
if you really want to optimize, if you
are really concerned about speed,
you should use compile function.
You know, there is a compile function in
Wolfram language that
will make your function very fast for
for basically numerical computation.
So,
our code here, which is written 30 years
ago, I don't think it's it's not
necessary. I mean, this
Make sure, okay? Make sure the people we
deleted.
So, the code is basically the same
thing.
Okay?
Okay. We decided we going to we don't
need this if statement, okay? Delete
that.
Delete that.
Delete delete delete delete delete
delete. Okay, we don't need this if
statement.
Delete delete, okay?
Now, simpler.
Oh my god, the code is now actually much
simpler. Just just that.
Okay?
Um
Yeah.
Okay, so what's the next thing to do?
So,
let me think about.
Now, when when the length is negative,
it generates re- refraction, okay? I'm
pretty sure. So, we can try it here.
You see, these are reflections.
The light rays reflected, okay? Let's
see, can we make it red?
Let's see, the the Darth Vader color.
So, I don't like
you know, that I I like red, okay? Shift
enter.
Fantastic, okay?
Now, here
make a copy. Here, use if you want
refraction instead of reflection, then
you say
neg here, you give a negative length
for this caustic line
GP.
The last argument. The caustic line GP,
the GP means graphics primitive. That
That was my naming convention. Shift
enter.
You see, now it shows refraction. Can
you see the difference?
You see, reflection refraction.
Um they,
you know, if you don't know, like
suppose this is a
horizon, the ground mirror.
So, you have if you have a light coming
from here,
it hit here and bounce it off there,
right?
Hit and bounce off.
Now, what does refraction mean? So,
that's reflection, okay? Hit here and
bounce off there. That's reflection.
Now, what is refraction? Refraction is
basically whatever the
bounce off line,
the other part of the bounce off line,
so it become there.
You see, so
Does that Do I make sense? Okay, maybe
not. So, if I do
Let's see, a copy. Let me do a
screenshot like like like um
like let's do a
lecture.
Open with
uh
snip
photo snipping tool. Let's draw.
Okay, let me show you refraction, okay?
So,
r e f r a c t i o n.
Okay, so that's reflection.
And do
That's refraction, okay? So,
the way it works is that if you have a
line
and if you have a light ray
going this way, it
Okay, that's reflection.
This is refraction.
Okay, does that make sense?
Save this.
Yes.
Overwrite.
Now, close.
Okay? Reflection and refraction.
Okay, now back to the So, you can kind
of see here, too. Now, back to the code
to the code. So,
uh we didn't document here, so it we
want to say
We didn't document it here.
If
length is negative,
it draws refraction.
Okay?
So, make it better documentation.
Okay, so that is that.
But now, what else do you need to do?
So, you map threads. So, those are
constants, okay? So, those are
like constants.
Sign
No, wait. The sign
sign is only used once, so we don't need
it there.
Um
Now, I'm trying to remove the length
because I don't want the length.
You see, because
because this function
um
it gives you the uh
So, essentially, it gives you actually
two lines.
What it really should do is just
the refracted
the reflection line, not the two lines.
Hello,
MHD
MHDNA.
Um
So, [snorts]
um
So, you see, this is about function
design. So, this function right now,
it's drawing the lines
both from the origin to the curve and
the reflected portion.
Okay?
Um
But what you want is um
You see,
Yeah, what I want to separate them
Yeah, basically, the important part is
just this part.
Ray origin. So, uh this is the function
of the Let me do a more tricky things,
okay? So, copy that.
So, let's rewrite the code. Now, this is
about Wolfram language. We rewrite the
code in a in a different syntax. Right
now, you see this ampersand,
that means it's you got a function. You
got a pure function there, so-called
pure function, which means lambda. The
The ampersand means this is a function,
okay? Which which is this part, okay?
That's a postfix notation, ampersand.
Now, those pound sign, those are
arguments. So,
so in this code, it's a function lambda.
And whenever the pound one occur the
number sign one occur, that means the
first argument. So, that's the first
argument, first argument, you see?
And whenever pound sign two occur,
that's the second argument, okay? So,
this is a like a notate special
notation.
Now, let's change that to something kind
of more intuitive, okay?
So, let's write fun
and
and let's write this way. Remove the
ampersand.
Okay, so now we have a function and the
the we we want arg1 arg2, so um
let's say AABB, okay? Two arguments,
okay?
So, now replace all pound sign one by
AA.
That's the first argument.
Okay?
And replace pound sign two by BB, okay?
Pound sign
two
by BB. Do it. Okay? So, only one
occurrence, okay?
So,
this code and this code are equivalent.
They are
purely equivalent because Wolfram
Language they will uh
turn one into the other to the, you
know,
to all to full form before it actually
do any computation. So, these two are
exactly equivalent, okay?
So, let's
let's use uh this one, okay? Because
Now, let me ask you guys let me ask you
guys a question. Which one do you think
is more
intuitive? Which one do you prefer? Do
you prefer,
you know, this is a function, that or
that?
You see, we are mapping a function using
map thread. The first argument is a
function here or here. And we map it to
two lists.
So, map thread is like in Python you map
plus a zip.
Uh it allows you to map a function of
two arguments to two lists in parallel
kind of.
So, anyway, so do you pre- guys prefer
the
the shortcut, the lambda notation,
should the ampersand say ampersand
notation, or the full function
notation? So, let me
tell me that, okay?
So, hello cuz I you I'm good. Thank you,
guys. Colonial
cuz uh can you tell us your opinion and
experience on Windows 11? Greetings from
Brazil. Okay, that is a
frequently asked question to death.
Windows, you know, which operating
system, okay?
Uh window Okay, so let me give you two
minutes reply.
I promise it's not going to be 1 hour
rant because every time people ask me
that it I started to like talk about
So,
so Windows
today sucks.
Windows was best in 1999.
Windows NT, around there, okay? Windows
NT. 1998,
99. And around 2005, Windows Vista and
Windows
7 8, you know, something like that.
That's the best time that's the best
Windows, okay? Windows XP.
XP and then Vista something.
That's the best.
Uh you know, but just among the Windows
versions, that's the best Windows.
Windows NT, 1999, then Windows XP and
Vista, you know, around 2004 to 2008
something like that, okay? Or 2010.
Today, you know, since Window Window 10
sucks donkey ass, they become flat, lots
of problems, okay? Like I I have like I
I have lots of articles about that,
okay? Go to ksati.info.
Um okay, let me quickly show. Okay,
okay, this is beginning to become a
rant. It is, you know,
window
sucks, okay? So, you go to search for
uh
Not just not this one, okay? I have like
20 articles.
This one. Microsoft Windows flaws.
Uh when did I rename it flaws, you know?
There's a
like titling issue, whether should it be
sucks or flaws. You you can't find it.
Anyway, so search the web, you'll find
my website, Microsoft Windows sucks or
Microsoft Windows flaws. There are about
how many how many articles are there,
okay?
Uh how many articles? Let's say uh let's
say yeah, I okay, so how
many
yeah, I okay? They are about 50 articles
on why Windows sucks.
Everything in detail. Full detail
documentation. Why it sucks.
You know, for example, this one. Windows
Windows 10 beginning like five years
ago. Oh, we got we created Windows 10,
the pretty boys, [ __ ] They go on
stage, you know, they they they they are
cool. They tell you we we designed
Windows 10, you know,
metro design, whatever. [ __ ]
When you actually use it, you know, it's
like you can't tell which window begin
which window ends, you know, it's like
confusing, [ __ ] No borders and no and
shadow is not done well. So, it's it
basically just sucks, okay? You eat
unusable Windows 10.
The flat [ __ ]
Okay, that's one article. Then there's
dark theme problem. Oh, we started to do
dark theme, you know, dark theme, you
know, the beautiful. [ __ ] [ __ ] their
ass.
They say they got dark theme, okay? I
talked about this many times, you know.
So,
for example, I wrote this program, so
you can search it, you'll find it, okay?
Ks toggle dark theme, okay? So,
you see, that's PowerShell. Run it.
And my Wait, what?
Then my whole system become using dark
theme, okay?
You see, the browser is also dark now.
I'll go it back. Wait, I don't want
that.
Okay? Now, they are back to white theme,
okay?
And I have like 10 articles about dark
theme. Is it good for you? Is it really
good for you? What does science say? And
how do you do it in cascading style
sheet? So, search my website ksati.info,
you'll find like
five articles about dark theme itself,
okay?
Anyway, so one of the in- window problem
is that it says it got dark theme, but
not really, you know, like okay, dark
theme.
Then you go to Okay, let's open the
preference. Okay, dark, very good.
Then you go to like
Like this tons of [ __ ] that's just not
dark, you know, like
like frequently.
Uh
Okay, let me show you um
like uh let's get go to disk management.
What what the what the [ __ ] is this?
Didn't you say you you you you have dark
theme? What the [ __ ] is this?
[ __ ] Microsoft, okay? It turned, you
know, it's like not just this window, so
many all over the place. That's the
that's the situation with Windows. [ __ ]
them.
Like all this is building uh
application. This is not random, you
know, there's so many so many more,
okay?
Uh so many more. Let's go to disk
manager, let's event viewers, okay? You
know,
[ __ ] their ass.
Didn't didn't you say you have dark
theme? No, not really.
Okay, so I showed, you know, so this is
a problem of dark theme, you know,
Windows. It just just just sucks,
inconsistent, you know,
everywhere.
That's two problems, okay? Flat design,
flat [ __ ]
and
dark theme [ __ ]
[ __ ] their ass.
Then tiny font, okay?
Like today, you have Windows um, you
know, they say, "Oh, by the way, we so
advanced you can change the font size
system wide." Not really.
Because
>> [laughter]
>> bec-
You know, like just like before, you
know,
I increase for example, I already
increased my system wide font because
I'm getting old. I need bigger font,
right? I already increased system wide.
But over here, some of these special
application old they they don't change
size. It's impossible to read this tiny
text.
You see, you you can't, you know, so
this is event viewer which which is
critical in Windows. It, you know,
basically allows you to
tell you like what what what's going on
in your system. You can magnify like in
this window, you can magnify, but as
soon as you switch to other, they become
small again.
The [ __ ] unusable [ __ ]
Do you guys know what I'm saying?
Okay, I talked about this, you know,
many times. So, anyway, so
So, back to the why Windows sucks, okay?
So, you know, I explained this, so if
you
tell your friends to watch my video and
uh share my links, okay? Because I I
explained it so many times.
Uh okay, I'm going to stop very soon,
okay? Two two more minutes.
So, then then this the problem does not
stop there.
The tiny font, dark theme problem, flat
design problem, taskbar problem, lots of
problems, okay? I won't go into detail
now, but then there is this
Windows
world clock.
You know, wait where is um
New York?
New York is in South America. New York
is is where Peru is at, see?
Where is Cologne, Germany? Oh, it's in
South Africa. You see? This is Windows
application.
Can it possibly be more stupid? Like
some [ __ ] idiots.
How is this even possible? You know, the
Microsoft huge giant corporation. This
application, World Clock. By the way,
they fixed it, okay? So, let me show
you.
Okay.
They fixed it like few years ago.
So, now the you know, they
>> [laughter]
>> Anyway.
So, you see? This is part of Windows
application, 2021, okay? They show this
incredible. This this this is beyond um
understanding.
Now, when when when you know, Microsoft
is a huge billion dollars corporation,
right? They have, you know, testers.
They have like In In fact, they probably
pay millions of dollars. They spend
millions on just testing.
To make sure whatever change they they
they create on Windows still works,
right?
But but you have
you know, you you you you got then you
have situation like this. This is This
is not forgivable. It's not possible for
anyone not to see this.
You know, like
London appears in in Cologne, Germany
appears in South Africa. In Africa.
Yeah, I mean, in Africa Africa
continent. You know, and and the Moscow
appears
in in in South Pole.
Moscow appear in South Pole. Can you see
that?
It's impossible. Okay.
You see? This is very you know, So, if
you ask me what's going on, something
very dark is going on, okay? This is not
like normal. And this is not
I mean, it cannot even be possibly
intentional mistake. It cannot be
something, you know, it must be
something
very dark, okay? I'm I'm that This is
verging on to politics. I'm telling you,
so there's something very dark deep
state going on, okay? That's when you
when this kind of things start to
happen.
You ask me about what what I think about
Windows 11, okay? Well, I haven't got to
11 yet. All these are Windows 10.
Windows 11
did not improve much of it. Same [ __ ]
you know? All these still applies
Windows 11. So, anyway.
And so, there are many more
many more problems on Windows, okay?
Since Windows 10. It's the worst [ __ ]
okay?
Because the So, why is it so bad? Well,
and you know, Microsoft Are they stupid?
Stupid? No. They got They they pay
millions dollars, million billions to to
these very smart programmers there.
Something is wrong, okay?
Like like there's some dark thing going
on.
Okay, so it's it's not about, oh, maybe
they didn't think about it or they made
a mistake. No, there's something very
dark going on. Part of this is
intentional.
And they don't care. Because
the Windows by now it's so saturated it
doesn't improve, you know, you can
improve it or it sucks, doesn't matter.
They will still have the same number
people using Windows.
Uh you know,
because they they they they sell it, you
know, by pre-install on you know,
on machines and also USA government is
very much
supporting this because Microsoft is
USA, you know. Bill Gates. Bill Gates is
another very dark story, okay? So, it's
all kind of connected, so
So, why don't they improve it? Well,
they don't need to. You still, you know,
going to use it. Okay, that's the
situation. For most people, anyway.
Part of the reason is because the Linux
[ __ ] This The Linux people are
idiots. They they are brainless. That's
why. Because if if they are smart, you
know, the open source [ __ ] If they
are smart, Windows will be dead.
Why? Because you got a free
such much better and free
operating system. Why would anyone use
Windows? They would be dead long ago.
But the the Linux people turned out they
they are just idiots. The open source
babbling, okay? Including lots of you
guys. The open source Linux you know,
[ __ ] Linux Linux got lots of other
problems in in in design, too, okay?
So, anyway, you ask me about what what I
think about Windows 11. Okay, so these
are the problems of Windows 10 and
Windows 11. There are 52 articles, okay?
It sucks.
Uh okay, that that's about it, okay? So,
as far as operating system goes,
UNIX or Linux and Mac, the story is
pretty much turns out to be the same for
the past 30 years, okay?
You know, if you want really the best
experience, the best design, the best
one is Apple, okay? Apple Mac.
It's getting worse since Steve Jobs died
some 15 years ago, okay? But still today
Apple is by far the the better
between Windows, Mac, or Linux, okay?
So, you can use Apple. The problem with
Apple is that, of course, it's twice as
expensive.
You have to pay. You know, pay to play.
Every Every thing you buy, even the
mouse, same mouse. When it's for Apple,
exactly the same mouse. When when when
they sell it for the Apple customers,
it's like twice as expensive, you know?
So, Apple, you know, so and if you want
something average usable, this Windows,
okay? It's pretty bad, but you know,
if you want something incomprehensible,
you have to be a nerd. You have to be a
[ __ ] idiots like a nerd. You have to
spend 1 year diddling about, oh, what is
kernel? What is memory? What is
programming language? The [ __ ] I
despise them so much. And Emacs ring.
You know, the if you are this type of
people, you know, these [ __ ] Linux
people. Yeah, you have to spend 1 year,
2 years, 3 years to understand and to
the understand what is distro, Linux
distro, you know,
>> [laughter]
>> I like Arch Linux. You know, I think
this one or or the or the Gnome versus
you know, whatever [ __ ]
Okay, so
then
Linux is for you.
You know, you don't care about you know,
you don't you don't you know, you you
you you are a nerd.
You are an outcast of society already.
You are the little minority like one in
10,000, one in a million.
Like people don't care about [ __ ] about
you, you [ __ ] You you just know
about computers, you you you can't
socialize, you don't understand nothing.
Then Linux is for you, and it's free,
you know, you you open source [ __ ]
Okay, that's my summary. The best
operating system, Apple, okay? But you
pay twice, and it's actually also the
most secure.
Uh on Windows, it sucks donkey ass, but
it's kind of usable and kind of free,
kind of.
And then, you know, the Microsoft, they
get into your pants, they
>> [laughter]
>> they they
you know, then you know, if you want
like oh, you and you know, you are into
freedom and you don't mind you are nerd,
you don't know nothing except computers,
then Linux is the best, okay?
So, I want to tell you guys, you know,
because I know a lot people is going to
tell me most my readers are, you know,
the Linux open source type people.
They're going to tell you, "Son, you
need to use this this or that. Oh, oh,
by the way,
deep state whatever. [ __ ] them."
I don't give a [ __ ] about the Linux and
open source.
Okay, I didn't plan
to rant, but I did.
So, am I going to back to coding Wolfram
language? Okay, so actually we did well
today, but
that became a rant. Um
Okay, so is there any comment on Wolfram
language?
Uh
So, RK19, did I answer your question?
I think I spent 20 minutes, or was it 10
minutes, answer your question. Did I?
You need to say
You need to respond, okay?
Greetings from Brazil.
Now, image, you said my name, which
means you are really uh live. Some
people are saying you died.
Uh pre-recorded, which got me upset. Who
said that?
>> [laughter]
[gasps]
>> Who Who said that? [ __ ] stupid
people.
I am team functional notation.
Fantastic. Emacs is the best operating
system. Functional notation. Team
functional notation. Which mean what you
What do you mean? You mean You mean like
the ampersand.
Colonial, you mean the ampersand.
Okay, let's get back to this. Okay, so
Um
Yeah, God. We went into a rant. Let's
get back to this. Okay.
Uh
actually, I've been coding for We've
been doing this for 1 hour already.
Okay, so
Well,
let's continue.
Okay, we got like some people we got
nine people here. Okay, so
So, we got this version. I don't want
this version because the function
version is more readable. Okay.
So,
AA is the um
Okay, X point.
Uh
Okay.
10 vec.
Okay, let's change the name. So,
AA
change it to X point. Do it. Do it. Do
it. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Do it.
Okay. And BB change it to 10 vector.
Okay.
So, there.
I hope it's more readable. Okay.
And uh
haters are saying, I guess, so fake news
after all. Yeah, that's kind of strange.
I mean, that's
That's not just strange, but that's kind
of like
I think that's a joke. Would you know?
Like most I know a lot of people on
4chan
read, you know, they they read me and
post my stuff.
And so, that those are kind of the kind
of the type of things from 4chan. But
even on 4chan,
I mean, who would say that?
Okay. So, because that's uh very silly
because for anyone who watch my live
stream, they would know
almost I do it every day, you know, live
stream.
You You can tell right away it's not
pre-recorded.
Anyway, so
So, we got this um
Okay, so we kind of break We We kind of
broke our um
thought flow.
You need to get back to this um
[ __ ] Not not good.
Because
you know, as far as this code goes,
let's put it back.
Syntax collect showing browser.
Uh we are still in dark theme. So, let's
put it back.
So, this code as far as this code, we
already talked for 1 hour.
But we really haven't start to
actually make make make it the way I
want.
So, it would be another hour
to finish it. Um
Okay, so that's
Maybe I should stop, you know, it's
um
Yeah, because then I just going to work
offline. This code is like
most people wouldn't understand it
unless you are Wolfram
coder.
Um
Yeah, so we You see, we got two
versions. Previously, it looks like
that. Now, we have it like that.
Yeah, we improved it. We improved it a
little bit.
Okay, so
You see,
yeah, so
here is a previous version.
Actually, that involves
you know, the earliest version actually
involves uh another if statement. So,
So, there's actually another version
before this. We already deleted.
So, we made actually we made, you know,
some improvements. Okay.
But
there's much more to go.
We need to combine this into just, you
know, just like one single
code block.
And, you know, without having this
separate functions so that people can
simply
define a curve, you know, give a
parametric equation for any curve and
specify
the light source.
And they can plot
this caustics. Okay.
Yeah.
So, I guess I going to work offline.
Yeah, more needs more work to do.
Okay, anything else?
So, MHD, where did you see that comment?
Is it on 4chan or is it somewhere else?
Or did you just made it up?
>> [laughter]
>> Uh yeah, so
there is actually a lot to do. I'm
wondering what should I do now?
Do I continue to work on this or do I
just
stop?
Uh
So, this code
Um God, there's a lot
things to think about. Um
Uh you have a very dark view about the
world. Whenever I listen to your rants,
I get that feeling. Yes, that's true.
Do you think the world is dark?
You know,
I can tell you why exactly. It's because
I have a lot hatred
in me.
And why do I have
this hatred? This This hatred you
wouldn't understand. Okay.
This hatred, you know, actually I'm
telling you something very personal.
Uh and I'm not sure you are ready for
it. Okay, so I have this hatred
and that is within me very deep since I
was teens.
And the degree of the the uh hatred the
like
you know, you wouldn't know, but most
American they would say
uh let's say let's call it um
you know, post stress syndrome. Some you
know, like the American white Americans
they talk about these things.
Post stress syndrome. Okay.
Something that like this uh P PDSP
something.
Okay.
Post-traumatic stress disorder, PTSD.
Okay, which is something the white
American idiots, they love to talk
about. They chant They chant about these
things. PTSD.
You know, 10 years ago your 20 years ago
it was beginning was women, you know,
the feminism era. The women, they got
they you know, the white people they
chant about rape rape rape every day.
Rape this or or that is that rape or is
that not, you know, they love to talk
about this.
So,
you know, before it was women saying
that, you know, this
They They have They all have PT PTSD
because they got raped. They raped or or
or then like you have to go to a doctor
to see a psychotherapist. Then they they
reminded you, oh by the way, your dad
raped you.
Did you know that?
The [ __ ] Americans.
Why do Americans doing this in the past
20 years?
That's That's when the rise of the
social justice warriors, okay?
Now, then then after that, then you got
the other, you know, then you got, you
know, okay, so the PTSD issue usually,
you know, you for example, soldiers
uh you got trauma traumatic experience
soldiers and um
others, okay? Anyway, the reason I'm
mentioning this P
T S D
is so that you understand
kind of my uh my my trauma, my my kind
of my mentality, my situation, okay?
Now, why do I have this
hate like this a deep hatred? Why do I
have that? Because, well, because my
family, because my dad, because my
upbringing, okay? Uh
so
from American California American point
of view,
you know, my family is, you know, it's
like one of those problematic families,
okay?
So
so technically speaking, I do have, you
know, as far as I know,
I have this some some kind of this
post-traumatic stress disorder.
Um
and uh so so my view of the world, I
wanted to be
very successful, I want to be very I'm
very ambitious. Meanwhile,
uh you know, so this full of views of
hatred
or injustice in the world.
Um
that kind of thing, okay? So
it's you know,
and it is not normal
and uh
not healthy.
You know, so many of my views
I can understand it's probably
it's a bit, you know, it's it's not
normal.
It's
you know, it's it's like a it's like a
perspective. Um
but
not necessarily healthy.
You know, not not necessarily incorrect,
but when you view things
in a negative way,
uh that may not be so good. Okay, I
understand that. So anyway, that answers
your question. Why do you have like very
dark view about the world?
Um
that is why, because
because I have the hatred, okay? That's
what I would call it.
Okay, I think that's it. Anything else?
Any
Okay, does that answer your question?
Any you know, so actually
this session is supposed to be like pure
professional coding on Wolfram language.
Well,
okay, I think that's it.
Bye, guys. I we shut down in um in 2
minutes.