good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of saw talk
show today's 2019 yes indeed it is
hi guys 2019 November 30th Saturday in
ten o clock thing after ten in the
morning the morning guys Emily and Papa
Moon Luna real lunara's so what is
today's topic I have to wait lemme open
discord oh this is not all set up where
is my discord wait what window is this
brave so this code and where is what so
what is today's topic randomness oh my
god random is Emily's pretty major
pressure on me randomness randomness I
don't I don't know nothing about it
it's a hard topic so randomness you know
it turns out random is hard to define
mathematically you know in computer
programming programming we have a
function in most languages that you can
you have a function that generates a
random number and we usually call that a
pseudo-random number because a
pseudo-random number because it is
actually not random because it's
algorithmic meaning that the sequence it
generates will be the same every time
and in fact I run into that problem in
real life in Emacs morning Emily good
morning - Emily - UK and so so random
random numbers yeah so you know I run
into that problem in Emacs actually so
you
we go through my settings so Emax
settings and such for random so Emacs
Lisp just like any others you have a
random function and I have you know I
have several commands that does two
random for example let me open a new
buffer and and you see this is a random
random alphanumeric
you know so I have this insert insert
random string then I have saw insert
random hexadecimal number such as that
let me show you so I'm keep keep doing
that oh I can insert random T small
number so I have these functions very
kind of useful and they are useful for
if you want if you are programming if
you have a variable you always add a
random number into your variable name
you know one day I was doing an
interview this is about six years ago I
believe it's Csokas tesora okay
kisara okay that's one of the company
that does tutorials
you know they create tutorials so I was
interviewing via Google hangout through
via video and in about the end you know
everything seems so well and we are I'm
going to do a live coding of JavaScript
so I did that but in the last step I
added a random string to all my variable
names and that through of the guys and
pen oh my god and he's thinking this guy
is not what we want and that's the end
so so anyway so random number so I have
these functions Emacs about random
numbers right and yeah so this in a
maximum Emacs functions so let's look at
where are they okay so let's look at so
they are in this file saw insert random
stream and then that's let's so this
file is 100 lines and it's such least
matching lines least or different so we
have insert random hex in the random
stream in the random number and insert
random UUID okay that one we haven't
demonstrated let's do that insert random
UUID do I have a key for it I'm not sure
so let's see describe function insert
UID so describe function that oh I do
have a key so let's call it there it is
insert random UUID now UUID is
interesting by itself you you ID stand
for universe or something something
random basically it's supposed to be to
generate the ID that is universally
random that is in the entire history of
humanity if you use this function to
generate a random number
there will be no repetition supposedly
so so this UID has this format and you
can look up on Wikipedia
UID so let's do so your ID generator
you know universally unique identifier
so that's what it's supposed to be and
and another thing interesting about that
it is that they are actually using
hexadecimals they are not using for
example random alpha numerics they only
limits the letters from a to
you know hexadecimals a2f so anyway so I
have these functions that's interesting
and you can get them they are on Mel paw
you can get them by this is the file
name so insert random ID dot e okay so
you you know you can get that and you
see I have to set a random seed here you
see this line random t yeah because if
you do not set that then every time you
Yuko a random number when you start
Emacs the number will be the same
sequence all the time
so actually we can demonstrate that
solid that why don't we do that so let's
go to share and okay so let's see so
today's topic you know until it's not
big is random you indeed random and the
mass aspect of random number is really
interesting as well but I don't really
know much about that to talk about it
so Emacs let's let's start Emacs Emacs
is always fun so it's not Emacs know in
each unit file so start it so we you see
we started Emacs okay so now new buffer
okay now this is Emacs I don't know the
default keys everything doesn't work how
do I magnify the font Emily
how do I magnify the font the more
interesting
okay so magnify the font I suppose you
go through God yeah I don't know this is
gonna be a problem
how do you magnify fonts okay so it must
be in the options I remember set default
font okay let's try it
mm-hmm set default font okay so there we
have it let's say 14 okay
regular menlo 14 yeah okay let's say try
18 so we are going to do why don't you
use match with eval for what purpose
like what will you mean evaluate random
numbers well I think I oh oh that's a
good yeah that's a good option but
anyway we already here so let's just
continue this so what we gonna do is we
are going to generate random numbers so
buffer is text only you're not God so I
need to create a new buffer that will be
control X control P no control X P okay
scratch buffer now let's call random
okay I don't have my keys and you know
random option limit okay so random we
call the random option I mean the
function and we evaluate it control X
control C that's great the proper key is
control X control E okay so let's do
what Emily says let's try this okay Eva
Eva and in text scale increase font size
okay I'm not sure this is gonna work
because I'm in unknown territory and the
thing we we want to avoid is is that I'm
trying to figure this out in for 10
minutes in my talk get this
do I need wait do I need the single
quote I do right let's try that
okay did you know okay we're and I need
I need dash Q so that means Noah Varma
you need fire yeah but if you use patch
like - - patch then Emacs won't launch
right yeah but I do want to launch Emacs
so let's try that
yeah I got an arrow so Oh wrong
arguments
text scaling increase okay let's figure
it out so describe function text scale
increase oh yeah you saw you need an
increment so okay let's control X
control C to get out then let's do it
again
text scale increase increment let's say
- okay do it
okay that's work that worked that's
great
so now we are going to try random random
can you guys see me let's see
oh the video is screwed and nothing did
I just lost did I just lost stream
because I create by mistake control
EXCI okay don't screw up this time
control X II there we have it a random
number a big one now we want to insert
it so control you first then control X
control e there we have it let's do it
again well let's let's write a function
let's just write a function now I don't
have my key bindings and everything so
this will be painful so set Q set Q X
from zero let's just say you know let's
go
the most basics while X okay Wow well X
is less than 10 let's say 5 then we're
gonna do then at the end we want to know
key binding is gonna be painful set Q X
equal to 1 plus X yeah I think I think
that work you know when you do a wire
loop if you got it wrong then it's gonna
be infinite loop so the usually that's a
that's painful because if you make a
mistake you better be sure it's correct
otherwise it's an infinite loop the
right now we are trying to generate a
sequence of random numbers so X 1 plus X
that's correct right or we can just do
SEC you X you know plus 1 instead of
using it anyway I think that's correct
let's evaluate it let's hope that it's
not infinite loop okay control X control
e
Eero void variable X of course don't
worry about that evaluate that first
then control X control e that worked
okay now we're gonna do now we're gonna
do print random okay let's see if we can
get this now I don't have my keys so
everything is a struggle and see ya okay
so if we do that let's see what happens
control X control e it seems to work
control H II to bring up the messages
buffer now the message but this buffer
is not the font is too small anyway so
this is this is not working out
but anyway so you see when we call the
random the first time it gives us this
number two two two one five something
something okay remember that okay let me
copy that control X control space to
mark then copy what what is copy copy is
meta w I think meta W I hope we got that
then we are back here then create a new
buffer yes okay so now let's switch back
and exit control X control C
oh okay that's okay let's try Emily's
suggestion we going further and further
way to the remote places of the universe
where I don't know what's what things
are out there okay so okay so let's try
let's do that so in order to do that
let's go through my home tour do I have
any secret in my home dirt no I don't
think so so let's go to my home turf and
create a fire this fire will be named X
X X dot e L okay
and now we can write eMac this to our
heart content okay say Q now it's going
to fly say Q x equals to zero and
magnify the font and show that and while
okay Wow okay let's not extend this I
Wow I less than I then let's do
something here and what we want to do is
print I and yes and open a new buffer
opened a new way open a new window show
messages buffer and we're gonna show the
result here okay we're gonna evaluate
this this lines and show it okay so
comment this out wait comment this out
if our buffer there we have it now it
says one two three four five six seven
eight that's wrong oh we are you know we
should print random not I so
let's do it again
0 1 2 where is my random oh it's not
printed ok print not point print random
okay give a buffer now I don't want the
extra but by anyway it printed out you
see that's a result so the first one is
to want something the second one is that
one that one but there is one more thing
I don't want though these extra lines in
between so to do that we can use print
see I think let's just try it let's see
what happens okay now Emacs please you
have printed tee you have print and twin
see and you have print 1 they differ by
yeah
twin see do not print the end of line
like a new line at the end then but the
print will just add a new line at the
end so so in fact we don't want to print
I let's just make it things simple so
let's do it again do it okay now it's a
bunch of numbers now we need to this is
we need to contact ok contract the first
string then the second string is
connection are gonna be a space ok IVA
buffer wrong type of argument sequence P
and then you need to turn the random
number a number type into a string type
okay let's do that string 2 number 2
string that's what we want
then random evaluate now that we got
what we want you know one line here it
is one single line of a bunch of random
numbers okay now let's try let's try to
run that in the in the Emacs you know in
a shell so let's do Emily's suggestion
so we want good morning but bodies alike
so we want batch we want batch and we
want yeah so we want we want Q and we
want batch and we want the filename so
that's gonna be killed tilde my home
directory X xx dot DL so if we run it it
should print out right in the terminal I
don't think so
so let's try it vennett no output
because well no offer because let's try
messages instead of print ok
you need to save it do it again yeah no
I put I've you should know I don't want
patch so so it should
I forgot what okay so sauce Emacs
tutorial to the rescue go to my Emacs
block load okay okay
it's listen to listen to Emily so Emily
say slowed go to terminal again and load
hmm okay so let's try it now you need
you need okay yeah actually it worked it
worked because I saw you see it walked
now there we have it now there is
something interesting now let's magnify
the phone okay use backslash for
directory path so you don't use UNIX
[Laughter]
let's see let's yeah let's increase font
size right Emily's right but now let's
increase font size let's see what font
wears fun here okay font
so the first random number is two two
eight one six six five eight five
something there it is
two two one five wait they are different
you know what I'm trying to sit to say
is that you don't see the random it
every time you run it the sequence is
going to be exactly the same but but two
two eight one so but right now it's not
2 to a 1 so let's do it again okay so
shut down and Emily says use load and
bash batch okay do it there we have it
okay now we now I need to magnify my
terminal and let's do it this multiple
times let's see and we don't need that
many numbers so let's say five times do
it do it each time it's different
no this is wrong oh because wait it is
possible that Emacs version 26 or
sometimes in the past five years they
have each time Emacs starts they added a
random seed but I don't think I don't
think that's the case you see what we
expect is that every time we learn this
the same bunch of numbers come out but
they are not why is that
let's let's try the most basic way first
let's just see what happens okay let's
try the most basic way so let me just do
random okay random let's just evaluate
this controlling see so it's 1 7 8
something 1 7 8 something okay quit
let's do it again
brunette now it's negative 3 0 7
something so it's it's not what I
expected
quit let's strike you okay it's not what
I expected
oh wait okay so now you need to switch a
scratch okay random control X control e
now it's four to seven so apparently
this experiment failed it's not doing
what we want that's interesting so there
must be some changes in Emacs in the
past seven years or so because I you
know at in the past ten years because I
do remember because right now in my
Emacs init file I have a seed let's see
what's the function seed seed random
what what is a function name what's a
function name to set the random seed we
can see it here there so you give it you
call the random function and you pass t
for true that will seed a random so I
have that in my init file somewhere
let's go to my unit file so search for
search for random okay hold
oh yeah files and let's see where do I
see it
okay it's not here it's not there but
it's in this it's in this you see it's
in this package my unifier loads this
package so every time my Emacs peeked
starts the random seed will be different
and but about ten years ago I did not do
that and in in and I was using coning
random stuff you know random function
and I noticed too you know I was
surprised because every time it I got
the same number I didn't realise for
awhile for like several month then I
realized that so I'd note so I realized
that Emacs does not set a random seed in
the beginning but now apparently it
looks like it does now yeah
so that's interesting and so that that
is about the Emacs think that that is
about the Emacs random seed you know so
what so I was saying the the function
the random function in vast majority of
programming languages they are called
pseudo-random numbers because every time
you every time you call them they give
you the exact same sequence of numbers
actually we we need to demonstrate that
since we are talking about that so let
me try it one more time okay now what we
gonna try is to set the random to a can
you can you set a specific seed okay
look into eMac this random number for
details and see
okay so you can you can set the seed so
let's try that
let's try so Emax documentation says
that if you give it a string let's say a
then that will set the seed according to
this string so if we do this then the
output will be the same let's let's see
so okay so let's go to the shower again
let's do that and see if we can do that
so it begins with negative two zero one
something do it again
there it is to it again there it is the
sequence of numbers are always the same
so that's about pseudo-random numbers
you know the just repeats because it
works by an algorithm now what else
what's the next topic so actually I have
you know I being you know I you know
random number is I learned I learned
apparently it's very complex and and you
can go to Wikipedia and it will tell you
a lot of things about it quite a lot
like random the issue about random
number you can study for years you know
get you can almost like get a PhD just
by selling story in random random
numbers all the concepts evolve you know
related to random numbers but anyway
modern algorithm that generates random
numbers are basically using this
function so you begin with a number
that's called the seed then then you
apply the mod function to the X 1 so X 1
so let me magnify so X 1 X Y is just a
beginning um it's a number you begin
with ok it's a number so you you call
mod on it with two arguments the
first argument is eight times that
number the seed plus C then the the
second argument is a constant some some
constant so you do that one time one
time you get a second number then you
repeat you put the second number into
the into there then you repeat you get a
third number and so on so that's that's
the essence of modern random number
pseudo random number generation and
wikipedia has a lot details but anyway
the random numbers is the concept since
you know it's not it's it seems like
it's nearly impossible to define it
mathematically and I don't know how it
is done you know it's it's quite deep
the only thing the closest definition
math definition I know is this this
thing Kokoro of complexity okay and you
can read it here I have written you know
I have blogged about it okay so one of
the concept of random number is the
statistical randomness which is not true
random you know the statistical
randomness you can pass several tests to
see if it's random in a statistical
sense meaning that you know for example
it doesn't have too many repetition of a
specific number or things like that so
that's statistical randomness so in
programming languages the pseudo-random
number they pass statistical and when
randomness but it's not truly random
because you know here we have a graph
that plots a bunch of pseudo random
numbers and you can see they are all
they are lying a plane
the way you do that is you take us you
know so you have a sequence of random
random numbers and you group them by
three you group them by three so you got
three numbers length another three
numbers another three numbers each three
number is considered as the coordinate
in space okay so you got a bunch of
points and you just plot them and they
look like that you know it's they look
like that they all form a plane all
these all these random numbers forms a
plane so in this way you can clearly
tell it doesn't look random at all and
similarly for you know if you just take
two points in step three and prodded on
a plane you got this regular pattern but
still they the thing about that is they
pass the statistical random definition
you know they pass many statistical
definition for randomness but that's not
true true random but so the interesting
thing is so how do you define what is a
true random number in a mathematical way
meaning that you have to define the
logic you know modern math foundation
you know logic cell theory and things
like that so how do you define a random
number you know of two to us programmers
we can say oh you just pass you know you
just pass this you just you know like
unit testing you know like the unit's
has changed
stupid unit testing you know he just has
has it through a several other functions
to see if you know to see if it has too
many tools or some average is you know
something not too big oh not too small
something like that but that's not
that's not Mathematica that that's not
truly random you got
problems when you study this fatigue in
detail you'll find other T's you'll find
other T's like that so that is why the
so so that is why this is so personal
you know random the concept of random is
quite post puzzling you have so so there
is statistical randomness but we know
for sure that's not random because
obviously this is statistically random
but you know when you do it you know
it's not exactly random so but the the
question now is but how do you define
you know mathematically random the
concept of random such that this thing
will fail you know you can you know if
you apply your math definition then you
know this is not random so how do you do
that
so that turns out it's it's one of the
deepest question in you know in math or
computer science in you know this all
these are about theoretical computer
science yeah that so that turns out to
be very difficult and the the you know I
you know you wikipedia'd has tons of
information you can spend days you know
probably years to understand them and
the the one definition I found so far is
I don't like it okay you know one of the
definition so it says here is what it
says you know you by the way we have
many of these interesting things let me
show you okay so they mean turn on
javascript these nerds nerds
you know nerds have this nice for hehehe
to entice and there are some nerds who
go extreme to test if these dice are
fair you know they throw it a million
million millions of times so there is
this guy who Bo this camera machine and
with this cup that just shakes the dice
you know he put the dice there and the
cup just shake it every you know every
few seconds
then the camera takes a shot then he
used image recognition to read the the
value of the outcome the dice so he does
this millions millions of times so he
can find out whether that dice is fair
and he did a report let's refresh okay
then he did a report of this result and
you can read his articles ok you can
read his articles here you know I'm
going to copy these links in my YouTube
description so after three hours after
the stream you can you can go read them
so this guy did a lot of tests on that
anyway so back to the the math
definition of random number we got this
passage this is very very annoying you
know like in computer science many of
you guys nerds you know are interested
is that there's an trophy you know in
the concept of entropy and also there's
you know this I never really like those
concepts like I don't really actually I
don't understand that to be honest but
one day I was on Google+ you know
Google+ which which closed down like
half a year ago one day I was on Google
first and there is this mathematician I
highly respect and you know I was
flaming the the the concept of entropy
okay and he told me he told me no it's a
good thing so yeah I suppose it is but I
never actually understood it you know
why am i mentioning entropy because when
you come when it comes through let's
let's go there okay I'm gonna do a big
rant on that intro P okay
you know we are going to get back to the
mathematical definition of random number
but anyway limited let me just read it
so the closest definition I got is this
okay
let's see where is it okay here so it
says he says okay hold on second
he says algorithmic information theory
studies among other topics what
constitutes a random sequence the
central idea is that a string of bits is
random if and only if it is a shorter
than any computer program that can
produce that stream okay that's that's
the definition that I mean that's kind
of from a computational aspect
definition that's that's actually not a
method definition in math you know in
math you know in at least the
traditional sense of math you don't
define something by saying it's a
shortest program you have to define
entirely in pure logic you can say oh
you know sequence of bits is random if
if it's if there is no shorter program
that can generate that string if you say
that then you have to define you know
it's very loose loose it's all English
you cannot do that
so in formal math that's not a formal
mathematical definition of random but
however you can you can rephrase that
English you know what into math that's
the thing okay but anyway let's look at
this definition okay so this is kind of
a computer scientist way of definition I
don't like it
so it's computed also and this relates
to you know Turing machines and all that
anyway anyway it says okay so a string
of bits is random if and only if it is
shorter than any
computer program that can produce that
stream this is nasty you know this is
this kind of approach of definition is
kind of nasty etiquette what what what
do you mean girl short is this nose
impossible to have a shorter program to
generate it you know it's too loose I
don't so I don't like that I don't like
this idea at all but anyway this I but
but however remember that this this
English sentence it can be turned into a
formal language cut into you know the
traditional math definition so
apparently this definition is called
comical roved randomness okay I have
pulled it up here and if you try to read
this this is impossible to understand
okay this is you know I know many of you
I mean my followers like like
programmers okay they will say oh I
understand and you know no I can tell
you if you don't if you don't have a
kind of like on average your PhD degree
in this field you don't understand it
okay that's that's what I am going to
say so anyway so this this come kamagra
of complexity so he says in algorithmic
information theory the Kolmogorov
complexity of an object such as piece of
text is the length of shortest computer
program that produces the object was
asked this is phat rewritten this
idiotic wikipedia this sentence actually
illustrates the one of the primary
problem of Wikipedia they try to be you
see they say object you know they say
you see the kamagra of complexity of an
object such as a piece of text is the
length of the shortest computer program
that can
that can reproduce the object this is
[ __ ] [ __ ] idiotic you know they
they they try to general generalize it
by using a coin calling it object just
just [ __ ] co-ed a number or a string
you know a sequence of strings but the
this stupid people you know they they
try to make it sound big but anyway but
they mean that's just the problem with
the writing style and this is a kind of
very typical problem of Wikipedia it
used to happen much more often today is
much better like 10 years ago this kind
of problem writing style problem happens
a lot more often so anyway so this thing
so this so this article you know it's
this article is not short and lots of
references and in it you are seeing
references to many other difficult
topics such as algorithmic complexity
then there is this solomonov column a
goal of chattin complexity then program
size complexity descriptive complexity
and algorithmic entropy you know there
it is
entropy that's why I say it's related ok
this this kind of topic so I I think two
years ago I was trying to you know I was
reading this article and and and and you
can see it also mentions it says the
notion of kamagra of complexity can be
used to state and prove impossibility
results akin to Cantor's diagonal
argument of set theory and gödel's
incompleteness theorem and terrines
whole team problem so you can see this
is no trivial thing this this is quite
deep you know
so you you want to understand this you
pretty much have to understand all the
others or one of you that they are kind
of interconnected so that's why that's
why I say to understand this pretty much
means you have kind of like a PhD degree
in in math not just any math okay you
you got you know not just any math you
go as a professor they probably cannot
tell you too much about this
you have to specialize in this
particular field and this chatting by
the way this chatting guy is also
extremely interesting this chatting guy
okay there is this guy who is kind of a
weird guy
this chatting guy didn't even go there
Gregory chat Charton okay he is a friend
of wolf and Stefan wolf am the creator
of Mathematica this is and he's 72 years
old okay
quite old and you know he study
basically he is a computer scientist
okay he's a theoretical computer
scientist by the way when we say
computer science okay by default it
basically means theoretical computer
science that is a proper way
computer science means theoretical
computer science okay what I want to say
is none of the programmer idiocy
you know the programmer seriously they
they don't know nothing about computer
science okay I've been talking quite
long so what am i doing good so I got
seven people watching still okay so
anyway let me finish this
so Gregory chattin he's a very
interesting guy so he studied these kind
of topics about define ability
computability and things like that and
I've first heard of him back in 1995
when I was a wolf and research
apparently he is a friend of wolf I'm
and he is reviewing wolf I'm booked a
new kind of science - you know he's you
know they anyway but so so you know
there is a constant named after him
chatting constant you know let's see
let's see constant there it is chatting
is constant and if you go read that you
know it's similar to is is it's a it's a
number chatting is constant it's a
number that is not computable okay so
let's see what it says
Chad III don't know how do you pronounce
that
let's see fight and okay Titans you
should be Gregory John tighten tighten
yeah
Titans constant okay so he says in in a
computer in the computer science
subfield of algorithmic information
theory a chart and constant or Titan
Omega number yeah that's that's a name I
remember Titans Omega number is a real
number that informally speaking
represents the probability that a
randomly constructed program will hold
that's you know that's it's a [ __ ]
deep concept represents the probability
that a randomly constructed program will
hold this there's so many deep ideas
mixed together into that sentence so
it's a it's a number that is the
probability that a randomly constructed
program we are hold it's a [ __ ] too
complex to understand
so these numbers are formed from a
construction due to Gregory Titan and
this number it turns out is not
computable oh there it is actually the
definition of random number I wanted the
mathematical definition of random number
is this one it's called Martin Luther
andum okay now you go there well it's as
probably buried somewhere here so anyway
this is a very complex topic too you
know it's a deep topic to study and it's
gonna be endless it's in this so I think
that's it for today so we happens upon
today's topic is random and indeed we
have been talking random about random
okay so that's it guys comments so Nabi
says you said a newbie in front of him
and asked them to try exit that is
indeed yeah and and and and if we
measure that then we will get the
chatons Chinese number constant to
compute that okay I think that's it for
today random number fascinating
fascinating thing and by the way did you
know now I need to market sorry a new
kind of science okay we're gonna shut
down in one minute so I've been reading
this book two times over the past twenty
years so you know this cellular automata
oh what a fascinating topic
it actually can generate random number
that's you know Stefan Wolfram he's a
guy into this very much so much so much
so that he wrote this book and named it
a new kind of science so anyway so this
Saru automata which is 100%
deterministic and very simple it's just
deterministic and apparently it
generates a I think true random number I
don't know for sure I don't know but
that's the thing you know that's why
this are so interesting because it's
it's hard to define you know unless you
I mean even so this Martin love
randomness you know Martin loaf is a guy
you know of you guys programmers Haskell
programmers you'll love it okay because
it's when you dive into this it's all
connected the Martin love is one of the
guy who created type theory you know
there are many branches of time you know
when you get into a math theoretical
computer science lambda calculus okay
lambda calculus is pure theoretical
computer science that originally it was
created to to study what is computable
you know like chewing machines
that's what lambda calculus is it has
nothing to do with you know scheme or
lease nothing nothing whatsoever you
know what would you you know you if I
can make a crime what you hear from the
Lisp programmer so oh you know least
programmers mostly when they talk about
oh this is based on lambda lambda
calculus it's it's it's pure [ __ ] as
pure as possible it has no no no basis
no you know practical any possible basis
at all that based on lambda calculus my
ass I don't know if that's maybe I'm
exaggerating a little bit but anyway but
so anyway the matter
love guys so if you you know you just
keep reading the Wikipedia that's what I
do we just keep reading it you know you
spend one hour two hours we did we did
tomorrow you wake up we do it again on
random number article and they have
hundred things you keep reading you know
if you come across a term you don't
understand try to read it so event so
you'll get some sense you you know you
have to of course if you really want to
learn math or this subject you that's
not a good way to the go it's not
efficient you rather begin as some book
you know textbook you know in the
beginning then you advance but anyway
you can keep reading Wikipedia and about
type theory to systems logic first order
logic foundation of math then you're
soon you know you're you read about this
smart and off guy you know type type
theory and all that this all kind of
connected yeah so so this Martin love
randomness this is the definition I am
interested about random number let's see
so okay okay one more one last thing
let's see if I can read off definition
of this Martin law of randomness if I
can there it is okay so history so
algorithmically random sequence history
okay let's skip history the three
equivalent definitions okay como guru of
complexity okay that's that's about that
says a random sequence is when it is
there there are no shorter programs that
can generate it that's the Kolmogorov
complexity definition of random sequence
then you have okay now this is getting
into foundation of math this part I I
like okay and and and also this
constructive martingales okay I don't I
don't understand them exactly but I do
get
to get some sense of it so this
constructive newell covers by martin
loaf 1966 okay so he says this is martin
lofts original definition so it says for
a finite binary stream w we get c w
denote the cylinder generated by w okay
i don't get what he's saying this is the
set of all infinite sequences beginning
with w okay it's too complicated
yeah okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching bye let's see how long
have I been talking okay one hour over
well and
bye guys