good morning guys welcome to another
episode of talk show
how are you guys
nobody is here
the
the poverty of star talk show
so today we are going to talk random
i was planning to do wufa mathematica
you know the fantastic wolfram language
uh but i think you know let's talk
random because we haven't done a random
kind of session for a while
and i'm going to show you this fantastic
mouse this is supreme the mouse with
keyboard mechanical switches this is
fantastic because why
because typically your mouse look look
look at my video look can you see
my mouse here this is a fantastic mouse
okay this is my main drive logitech
okay so let's you know let's begin to
talk random okay so today's random uh
topic let's show
so let me set set up the background let
me tell you guys who haven't watched my
video the background uh
what's going on here
so video check
check audio check that's good
close that
and we are going to talk i'm going to
show you okay so first of all keyboard
and mouse okay
keyboard in mouse
uh i was going to start to talk about
the this fantastic keyboard okay so
let's post it here
uh i was going to talk about wufang
language but up to your interest if you
are if you guys are here
uh
hey andrew good morning andrew the you
know the concurrent viewers from the
youtube studio report is incorrect
uh
so uh depends on what you guys like so
we're gonna talk about uh
random issues several things but first
of all look at my you know you go look
at my keyboard
guide okay so keyboard guide go to mouse
so my current you can see right here
logitech okay which one is that that
that is this one logitech g502 fantastic
mouse okay now by the way i have another
you can see this one is wireless and
you can see that it's got six thumb
buttons
okay in theory
emacs okay andrew wants to uh
you know talk about emac stuff okay
let's do do you do you have any specific
uh do you
like uh some direction give me some
direction like do you want me to code
some emac list live or some general uh
how to use uh
emacs or workflow or any kind of thing
or i can demo software keys okay so
anyway so this mouse so type it okay
andrew
so this mouse in theory uh logitech six
zero four you can see
now
my camera you know i need to get new
camera this still allows you know this
um
you know i i which one is clear actually
here is better
lights please
let there be light and there is light
okay so this is logitech 604
in theory this is better but
however you know because this is also
wireless however
the buttons each of all these buttons
are harder to press
than
than this
then
than this logitech
then this logitech uh classic you know
this
uh five zero two so you can see if you
go to my keyboard uh page you know just
search for exactly keyboard okay then
you can see this is uh this is my main
drive and this is this is the one where
i i use when i'm lying on bed in bed you
know like flop and
type on my
surface pro
okay so but
this one in theory is better in
except all the buttons all the side
buttons are harder you know it requires
harder uh
pressure to activate okay
and what by the way one of the fantastic
thing is this you know this infinite
squirrel okay so let me show you so go
to cousin code wait
so go to keyboard
infinite scroll you see my hands out
here
you know
if i push it lightly if i push you all
the way
and you know
you know it's much better than this okay
like you press that
that that that that that that okay let
me show you let me show you um oh this
is fantastic this is chinese buns with
meat okay
so i'm talking about over okay so i need
you guys to say what do you want to see
do you are wielding pens exactly this is
a light saber saber you know
zero says i have 15 dollar mouse 300
dollar keyboard that's fantastic what
are we still talking about my
keys l track trackball for the win
uh xkcl track okay trackball you know
look look let me show you okay trackball
so you want trackball so
if i
okay this camera sucks how can i move it
okay let's try this
you see there is my trackball i bought
this but
uh you see
okay let me tell you about one of my
techniques to manipulate the window the
operation you know someone asked me on
youtube like how do you can you explain
how do you what is what is your
efficient setup configuration for
operating windows you see
i'm not doing alt
tab i talked about this many times oh
tab is one of the most idiotic
[ __ ]
you know
and the elite coders they they don't
know they don't know nothing you ask the
emacs hard code hardcore emacs phonetics
you know they say oh you need emacs you
need to set this key you know um
uh the control key to this proper place
the [ __ ] idiocy and the vim you know
the unix linux
window managers
idiots okay but they are all doing this
you know
they are doing this because you you
watch youtube you look at them they they
are [ __ ] idiots
okay so so let me show you one of the
so when it comes to efficiency i mean
when it comes to operating your computer
there are two aspects okay one is
efficiency like minimize
minimize the number of keystrokes or the
minimize the number of energy you your
body spent on on getting to specific
thing you want like for example
switching to a particular window
you know and that also counts like the
button pressure that's why we are
talking about the mouse pressure that
also counts okay so minimize
so efficiency okay that's one thing the
other thing is ergonomic which includes
efficiency actually ergonomic means you
want to working away
so that you so that you don't develop
repetitive strain injury long term okay
suppose you work on computer eight hours
a day you know
long term that's the key okay let me not
get distracted so i was saying so i was
saying so okay let's go back i was
showing you guys
this efficient operation of activating
the window so you see i have emacs here
i have obs here i have a chrome
browser here and i have okay so you see
you see that you see that at the bottom
that's the bray browser i don't have it
on but i move my finger over here
press it
i missed it press it there it is there
it is my chrome browser i mean the the
bray browser okay so i operate several
browsers um
in uh multiple browsers at the same time
so right here is the
is the um verdi the linux phonetics
thing
and firefox has been out of uh
has been displaced okay so vavati here
you know i switched to brave okay so in
go to brave we need to enter twitter
okay so now i need to press that button
so i move my finger here on this smart
keypad this ultimate hacking keyboard
this is kinesis advantage 2
so automatic hacking keyboard press so
that key is the mouse left click okay so
i don't have to i mean i can do both
ways okay
by the way i injured my finger i told
you last time like two in in my previous
video
um
you see this finger because i was
pushing with my wife playing and and and
it got you know the knuckle got bending
more than it would go so now it's like
that
so but i think it's heating slowly i
think it's um wait let me move my head
away
so so now my fingers it's like just that
but i think it's heating slowly
so anyway so so i'm talking about the
operation so one of the way to activate
you know one of the efficient
and ergonomic way to
to to call the command to activate the
we activate the window is by turning on
hoover
click okay so
of course i have full details on how to
okay so now for example i need to open a
new new window one finger
operation okay new window new tab okay
new tab and and let's search for xrd
uh
keyboard okay
uh okay
uh b-o-a-r-d okay
that's all muscle memory okay so click
on here go there and i'm using my mouse
yeah you can see the trackball oh yeah
so
oh yeah i i missed showing that
so this so this this is click okay so
i
put here at my i put my cursor on the
link here you see and now i want to
click i can click either this button can
you see it oh [ __ ] this [ __ ] idiotic
camera
so i can either click this button or
this mouse button or
click this button okay so do it there it
is my emacs page okay now i want to go
back
this button
go back okay one finger operation so let
me go back to the focus so i was saying
so go to socasa keyboard blog you go to
uh
you go to um keyboard shortcuts then
there's a entire section on windows or
linux or mac so since i'm on windows you
click on windows so the entire
guide on how to operate windows
operating system what tools to use and
how to use them and so on so one of them
is
okay single click to open file which is
important and the mouse whoever to
activate window so click on that
so you so i give you a guide on how to
set that up so that is the mouse hoover
to activate window
so okay so normally so can you see my um
now you cannot see my trackball i
[ __ ] [ __ ] this camera
ah i need more money more money to buy
things and that come to the point that
you guys need to donate okay that's what
i'm here for
youtube
okay donate please please click if you
like it please subscribe and make sure
you click on the on the bell the [ __ ]
google
you know the google induced society you
know the millennium millennial
generation idiots
so uh so back to the so let's not so
let's let's finish focusing on these
topics so mouse hoover to activate
window that's the best thing okay and i
have a guide for
uh you you linux phonetics you know
like
the linux phonetics every time you talk
you speak to the linux people first of
all you want to uh
you want you you want to prove that you
are you are a man in the linux you know
you that you are you you know about the
linux uh tech techno details like the
bash and
you have to use the fancy jar jargons
otherwise they don't listen to you they
think you are a windows idiot
okay so i have
1 000 tutorials for you linux idiots
okay the technical detail you know the x
you know x mode map and whatever okay
let's see some of them the the [ __ ]
linux idiots
okay so we're so so linux keyboard
software guide i give you an overview
how how do you set up keys how do you
change mouse buttons how do you change
mouse cursor speed how do you
swap keys how do you make a keyboard
marker using the linux operating system
the linux idiocy okay
you know
you know these days i'm on 4chan orphan
that's the home of the linux idiots so
they so now i'm becoming the
the next
the who what's the his name the guy who
wrote the linux god operating system
because i'm autistic
my friends i'm autistic that's why i
have the um i have the certification of
autistic autism
so you need to trust what i say
so so linux so so here is overview of
the all the things you want to know you
need to know about how do you set up
keys what is a scan code this linux the
[ __ ] techno idiots scan code key code
key sim executable 11 x11 is the worst
software possible in the entire uh
software
history
in the past
50 years
x11 and today the linux you know you
know you know today the millennial
generation the new generation they don't
know nothing about unix
well when they grew up that you know
linux they use linux they've never seen
a unix before they don't know what so
i'm getting old so x11 is the worst
software possible you know it's you know
and then
but today the linux you know the the
young guys like you guys you know
teenagers they think oh you should use
um
what what's the name
what's the next generation of x11 i'm
getting oh that i don't even remember
names so the
um
what is the
uh
you know the x11 replacement it it's you
know it took 10 years and it's not still
still not
not
going about so
you know so uh so say it guys help me
help out
uh
you don't you don't need gui uh well you
you do need gui because gui for many
tasks is actually the most efficient way
okay the most efficient way to operate
in many cases especially for example
let me show you one random things for
you linux idiot
ah jesus
so we here you are looking at the most
advanced programming language okay
wolfram mathematica you go buy it okay
and actually it's free i talked about
often and in fact today we are supposed
to do some wolf and language coding so i
want to show you cube okay
now okay i'm going over okay so let me
show you just something okay let me just
show you something for you linux idiots
okay graphics 3d i want no i want to
create an application you know i'm a
coder okay i'm a programmer i want i'm
going to call create a
three-dimensional graphics of a cube
such that you can rotate it okay let's
see
um okay okay that didn't work
what what is it oh graphics okay i'm i'm
too
uh distracted while i'm talking
okay let's do it oh oh there it is jesus
and can you rotate it oh yes you can
jesus how many lines is that oh one oh
my god
linux cc plus plus [ __ ]
you know you know the you know the linux
people they like to chant opengl you
know that's their thing opengl webgl uh
you know that you know
memory
malloc you know the rust you know just
float int you know that's what that's
the thing including opengl and webgl how
many lines of code to do this in opengl
1000 no kidding
okay back to so
so you are saying oh you don't need
mouse
okay
false you know for if obvious one
obvious example you see you need a mouse
to operate this okay i don't like
actually i don't like using the
um
i don't like the using the trackball you
know so i
you know i i you know i'm going all over
but i was you know i was going to tell
you why trackball is not it's just not a
suspicion okay so let's go back to mouse
okay
so you see i can rotate this okay and i
can do fantastic graphics which i showed
many times but not today
so back to so so linux uh guide you know
all you need to know about uh linux
how do you remap keys or create keyboard
markers and so on
many tools are there and uh most of the
time half of the time you try a tool it
doesn't work then you go to stack
overflow you know the stack overflow you
spend half a day there you know then all
the documentation you found on linux you
know arc linux you know arc linux site
is the best linux documentation arc
linux gentoo gentle [ __ ] idiots you
know these linux idiots they you know
they you spend half your life you know
trying to see how they work you know if
they work at all
but thanks to xa who have spent the time
for you and enjoyed all this guide you
know for example how do you control the
volume without a mouse
yeah you don't want a mouse okay i'll
show you how
you know i'd show you how to control
your uh
you know the sound mixer using keyboard
itself okay so there's a lot of articles
here that's about linux now
so okay so wait uh okay so let's copy
and go back to emacs one single key
press
and what is this page show
okay cuz on talk show yeah that's
today's page one one button press to go
back to previous window or i can use the
mouse to switch you know no alt tab [ __ ]
okay now i want to comment this out do
it one single key press oh by the way i
forgot to say you can see all my emacs
commands and keystrokes on the pink
window you see
do you see your control there no you
don't see your control there because why
because i'm using soft light keys more
efficient than vim the vim idiot
okay so for example i can delete ddds
undo show in browser or one single key
press but you know you might be
wondering but it says cr c means control
no actually because this keyboard macro
you see okay so go go to the browser
close it
go back to emacs
now press this shift key this is a key
marker that will
uh
show the current emacs buffer in browser
okay so do it there you go
this key switch back to the last window
okay do it i'm back in emacs
now um
so what's what what what's my point oh
yeah so i was saying you see it says
control r well actually i didn't press
any control did you see me press ctrl no
well that's that says control r because
there is a keyboard marker that that
sends control r
so you can see on the pink window you
can see all my key strokes i'm typing
all the um
all the end and the emax command line
and if you
for example if you are wondering what is
this end line or
block you just copy it
okay copy it
paste it here again single key press k k
is work which is a quartis v so you can
you got the command name now i want to
look up search the browser for that
command name now look at the pink window
okay
one two three three keystrokes delete ht
delete is right here this this key okay
so that three single key strokes no
control modifier [ __ ]
okay now you see it's such it found it
you see
uh
github no
i
i closed all my github except stuff like
key so here uh where is it
okay
there it is now you can see the source
code so you can grab it
free
both free or severe and the freedom you
know as in freedom as in liberty you can
grab it for free
for your own use
okay and of course you can pay me you
know donate me paypal patreon and or buy
my emacs tutorial by my javascript
tutorial and stuff okay
uh so i was talking about we were
talking about first of all yeah linux
man so copy you know for copy the url
press this key back to last window okay
that doesn't work because the last
window is the variety i want to go to
emacs so this
this
this button can you see it
ah [ __ ]
[ __ ]
so this button switch me to emacs okay
so now i can just paste it
here
so linux command okay i don't i actually
i don't want that okay i want to go to
practice practical linux tutorial okay
so this is a full tutorial on linux
command line itself not just keyboard
but for the keyboard specific you go
here
copy back to emacs paste it there make a
link
and the list
and the code delete that showing browser
fantastic now switch to grave by just
moving the mouse and do i still need
this page no close and now we are back
on twitter now let me show you the
fantastic comical
uh
system of this spin square okay so first
of all let me show you go let me show
you click close that let me show okay
i'm gonna talk about this
this mouse okay actually but now
we are focusing we i'm going to tell you
this spin wheel okay
so uk back back to twitter spin
my hands is here and it just helped me
keeps me oh
it shrink the it shrinked the font size
by mistake okay do it again
so the mouse is spinning so i can just
sit here and for it to reload this is
the infinite scroll
so that
is why
the swing mouse is fantastic as opposed
to keyboard okay for example you keep
your oops
you see that shoe that's a five finger
shoe that's a great shoe but it cut in
half okay now page up
yeah but i still don't see the picture
okay so now you need to press the arrow
key to adjust that's a [ __ ] idiot
idiocy
of the linux most of you
they don't know what you're doing
so you want spin okay so spin oh
everything you know
is just uh you can move to any image to
the right point you know you don't have
to
you know for example
move it a bit you can see the full uh
video this is demonstration of the spin
wheel it's gonna it's going to spin for
like 30 seconds
okay i'm not i'm not going to play the
whole thing stop it
uh so spin wheel okay that's fantastic
you know actually i talked about this in
the past already so let's see what you
guys are saying and what
are we going to uh talk about next so we
already talked about uh
lots of things but let me go back so
open the last closed window
wait open that way dd
wait why is the history not work okay so
anyway so
i want to yeah okay so wait
copy that
back to emacs pasted that make a link
and i want to show you
so go to the mouse section
i want to
open
i want to open this one and this one in
a new window okay so how do you do that
that's middle click okay middle click
you can do that so hold on a second
shrink
let me see if i can see myself okay so
middle click is this button okay so let
me show you
so watch my keyboard here okay so first
of all movie here
open a new tab and move here
open the new tab and now i want to
switch to the next tab okay so this this
button you see there it is there it is
there it is now i want to toggle
maximize window okay now okay switch
back toggle maximize window okay
uh and
okay you know on windows windows ui is
the most idiotic because windows ui you
have these
uh windows down arrow
and you cannot toggle it because you
press down arrow one more time it hides
the window and it's impossible to get it
back the [ __ ] idiocy of the windows
the you know the
you know so let's go back let's reopen
that
or if you you know windows key then up
arrow maximize but you press you know it
doesn't toggle the [ __ ] idiocy of the
windows so that's why i created macro
and how is this marker done this marker
is done by using auto hard key so switch
to emacs let me show you
so there it is you are looking at the
source code i mean my autohotkey script
big wait but why is it not showing
uh xsa autohotkey mod
okay it's not you know i have a auto
hotkey mod let me turn it on okay so
today is just random okay let's see what
you guys are saying hey cafe
kathy is the most beautiful
girl in our group okay
now you guys you have to now you know
get on swamp hit on kathy
kathy is a you know
economics expert
phd students in
artificial machine learning economy you
know economics using machine learning
and artificial intelligence to
you know to
analyze and dissect economic issues
and kathy's emacs user
so who so what else uh so if you have a
questions tag me okay so
so now
i'm missing my auto hard key where is
that
yeah too [ __ ] where is my auto why is it
not loading you know i want syntax color
synthetic color is missing we see
emacs okay so and you can buy my exci
emacs okay let's see packages
okay
so you are looking at my emacs packages
let's magnify or single key press
remember let's show the pink window
okay so
magnify magnify magnify magnify the
entire beauty of the font
the geeker's favorite thing found now i
want to delete all files ending in that
tioda so in e-max press this key they
become highlighted
magnify window so you can see the hole
and okay too big okay shrink shrink
shrink shrink okay
now go page up now hide
hide these you know this unix [ __ ]
by pressing the
parenthesis left parenthesis okay now
you want to i want to delete those uh
tioda files okay x
do you want to delete this yes
wait what
do it again yes
yes oh yeah yeah you have to say yes or
no okay do it okay now it's good now
shrink uh shrink shrink okay
so these are all my packages
auto hotkey is not here ah [ __ ]
yeah you know i need to i need to find
my autohotkey package and you know it's
not loading but let's
let's you know let's forget about it now
but anyway here is the autohot key my
auto hard key
you know
let's just let's switch to um
let's just switch to emac this mod
because i want at least you if the
comments are highlighted then it's
helpful so
um
okay so now
i'm using emac
saw emaxley smart to show autohotkey so
at least some color
so you see toggle so search for toggle
so here is the part toggle max window or
the hotkey okay and of course
okay so we we're going over all over the
place let's go to start talk show make
sure we write down whatever
yeah so copy this
copy this
and
make a link and now let me show you
close that now let me go to auto hotkey
tutorial like i said before you go to um
keyboard shortcut then you have the
everything you need to know about
windows then there's an odo hockey
tutorial every you know start from there
and your life will be good
okay
so uh oh so the hockey tutorial so let's
um
open that copy that back to emacs paste
it here
do a link back here
go back to previous page go back to
previous page and this linux and there's
mac okay so wait so there is mac open it
uh on the mac of course you have also
how to about i talked about uh
the
keyboard viewer custom key layout switch
to work layout hoover to switch window
here is how you do it hoover to switch
window
i was using mac for the in the past four
years and uh you know so you have linux
windows mac they can all do hoover
switch to window and let me finish that
topic so to do this workflow what you
want to do is that every application
once you open you set it you set it up
to a particular position so that there's
always a corner
um you know left open so for example
typically i want you know
i want to switch to the my main browser
the
this uh vivardi
so typically i set up so that the left
you know this or you know there's always
little room there so i can just move my
mouse there and your launch and if i
want to switch to emacs there's always a
little
uh room at the bottom here so you see
and the same thing for chrome for for
brave and for discord okay now this
window you know for discord and if you
haven't already joined discord okay
interesting people over the diverse
opinions
okay
i think that's a lot rambo about
keyboards
is there anything
kathy says i'm a normal unixer
okay so did i miss anything is there any
questions for me did okay so let's see
let's go back to the um
you know we were talk we were going to
talk about wu fam language but in the
past five or so videos it's all about
wufam language so i think i let's give
that a break
so random yeah so okay so hoover to
click yeah that's important let me just
write it down hoover to click you know i
have you know i have 1000 articles you
know um
mac keyboard tools okay back to keyboard
guide uh okay back to code
keyboard blog so i wanted you know i was
going to talk about this
this mouse okay now like i mentioned
before
when you want efficiency in operating
your computer so one one of the concern
is about
is about how
how much your body exerts the energy you
know the amount of energy your body
exerts in order to
execute certain command okay
so that includes that includes counting
the pressure of the key you know key you
know for example if you are into if you
into do it yourself mechanical keyboards
you know they first about which switch
is the best switch okay so for example
let's show you so you go to
you go to uh design
you see here's everything you need to
know about design of a keyboard or every
aspect you have
design flaws you know much of our
keyboard came from the [ __ ]
mechanical typewriters 200 years ago
that's why the jagged you know the
[ __ ] jagged or stacked
you know layout of the
of the key rows and and so on you know
i can go on this for 10 hours
but anyway so the keyboard flows and key
switch big topic you know among the
notes which switch is the best oh
topper switch cherry switch and so on so
so why are they concerned because well
it actually it does matter okay so
so
key switch
different ones they have different
activation pressure okay in general in
general i mean
people have different preferences but in
general
the lighter
is better because lighter means you have
to exert less force to
operate to activate it
so
especially if you already have hand
injury like me you know hand pen typing
too much or you know
if you already have that you think you
know lighter is better okay but if you
are young or if you never had problems
maybe you like brown switch maybe you
like blue maybe you like some other
topper or whatever
that's fine okay because
different people the muscle you know the
dna for you know the you know the
sensitivity of the you know
uh is different okay so maybe you like
blue switch you may be linear red switch
is too light for you that's fine but if
you have rsi already then you should try
you know that's that's that's what i'm
saying you should try to get into the
lighter switch the better of course i
mean not not like too light you know
like the apple butterfly [ __ ]
or even there's some key switches that's
tactile there's no pressure at all then
you know you just touch it and you know
it's like like like the
ipad you know the phone screens like
those sucks
okay i'm talking over so what so what am
i so so let's connect
what i'm talking about back to the
back to these mouse
so
why do i think this is great because a
typical mouse that
okay i see let me
show myself a tick
a typical mouse or
a mouse or um
track pull track
trackball uh button uh
the activation force for the button is
much heavier than keyboard key switch
than than the linear key switch so a lot
of people have mouse pen i don't have
mouse pen but a lot of people do so
there are many reasons i also have
article on how to avoid mouse pen which
is
too many articles what am i talking so
uh so you go to mouse you go to mouse
you'll find it how to
th here okay
here is great artwork by alan
uh [ __ ] with i want the big version of
this artwork uh okay so
okay so let me get to it okay so first
of all
so let me get to it
oh [ __ ] look at this look at this [ __ ]
you see they are repeated why are they
repeated because the
because the vaivardi [ __ ] has a bug
every time because it doesn't change the
url [ __ ] [ __ ] vardy [ __ ] the open
source [ __ ] it
by rd you know it's it's chanted you
know by the open source [ __ ] heads
meanwhile my body is like actually
proprietary
but it's loved by the you know typical
linux people that that's that's the
crowd they chant about their body all
the time but they have this serious bug
[ __ ]
so what what was i trying to link before
i don't you know that's a um
yeah mac okay i was trying to
link to the mac
[ __ ]
the
mag uh hoover to click and windows
hoover too quick i think i think
so um
okay now copy that back to emacs
so delete the repetition and i also want
to link to the linux keyboard tutorial
okay mousespin wheel that that that that
okay and there's also of course there's
a linux version
in fact in linux you have uh
so here is a linux hoover to click
or hoover to raise windows so there are
two ways okay
so let me paste that
conjoin okay so let me show you now back
to emacs now the emacs operation you see
here is a list and here is another list
i want to join them so press the button
press the button press the button
okay showing browser so now now this you
know linked together so of course again
these three needs to
be joined together
do it
do it show in browser
fantastic okay now back to what i was
talking about close that
uh emacs move cruiser okay to beginning
a paragraph okay that's the command
that's the command i'm doing you see
i don't press page up and down okay
press this is page up down no that's not
efficient you know i just press this uh
this jumps by paragraph or jumps to the
beginning of line or end of line or if
you keep pressing it it just jump by
paragraph
okay so that is that let's paste it here
link it
go here uh wait and press the wrong key
link it go here press the key to join
them showing browser
so that is that
uh source code
so now
46 minutes so we can talk uh five
minutes okay
general emacs work through your tutorial
okay so talking about ten things at a
time yeah
all over the place okay so
so this is something i want to finish so
i showed you about the nice you know the
fantastic spin wheel
and why why am i
[Laughter]
now i'm a star on 4chan okay you see
look at that
xsa jack sajak appears no you cannot
like things i don't like stop it now
uh okay so
okay so that's twitter
so do i have the okay so let me show you
yeah i was going to we were talking
about yeah so let me show you this page
okay magnify
go here
xr discord artwork so now this is a full
glory of
alan
oh alan here alan's artwork fantastic i
love this one
my fingers are that's that's you know
that's i'm like that you know that's me
my fingers are now damaged and uh
and stuff okay so
all the links here are kind of out of
orders because i today i talked of you
know over and then and and the jack is
the casa jack here did i
so there so here you know there are
several artworks this is most of them by
allen so this is alan
and this is alan
okay and there's some artwork by other
people of me in my early days
yeah and this is zumwalt okay
uh uh alan okay saw jack some you know i
found this one on 4chan
and here is our ripper
you know this you know anxiety discord
okay
so
um
okay so that that's some of the artwork
so let's go back to what um
go back
start talk show go back let's go back
close it so this is the source code for
the emac stuff close it
so programming block close it start to
do classic close it okay
where are we
uh yeah so how to avoid mouse pin so if
you want to know how here is the detail
okay now look at the url the [ __ ]
vavaldi
you see this page is about how to avoid
mouse pen but the url says auto hotkey
[ __ ] the
[ __ ] the linux open source [ __ ] it
refresh
now it works now you see the hand mount
you know the url is not correct okay
copy that shrink the window back to
emacs
paste it here make a link
join the
list
showing browser
scroll down
how to avoid mouse hand paint okay you
know there's lots lots of details you
you need to read through i'm not going
to explain
okay
uh as for emacs tutorial my emacs
tutorial okay let me show you so andrew
asked the question you know can you give
a guide to your emacs tutorial okay so
you go to ergo emacs okay so let me show
you okay so hold on a second copy the
link here
close that
paste link here make a link okay
now go to the
brave browser
new tab
ergo just search for xrd emacs okay
sorry emacs
then this one
open it
so this is my
emacs tutorial now go to the yellow
button
click it that's the home page so if you
look at the url that's the you know home
page of urban emacs by the way i'm going
to move
every content on this ergo emacs domain
to xrd info
that is a chapter that is a closing
of a sad period of my life
from 2010 to 2020.
so anyway i'm going to move everything
from this page to xari.info
okay so by next week
you know every
you'll get a redirect okay every page
you visit from ergo emacs will say okay
the address the url has been moved to
you know somewhere here you know by next
week you know by the time you watch this
video
you know you probably you'll probably
change okay so let me give you a guide
about
my emacs tutorial basically so after i
move the structure will be
exactly the same
so
you click so there are three tutorials
on using emacs so you know
so
so basically
you know you can use the left panel so
there's an emacs tutorial and each of
this topic
is about how to use emacs how do you
switch windows how do you open files
what are the you know efficient ways
what is diet diet is for control control
you know directory you know copying
files moving files rename files these
files that's a diode so where to
download uh for windows on linux or mac
you know so all these sections is about
how to use emacs okay for example white
space how do you control indentation
what if you want tabs what if you want
space how do you remove all tabs how do
you convert or space two tabs things
like that so indentation
um you know how to use split windows how
do you you know
yeah so what is a buffer how do you
release buffer how do you switch buffer
everything you want to know so this is
the
this is the first one emacs tutorial
so there are three of them then there's
the emacs in it so in this section all
these pages are about how to use setup
customize emacs okay so what is the init
file i tell you what is init file so
let's turn on
javascript
okay so you can see the blue
highlight the green highlight so what is
the init file what is the major mod what
the [ __ ] is the major mod the emax
jargons what is the miner mod
okay so what how do you what is mx
customized
maybe you have seen this before maybe
not if you are new to emacs so
all the and and then how do you install
packages you know what is the package
how do you install them uh how do you
check which operating system you are on
because sometimes you are at home you
are using mac or linux maybe at work you
are using windows so you need different
configuration for different machines
so how do you in your init how do you
find out which you know
operating system you are using so
anyway so all these are about
configuration init emacs in it okay how
to set up emacs
then this here emacs keys is an another
section
huge you know uh 50 100 articles about
all about key binding okay because emacs
emacs is about keys
keys is the interface to your computer
okay keyboard and mouse so key
key shortcut is the most what you know
one of the most important thing first of
all by the way i said this many times
the most important is actually the
physical keyboard go [ __ ] buy a nice
mechanical physical keyboard you idiots
you you know you linux vim emacs you
know phonetics so you should use uh
motron
codemac layout
you know layout and sure cut [ __ ]
idiots first of all if you don't have a
mechanical switch keyboard you don't
know nothing okay you are going to get
rsi in no time
regardless what window managers you use
okay you [ __ ] idiots window managers
linux you know
i've been talking for 55 minutes okay
we closed down in five minutes so is
there any more comments for me
so celtic orthodox hello and alan
so so i was talking about so let me
finish the
introduction to my emacs tutorial so you
have emacs
tutorial emacs init
everything about emacs init
then everything about customizing emacs
keys okay then you have several several
sections about emac lisp okay here is a
practical emac list which is an
introduction to emac lisp
uh which is important because in emacs
the entire emacs is written in emaclis
you know just like the entire vs code is
written in javascript so emac is
learning a little bit emacs list will
help you
know emacs by a lot okay so
so you know you don't have to but you
know it's nice so spend time to learn
some emac lisp or emacs list by example
so this section is all about
so i have code you know the actual
function you can just copy it and paste
in your emacs and you'll be able to call
this function meta x and you know so all
these are
sample functions for example
title case region or line okay let me
demonstrate this one for example because
this is
simple to understand so
change title case to um title case okay
so
open a new buffer
something in the water
fantastic
okay now magnify
okay magnify okay actually too big okay
something in water now
typically now this is an english writing
you know guide english style guide you
know in programming you have idioms
[ __ ] idiots then you know the pythons
especially the python [ __ ] [ __ ]
idioms idiom they are s
so you have style guides in programming
same thing in english so typically so
how do you title so if this is the title
of your article
there are many ways to title it okay so
let me show you some of the ways show
the pink window please okay
so many ways to title it the first way
is the great convention this is the
breed convention
now this is american convention
now no then then then there is uh
okay so let me show you okay so the
different conventions okay
then let's see let's see that okay so
there are four different ways let's
shrink shrink shrink okay so shrink
shrink so you can see
this one capitalize the first letter
and that's it
this is the brit
united kingdom convention okay
now this now the second one this is
american convention now notice it's not
just capitalizing each uh first word in
each
word first letter in each word but but
no
the in and
the must be lowercase okay so this is
american
idiocy
you know they have you know for example
um
basically articles articles
and
verses
in
the this is what you don't capitalize
okay anyways that's the american
commission then this then there's this
one
systematic
simply capitalize every
first letter of every word this is a
what shall we call it programmer style
okay
but it's rarely used you know at one
time in my for a year or two i tried to
use this but i eventually i dropped
this using this convention because look
at my article for example change
emacs change to title case the two is
not capitalized but however you know
you you could you know so
one of the convention is just simply
capitalize every first letter of a word
okay for title
then of course then this this all caps
okay so here's the same some of the
common okay so
i would say in in terms of um in order
of common
how common they appear it would be this
order okay
so
so okay how do you how did you do that
okay so copy the whole thing
select all
make them all lowercase okay so you can
see the pink window that's the command
i'm calling okay now if i if you want
the american convention just move the
cruiser there and press a key
you can see the pink window it says
space space dot
that's my key and the name of the
command is title case region online and
the source code is right here just copy
it and you can have it free
courtesy of xali thank you thank you
guys and are we done yet and i think
that's it for today
okay so um
yeah so we but no okay so continue we
haven't finished the introduction the
tool guide of cymax
uh tutorial okay so so this section is
all about example actual code useful
code for emac these you can grab and use
right away then
you have this section emaclis write a
major mod now this is more advanced if
you are going to write your own major
mod you can then study you know i tell
you how to okay
there are many things you need to know
so that's the basic tool guide of xia
emax tutorial so you have three sections
on emacs
tutorial init and keys then you have you
know you have three and three major
sections on how to write emac lists
then in the miscellaneous and others
then there's a bunch of other
miscellaneous articles my
my rants my [ __ ] my
packages okay this is all my package
packages now you actually you need to
you like them for example this one is a
math input mod for example i want to
insert pie
okay
pi uh
okay so there you see
there it is pi okay so wait
so uh and the fee
greek v
let's say um mu
what else let's say sum summation
integral
uh degree
okay
you know for you math writers or
or the
real numbers what is the real number
that's the one of the most
um
let's remove this fantastic okay let's
remove it okay show the pink window so
you can see the commands
so undo let's do it again so the power
of emacs okay so now we can magnify this
small so you can see the full glory of
these symbols so how do i do that
for example arrow
red arrow which is often used
a
uh b
okay
okay so a you know a to b
uh function for example let's let's see
then you have a function okay uh
what is that yeah function
so you have all these uh unicode symbols
and uh how do i do that well that's uh
math input mod you can get now you have
to pay okay pay me and thank you guys
and you know
uh because i uh you know if you haven't
if you didn't know about 10 days ago i
removed
my 20 my 10 years of open source code
from github
now they are still open source but you
pay me to get it
uh
as i said you know very depressed
uh period of my life
lingering around death around hunger
hunger
death by hunger in america very strange
tale
that you cannot possibly imagine
not not the typical americans but anyway
so
so that's it okay so
that's a tool of my emacs
website okay in which i'm going to move
to to casari.info
cut that close that
um okay this is autohotkey close it
and let's go back here okay so um go
back here
paste uh text okay
paste it showing browser that's about it
for today's star talk show
now i'm going to read comments and we're
going to
shut down in
in two minutes
no question address me okay
uh per globe programmer okay you want to
know my daily routine join
xrd school okay join this casa discord
essentially
i elaborate my daily routine too
you know
you'll get tired of it
i wake up and sit in front of the
computers and cold
and every few hours i walk for 30
minutes to and fro
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching
wayland that's right the linux idiots
not you know they are like
you know it's a you know it's it's like
a new new fashion like they don't they
don't know nothing but but but to them
you know the young people right yeah of
course they are young they don't know
the history but they are saying oh yeah
you should you need to use wayland oh my
god wayland is
linux you know linux
it's you know even
unix for like 40 years i mean let's just
let's just say linux okay
when was linux spawn linux was wrong in
early 1990s okay let's say 1990 exactly
because somewhere around there you know
you know it's hard to say because then
there's a time i mean it depends on what
kind of date you want you want the date
where
linus towards announced linux project or
you want the date when linux is
mainstream okay that depends on you know
so
you know so basically linux started to
become
um
people heard about it around year
1998 let's say 1998 everyone you know
programmers you know nurse you know they
heard about linux
then around let's say year 2000 then
many
companies started to google for example
they started to use linux because it's
free
free or seen they don't have to pay
otherwise they have to pay microsoft
they don't have to pay so
um
so what's my saying what am i saying so
linux for you know
you know linux okay
i don't i don't i'm not going to get
into a rant about unix because i did
that too much too often but basically
the my the the thing about wayland is
that linux x11 is the worst [ __ ]
possible
x11 okay
so exactly unix pestilence okay you want
to read about my gripes about unix you
can start from this uh this this page
which is let's turn on javascript
which began i start to write this
refresh i start to write this uh in 2002
okay when i was working in the industry
uh you know i was using cis i was a
developer and system mean for solaris
okay so iris is one of the unix of
course it's dead
and hp unix
and then linux came up then in the
beginning this most estabian
so say
however you pronounce it i always
pronounce it susie or something and then
red hat and a bunch of others yellow dog
linux and so on
then there's a bsd okay so
so windows 11 is the worst crap possible
okay so do i have the article here
i have you know
i have it somewhere here yeah so you
want to read this one very popular back
then x windows disaster written by don
hopkins
don hopkins he is the one of the top
expert of xc x window x11 okay
and this is this is written in 1994 so
in around 1990s everyone knows this
article the nerds you know
this is a unix tradition
windows 11 the worst crap the worst
software in the
you know you could say one of the top
five worst software in the entire
computing software history okay but the
unix idiots they they don't know it they
they you know they don't they don't want
to hear it
[Laughter]
they pretend the the problem doesn't
exist
instead in fact this instead they say
x11 is the best thing because actually
it it has the technology of separating
the server from the
from the client and by the way x x 11
reverse the the terminology so what we
call server they call client what we
call client they call server so when you
are using x11 it's actually server
client um
uh paradigm you know so linux you know
the unix [ __ ] they would say oh
unix is fantastic because when it comes
to gui you have this
fantastic advanced architecture server
and [ __ ] [ __ ]
they are [ __ ] ass
what they say is blatantly false you
know you
you know for example look read this
article yourself written by this uh
fairly famous guy he's on hacker news
okay you can still go to hacker news
go to hacker news search for don hopkins
he hands around there even today he's
pretty old now 70 or 80 something you
know he's pretty old he also created he
ported the entire sim city to
unix okay with using x11 he's an expert
he is also a
expert of ufam language user mathematica
he's been using wolfen language for like
like me for like by now 30 years okay
don hopkins and now and then i you know
communicate with him
don hopkins he's also a emacs user okay
so he you know and this x11 disaster is
one of the chapter of the
of the this popular book unique unix
haters handbook okay
if you know you guys the millennial
generation you don't you don't know
nothing
even back then
yeah you don't know about this so yeah
because i'm old i'm talking now i'm
talking it's like property it's like
history oh he's talking about history oh
world war two happened
well two back then this this airplane
looks like that you know you don't know
what i'm talking about
so
so x11 okay the worst
technology in every way like the worst
design the [ __ ] just [ __ ] just
[ __ ] hack okay hack just [ __ ] hack
a pile of [ __ ] that's what x11 is
and when and when linux took over
you know they inherited you know
basically they adopted x11
back then there's a project because
the people who know you know who called
in unix they they know
they know x11 sucks
but
there's no choice
you know either you go you just you know
it's already there you use it or you
have to rewrite the whole you know
windowing system which is not easy okay
not easy
so they just adopted but they are there
were project you know several you know
trying to eliminate x11 trying to
replace you know trying to create a new
framework for gui for for
windowing system graphical system
but they failed because it's a it's not
easy it's a big but also the other
reason
it doesn't
happen because
all the software written for linux and
unix they rely on x11 so if you create a
new framework all your software stops
working so
that's a sad story
of
unix
in part you know that you know you blame
the unix [ __ ] and the linux
[ __ ] why are they [ __ ] because
they are phonetics okay when when you
become a fanatics you believe in
something which is just force but you
believe it deeply
then you got lots of problems then you
you got this x11 you know the worst
technology crap happening you know but
you don't even know it but
you know so i have too many things to
say because i i was about to mention
how is the situation in mac or windows
okay they have a much better system than
the x11 [ __ ] okay so anyway so this is
20 years ago 20 years ago linux you know
happened and linux adopted x11
but there are several people you know
tried to rewrite it you know they all
failed and you know the until now
wayland wayland is by now 10 years old
you know but it's not i don't i don't
think it's not like in every linux yet
we
land uh so so yeah you know stop using
the [ __ ] words
so we land
finally
wayland started to
started to become useful you know
i don't know the technical details i
haven't been using linux for five years
for more than five years but um so
that's the story of wayland okay
um okay that's it for today bye guys
you