good morning everyone
am i alive
welcome to another episode of our talk
show
today is 2020
september 14th monday
noon san francisco time
and am i alive i think so
i think so video check audio check so we
are going to do emac list
okay let me show you the background
image
error youtube is not receiving enough
video info
what the heck
concurrent view dropped to three
what is going on
so am i here can you guys hear me type
something
hey bot and alan
okay so we are going to do emac based
coding
first tutorial and let me show you this
keyboard
this background image so i just found
out this keyboard today
this is actually an input device for
video editing
and photoshop so i found three versions
of it
this uh this is uh made by
what's called loop deck something like
that
so there is this version and then
there's a slightly
different one this version and then a
fancy version
i'm not sure those are displays uh
probably so
so um so i found so this one this one is
for adobe
lightroom 6 and lightroom cc
uh lightroom is a photo editing software
kind of like photoshop but not exactly
it
you cannot edit images you cannot add
text and so on it's just for photos
anyway it's a kind of photo editing
software adobe lightroom and there
are several versions so this input
device is designed
for adobe lightroom 6 and cc you have to
check
exact you have to check the exact
version
because otherwise it doesn't work i mean
you know either it's lightroom cc or
lightroom classic or lightroom 6.
so so you have this loop deck you know
this is
theoretically this is fantastic because
you know
instead of you know doing knob and
wheels you can just
let let me show you okay so let me show
you i
let me start uh for example let's look
up
uh let's look up this photo okay so this
photo
and let's open in uh gim
so this is in emacs yes emacs can view
images and you see close it
so open opening game
so you see when you are in a photo
editing software
you have lots of controls and you
use mouse or keyboard to switch
to different uh controls
and those are tedious so you see we have
photoshop
so you click you know you click on that
if you want to
what what is this transform or something
then you click that you have the smudge
tool
then you know you have to switch towards
then you have to adjust these
uh too many adjustments so with this
kind of device
you can you just twist the knobs and
sliders
it's fantastic and then
this version loop deck plus this is
this is for adobe um
lightroom classic the end is also for
premiere pro final cut pro photoshop
with camera
raw and a few other applications so
so this one is for image editing plus
video editing
okay so am i am i like alive
oh i am okay good alan and alan
and uh east wester is a weasel
okay so so this one um luff deck
is for image editing with
lightroom certain version of lightroom
but this version is for image editing
and plus video editing specific to
particular applications
premiere pro final cut pro lightroom
classic and so on
i look at i looked at the reviews on
amazon
these those they are no good you know
they are
fairly expensive like this one is 170
okay 180 and
the other one is uh similar and the
review says you know they are made in
china they are cheaply made this this
one is 250 they are cheaply made
you know if it works it's fantastic i
mean this is really fantastic but
the product is very cheaply made
and this one i haven't looked at the
reviews yet
you know i just discovered them today
this
this one is 550 dollars you know so
these
companies you know i so i have been i
said this many times
a device a input device like this with
terms of sliders and not wheels physical
you know sliders and up wheels they are
wonderful
instead of the keyboard nerd facts you
know the keyboard nuts
they say oh you you need a 40 keyboard
or you shouldn't use the mouse these
[ __ ] idiots these
emacs and veeam and unix people they
have no idea what they're
doing you shouldn't use the mouse you
know you should
you always you should you use the mouse
you should depending on what kind of
input you do there are specific there
are input devices
specific designed for them uh meaning
that
it will make it uh supremely
efficient you know for example mouse is
so many different designs and wheels and
buttons
so it in particular for photoshop for
video editing
and image editing and also 3d editing
you know if you use blender you know
there's lots of professions doing that
you need those things
so anyway so i looked at this so the the
first two is cheap i
i don't know what's a review for this
one but but you see
they these people apparently today you
go to amazon there are quite a lot
of these you know designed for photoshop
or video editing
these people see a market and they you
know they create it and
people buy it and they sell it extremely
expensive this one is five hundred fifty
dollars
but if you know it you know
normally if if it's
you know they market you know they
that's due to marketing they sell for
five hundred dollars
but let me show you some of the other
photo uh editing devices you know for
example
uh this one we talked about before
and this one and this one
and this one so this one is for
photoshop too
and i saw i i look at the amazon reviews
it's okay it's so this one you you
rather you want to get this one
and then let's see
then this this uh
jock wheel and shuttle ring those are
classic since 1990s
so if you do video editing it's
necessary it's it's
it's uh extremely efficient
then you have these you know this
tangent ripple they sell you know this
is for what you call um
this is for video editing for the task
of color grading you know i
like i don't know what it is but i
looked you know basically they
basically they changed the color of the
images in a video
and they sell this one is for example
350 dollars
and they have more expensive versions
that's
that sells for this one this one
three thousand dollars
but this thing doesn't really cost three
thousand dollars you see
we have basic economics here you know
the thing of a value
how do you judge the value of a thing
the value of a thing is equal to
how much money other people are willing
to pay
you know that that is actually the
i mean that that is true so you might
think no that's silly
what do you mean depends on how much
other people have to pay exactly
exactly actually that is like that so
anyway this
this thing sells for three thousand
dollars and people
will buy it you know because people you
know professionals they
do uh video editing they buy it you know
so
when you look at this thing contrast you
know when you look at this
you see we are programmers so this video
editing and
photoshop you know image editing there
outside of our community
but people are willing to buy this kind
of thing you know
but when you look at this thing then you
go back and compare
to your community your community's
mantras and chants about
emacs and vi and not using the mouse no
you shouldn't use the mouse because
you know you should v you use vim doctor
or what are the [ __ ]
these people [ __ ] they are extreme
idiots they have no brain
because because when you compare you can
see
what's what's with the theory that you
should only use keyboard because that's
nonsense
when you look at this thing you know
it's nonsense because
then you might say oh because they are
doing gui no
that's not just because of that okay you
can make your emacs and or vm gui as
well
if you really want to go with efficiency
okay anyways a bit rant so
so anyway so i'm going i'm just showing
you some of the devices i found
uh video editing and photoshop editing
and i'm saying that
these you know specific tools for
specific tasks
this will make it much more efficient
make your you know and
so let's go back to where i was saying
okay i i uh hello everyone so
my uh my friend's dog is sparking i
don't know what's going on
so let's go back to emacs i want to so
what's
what's today's deal so okay
you can go to my xr keyboard just search
for
xrd keyboard
and click on saudi keyboard blog and
you'll find my articles
and today by the way today i found this
strange thing
this strange thing called um
switch opener for key switches
i have no idea what it is it's pretty
strange
so it you know they have this uh
prism shaped thing
for key switch opener i have no idea
what that is i haven't
i have to read in detail read the
comments and so on
for keyboard key switches
so anyway let's let's start coding emac
these
okay uh my javascript stuff
javascript so much i've been working so
much on javascript
in the past week so adam says have you
seen
alfred app uh yes i
i know it but i have not tried it
what is your opinion on automation in
general one key triggers several actions
yeah yeah that
is fantastic let me tell you i'm the
master of automation
uh since 1992 okay
so let me give you a brief intro of my
history of computer using and automation
so
since 1990 so my first computer my first
personal computer
computer that i bought with my own money
i own is mac 2si
i can show you some photos mac 2si
okay apple uh so this is 1992.
i bought it for a thousand or two
thousand dollars anyway this
plus the apple rgb monitor 13 inches
640 by 480 pixels
you know so remember this is 1992.
you got a rgb monitor 13 inch
that's kind of top deadline top of the
line
you know the and that's only
640 by 480 pixels so together with this
machine
together it's three thousand dollars so
this is my first computer so i'm
i've been a mac user from 1991
to 2000
to 2009 then i switched to linux for
well windows for a while linux for a
while and
about three years ago i'm back on the
mac
so so you know so in the past 30 years
you look you know just like today you
read about news and everything
debates you know controversies which one
is better linux
i mean windows or mac throughout 1990s
it's windows versus mac
you know every every every every month
every year you know you have articles
debate debating you know people argue
about it
then linux camera so anyway
so back in 1992 uh there
are mac is that you know it's it's far
more superior than windows like
far more period today it's maybe a
little bit
but back then it's far more superior
than
than windows because windows and back
then you have dos okay that's just text
you don't even have graphical user
interface
you you don't have drawing apps then
after a few years you do have
then then then windows 95 you know
windows 3
came up and so on and linux is the most
idiotic [ __ ]
to this day the graphical user interface
or not
because they they are idiots these linux
it's not
people you know why is linux that way
because these
people because they they have no brain
and they will argue
that with you to the end like like right
now
you can see on my video comment comments
some
linux people you know these nuts idiots
they will they
they saw my video and they feel angry
they will have
sometimes they will comment oh my god
this you know i love your stuff
but today you are so wrong
no you are an idiot okay
it's kind of sad story so anyway back to
automation so
in 1991 i created back then mac doesn't
have vora keyboard building
so i created use reddit rest edit okay i
talked about this before
rest edit
that is a tool on the mag
e d i t
yeah they don't have the
yeah here okay here's the classic here's
the icon of breast edit this
this is what it looks like okay wait
uh i said here
so let's edit so i used rest edit to
create a
viral keyboard layout in 1992 on the mac
that's when i began to use voracle
actually i began in 1994
i was a quality typer and
back then there is a tool this is
universally agreed
to be the best tool automation you know
it's
com you you could say it's still the
best but
anyway that tool is called um
uh oh god it's been so long
let's go to my keyboard page
maybe i have it listed there
uh you know it's long history
uh so let's go to
let's go to software then let's go
to mac mac keyboard tools
so on this page is an introduction of
the several
uh keyboard auto keyboard keybinding
tools keyboard layout tools or
automation tools
they are all related so the best one is
actually just carabiner
or there are several you know the mac os
itself allows that
uh allows several basic uh maneuvers
for key binding and shortcuts so anyway
this page
is introduction to them all because i
looked
into them every year since 1992 okay
um but things change you know all these
software coming go but anyway
so let me tell you about uh app launcher
so quicksilver
is one of the earliest it came up around
when mac os x you know the unix based
one
came up so 2002 quick silver
and there's alfred this is new i never
used hammer spoon i never used
keyboard maestro is also pretty old now
it
came up around 2005. okay
then uh then default you know this one
you should uh
this one is bld in mac os you should try
it out
because this one is this this one is
about creating
your own uh editing command layout
for example like emacs move cruiser copy
paste you can you can actually create
your own
building in mac os x mac os
so you can read this tutorial and you'll
see it
okay so back to keyboard tools so anyway
on this page i give you an intro okay
then uh then there's usb overdrive
which is kind of the usb tool that kind
of transformed the usb
signals to do something else i have used
that that's pretty good
and the keybind keybinder so it's
controller made i have not used but i've
heard
you know good great things about them
okay
so so there is this tool back in 1992
1992 it's on this page for many years
but i removed it because
what's the what's the name of the tool
let me think about it
um does anyone remember
no it's not auto hard key okay but auto
hard keys on windows auto hotkey
is windows thing and the auto hard key
came around 2007 around there
auto hard key was based on uh another
thing called auto key or something
but anyway that's that's a windows thing
but let me tell you
so if on windows auto hotkey is the best
kind of the most powerful and best thing
it's actually it's a
it's hack it's tremendous hack it's not
actually that great but
practically speaking that's the best
thing you have on windows
so if you're on windows you want to
control your keys
via the operating system then use auto
hard key okay
so i have you know for example i have
the you know you
you click on windows here then you have
the introduction to all the possible
all possible windows software tools for
key binding
related things okay
but let's go back to the mac because i
want to
i want to remember the tool let me think
for
a few seconds uh
i can't remember
so i'm talking about history so anyway
these two
well i need to get the name first before
i
actually talk about it because this this
tool has 30 years of history it is it's
still
around i removed it because you
because first of all i need to find the
name okay
so um okay so what we do is actually we
just
open this page okay magnify
change it into a url so this is the url
now i want to go to way back machine
way back machine so let's go to chrome
open a new window way back
machine
okay so we are going to look at the
archive
page of my my website
i hope i didn't change the file name uh
so i
i must have changed the file name so the
earliest instance is 2012.
okay where is it
let's see 2013 okay there
so let's look at my page from 2013
january
you know this is interesting when you
write a article
or a blog over the years
you know things change if you don't
change your article
then it bit lots you know it becomes
irrelevant
even though it technically is still
relevant but people you have to change
you have to keep changing
actually but the other thing is um
anyway so so anyway this is how my page
looks like
back in 2011 this is not uh
yeah so i have the article since 2011.
uh so back then you know i don't have
images images is for marketing you know
i give you the gist of the information
you read it that's the
that's the you know 20 years of
experience then you follow the links to
it download them
but but if you don't have images you'll
notice because
google and all these companies they push
for you know marketing
link link uh clickbaits and so on so
if you don't have images people don't
visit your site you know because
google search doesn't show up to show
your site things like that
so that is why today's website they are
all crap
you know every website they look so
pretty this [ __ ] javascript
frameworks
you know every every website looks so
pretty but this empty content you look
at the [ __ ]
garbage uh
millennials okay we blame this you know
if we
find a generation to blame that's the
millennials
millennial generation made this happen
partly because the internet it's a new
era okay
nobody knows what's really going on but
that's how things are
how things turned out so anyway back
then
back in 2011 my page app launchers okay
so uh keyboard maestro is still there
you can see
let's magnify okay
okay so uh quick keys there it is
quick keys quick keys existed
since 1992
it is the best automation tool
barnett on any operating system on any
platform
and even back in 1992 is the best
automation two of them all it can recall
keyboard markers
it can record mouse markers okay
back in 1992 okay this is
so it's you know among mac users
every everyone agrees this is the
must-have tool
it's by the way back then it's not open
source it's not there yet open source
didn't begin
in 1997 also you you pay for it
you know so quick key that's the best
tool okay
far better than auto hockey
but so the company actually changed
hands
over the years you know that's the
history of companies you know the
company is changing the source code
change and the quality degrading
and so on it happens so
so quick key it's for mac os but
when in around 2002
when mac os x the unix based you know
mac os came up so quick key
you know doesn't run anymore you have to
rewrite it you know for mac os
x so it took them like
two years kind of late to do it and also
by then
it it's so to uh study.com
let's see if they are still around quick
key okay
open a new buffer search for quick key
yeah okay i guess it's still around i
i'm not sure there are many people using
it anymore
uh anyway so this is the best troll back
in the 1990s and did the company change
hand many times
the mac os x version was not that great
it actually it's not good
and you know so do they still sell it
i guess um
okay so that's that quick keys okay
so yeah so i've been using automation
tools since 1992.
i if there's a application or launcher
or you know let's say from throughout
1990s to
to let's say uh 2010. i've seen them
i've tried them all
you know i i i tried i review
because i'm obsessed i'm obsessed about
this
uh automation and efficiency i'm i'm an
efficiency
uh nerd extreme one so so if you are
linux fanatics or emacs
go [ __ ] yourself you don't know [ __ ]
uh and you know you can quote me on that
okay
that's that's not a joke you don't know
[ __ ] when you want you know when you if
you want to argue about
with me about 40 key binding or this
have you tried you know my life is
argument i've done that many times and
they don't know [ __ ] these
uh geeking nuts [ __ ]
okay so that's that's about quick keys
so
what are we doing i don't know so i you
know i
maybe i should go back to um
shall we start to do emac this coding
i don't know we already talked about
keywords for long
uh 30 minutes okay we still have time to
for emacs
so let's see so have you been have using
alfred yes i haven't used it okay
oh yeah okay let me since we've been
talk we are talking about this let me
continue about
uh give you some opinions
so why have not why have not
you know what happened i tried you know
the outfit
the hammer spoon uh and some others
well because uh things changed you know
the technology the landscape
changed you know things changed today
it's open source right
open source is everywhere you you
usually don't pay
for things and in some of the many of
the open source tools are great
so that's part of the reason i removed
quick
keys for my website from from from this
uh intro page because
i haven't been using it since like for
over 10 years now
it doesn't make sense to say oh i i you
know i use quick
keys you know since 1990s
you see he he so so here is interesting
thing about writing an article
on online and what happens to it over 30
years there are
many issues like if you if i keep
the passage about quick keys then
that changes the nature of this page
you see back then the nature of this
page is
introducing to the users many great
tools
but if you have a tool there after 30
years
you know after 30 years you haven't been
using that tool for
over 10 years then
even you if even if you haven't edited
the page
but the nature of the page changed the
nature of the page becomes now history
so this so the page becomes a historic
you know history of
automating keyboard you know automating
tools
so the nature of the page changed even
if you haven't edited the page
so there are things like that so if you
are writing a blog you know you there's
lots of issues to be to deal with
anyway so so why haven't
uh so that's why i removed that quick
quick keys tool
you know my paragraphs about quick quick
keys but
what about hammerspoon and alfred i
haven't used them because
let me give you a tip okay today i
recommend
do not use i mean uh you can still use
them but
the best thing is to buy a programmable
keypad
okay now i show this many times i have
to show it again my keyboards okay let
me show you my current
keyboard okay uh let's see let's see if
i can
okay so i can actually so you see
so kinesis keyboard kinesis advantage
to uh let's see
kinesis valencia 2 and ultimate hacking
keys
now this keyboard is all about shortcuts
okay
so for example i can switch to last app
and i can switch tabs
you know switch type back and forth and
close close it
reopen it refresh you know
uh fantastic okay so that's
that's the ultimate hacking keyboard
okay i'm using us
i'm using it as a marker keypad that
keyboard has the best programmability
features
let's uh put it back there
okay so um
so what i'm saying uh what i'm saying
yeah so
i recommend you buy okay let's go back
to
my keyboard page you buy a programmable
keyboard
because you know pro you know technology
keeps improving
so today you have tons of these
great powerful flexible programmable
keyboards
you program the firmware so they send
the what whatever your macros directly
to the operating system
as opposed to you know if you program
using those tools quick keys or whatever
you press a key then your macro is
interpreted you know then you transform
it then send it to the application so
it's like
indirect and that always have glitches
auto hard key on linux you know uh
x mode map or whatever linux you you
know [ __ ] idiotic linux [ __ ]
linux you know linux story
linux is truly the worst [ __ ] possible
let me let me digress okay linux you
know you might think
you know why why when i tried to uh do
keybinding on linux about
almost 10 years ago now i thought linux
would be the
the greatest uh
operating system for someone to
customize their keys by
the operating system tools because linux
is
geeks operating system right you have uh
x11 x mode map you have several tools
you know and if you are a programmer
like me
a nerd you know i know linux you know i
know unix i know shell bastion or that
so you should be able to it's it should
be more powerful most powerful and most
flexible linux okay
so i i i spent you know several years
doing linux keyboard
it turns out it's the most worth it's
the most
worth [ __ ] possible compared to windows
or mac
on the mac if you want to you know
automate
change keybinding creation cards create
a new key out it's
most easy the most easy of them all
also free also free and often the
software also is open source
on linux on windows is the second best
okay you just
install hotkey auto hard key you have to
spend quite
some time to learn it and that does
everything basically
auto hard key is the most powerful okay
on on windows
on linux it's one [ __ ] up [ __ ] [ __ ]
the linux people
[ __ ] you [ __ ] the idiots you know
they they
linux viewer they they drive all these
nuts about
you know about all these different tools
1000 tools
extremely complex to understand shell x
set
you know x11 then but but it turns out
it's the most difficult to do you spend
you spend a mac you spend let's say one
hour
to do all your keybinding needs you know
you learn the tool and everything
let's say one hour on windows it would
be five hours
on linux it would be something like um
50 hours okay
no exact exaggeration for doing the same
thing
you spend 50 hours to learn all the
tools not just
the [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] you [ __ ]
linux okay this this is this is
this opinion
came from uh um
you know i learned it the hard way you
know because i i was on linux
as my home mid desktop i learned i tried
to you know have my keybinding system
you know
i learned the hard way little by little
over three or four years
to write all these articles so what [ __ ]
possible so
mac just turns out the great you know
mag just just like
30 years ago mac turns out the way
maggie's design
their system their developer community
is just good
it just works so anyway
so back to the what i was saying i
recommend today
you buy instead of using the operating
system based
software for key binding or key markers
or
keyboard layout you buy a programmable
keyboard
or programmable keypad instead okay
there are several
um good choices
so this one is fancy for photoshop you
know you want for example this one okay
you can get that one or that one
quite a few you have to look okay all
these
do it yourself uh once use using qmk
one of the best software the most
powerful to do what you want
or you can get you can buy a ultimate
hacking keyboard like this this is my
ultimate hacking keyboard i just showed
you
uh you know you know you can use it as a
marker keypad
okay so that's it that's it that's about
it uh
so how long have i been talking i guess
no emacs then
we've been talking for too long about
all about keyboards yeah let's not do
emax
because because then when i'm done with
this video the title will be
you know keyboard keybinding you know
stuff
it wouldn't be something plus something
else because then
emacs people will not be interested in
keyboard stuff and keyboard people will
be
uh not interested in
in the emac step
okay what else alan says sweeper
hotkey bar says okay never used it i
just heard about it a lot so many people
love it auto hard key yeah that's that's
a windows thing
uh during intensifies uh just
works yes okay that's it
for today i guess that's it for today
anything else
okay uh you know you can
you can type anything you want and i'll
read and
answer possibly uh we shut down in
in five minutes probably so i'm just
going to talk random about keyboards
okay now so
go and buy a programmable keypad now let
me tell you
which to choose okay there are so many
different choices
i would say most of you for most of you
you want
um let's see how do i recommend it
uh you know they
it's hard to it's hard to give one
recommendation okay because they are
they are quite different
for example this ultimate hacking
keyboard now this is 250 dollars
are you really going to spend 250 for
this
as a keypad yeah maybe you would
you know so but if you are just going to
buy a keypad this
is too big you know you know for me i
haven't even used the other half i only
use half of them and
many are empty keys and plus when you
have lots of
keys you don't want them all to be
together you want them rather for
example like that
you want them to be different shapes and
in different positions
so that you can you know without looking
you can feel you can you know you can
look at your screen and operate on it
without
you know without actually having to look
at your keyboard so this
for example this design is not not too
bad for example these six
keys on the right and six keys on the
left you can feel it
and also these three knobs on the right
and three knobs on the left you can just
feel it without
looking now these buttons in the middle
you'll have some problems with the
middle buttons you see that that's the
issue
so when you have a keyboard you know if
you have a keypad like that
that's a problem you know unless you put
your hands on it you learn touch typing
otherwise
you got a too many keys in the same
shape
problem so anyway this this one is 250
dollars so
it's very good it's one of the best but
it
you know you it's 250 if you want to
spend that much on a keypad
so and this one you know otherwise
i would i highly recommend you know i
would
i think the physical design of these
things are the great
the fantastic best okay that's the best
however
this turns out to be cheaply made in
china
and also it's not general purpose it's
for example this is only for adobe
lightroom
you know you cannot program it for in
image or
for browser for controlling browser you
cannot
so that's a so so it's not general
purpose and this one i
you know i think the same thing applies
it's not general purpose
so that means you have a hard time if
you really
i mean if you want to use these two as a
general purpose
uh key markers uh
device you have to hack it yeah i don't
i
don't suppose it's easy you know it's uh
the source code is
probably closed maybe i don't know
but otherwise if you look at just the
physical shape
these these are the best okay now now we
let's hope someone
open source create something like this
you know you can you can use it with
open source uh qmk software that would
be the best
now this one for example it's also great
but
you know it's only got 12 keys okay one
two three 15 keys
one two yeah 15 keys and they got a
lcd display on them which is kind of
fancy
um you know not not that many keys
but um and it's then you have this one
32 keys okay so these 32
keys has the problem of having you know
a grid
regular uniform keys
so so it's easy to press for example
this the five keys on the edge
you know the four keys on the edge and
plus maybe that one but some
the the ones in the middle you have to
look you have to look at it
you know so that's not good and
okay and they got a display in the
middle okay so this one is something
like
150 dollars i think
okay so depends on what
um and this one is similar okay
this also got a lcd display similar to
that one
this one is great it's not expensive
it's from china and it's cheap 54
dollars
but the software is not that great
you know it's it comes with a windows
software
and and not open source so
you you have to learn the software
to program the keys then you can throw
away the software
then you can use the keyboard on windows
but the software is not that great
and the programmability is kind of
limited
uh yeah but you know fifty dollars
uh this one is the same like that one
they are made
by the same company the cooler trunk
uh then you have for example this butter
stick
now this butter stick is do it yourself
you can buy from this guy great
guy who gave me the google keyboard let
me show you
you see i have my keyboard connections
now
you can see my google keyboard let's see
where the
how does it work yeah you see
so it's made by that guy
who created the same guy who created
butter butter stick
and then this is a googleplex
okay so yeah googleplex
easy
so okay but
what i wanted what i want to say
is that the butter stick
surface the same problem of uniform keys
to too many keys in the uniform position
for example if you want put
you if you want to press the left four
keys or the right four keys that's easy
you can
do it by touch but not the middle for
example these four keys in the middle
yeah but a stick but you know it's got
the most powerful software qmk
then you have this one okay this one is
so this one is classic
it existed uh since like 20
20 years ago but the um but
but the software the software is
kind of dated it's um i don't know if
it's still available yeah ninety dollars
it's kind of expensive
the software is kind of uh
old and also it it's got too many keys
uniform
key problem you see so it's hard to
press press
you know many of the keys in the middle
it becomes wasted because
then you have to look at it
then then this one
the reviews are not so great this is
modern okay but the review isn't so
great
uh then this this is also classic
this this is like 30 years ago uh the
company existed 30 years ago
x keys okay you can buy it
on okay 150 yeah
way way expensive way more expensive
than necessary you know if you're gonna
spend 150 on this one
you rather i rather recommend you buy
you know they also have like 60 keys
versions
anyway so if you're gonna spend 150 on
this one
i rather recommend you buy this you know
this is
much cheaper and the qmk software is far
more powerful
okay i think that's it about keyboard so
again let me repeat okay if you want
automation
you want create keyboard markers for
efficiency
for automation i recommend you buy
a programmable keyboard okay uh where
here
you you buy a programmable keyboard or
programmable keypad
okay like like some of these i recommend
i suggest it no
but if you don't have money or you on
your laptop you
you know you you don't have choice to
have a
uh you know physical device then
then well then use software okay on
linux you have
you know you have several tools you have
x mode map you have uh
you know there's a guide of them all
x mode map then you have a scan code
key code key sim you have what's the
tool
um x bind keys
uh wm control you know [ __ ] complex
linux [ __ ]
uh then on the mac
anyway so yeah so that's it for today
uh thank you guys for watching bye guys
cough in house coughing up coffee mouth
says unable to acquire the
x-bisp front end lock
valley block front end are you root
what
jung jung hani
says i've had the same cherry keyboard i
bought in 2008 still works fine
there's one thing i want to just uh i
just remembered one
thing
on the programmable keypad okay
you see we're talking about programmable
keypad and there is this guy
this guy is old school you know they've
been around
for i think 30 years and
you know you know what they just bought
you know let me show you this trackball
this trackball l
track is sold to that
company x keys so x keys now
makes this trackable now this this is
the highest quality
trackball okay that's it
bye guys so you go to my website go to
my keyboard
buy my stuff thank you and donate
donate stuff and stuff stuff stuff
bye
uh alan says knesset's advantage
too still the best not necessarily
that depends uh that depends quite of
a few things
you