good morning guys welcome to another
episode of star talk show today we are
going to talk about wufang language it's
going to be a wufam language tutorial
and
pure wolfram language tutorial
and i'm going to talk about wufang
language syntax you know wufang language
has this particular syntax
shortcut system a systematic syntax
system which is very similar to
you know the wolfram language syntax is
very similar to lisp so
first of all i'm going to go over wolfen
language as a tutorial for any one of
the uh one
you know any of you guys who never coded
wufang language before
so you you know if you want to learn
wufam language uh you know this is a
great video to watch
for beginners and as well as if you have
some experience with with
language because i'm going to cover this
syntax
issue which is uh
you have to know it if you want to
master wufang language okay
so that's what i'm gonna talk and also
i'm going to cover some
similarities to lisp you know if you
code emac these or commonly support skim
disk you will notice lots of
similarities because wufam language is a
lisp
uh okay so let's begin so um so let me
check
hello guys now if you have questions and
comments posted okay i'd love to see
your comments and questions
but please focus it on wolfen language
or this or programming language you know
for those of you interested in
programming language design this video
will also be pertinent okay let's begin
so i'm using emacs i'm using emacs and
uh you know in the pink window you can
see all my emacs keystrokes
and uh
command names okay
keystrokes and command names let's turn
on global highlight highlight mod so you
can see my keystrokes and command
names
and uh so this is the current page sas
talk show and click on ufm uh this is
the notes to class talk show today
and click on language syntax tutorial i
wrote this about a month ago and it's
complete
and so and and so emacs and here's the
wolfram language and you can see my
um i'm using stuff like keys
soft like keys and
i'm also using a vora keyboard so this
is kinesis advantage too
uh go to star keyboard blog click on
ergo keyboard and you can see kinesis
advantage too fantastic
i recommend and also i'm using uh this
one is
ultimate hacking keyboard i use it for
as a keyboard marker it's the best
keyboard marker system okay and there's
also a review and videos and so on
okay let's begin let's start to talk
about wufang language okay so
um
show this uh close that close that close
that show this okay so let's go to
wufang language
okay so let's talk about wolfen language
so first of all so let's evaluate so
this is a wolf and language code okay
now let's copy it let's paste it here
evaluate it you can see that it
generates these um
you know it generates a bunch of this
list nested list code okay so now pay
attention to the syntax okay
this syntax is fully nested brackets
okay so essentially everything follow
you know look at this follows this form
so you have you you begin with a
you know a symbol then followed by a
square brackets
or
inside the square brackets you have the
arguments you know and they are separate
separated by com comma
and
and so on so
that constitutes the wolfram language
syntax purely nested form okay so you
are looking at that here so for example
you have you know and pay attention so
the symbol names are pure letters
english
letters or other language letters so
there's no dash there's no low land low
line or underscore there's no question
mark so the symbol names function names
is purely just letters okay and bld
letters begin with capital uh building
functions begin with capital letters
anyway the the point to focus here is
that you will not see a plus sign
uh uh well i mean you will not see any
you know dollars uh you know let's see
punctuations well basically
everything is the form
you know uh
a single name
then square brackets
then
you know a bunch of
other things
separated by comma okay so you can see
uh
you can see
how the nesting structure is fully
nested
okay
so that's the wolf
language syntax okay but however you see
it's all nested you know so it looks
like that nested
you know purely nested syntax is pretty
hard to read for example you can see
uh compared to lisp for example for
example let's go to some some this uh
code you see it's all
nesting
it's all nested you know it's
they are
good qualities
and they are good points and bad points
you know one of the bad point point
about nested purely nested syntax is
that it's it's kind of hard to read
because then you have lots of these
brackets
in the same similar way
that's true for wufang language you see
you see your highlight you know as i
move the cursor let's see if i can
magnify more so you can see the full
glory if if when i move the cursor it'll
move your highlight the matching
uh
square
the matching
square brackets okay so you can see i
move the cursor to to anything you'll
highlight the matching square brackets
so
one of the issues with the fully nested
syntax is that
too much nesting is hard to read for
example if i want to do let's if i want
to do you know one plus one plus
let's say uh
let's say does you know when you do math
let's say the
formula for
quadratic equation okay
negative b
plus square root
you know two
well i i don't remember the quadratic
formula so let's see
okay that is the easiest way is to solve
okay let's show you some movement syntax
solve
a
x squared
plus b
x
plus c
sub for x okay
uh it's not a okay so you need a
equation so equals to
zero okay do it again so there it is a
quadratic quadratic formula now suppose
you want to type this okay so you type
b
minus
let's say plus okay
square root
b
squared minus 4 a
c
divided by
2 a
okay
now you can press the key by the way wu
wufang's language you can press the key
to typeset it so anyway so
so you we are you see this syntax is not
you you can see there is this uh correct
that means power and you can see there's
a slash that means divide
so that syntax is not the
it's not like that you know
so
how does it work so the wolfram language
so let me show you so the wolfram
language for each of the form f
something
you know each of these forms
they provide a syntax shortcut
they provide a syntax shortcut for
example let me show you some examples so
so for example plus
1 2 okay
now
you can write the plus 1 2 by
by this by this way it's the same thing
so for example let's say times
times three four okay now there's a
shortcut syntax for that times function
so you just
in fix notation
so there you go what about list so if
you want at least just just like uh lisp
so this list a b c three things let's
say a b three and and 4 okay
so you got at least now there's a
shortcut syntax for list two so the
shortcut syntax for this is
this okay abc 4.
you see
and we can you know if you know so
so for for many commonly used functions
first of all remember everything in
wolfram language has this form you know
a function name square brackets and
whatever separated by comma just like
just like in lisp you have parentheses
you know
but however for many of the commonly
used functions there is a shortcut a
systematic shortcut syntax for it
so for plus
that's a plus sign
for for multiplication that's the
asterisk
punctuation you know character for list
there you know you use the
curly braces you know so in the this
syntax
is called
match fix
so the first sign
the plus sign with the arguments on the
left and right those got that those are
called infix notation
so
same thing for multiplication in fixed
notation
so for the short cut for the list
function you have the match fixed
notation now match fix is very common
for example in python in ruby in
javascript you have the square brackets
to indicate to indicate the list you
know three four five you know
in in in language you you the shortcut
syntax for this is the curly braces okay
so the point here is that
wufam language
has this kind of lisp nested form
symbol name square brackets then
whatever inside the entire ufm language
source code is like that so heavy heavy
lots of
nesting
such as this however heavy nesting is uh
have flaws one of the floor is hard to
type
you know when you have a missing bracket
then it's a problem you know it's hard
to type how to read sometimes
so
and especially when you need to do a lot
of mathematics such as you know the you
know mathematical formulas
so if you want to write this in a full
form syntax let me show you okay let me
show you quickly so for example
so for example if you
want to write this in full form syntax
let me show you
so you paste it again
hold i'm gonna explain the whole thing
okay uh
so you do that
yeah
you wanna and that's not um
okay so
do
okay so wait um
there it is
so you see this this thing
this complex you know so this is the
full form syntax i mean that's a you
know symbol a symbol
followed by
you know whatever arguments then
separate that comma so that's the that's
the you know you can type this for
example let's uh
let's type this
so you type that
evaluate
you know then you get that so
so that's a shortcut syntax system in
wufang language for many common
functions you have a shortcut
syntax for it and they are 100 percent
equivalent
meaning that
when wu fan language for example when
you type this okay
when you type this
you know when you type this into from
language uh let's let's get it to input
form okay so when you type this
into wufang language
before it does computation it will
translate it will transform this syntax
into
that
okay before it starts to compile
whatever it will
transform
you know any of these you know three
times four or
one plus two it will transform them into
the fulfill syntax
as the first step then it does the
computation so this is critical to
understand if you are going to master uh
language you know before it does
anything it will transform any of these
syntax
you know uh
any of these syntax into the full form
equivalent
so
and and similar for this you know before
it does anything with solving this
equation it will transform them to
um
to this uh kind of form
so why is this critical so when you do
because when you start to do pattern
matching pattern matching is one of the
powerful mechanism
of how we find language does computation
you have to understand the full form
syntax of whatever you typed okay
so anyway that i hope that's uh does
that does that clear does that um
okay so there's a question uh have you
done container tutorial on your blog
container
mukul says have you done container
tutorial on your blog what do you mean
by container you mean javascript or what
what what container
okay uh hello good morning so c
asks how does it determine the order of
operation okay so let me explain that
so when you have a fully nested uh
syntax such as that
there is no notion of operation operator
precedence okay so
for example let's go to okay so you see
this fully nested form
you don't need operator precedence
because there's no operators because the
precedent precedence is
explicitly determined by the nesting
structure for example
this will evaluate it first okay
then
that will evac be evaluated then that
then you see
you see then that
then
that then
that you see it's just nested so
whatever is innermost they get evaluated
first there's no need for
operator precedence okay
but now but once you have you introduce
the infix notation
or the
match fix you know the or post fixed
notation for for example post fix
for example let me show you another
example so
so let's say you want the core function
a
f and g evaluate at x okay
now
you can now there is a shortcut notation
for this uh
this
for this fully nested form okay the
shortcut notation is
x slash slash g
slash slash f
so this is analogous to
the unix
pipe notation the vertical line so you
evaluate x pivot to g pipette to f
so this slash slash is a post fixed
notation it's a syntax syntactical
shortcut
to to that
okay so let's evaluate it you see it's a
it's the same
so once you so my point here is that
once you introduce many of these
shortcut notations that's not fully
nested such as that
or the infix you know then you have the
issue of synthetic precedence for
example
a plus b times c
you know so we know that p and p b times
c must be evaluated first then a plus
then a plus whatever the result so the
the
full syntax the full form
of that is let me write it out
plus
a then
times
b c okay
that's what that um so evaluated
so
so when you have this syntactical
shortcut then you have uh the operator
precedence notion
okay so how do you so what is the
operator precedence okay so wufang
language you know so
when there is analogous traditional math
notation it basically follows follows
the same precedence for example the
asterisks you know the times comes
before plus
um
and uh so how do you so what about
others so they are a lot okay so
basically the way to
so so okay so first of all you have the
notion of operator precedence okay
now the next question is how do you
actually implement
the notion of of operator presence in
in programming languages for example in
python in javascript in you know in
python in javascript in java in c they
all have this operator precedence
but how do you what how what is the
mechanism to implement it
you know there are several ways in most
languages java python
see essentially all languages they
implement
that the operator precedence
in the parser you know basically it's
defined as part of the
grammar of the language you know it's
basically implicit you know when when
you have the grammar specification
called um
okay so let's uh start the
parser
okay i i started to write some tutorial
about how compiler works but it's not in
it's not complete okay
so how compiler works so you can see
you know this is my beginning tutorial
about how compiler works but the most
important thing here for us is the
grammar you know before you can write a
compiler before you you need a password
before you have a password you need to
write a grammar
specification of your language
so
in order to write the grammar
specification you need what is this
uh you need this
what's called uh backers no form
notation basically it's a syntax to
specify grammar okay
and when you
do this
it
when you use you know the b and f
backers no form to specific
specified grammar you
you essentially implicitly introduce the
operator president presidents okay
so anyway that's how traditional
language soft you know implements the no
you know the issue of operates operator
precedence
now in ufam language
you um
it's you know so it's probably
implemented in a similar way okay i
don't know for sure because this is
about
the implementation of wufam language but
however on a higher level a more
abstract level
it's very easy you know all you have to
do
all you have to do about operator
precedence
is that you assign a number
or integer for example you assign a
number you associate a number to each of
the
infix operator
so we can say you know we can say the
multiplication
multiplication sign has
a number let's say
uh 50
and the plus sign has a has a priority
of let's say 30 so 50 is greater than 30
therefore
the multiple multiplication sign has
higher precedence than the plus sign
okay so that's a
high-level way
of how do you implement operator
precedence so you can have a lookup
table you know whenever your pastor
encounters the multiplication sign
you know okay then it's 50 you know
priority 50. then
then whatever other sign you know
depending whether it's less or
greater then you have the upper operator
precedence notion
and another notion is
for example let's say a times let's say
a plus b plus c
you also have to give a operator
precedence when the same symbol is
encountered
now in the first case it doesn't matter
because it doesn't matter
because it has associated property it
doesn't matter whether you compute b
plus c first or you compute a plus c a
plus b first doesn't matter
but for some
operators it matters for example this
postfix notation it matters
whether you compute
you know x
and g first or the g and f first
so
when you specify the operator precedence
you know you associate a number to the
slash slash
us you also have to specify
whether it's a left associative or right
associative
so in this case
it's left associative so
the left side takes uh priority
so in summary
in summary
about the operator precedence okay let
me summarize it
once you introduce
operators you know which doesn't exist
operators doesn't exist when you have
fully nested notation okay but once you
introduce the infix notation you know
the infix notation or
postfix or prefix or match fix you know
this
none fully bracket not non-fully nested
notation
then you have the issue of operator
precedence
now
to implement operator precedence in
general in programming languages you do
it by you know it's part of the parser
and grammar specification
so it's actually irrelevant to the
programmer okay
it's more of an issue to the implement
implement
implementation of the language as a
programmer you don't care you know you
just look up the documentation okay
that's all you care you look up the
documentation about which
uh operator is more uh has higher
precedence than the other okay so
for most languages it's a it's
implementation issue
but however
more generally speaking
you can understand operator precedence
by
first of all assign
associate a number to each of the
operator and then you specify whether
it's left
associated or right associated
okay
okay another question can the programmer
make their own short
hand syntax yes exactly yes you can in
uufam language okay
so i have another article about that
um uh let me let me let me point it out
okay so first of all shrink this a bit
so go to the home of wufan language
click on the yellow
then we arrive at this page
then you have um
then you have an article about how uufam
language does unicode
so this is about how would language deal
with unicode and in here
um
i don't think
okay so let me try to focus uh in here
okay it doesn't exactly cover how to do
it but
but i have another article
okay let me show you
okay
sari
language unicode okay
uh
why is this article mentioning why is
this article show up oracle
documentation
and
function name unicode again it's there
it is unicode in function name and
operator okay so
let's open that
so in this article
you know i compare all these languages
on the issue of whether
they support
unicode symbols in their function name
like can you define a function
uh
that contains a unicode symbol like one
of these or can you have a variable that
uses one of these symbols in variable
name and
these are all separate issues okay so
whether you have you can have a unicode
name in identifier then the other
question is can you define
your own operator
in
in these different languages c c plus
plus go java javascript python per ruby
or camera haskell
and this and so on
so first of all can you have a unicode
in attend in identifiers function names
or variables names
then
can you
define your own operators that's a
separate issue then can you have a
function name as your operator
can you have a unicode character such as
circle plus or circle times
as us in your operator so in this
article i compare these languages on
this issue and for the wufang language
that's yes for all
so but
i actually never tried to do it so but
if you let's look at woofing language
syntax okay so woofam documentation they
have a page that
shows you how to do that so wolfen
define operator okay so you just search
for wolfram define operator
defining your own function okay so
so there is a woofing community article
on how to create a new operator
but let's open this okay so it's a bit
more advanced so let's see oofam
community so
okay there it is notation
package you don't need a package okay
what year is this
notation package the notation package
allows you to extend the wolfram
language so it understands functions
and correctly with the new typeset
notations okay
uh you don't need a package okay so
so i'm telling you i'll say you know
yeah i'm telling you off the bat you
don't need a package for it you can
define
a operator of your own in language
but
again it's a little bit advanced okay so
let's see where is the documentation
operator applied no
okay so let's try another
okay wolfen language syntax uh
so there is a
so here is article
on
operator precedence okay so you know uh
more advanced technical yeah so in here
so so they they show a list of the shoot
shorthand notation on the left hand side
and the fully nested notation on the
right hand side
okay and they also
shows shows you
the operator precedence okay
and somewhere in this article or a link
format it will explain
it will have a link to a documentation
about how to define your own operators
somewhere okay
you know there are like hundred thousand
pages on the woofen side you can find it
but let's go back i mean this so let's
go back uh to our
discussion on the wolfram language okay
so because i haven't we haven't so
anyway
so
so let's let's show you some of the
basic
uh
shortcuts
okay so let's see
so anyway i think that's basically we
covered um yeah okay okay so let me let
me show you some actual examples useful
examples of the
syntactical shortcuts
so we have explained the
uh
yeah so you might want to check out read
my article so how many people are
watching two
okay so i uh let's see what
what to do next
okay let's go over some of the basic
examples uh for example
a
equals to three
okay there's a syntactical shortcut for
that
i mean what okay so the okay so
a equals truth three is uh the full form
is set okay let's say b
three okay you want to set b23 do it so
there's a shortcut you can just say
b equals to three they are exactly the
same thing okay
and
one of the way to see the full syntax is
you just slash slash
hold slash slash
full form
that will show you
okay that's already evaluated
okay let's try another x equals to three
okay so
i don't know if that will work
no that doesn't work because x equals to
three
gets evaluated already
so another okay so
basically
whenever you have a some expression and
you want to see the fully nested
notation of it
this is what you do just say slash slash
hold and slash slash full form
now in in this case it doesn't work
it's because
again it's because
uh some kind of operator precedence
issue because x equals to 3 already gets
evaluated
before you know so it just becomes three
so that's why you just get a whole three
you want to hold the x
um
so
how can how can we do that
let's try this okay sometimes it
hold is protected okay so
let's try this
i don't think it work
no there it is so
so you can see what happened is that
this post fixed notation
there's a difference okay so what what
happened here is that okay so what
happened here is that
when you say x equals to three then hold
this syntax
is slightly different
than
then if you just say hold
x equals to three okay
ideally they are identical but they are
not because
x equals to 3 will get evaluated
here
but here
no
so what ah okay so let's try it again
okay do it
you see
you see the difference
so anyway my point is that whenever you
want to see the full form of some uh
expression you can just say hold in full
form so for example let's do this
in the full form way
[Music]
there it is so you can see x equals to 3
is equivalent to you know the function
set
okay so
so that's some of the you know so the
most commonly used functions has a short
short cut syntax
so i i'm showing you basically on this
page
is a list of all of them
okay i think that covers uh what we
talked you know today's topic um
yes hold is like quoting lisp exactly
exactly but again because they are
different languages so there's a minor
you know nuances but basically hold is
exactly
uh analogous to the least
uh quote
uh quo yes
uh because this and because wufang
language you know the the
uh wufam language is based on this
primarily
and uh apl
you know if you want to
um say you know basically yeah so
there's a heavy influence it is
essentially it's a lisp okay so
because
every
uh the
defining characteristics of lisp
is also in wufang language for example
let me list so first of all nested
nested brackets as the syntax
that's uh defining characteristics of
lisp
check also in wufang language you have
seen
uh you know like like that
so next nested brackets check
symbols symbolic computation everything
is symbols check that's also true in
wolfram language
uh list marcos
which means transformation of the
symbols these markers true in language
that's symbolic pattern imagine it's
actually far more powerful than this
okay
then this you have readers
you have reader markus which is which
means
a list reader is a
is part of the this
compiler
that before you do anything you'll re
you will read what you type in and do a
transformation
then
then the result is fed into the lisp
interpreter
so
the the way this
this programming language works is that
first of all you type whatever the
source code
before the
this uh does anything it goes through a
thing called reader okay uh called um
uh
it's just called reader you know you can
find it in close your documentation in
common this documentation in emac this
documentation in skim this stuff
documentation okay so i have an article
on that so let me quickly show that
um
these readers okay so i there's a whole
collection of articles about
lisp
is this syntax readable what does
symbolic language mean can this marker
change this syntax okay here so here is
a collection here is a screenshot of
different documentation
where they talks about the reader thing
so in these languages you have the
reader thing so what does that mean so
first of all you type something that's a
source code of lisp before it does
anything
the reader will read it
then it will transform it into a
different syntax
the result is actually
so
the reader will transform the syntax
then the result is fed to the lisp
interpreter or the this compiler okay
that's the job of the reader so in this
so that's why in this you have this kind
of thing
uh
okay let me show you
you see so you have this kind of um
quote you know a shorthand
a synthetic or shorthand for the quote
function so let me show it so
so for um
so for example you see the apostrophe
there
so
so what um
so the reader the list reader will see
that and we'll convert okay let me show
you an example
i
i think i
pressed
defining a
key marker of my kinesis by mistake now
i need to cancel i don't know what i did
okay a keypad i think i
what
oh i up my keyboard
now i think
it's in keypad mod and its cap lock is
activated
okay now i'm back
uh
yeah so let me show you an example
in this three four so that is that is
identical to
quote
3 4 okay
let's try it let's try it okay let's put
a equal
so run it near okay so
yeah because equal means
equality in symbol but here we want
equality of the value so run it you can
see
it shows t there at the bottom can you
see that
you see this t that means they are true
okay so
these
these two are true because of the reader
the reader reads them and convert them
both to the
the result is exactly the same so
in the same way wufang language also has
a reader
and in fact you can find the
documentation uh
there i think that's the one okay so
let's um
there it is
uh what
ah
i pressed some wrong key and wufang
language crashed
uh
it crashed
okay let's try it again
so read let's you know you can look up
the documentation
uh so that's the wolfram language reader
so i was talking about
the characteristics of lisp
nested
syntax
symbols
reader okay then you have these markers
you you need the reader
you need it to be symbolic and reader
then you have these markers so these
these four things are the
characteristics of this and they are in
wolfen language as well
okay uh i think that's it for today
thank you guys for watching yeah i think
that's it we talked for one hour
uh anymore any questions um
[Music]
so what's this symbol in wufang language
that's you know whatever you type is a
symbol so
let's you know
so that's a symbol so for example x
equals to 3
then you can say hold
x
you know then you can say evaluate
uh evaluate x
okay or you you don't have to say
evaluate you just automatically evaluate
or let's say you can say x equal let's
say y equals true hold
x
okay
now the value of y is whole x
now if you type x
or x is three okay so but if you type y
the result is hold x so now you say
evaluate
y
okay so you have to say unhold
it's uh
unhold i believe
release hold okay
there it is release hold why
you can see now it's three
so
so that's you know so so why can you do
that because symbols you know everything
in um
so when it comes to sim so how do i know
so
how can i prove
now i want to prove to you
that wolfram language is all about
symbols you know
just as lisp so how do you do that well
the the the most
fundamental way
is to show that the language has a
symbol table okay now in this it's
called um
symbol table okay up array okay so
in in this
okay that's the thing okay so that's a
variable building variable and this up
array holds all
symbols you ever
uh including building symbols and the
user defined symbols such as let's say
uh
let's say set x
x okay
three okay let's evaluate that then the
set becomes a symbol in the up array
symbol table so up array is a building
variable let's see what's the value okay
uh describe variable up array
so you can see
here's the result of up array so it's
all
it's you know it has let's copy it copy
it new buffer paste it
okay go to the top
then
space to new line
so we get so we got we got a nice so you
you can see
right now in my emac list session
i have about 1500
symbols okay let's see
yep
1500 symbols
so every function name every variable
name in this is a symbol so so you see
many of these are
you know for example
w32 system course that's a that's a
function
image type that's a building function so
beginning of thing that's a building
function you know sequence that's a
i'm not sure what that
let's see let's see describe function
it's not associated with a function it's
just a symbol spilling symbols i believe
so you know when you look at the op
array which is the table of all existing
symbols in your current session you have
lots of things
we are getting into the internal of this
language okay
so all these are symbols let's can you
let's uh sort them okay let's sort them
so
so many of the building symbols let's
see uh dollar sign
that's my thing that's my that's my
personal
parameter names you know symbols anyway
so you can see
what's the zero let's say delete
duplicate
um
and
delete duplicate lines okay let's just
call delete duplicate lines okay so now
there's no more duplicate so let's pitch
down
so you can see
so these are building
uh
symbols yeah so these are these are
property symbols
so anyway these are symbols okay in in
in emac this
okay up array is the
it's a variable that holds
all these symbols
in the same way in language you have
you have a
a table that holds all symbols so
how do you
show it
um
you can
you can simply say
system
so that will list all symbols in the
system context okay i believe i'm not
sure no
okay the easiest way okay okay yeah type
that
there it is okay that's
that's
that is all the symbols in the system uh
context you know you have the context of
uh you have the notion of the context
which correspond to
module names uh for example that also
exists in common list
so anyway here is a
you know table listing all the building
symbols okay they are they are like 6
6 900 of them
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
yeah if you like my stuff buy it okay
donate
so you can buy
so go to
go to xrd emacs somewhere go to the home
page
uh
go to ximax packages so i built a lot
packages you can support me buy them
thank you guys for watching
and you can of course you can patreon me
paypal me
amazon gift card me
you know it's it's you can find the
links on my uh
website you know just go to
uh what else okay we shut down
in two minutes
let me just uh so go to class talk show
so let me just paste something we
talked about
today
okay that's it bye guys