morning everyone welcome to another
episode of exan talk show today we are
going to code emac lisp I'm going to
write a command that changes a link to a
dead link by making it a cross out
strike okay so emac this today we're
going to do something different so this
talk show is going to be just 20 minutes
let's see okay just 20
minutes oh we started early so 3 minutes
early so anyway so my keyboard This is
kesis 360 fantastic okay with pink
switch if you're going to buy it go to
my website Kar keyboard buy the kesis
360 with pink switch okay that's light
linear switch uh you know you want want
to make sure you get that and this
keyboard is automate hacking keyboard
it's also fantastic also super light
switch I got 35 grams you know super
light so anyway let's begin coding okay
so uh emac
list okay so the pink window shows all
my command Calles as you can see I move
coer or delete something you can see the
command name is uh show right there and
also the key stroke on the left side
let's see can you see it yes and uh then
okay so then that's uh so I'm using S
flly
keys and CA FL Keys is a emac package
just search for it it's like VI model
okay ca keys and I'm using a v keyboard
okay so here's my keyboard block and you
uh let me digress okay so you can see
there's a new mouse this is new track
boo I discovered new Lear M5 05 actually
this so there's this one which is
modeled after the
Microsoft tracko Explorer this this this
track B is the best track B 20 years ago
you know on Amazon people are selling it
for
$500 you know they no longer may make it
for since like since like 20 years ago
so anyway so now there is new
Leia track roll okay so check it out on
my website uh and but actually there's
also two more uh brand another brand is
pro AR I don't have a web page Pro AR
which looks exactly the same like new
newa I I think these are Chinese
companies so it this Chinese product
usually you have the same product but
several brand names you know I'm not
sure what exactly is going on you know
maybe they use the same same Factory
anyway so Pro Arc and
nuia you know so there's a question you
know of course they they are identical
you know the track you know they look
the product looks exactly the same
however The Branding on the track board
they are different so one of the
question is are they the same product
that is likely to be sold for I'm pretty
sure 99% same product the other question
is are they actually different company
you know two different actually separate
companies using the same you know
Factory uh and uh it seems to me they
are different companies I'm not sure you
know so one is newa the other one is pro
arc Arc Pro AR so you know sometimes
it's a case it's the same company but
they just have different brand names you
know one for USA for example you know so
I'm not sure I think they are different
companies so
nuia and porar they both produce this
track ball uh I think I'm going to get
get it and there's another company
called um a Japanese company also made
one very similar to
this uh but it's different product for
sure and that Japanese company uh I
forgot the name for the moment but if
you search for newly track B you'll see
redit you know they mention they'll talk
about it I forgot the name of that
Japanese company C something sea
something anyway so this is a good track
boo okay so you can look at my all my
track boo reviews so there's track boo
controllers then there is track B uh
track B all the track B you wanted to
know ever created so the the most these
are currently available I give you my
ratings then there is track B history
these are historical track BS so track
BS are fantastic okay so anyway let's
already two minutes okay let's start
coding so if you are here say hi okay
love to see your comments and stuff so
let's pop this comment
out where is the comment restore
chat
uh
so we're going to try to finish this in
two in 20
minutes instead of being chatty and so
on okay so let's start to code okay so
hello n nut boy any thoughts on track B
on the index versus track B for the
thumb let me talk about that
quickly so so you know so there are two
type of track BS of course you know one
is index finger based such as you know
you know they usually have bigger ball
so you use it like you know you roll it
the other type is the thumb based so
this is the first thumb based track
board so you use your thumb you know uh
most popular is so so this is a funny uh
funny ad you know they say some people
think you are aliens you know that that
index finger track B so they make they
make a mockery of it and the Logitech is
more natural using the thumb okay so
this is the first logic I believe this
is the first uh thumb based track B so
then Logitech makes that for example I
lived through it so back then this is
like uh 19
1996 something like that 1991 okay so
you know I I've seen I've touched these
track B so anyway Logitech then the most
popular one is the of course this one
this this uh this this model so this
model today you have for example you
have this one then then the latest is
actually this one you know Logitech uh
MX
Ugo this one is pretty good okay I have
a friend who has it so and I have the
one I have is um I have it I have this
one okay this is the lesser lesser model
less expensive but less features but I
have this one
m575 okay this so all these are based on
the classic um you know based on Classic
this model so anyway so these are thumb
based now my opinion you know if you ask
people if you I read you know thousands
of of reviews Some people prefer the
thumb Some people prefer the index
finger but my opinion is that you uh the
index finger is better because if you
use the thumb track boo you have the
issue you don't want to move your thumb
like that too much if you you know are
coding or photoshop or whatever video
editor every day and you use a thumb
track B let me get it let me show you
one so there it
is oh my God 20 minutes talk show I'm
not sure I can do that since we
digressed into this
topic so can you see it and why don't I
show you you see this thumb based track
Bo let's turn it
off okay so
you you move your thumb like
that you you don't want to do do that
too much okay because if if you do that
too much you know if you work long hours
or you you your habit is just keep your
hand there and move just you know use
your thumb you got you're going to have
thumb problems okay you're going to have
thumb problems
so so I would
say you know this is not bad I mean of
course every device if you use a bad
habit you know or if you use it too long
you're going to have problems so this is
not too bad but if you are really into
track ball and you are uh you know work
for hours every day probably Thum okay I
mean you want the you you want the let's
go back you want the index finger based
track B okay and when you use you know
the index finger so this is the classic
let me show you the kington this is the
the best one you know back in 1991 I was
every Mac this is the superior device
you know every Photoshop Photoshop
started its life on the Mac all the
drawings and Photoshop you know desk
code called desktop publishing so this
this is one of the elite device costing
over $100 back then that I wanted this
but I don't have money that I was a
student so Kensington expert okay so
this is the earliest version and today
and today's version is kind of like that
this is a special version they sell in
Japan pink
version so what I want to say is that
when you use a index finger track B
usually they have larger but you don't
want you don't want to do this okay you
don't want to bend your wrist like like
do this instead you want to move your
whole hand this is this is general
advice for keyboard as well like you
don't want to press
the back delete key by by doing that you
know back delete back delete you don't
want to do this okay in general doesn't
matter it's a keyboard is mouse you want
to move just move your whole hand okay
press and also also you don't want for
example on my Kinesis you don't want to
like use your trle your thumb you want
to try as much as possible I mean
develop a habit like just move your
whole hand and uh like let your hand be
relaxed and don't don't move them avoid
moving moving them at all the times okay
even pressing a key so anyway so for
example on the Pink Key let's see on the
Pink Key usually you you press the caps
lock right so when you do that you don't
want you don't want to like try to move
your finger and try to do that instead
just move your hand to the left a bit
and uh and uh and just uh move the whole
hand press the capslock key for example
for Vi users for example you set that to
uh to switch Modo you know uh insert
versus Command so anyway let's go back
to code uh let's go back to code okay
that's about track
B I also have the exact same model I
love my
m575 yes I have that but I guess I never
thought about the orgonomic implications
okay hey so qrious why 360 now it's your
main keyboard well I have so many
keyboards okay so whenever I use one as
my main people will think why do you
switch oh this cuz you know this must be
better because now this is man
okay that's not the case okay I have
many keyboards right now the glove 80 I
use for my can you see
it okay
so yeah you can see it you see it's
right here
so
four my
laptop so that's kind of that's why okay
so and also the kesis 360 I got wired
it's wired so it's no
Bluetooth so for my desktop for my power
station or battle station I prefer it
wired so it suits me the best to put
this one on desktop and that one
to the on the go you know because this
this too heavy thing you know very heavy
where it's I think 1 kilogram or more
you know I it's not suitable if I put on
a bed because it's heavy and I have to
and no blue tooth you know so that is a
reason so let's start coding emac list
shall
we okay so yeah
so yeah let's let's go back make sure my
video is uh okay so we are going to call
the emac this code
okay let me show you okay so show show
this is today's talk show you see I have
this YouTube video you know I wrote I
write blocks for like over 20 years
since
19997 okay so I have you know more than
20 years of blogs many of the YouTube
links went dead and other links so I
need a command to quickly I don't want
this you know because I I need a command
to change the link to a dead link for
example here's a
YouTube embedded iframe okay so I want
to press a key then it becomes stad link
not having to fetch YouTube You Know
YouTube is lots of
censorship since five years ago very
nasty anyway I want a command to change
so let me show you a command so uh let's
say let's see some website so
so uh
okay so someone is telling me about new
shell so new shell is a new shell okay I
don't think it'll go anywhere so you
know because yesterday or two days ago I
was talking about power Shell versus
bash so someone tells me about new
shell I mean asking me but anyway I
don't think he'll go anywhere it's on
Twitter okay someone asked me the
question so anyway I want to show you a
link so here's a link so showing browser
you can see we linked to new sh but it's
not a link so I press the key ban so it
becomes link so you can see the command
is called that it's part of kar HTML
package okay showing browser so you can
see now it's a link I can go to it okay
now let's say after you know a year or
two this let's say this this link can be
a you know political article or whatever
you you know many will be many many will
be dead okay so now I want to for
example I want to make kill this link
make it dead so I press a
key you can see that command is HTML
make link def defun HTML make link
different so now showing browser you can
see it now it's a dead link you know
it's with the s s tag means strike out
okay so that's a example of a command
that changes a link to dead okay so now
we don't need this let's remove it
okay so now I want that command to work
on if frame it doesn't work on iframe so
you see it says search failed a so I
want to modify the command so it works
on iframe okay so let's start to do
that okay so let's look at the code so
here is this code Kar HTML make link
def okay let's magnify so copy it make
it new buffer so 40 lines of code save
it XX let's say today
uhel so temp file okay so here is the
command very easy okay
so now I want to show you guys a command
so you can use right away so make link
okay so
actually uh so
Search emx tutorial search for link and
HTML so there are several
commands uh here okay so all these
command are here so let me show
you so actually there are several
versions so let so you can just go and
grab it and you'll have the code so this
one is HTML Amazon URL link F so
this this will for example you got the
Amazon
link uh let's let's go to talk show
so go to talk show let's say you have an
Amazon link showing browser here's the
Amazon link you just grabbed from a
website you can press a key and showing
browser and it becomes that so it
reformat it makes a URL into a link but
reformat the link into a canonical link
with possibly addition to your
affiliation tag you know a lot of people
you know do that so you know YouTubers
and so on so you so it so that that is
that command
okay this one search for it you'll find
it make Amazon URL link F okay now
this
version uh iMac this URL to HTML link
first state so this one will for example
let's
[Music]
see uh what is the new
Shell let's try that new shell again so
copy a link paste it so when I make a
link you see there is the custom tag
accessed date date Das access and there
is Target blank that means when you
click it you'll create a new tab and the
release no referral usually you
know you want to remove referral because
these stays a lot of websites they are
kind of nasty and also there's a dome
bug
where where if you have blank and if you
don't have if you have blank I forgot
exactly but I have a Blog about it it's
just search for blank okay so let's try
oh God uh you know there it is HTML link
problem underscore blank n no opener no
referral there is a nasty bug that
allows you to allow your the target
target site to kind of control the
previous page but anyway you read this
you'll see the detail so anyway that so
so I'm showing you so so this is a
command that makes a URL into a link
plus the date the date is very important
because if you write a blog after 10 or
20 years let's say
10 you know some link you don't know
what that link you forgot what that that
link is about and you need the date you
know you need to know when was when did
you link that when was that site you
viewed so
a few years later you can kind of if you
want to you can check website archive
you know and so on so the date is
usually important so anyway that's this
command you can grab here the next
version make HTML to that link that's
the version We demonstrated for example
this link I press the key uh wait press
the wrong key I press a key uh needs to
be inside I press a key you see it
becomes d fun link okay so that's this
one you can grab the code
here uh then and this one is the most
basic just change your URL into a link
okay so you can grab all those
code now let's go back to focus on what
we are going to do today okay it's
already 18 minutes okay so let's let's
go back to focus on what we are doing
today uh let's just make this make this
make this okay so later so I want to
modify the one of the command to work on
this okay so let's go back to the code
close that this code
okay so make a URL like that into like
uh all that
into into that okay
so the key here is that we want it to
work on on the if frame okay copy the if
frame so let's
see search backward uh search backward
search forward okay
so this is kind of uh too big let's
shrink it a
bit forward chart
so so that's one okay let me me just
work on so so this section works on
the this section works on the HTML tag
okay works on the a tag let's see so
let's let's put some so let's make them
into a syntactical unit
okay okay so that's one
thing uh where is
xp1 xp1 is the beginning position of the
tag xp2 is the end position of the tag
okay get the boundary of the the opening
tag okay
so you find the beginning tag and then
okay uh yeah okay
so beginning tag and find the boundary
of the end tag okay so let's move this
here we want to forward three characters
in case in in the case when the curer is
at the beginning of the tag
okay actually maybe let's not do that
okay
so search
backward then if found then search
forward
okay
uh so actually we just change this to a
regular expression
okay
[Music]
so uh okay so after you got the tag then
here's the entire link string then you
process the link
string then you search for
href Okay so to modify this you know so
if you wanted to work
with I frame you know if you wanted to
work with like an i frame there's a lot
modification you need to do so rather
it's
simple if we write a new one for the I
frame then we merge them
so
yeah okay so let's let's just let's just
do it
okay let's just say you know for for the
sake of today it's easier clear if I
just show you this
okay make a HTML I frame under Cruiser
to be to be def def okay if frame looks
like that for example
for
example
becomes okay that's an example and
uh
okay so that's the goal so all you have
to do
is
um yeah you forward charts so how many
charts is
this 14
CHS
okay so comments comments comment okay
comment
so so of course this is going to be
I
frame so you search for the iframe
tag then search backward for the iframe
tag then
[Music]
you
don't want
that then you search for
word
okay
and uh we don't want to save excusion
okay so we found the beginning tag
position and in tag position okay search
backward search forward then
we then what is if frame
tag
I frame tag looks like that okay
so yeah
so so we got the beginning and end
position then we want to grab this
Source
okay then okay so the whole string whole
link string
okay holding streen is that then create
a temp
buffer
um generate replacement so insert go to
point mean so search
for
Source then the URL is match string no
properties okay then date accessed
usually we don't have have dat data
accessed
so uh so let's remove that if
date
so data
accessed so usually iframe tag don't
doesn't have date access so let's remove
that it you could add that but usually
not
so let's search for Access State remove
it
okay don't worry about that okay
then then set the results okay day def
defun we don't
care so the result is
just you don't
care just that okay the result string
then just delete
region the whole tag go to the position
of the beginning of the tag insert the
string okay so this will do
it okay so actually we
can yeah eval the buffer and show the
pink window eval the buffer okay let's
try it out
so copy that paste it here then put a
curer here
s
iame defun okay correct there it is
showing
browser you see it
works uh so it works now so
now now there is a you know so basically
we we got our code the codee is this
okay let's copy it go to the talk show
uh let's create a code imag LP paste it
there color
it showing
browser so we got a code now essentially
we are done okay
so very easy no dependency
uh but
now there's a design issue for me for
example should I merge this
command
into this make link def defun should I
merge them so there's only just this
command or should I
like create a wrapper that depends on
whether the link is a normal link or is
a iframe then call each one of them you
know like Ste two command two or three
like a rapper then dispatch or the whole
thing should be just one
command uh actually I have to think
about that which one is a better design
so this is kind of
the interface or a package design issue
separate from the actual code because
you you know whether you should
um yeah there so the criteria is there
are many criterias for example if you
have one single command that's kind of
simpler for user you know whatever link
just make it def def you know user don't
have to worry about what whether it's
iframe or is it's a normal link or you
know so then there's a implementation so
if you decide just have one single
command so first of all to the user you
can have one single single command or
you can have two or more command so for
the user they have to decide whether you
want to defun a link or defun a if frame
because they are they are kind of
different so you give more Precision to
the
user so that's first thing to think
about what do you want for the use what
do you want the user to see that's the
most important this is the kind of the
API aspect
so after that there's a implementation
issue so doesn't matter which way you go
I mean in if you you know one is just
one single command the other case is
several command
now the implementation case if you want
a several command then what we have is
like perfect okay one is just for if
frame one is for normal
link but however if the if you decided
the user interface should have just one
single command then there are several
ways to go do you want one single like
merge these two or do you want a have a
wrapper that c
different internal command Okay so
that's the thing I have to think about
for my package okay that's it for
today I forgot to close you forgot to
close the opening s tag in a description
did we
I think we did we we have it here you
see you forgot to close the opening tag
in the description oh in the
description uh yeah it's
here okay that's it that's it for today
thank you guys for watching okay so you
know if you like my stuff 32 minutes
okay go to s code and uh it's my website
and the bottom you can see PayPal
patreon me okay thank you
guys
bye