good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today is
September 26th Thursday 2019 9 o'clock
a.m.
San Francisco time good morning
Bartholomew good morning Pablo
good morning Bart Romeo to Germany and
Pablo in Spain so you see I got two
video cameras web cameras here
so with towers towers tell me guys which
one do you think is better so the one on
the left let's see if I can make this so
and the one on the right so I am i alive
check two video cameras tell me which
one is better
okay starting okay I just woke up 20
minutes ago
I'm not fully awake yet moaning battle
meals so bathroom USA's so which video
is better guys temp tell me which which
video is better the brighter one or the
darker one wait
yeah one is brighter
am i okay though
okay say this the smaller face one or
the big face one tell me with which
one's better okay
the smaller face or the bigger face now
bottom ear says number thirteen patent
trolling Nam soon because of show tell
sure because of shot well how free
software is the solution to proprietary
capitalistic drawers okay let's talk
about that let's say that's a
non-technical topic and take its let's I
hope let's hope that's not gonna be like
yesterday it became a bride old red
actually that was bride out yesterday
but anyway so patent rose
you know patron so patron so let me
explain what that means so that you know
apparently there are some you know in
capitalistic countries like USA let's
let's even avoid the word capitalistic
because whenever you say that or
communism or capitalism then people have
certain fixed views attached to it
like they may not know exactly what what
it means they just have a fixed opinion
because in your mind you know in your
mind capitalism means something and but
in my mind or someone else Mayan capital
kept a bit capitalism means associated
with bunch of other things
so these jargons are typically not good
okay I mean they they are good in
academia but in general they they just
have associated information so anyway in
USA you have what's so-called patent
trolls they are companies who just by
patents and you know just by a bunch of
patents and and watch and get you know
to sue any corporation that possibly may
infringe the patent I mean that's there
are companies like that they do this as
their so away only way to make money you
know that's what patent row is okay let
me see what I want to say about that you
see in a free country free market
country meaning like freedom okay you
can do whatever you want
you know if you do this people don't
like it they don't they don't buy it
okay I think that's a great idea
free market I know a lot of people some
of you like like today especially today
some of my followers they are communists
you know I really annoys me because what
I want I feel like what I want to do is
I want to just explain to them a lot of
things but there's nothing you can do
just just just like my opinion about you
know free software foundation or open
source you cannot just especially on
Twitter you know or online text-based
chat forum you cannot just convince them
hub doesn't matter how long you write
the longer you right there you know they
ignore the part of the reasons they just
see what they want you know they have a
set mind a fixed mindset you know they
doesn't matter how reasonable you are
they did it just go over their brain it
doesn't go into their brain for example
like Emacs for example like you know as
you know I argue with Emacs people c'mon
interesting good morning he's very I'm
not late you are late and five I'm three
minutes early so just like Emacs okay
this is about 10 years ago I vividly
remember you know on Emacs I think it
was [ __ ] Todd eMac komtar Emacs
yeah
so anyway this you know in emacs so I to
explain something I think I think it was
about keybinding you know we had
argument you know there's a flame wars
so but I try to explain something and
but the other guy like just totally he
did he just totally like don't don't get
it and you know skipped my reasons and
and often doll so often it's the case
that you know someone should shut back
you know he's criticizing you blah blah
blah blah but the you see the what he
criticized is exactly what you just
explained you know so it's like when you
the now this doesn't happen just meat to
me okay this happened as far as I know
it's to anyone and also this happens in
argument okay husband and wife or you
know or you and your brother this all
happens when you have something
disagreements strong disturbing
disagreement especially about politics
or religion that those kind of thing
reason like does not seems to work like
whatever you say just fly over the other
person's head happens often so anyway
back to Peter and trolling what uh what
was I going to say oh yeah I was saying
you know capitalism communism you know a
lot of people they just have fixed ideas
so anyway you you have patent trolling
USA i as far as I know I know this this
guy okay I actually emailed him he
contacted me once let me tell you this
guy is a famous with a famous program
technologist he was the second or third
you know the the city of the CEO the
chief technology officer at Microsoft
during 1990s do you guys know what's his
name
say it okay so he's the chief
technologist at Microsoft in in 1990s
and
and and maybe all mm okay what's his
name he's very famous okay because now
and then you'll see his articles okay
there is something wrong bottom you know
there is AI was already wrong for what's
going on with this video video I was
already on for like seven minutes and
that was something wrong about yeah I I
thought I was talking about patent
trolling I already talked about that for
five minutes yeah I think there is
something wrong because oh my YouTube
YouTube screen it showed up five minutes
late why did why does that happen is
that because YouTube started to like
delay my videos or something I don't see
nothing I changed you know anyway I have
two videos I was going to ask you guys
which camera is better so tell tell me
okay is a bigger head better or the
smaller head this is a bigger head video
camera okay is the bigger head better or
the smaller like tell me which which
video camera is better yes something I
already talked for five minutes you know
yeah so so that's so bad so just change
did you see okay just in say is the
right one is better it's smaller head
alright a bigger head because I'm afraid
that there might be a reversal so what
you see on the right is what is my left
oh so you think the smaller is better
okay
Bartholomew says the bigger has better
colors but the smaller has much better
overall quality oh really so you guys
like the smaller I don't think people
come to look at your beautiful
[Laughter]
thank you thank you easier so I was you
know because I was actually thinking the
smaller is better anyway I was talking
about patent trolls I already talked
about for that five four five minutes so
so bottom you know you might check out
the video in some YouTube patron throws
okay so let me talk about that yeah
continue a little bit so anyway that's
the bigger has made you a lot black
really oh that's right okay let's let's
unplug it hit let's unplug okay let me
show you what they are
okay the video cameras
so the the the more detailed one the
smaller head you know the one on the
right
this one this one you know the more the
best better detail is this one it's
widely recommended on the web over its
Logitech c920 and there is a another
model of variation C 922 that is the
this one okay but actually it's no good
okay because it cannot focus like if I
in if I'm going to review my keyboard
you know it cannot focus so I do not
recommend it at all it's a mistake so I
would recommend you buy this one okay oh
my Amazon so let me let me post it so
let's go to talk show and it's close
this talk show pasted maker link copy
switchback
I saw your video reviewing a keyboard
which turned to a review about c920 when
you at least seemed in better mood I
hope this is another video there's no
obvious lag the bigger has major lag
okay so anyway so so this is better okay
I don't have it yet but I'm planning to
buy it because I checked on Amazon
reviews this one has focus so anyway let
me unplug the smaller one so unplug yeah
mistake [ __ ]
I'll remove remove the big one let me
read let me add it back
the
these problems
and remove that one okay
remove okay okay so that one so I guess
I'm not going to use that one day okay
that's about video and good morning
Kathy good morning to China to London so
we were talking about patent trolls
should we continue talking about that
patent rose so yeah bottom you was
asking about patron patent trolls so in
USA you have this potential oh yeah so
there is this Microsoft guy do you guys
he is a CEO of Microsoft in 1990s city
or central chief technology officer does
anyone remember his name type it
Microsoft CTO 1990s okay I actually
talked to that guy
okay so
Microsoft CTO okay
in the 1990s Nathan I think his name is
Nathan and he is this one this guy okay
Nathan my board her name hard to
pronounce is is that the Polish name oh
that's why he looks like Nathan Paul my
board you should see dodge yeah well
anyway so he he you know back in the
1990s he emailed me for one of my
programs because he's interesting guy
the reason we are bringing him up is
that he is a patent troll I mean what
you call a patent troll because as far
as I know he has sparked patent company
yeah in popular press in the popular
press my board and intellectual virtual
intellectual Ventures have been
repeatedly accused of acting as patent
trolls and stifling innovation by buying
patents and enforcing inventors to
license their ideas by means of
litigation okay so that this this is a
guy I kind of know this guy and this is
the only case I know about patent trolls
now first of all let me say let me tell
you about his story okay and also let me
talk about the patent trolls let me talk
about parent rows first so in a free
market okay I know everyone has their
own opinions and you know attached
opinions to capitalism in communism
means that those speak words and most of
it is is wrong okay
unless you've spent one year studying
you know capitalism in academia in
history I mean you did you literally
spend full time every day you know five
hours eight hours a day for a year you
studied that then otherwise you don't
know okay so I am for free market
basically you know economic capitalism
okay I think it's it's great it is free
market you know the capitalism that gave
us cause you know Google you know so
kick give us the webcam technology that
we can talk you know YouTube you know
that that's that's all from free market
okay if you have communism you don't
have that for example look at China you
know China beginning around 1976 they
started to have economic you know free
market for economy you know they start
to have free market economy
they basically ditched communism well
politically as a organization they are
still communism okay kind of you know
these it's like you know they because
they they know it doesn't work doesn't
work starting with Deng Xiaoping
they know it doesn't work so the in 1976
around there they switched to capitalism
so that is why today China is striving
over you know they sent ships to the
moon
you know they yeah so anyway so so free
market is a good thing okay and it in
free market then then you have the
patent idea which is kind of I think
it's kind of I'm not sure in my opinion
I'm not sure it's that good of an idea
or copyright you know for example
copyright and patent I think they should
they should exist okay but how I have a
copyright you know the history of
copyright is that America they they
extended extended extended you know it
two Americans benefit for example the
last time they extended copyright is
when Disney Mickey Mouse is about to
expire so the u.s. you know lawmakers
they decided to extend copyright
basically just so so that they benefit
Disney so that so the Mickey Mouse is
history in copyright you know so that's
evil but I think copyright in general is
a good idea you know like let's say
until the author dies all you know
copyright for 20 years 20 years is
enough okay so again these kind of
issues are complicated issues but most
opinions you hear online are just crass
you know they are no good they they have
you know they they either say oh it's no
good or you know those opinions are no
educated opinions and they are usually
angry and out and stuff so anyway I
think copyright has some some some some
values
okay what about patent patent is kind of
similar to copyright I think it also has
some values I'm not too sure okay anyway
in free economy then once if you if you
allow patent okay suppose it's okay idea
so once you allow patent then you can
have someone who just by patents because
a patent just becomes a commodity or
something you know like in free market
you can sell everything you can sell
labor you can sell ideas you can sell
you know I sell if you want it you pay
okay if you don't want it you don't have
to you know three every you know it's
freedom so once you have patent once you
allow patent then you could have a
company that buys patents so that's kind
of the origin of patent trolls now in
this case in
this case you know you just if you are a
company you just buy all the patents and
all you do is just you suing other
companies I don't think that's good okay
that's I think you know that inheritance
fee that's not a good thing so I don't
think maybe this guy is not doing a good
thing anyway that's that's a that's only
case a patent troll I know of anyway so
so this guy you know he's so this guy he
actually emailed me back in 1990 1990s
because he he liked he liked a package
I've written for tiding let me show you
that okay
math software graphics gallery so this
package so I wrote this in 1997 this
package generates tidings all sort of
tidings you can generate any tidings in
Mathematica and that guy my my board he
is you know he's very rich so he is
building his own house he is building a
house such that it seems like that every
decoration every design of the house is
based on mathematics some something like
that okay so he wrote me to thank me
you know for my package that yeah so
that's that's how he I know him then you
know 10 years ago so later on I have
also read okay so he has this patent
company intellectual Ventures and also
on a news it looks like he's building a
Museum of dinosaurs or something like
that
like he's into dinosaurs you know
you know he's he's I think interesting
guy okay I don't know I don't know why
is he he's doing the intellectual
Ventures anyway that's so that's my
opinion about patent so just in say
speak problem in software patents that
are so simple and vague they should not
have been granted that that I agree so
so let me tell you guys don't do not
confuse corruption with with patent or
copyright or the government okay because
I know a lot of people you know they
they look at today's society and they
think Oh capitalism is bad they they are
they are they believe in communism you
know I also agree today's society is
very bad okay but that's not because
capitalism because that's because
corruption corruption means you know you
know if I'm if I'm the president I take
your money you know you pay me you know
two billion dollars you know help me do
something that's corruption and and this
corruption that is a reason to me that
today's society is pretty bad corruption
not capitalism corruption okay you know
because because of a corruption or you
have the you know take you know the boss
of tech companies like Google Facebook
Twitter and so on and then you have
politicians and they are all corrupt
they just take bribes take money bribes
you know to do whatever so it becomes
worse and worse and to two people who
are now who have not studied capitalism
or you know history they they think oh
this is capitalism this is bad
oh look at America you know they you
know bad in many ways and also the other
thing is America you know my country you
know they you know you know we attack
other countries for our benefit we and
all your stuff you know things
that it's kind of a sensitive topic to
talk about you know the tulsi gabbard
I think she's a great candidate for
president 2020
she calls it regime change you know she
kind of popular popularized the term
regime change and there's also stories
about CIA and net I'm not sure I should
talk about that anyway so that's about
patent trolls vartholomio that's my
opinion about patents in patent trolls
and stuff so you want you don't want
corruption corruption is one of the most
critical thing
one of the most probably top three I
would say that that that tells you that
kind of governs how our country fairs
okay when you have a corrupt corruption
the country we are not doing very good
okay let me read the comments so we
talked about patent trolls it's let me
write down on a second let me copy we
it's copy what we talked about today so
and then let me read the patents so math
blog so wait so back to Emacs close kibo
blog back to Emacs close talk show okay
paste that that guy and keyboard we can
talk about keyboard and geometry I want
to talk about with we talked about that
and patent rose okay okay it's cuz that
because that Nathan because that hello
and webcam okay web can oh I already
have that okay so
so so let me read the comments okay I
type your questions and let's get it get
to it so the feature you are saying so I
saw your video reviewing Kibo which
turned to a review about 9:20 I think
you reviewed the hacker keyboard that
you can break in half okay yeah that
hacker Kibo oh yeah that video yes so I
have a video review about the hacker
keyboard just such a you you'll find it
so Israel says I don't care if you hate
some whatever but at least have
something to say
okay so Israel is agonist again is
swearing
hello there
good morning green deck - good morning
to Russia and so Israel says if you are
going to talk about Microsoft I started
a document about you are wrong about EEE
what what is he you should see the DOJ
document I think I disagree you know I
think we're gonna disagree on this
almost no matter what Israel because
because these kind of issues are like
religion you already believe it like
like doesn't matter how you know it's
it's like does not matter how rational
or reasonable I present my idea so or
proof or stuff you we are not you you
likely you will not be convinced in the
near future
okay likewise likewise so doesn't matter
what you say I'm not coming in you know
DOJ document I you know in fact I'm
going to I'm going okay meta criticized
that I've seen it you know I live
through it it's not like I haven't seen
it you know the fully sampled it yeah
let me give you a counter okay so you
are saying that DOJ document which is I
don't remember what that's stand for
exactly but basically Microsoft got sued
by government okay and you know so the
church says oh you are you are criminal
you know they say Microsoft did this or
that wrong okay but let me tell you that
you know today we have social justice
scan right and I know you are with me
that we don't like social justice guy we
hate it we I think they are doing so
many you know evil things however you
know Google if I fired this this guy
damn off you know who talked about me
and women issues in technology like why
why are they or more where that where
they are not more women in as
programmers so the more say is possibly
or maybe because women don't want to in
general that you know the women
preferred to provide people jobs you
know talking to people they preferred
relations with other people instead of
things you know which is you know true
it's a scientific truth you don't have
to go by science you can ask everyone
around the world every every you know
everyone know from you know his story
from history from 2,000 years ago to
today everyone knows that I mean women
they generally they are not into you
know they prefer okay it's not good or
bad they just prefer different
preferences and they are reason for that
as well but anyway James Tamou you know
he said that and he got fired so you
think it's wrong right I think it's
wrong and you agree and I know that but
however that you you have the courts you
know US Code the Labor Department they
did they they put out a document saying
no the moon is wrong you know you don't
have a case what you gonna do so if I'm
a social justice warrior I'm going to
tell you look look even the court says
you are wrong so what would you gonna do
so in the same way when you when you say
that you know
the judge saying that Microsoft is wrong
I think the church is wrong I mean is it
you know what what does the church do
you know I mean when it comes through
controversial topics you know Church you
know if you look at history judge
sometimes right sometimes wrong they are
not always right I mean they are not
they are not God okay I mean even God
for some issues in society
there is really no right answer you know
but you have to make a church judgment
you know there's no right answer so you
can't just say oh DOJ document this or
that in fact I can tell you again
okay I'm not going to talk about this
topic because these names gonna be one
hour okay then big but but let me just
put one more sentence you know it's a
Sun Microsystems they are far more evil
in my eyes they make the Microsoft they
Sun Microsystems Apple and the next
computer and the not next with the I I
got too many things to say about that
but anyway what I'm saying is that all
these UNIX companies they are doing
exactly embrace and extent just like
Microsoft okay is because you don't see
it because you you you want to support
Enix you don't see it any any of such
thing just flew by you know you don't
you flew by your you don't see it so now
again I'm not saying I'm absolutely
right I'm not saying OK my opinion about
how Microsoft is more ethical than the
UNIX companies that's not no that's not
true in fact possibly Microsoft this was
ok passed I would at least say possibly
I would not say for sure but at least
what I want to say is that I want to
tell you guys you know the you know all
those people UNIX fanatics who everyday
you know blaming Microsoft on everything
including keyboards like nut case not
jobs you know including keyboard keys
you know Microsoft kissing or every
everything I want to present counter
opinion because every time I go to the
the [ __ ] reddit I got bad you know
every time you have such opinion you got
and lonely that is why you know so at
least I want to present my opinion so
you can you know you guys you know it
since you guys are you know watching me
so I can you know present my idea so you
can for your consideration okay that's
about that that's that for Microsoft
okay that's that's that's it but about
Microsoft for today so let's see what is
the next topic so guys post you know
post the topic for next topic
so guys don't argue too much with each
other okay
I don't know I'm setting a bad example
so Joe good morning George
good morning George now George you are
in Australia right because yeah I think
yeah you are in Australia I'm pretty
sure so any chance you could give us a
tour of your website set up server
software build step script okay yeah we
can do it right now
it's not it's not complicated at all so
all I do all I do is for example so
George so I do oh I do is you know just
create a whip you know create a HTML
file write something okay and then when
I'm ready I go to ow hold on a second so
yeah let me show the on the Left window
you can see all my emails commands so
close that window I go to a show and I
just call this command that will sync to
my server so now if you go to sorry dot
info you go to our top show let's see
you go to programming blog then on the
Left panel you'll see a talk-show okay
this is the index of all my past talk
shows then this is today then there it
is this is you know what I just have
written just now and now it's on my
website so that's and in fact that's
basically all so it relies on two things
okay so so this is a directory go up go
up you can see this is my shot you know
web slash sorry the info
directory so you know I just create
files here
then I sync to my web server and that's
it that's it so there's not much so the
bulk of it about the structure and
there's no like structure or template
you know it's everything I do you know
it began in 1997 was manually coded HTML
and eventually you know I have eMac
these commands to help me create tags
and so on you know that and that's it
there is no fixed directory structure or
things like that
yeah so that's that's that's it you know
if you have more questions about that
let me know so back to the comments yeah
so dingo says any love for monarchy
monarchy you mean the like king dingo
why is your comment blocked Brock I
don't know yeah this YouTube is Google
is getting very evil understand your
accounting creation is surely uncommon
theologians done
yeah religion you know okay so monarchy
is the best system prove me wrong
monarchy I don't know I don't know I
don't know about that
so Bartholomew says you say you have to
learn a lot to understand something I
don't see how you studied free-market
enough if you think it's a good idea
it is true I don't
okay my opinion let me tell you that
okay so so there are a few things about
that okay first of all is I can tell you
why I think free-market is good okay
the other thing is that it's kind of a
logical contradiction so you are saying
you know to learn something you have to
study it a lot before you can cram you
know you know it so why am i claiming
that I know free-market and you know I
actually have not studied a lot about it
so let me answer that contradiction or
paradox well first first of all you know
how do you define learn you know you
learn something sufficiently for example
you can't go buy college degree you know
college especially especially today they
tongue out PhDs by the millions every
year so every year you have you know
millions of college you know the PhDs
but they a lot of them don't know
nothing meanwhile as an example greatest
mathematicians in history many of them
don't have a degree for example and
today in tech you know we have Bill
Gates Steve Jobs there are college
dropouts right they are famous for you
have to be a dropout you know so so
college degree doesn't tell you it much
about you know so I mean the thing is
how do you define you know have you
studied enough about the free market
okay so that's that's funny how do you
define this is this really know actually
yeah when you talk about these things
there is no absolute definition about
when when is someone really you know can
be considered really have studied a lot
know a lot about something before he can
claim he knows it typically okay but I
can tell you a natural way to judge
someone knows a lot about some subject
basically in society any subject matter
you typically have a group of
now again who defines who is the expert
that's open issue but in general I mean
with let's not get into philosophical
details because if you go in deep into
philosophy there's no answer for nothing
no you can't answer one plus one equals
two five okay so let's not you know keep
digging into philosophy per inch okay so
in general in society a group of people
you can say they are expert at something
okay you know roughly you know depending
on who you ask is exactly you know
exactly who are in the group may you
know different people may have different
opinions but general they are you know
roughly a group of Google people
everyone agrees they are expert about
subject X okay so you you ask you you
take this as X experts okay these
experts can church someone okay let's
say person B is is expert about
something about about what they are
expert at okay this this group of
people's in other words in other words
in other words how do you know how do
you know I'm a Emacs expert okay you can
tell like I mean if you ask any other
Emacs expert you can kind of get answer
you can tell you you know I'm expert in
Emacs I don't have a college degree for
eMac B's and also you know if you ask
someone who hates Saudi they will tell
you I know nothing about eMac B's okay
you get you know you start to get into
this political area where you know
nothing is you know people just attacked
each other anyway so you get idea you
know so how do you judge somebody's
expert in general if you are not if you
are not too controversial I mean if you
are not tied into some culture but I
mean if you stand outside okay if you
look for where you you know who are the
experts well who is who are not now when
and when it comes to free market
that is not you know free market is not
actually a academic subject I mean it's
not it's kind of you know it can be like
academic subject but it's you know it's
just it's a just idea but let me tell
you why I like free market okay free
market okay let me tell you my opinion
basically free market is basically the
most you the most natural okay that's
just natural
that's just like why do you why do human
talk let me ask you what do you why do
human talk I mean if you if you don't
have a PhD in how human talks how do you
no human can talk you know that's city
right in the same way I think free
market is is it's just a natural thing
for example you and me okay I have I
have a pen I'm gonna give you from ten
dollars you you want it you know if you
like it I give it to you you give me ten
dollars if you don't like it don't do it
that's freedom that's free market that's
how things are on the other hand the
communism that's in a sense that's also
natural because you know sometimes I
just give you something free that's
share but anyways it's this tough topic
to talk about okay so
GTG for a big what is Gigi Gigi so
Justine says China became more free
market capitalist around the same time
that relations with us resumed in 1979
seems like big coincidence
it has nothing I can tell you it has
nothing to do with USA ok so I don't
know if you know China history maybe you
have studied it Justin but as far as I
know it has nothing to do with USA USA
the you know the who is the Nixon Nixon
Nixon President Nixon you know it's the
big victory sign he visited China
because why because China got atom bomb
that's why he he's he visit China that's
why when when you big when you become
powerful people BP France you that that
is the most fundamental nature of
humanity when you at you when you got
nuclear bomb people befriend you
befriend you
hey Mad Money met match dingo Payton
okay so okay so no more common address
to me what's the next comment guys so
that's it so Israel says back did I miss
anything good yes you meet you missed a
big chunk I was just talking about your
idea about
DOJ and Microsoft okay you guys are
talking to each other I don't know what
you guys are saying it's too much to
read
Sabitha Romina says you're jealous you
jealous of our extensive argument you
wanna be part of it you guys arguing
about something you know be aware there
are a lot misunderstandings you know
especially yeah you know you know right
when you talk about politics you know
religion or this kind of thing and also
also in my for example here for example
am i you know on the YouTube chat you
know usually like sometimes you guys are
making jokes but the others guy do not
see it you know didn't realize it's a
joke so it gets wild
so anyway so Matt says I know you kind
of married to Emax but what do you what
what are your thoughts on Adam beers
code and the like okay that's the
interesting thing
you know I so yeah I'm kind of married
to Emacs and now I'm getting too old
it's hard to switch it's hot you know I
don't have time to explore new things
like there's another person I forgot the
name but he asked me about fish you know
she'll there's a new there they are
quite a few new shells you know there's
the zsh there's fish and I think there's
another you know they want to replace
Bosch they asked my opinions I think
they are good you know every today you
know since 10 years ago every three or
five years is a new stuff I mean so
today you know exponential take what
growth you have so many things you like
you cannot know anything much anymore so
for me I don't have time to explore that
any anymore when you are 50 you don't
you know this this is a natural state of
things okay when you are 40 when you are
50 it's not like when you are younger
when I'm younger yeah IIIi dive into
those so much you like every time
there's a new I would dive into and you
know know everything other people says
and whether I should use it and stuff
like that but not today you know even
even new languages you
I have time to explore the other thing
about fish you know this new shells new
grab you know there's quite a few great
replacements he said they kind of they
become insignificant
they are not like you know twenty years
ago you know today there are so many
languages you you know you rather you
know you can you can use : you know I've
showed this quite a few times for
example I have this : that that do grab
you know this this file 166 lines you
know less than 200 lines you know it
does squid and you know I showed it this
many times you can just search my videos
so and you have grab you have also find
replays so that they can you know this
this or these kind of things everyone
can write you know you can write in one
hour and those those scripts repair
replacement
you know she'll replacement they they
are not significant anymore and even
languages as you know languages comes
you know new languages every three years
so the important thing is not about you
know which shell is better you know
that's becomes less less and less
important rather you you just want to
create programs like today people are
talking you know Google they have AI
libraries right you know the new neural
networks libraries what they call it
tensorflow
[ __ ] google tensorflow and you know
so you study you know you study those
and you know create something useful the
the tools and stuff that becomes less
and less of you know importance
especially for us you know we are nuts
we we like to dive into those things
like which one is better which one is
exactly you know one inch better than
the other those are not really important
so gotta so you want to spend your time
to actually build some project that's
useful to people that's a way to go you
know that that is the you know really
importance and also that you can survive
you know you make money and stuff so
yeah so the question about what do I
thought think of a demand vs code okay
so but just for pure interest I'm
interested in that question because I
always thought you know Emacs is not
really that special because oh you have
all you really need is a scripting
language a programming language that
serves as a call of an editor then you
could have some something similar to
Emacs and Emacs is pretty old right
Emacs is like 30 or 40 years old like in
1985 or so anyway so so so so Emacs and
by the way Emacs anyway so so it should
be possible in fact not difficult at all
to have a Emacs alternative that is
better than Emacs in almost every way
like a modern version and possibly using
it you know the language may not be this
it could be others
although Java JavaScript language is
pretty bad okay but anyway it could be
you know Python for example Python will
be it's possible to have a Emacs
replacement so I always thought about
this you know I really want thought
about this because the free software
foundation the Emacs people they got
lots of problems so you know one thing
with with Richard Stallman gun you know
gone from free software foundation I
wonder whether he will still be in the
Emacs dev mailing list you know he's a
pain you know he's a you know it
obstacle there so I wonder what will
happen in there so far you know since he
got he since he resigned
I have not seen he posts into the Emax
there the you know two days ago I
checked he have not yet so I don't know
what's going on to be happening there so
anyway Emacs got problems so I'm I do
look forward for you know any editor
that has the same powers Emacs a modern
replacement and I always thought that
Adam and Mia's code possibly possibly
such replacement because Adam as you
know it's created by github organization
and they they you know they use
JavaScript as they're called to create a
entire editor the the whole editor is
written in JavaScript so so I think you
know that's got potential possibly you
know maybe that that is the modern Emacs
and VSO vs code comes out at Adam
it seems vs code is more popular today I
have not tried I have not tried vs code
I have tried Adam for like a day you
know so anyway so I think Adam vs Co
they are past potentially Emacs
replacement you know better than Emacs
and do and more powerful than Emacs in
every way but the problem is that I have
not actually looked into myself you know
like I'm you know I'm 50 I'm getting old
you know it takes learning is smaller
and I don't have time you know to look
into that it kind of yeah so yeah that's
my opinion about Adam and BS code you
know I I would like to I like I really
like to look into because that will
solve that will answer this you know
curiosity question in my mind for long
because you know I love Emacs but I do
find this tremendous problems in Emacs
especially you know the emag based
language has been stagnating for like 20
years and all the Emacs dev the fact you
have to sign copyright
and Richard Stallman getting old and
doing these all these damages to Emax oh
I don't know
really enjoy all these aspects and of
course I criticized Emacs over the
people flame me me so you know so but
anyway I haven't looked into Adam okay
so that's what what else questions to me
okay dingo is using vim okay good
morning Michael thank you you are
welcome so anything else okay if you
have a question you want me to answer
put my name okay make it orange so I can
see if you didn't you know try it let's
see how do I make someone's name orange
let me try bathroom you okay but Emil
something
new shell what's new shell Acme no I
have not tried Acme I have not tried any
of this Oh anyway so let's go back to so
you know Adam you know because it's
based on JavaScript so you can I mean
Eve even though it's based on JavaScript
I mean from the ground up you know it's
written in JavaScript but the one
question I'm not sure I'm not sure is
that whether it's really like Emacs
where you can just evaluate some Edy's
code and has it become you know you
don't have to recompile anything I don't
know if that's true for Adam so max
Reiter says please let's to emac Lee's
major my life for wammy
okay we can do that but today is kind of
late because I already talked for 51 31
minutes but there I did one video doing
that you know you did you are we are you
aware of that
Maxo raider i did one video of live
coding or actually it's a live tutorial
of Emacs major mod so if you do not know
that check it out but if you already
know that if you already seen that video
but rather you have some other questions
so find that video not so good then we
can do it again yeah let me know you
know come on come early okay in this
week I'm gonna be 9 o clock every day
so if you can come early and we can do
that stop liking not-safe-for-work
treats on Twitter I don't think I like
not-safe-for-work treats I haven't done
that but however I don't like the
not-safe-for-work things okay I think
you know because I think everyone
I know some of you have criticized me
for that
you know besides amend you know but
however you know because I think okay
let me explain why I think that's you
know I think you know in society you
should do whatever you want you know not
not subject yourself to these especially
then not safe for what work you know
that's that's crap
you know that's garbage you know if it's
legal then you can do it okay well
there's some conventions I mean for
example you do not want to post some
nude pictures like you know blatant poem
you know because other people are using
twitter or something you know three to
Facebook you know a walk you know is so
so the my reason for not post posting
you know fool like poem [ __ ] [ __ ]
pictures okay my reason for that is that
because there is a certain convention we
must respect for example you don't go
out to new you know to the street nude
you don't go to your workbook you know
you don't go to your company your
workplace and take off your clothes like
take your bed off because that's the
Swap disruptive you know you I mean in
theory there's nothing wrong with naked
being naked but yeah but we have to
follow this convention because if you do
that people get hot on you know that you
know then this is distracting because
that's you know that's sexual nature so
this is the reason I think you should
follow certain conventions for example
you don't go out to the street nude
you don't you know you don't strip at
work face things like that and in the
same way on Twitter on Facebook you know
you should not post you should not just
post up you know pornographic picture
like like two people are [ __ ] each
other you know all animations of it you
know you should avoid it you should not
do that so if you want to do that then
okay maybe
maybe post some kind of warning you know
so that it's adult okay that is that is
I what I agree and that is what I do as
well usually - yeah I - I typically
follow that now that's my opinion about
that now there's another thing which I
think is nasty you know about that in
FSF concept you know that concept is
nasty in my opinion okay so in modern
society as I mentioned we have this you
know convention you you you don't want
you don't want to disrupt Society okay
but however then there are Isis starting
around year 2000 okay I can tell you the
exact year starting around early early
2000 let's say 2004 let's say 2005 in
fact in fact you'll find that wording
Wikipedia because I read Wikipedia you
know and not safe for work
there's an article on Wikipedia and that
will tell you which state it began okay
because I've read that article
it's nasty concept it's a nasty it's
this is why you have social justice
today Israel okay this is nsfs is one of
the element that gave gave gave out
today's social justice okay so from
Wikipedia we can find which is the date
this concept arrived you know they don't
have it right here but you know if you
go to edit history view history if you
go to view history okay and you can
trace back when did this article begin
and you as you'll find a date okay let
me show you some techniques of the
Wikipedia stuff because I've been
reading I have I have like 10,000
Wikipedia links
have I showed you guys that let me show
you okay
what's going on
okay so here is a page so as of 2016 I
have a total of 7,000 links to Wikipedia
on my website for my websites I stopped
I stopped maintaining this page and I
stopped linking to Wikipedia in fact I
started to remove all my links to
Wikipedia so I have you know seven
thousand links to Wikipedia you can see
on this page you know each line
indicates which page our link to
Wikipedia and then you go to that page
you'll find a link but I started to
remove Wikipedia links since like three
years ago because I think Wikipedia
becomes corrupting in several ways when
it comes to political topics they
becomes totally corrupt today they are
just most most of it is social justice
so anyway that's Wikipedia links so I
mean you know anyway so not safe for
work okay so not safe for work the idea
came from the modern you know modern
yuppies in cities you know that
programmers mostly they came from white
white white people white-collar
programmers like today's social justice
people okay
that's our ancient that's the daddies of
social justice they you know they don't
know about society they don't know
nothing but they just they just have
this you know they just have this
concept oh that's not safe for work say
you know say safe safe what the [ __ ] is
the word safe safety like safe space
that's our engine of all these okay safe
not say not safe for work and today the
social justice has become degenerate you
know they actually a lot of them are
doing pong insert pong and transient
stuff okay let's stop there let's not
get into that topic
Musha what's new shell okay new show no
shell is a new show I guess
please like only not say for things on
Twitter because you know it's not safe
for work okay that's a term once you
have a term it becomes a jargon you once
you have a jargon okay then all the
actual meaning or concept they start to
deviate they have a life they become
they start to have a life of its own
that is the case with me not safe for
walk let me tell you the history okay so
now not safe for work
it began in 2003 or so something like
that in the beginning it means you don't
postpone okay that's it that's basically
it you don't post the poem on you know
on reddit online forums that's it that's
it no you know [ __ ] pictures no
totally nude pictures that that's it but
today today it becomes something else
but you've become so many things
especially on for example you can see it
our master then master done is created
by this young guy millennial okay who is
kind of into social justice so I must
master then you know you it's like if
you post political opinions you also
have to post you also have to tag it you
know sensitive even if it's all just
text you have to say sensitive or if you
post something nude not point at all
like today you know the the
post-standard
they change over the past 30 years you
know in for example in in 1960s if you
wear bikinis you go to chair okay you if
you are a magazine you publish people
with today's Brazilian bikinis you know
g-string or whatever you go to jail
because that's you you violated you you
Tran West obscenity law in USA bikini
okay in 1960s in 96 in 1960s if you have
a girl have a full body swimsuit that's
considered you know risky that's that's
like oh oh my god
you are posting palm you know full-body
swimsuit you know but over the years
then you have you know then you have
miniskirts then then swim suit becomes
bikini then you have cheese stream you
know then you have you know things like
that so today today if you post nude
some girl nude as long it's not like
spreading their legs you know it's like
you know just a nude picture you know
maybe you know that usually a co-ed
model of photography okay like like you
know photography of a nude that's that's
like not considered pond that's you see
it every day you know it's you see it
even in movies you know today in movies
Hollywood you have cutting people's head
off you have all this violence you have
massive you have war depiction in you
know in realism just just like actually
they are so real did they are like they
studied you know the directors they
science had advanced so advanced you
know that you cut people's head off they
are just they are realistic there are no
difference from fake you know they
actually what what you see in movies are
like realistic it's just like you know
happens in real life okay so so I was
saying you know you see you know Po and
you see everywhere you know the and
today the search you know it's well it's
not getting into details so so what I'm
saying is that so on one hand on
Hollywood for example this standard
about nudity becomes so you know for
lack of better word let's say degenerate
it becomes very degenerate then you have
trans right you have gays trans and you
have you know gays [ __ ] each other
and and and and the social justice
people of course they they they actually
post pictures of that on the news they
want to tell us you know case kissing
each other they want to promote it they
know so you have things like that on one
hand and Hollywood you know how do you
would you find also the things you know
and also the point
industry they becomes I'd rather not
tell exactly what's going on but you you
you you know you've you probably know
you know you have this category you have
so many you have like so many category
of things import okay and they are
headquartered they they have a castle in
can San Francisco which is the heart of
social justice you know extreme left is
in San Francisco you know where I live
you know one hour drive that's their
headquarter they they are the mega phone
corporation they produce this this class
at home okay that's for the whole world
so anyway that's on my hand you have the
all these things going on on the other
hand you know on the other hand for
example our master then you have this
not-safe-for-work
and you have this all these warning
labels trigger yeah trigger trigger and
warning labels what a [ __ ] is that
so my opinion okay the reason I'd you
know like I said before you don't want
to post you know plate and knew that you
know pong whatever is current standard
you don't want to post that directly you
know it's like suddenly your friend your
your coworker is reading something then
suddenly he scores the next the next
screen becomes full point you don't want
to do that because you want to respect
certain conventions okay but on the
other hand what's the [ __ ] with a you
know not not safe for work like today
you have to like if you post a political
opinion you have to like have a warning
oh oh trigger and you know it's like I
said not safe for work they become so
many things you have the trigger warning
for a political opinions or for anything
that might be offensive then you have
the safe for work for anything that's
you know things like that and meanwhile
by the way meanwhile there are so many
Twitter account that that's all pong you
know so like to let me talk let me talk
about this on Twitter for example oh I'm
a student it's you know pongs pongs
become such that either you are a
hundred percent pong like there are
thousands thousands counts on Twitter
they are just 100% pong like every post
is for like they are just dedicated poem
you either have that oh you have all
this or this Sen white people you know
or these same people they are they are
or good immoral people they don't they
never post anything that possibly
considered not-safe-for-work anything at
all they are all this sent when we when
Richard Stallman got kicked out they say
nothing
these [ __ ] they say nothing when I
opposed to Reddit you know I know a lot
free software phonetics they are you
know they did every time I say something
negative about Richard Stallman they you
see a thousand posts criticizing me okay
they take me down they did they thump
down but now Richard Stallman Cal kicked
out it's all quiet you don't see these
all nice people they are all quiet
[ __ ] them so easy it is these people so
they never post controversial like they
are they are kindly they are all
climbing the ladder you know yeah they
are all climbing the ladder they are
going me they staying you know they they
work for Google Facebook or the
cooperate they say nothing controversial
they keep it you know so nice so they
climb the ladder they make money so
that's not my opinion about that issue
say for work so to you you know you
think oh that save for walk is still
totally different from the social
justice trigger warning that's you know
that's your perspective but to me they
are kind of the same thing they Eve are
they they are the same same same trend
okay it just becomes worse okay that's
my opinion
I mean I mean there is no for this issue
I don't think there is a right answer
okay there is no right answer and so
that you know that this is the right
answer for every society okay I don't
think it's a right answer so it's like
you know if you you know you think that
way I think this way okay that that's
what I think
so you know so instead of you know
instead of you know accounts that
dedicated to Paul and meanwhile all the
people say nothing about you know six is
everyday life stuff sex is like eating
everyone has to do it you know you you
get married you have sex okay sexual you
know it's it's natural life so what I
like to see you know in my opinion you
should it's natural okay so maybe maybe
once a month or twice a month you might
post a picture of yourself engaging in
sex okay because it's natural that's you
know there's nothing really wrong with
it you know with you with your wife or
girlfriend or husband maybe you have
some naughty pictures once in a while
once in half a year let's say so that so
I would like to see that that that would
be more natural like everyone you know
because you do that everyone does that
you know it's natural but today we don't
have that today's today's society you
you today's society you have these all
clean people then you have this
dedicated palm accounts that's no good
you know did you you know that's no good
that's that's no good
so again like I said you know you don't
yeah I mean this I don't think there is
the right answer for these so it depends
on society it depends on your you know
your location your culture your and also
real religion so you know so so I have
my opinions I don't I don't push it on
this okay so but but meanwhile I think
the social justice are evil so usually I
don't I don't I don't conform to
whatever you know so I you know
occasionally you might see me post you
know actually I don't
I haven't postponed for years like my
command of English and what's with this
new shell new shell part of me what's
with this new show new shell so new
shell ok new shell is anusha right like
the fish you know a fish I guess wait
what is new shell log into nutshell okay
not nut shell new shell yeah okay this
one new shell oh yeah sure rittany Ross
yeah I can recognize because everyone
everyone wants to see the sons of lost
this is the greatest language now how
much money would I need to put Acme
features to Emacs are you asking that
for serious because most people ask that
it's not serious actually and also also
even if you give me a lot of money I
would be the wrong guy to do it I don't
know see okay's and I don't think that's
something I can do well okay so that's
that's actually yeah I wouldn't be able
to do it Akemi I never used it I know it
I think it's so it's from plan night
right so even if you pay me let's say
hundred dollars an hour I can do it
because I don't know see
I find it ironic okay mark says I find
it are okay I think that's it for today
I'm gonna answer that and that's it for
today one hour you know maybe it's two
three five minutes okay so if you have
best questions for me just posted okay
and that's it from for me today my
command of English everyone wants to
make fun of me of that okay so so yeah
so the question is I find it you know
mark says I find it ironic that you are
so again is social justice companies
like Facebook Google and others yet you
are streaming on YouTube okay here's my
explanation you know I know a lot of you
guys and a lot of people who are into
Emacs UNIX people Linux people you know
you guys always niche you know you guys
are forever remaining this niche in
society okay yeah I know I know I'm
against YouTube but I'm using YouTube
because YouTube is the you know it's a
mainstream I mean as far as you know if
you want to you know you want to
convince people you want to spread your
ideas right you want to tell people what
is evil what is not evil okay oh you
want to spread the Gospels of Linux
right you want to do it in a public way
not in a [ __ ] nerd like English in
some sewage in some underground you know
talking about what we should all use
Linux you know that's that's that's what
you guys doing and that's we've been
doing for the past 30 years niche you
know like skin screaming please be the
greatest language skinned Emacs wimp
you know and yet you always studying in
underground basically on this you know
nobody cares okay like today I know you
have shoot you know YouTube shoot
whatever what what whatever is on it but
people don't read that okay you want to
get you want to go public you want to
change society that's it
change
you know you don't like so sure justice
sailor and say it with a real name not
with the anonymous not with memes that
okay 4chan [ __ ] 4chan means not don't do
it okay try not to do that go with your
real name
say what you actually believe use
YouTube change society okay make your
voice heard not in in a sewage in this
niche group in this in cryptography you
know in crypto systems whatever [ __ ] you
know this GE max versus VI you know
staying there you guys we've been there
forever for the past 30 years you get
nowhere sir Cyrus society gets worse and
worse and you guys still in this niche
group thinking you are doing something
that you know so go out use YouTube put
your real name there speak to the people
you get to come to Tonko extreme okay
don't go extreme make reason reasonable
voice heard
okay that's my opinion about that and
that is why I'm using YouTube that's
most that's kind of the reason that's
half of the reason at least the other
reason is like yeah the other reason is
I mean I don't be I don't want to
support YouTube okay but I don't write
like right now I don't have money I
don't have nothing I don't have I don't
have much choice I don't have time to
spend to the niche you know [ __ ] shoot
and whatever there are some others and
also others they don't work well like
you don't you go to you know for example
the other popular ones saying you know I
know the names but what's the name video
or something they don't they always like
whenever you use them they they they get
stuck okay they are not like YouTube
they get stuck and stuff so what I want
is so anyway so yeah that's my
recommendation okay go go out with your
real name say something reasonable
change change award not staying in Asia
okay nice nice group
okay so easier says I should back up my
video to lie be I know what you're
saying but I don't have time like I
don't have I don't have hot discs you
know you act like I sent I say this like
yesterday I don't have you don't you
don't know me you know I say it you
don't understand I am in a situation I
can't I don't have backup and I anyway
listen on it let's see what happens okay
I need to get I don't have time you know
I need to get you know like right now
YouTube even to me it's like it's just
my it's just my I'm doing YouTube it's
just it's just like my my own
distraction my procrastination you see
I'm not doing things I should be doing
you know each YouTube is just my it's a
record of sorry okay so what why I'm
dead you can see okay this is what
cazali is like that this is kind of like
that kinda so that's so that's it for
today
so meow cat backup yeah yeah yeah right
so that's it for today thank you guys
for coming and again you know I'm you
know like some of my opinions I mean
some of these things they don't have
absolute right answers okay and I give
you some of my opinions that's that's
all that's just opinions so so try to
set up with a conversation with nukes me
yeah we can you know so Duke Smith we
can do that if you are interested I
don't know how that will go we can you
know maybe we debate or maybe we not
debate but just talk about things that
will work you know the other thing I
don't have
okay maybe I can join you know is if he
is interested I can join his show
because I don't have I don't have likes
to say and stuff set up properly so
my screen so maybe we can do that we can
talk about Emacs yeah we can do who
Emacs versus VI for sure okay that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
and hope to see you next
yeah I know he's got the guest I've seen
a few so maybe I can talk to him yeah
read my comments I read all your
comments permission to pack up do you
give me permission to make a backup
channel of your stuff
yeah you already did right I mean
YouTube yeah sure go ahead
I'm not gonna research new show and I'm
not gonna research to new show and to a
report on that I'm getting too old for
Nash new show you know yeah I know he's
a meme user so okay bye guys
yeah back up yeah of course back up of
flying even especially for offline you
don't have to ask right I mean every we
can get back up back up
bye guys