good morning everyone welcome to 2020
the year of our Lord and January 23rd
Thursday and today is right now it's 3 o
clock in the afternoon San Francisco
time California way yay California
I got a unexpected guest you know life
you know my my in my apartment so there
is some today so we got a tons of things
to talk about and I don't know what are
the topics but I know one thing we're
gonna talk about is the gogo keyboards
okay the go-go keyboard
let me show you okay so this is this is
my new toy
you
I have to do
gee [ __ ] so there it is okay so there it
is
you
Jesus Jesus I've been talking for 10
minutes with our audio this or fact a
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] oh factor [ __ ] [ __ ]
the modern technology [ __ ] society I
mean talking for 10 minutes with our
audio Jesus the year of our Lord
plasmas right as you spoke the sky
darkened what does the reveal no sound
no audio when you switch to the camera
ok so at some point I lost my voice all
I want is your voice [ __ ] the modern
technology [ __ ] the complexity [ __ ] the
technique as [ __ ] open-source [ __ ] free
software foundation [ __ ] Emacs ok so
that means we cap so this is wait so
when did I have lost sound audio ok so
let me recap ok so this is the Google
keyboard ok this is a Google keyboard
and thang-thang them to the guys he sent
me one and I'm going to so this is chalk
key switches ok chalk kiss which is
stupid logitech camera you know he
cannot see well but anyway so that's the
keyboard and right now I'm half drunk
I'm 50% drunk just like the 50% keyboard
I'm 50% drunk because I drunk a half cup
of beer wait I still have another half
cup so yeah I'm going to get drunk today
Oh
melodia sness I should try a melodious
Ness hi guys oh you beautiful people now
I'm going to do a melodious video the
point about melodious video is that you
watch it you will be
naturally attracted to it because the
voice sounds good
and it's confident and it's soothing it
pleases your nerves
melodious 'no snis okay in fact that
drunk on a bit of Corona Corona
it is indeed I'm drunk I'm drinking
Corona beer so there is half a cup
should I show it let me show it okay so
there is half a cup half cup more so I
have to I'm not you see this black box
on top in bottom that's idiocy yeah I
can fix it but you know that it's a pain
with the modern technology [ __ ] with
this OBS open source you know supposed
to be open source good open source
whatever open source [ __ ] you know the
end result is that we don't have power
and the corporation's big giant
corporations Google Facebook Microsoft
and the government the politicians they
[ __ ] around every day then then the
common people especially young people
they become that you know they have no
power and they become they cannot do
nothing they are degenerate they become
weak you cannot even if you code you
cannot make a living with code because
this is open-source there are 10,000
programs open source on github whatever
you're gonna write because these 10,000
programs are written by open-source
[ __ ] who are working for Google at
theta theta so Google tells them to you
know write code you know at nighttime so
you you don't get the job the only way
for you to you know even if you code is
to work for Google these open source and
free software foundation [ __ ] and
Richard Stallman [ __ ] you know
Richard Stallman he is saying Oh freedom
freedom of the individual
freedom of the software freedom his ass
let me tell you about that okay freedom
freedom about software you know so we
Richard Stallman he's he's concept of
freedom software you know as you know he
is saying that software as such should
be such that you can modify the source
code you share and then you know
communism share share your properties
share your house share your car your car
is my car that's the ultimate ethicality
so anyways the software foundation that
I mean the fist of information Richard
Stallman [ __ ] it you know he saying
free software software should be free
because he said you know he's he's
abusing the word freedom let me tell you
what freedom means freedom means you
know for example I say to you you cannot
go out you can you you you must what
whatever exactly what I tell you to do
okay you cannot you cannot say certain
things you cannot do certain things you
must stay at home and if you are women
if you are a girl you must be your sex
slave that is freedom I mean that is the
that is what no freedom means that is
freedom freedom of real freedom of what
you can do okay not to that is the
actual important meaning of freedom such
as free speech you know free speech that
is about freedom of speech of what you
can say then you have also freedom of
behavior freedom of action for example
in in some countries you can you know
women if you are women in Islamic
countries you have to when you go out
you have to wear you have to cover your
face okay like that like this well
actually like like in Islamic countries
you have to cover your face okay so like
that if you are a female that's so that
that that is freedom okay that is the
issue of freedom no freedom okay that's
the meaning of freedom
okay now comes that Richard Stallman
[ __ ] he says that when software does
not allow you to have source code is
it's you know limiting freedom now what
he is saying is actually just his
opinion about how software should be you
know the software license it's not about
freedom at all in some sense its freedom
but it's like you know you see in his
personal sense about freedom so he is
abusing the word freedom and he's just a
Easy's he's just wrong and [ __ ] in
so many levels today because now he's
been kicked out just like that by the
social justice scan and he's saying he's
like oh I'm okay
you know life goes on I'm okay with it
haha [ __ ] it we just stolen you know
before we follow even though I disagree
with Richard Stallman
because he he has many bad you know he's
just no good okay he's a bad Technic
leader he haven't been coding for ten
twenty years and he's but he's telling
us what to do in a max death you know
he's telling what Emacs what feature he
should have things like that you know
[ __ ] [ __ ] Richard Stallman but
now he is and also I don't like him but
still still which we hear so many is
good for one thing because he is
opposing the the big corporations in
government and that's a good thing
because you know that's a good thing
okay but now he's like now he got kicked
out by the social history scan like he's
he become a week a week [ __ ] so he's
like oh I'm okay yeah I'm gonna resign
you know the week [ __ ] it
so so even so so he becomes you know
batting always no good so I make sense
okay I'm half drunk and today's topic is
whatever
you know maybe I should just shut down
the talk show so people guys talk okay
I'm good okay I'm supposed to talk about
something about a keyboard so I got this
keyboard right go go okay so let me show
you the pages I'm going to show you the
pages go go key was F M s where are you
from FMS so you want to talk about
coronavirus are you in China that's a
question are you in China or are you are
you Chinese oops
something real went wrong [ __ ] stupid
Google
check status ms you're talking today's
video is kind of [ __ ] up I think so we
talked for 10 minutes so all you guys
watching say something
ok so good morning Alan and good morning
Bart and good morning Lord and good
morning
nam - soo no do ok so good morning
FMS ok oh wow
I already have five likes Jesus when you
swear you get likes I'm drunk I may
actually have drunk because things okay
so I got this keyboard so you guys
should you guys should go check out and
buy it you know this guy when he saw my
video talking about his keyboard it's
gonna it's gonna be pretty bad because
normally it's supposed to be promotional
you know like you know you talk about
this keyboard how good it is or things
like that only you Oh or you'd give a
review of it then you then you know
people you know get a review then you go
P some people will go buy it but now I'm
like drunk in this [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] tub
or [ __ ] up video and appearing like
idiot talking like a idiot so Alan says
what are your opinions on alcohol how do
you feel when you went drinking I don't
like I don't like alcohol in general and
alright well I don't like beer okay I
don't know most guys like pious you know
most guys buddies you know typical
people you know they like pious buddy
and what bro programmers or whatever I
don't like beer I don't enjoy
I don't enjoy the taste of beer you know
and about alcohol in general I don't
like it neither because I don't
the idea the concept concept of where I
am in my capabilities in thinking is
decimated okay that is what I going
what's going on you know it DB rotates
your brain that's that's what alcohol is
about so in general I don't like our
alcohol I don't like I don't like beer
don't like alcohol clean your room why
are your opinions or during your living
space what are your opinions well what
is your current sleep schedule why don't
you do a normal normal schedule well
that's you have to ask the question
seriously like do you actually are
asking about those questions because if
the if you are not asking those
questions seriously like you are as if
you are curious or you want to know then
it doesn't it doesn't make sense it
doesn't it's like it doesn't in leavin
the video because because I'm not
getting what do you want to know really
so I'm interesting some lifestyle not
trolling ok my lifestyle
well my lifestyle is mostly aesthetic
not in some religious way or in some
ethical principle way but rather it just
happens to be my personality and happens
to be my style so my lifestyle is you
know if there is one word or two words
to describe it it would be aesthetic so
you know that's also that's a Greek
thing that's a lots of Greek
philosophers like that and in quite a
few other people for example let me show
you okay so they actually so let's go
through some talk show page talk show
okay here we are
magnify magnify superpowers in the
kisara start chimeric mod so I'm drunk
and so I
talk at random okay so this is the
opportunity for you to ask me questions
as asking us secrets
so aesthetic I hope I spelled it right
aesthetic okay let's check spelling with
the stupid grooves I spell [ __ ] [ __ ]
the new open-source they do nothing good
okay aesthetic esthetician there it is
Wikipedia article asterism so that's
kind of what I am that I'm like my life
because well I'm like that and and also
okay in bog okay bog
means which means okay let me magnify
which means everything is functionality
no fluff okay and in this respect is
similar to military style military style
okay so you know what is a military
style like if you go to soldiers you
know US Army Marines or whatever
military style you have bunkers you know
everything is functional you don't have
pretty you know pretty decorations
pretty sculptures you know the you don't
have nothing like that
pretty colors pretty keyboards you know
nothing everything is purely functional
liking in a war field that's a military
military style of things I don't like
military much you know itself but
however the military style of things
that's what I like because it's smarten
so in other words to describe my
lifestyle is smarten okay let's look up
Wikipedia spotter and we are sparta
spartan army in whatever spartan sparta
so but actually I want the
adverb adjectives so smarter means of
all relating to Sparta or its people it
also means rigorously self disciplined
or self-restraint yeah that's the one
or simple frugal or austere
oh yes that's why I am austerity that's
how I roll guys now you roll your way
rock and roll drugs or hippies or trends
you know we have season who is into
those things or you do weightlifting or
whatever you that you know you do your
things you do yourself but my style is
austerity a UST R ity austerity okay
like you know austerity austerity so
that's some of the words that describes
my I guess my lifestyle aesthetic
Spartan austerity and bog now what why
bog because bog is the perfect a bog you
know book bogie you know of the Star
Trek race it's a perfection of
perfection they don't care about
anything else other than functionality
so that is kind of my style that's how I
like my things my keyboards my computers
my computer programming style my Emacs
workflow my windowing systems you know
or the hull Tiny's tiny managers sucks
because why why I think tiny manager
sucks because IO am only concerned about
efficiency and functionality nothing
else
meanwhile the tiling manager Linux
idiots they are actually they say they
think they are concerned about
efficiency and functionality but no they
are actually concerned about following
fashions in fads and [ __ ] it Linux
idiocy
and granola Teck Teck idiocy you know
they are concerned about kerning
typography like pretty nice but
meanwhile they claim these nuts this
[ __ ] opens those [ __ ] they think
you know they believe they think they
are like very efficient functional
people they want everything to be raw
you know the tech the tech you know they
think they are efficient but in fact
what they are actually concerned is
about this insignificant and
inconsequential kerning you know like
how close to two characters must be
these [ __ ] these idiots extreme
idiocy okay so today's talk show of
being drunk okay so what else asked me
questions this is you ask me questions
in answer just in scarf I so it actually
good morning sunshine actually Justin's
Kossoff I scoff I asked me some
questions but the Google Chat scored it
off I forgot what other questions
so Alan says did you get enough of my my
my answer to my lifestyles things so
actually Alan is kind of similar
Alan is also pursuing this this kind of
aesthetic things and one of the Alan's
thing is he he sits on a cold floor with
a mat that in fact that actually I
cannot adopt so about cleaning rooms
okay my room is a [ __ ] garbage it's a
[ __ ]
the [ __ ] I am in I have showed my
room before I mean why don't I just show
it
let's show a big video okay so let's try
the let's see if there is some let's see
if there is some wait so I need to some
delay if I show the video yeah there is
some delay because okay so there it is
my room okay so let me show you so on
the right side okay so I have to show
you the perspectives and so you get the
sense of how my room is like okay so so
that so this is behind my back and you
see those piles of papers let me show
you okay those piles of papers are like
10 years old of males whatever [ __ ]
males and there's a pathway here there
is a passage for me to go into my room
and then a pile of math books in
whatever and they my desk from the top
okay and so now actually so let me show
you from this angle
okay how drunk can I be so this is my
desk and then there is the mirror and
there is micro DH you see so the way I
manage my clothing is you you just pile
them just throw them form into a pile
that's the most efficient way to manage
your clothes
oh my clothes are just basically just
t-shirts poor brown says 36 key board -
because I would hate my workflow 36
Jesus 36 keys total are you kidding okay
hold on a second let me switch back
switch back just the video okay I'm
drunk I'm slightly drunk st. say my okay
say my drunk so Reaper good morning
Reaper so Paul Brown says 36 keyboard
wow you are using 36 keys that I cannot
believe so
since I'm drunk maybe I should do some
drugs you know
confess
d w m+ whimpers la la take the worst
[ __ ] possible gathered under or under
your fingers DWM and dream and dream in
attack
why are you drunk in the morning sigh
well I happened to have a guest coming
by and the social circumstances cause
for you know opening a big bottle of
beer
so that's why I'm drinking you know once
I drink the next few hours I cannot walk
anymore
so so you become wasted but anyway so
there is this I show this a few times
this is PHP or TBC or THC you know I'm
not from here with this this hippie
jargons but anyway this is the substance
of the march of wanna and it's legal in
California ok it's legal I got this from
a friend you know a friend a good friend
but once you do this you cannot think
anymore
you know this these things in alcohol
they cut off your brain's ability to
think but thinking is what I like you
know I have to be a lot you know I'm
always my whole life is basically on a
emergency situation emergency situation
so I don't in general I don't like I
don't like alcohol and no do I like I
don't like this ok but because you do
them you cannot think anymore
so any questions anything else and rip
her what do you say so we'd an alcohol a
good man
a good mix okay I'm gonna start to sway
you know I'm gonna rock okay what else
now I'm supposed to have okay we are
going to we're supposed to talk about
this go go keyboard I'm not in no
position to talk about that but however
I can tell you you know so I got this
keyboard and technically I'm supposed to
show full head again so technique well
I'm going to show you actually you can
type on this actually I mean try it okay
you can see me typing on this so I put
the camera on my shoulder
OOP oops not [ __ ] I put the camera on
top of my head okay so let me try that
okay and is it per plugin yes I think so
let me start actually let me start the
you mean start the event viewers so
actually I know what key it is sending
so this is the event viewer on a Mac so
you can wait can you see me okay now I
turn my head and it's going to okay so I
have to keep myself in this position so
now you see I type keys okay asdf so
right now it's in corty okay you know it
takes some time to actually adjust to be
able to learn to use this keyboard
25 each side 50 keys total okay so it
will take some time to to get used to
and of course this keyboard is runs on
the qmx qmk software let me tell you
about qmk so you go to Microsoft
keyboard blog and you type comments okay
keep the comments going or else I run
out of topics and I'm gonna shut down
okay so whoever is where whoever is
watching type type something so this you
know he also sent me some of the
stickers let me show you okay so you can
see there it is
the stickers MX pad
MX pad so what does that mean that means
MX refers to Cherry MX Cherry MX is the
most popular keyboard key switch okay so
let me show you if you don't know most
of you already know if you are into
keyboards but some of you may not know
so MX Cherry MX that's the name of the
cooperation cherry you know these these
are cherry MX mechanical key switches
okay so they are the most popular so
chary cooperation they are made by Jarek
company called cherry corporation cherry
you know like popping a cherry you know
there is a German Germany company in
Germany they happens to I mean their
company names just just cherry
corporation and they make these key
switches okay
they make these key switches oh wait you
are not seeing it
[ __ ] actually I'm showing you on my
keyboard block okay so you go to my
keyboard Prague Saudi keyboard you go to
the design page then you click on a key
switch then you page down 1 2 3 4 then
you can see the Cherry MX switches now
these are the most well known mechanical
key switches okay and here's animation
showing how it works so this is the most
well-known and they are actually
something like 50 years old designed 50
years ago so so why does this guy have
this what wait where why does this guy
have this this MX bad thing the sticker
because well actually I mean this is a
semi joke because he's saying Cherry MX
key switches is actually bad I mean if
you are a keyboard phonetic if you are
keyboard enthusiastic if you are a
keyboard Kaunas you then then you would
know the Cherry MX you know it's it's
actually not that good because it's 50
years old so the better one is for
example he so the better one this this
one is using chalk keyboard chalk I mean
chalk switches okay so actually I don't
know if I can show stupid [ __ ]
idiotic logitech camera [ __ ] I cannot
focus okay I have this you know it sells
for $70 [ __ ] Logitech and these big
corporations you know let me show you
about the logitech camera they so I
bought this camera I thought I thought
it's going to be miscellaneous okay so
you go to miscellaneous input devices
then you go you scroll down you see this
is what I have this is what I'm using
not GTECH c920 in fact you go to a lot
camera review website and they will they
will say oh this is the best one by this
one so I so I bought it a year ago and
this is [ __ ] [ __ ] so they are this
review site sites actually light this
camera has it's about 70 dollars or
something okay it has autofocus but
actually it's got a problem oh no it
look looks like it's discontinued it's
got a problem of focusing autofocus it's
got a problem because when you have
anything close it doesn't actually focus
I mean it's not that it cannot focus it
can it can't focus you know very close
to things but however the problem is
that it the problem is that it the
autofocus software is a problem because
when you have something close by it
doesn't focus so that is a problem with
this camera so I need to buy a new
camera I need to spend $300 or something
anyway so there is this one you know
after some research so this one on
Amazon is only $43 it's like half over
the price of the logitech and you know
this one is a nameless from China and it
can focus okay so you see so Logitech
these companies they are just [ __ ]
around you know because they become
famously it is they just [ __ ] around so
and so this Chinese camera came focus
you know actually I talked about this
before in my video but the thing with my
livestream is that nobody watches it
only like 50 people 100 people watches
every time I do a stream there is like
total of 100
200 watch it so I have to repeat things
every time so what what what else what
are the comments so we digressed and
let's get back to perhaps the the what
are we talking about that the yeah the
Google keyboard so okay so he made these
stickers to make fun of the AMEX cherry
MX because it's really it's not that
good okay the switch so you have you
have quite a few modern switches you go
to my website go to the keyboard
mechanic
you know the key switch page and you
will see it so visit my website and pay
me okay donate $1,000 or $2,000 that
that's okay you know just just transfer
your bank to PayPal to my account let's
make the this help humor animals you
know so what are you guys saying so let
me read actually I need to piss I have
too much drink now I need to go piss I'm
so poor I cannot afford a piss pot now
that's a line from from the movie you
know the movie about the Mozart what's
the name of the amiduos okay that's
there's a movie Amador's about the
Mozart the composer Mozart so let's see
what you guys are saying so and maybe
that's it for today so I've been talking
for how long 40 minutes so what's an
interesting mechanism okay we depress
alcohol a good mix okay
how is the light switches I'm using vim
tech and utility slips okay happy
hacking keyboard is the worst [ __ ]
possible you know that's a trope you
know that's that's my trophy that's one
of the things I talk about happy hacking
is the worst possible keyboard you know
if you give me a happy hacking keyboard
I would not use it you know I would
throw it away dumpy attorney in the
trash can and we have a friend who spent
three hundred dollars to acquire this
keyboard called Rio Rio force Wade
[ __ ] what the [ __ ] what happened to
my [ __ ] I lost all my tabs [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] grave [ __ ] google [ __ ] browsers you
know I have my browser set so that when
I close you know when I close the
browser for example let me show you you
see I have so many tabs right I have
thousand steps but if I close it and
restart all those tabs come back
I need that because that's the way I
track what I'm working on okay so I have
the same so now let's restart Firefox
wait can you see it yeah you can see it
so I restart Firefox you see all my
attacks are back ambiguous grammar you
know that's one of a project I mean
wanting to write for two years passes
about passes so the on this page I am
talking about ambiguous grammar deep
math math and programming stuff but
whenever I talk about this on my live
stream nobody cares for it because
whenever you talk about advanced stuff
nobody knows the thing
so anyway so you see all might have czar
back but so I have the same set for Bray
but now something [ __ ] up whenever
this happens it's very annoying because
you lost it's like you know you take
notes right you take note notes in your
class or you have your to-do list so my
to-do list is the taps you know I have
the taps each one means I I need to
still need to walk on this page
that's my tabs full but now the [ __ ]
brave lost my tens of times it lost it
some it happens sometimes you know in
Firefox or opera because I was just
going to I was going to go to brave and
show you the the picture that someone
bought this real force keyboard actually
the pictures are here so you guys join
discord okay we have great people and we
have great people and great photos and
Alan is posting a picture about Alan
history
what is Alan doing he's saying something
I stand by the position that improve
technique can allow people to surpass
most isolated problems don't know what
Alan is saying but we have great photos
ok photos from each person not just
[ __ ] random link from website you
know if you go to the internet every you
know every website hacker news dreaded
or whatever everyone is posting [ __ ]
4chan you know just link link to random
pages [ __ ] [ __ ] them [ __ ] idiots
that's what society has become everyone
is like this just random you know who
cares ok ok cool who gives a [ __ ] you
know just you just post through your
random you know opinions you are not
actually talking to people you are just
posting things nobody in and other
people nobody very few ok most people
don't care what you post it it just went
over it's just like Twitter you know
every day is this 10 billion things you
know fly by
but on discord we have more of actual
real people in photos you see this is
one of my photo my personal photos okay
and we have other people's photos okay
there's a lot talk on this court but you
can see personal photos every day that
means we are good people
okay we are the good guys not the
[ __ ] random [ __ ] on the internet
nameless [ __ ] nameless and cow and
posting random saying whatever [ __ ]
Linux or whatever [ __ ] Oh politics you
know social justice so fortune [ __ ] but
we here have real people showing us real
things so for example so this this guy
this guy is what's his name you know he
showed he bought this you know keyboard
he bought this real forced keyboard this
is real for high profile keyboard and
this keyboard is three thousand dollars
guys this keyboard is three thousand
dollars three of us
high-quality Topor mechanism topple keys
which is same thing using happy hanging
keyboard I cannot understand why people
would you know you give me this keyboard
I'll throw it in the trash okay I
actually need to go to the bathroom to
piss okay so I will be back in one
minute
what a show today I'm drunk and I don't
know what I'm talking about okay so okay
so let's see what you guys sing I heard
so we have Paul Brown says I heard just
resting your fingers on the keys is
enough to trigger a key press with those
slide switches okay yeah so let me tell
you about this keyboard okay so this
go-go
you should you know you guys should go
to my website you know check what I have
to say because I'm going to update the
page
you know actually so let me show you
okay so actually let me show you my page
so you guys go to just you know such
sorry keyboard blog you will see it
Google keyboard okay so this keyboard
I'm going to start to write more things
about it so you've you know one of the
thing about this keyboard is that it
uses the qmk software now qnk is the
great is you know it's a great software
open source for you know for
programmable keyboards so it's is very
powerful it's one of the best okay I
would not say it's the best but now this
is critical okay it's one of the best I
will say top three best software for
programmable keyboards from where right
so anyway so but qmx
it turns out you have to spend you know
hours to study yet because qmx is is is
oriented for programmers you know for
example so now I have this keyboard
I want to program it you know to do what
I want because I cannot get used to the
50% keyboard you know the it's
it only has 50 keys which is not enough
whenever you want to press you know for
example you want to enter a number you
cannot just press a number it is you
know you have to hold a modifier you
know to get a number that's a that's the
thing that's the thing with this you
know 50% keyboard if you want to press
if you want to type a question mark you
have to hold some key then press the
question mark it's you know it's not a
[ __ ] [ __ ] up system but a lot of
people like it you know if you are young
you don't have a problem and you don't
really type that much that's fine
but if you are professional if you have
to write a book that's not fine okay
that's gonna or if you type in Chinese
or Russian you're gonna have problems
you cannot have Syria you not see a
doctor within one month if you use 50%
keyboards okay that is my opinion so but
apparently the 50% or 60% is it's a fad
like we have tons of people they want
the you know 50% over 60% 30% it began
but I can tell you you know it began by
this [ __ ] Atreus [ __ ] this is the most
idiotic keyboard by the tech code by vo
hackleburg you know he's a he's a good
guy but he sees opinions about keyboard
is idiotic he know the 60% 50% 40%
keyboard began it's only has 40 42 keys
so when you need to type a number or if
you type need to type a question mark or
parentheses you have to hold down some
you know control order whatever [ __ ] and
if you have to type Chinese or Russian
Russian with its 36 characters alphabet
forget it you know then you you know
you're gonna see a doctor within a month
these [ __ ] idiots this these nerds
you know these they don't know what
they're doing and also you have this
prank becoming very popular
you know it's 47 47 Keys only
okay anyway that that is my rant about
these 50% keyboards you know it works
for a lot of these people because they
don't they don't type much you know they
type 10 minutes a day that's that's it
if they if they are a professional
programmer or they type is like 10
minutes a day if you if they type it
continuously just a minute so gates
today they then they go to watch movies
they talk to their mom they talk to they
go to conferences they have to drive
home and that's most of the how they
spend their day they eat they they go to
Starbucks the idiots they don't actually
type more than 10 minutes a day 15
minutes okay max so that's why they oh
yeah they love this 50% oh it's it's
portable you know so you have all these
50 keys you know 50% so idiotic jargon
they call it percent they like to call
it percent 50% keyboard 60 percent
keyboard or tank heaters tank EVS my
[ __ ] ass keyboard they like those
jargons okay anyway so anyway so a lot
of people like them because well it feet
it fit their needs you know because they
don't have that much they are young they
are the you know hippies fobs on the
street you know it suits their needs
it's 50 percent 50 keys is fine and they
don't they only type English they don't
types Chinese they don't type Japanese
they don't type Russian okay they are
monolingual they're yeah that works that
works and then then you have this kong
keyboard you have a lot of this okay you
40 keys
so this one is 42 keys and they they are
thinking you know they you want to you
know two chords another idiotic idea
okay i have an article about codes about
this this idiotic i did a video on this
like for one hour okay so I did actually
multiple videos on this about steno and
for over the most extreme idiotic [ __ ]
is the Provo project if you know what
I'm talking about good if you don't know
you can you know just such Saudi
keyboards and go read my website how
explain to you why it's bad anyway it
turns out I'm flaming this keyboard but
actually so this so you guys buy this
keyboard okay so so anyway so I'm saying
so 50% keyboard okay that's fine for a
lot of people but that's like that's not
that's not good for me I need I need
hundred keys okay so so what I so what
so I'm going to use but but I still this
is a great great because I'm going to
use this keyboard for I'm going to use
this keyboard for ASCII macro paw pad
okay
for example arm browser okay so let me
show you my browser so I press a key
previous tab okay
previous tab next time previous tab next
tab in Lodge in Lodge
you not shrink shrink shrink JC I came
in all the way you see shrink and I can
go back to previous page I can go back
to next page forward and backward
backward forward left tab right up left
up right left I'm right I'm right arm
you see and this one is cut copy paste
okay and then you have this one is open
last closed okay this close tab open
eyes closed
you see close tab over last ghost okay
close have new tab
okay so that's a new tab close it and
this keys refresh so let's go to the
left and refresh refresh refresh refresh
you know it's you can keep holding at
every fish so let me show you how I fly
through my tabs you see you see oh [ __ ]
I didn't show my windows so you missed
all the windows flag ah Jesus
okay I'm drunk okay so just let me show
it again
so back back so left half right our left
half right up right up previous page
next page preview page next page right
so magnify shrink okay and close tab
reopen okay new tab you see so that is
the why you want those you know that's
my set up as convenient so I plan to use
this keyboard for that purpose right now
this is a numeric code keypad I
programmed using carabiner okay I'm not
gonna show the code but I program using
carabiner
so that's this one and carabine I okay I
mean let me show you okay it's very
complex
let me show you carabiner
okay check preferences okay god this
switching back and forth carabiner is
very complex you have to spend days to
learn it but it's very powerful indeed
so anyway I'm using her by not to
program a number numerical keypad so
it's not it's not a program of BA keypad
but I'm going to plan to do it with the
with this turd a go-go keyboard okay
where is it
I need memory I need memory for my
computer okay I'm I'm planning to use
these for as a Mac Marco keypad so it's
gonna be very powerful okay so wait
anyway there's a question about a key
switch so there is some special
something special about this key switch
this this keyboard a comes with a switch
that is what
wait a mess y'all check the video is
gone [ __ ]
what happened Jesus
am i actually still um okay okay so yeah
well there's a question about the
Chuck's switch okay so this there's
something special about this keyboard it
has normally your key switch is like 50
grams pressure okay 50 or 40 42 40 40 to
55 okay
for example cherry cherry MX black is 55
cherry cherry MX brown is 50 Cherry MX
red is 40 okay but this goggle you can
buy it so that the the pressure is like
12 grams so it's so light such lights
it's so light that you can actually blow
like you know blow it to activate the
key so that's very interesting but the
one I have they sent it to me is
actually 50 grams I would you know I I
just got that so so that's about that
okay maybe I think that's it for today I
kind of I'm drunk okay I'm out of I'm
drunk about key rings I don't have Kiwis
so I don't have a key reason just in
scarf scarf I asked about YouTube about
how to how to become a YouTube you know
I just seen scarf like post songs
discord public so I can answer okay post
on discord because too many questions I
can tell you how to do it it's very easy
okay what else anything else I think
that's it I'm kind of I'm drunk and I
don't know what I'm talking about
and
okay so what else there's gonna make for
interesting typing experience how - how
do you like it so yeah so I haven't
really actually start to type on these I
just got this yesterday I only got it
yesterday so is you know you're taking
me a while to see what I'm gonna do with
it you know I'm gonna do quite a lot of
things but one of the problem is the qmx
software the qmx qmk software turns out
it's like it's for programmers so it's
not just for you you know who just
bought a new keyboard you think okay I
want to remap the keys you just go
through the queue and make a website and
do it no it's not like that you have to
learn how to flash the firmware and
stuff you know lots of for I'm technical
stuff so this does anyone know oh I want
to do right now is just change the key
bindings you know like how do I do that
so you go to their website you go to
their configurator let me see if I can
no okay it's not showing you know you go
to their website you go to their
configurator it's not you know there's
no instruction about what to do it's
like oh this programmer programmer nerd
[ __ ] this programmer nerd [ __ ] okay so
you need JavaScript so let me this
program nerd [ __ ] for example I just
bought you know for example I just had
gogo all I want to do now I want to
program it so that it becomes my keypad
but I cannot do it you know so here is
the qmk configuration page right so you
go you go here you type go go you select
your keyboard grg oh there it is okay so
you select your keyboard good so I got
this is the keyboard I have
but what i do i do what do i do next
what do i do you know i want for example
I want the jakey to do ctrl C copy what
do I do next this [ __ ] idiot the
program this tech this hacker types you
know this holier-than-thou this elite
they think they are superior you know
these [ __ ] open-source [ __ ] they
don't know what they're doing so I you
know I just got this keyboard so I want
to program the jakey to do control C so
he says okay I go to the qmk website I'm
now now in a qmk website so later
keyboard I said okay I did and now I'm
not what I do
so there is a you know I download what I
do there is no instruction this [ __ ]
idiot
[ __ ] the open-source [ __ ] these
nerds you know these typical Linux you
know this program Linux BSD you know
this this type of people they are like
that you know because for two reasons
okay one is elitism this is the way to
show they to show that they are in group
they are you know part of this elite
community this is how they show it you
know implicitly this is part of the
standard human animal behavior you know
they show that they are in group the
other reason is that they these people
they don't know they don't know about
society they don't know how to tell
society works they don't know how it
works so they can they are incapable of
designing a good UI even when they want
it to so you know that's a problem this
geek nerd tech kickers you know anyway
so that's about that so yeah so anyway
the problem facing me right now is that
I want to I want to make this go go to
do keypads you know to to send copy cut
paste previous tab next time but now I
cannot do it because then I'm going to
spend a few hours to I need to spend few
hours on the qmk website to study how
things work you know another thing
very idiotic about about the qmk set on
their website the qmk website there is
no link to the documentation and ok
right now several la tons of problems
first first of all when you are on this
config website but you don't know what
that what the [ __ ] they are but what
does this why is this service
highlighted and what does this ready
ready means what does the for what the
factors it me you know you click on the
settings
okay that's configuration settings what
ok this fast input whatever don't know
what they are ok then you click on the
configurator you know this know is
appears there's no way to get back to
the qmk homepage a [ __ ] idiocy these
[ __ ] nuts you know there's this
indeed they think they know what to you
know they think they're all here then so
let me go to the homepage let me show
you qmk there you search for qmk then
you will go to their homepage okq ok qmk
not qwk you know so you go to a qmk from
where ok this idiotic page they now one
first of all there is no link there is
no link to go through their
documentation page oh there is okay wait
okay there is actually ok I was wrong
about that there is a link to the
documentation but it's it's buried you
see anyway this is oh wait wait let me
go back
magnify okay so you see it should be
over here but it's over here ok anyway
so you have to I have to go to the
documentation and this documentation and
they are on first of all 100 there's 100
things wrong with it
first of all it's gray on black [ __ ]
unreadable [ __ ] it's great on black you
know I I have an article on that
great text on black
okay good query on white not clear on
black this [ __ ] web design [ __ ] these
idiots they create things that seems
pretty but impossible to read okay
can you actually read what this says
impossible to read okay this [ __ ]
idiot open-source [ __ ] so anyway
the QA Mak the qmk website the doc page
is it this is not you know it's hard to
read even if you magnify you know it's
kind of the especially on the left you
see it's gray and white how to read then
it turns out you know if this is
actually written for programmers so I'm
going to have to read like 10 20 hours
so that I can actually program my
keyboard 10 yeah 10 20 hours is no
exaggeration
then let's go back to the qmk homepage
you know so so one of their big thing is
the online configurator you know so so
this is a page where you supposed to
program your keyboard but there's no
instructions like there is no link on
this page you don't know what is going
on there is no instructions whatever
whatsoever this is like [ __ ] you are
just and there is no link from this page
to the documentation neither so this
open source they are [ __ ] idiots
that's what they are
okay that's it for about it that's about
it today it turns out is just a huge
huge rent ok Paul Brown says it's easier
to program without the fancy GUI ok I
understand what you are saying but there
are two aspects ok let me tell you ok
the problem you guys have okay
you see so you are saying it's easier to
program so I mean my problem right now
he said I need to program
keyboard you know you just bought a
keyboard from from from this great open
source to in yourself keyboard yeah it's
great I love it I love it thank you know
I love it thank you you know the Google
keyboard so so now I need to I want to
you know make it useful so I need to
program key program the keys but I can I
have a problem I have to spend 20 hours
for it that's a problem that's that is a
problem okay that's you know these I
don't know what what you open source you
know these elite geeks are thinking is
that a problem or not that's a father
you know you don't for example Google
when people you know Google for example
what they want to people to use their
browser right calm you know they don't
they don't tell people oh don't know
this and download make and download goo
CC then read this documentation guru CC
for 20 hours so then you compile you
download the source code of chrome then
compare it then you have composite write
to Google to that to any of these who
wants to make money do that no but the
the Nerds they don't seem to understand
it they don't get it it's like oh make
compile [ __ ] [ __ ] this Linux [ __ ] it's
you don't understand even when they want
to because many of these keyboards are
actually commercial you know these many
of these do it yourself keyboards I I
sell you know let me show you okay let
me show you my pages okay where is it
let's go to a close that UNIX UNIX
characters character encoding okay then
yeah let me show you keyboards you know
you have tons of these all these are do
it yourself keyboards in many cases let
me show you a hold on a second in many
cases they sell directly free pre build
for example you can buy these over docks
you can buy it you know everything out
of the works out of the box you can buy
this diverge you know the
most of them also run on qmx you know so
for this company so you want people to
download it and be able to program it
but you cannot with this [ __ ] qmk
[ __ ] idiot webpage again the other
thing is that it's not because these
programmers are incapable of creating
are easy to use but for many reasons
they don't understand they don't see it
okay the other thing is yes I understand
you know after yesterday I started to
read about the qmk software so I can see
it's actually a programmers tool in fact
it's a big understand undertaking to
read it because it's it turns out it
seems to be QM Kaiser is kind of a huge
software suite you know it's not just
one software it's a bunch of tools for
from from where you know for so you can
create a new keyboard and have and and
program your firmware so it's a big
giant tool and it turns out you know it
looks like I'm gonna have to spend
actually 10 20 hours to study yet so
from you know from what I read yesterday
so I can understand you know and also
from the guy you know so I can see that
it you know you can actually apparently
the way you program the keyboard is that
you can have a convicts of config file
like Jason you know you just modify the
config file then you just run some
program then then you'll be updated so
you don't have to use a GUI but that's
the thing you know anyway the the this
elite coders they don't understand
you see meanwhile me let me explain okay
meanwhile they do have a GUI you know
they think they do have a they do have a
GUI so that whenever this argument come
up they can say oh actually actually
this is very easy to use look just go to
this website and you see this GUI but
then then the other half
they say oh no you had this [ __ ]
[ __ ] nerd linux unix linux [ __ ]
they'd never understand a thing okay
that's it for today so that's it for 20
hours he's a problem yeah
okay I'm gonna good money break the loop
so I'm gonna well that's it for today I
don't know if I answered questions or
not well that's it bye guys one hour and
15 minutes okay bye guys