Morning everyone. Good morning everyone
and good evening. Welcome to another
episode of talk show. We are going to
code F today exploration
write a find and replace script part
three. So, in the past week, we've done
part one uh and uh so episode 735
and episode 737 part two about two days
ago and today. So, we are just I'm
learning F and I want to complete the
find and replace script which is in Unix
jargon it's said. It's like the set
program but much more superior,
more fullfeatured. Okay. So,
so last time we finished, we actually
created a script like that. It does the
job, but I want to add more features
such as making a backup like
uh you can optionally create a backup
before you do find and replace. And you
also want a regular expression option.
And you also want multiple pairs. So you
can do one shot replacing multiple pairs
of find and replace. Okay. If you are
watching this offline, play at speed
two. If you are watching here, say hi.
Love to see your comments. And hello my
Discord friends, Steve and all the other
people. and Reaper we do arguments about
programming languages and stuff.
So anyway, so let's uh start uh F. So
let's go to replace. Like I mentioned
before,
I have find replace script all over. I
have them. Let's remove the backup.
Okay, so wait, remove the backup. Press
press. I'm using Emacs, the most
powerful. So you can see the power. This
is Emacs. And uh let's go to talk show
and today's talk show. And actually
let's go to um previous talk show
because I want to show you some links.
There's a video summary and then there
is uh find replace script. So I have
written this in Goland, in Python, in
pearl, in Emacs and in Wufam language.
So this is very interesting uh because
you explore programming language design.
This is my my first task when I want to
learn a programming language. Okay. So
let's let's keep going. So so let's
start to write F. Stop talking. Okay. So
close that uh today's talk show. Yeah.
Let's stop I mean let's start
um
uh writing uh code. So free uh not pre
uh f. Okay, let's begin the code and
let's go to my find and um replace. So
last time we have fsx.
Let's find replace in F.
Okay, so that one. So that's the code so
far. So we want to add a feature. So let
me go over the script again. Play at
twice the speed. Okay, if you are
watching. So we So you got the input
path. This is where you want to do the
find and replace. And uh let's create a
um temporary directory so we can do the
test. So anyway, so the input directory
and this is a file pattern on whether
HTML files or txt or Java or py Python
whatever. So you can filter out this is
very actually critical and here's a find
string here's a replace string and here
is how you get all files recursively.
they return a list. Then here is a
function fantastic functional
programming. Here's a function that
that for each file path you open the
file.
Then you do the replacement. Then you
write back to the file. Then you print
finished. Okay. Then at the end, this is
the main part. So for the list of files
you pipe it to the function.
Okay. Then done. Okay. So uh so this is
our script. Make a backup. Now let's go
to a directory where I can uh make a
copy of lots of files. We can test on
this directory. Okay. So close that. So
we are I'm using Emacs the most powerful
text editor. Uh video check, audio
check. Okay, say hi. So, uh let's make a
copy of that. Uh copy. Um um
Okay.
Make a c copy recursively. Yes. So in
this directory there are 1,000 files.
Okay. And split the window and go to the
talk show and go to the directory. And
uh let's move this the directory the
test directory into the talkshell
directory. Okay. Press press.
Okay. Moved one file. Done. Refresh. So
there it is. Open it. Copy the file
path. Close. Close. Uh talk show index.
Close. Close.
Refresh. Close. We don't need that
anymore. Close.
Uh, this is my Emacs blog. Close. Back.
Close. Now we can put the path here.
Okay, that's a file path to do the test.
Uh, so what feature you want to add
first? You want to Okay, you also Okay,
so let's write it down.
how to um get current date
in F. That's one thing we want to know
because when you do a backup, I want the
date in the backup file. Okay. Then how
to uh another question, how to
copy a file in F. Okay. Let's uh Okay.
So let's how to get current date. Okay.
And there is the comment. There is this
is alternative syntax for comment. This
is multi-line comment. Okay, I prefer
that. So let's that's a question we want
to know. So let's
utilize AI help.
AI help.
Guac. Guac is the AI of my choice.
magnify the window so it's huge so you
guys can see.
Okay, so let let me just um
Okay, so go to the top. How to get
current date in F. Okay, system daytime.
So here is the code. Copy it
to uh close that. Go to talk show. So
here are the questions we want to know.
Wait.
Okay. So, did that how to get current
dating in F?
Uh, okay. And, uh, we already copy the
script. Copy. Let's test it here.
Wait, why is it not copied? Copy.
Paste. Okay. Pop it out.
Excuse me, I have some cough comments.
Okay, so back to Emacs now.
Run it.
Process finished. Okay, so uh this is
current date or current date equals
daytime UTC. No, I don't want UTC and uh
so let's just print and uh current day
time.
Okay, will that work?
No. Okay, you need to convert
a date
type to string in order to print. Is
that right? Uh let's see. Because F is a
strong type language. Yeah. So you need
to convert work.
How do you print it? And daytime
location uh daytime now returns daytime
value representing the current local
date and time. That's what we want. If
you only want the current date without
the comp time component. No, I want the
time component. Okay. So but there are
some other alternative options
which is good to learn down the road.
So,
so current date only and current uh UTC
UTC is a universal time that's basic
that's based on a local time around
England green switch something something
around there. Okay. But we want to know
how to convert uh daytime to um print.
Okay.
Oh, so a current date and time
percentage capital a. Okay. So this this
tricky part. So this is a minute.
Fantastic and beautiful. Okay. Fantastic
and beautiful.
But problem I don't like this American
style date is this date format is
American style month slash
uh date slash then year uh which is
quite ambiguous then uh time pm a.m.
Okay, I want the ISO. How do you get the
ISO time format?
Uh note for better handling of time
zones and offsets
especially in production code consider
using daytime offset do now. Okay offset
now. What does that do? I don't know. So
I want to get the daytime in ISO format.
Okay. How to uh get the date time in ISO
format.
Okay, continue in this question.
Continue. Press press press
the AI
challenge the AIS iso A601
standard.
That's an example correct
uh with all or with offset. Okay, here
are the most common reliable approach.
Okay, let's see. Let's just copy. Let's
see. Um,
copy.
Uh, let's see how does it do. Okay.
So, paste and go up. Let's see. Open
system ISO now. Okay. So, let's see how
what is the difference.
Uh, let's uh add today's date
sample code for getting date time. Okay,
very interesting in different
programming languages. You got Python,
you got Golan, you got JavaScript. Let
me show you my JavaScript one because
JavaScript is very complex.
So, Si webde blog go to the top and
JavaScript in depth and there you have
magnify. Can you actually you can see
the other part. So let me just
uh so now you can see the panel the
panel on the side otherwise it goes
through the bottom. This is because the
responsive design of the zoomers the
zoomers don't know they think well
actually this is responsive design but I
was going to talk about fixed layout
versus flow layout that is much more
fundamental issue. Okay.
In fact, if you search my articles,
you'll find it. Anyway, that's another
issue.
So, JavaScript in depth. Now, you just
go to date time. So, it's a big topic.
So, miscellaneous state. Okay. So, this
is a simple tutorial on how to get the
date. You can run it quickly. So, open
the uh web page. Search for pre right
here. Pop it out. This is the
JavaScript. So you run it. So you can
see these are the output.
Okay. F you know uh okay put it back
syntax color it show in browser. I just
wanted to show you this quickly. Now
this is just a example but when you dive
into detail daytime is actually one of
the most complicated thing
in programming languages and not and
actually because it's about calendars.
Calendars
the the gist of calendars is about
astronomy
solar system planetary astronomy.
That's the gist of date and time, month,
week. Uh you know then then you
basically you need to it's astronomy
about the position of the sun and earth
and the moon. Okay. So and so in fact
this is very very complex
not just mathematics but basically you
need to know astronomy you you need to
know how the planet moves and track them
in detail.
So after
h human animals recorded history by now
it's like 4,000 years we kind of know
exactly down to like microsconds
that's why we have atomic clocks.
So anyway, but it's this is this is the
beginning of mathematics trigonometry
since like three or 4,000 years ago
daytime.
Like you might wonder why don't we just
number them like one to 100 every year?
One year is 100 days. Why can't you why
can't you do that? You know, you just
increase the number. What's the matter?
Well, the problem is you got the seasons
wrong. you up the seasons because
in your new calendar,
summer is not summer anymore.
Then you might check, you might ask, you
know, why do you need to know what you
know what what has to do with summer?
Well, the reason for the daytime
is actually you need to know when does
it rain, when does it get cold, when is
it warm. Why do you need to know that?
Because your food depends on it. Without
knowing this, you die because you plan
things in the wrong day. You know, it
doesn't grow. So this is so that is why
the daytime the calendar became like the
the most critical
and the most important science from the
Asian times calendar. Okay.
And so daytime is very complex because
it has to do with astronomy, position of
the planetary bodies and sun and and in
programming languages it is also very
complex not just the calendar because
then you got the problem of how do you
like represent the daytime because
daytime is not decimal system. It's like
by 12 then week is 7, month is 30 or 31.
It depends and then you have leap year.
So daytime is very complex issue and the
Unix
people
they invented the Unix epic time that's
another story. Okay. So anyway daytime
uh so so I'm showing you the JavaScript
here and I it's very um uh date uh
constructor daytime constructor daytime
prototype. It's very elaborate very
complex. Okay. JavaScript. Uh you got
you got wait where where is the uh data
prototype?
Um
it's quite complex. Okay. Uh in fact I
know JavaScript the most because I spend
so so many months to write this
documentation in detail. Then you got to
know of course UTC, GMT, Zulu time you
you know what's the difference? Is it
just a name difference or is there
actual differences? because they are in
some of these functions you know you you
got uh UTC2 string ISO2 string GMT two
string what's the difference you know
and in F as we know you also got um
uh ISO UTC now right so digression about
calendars and astronomy and uh the
importance to humanity Okay.
So, let's copy that. Close that. So,
what is this? Uh, web block. Close.
Close. Close. Now, let's go back to talk
show. Let's just paste the link here so
that later people can reference it.
So, anyway, so back to F learning. So,
this is how you do um the ISO format.
Format is another thing very complex.
the format of daytime because every
country USA, Europe, Germany, Russia,
China they have like different format
and then you got the design issue. You
might ask the question which which
daytime format is the most is the best
let's say the most concise the most
universal or the most popular or the
most um precise or the most unambiguous
for example time you know if you are
American you might know you might be
familiar with the military time style
like um you know like like 2:00 26 6
minute PM. They don't say that. They say
uh 14
uh by 14, you know, like 14 something.
They have a special way to say it. They
use the 24-hour clock system. You see,
which is in which is also critical
because in military of course you cannot
make errors about time like we need to
on this time we need to do something you
can't make a mistake.
So daytime. Okay. So now this is
American style. Now let's say let's see
the ISO style. Can we like print it? Uh
yeah. So let's we I don't care about
that. Let's do that.
Fantastic.
Okay.
This is the ISO style. Okay.
We made a progress. Now furthermore
this is correct ISO style. You see they
they include microsconds. Can you see
that? That's microsconds and in decimal
system. I don't want that.
I want for example in EMAC I have this
command insert daytime. Which style do
you prefer? ISO date that. Okay. Now
insert day time again.
USA
there. Okay. Daytime again.
ISO date uh USA a brief. Okay. Insert
daytime again. Uh USA ISO code format.
This is the best format for coders for
programmers because it's the most simple
to pass year month preceded by zero. if
there's only one digit and date preceded
by zero followed by underscore not t
okay because in ISO format they
typically the separator between date and
time is a capital T which is hard to
read okay so programmer format this is
very popular then followed by 14 that
means 2:00 p.m. 37 minutes then seconds.
Okay, so that's another format. Then you
can add
then all digits. This is another very
popular format for programmers,
you know, it's just all digits. Okay.
Then you also
then you got the Unix seconds. This is
the Unix people. They love this. Okay.
Unix second Unix epoch from I believe
1970 something counting starting from
there. Okay, Unix and then you got year
2k problems things like that. So daytime
is actually very critical in programming
languages. Okay. So what I want to say
here is samples example of different
daytime. Okay.
Okay. That's some of the kind of popular
format.
Comment sleeper.
Sleeper tiger.
Hi. We got six people watching. So say
hi. Okay. Say hi there. Feel free to do
it. Now go back to F. We coding F. So we
got that. But I want a um
so I want a format. Let's say for now
let's say I want this format. How do you
do this? So this relates to how do you
manipulate strings? So I don't know that
yet. You know how do you do find replace
in a string? And
you know for example given that how do I
change it to that in F
of course you do string replace but
maybe there's better way or something or
if you have a daytime object there's
maybe there's a like a method that just
convert one daytime to another format.
So let's see. So this is when you want
to see oh you got the two string.
Okay. So let's look at that's um that's
a new information about F. So they don't
have two string here but now we are
using two string. Interesting.
So okay. So question how do you print
daytime in this format?
Okay, let's ask
how to get date
time in this
format
in F sharp.
Okay, let's ask guac.
So,
let's see if guac understand it. I think
so. Okay. To format the current day time
in F as this kind of format. You see
this is interesting question because
this format is not a standardized format
but it's rather just you know it's very
common but it's not like ISO standard or
anything.
So it says so let let's see what uh it
tell us.
recommended approach. So, oh,
oh, you just give a template.
Very nice.
Did we do that before?
No. Okay. So, this is a new thing.
Uh, round trip format is Oh, okay. So,
this is a new thing we learned. Copy. Go
back.
So this
so now you you say two string and you
just say that that will give so let's
try it
okay let's run it run it
fantastic and beautiful there
wait where is it uh the here okay So
fantastic.
And what does this come? Where does this
one come from?
That's the T. Okay, that's a T. Okay,
remove that. Okay, so we have learned.
Now put it back syntax color
and uh copy this
book answer so we can actually learn
about it.
later. Okay.
So, let's format it nicely
and show in browser. So, we learned
about daytime in F.
Okay. So, and uh this here is our code
just daytime.
in ISO format or in this format I want.
Okay, that's what I want. So, copy this.
Copy.
And uh now let's go back to my code.
So, I need a date time. Okay. Now, let's
delete that. This is find replace
script. So, okay. All the above is user
input. So this is directory path to do
find replace. This is glob pattern for
file name. This is find string replace
string and after this line it's out of
the code. So this will be named x date
time. Okay that's that's what I want
because when we do backup we want to
append this datetime string into the
backup file. Okay.
Okay. Fantastic. Now go back
uh go back. What is this? Find replace
go language. You see in go language you
can also see
uh you see input directory regular
expression for file name. Write to file
true or false. We need to add that
feature. Do backup true or false. We
need to add that feature. Backup surface
surfix. We need to add that feature.
This is using Emacs convention but you
might also use BAK which is also common.
Then directory to skip we also need that
feature because we don't want it to you
know do find replace in the git direct
directory that will result in major
if you you know change all files
in the git uh engine.
And also another feature for find
replace is that sometimes you want a
specific list of files that you want to
do find replace not all files in a
directory. So there is this feature. So
if this list is not empty then just do
these files. Okay. Then here in the go
script golan is a list of find replace
pairs. a list of so you can do multiple
find replace in one shot
and uh then after this line is the
actual code so this is goland script
findreplace go okay uh and the URL is on
my website I showed before so Goland
find replace you can grab it and have
fun with it
okay Close,
close, close. Now back to the find
replace F. Now the next job is to know
about how to copy a file.
There are many ways of course. One way
is you simply open a file, read it and
write to a file. So you create a new
file. Another way is actually just like
use a copy command of a file path.
you'll just copy. So let's ask guac
because we need to copy you know for
making a backup then we will need to use
the data to append to the file name for
the backup. So you would know you know
each backup file there's a date and
second you know so you know ex exactly
when it is uh being replaced.
So now the question how to do copy in F.
Okay. So new question please. Qu new
how to copy a file in F help.
Okay let's see the comments.
Are we using regular expression or
custom implementation?
Now right now we are doing find replace
just plain text. So there is no you know
it's just plain text it's not using
regular expression but that is something
we need to add. Okay I'm again I'm
learning F.
Uh I think it's fantastic because I love
functional programming. Wuam language uh
is I've been coding that for about 30
years and eac lisp for about 20 years.
So anyway to copy a file in F the
simplest and most common approach is to
use the static method
system io.file.copy.
Fantastic basic synchronous file. That's
what I want. Okay. So, you need to open
system.io.
Copy that. Do we already have it? Yes.
Then you need uh to copy the file. This
is what you do. Okay.
Okay. So, now go back to talk show
to copy your file. Let's write a uh F
script. paste and uh
wait show in browser. So what do we have
here?
Uh
so these all these are about daytime.
Okay, let's clean up a little bit.
Date time. So you can watch how I use
Emacs my workflow if you are Emacs user.
So copy that paste it here. I'm using
HTML mode. So you see one single key one
single key press it will deal with the
entire HTML element. For example, see C
see C see C see C see C see C see C see
C see C see C see C see C see C see C
C and it will accumulate what you uh
copied
okay well actually this needs to go
inside there okay so that's F then we
need to um
example of different data and cut cut
okay go back here here paste okay show
in browser
magnify. So you can see daytime. Okay,
we got some arrows there. This this
section is about daytime learning F.
Okay, so you got an arrow here. Oh yeah,
the U needs to be there. Okay,
fantastic. Okay, next task is about
copy.
Okay, so let's go. So copy
copy file
Fantastic
how to copy. So Gro says this way
does not override if destination exist.
Okay. So you also need the system.io.
So let's copy that. I mean system wait
is it wait is it system or system.io
system.io
oh interesting so system got daytime but
system.io IO for the
input output
copy file. Okay.
Copy file example.
Okay. So you just say that then let's
try. Okay. So
okay source destination does not
override. Okay. Or allow override. Oh
just an option. Okay. So now let's pick
a file to copy. Let's see this one.
Uh, make a backup just just to be sure.
Go back. Okay. The source equals to that
file path
and the destination equals to let's say
x you know tilda x tilda. Okay. Now if
we run it now first of all open the file
go to the directory. So you see there is
no tilda xtilda close back to the code.
Now if we run it it should be it'll
create it. Okay
done. Okay now open that file.
Uh it it is opened. Fantastic. It opened
in the default HTML mode which is not my
mode because I'm using SI HTML. You see
I'll go to the directory. So you see
fantastic
fantastic okay this is how do you do it
back syntax color it refresh.
So here is how to copy file. Now we know
how to do this. Now we need to
go back to our find and replace script
and let's see how we going to do this.
Okay, here is how you copy
override. Uh do you want to override?
Yes.
Okay. Yeah, because for backup I don't
care. I want to override.
It's not likely they uh
Oh, so but if you run this we already
run because you don't have you know you
need system not you also need system.
So let's try to run this see if it
works. Okay it will complain maybe will
complain
no daytime
now found because you are not using this
system. So, let's try it. Okay, hold on
a second.
It
okay indeed error name space type or
module date time is not defined. Okay,
so that means you need a system and this
is or date time. Now this this comment
is not precise because so far I don't
know exactly.
Okay. So it should say that that is the
module I suppose
and uh you know so right now I'm not
familiar with what module involves
because in other languages I would know
in Python, Emac this you know I would
know okay this module is because you
need this this these functions or
objects or methods but I'm not exact I
don't know what F module is about. So
but anyway something like this is for
daytime and that io is for
getting these
uh getting the content something like
that. Okay. So as we learn about the new
program language programming language
more we we will know like exactly what
we need to say there like is it the
function or is it the object that you
are like what what for example as far as
I know I learned few days ago this open
they actually don't load anything they
they just create a name space
so I don't know the detail yet okay so
anyway Okay. So now if we run this your
su success you see you see now you can
open one of these file and search for
save. Okay not here but um
um because it doesn't appear there. It's
what about this one? Save.
Uh not there. So which one does it um
uh search for? X save
in all these 1,00 files.
Okay, first time it's going to load the
disk.
Done. Wait. So, it did not
uh let's try again.
X save capital S.
Wait, it didn't find it. Why is that?
So, we are actually let's see
close.
Now let's make a change to the file. You
see we are trying we we are trying to
find the saving and replace it by
saving. Okay. And we are only
doing that for file starting with
capital A. So let's see if we did uh
let's see kasar find. Did we actually
change? Yes we did. So we did made some
changes. You see this is find package in
Emac this. So we did successfully. So
open it. So you can see there is there
is that word. So you see
you can see it but it's like cut off.
See there. Uh so yeah successful. So we
want to make a modification. Close.
Close. We want to make make a
modification. print only if
file changed. So you when you want to do
that you need to compile uh compare
the compare this old string and new
string or
how do you know if the replace happened?
You see one way is you compare comp
compare the old string content versus
the new. If they are different then
there's a replacement
but that's inefficient.
So it would be better if you
can find out you know whether the
replace method is successful.
Okay let's ask work. Okay
to
modify it so it only print changed file.
Okay. So we don't have the problem of
you know checking which file changed.
Okay. So we got quite a few things to
do. We need to do the backup yet. Uh to
do make back up
with timestamp in the file name. Okay,
that's one to-do and that's why we have
this
and
also to-do modified. So only print
changed file.
Okay. So, we need to ask gu um
in F when you
and you do
how to find if
replace
actually happened. Okay, that's the kind
of the question we want to know.
Uh so much to learn, a lot to learn when
you learn a new programming language.
So this is about copy file. So next new
question.
So copy the file path I mean copy the
guac answer and put it there.
Okay.
New question.
How to find if replace actually
happened? Okay. The method always return
a new string even if no replace was
made. It simply return a copy of
original. Okay. To check if a
replacement actually occurred,
the most common and efficient ways to
compare the result.
Okay. Yeah. But that's not efficient. So
you know, so what Okay. So you can do
with this less than and greater than
that means not equal. Interesting
syntax.
Haven't seen that syntax used for a long
time. I think that was very old syntax
40 years old.
Like more common today is just
exclamation equal.
Uh okay. So
why this works? Okay. So yeah,
alternative. Okay, count occurrences
first. Okay, that's that's what I want
because usually when you do find
replace, you want to know how many
changes happened.
Oh Jesus.
Wait, this is not functional
programming.
Okay, it's creating a function loop
recursive function
if position equals to -1. So -1 means
not found. Okay. Uh okay, which is also
CD. Okay. Find original.index
of then ACC.
If it's not found then ACC so ACC is a
count okay just terminate basically else
call itself then find length
uh what is the find what is find index
of okay find is the text.
Okay, original is the text.
Find is the string you want to find.
So that means this program that GU gave
out is not a complete program. You can't
run it because it doesn't know what is
original and what is find. So not good
because when I write tutorials, you
know, I've been writing tutorials for 30
years.
You always want your sample program to
be complete. So for example, in this
case, simply add two lines where you
give a you assign a string to original
and assign a string to find so that your
program is complete. it can run
and also when people read it they will
see oh this find is a variable this
original is a variable because otherwise
you know it doesn't say but anyway go
you know they explain a lot so anyway so
so to count occurrence you basically
have to write a recursive function
don't they just have like a building
function that's surprising
because I believe in Python and and
almost others they have like building
for Emacs for sure and uh I think Wuam
language
too.
Okay. So you have to write a function to
count it. Uh okay that need that's
interesting. Okay let's let's copy it.
Let's see if we can run it. Okay, again
we are just doing exploration. No hurry
to finish anything.
So but we need to you know uh write our
code here. So so but first of all this
is how to copy file. So another section
new question which is about um F code.
This is about F
count occurrence.
Okay, let's see if it will run. So again
we need to define
let.
Let let F is let stuff. You always just
let something let.
So original. Let's see. Alice in
Wonderland. That's my favorite
literature. Let's go to Alice in
Wonderland.
It's classic text down the rabbit hole.
Copy that. Copy.
Uh, close that. Okay. Original Alex in
Wonderland.
Okay. And, uh, find. You want to find
Alice of course
and then then count equals. So let's see
if this runs. Okay.
So how many occurrences
twice? Okay. So
what? So what does this mean? So count.
So this is a function. Okay. Very
tricky. You see when you learn a new
language you don't know which which word
is variable
function name or function name that you
define and which word is the actual you
know the programming languages keyword
that you cannot change. So the loop is a
function that we define. So we can
rename loop by f
loop
and the index is also functions
parameter. So we can change it to
anything we want. Let's say z index
change that you cannot change indexer.
Okay. Change. So this is the advantage
of using variable names or parameter
names or function names that is
independent
from English words. So you won't have
wait so when you know so it's become
clear and also this ACC
change it to um x count okay change
change change
now find string this also we want to
change because
find
x find string okay change
uh yes you can change there change
fantastic Okay. So now it's starting to
become more clear. So
so you writing a function loop that
takes index and count two parameters.
You let the position equals to okay the
found position. Then you repeat and then
wait. So index of returns the first um
occurrence.
Are you guys bored? Hello.
So, and else. Okay. So, let's just run
it first. Let's see if that
So what does this if uh so we need to
print
wait
is and this is a Uh,
okay. How do you turn this? This I
suppose is true and false booleing. How
do you turn a booleing into a string? I
don't know. Let's comment. Let's just
run this. Let's see what happens.
Find string. Wait. Replace string.
Oh, okay. So, wait.
Uh this is not good because now you see
this loop function is dependent on a
variable original
that is not part of the parameter of the
loop. In other words, this loop function
is not functional is it has side
effects.
Okay, guac, I think your answer is not
very good.
So change the original to input text.
Okay.
G. Let's run it. Let's see what happens.
Okay. Arrow. A unique overload of method
index of could not be determined based
on type information. Well,
what?
Oh Guac,
your answer is not good. You stupid
thing.
You see this orange. You know you are
writing a leaky leaky function
with side effects in F.
What are you doing?
We never going to finish.
So alternative solution
text regular expression.rejects.replace
replace checking result count.
This is much better. This is much
better.
Can you guys see? Do you guys
understand? Can you guys see the
my learning process?
You see, we look at this solution. This
solution is no good. It's writing a
loop. I mean, it's writing a recursive
function. And this recursive function
has side effect. It leaks the original,
you know, a variable that's global
variable. No good. But this one is much
better because it um
it uses the building function reject.
Okay, let's do it. Copy.
Okay, now this won't work. Now let's
comment. Okay. So, so that we don't get
confused. Um, this is important because
when you do a lot of notes, you want to
say what they are because after a while
you have 10 notes.
By tomorrow, you forgot what what is
this doing? Why are you doing this? You
know, you forgot you have 10 different
programs. So, this is a example of
finding
Count of occurrences.
Okay,
not good. Won't run. Okay, now put it
back.
Syntax code. Now let's go to next.
Start a new one. F and paste the code.
Okay, regular expression. Let's see if
we can run. Let's just run it.
Error. The value of the constructor find
is not to be okay. So you need to again
it's not complete program.
So you need to let's we need to copy
some.
Let's copy this. Okay.
Copy the Alice.
Okay. Now do it. Now paste it.
Now cut put that at top. Okay. Uh do we
need system? Let's not. Okay. So input
text find string count close
delete delete. So now rejects equals to
find
replace find by find string. You see
when we do that it become much clearer.
Escape if needed. Okay. Match result.
Then let's highlight it.
So you need original. Change original by
X input text. The importance of variable
names.
Okay. Input X replace with um
Oh, you need a replace string. Okay.
So
let
replace the string. Okay.
Okay. You need to change that.
X replace
change. Change. Okay.
and replace string uh queen
replace Alice by queen okay let's color
it make it colorful then you got count
h
in 32 max value
what
oh number of times you want to count I
suppose I mean the maximum number of
replace you want to do. Okay, that's
why. So this is another interesting
thing in programming languages. You have
the maximum integer limit is represented
by that builtin variable
in Java. In EMAC list you also have that
max integer representable.
Okay. So you so okay so you got match
result then
oh in inn net a play uh you can get the
count directly
what
oh god this is confusing
input text let's color it
starting in position.
Wait, this this part there's no count.
It's not working. So, what about this
one?
This is how you get the count. So, let's
see.
Comment those out.
Let's just run it. See if it runs. Oh
Uh the value name space type of module
rejects is not defined.
What
gu
is not doing very good.
Okay. You got the gu is got is not doing
very good.
Now if we change that will this work?
Wait, how do you
what
uh what is the error? So
oh maybe you want the following. So
maybe you just um That's right.
But then
okay so
Okay. So there is a result. So match
result is it used? No. Okay. So maybe
that try
the name space rejects is not defined
line five.
Okay, that's incorrect. So
line five rejects is not defined.
God
int 32 is not defined.
The module int 32
is not defined. Oh Guork is giving
a lot bad
results.
Yeah,
GU is not
doing correct. Qu is giving a lot bad
results. So this is like wrong in so
many places. I don't know how to fix.
Okay. So
now it's one hour. Maybe we should stop.
Uh
yeah. So you are asking Gork and it's
not giving you good results.
What's
Did we not read this carefully? So this
one
this one is not working right. Put it
back.
Run this.
Unique overload for ma overload for
method index of could not be determined.
Oh god.
string index of search for index of.
So input text is there.
Okay. So G is not giving good answers.
Okay.
Candidates string index of
value comparison type.
Yeah, but this one doesn't doesn't
contain
the string you want to find.
You see? So,
I don't know. So this is not working.
Put it back. Syntax color everything
back to browser.
So date time we find we found out how to
do how to copy a file. We found out how
to do but the count occurrence
became complicated. We don't know how to
do.
Um and this step is actually quite
critical. So we need we need need to get
through this
before we move on because our job is to
write a find replace script.
And if you don't know how to do regular
expression or if you don't know how to
count the number of occurrences,
you don't have much purpose. So before
we continue with this script of doing a
backup, you know
the we really need to get to know
to become familiar about all the stream
processing
count number of occurrences and how to
use regular expression. Okay, we need to
do that because right now it's printing
every file it touched but we want it
just to print only files that
that change happened. Okay, so what one
one way we can do is just to compare
string gu mentioned that. Okay, so like
this line copy. So let's maybe let's
just do that for now. Okay, then that's
it for this video. Okay.
So
uh so but how do you do if statement? So
if
I don't know how to do if statement
questions
how to write if in F.
Okay. So that
what about uh wait I asked for F sharp.
Qu is not doing very good today.
C. Oh, I didn't say uh I typed it wrong.
Okay. So actually I want to say F.
is a expression. That's right.
Functional programming. Fantastic. If
condition then expression else.
Fantastic.
Okay.
Okay, let's just do that.
So
if
the
X content is not equals to X new content
then
then something okay then we print.
Okay. So wait.
Okay. Then
we
print
else
change.
Okay. Else we say
no change.
Okay. And uh you need to
you need to like
you need to add the indentation. Stupid
indentation.
Okay. So now run it.
Make sure. Okay. Fantastic.
Fantastic.
So, some of them no change, but some of
them changed.
Highlight. No change. You see some of
them no change. Some of them changed.
So, open this one.
Search X save. There it is. It changed.
Fantastic saving. Oh, okay.
Okay, that's it for today. Our
exploration of F. Let's copy this. Um,
yeah, let's copy this. Close it. I'm
going to learn it um offline
more. So,
F paste the code. Go to the top and uh
Fine
and replace script
syntax color. That's it. Thank you guys
for watching. Bye guys. See you next
time. Tomorrow we gonna go back to wra
language at the end of code.
Okay, fine. Repeat. Fantastic. Bye guys.
F is Microsoft's Okamo. You are correct.
So F or Microsoft began around year
2000. Okay. Or 2001.
It is derived. It's basically your
version of Okamo.
Okamo is derived from a version called
camel. Camel is derived from a version
called ML
which stand for meta language
which originated from kind of
mathematical proof systems.
Okay, that's it for today. Now uh you
guys if you like my stuff you know you
can watch lots of my saw talk show by
now there's 700 videos starting about
five years ago and go to my website I
have lots of programming language
tutorials
um on emacs and also technicality on all
sort of keyboards
keyboards videos and uh programming
languages mostly
and also lots of mathematics and hacker
code. Those are related to programming
language issues such as documentation
for example this one.
Why Python documentation sucks. Keep
this under your pillow like the idiotic
guyo vanrosen
creator of Python programming language.
So here's documentation of the problems
of documentation in Python. The Python
documentation is one of the worst. Okay.
And then why Python sucks. These are
linguistic details. You know the G von
Rosen they
is a funny. So I have a video titled why
Python sucks. That's like one hour more
than one video of why Python sucks. and
and all sort of issues about programming
language syntax and semantics and
practice programming language style,
formatting style and conventions and
this you know why HC why I love Golan
why I love PowerShell PowerShell
complexity run for your life
then why bash sucks bash is the worst
basically anything from Unix makes is
the worst Okay, not just me, lots
of other people give details about it.
Uh so anyway, so so that's my website.
So lots of stuff, web design, website
design, CSS, uh web tech, history, and
then lots of math. So if you like my
stuff, pay me, okay? Pay me guys, okay?
Sponsor me. Patreon, Amazon gift card,
PayPal, that's at the bottom of si.info,
no http, no s. Okay, if the browser
says, oh, security error, that is
because they are trying to censor about
20 million sites, website, old websites,
you know, they they want instantaneously
censor all these old websites. So you
don't read about the actual history of
the web of the internet of older people
what do they have to say about
programming language about you know like
the entire thing the internet pioneers
you know today they are old or they died
80 years but they have lot left a lot of
information and they are not HTTPS
but Google and Firefox pushed it so that
all these old website when when you read
it, they say, "Oh, security
uh problem dangerous because they going
to steal your credit card, you know,
instantaneous sensor like millions, 20
millions of websites, usually old
websites. That's what they do. Google
and Firefox, you know, even if you have
even if you have this auto HTTP turned
off. Let me talk about this one more
time. Okay, but bye for now. That mean
that's it for today. Okay, so for
example, you you look at the auto HTTP
search for HTTP.
You see HTTP only mode
don't enable. I says, you know, I say
don't enable. I don't want that. Okay.
Don't auto I don't want auto
anything. I want everything manual.
Okay. You specifically
explicitly
has a preference. I can turn it off. You
see, you can enable it or you can
disable it. I disable it. However,
now if you go to Kasari YouTube, let me
demo de demonstrate this. Okay, I did
before, but okay. Kasali YouTube. You go
there YouTube
live. That's right. So, but let's go to
uh let's see uh this one two days ago.
Okay. Wuam language. We're going to do
advent of code. So you go down, you open
video summary generated by AI and here
is my notes. So HTTP nos
you click on that and Firefox says
security connection failed. Oh,
dangerous. You cannot visit that site
because it's not HTTPS.
Why? Because Firefox,
they secretly
add the S into your URL secretly.
Even though I turned it off, I
turn it off. They couldn't do it anyway.
That's the, you know, the degree of the
scum of the Firefox and Google browser.
I think Google Chrome stopped doing
that, but Firefox still do does that.
Every time I talk about this to the to
today's coders, young Zuma, they don't
know.
They they they they don't know and they
don't care. They think, "Oh, you need
HTTPS because it's secure."
Okay. Bye, guys.