Hello guys, good morning everyone. We
are going to code Emac Lisp today. Emac
Lisp, the most powerful text editor.
Uh okay. Uh let's start. Let's switch to
my uh screen and uh here is my Emacs.
So what is the problem? So okay, so
there's a command. So let's say A B C D
E D E F cat dog. So you press a key.
Press a key. Uh wrong key. Press a key.
Wait.
Press a key.
They become a list show in browser. So
you can see ABCDF cat. Uh and that
command is open. That is that command is
HTML line to list. Okay. Let's show the
code.
uh HTML line to list jump to source
code. There it is and it's on my
website. Open it. Show in browser. So
you can get a code. It turns a line to
HTML list. Fantastic.
So today what we're going to do is
something similar. Okay. So let's paste
the URL there. Show in browser. That's
today's talk show. Oh, I forgot to uh
increase the font size. So alt ts
increase the font size. So if you are
watching offline play at 1.5 speed
and skip skip around because I ramble.
Okay. Delete that. Showing browser.
Fantastic and beautiful. Okay. So HTML
line to this fantastic command. If you
are watching here say hi. Hello Jang.
Hello Christian.
Okay. So we're going to talk about uh
we're going to do this code and uh kind
of random random Rambo is so if you have
questions for me post it.
Okay. So so that that is a command list
to uh lines to list.
There's something else we need to do.
Okay. Uh so that is turning a
ul to DL. So let me show you what's an
example. So ul is a unordered list like
that. Okay
let's say cat dog let's say
uh bat
fox. Okay so we got bunch of canines and
the flying animal
uh mouse that that's that would be
called um bat. bad belongs to the
mu murai. Okay, I believe that's murine.
So now this is English. Wait, is it
mine? Maybe not. Okay. Uh
yeah, it is murine.
Murai of or relating to a rodent of the
subf family
murin which includes house mouse and the
brown rat. Okay. So I'm not sure bat
actually includes it. Let's let's see
check search for bat. So this is uh yes.
Oh wait
and is larger than all mammal orders
except the bats and the remaining what?
So
the old world rats and mice part of the
family mur in the family murday comprise
at least 519 species. Member of this
subf family are called murines. In terms
of species richness, this subf family is
larger than all mammal families. Wow.
Except
today and the mural day and is larger
than all mammal orders except the bats.
Wow. Okay. So, bat is not uh
moon. Bat is chipper terra something.
Okay. Bats. Anyway, we got a bunch of uh
a list. Okay, that's a ul is a list. So,
let's cut that. Paste it. Paste it
again. And let's call a command kasa ul
to dl. DL is definition list. Okay, do
it. Do it.
Uh, okay. Wait, you need you need
you need a separator. Okay. So, let's
just say
cat. I know have
no two
bats fly. Okay.
I like cats. I like dogs.
Uh dogs
is okay. And bad fly. Okay. So, you got
a list. Now you want to turn that into a
definition list. So you just call this
command HTML ul to DL. Do it. Now you
need a separator. Okay. Arrow. Okay.
Remove separator. Yes. Okay. That is the
now selected. So you can see this is a
definition list show in browser. So with
cascading stylesheet it looks like that.
So you got DL is definition list. Then
dt is kind of the term definition term.
Then you got dd is a definition
definition. Okay. So you got you know so
that commands turns a
ul an order list to a definition list.
So but what I want to do is to
better it. Okay. Right now it's got a
problem. So you know so for example if
you have bats and you don't have any
definition for it and if you call it
okay separator right arrow yes remove
separator yes but you got error so you
see so normally you got the dt and dd
okay dt and definition term and dd but
for these bats because you don't have
anything there
You got DT opening and DD closing. So
that is incorrect.
How do we know? We can
validate the syntax. So look at the pink
window. You'll see it my command. So you
see arrow
file this file closing tag dd at
position that does not match last
opening tag dt at position that. And
that command is kasan html validate XML
buffer. That is one of the greatest
command I wrote. And actually we wrote
it live about one or two years ago.
Okay. Just search for on YouTube HTML
XML validator.
We wrote it live and that's fantastic.
So you see that tells you this. You got
the HTML
uh syntax error and uh wait open it. So
it says position 660. So where is that?
You can jump to it. Kasa go to uh char
wait
go to char other buffer. Do it. There we
have it. It's right here. So suppose the
cruiser is here and you got this error
message at position 660. Where exactly
is that? Just call the command
just call the command casar go to char
other buffer. It jumps right there.
Okay. So that command kasar go to char
other buffer. Actually we also wrote it
online.
Okay. So let's let's just copy. Um so
here's a documentation. Let's just copy
that. Okay. Undo. Do we have undo? No.
Okay. So, hold on a second. So, we
um So, wait. So, let's clean up a little
bit. So, anyway.
Okay. So, let's see the documentation
now. Do I have a web page for it? Yes,
indeed. Cuz go to ch the buffer. Open
it. Oh, it's in talk show. So, we did
this. We called this live but you got a
code here too. So you can get the code.
Okay. Copy the path. Close that. Paste
it. And uh make corner bracket there.
Uh and uh and uh make it HTML. Cut. Put
here. Make a list and make a link and
mine which is a vocabulary.
Okay.
No, we don't have
Okay. Make a list. Join the list. Okay.
Clean. Beautify. There. That's today's
talk show. So, we got this
DL2. Okay. So, wait that what is that
command? XA
uh
wait
ul2
DL. Okay, let's look. Let's So here is
the command. Now, do I have a link for
it? No. So, you have to um
uh you have to write it yourself. Okay.
So, anyway, so we're going to write that
command. I mean wait not go say wait
where is it here. Okay so this command
so let's make it corner brackets
turn to HTML code there. Okay
so what so we are going to so describe
function that function and go to the
source code. So here's the source code.
Copy close.
Okay let's why don't we put the source
code here. Okay. Okay. What is this?
Okay. So,
wait. That's not the
Wait. So, okay. So,
EMAC this
past code. Okay. And but but above what
is this?
What is this URL?
Oh, this URL is today's talk show. Is
it? Yeah,
he he we are nesting. We are deeply
nested.
Okay. Close that. So this today's talk
show got to move to the top. Okay. So
today Yeah. So we forgot. Yeah. There
there showing browser. Fantastic.
And oh yeah syntax color this you know.
So because you see now it's not correct.
Okay, press press show in browser.
Scroll down. Now it's beautiful. HTML ul
to DL that is code. So we're going to
fix we're going to reimplement this
command so that it so that when the
you know when there's no definition
it'll still work. Okay. So we're going
to we have a new algorithm.
Shall we code that? You know, right now
like now I don't uh feel
where where are we? So now I don't feel
todo
show that's my todo one 10,000 items.
I'm busy every day. Um
so shall we code that code that? Okay.
So let's go to the um file again. So go
to the bottom.
In fact, I started to code it today to
reimplement this thing.
Uh but now I kind of
not feeling like it because
once we start coding especially EMAC
bisp which is esoteric nobody knows uh
then it becomes boring. Uh but the other
reason is because let's go to my EMAC
blog the complete tutorial for Emacs
EMAC in it EMAC keys and EMAC list
you know like there are about 800 files
I mean uh tutorial so so on this page
there is video tutorial so I've done by
now over 100 Emac list coding tutorials
in the past three years also. So this
collect, you know, the best ones are
collected here.
So,
so I was going to, you know, code this
today, but maybe not. So, it's up to you
guys. You guys tell me what. Okay. So,
you got to answer for those of you who
really want me want to see me dive, you
know, code emac say it now.
Uh, I wait for a minute otherwise
otherwise I'm just gonna start to talk
random. I'm gonna tell you what I've
been doing. Uh, you know, other coding
stuff, Unicode and Wam language, you
know, kind of randomish. Uh, tell you
what I've been coding in the past week.
Okay. So, lots of stuff. I think that's
that's what I want to do. So, let's go
over the comments and see what you guys
saying.
Hello Dan. Hello Christian. Hello. Hello
Stabilizer. Hello ACP. Hello world.
Hello ACP says, "Have you incorporated
any LLM AI system into your computing
workflow or elsewhere?"
Yes, I did a live stream about it. You
know,
gosh, you guys don't watch live stream.
Wait, I got a phone call. I got a So,
hold on a second.
capture. Audio capture check and back.
Display capture check and back. Display
capture check and back. And uh the
speedo face camera check. I'm back.
Lots of spam calls today. I mean not
just today but like since 10 20 years
ago since like 30 40 years ago you know
we are in America which is the spam inc.
They uh you know they want to sell you
things or make money or whatever or scam
spam scam lots of that. Okay. So we are
back. So you know so let us let me know
if you want me to code emac or or
don't says I enjoy random. Okay. Let's
let's do that. And Brian says vote for
random. Okay. So let me finish reading.
So yeah. So the question have you done
any ILM? Yes. So you go to talk show
on.info
and uh a month ago you know we did like
two or three live stream installing
OAMA. Okay. So search for
uh what is it? Uh uh
search for there it is episode 648
on April two month ago AI botm tech
deepseek nt okay and the day before that
episode 647
install Emacs AI bot interface or lama
deepseek chat chat GPT and then before
that and you know so you guys don't pay
attention you know you like
which is kind of normal because most
people just you know YouTubers like that
you know there's a million of you
YouTube tubers so you watch them
randomly you you you know you don't
really know what's going on but anyway
so there is these three uh you know
YouTube that we installed it and talked
about it uh each one is like one hour
okay
uh so Let's let's leave them open. Okay.
Uh or llama. Yeah, we installed it and
we talked about deep seek and others.
Okay. So, let's go back to So, next
question. Let's see.
Doce says,
"I would also be curious about your
thoughts on some of the LRM packages in
Emacs. I find GPT to be amazing. Okay.
Okay. Another question about that. So,
let me tell you guys my uh something new
I haven't talked about. Since I
installed O Lama,
you know, actually I can run it. So,
let's see. Uh I forgot what's the
command. Uh you know, I because I don't
use it actually. Uh what was the Emacs
coa? Okay. So,
so wait, we did we did. So, this is
episode. So, this is install Emacs AI
bot interface or llama o. Okay, I
installed lama but I did not install
chat
um you know gptel.
So, I installed
and deepse
what's the command deepseek.
Okay. Uh so let's call a propose command
seek.
Okay. None. So let's do again
a propo o r l a.
Okay. There's no such command. So what
is the command I installed?
Elama. Okay. So wait.
E R L A
no match. What What was the command?
Did I Did I uninstall it?
GPTEL or was it GP GPT?
There it is. Oh, that's the one I
installed. Actually, I installed it.
GBTEL. Okay. Uh so what was the uh GPT
send?
Yeah. So I can you know open a new
buffer GBT uh let's say describe
function uh yeah what is it GBT send
okay so GBT send you submit this uh by
default content of the buffer up to
cursor up to cursor position are send
okay so what you do is ask a question so
last time we asked what's the t uh
let's the
let's just do you know what is Emacs? We
asked that before. Let's see something
interesting.
Uh which is the most iconic
tile in M.
Okay. So, MetaX
GPTEL
send
do it.
Uh, no GPT API key. Oh [ __ ] What the?
Okay, I need to go to my init because
maybe I might remove it. So, search for
GPTEL.
Uh, search for O L A.
Okay. Not here. That's collate and
stuff. Okay. Um, collator compare.
What is this? This is PHP mod. Stupid
PHP mod. Okay.
So, anyway, so let's go to my personal
init. Search for O L A
collapse. Okay, there it is. Olama
interface. Okay, open it. So, GBT. So, I
have it set. So, why is it not um
Okay, describe a propose
uh a propose gptel.
Let's see what is the other command to
start a shell something like that. Oh,
okay. So let's see
GPTEL
create or choose a GBTE buffer. Okay. Uh
let's just say new GBT
what
you know but basically I installed OAMA
you know like you know that's like two
gigabyte or three but all this trouble
trouble I turn it turned out the power
of the locally installed AI chartbot is
much inferior to to Gro
Okay. Like to to Gro
much more inferior. Okay. So let's see
open new G.
So you can ask GU anything. So so that's
why I stopped using local chat GPT. You
know I only you know I only have let's
see uh shift control escape.
I I only have 16 megabytes of RAM and my
GPU is like 16 megabytes of six only six
megabytes of RAM. So anyway, the point
is local local AI bots is much inferior
to
what whatever the web based.
Uh the advantage of local bot is that
you can ask sensitive questions like
politically sensitive questions or
questions you don't want the public to
know. I mean the like whatever you know
who is running whoever is running the AI
bot
that is an advantage
but I rarely do that. So for me, the
local chatbot is not useful unless or
alternatively you spend like $10,000 to
buy a hardware that is powerful enough
for local bots. Okay, that's about that.
Uh
Brian says, "Thank you for gracing us
with your ew wisdom on this day.
Okay. Is my answer about the RM good
enough? I forgot what's the command, you
know, because I don't use it now. And in
fact, I want to uninstall it. Um,
GPTL.
Oh, GBTEL mod. Okay. So GPTL
mode.
Okay. Well,
what what is not supported? New
what?
Describe
function
GPT.
Um
what
mode?
Oh okay. So new buffer then set it to
GBTL mode. Then um then what I forgot.
So
describe mode then wait this is actually
wait
what
describe function
GPT mode is a autoloaded interactive
something okay so minor mode oh it's
minor mode [ __ ] idiot periodic minor
mode.
Okay. So now switch to text mode. Let's
then call GPTL mode. Okay. Now finally.
So you so how do you ask questions? I
forgot. So um
so major mode. So
uh no wait. So I forgot what's the
question. So
um
uh anyway it's not worth it. So you know
just go watch my previous videos
about using that
GPT config start put that and then just
GPTL to start it type a question C
return. Okay there is instruction. So
what is this? Uh okay. So new buffer
GPTEL
do it. Create or choose a GPT buffer
default. Okay. Let's just say that
uh no chat API key.
Enter. Okay. Uh what day is today?
Okay. So, is it starting? If it's
starting, you'll see all the GPU goes
up. I don't think it is starting.
Oh, wait. What's the What's the key?
It's control C return. Okay, let's
change it to some interesting question.
Let's say um
you know interesting question.
Why is
Persian
Persia changed name to Iran? Okay,
that's the current news. So you have to
press Ctrl C return. Okay, control C
return. There it is. What? Arrow. [ __ ]
Arrow. You didn't provide API key. Wait,
I'm using
Oama deepseek. I don't need API key.
Okay, stupid.
Uh, when is this?
Run it. True. Run it. True. Run it.
True. Run this true. Okay, so it's all
installed.
uh set GPT
mo model so
GPT40
so that is no that's not what you didn't
run this line okay
so why is this file not run because
let's go to init
okay so
search for external
Yes. So this file is run. But why is uh
so describe
variable um GPT backend describe
variable is not even
defined.
Did I install it? Did I uninstall it?
Okay. Uh, so go to my init file again.
Go to a directory. Go to alpa.
There it is. GPTEL. So I did not
uninstall it. So why is that? Now it
doesn't work.
Okay. So
set Q backend describe variable
GPTL back end is a variable defined with
that value is below back end to use. So
there is no value. So anyway let's
evaluate this. Okay. Now evaluate it.
Now open a new buffer
and uh GPTL
do it. create a GPT buffer or llama.
Yes. Okay. Now ask the question
uh what where is the uh
okay let's ask that question.
Uh
wait. So
why is
Persian Persia
now named Iran? Okay. Paste it and uh
Ctrl C return. Okay. Now check my
graphics card.
Why is it taking so long? Why is the
graphics card not going up?
Uh anyway, so why is this
something is wrong? Because
if it's working, you'll see
the graphics card usage going up,
but it is not. So something got [ __ ]
Okay. So anyway, so I don't So the new
thing is is that it's a fa fatal flaw.
You know, before I thought it's great to
have a local AI chatbot because you can
then ask it anything without without
these corporations knowing what you've
been knowing what you you know what
what's on your mind. But I discovered if
you don't have $10,000 computer, it just
you you know it's like useless, you
know, because the online version is much
more powerful. Okay,
maybe that's it for today. I was going
to do something but then uh
so do says do you like uh post frames in
Emacs? I have started using them for
many things. Small popup. No, I don't
know what I don't even know what's post
frames.
Random talk. Okay.
Okay, that's it. That's it.
Uh, this is very annoying because
I don't know why is it not working.
Okay, let's just copy that. Close it.
Uh, go to today's talk show and uh let's
just post it here for whatever reasons.
I'll check them out later. Okay. Then
then here's a code close
next buffer
chat GPT config. Okay. So what is this?
Oh yeah that's uh
okay.
Okay okay okay.
So let me tell you something random.
Okay. So I've been working on unic code
today. uh something Unicode. Unicode is
fantastic because it is the writing it
contains the writing system of the
entire
humanity
of the past 5,000 or so uh of recorded
history like for 4,000 years. So it
contains all the symbols we used. So to
know unic code you know like usually you
want to know like what what character is
this what strange character you know you
know if you know them all it's almost
like then you become a god of
archive a god of archival a god of
records
okay but which is impossible because you
cannot possibly know because the all the
entire every human language either today
or head such as Egyptian
uh in unic code. Okay. So that's
fascinating.
Uh and I've been wanting
you know so I've been working uh on some
update on uni code today and uh some of
the interesting things.
So,
hello. I got a cone keyboard and I was
wondering what do you use home row mod?
Do I you do uh do I use home row
modifiers? Okay,
so
god of uni code.
Why is that funny? So, home row key home
row home row mod. I have article on
that. Okay. So, just search for keyboard
block and search for it. Cuz keyboard
block and uh home.
Wait, why is that there not? There it
is. Dual function keys in home row mods.
Okay. Basically, my opinion of it is it
sucks and I've talked a few times about
it like
okay so yeah I don't recom I you know
you you you know if you got the cone
keyboard
then it's almost necessary
to use home row mods okay
you know I I talked about this so many
times so you know like what you got is
the corn keyboard which is the circus
minimal you know it's minimal minimal.
So if you got this kind of keyboard then
this dual function keys home mod is like
essential. Well it's basically
essential. Uh then you got, you know,
then you got hold on, you know, hold on
this, you know, make sure do you you you
you you
press this key first, then press that,
then before you release that, you need
to release that that that one first and
you know, [ __ ] up [ __ ] confusion.
That's what you got. Uh, and you have to
be careful because if you just type fast
then you got lots of errors like you you
if if you type uh like some thing what I
hi mom u and you you you'll find that
your text got deleted because you press
some combination keys you know so I
don't you know my opinion I don't
recommend these uh 60 42 keys you know
this this thing and uh for technical det
details about the home roll keys, home
row mods. This got several problems.
Okay, several problems. So, I don't use
it.
So, I got a Chrome keyboard and I was
wondering um what do you use home rule
modifiers? Okay. Um now I have created a
layout that does not currently use any
home row modifiers. Okay. Uh but a lot
of people tell me to try it.
Yeah. Yeah.
So anyway, so
so what what else? So now it's 50
minutes. We talked for 40 minutes. Uh
let's see what else today.
Uni code. you know, I wasn't prepared to
um I was just going to code emac this,
but I wasn't prepared on other things.
And I can talk, you know, there's like I
can just start to talk on random things
nonstop.
But um so another question, Christian,
it's been a while since the last since I
last watched you. What's your number one
keyboard recommendation for programming?
That's easy. Okay. Kinesis I mean this
this glove I mean glove 80. Okay. That
is my
my number one recommendation.
Uh
uh if you want other you know what about
others? So all my opinions is like
written here. Okay. Just go to
uh keyboard kasadi.info
keyboard blog. Search for it, you'll
find it. And uh go to the ergonomic
keyboard section. Best ergonomic
keyboard pick. So you can see all of
them here. So
G 80 my number one choice.
Kinesis Kinesis 360 I guess my number
two. Uh not necessarily but anyway. So
this this I I recommend. Okay.
especially this one expose
uh
and ultimate hacking which is that one
it's pretty good but expensive and but
today you have lots of others for
example this Apple maker this Chinese
China cheapos very cheap $80 or
something and you can so the number one
thing I recommend is get the light
switch so you want something like 45
grams or less
Okay. So, you want and also go get
linear switch. So, you don't want
clicky, you don't want tactile, you
don't want whatever. You want linear
switch
and uh less than 45 grams.
Okay, that that is like my top number
one recommendation for those of you
coders who type a lot or starting to
have uh typing problems. So number one
of all keyboard criterias
get a linear light switch. So 45 g of
touch force or less. So right now this
one is 35. So right now the one I'm
using is 35 grams. Okay. The other
issues like ergonomic shaped and uh and
uh you know what shape they are uh or do
you want you know that's less important
or angle you know that's less important.
just key switch linear and super light.
Okay,
GPS. Okay, I think that's it. So, so
let's go back to let's see I got some
you know um
a lots of talk about Emacs. Okay, so
Emacs, what's new? some updates
uh programming block uh powershell okay
dynamic range uh second life virtual
world you know second life is a huge
disappointment because the second life
technology is the worst uh why in
summary you know when I when I go to
second life I thought
you know it is the most beautiful I mean
it's fantastic Because you can see
mathematics, you can see for example,
you can see this, this is in second
life. So you are in you know this is
like a game you know like you're a
person looks like that inside you see
this is a geo geodistic dome and this
these are other people. This is about 15
years ago I and this is me. So I was in
second life for like uh 5 years
almost 8 hours a day and so it's
fantastic. So initially I was there to
to to understand and to build these
geometric structures. You see all these
are geometry by uh sediment Henry
Sederman.
Um so you need to learn how does it
work? How is it possible you have you
can have this like CAD 3D CAD AutoCAD
this system in a virtual world where you
can like walk around and just amazing
truly amazing you know as you know like
and beautiful and you can build all sort
of other architectures
like inside the second life you know you
are actually a little person like that
and you can walk inside these buildings
just just like you know almost like in
real Okay. So that's incredibly amazing.
You see this this this thing. So how
does it work? You know, such amazing
technology. I want to learn, you know, I
was going to do geometry in it to do um
you know like virtual reality geometric
visualization and this amazing this fly
blowfly ride is amazing. So this guy a
kind a friend who you know so this fly
is a flying machine. So we can go inside
and write it.
So so we are looking at this from a
third person view but actually you are
you can you can switch to a first person
view. So it actually fries. So it's
amazing. It's incredibly fun. So but the
question is how does it work you know?
So I spent three years in it. I studied.
Turns out it's like the hacking [ __ ]
extreme to the extreme degree. You know
how do you actually build all those
things you see these beautiful things
how are they actually done they are done
by by the worst kind of digital Lego
blocks
like the worst kind like doesn't make
sense like you know you have this
primitive a cube that that there's a
parameter you can twist for for nothing
and some other things you want to do it
cannot do. So you just use this to mimic
the appearance. That's kind of what it
does. So you see all these beautiful
structures, they take tremendous time to
like to create. So it's nothing like
CAD, you know, AutoCAD or Maya or
whatever systems. So second second life
is one of the uh biggest hack and the
programming language the Second Life um
Lynden script is also the worst. Okay.
So I have a full tutorial on Second Life
in Lynden script.
So anyway, that's um that's a run. Okay,
I think that's it for today. Um not
really prepared to do live stream. Okay,
so 12 people unless you got questions.
That's it.
ACP says Dr. Go has a has a privacy
preserving
interface called Duck AI. No, that's no
good. Doug Duck Go since since the
Ukraine war began, they are censorship.
They are pro censorship because the
founder, the creator himself like
posted, you know, because when the
Ukraine war began, he says, "Oh my god,
we can't take it anymore. Now we need to
censor because this full of uh fake
information. you know be actually those
fake information are actually real
information.
So the duck duck go is kind of like deep
state you know either he's part of the
deep state or he's pro deep state. So
the way he's you know so either he's
like blatantly just lying or he's or he
doesn't actually know how things are you
know what things are happening. He think
that you know so he started to do censor
censorship you know
I have an article on that in fact I
talked about this before just go to
sard.info info and search search for
Duck Duck Go. You can see the the
screenshot of the tweet tweet he made
and so on.
Okay. Second Life is a giant hack. Okay.
So, what else? Oh, yeah. So this um
hacker news article one of my article
yeah it's old old news hacker news you
know one of my article went to hacker
news it's about this
and wam language lots of things wam
language okay so then lots of things you
know busy I'm busy coding every day
uh programming blog webdev blog yeah so
lots of work on webdev as as well and uh
mathematics which yeah so what I've been
working on the most in the past few days
is wufam language okay
on this wam language uh visualization
stuff
uh but we'll do it another day soon okay
uh okay that's it bye guys
join your discord Okay.