Good evening everyone. Welcome to
another episode of S talk show. We are
going to code wam language doing
geometry. Uh we are going to code
graphics programming uh programming
animation. Continue from yesterday. You
are watching S talk show. Uh this is my
keyboard ultimate hacking keyboard
UHK80.
That one. Okay. So search for YouTube.
You will see my reviews on YouTube.
Uh and now let's go to the topics
proper. Uh we did this. So we did so
we're going to start coding. If you are
watching this here say hi here. Love to
see your comments. If you are watching
offline at 1.5 speed.
Okay. So asteroid that's what we did
yesterday. So what I'm going to do is
basically I'm just going to code uh work
on my website. So we're going to code a
lot wam language. So you can see we did
this uh we did this one yesterday. So
let me show you this one. So play it. So
you can see that generates asteroid. Now
can you loop? Yes. Speed do a loop. Play
it. So this is this this thing is called
treml of Archimedes.
Traml of Archimedes. And it shows uh
wait why is it not working? Oh the
browser stuck. It shows it gen you know
this bar moves about and the envelope of
the bar is called
is the envelope is the Archimedes. Okay,
hold on a second.
My browser froze.
Okay, so anyway, so back. So this is
called Treml of Archimedes. So
and the trace of this bar the shape is
called
asteroid and that shape can be formed by
rolling a circle around inside another
four times smaller or you can roll a
circle inside another but now this time
the radius is 3 over4
of the bigger
Sorry, that was my alarm clock. I need
to stop it. I set it every an hour or
two. So, I get up and walk to prevent
asteroth. So, anyway, back to asteroid.
So, asteroid is this curb. You can
generate it in multiple ways. One way
the definitive
way is rolling a circle four times
smaller inside another circle. Okay. So
you get asteroid and this
traml of alchimedes mechanism is another
way to form the curve. Okay. So we did
so we coded this yesterday. Here is the
wam language code using wam language.
And what we're going to do is we're
going to um work on this code. Maybe
possibly improve it. Okay.
So, uh it's probably boring for you guys
whoever you are watching. It's pro, you
know, it's maybe boring, you know, for
those of you uh high school students,
young people or in or programmers
interested in mathematics, then you
might find it um not boring. Okay, for
example, let's paste a code. So here we
we we did this yesterday. So now shift
enter and uh it defined the curve. So
now you you can just call this function.
We define this function and now you just
paste it and shift enter.
That will generate a bunch of graphics
showing that showing uh all these
frames. See
uh treml of alchimedes and all you have
to do is now
you say uh
list animate. Okay
then it will generate an animation.
See fantastic. Now you can play it
forward uh and backward loop.
Cheers.
So, how do you do this? Easy. The key
thing to generate this is that you want
to generate a bunch of graphics. So, you
do a loop in a programming language,
right? You do a loop. Uh, by the way, if
you don't know already, watch my
previous video. You can see
where to download Wuang language. Just
search for xard wufam download wam
language. You can download at wufam
wufam.com/developer.
Okay, that's their website. So you need
to turn on JavaScript. You can download
it. It's like 4 gigabyte or 5 gigabytes.
It's huge. It's the most advanced
programming language based on term
rewriting system. Okay. a magnitude
higher level beyond Pascal, Python,
Julia, JavaScript,
uh, F or camel, Rust, you know, it's
like a magnitude beyond. Meaning that
for one line of wam language, it's going
to be 10 lines or 1,000 or even a
million lines of Python. Okay, one line
of language is like 10 or 100 lines of
Python or even a million if you count
about if you do you know solving
equations, solving partial differential
equations, those kind of thing. Okay. So
you can download it for free since like
few years ago and you also want to you
know basically just re read my uh page I
explain you know all the details
technical uh difference wam script wam
engine mathematica wam language you know
what's the difference between them okay
so you download them okay so and the
other thing you want to download is the
wolfam language kernel for Jupyter
notebooks so that allows you to have
graphics. Okay, display graphics.
Otherwise, otherwise you use it inside a
terminal like wampam script. You run it
in a terminal like a shell like a bash,
you know, or python ripple. So anyway,
so you download it. Okay, so that's the
introduction. But now let's go back to
uh talking about this. So for example,
one of the feature is graphical
programming graphics, you know,
interfaces. uh you know you can do you
can do graphics you don't need to think
about oh what kind of graphics library I
need it's it's built in it's integrated
you know the whole coherent woofam
language okay so how do you do this you
see to do to generate this animation all
you need uh is you you all you need is
the essence of this animation is that
you need to draw several frames okay
several drawings For each one you need
to find you need to move a bar this bar
fixed length. Okay. Such that for each
one you need to find the basically the
beginning and end position of the
the bar. Okay. The the the two you you
need to find the coordinates for the two
end positions of the bar. And for next
frame you need to know where do they
move to? How they move. Okay. That's all
you need to know to generate this.
That's the essence of this animation.
Okay. Once you know that you can do this
animation in any programming language,
you know that's the essence. So, so what
so our code
uh our code is here. So, uh so first of
all we so we define this uh
we define this um function that
generates animation. So first of all
this is the inline documentation
and this line defines the option. So you
can so by default you're going to
generate 41 frames
by default otherwise you can um
for example let's copy that. So
otherwise it's you know you can like um
you know you can say
number of frames let's say five. Okay
it's very short. So all you get is um
actually so this is a mistake. Oh
actually this is not a mistake. You see
five frames the bar is here. Then the
bar is vertical. Then the bar is on the
left. Then the bar is on the bottom. And
the last one the bar is on the right. So
five like fits. Okay. So you can set the
bars like number of frames. Let's say
nine. Make it like less even. So okay,
you got that
you know. So you got nine frames of
animation. If you uh change it to let's
say
uh 15. Okay, let's see what you get.
Okay, you started to get some more
frames. You see?
So, you can say lots of frames. You can
say 90 frames. Let's try 90. Then it's
going to be very refined.
You see very refined. Refined. 90 uh
images. Wow. You see now you can of
course you can make animation of that.
Okay then okay then let's do it here
and uh all you have to do is you have to
say list animate
which takes an argument that's a list of
images list of graphics then it will
create animation. Okay. So do it.
So now we have this more refined
thing. Okay.
Cheers.
Now let's get into technical detail. You
see what we want to what I want to do is
to optimize this code.
So this code I wrote like 30 years ago
and uh you know I can actually let's do
this in language. So let's see let's do
it here. So go to asteroid go to astro
page show okay and you guys again you
guys you can search for visual
dictionary of spatial plane curves
you'll find my website and there is
asteroid then you can see what we are
seeing here. Okay. So we are talking
about this curve. So
so we want first of all um what should
sh you know there are several things I
want to do. One one of them is to
optimize this code. Okay
optimize this because this is written 30
years ago. It's very efficient but
however because you know 30 years is a
long time there's a writing there's a
coding style changes and and there's
also possibly some uh wam language uh
changes for example for example let me
tell you guys 30 years so this is like
30 years life experience so for example
you see this hu
hugh with an argument 0.7 75 that
represent kind of blue color. Okay,
that's you know kind of blue purple. So
that's a rainbow color. But today you
have a symbol that just represent blue.
And do you have purple? So let's see. P
U R P L E. Yes, you do. So you see
you see 30 years ago you don't have the
function blue. You don't have the
function purple. Those are symbols that
represent the color. But 30 years ago
you have this generic more like general
purpose
uh representation of color. One of the
model it language also supports RGB
color
like RGB color. So you can also do RGB
color and with three arguments each one
is going to be uh like red, blue uh
green. So you can say each one must be
between 0 to one not 0 to 255. The
idiotic from programmer idiots like the
Unix and C people they are idiots
because they think you know 25 to 55 is
the binary like they they they use a
bite to represent the value. But in Wuam
language is a math mathematician
mathematical based languages. So each of
the RGB value is from zero to one. the
ideal situation like 0ero to one is a
infinite number of u items. Okay. So
anyway uh RGB 5.5 that would be gray.
Okay. Shift uh shift enter to run it. So
you can see it's gray. So anyway, what
what I and Wuam language also supports
uh
uh s y
c y uh cm yk uh yk that's c and uh cm
magenda you know that's substractive
color modeling anyway so wuang language
supports quite a few color models so
let's see the documentation so we can
Hue.
Okay. So you can see hue color model. By
the way, color modeling is fairly
complex actually quite extremely
complex. Okay. So you got hue which is
one of the color model like more
intuitive. Then you got the RGB color.
So RGB color model. Let's go there. RGB
color model. Uh this is more this is
more simplistic according to kind of
like
uh physics you know addictive modeling
you know RGB color. Then you got uh
CM Y K it stand for CN magenda yellow
and what is K? Uh
yellow and black. Okay. So this is more
this is kind of like subtractive
modeling of color which is
suitable for printing like inks when you
do when you want to paint or you you
know you kind of use this model. Okay.
So color models are very complex fairly
uh complex. Okay. So anyway, so Wuam
language supports all these models, but
what I'm saying is that 30 years ago,
you have hue, RGB, and C, CM, YKK, but
you don't have like one symbol to stand
for a color. But now you do. They added
uh that for example. Let's look at they
added like that like 10 or 20 years ago.
So the function blue to represent the
color blue is added um in 2004. fairly
early. So that's 20 years ago
they added the the hu. So that's why my
code, you know, so this code
um could could use some improvement. For
example, you see this is my
you see back then I memorized the hue
values. So 0.3 is like greenish. Okay,
0.3 is greenish. So can we do that? Yes.
So 0.3 is uh greenish and uh that is the
brightness and this is the saturation.
So this would be green. There it is. You
see like kind of like perfect green.
Dark green. So today you can you know
today there there is a word to represent
that color. You can just say green.
Okay. Well do you have dark green? Not
necessarily. Okay. I don't think dark
green is building.
So anyway, the wolfam language started
to support named colors but not a lot
like they support like 10 or so like
fundamental named colors. Okay.
So anyway, so so you got uh green um so
um you know coloring is interesting
because I can show you uh CSS color. So
that's my uh website. So that's on.info.
Xhinfo.
Okay. So in CSS you got colors, you got
color basics. Um so these are my
tutorials about CSS. Okay. You got color
syntax. You got um
Okay, there's something
going on there because the background
color is not filled with that anyway.
So, you got color picker anyway.
So, about color. So, okay. So, let's
update the code. So, I need to update
the code. Uh yeah, let's just do
something. Okay. So, close that
asteroid. Okay. So, asteroid. Um,
okay. So, go to it.
Go to search for pre. Okay. So, this is
the astro.
Um,
let's see.
So, here's a code.
Okay. There's a lot to code. Okay. So we
you know
if we going to code this I'm going to
code this it's going to be very deep wam
language esoteric technical details okay
uh because you know I I can go over like
like overall what's going on how you
know how do you do it it's pretty simple
okay let me go over the code so first of
all you got this online documentation
inline documentation this is like the
dark string.
So, so when you have this you can people
can type you know people can just type
um for example question mark asteroid
generate the function name question mark
and it'll tell you the usage symbol.
Okay
close don't save. Okay that's this part
usage documentation. Okay.
uh
you should have it you know if you
define your own function then then this
section uh this section is defining a
optional parameter optional parameter
for this function asteroid generator
okay that's how you do it in wam
language okay so you basically you just
say options asteroid parameter equals
true then in our case it it should be
number of frames is the is a parameter
you created. Okay, so it's your personal
like for this function. This is a
parameter for this function optional
parameter.
But but you you want this function to
also be able to take any options of the
graphics function. So if you guys don't
know, you see wuam language has this
graphics function which is
allows you to generate lots of graphics
stuff. Okay. So [snorts]
but and it has a lot of um for example
let's look look at the documentation. So
you can generate triangles you Okay. So
you can generate triangles, you can
generate arrows,
um you can generate basia curve, spline
curve, B spline or well the fundamentals
are circle lines, field curve, disk half
line, half plane, uh line and point and
parallelogram. So those are like in
triangle and text. Okay, those are like
these are graphics primitives.
Okay, and exact you know so for example
you can see a line here. So you can see
this is a line this represent the line
line takes a two two uh argument of two
points coordinates you know beginning of
the line and end of the line. So that's
how you generate all these lines
and once you have so line is a graphics
primitive then you need to wrap it
inside a graphics you see this this you
see this is how you generate graphics
this is one single frame graphics then
hue means a color then you do some
computation like you take some of the
list uh generated line yeah [snorts]
that that's basically the line list GP P
is a bunch of lines. Okay. Yeah. So
that's you see that's that's a lots of
lines.
So anyway, graphics is a like a wrapper
for all 2D two-dimensional graphics and
it takes one like it takes uh you know
any number of graphics primitives such
as line, circles, polygon, point or text
or more comp complicated things such as
an image or raster image infinite lines
uh join curve insert But I'm not what
sure I'm not sure what is inset
represents an object
insert in a graphics. Okay. So it kind
of you know gets complicated.
Okay. So anyway so that's graph. So
okay. So um you see so so this option
you define the number of frames as an
option for astro generator the function
but you also allow it to takes
to take all options of graphics. You can
see all these are options for graphics.
They include things like background
color uh axis whether to draw it or not.
Uh they include other things like frame
tick like if you like do do you want um
do you want like tick on the on the on
the axis you know like tick or do you
want uh grid do you want to draw grid in
the background
you know those are like options for the
graphics okay so can you see that
okay so so what we are thing is that we
want this function our function to take
all these
options you know valid options for
graphics so that user can for example
let's do it okay so let's say another uh
let's say grid lines I want to show
grids okay so grid
um what what is it uh search for grid
grid lines okay so you should Search for
grid lines.
Oh, interesting. Uh, cancel. Okay,
so you want to say grid lines
automatic. Okay, now not so many frames.
Let's say uh 20 frames and let's say
list.
Okay, shift enter. So now you see we
have this animation. But now we got
these grids in the back.
Uh kind of interesting. Um not really.
So let's see the grid. Let's say let's
say let's change the option grids to um
uh can you can you like do 0.2?
Does that work actually?
No. So the grid lines needs to be
uh it needs to be okay. X grid and Y
grid are they uh grid lines specified
separately in each d direction.
Okay. But how do you specify them?
Uh grid lines. Okay. Uh
okay. So they need actually be uh
x pi to 2 pi
anyway we're not going to worry about
this.
So what I'm saying so what I'm saying is
that this um
this this is how you define
an option for for a function. Okay. Then
the heart of the function is this part
basically this part. Now this a bit
large so let me shrink it.
Uh let's see.
Can we like shrink a little bit?
Okay, we we can shrink. So I think that
Okay, so this this is a function this
whole thing. Okay.
Uh okay, so what we want to do?
Does that make sense?
Hello.
Hello color serve.
Okay, so we going to h we're going to
improve the code. Okay, let's do that.
So to code this actually is fairly
esoteric, you know, because you got so
okay. So so basically you you call
module. Module is like declare a block
uh declare local variables. So these are
local variables. this this module thing
is just like
uh it's just like local variables for
the function. Okay, that's how you
define local variables for the fun for
the for this function. Okay, then you
number of frames. This is how you get
the optional value number of frames
which is a integer. Okay. Um
Okay. So, so, so number of frames is an
integer. Then t minep
that's um
that's
okay. The the the you see the bottom
line is that remember to create this
animation. It's too many. Um hold on a
second. So let's delete that.
Now the bottom line line remember to
create this animation all you want is to
know the location of the two end points
of the bar. Okay that's like two points.
You need to know the location of those
two points.
So so those two points are created by uh
this this okay you generate a line GP
means graphics primitive. So you
generate a line and the coordinates are
cosine
at a value and zero. So the yaxis is
zero. So you can see the [snorts] yaxis
when if you play it you know the y-axis
is always zero. This blue the beginning
of the you see the the the purple dot
the y axis is always zero. The x axis
moves about. So that's that's this
that's this line that's that cosine
something zero that there and the other
end point the other uh the other point
of the line is the coordinate is just
zero and sign something. Okay so the
other coordinate is a green one. So you
can look at the green dot you see it
just moves up and down. Okay.
So meaning that the x axis is always
zero. The y axis moves up and down.
Okay.
So that creates a line that's this
that's this this is the essence. You see
this is a heart. Okay.
Now you are wondering so what so what am
I doing there? So you see that's why I
need to um you see this that's that's
this line. Okay. That's this line. And
this line can also be written. I'm
written in a you know wam language
shortcut way. So but it's cryptic you
know it the syntax is shorter but for
most people you don't understand what is
it what is this amperand what is slash
add what is at you know what is this
number pound sign but if if I write it
in a way you can understand that would
be like this okay so let me try to do
that
um
okay so let me do that that that that
that
okay so actually
okay so so this line is equivalent to
this line so basically what you do is
you map so you can see you map you map a
function
and the function is this function okay
uh function of line and the input is the
pound sign that's a number I and you map
that to this uh this value t range list
and what's t range list t range list is
defined
it's a range of numbers okay so so this
one is equivalent to that so we don't
need that anymore so
okay so that's basically that's a bunch
of lines lines list that's a list of
lines okay when you map when you map a
line function
you know this to a list of numbers. So
you got list of lines.
So that is the um lines GP and once you
got that essentially effectively
effectively you got animation. Okay. So
um you see but each time you want you
see each time you want to draw all the
lines of the past frames.
So you don't want to show all the lines
in one shot because if you show them all
the all lines in one shot what you get
going to get is in is the last frame. So
every frame is going to look like the
last frame because you got all the lines
right. So you don't want that. you you
want so for each frame [snorts] you want
to generate a graphics. So each frame
you take you take just um you you take
from the list of lines
only t items of them you see. So where
does t came from? t came from uh what
you see for each you see here. So t goes
from one to length of t range list. So
basically each time you just take two
items from the list.
Okay. Do I make sense? Does is that like
interesting? Oh Jesus. I don't think
anyone is watching me. Um so
uh god. So that means I just um why
don't I uh Okay. So what I do I what do
I do now
I I
go this
I can just improve on the code for
myself.
So first so you know so did did did did
but did we finish explaining the code I
think almost basically so you got this
function so this function
defines uh basically you have a
parameters you have two parameters okay
one of them is t range list by default
it's 0 to2 pi that's what that means
okay the other uh parameter is the opt
opts and that is the
options pattern which means um
which means
when whatever user typed
it will
be available in the function body as um
as opts. Okay. So you can see the opt is
used um
is used here. See
uh okay so
[snorts] so
that is a lot of wang wam language code.
Okay. So you define the options, you
define the t uh parameters, then module
is a list of local variables. So these
are local variables.
And then you got number of frames, which
is integer. And then you got t-min
for generating the line you know like
you know you want um you want a value to
control the movement of the of the end
points of the line. So that basically t
range list you know it's a t min is zero
usually t max is 2 pi t steps is usually
like 0.1 okay so
you got a list of uh t- range list list
of numbers then you create a list of
lines by mapping to the t range
then what you get is then you have this
static GP statics static graphics X
primitive GP is my convention for
graphics primitive which means this
graphics will remain there always in
every frame so this means hue 0.75
that's a blue so you want the line from
-1
0 to one zero so negative 1 so so
basically this static
uh graphics primitive means you always
want to draw a line regardless frame.
You want to draw the vertical line and
hor horizontal line. Okay, you want them
to be there always.
That's what this static GP means. Okay,
then the moving GP means moving graphics
primitives. So
here you have a thickness you have hue
zero hue zero is red then you have a
line there
that okay so this moving GP is this red
bar okay that's like constantly moving
just this one okay this red bar
so the moving GP you know depending on
so it also Um
uh so this is a function this moving GP
is a function then you map you see here
you map the moving GP
you apply it at the T range list
uh okay yeah so
okay so anyway so then you got the last
frame fra
uh what is the last frame GP? Last frame
GP is not used
actually.
Yeah. So that's the case. If people
wants only the last frame of the
graphics, then what you do is you use a
table. Table basically just create a
list. It's Python. It's like Python's um
it's like Python's uh
list comprehension. Okay. So anyway, the
first argument is the expression. The
second argument is t from
from one to by default it's one from one
to length of t range list. So and this
expression. Okay. So
basically hue uh hue zero is red. Then
take from the lines show up to the
current number of lines. Then you pass
the options for graphics. Graphics here.
Then you add the option of so you see
this is one single expression. You see
the table takes two arguments. the
expression and the variable from what
value to what value. Okay, so this
expression returns the graphics and what
the graphics is uh several parts. First
you know the main part is just list of
lines and the red line the last the bar.
Okay the moving bar you see
you see the list of lines in the past
and this current red bar you see that's
the so that's the past lines and this
part is the current the red moving bar.
Okay, your location
then so basically that is the graphics
you all you show is the you know the
past boss and you show the static
graphics primitive which is the
horizontal line and vertical line. Then
you show the current moving item which
is this red bar. See
then the rest of this graphics thing you
see graphics takes two arguments. The
first part is list of graphics there.
The rest the rest is like a bunch of uh
options. For example, you filter rules
is like you pass all the options
fed to astro generator to the graphics.
You put them here. Then you say aspect
ratio. Aspect ratio automatic means
means that you want this to be not
distorted. Okay? like like one unit in X
X axis means exactly one unit in Y axis
they have the same length
then axis true that means you want to
draw the axis X and Y and then text
that's you know that's the text you want
to show negative one 0
uh negative0.5 posit positive 0.5 that's
what those are and plot range Okay,
broad range is how much you want to show
grab it. So you see at the end of this
function, it just generate a table.
Table is just a list of things like
Python's um
list comprehension, you know, just
generate a list of things. What things?
Graphics. Okay, this graphic thing by
the variable t from one to this length
of length of t range list. Okay,
so is that clear? Does does does that
explain this um how this works? Um
yeah. Okay. So it takes 20 minutes to
explain that. Okay.
But what I want to do is see so
but for me I I want to
basically rewrite this function. Okay.
Because
um
okay. Okay. Every time I started to do
this, uh, I run into
issue because I need to rewrite this.
That's a that's a thing. That's what
that's why I'm starting this live
stream. I I need to rewrite this code
because first of all, you don't want to
use module because well, you should I
mean,
if you want it to be the fastest code,
then you shouldn't use module. Module's
got lots of problems. Okay, module
basically it creates basically it's a
lex lexical scope. Okay, so this is
about variable scope of the technical
detail of wam language. So in wam
language module creates a lexical scope.
However, there's a high price to pay
because wuam language is a term
rewriting system. So you don't you you
can't easy create like
lexical scope. So what woofam language
actually do is that whenever you use
module it creates new unique symbol
names for all the local variables. So it
creates lots of new symbols okay
internally.
Uh so and and that's very costy very
slow. So you want to use block instead.
So you know for example I would improve
the code right away like that. Okay that
that makes the code much faster already
by well by few microsconds because today
computer is very fast. Okay. So, replace
the module by by block. But
there's a lot more issues I need to look
um you know I I can change. But if I
have to also explain them then it take
you know like each one of these like all
the like almost every change I want to
make I have to explain it and each one
will take 10 minutes or five minutes. So
it becomes impossible
for me to actually do work on this code
while I do live stream because
you know I thought I'm just going to do
live stream while I code but I can but
then you're just going to uh watch me
code like no explanation like you you
have no idea what's going on.
Okay. So, so I do need to explain then
then but but like almost each item
it will take like five to 10 minutes uh
if I'm going to explain.
So what are some examples? Well, first
of all is this block versus module.
Okay. Um
uh if you don't know, so you can you can
look at my woo fam language tutorial or
search for it. you'll find it and you
can go to so you go to the Wam language
in depth and then you go to basics
comments and print string and number and
boolean list and you'll have variable
section global variable and local
variable so you go to the local variable
section so you can see here there are
three ways to define a local variable in
wam language okay one of them is block.
One of them is using module. The other
one is width. Okay. Block and module.
Block is dynamic scope. Module is
lexical scope while width is local
constants. Okay. Each one of them
actually got problems. Okay.
Um so
in g well each one of them got issues.
So the the module is like
technically the best because it creates
lexical scope. So it's you know
that's what you want. Okay. So I you
know well I don't have to
um you see the the issue is that then I
have to explain lexical scope. Do you
guys know what it is?
So it's like every time I need to make a
change I need to you know it becomes 10
minutes explanation.
So I can't really actually um
code this because I
because I then you nobody knows what I'm
doing.
So anyway so there are three ways to um
create local variables. Okay. So, but
the pro the problem with module is that
it's um it creates like
internal internally unique symbols.
Okay. And it's pretty costly. It's
pretty slow.
So, in general, you don't want that. But
if you use block then then it's lexical
scope. I mean, if you use block then
it's dynamic scope. dynamic scope got
its own problems because you got the
collision with um
you you you have the potential of
possible variable collision with global
variables. So if you do not ever define
global variables then you don't have a
problem.
Well, but the the fact is that people do
define global variables especially in
Wuam language because it's just
convenient like X equals true something
right. So, so um you got an issue there
block variable uh using dynamic scope.
Then the other option is use width which
is which which actually is the best. It
creates local constants. But the problem
is that you cannot the later variables
do does not know the value of previous
variable. That means it no variable
chaining so-called it's known as
variable chaining. So you can't so later
variables cannot depend on the value of
previous defined local variables. So if
you want to do that then you need to
nest with then which becomes very ugly
like with with nested width kind of
ugly. Now in Wuam language about two
years ago or a year ago the new version
they fixed that but then you but they
fixed that by requiring but they fix
that in some way by requiring you to
have subsequent this this curly brackets
within the nested uh within the width
function.
So they kind of fix it but it's not
ideal. So you you know because then you
have subsequent you know variables. So
anyway so so so what I'm saying here is
that language you got these three
ways to create local variables and uh
they are not ideal. Okay.
So then what I'm saying here is that
this code I like to modify change you
know uh is using um
is is is you know so it's coded 30 years
ago but if I'm going to
any change I make it'll take like five
minutes or 10 minutes to explain so that
is the problem. So I can't really work
on the code. You see what I'm saying? So
we just we just took five minutes to
explain the block you know change why we
should you know why I want to change the
module into block okay
we so then there's quite a few for
example um for example in this part you
are assigning three variables by by this
by by um
okay Well, so you see I need to explain
this. This this range thing came from
came from the input. So this range list
means uh let's see
what what
can you do that?
Let's do the green.
Okay. Where is this range list search
for? Oh, it's not found. That's a
mistake.
Okay, we discovered the code mistake.
Did we?
Oh, wait. No, that's correct. So, range
it it requires the head to be a list.
Yeah. So, this is a pattern, you know,
they requires the head to be a list. So,
um so if you don't give it that the
default will be that list.
So but the the problem here is that
you see if the so if the list got three
items minimum maximum and the step then
you turn them into numerical values
that's what this capital n is then you
assign them to these three variables
okay now if they if the range list is
not three values Then what you do is um
yeah then you take you you know you take
the first element then you take the
second element then you
then the step is
the second element minus the first
element. So where does this maps
uh where do they came from?
t mean. Okay. So if there are if there's
not three elements you do
you define them that way.
Okay. Yeah. So the first part is going
to be just
if it's three items otherwise
uh there are several issues with this
code. Okay. Uh the way I would like
write to write it today is
there are several issues equals through
the code. Okay. So
okay.
So the way I would write it is
okay. So this would be second
true and this would be just um
let's use that syntax first second and
the range would be the step is the step
would be
if okay so if range equals = to three
then that otherwise
otherwise
okay
in fact
okay so if it has three elements then
the tep is just that okay
uh So that that that is just
last at T range otherwise
otherwise you say it's T max.
Oh T-max is defined here. So you see
tricky.
So you see this code I like to kind of
improve it to be like that because when
you run this code it depends on like
sequential evaluation.
Okay. You see this last item depends on
t-max and t min having already have a
value.
So wait is that? Yeah. So if something
that that
do I make sense.
Okay. So but if we write this this way
T- max P uh T mean so
T mean T- max. Okay. then uh
otherwise otherwise you shouldn't you
don't need that
number of frames. Now do we have number
of frames? Yes.
And also I like to change the variable
names um
like number of frames you could you
know.
Okay. So anyway, so
yes, it makes sense. Okay. Okay. So are
you a wolfam language coder? Because
most people wouldn't know what I'm
doing. So that is um
kind of so
so anyway t-max teing and t-step and um
well actually
Then you do T range list. You see you
see there is a lot um
so where are they used?
You see they are not used much.
So except here. So you don't you know
you
you may not for example you this
variable t minimum is maybe redundant
because basically it's only used once
here
and t-max is also kind of redundant
because it's used here but one more time
here. So
um you probably don't need it. And what
about t-step? How how you know where is
the t-step used? T-step is used only
once. So you don't even you don't need
uh you don't need a you know set up a
constant for it.
These are like trivial details but if
you are doing optima optimization that's
what you know that's what you are
looking for. So in effect, we don't
need, you know, we we spent like five
minutes doing these three. Actually, we
don't need any of them.
Uh do you guys see what I'm saying?
Because this T mining would be just
that. Okay. T- max would be just that
that. Okay. And it occurs one more time.
Uh this occurs one more time. So
okay so we can kind of replace that and
t-step only occur one time. So t-step is
actually
uh tep is like you can delete the
t-step. T step is just that. Okay. So
now we can kind of actually delete that.
Delete that. And we don't need this
anymore. and t minax t-step or delete.
So our code becomes much simpler
and uh yeah so
so anyway so number of frames I like to
rename this variable I don't like this
and also this uh syntax I like to change
to this syntax okay so this delete
so number of frames um
I'm learning it okay so you are learning
language fantastic
Okay. So, so number of frames is equals
to that. Now, where is number of frames
used like one time? Okay. Number of
frames is used one time here. So, do you
need it as a standalone variable? Not
really. Okay. So, number of frames.
Okay. Delete it. Delete it. Number
frames. Uh, delete that. This is just
here that. Okay. So, you don't need this
variable anymore. Okay.
The T- range list is um
this is range. Yeah, range. You need a
range. Range uh
minimum, max uh min for minimum to
maximum and steps. Okay. So that's the
steps. Now wait. Okay. So actually it's
using T mining and T-max there.
Well,
okay. So you need um
Well, so T-max,
this is T min
and this is T-max. Okay. T- max minus T
min
actually so you know so so you know we
are kind of like right now I'm doing
blind optimization this is not
explainless because for example this you
know this definition you see we are
defining this function
so by this pattern And that so so wait
uh so what this means is that it tells
woof language whenever you see this
pattern starting with asteroid generator
then then a uh square bracket then
something inside two items okay one item
and the other item optional so if the
first item does not occur automatically
assume this list Okay. So basically here
is a pattern and this colon equal means
set delayed. Okay.
Again you can read my wolf language
for programmers. You can uh go to it.
You can see set delayed. Okay. So that
is about setting a variable. So you can
see number boolean list uh expression
atom head variable. Okay. conditional
loop expression assignment. So we need
something like had a matching function
loop iteration.
Um
so you need then data structure basics.
Okay. So common print string
numbering
list. Uh so
what you want to know is uh variables
local variables. Let's go there. Okay.
So wait,
we we did that. Uh
okay, glo. Yeah, global variables.
That's what you want to go. So let's go
to global variables. So set you know so
you have this common commonly used set
something equals to something like x
equals to three then you got set delayed
okay here
you see that's that's the um
set and set delays okay so here it's
talking about set then set delayed is
here so you got this colon equal That
means set the right hand side to the
leftand side symbol
or pattern. Okay, set the right hand
side to the left hand side but don't
evaluate the right hand side yet. Okay,
evaluate it only when the left hand side
occurred like matched. You see? So
that's the difference between set and
set deate. You see? You see one is just
x equals to something syntax. The full
name is set function. The other one is
set delayed is x colon equals through
something. Okay. The difference is one
is set
one is set delayed. So what's the
difference? Well set will evaluate the
right hand side right away. So the right
hand side x equals to something. The
same thing can be a expression can be x
can be y or can be complicated
expression it'll be evaluated then that
value will be set to x meaning that
whenever wra sees x you'll replace it
with that value okay but the right hand
side is evaluated now the set delayed
using the colon equal is that the right
hand side is not evaluated
it will evaluate the right hand side
only when the left hand side actually
occurs somewhere. So that's a
difference. Okay.
Now there are several things I'm talking
about here. One is the you know
difference between set and set delay.
The other thing is about the short
syntax you see like in Python you know
or JavaScript or other languages we are
familiar with X equals to something but
that in wam language is actually the
function set X two arguments set X and Y
okay so anyway that's that's a set and
set delay so in as an application here
what we doing is this we are you know
saying that Whenever you see astro
generator something something patterns
there then colon equal means set
delayed. So when it you are telling w
language whenever you see this
uh make replace them by the right hand
side. However because it's colon equal
means set delay that means don't
reevaluate the right hand side right
away.
Okay. So,
so that's what what's going on. Okay.
So, why am I talking about that? Because
because this pattern that we are talking
about can be written in a different way.
Okay. This pattern let me let me try to
so we are rewriting this pattern. This
pattern can be written such that you
don't do that. Okay. Well,
uh,
so you can actually say T main here.
Wait, can you
T mining
T-Max?
Um
so that way you will um you will
actually have the value t and t-max
and uh this optional so
I believe I'm pretty sure you can do
that. Okay. So if you do that then you
have the value of t mining and t- max
like then you don't have you don't need
this complicated t range first part t
range second part.
Okay so but in order to do that then you
need to evaluate the whole thing as a
experiment. So for example paste that
separate it and uh so now we have that.
So now instead of saying T range, we can
just say uh wait. So delete that. Delete
that. Okay. So now with that, we got
that. So we got uh does this actually
work?
Yes, I think I'm pretty sure. Okay. So
copy that. So you don't need this T
range. T range is just that. So it's
simpler. And T range second part is
T-max.
And uh
then uh what about the t-steps? That's
the third one. Is there a way to like
Yeah, we can actually. I think I can.
But um but there's more code anyway. So
but so you can you can see that we
improved this code pattern. Uh wait,
you see we improve this line by
wait. Okay, this is here is the original
then
uh
new. Okay, original and new.
The question is does it work? Yeah, of
course. You know, so hold on a second.
So we can also
the t mining
this is just t mining okay and uh this
is just tmax so
okay so it's simpler you see
does it work I think so
um
yeah those you See this colon something
is a way to specify default argument
but actually it's much more comp
complicated because okay so let me go to
it so let me tell you so we are doing
pattern matching so that's how that's
like how woofam language works pattern
matching okay uh the foundational
mechanism of how wam language does
evaluation
And so what what what we are doing is
that we are doing um
we are talking about this uh default
value. So how does it work like what do
you mean by default value? So default
value basically is a
from from what I we what we want to do
we think of of it like normal
programming point of view. We think of
that as default value, right? Because
this parameter what we really want is
that if there is no argument given, it's
supposed to take two arguments separated
by comma. If there's no argument, then
assume the first argument is going to be
zero and 2 pi. Okay?
And and the second argument if none is
given assume it's just uh
you know assume it's just um
doesn't assume doesn't assume anything
assume it's empty. Okay. Anyway so
that's so from a normal programming
programmer point of view what we want is
default argument. Okay. [snorts] But
from a woofam language technicality
point of view these are pattern
matching. Okay. So you are trying to
match your pattern that start with astro
generator the symbol then followed by
square bracket then followed by
something. So the tricky part is this
here something. So here it means so what
we want is a pattern such that it can
match empty.
So if it's empty then it returns this
zero and 2 pi as a list but if it's not
empty then it returns whatever the user
input and it must be a list. You see
that's so this is the pattern matching
part.
So that part you get you go to this uh
so here on this page you have
introduction to pattern matching you
know what does it mean? So you got left
hand side right hand side you see in our
code the left hand side is this you see
astro generator bracket something the
right hand side is this this this whole
block you see and we are using set
delayed you see colon equal you see
you see so explanation of the pattern
matching so from a programmer's point of
view we are just defining a function
That's all we want to do. We want to
define this function which draws
animation. Okay. But from a wam language
technicality
the you know technical tech techn
technicality of the woofam language
point of view what you are doing this is
pattern matching. This is defining what
you are doing is defining a
rule so that when this whenever this
left hand side this pattern occur wam
language will replace it by the this
right hand side it's a you know it's a
you are defining a rule the left hand
side is this pattern the right hand side
is this code and it's
set delayed meaning that you know Don't
evaluate the right hand side yet only
when the left hand side match some you
know some code. So that's pattern
matching.
So you got local and versus global
pattern matching. Okay. So basically set
delayed is creating a global pattern
matching rule global transformation that
you are telling language that whenever
whenever you see this thing on the left
hand side just replace it by the right
hand side. Okay.
So so that's this part then so so you
have two ways to create create the rules
of pattern matching. One one is uh
um
okay so local and global so you have two
aspects for global you have set and set
delayed okay we talked about but for
local you you got rule and rule delayed
okay wait um yeah okay I'm not going to
explain that but anyway pattern matching
so what you want so then what you want
is the pattern matching syntax
so how is it possible to create a
function with optional parameters. Well,
in w language you have to do pattern
matching. So,
so that's when this part pattern
matching syntax. So, that's when this
you know for example what does the un
under uh low line mean? What does the
colon mean? That's the syntax of the
patterns. Okay. So, so what we here so
we have um syntax for any expression we
have syntax for blank blank means
anything. So that's what the underscore
is
then you can match. Okay. So then you
got named pattern. So
yeah then you you know so you can name
the pattern so that when it matches when
when you want to do the replacement you
can refer to the pattern by name.
Uh so you got uh so you got that you
know so this is actually the the most
complicated part about woofam language
because wuam language do computation by
this by this so-called term rewriting
system basically repeated
pattern replacement okay
or also known as syntactic
transformation or you can if you are if
you came from lisp you can think of wuam
language is macros. It's all about
macros. Okay, the maros is far more
complicated than
lisp maros. So, wuam language is
basically a a language of maros.
Okay. So, so you got so repeated pattern
you can have. Um, or if you came from
Pearl or Python, you can think of this
this syntactic transformation or micro
language or the pattern matching, you
can think of it as uh regular expression
but instead of working on strings, it
works on the code, the symbols, you
know, the code itself. So, the pattern
matches all this code. Okay.
So anyway pattern. So so what we have
here. So for example we we are talking
about
we are talking about like def default
values. So the first part is a parameter
such that if if none is given then you
should assume this default list of two
values. So what what exactly is that
pattern? So the pattern for that is
um
here. Okay. Some somewhere here pattern
negation
advanced patterns pattern sequence uh
pattern rel related to functional
optional arguments. Okay. um longest and
shortest very complicated thing that's
like analogous to regular expression
like um longest and shortest match
literal patterns. So um wait where's the
optional
default values? Okay that's what we are
talking about. So that involves a colon
uh except alternatives
uh condition no
talking about pattern test no pattern
with a conditional test that is you
given a pattern but you want it to match
only if a function returns true on that
pattern. You see so that's what that is.
So repeat it. No. So you uh so wait you
want condition. Okay you want no what
you want is a um default value. So you
want basically you want to match a blank
which means
like no expression. So when you uh I
think wait is that right? I think so.
Okay.
What?
Uh what?
Okay. So, okay. So, that's called
optional. So, you see, so the full name
for this optional pattern syntax is
called optional. It's just a function
optional. So, the shortcut syntax is
something colon something. So on the
left hand side is a pattern the right
hand side is the default value. Okay. So
you can see our code you see you see
this T range list on the left hand side
is um
a value. Okay that's an well actually
hold on a second. Hold on a second.
I think my wife is back. I'm going to
have dinner.
My wife is back. So, actually, I think
I'm going to go.
Oh god. Um, oh god.
You know the thing about live stream is
that you know so I want you know what so
did I already explained enough yet? I
what I want to do is just improve the
code. So normally you know I would just
work on the code but but to do live
stream you need to explain it right but
whether otherwise what's you know people
are just going to see you code like they
you know they don't know what's going on
unless they are already kind of wam
programmers and fairly expert
so but in order to um so I need to
explain for everything I do so but every
item will take like more than five
minutes to explain. So I can't even you
know I didn't even start to well we did
we did start to rewrite some part of it
but um
anyway so we were talking about this
optional thing. So you see a pattern and
colon and the default value on the right
hand side. So here you see the left hand
side is a p pattern that means t range
is anything it must begin with a word
list okay that's that's a named pattern
okay you see we talked about named
pattern before named pattern you know we
we mentioned it before so so the left
hand side is a pattern that pattern the
right hand side is this thing a list
zero and 2 pi so the right hand side is
means default mode. So this this P you
know a pattern colon something can be
rewritten if you want to by this by this
optional you know the full functional
form you know because that's what it
means optional parameter so you see wuam
one of the I think great syntactical
feature of wufam language is that
everything is represented by the full
functional form okay even more robust
than lisp. Okay, like everything is this
full you know function name square
brackets then whatever but but then you
have the syntactic shortcut they are but
they are equivalent okay because every
you know when wam language evaluate
anything it changes this syntactic
shortcut syntax to this full form so you
can write this way or that way either
way okay so anyway so this this syntax
is a pattern
which means you know the left hand side
is a pattern and if it does not occur
like if there's empty there's nothing
then it will automatically match and and
it will be supplied by supplied by this
default value okay so that's so so here
I explain typical usage again this is my
this is my uh kasawam language
code okay I mean for a tutorial just
search for it kasali.info info on my
website. So fascinating. Okay. So why
are we So we were explaining about this
um search for option. We were explaining
about this this
basically from a programmer's point of
view we are trying to define a function
that takes a optional parameter with
default values. But from a technical
point of view of Wuam language this term
rewriting system what you are doing is
you are creating a set delayed pattern
and the left hand side is astrogenerator
something and it it involves two parts.
The first part is this thing something
colon something and which actually means
this pattern optional something. Okay.
So when this pattern so when wam
language sees like astro generator like
for example like um like here it doesn't
see any argument so so this this p is
empty it matches because because of this
pattern it match but it will wen
language will give it you know the value
of definition the like default actually
I should rename it this to be default
value
uh because it confuses with definition.
Okay. So, let's rename that. So, let's
go to So, do I do you uh do I make
sense? Okay. Um, so
optional. Wait, search for optional. Do
I make sense? Like, is my live stream
make sense or it's like esoteric? Okay.
So, anyway, so
Okay. So, refresh. So, you can see I uh
big fan. Thank you. Hello, Ga Ga Gupta.
Uh in a module, how are the final values
of T min, T-max, and TTEP determined
from the user input T range list?
especially when handling the optional
tep.
I love Emacs. What your setup? Okay, I
think I'm going to go. Um, you know, so
we we were doing we not doing Emacs
today.
So in the module, how are the final
values T min determined from the user
input?
Well in the code before we modify the
code you see we we we in the parameter
we don't have t-max t min
are local variables here and there you
see and they are defined here in this
line so t minep
equals to you know if the range if the t
range is three items then then just
equals to the range you So the first
item is t mining. The second item is
t-max. The third one is t step. But if
there are not three items then
then the t-step would be t max minus t
min divided by um the number of frames.
Okay.
Okay. I got I got I got to go. So I
can't you know I can't
I can't fruitfully work on my code. Uh I
gotta figure out something. Okay. So
because because because we and we
haven't tested this yet. Okay. Actually
we have not tested the code. So can we
test it?
Actually I'm not sure it will work.
Okay. Astro generator. Let's say shift
enter.
It does work. Okay. So anyway, so yeah.
So alcohol you know we we did some
modification it works we changed the
module to block fantastic
and we also eliminate eliminated the
like the variables t min
shorter uh but there's a lot there's a
lot to do so
anyway I hope that's some you know
uh useful okay bye guys I gotta Oh,