hello welcome everyone welcome to
another episode of sound talk show we
are going to code wolam language today
and if you are watching this offline
skip around okay because I talk slow and
uh this is probably going to be an hour
or uh an hour and a half now Advent code
as they go into day 10 or you know 14
we're going to do day 14 uh
2020 what 23 so last year day
14 so when you know the later problems
gets
complicated and uh usually you know last
time I took six hours and not done so we
just going to go I'm just going to go
code it easy and for an hour or two and
if I didn't finish then that's
okay and so play at speed to or skip
around okay when you are watching
offline you have to skip around uh if
you are here say
hi uh so let's begin let's see how many
people I have uh nobody okay oh one guy
K hello hello k i i remember you last
time so wfam coding wfam language okay
so we going to start um yeah so my
keyboard glove 80 keyboard ultimate
hacking two keyboard newly trackable
these are fantastic okay check out
search for them on YouTube you will find
them uh I have video reviews of
them okay Advent of code uh
2014 I mean
2023 problem uh 14 day 14 okay I haven't
read the problem yet uh I'm going to go
slow okay
use some red wine to soothe my soul so
what I hope to achieve is that you can
learn some uh wolam language which is a
term rewriting system a basically a
programming language that's different
from all that you've
seen and in the past month I have been
working on my w Language tutorial a lot
especially on the pattern matching so
basically pattern matching if you do
functional programming such as hascal or
camo or Erland you might know somewhat
but wolam language Panda matching is
symbolic that means basically
essentially what wolam language the way
it does
computation
is uh is just transform
expressions like like your source code
is just like a string so whenever you do
you write a function you call a function
it's actually doing transformation of
the source code so it's somewhat like
like list maros but it's far Advanced so
imagine if you are coding iMac LP every
function is marro that's essentially
what uh wolam language is okay you don't
actually have like normal functions
every function is like just transforming
your your source code
and uh we have live stream talking about
that before so anyway in the past few
days I've been trying um I've been
working on a comprehensive um in-depth
coverage of wolam language patterns so
anyway so here's my tutorial search for
wolam Language tutorial you'll find it
uh wolam language in depth and uh you
can down downloaded the wolam script for
free okay some uh I'm looking forward to
buy that keyboard you recommend me last
time expose yeah okay let's start to
code okay let's see how far we can go
day 14 parabolic reflector
dish uh you reach the place where all of
the mirrors were pointing a massive
parabolic parabolic reflector dish
attached to the side
okay uh in short if you move the Rocks
you can focus the dish the platform even
has a control panel on the side that
lets you tilt in one of the four
directions the round the rounded rocks
zero Will Roll when the platform is
tilted while the cube shaped Rock pound
sign will stay in place so zero Will
Row pound sign stay in place you not the
positions of all of the empty spaces
which is dot okay and rocks your
personal input for example okay so you
got a person input like that okay start
by tilting the lever so all of the rocks
will slide North as far as they will
go okay uh so zero is where you can take
tilt pound sign
is no and Dot are spaces so zero so that
means zero can move up so when whenever
you see a zero it can move up so all of
the rocks will slide North as far as
they will go okay so they will they will
move all the way to the north what
exactly is the
problem so you got a bunch of parabolic
mirrors okay whatever so anyway zero
will move up all the way okay you notice
that the support beams along the north
side of the platform are damaged to
ensure the platform doesn't collapse you
should calculate the total load on the
North support
beams looks like you want to determine
what is the eventual result for the
first line okay the amount of load cost
by a single Round Rock is equal to the
number of rows from The Rock to the
South aged of the
platform uh the amount of load caused by
a single rounded
Rock okay amount of load is equal to the
number of
rows from The Rock to the South edge of
the platform the number of
the platform including the row the rock
is
on uh Cube shaped Rocks Don't contribute
to load okay so the amount of load
caused by each Rock in each row is as
follows amount of load caused by each
Rock in each row so so first row is
10 how do you get 10 uh I don't know
let's
see the amount of blad caused by a
single Round Rock is equal to the number
of rows from The Rock
to the South edge of the platform so you
count the columns the number of zero in
the columns below something like that so
let's
see uh 1 two 3 4 five zeros so but you
got 10 that
means uh is uh amount of load caused by
a single Round Rock is equal to the
number of rows
number of rows from The Rock to the
South edge of the
platform including the row the rocky s
so let's see 1 2 3 4 4
three 7 7 8
9 10 okay so
basically for each zero in a row you
want to
count all zeros below it but not
including when you reach a rock okay so
the First Column the we are doing the
first row first the first
row it's magnify okay so
oh so we are doing this Row
first and we do each column so the First
Column is four because there are four
zeros below the second column is three
because there are three zeros including
itself the third column is just one
because there's no zero below it you
know you stop at the pound sign okay the
fourth column is
one and uh this and this whatever this
column there's no zero below it so it's
also one so you got
43 431 one
one so 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 so that's why it's
10 now let's check the second column
it's
nine uh
what wa wait why is it
n uh the amount of low caused by a
single Round
Rock so the amount of blow caused by
each Rock in each row okay amount of
load caused by a single rounded rock is
equal to the number of
rows oh my God this is going to take
hours equal to the number of rows from
The Rock to the South edge of the
platform including a row the rock is on
Cube shaped Rock don't contribute to the
load so the amount of load caused by
each Rock in each row is as
follows so the second row we got two
zeros and
uh and why is it n so why why is it this
9 10 87 they are seems to be in order
oh
God N I don't understand this n hello
care uh okay
so
okay the total load is a sum of load
caused by all of the rounded
rocks in this example the total load is
139 why is it 139 9 is it because one
add to 10 I don't think so one add to 10
is not 139 so let's do a some uh W
language so you do
sum 1 to
10 uh one wait X okay so X goes to 1 to
10 that's called uh yeah that's 55 so
that's
not you know that's not
so how do you get
136 tier the platform so that the
rounded rocks or roll North afterwards
what is the total load on the North
support
beam okay what is the support beam does
it just mean the north support beam does
it just mean r
one okay so you have to read the problem
the elf
uh oh God I'm going to do this problem
today are we going to do it yeah let's
try to have fun okay the dish is okay so
you reach the place where all the MIRS
are Point
uh where all of the mirrors were
pointing a massive parabolic reflector
dish attached to the side of another
large mountain this dish is made up of
many small mirrors but while the mirrors
themselves are roughly in the shape of a
parabolic reflector dish each individual
mirror seems to be pointing in slightly
the wrong direction if the dish is meant
to focus light all all it's doing right
now is sending it in a vague Direction
stupid
English uh this system must be what
provides the energy for for for the lava
what
whatever okay so if you focus the
reflector dish maybe you can go where
it's pointing and use the light to fix
the lava production so you just need to
fix this mirrors Direction upon closer
in inspection the individual mirrors
each appear to be connected via an
elaborate system of ropes and pulley to
a large metal platform
below the dish okay the platform is
covered in large rocks of various shapes
okay depending on their position the
weight of the Rocks deforms the platform
and the shape of the platform controls
which rope move and ultimately the focus
of
this shape of the FL stupid
English stupid story in short if you
move the box you can focus the dish the
platform even has a control panel on the
side that lets you tilt it in one of
four
directions the rounded rocks zero Will
Roll Will Roll when the platform is
tilting okay so you got a you got like a
slab
okay on this slab is a grid it's a grid
of things like like this uh text okay so
some of them are pwn sign pwn sign are
just like fixed whatever whatever thing
the zero is
[Music]
the uh how does it roll if you move the
Rocks you can focus the dish
so what so the rock is a
mirror upon closer inspection the
individual mirrors each appear to be
connected via elaborate system of ropes
and pulley
the platform is covered in large rocks
of various shapes depending on their
position the weight of rock deforms the
platform what how is that
significant uh so anyway purose or input
so you got this start by tilting the
lever so all the rocks will slide North
okay okay so when you til let's see if
we understand the problem okay all the
Zero moves up okay
uh so let's look at these two yeah so
this two and this second column moves up
yeah okay you move it all the zero rows
to the north okay you notice that the
support beam along the north side of the
platform are damaged to ensure the
platform doesn't collapse you should
calculate the total load on the North
support
beam so it looks like you just need to
find some kind of a number for row
number one okay that's what it means the
amount of load caused by a single Round
Rock is equal
to the number of rows from The Rock to
the South edge of the
platform including a row the Rocky song
okay pound sign doesn't count so the
amount of load caused by each Rock in
each row is as follows
so the first row we determine it's 10
because because because it's
43 1 one
one that's 10 okay the second row is
nine we don't understand how it works I
don't understand how it
works so the amount of load C by each
Rock in each row is as follows
so it's saying this text block is
actually the load for each
row uh the number but uh but I'm not
understanding the second row so the
third row is eight let's see one two
three
four five no I don't get why it's
eight uh then
okay so the amount of load caused by
each Rock in each row is as follows
amount of load caused by each
Rock
up so the total load is the sum of the
loow load caused by all of the rounded
rocks so you want to get the sum for all
rows uh in this example the total load
is 136 it's not 13 36 so how do you how
did you get
136 sum 1 + 2 you know according to the
row number 1 + 2 + 3 up to 10 is
55 does that make sense
yeah let's
see 10 20 30 yeah about 55 that's
correct because you add them you know by
pays
uh but how do you get
136 the total load is the sum of the
load caused by all of the rounded
rocks the amount of load caused by a
single rounded rock is equals to the
number of row from The Rock to the South
edge of the
platform okay but first of all you roll
them to the north
right so this is your personal input you
roll them to the north and you got this
thing and but I don't understand the
load do you guys understand the
load uh to the platform so that the
round rocks or Road North afterward what
is the total load on the North support
beam okay there's something I don't
understand how do you get the number 136
amount of load caused by each Rock in
each row is as
follows oh
God this night doesn't make sense what
about this one
eight oh oh wait do you have to count
also the one above no the amount of blad
caused by a single Round Rock is equals
to the number of
rows the number of rows from The Rock to
the South edge of the platform so you
don't count whatever is above
it right so for the second
row why is it nine now if we count the
thing above it one two three 4 4
three if you count above it it's
four and three 4 + 3 is 7 so it's not
nine uh so what is going
on equals to a number of oh number of
rows from The Rock to South edge of the
platform
so it is the number of
rows not the number of uh rocks so the
number of
rows from The Rock to the South edge of
the
platform including the row the rock is
on Cube shaped Rock don't contribute to
the load so let's try
again so the second row
number of rows so the first column in
second row how many let's see one 2 3 4
five 6 7
eight okay eight now the second
column let's see one two three uh wait
uh below okay from below so the First
Column is 1 2 3 4 five 6 7 seven the
second column is 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8
n okay so if you add seven and nine it's
more than n so that still doesn't make
sense
God C
crap am I drunk I've only I had you know
I have I had 100 MERS of red
wine which is a quarter of a
cup I'm not
drunk oh God this is not doing
good support beams on North side of the
platform are damag to ensure the
platform does collapse you should
calculate the total load on the north
side support beam the amount of load
caused by a single rounded rock is
equals to the number of rows from The
Rock to the South edge of the
platform including the row the rock is
on so let's try do column I mean Row one
first
again a amount of load caused by a
single Round Rock zero Z so zero is
important we just want to deal with
zero okay is equal to the number of rows
from The Rock to the South edge of the
platform including the row the rock is
on okay but excluding the pound sign
okay so let's
count Row one column one 1 two 3 4 five
six 78
Row one column two 1 two 3 4 five 6 7 8
9 10 so so that's already 18 which is
more than 10 so this number is incorrect
so that means our interpretation is
wrong what the are these numbers 10
87 you see it says so the
amount of load cost by each Rock in each
row is as
follows so it by chance
this amount of load for each
row happens to be descending consecutive
integers 10 9 8 7 6 5 4 3 2 1 why is
that I don't know so for example the
last
row the amount of of
load costed by each Rock in each
row you see it says cost by each rock it
didn't say cost by all rock in a
row it just says cost by each Rock what
the what the is
the okay do I make sense are you guys uh
watching
oh
God H I don't know what's going on this
immediate problem just under
understanding I was using the
oromic chair but now I feel
like using the standard
chair I don't understand the problem
you should calculate the total load so
the goal is to calculate the total
load and but so given a input like that
but first of all you need to move all
the zeros to the north
okay wait so given an input like that
first of all you need to move all the
zeros to the
north but
um let's let's understand so you move
all the zeros to the
north right yeah you do that so are
these two images the same yes so first
of all you move all the zeros to the
north then you need to find the amount
of load
on the North support beam it just means
the roow number
one uh total road is the sum of the load
caused by all of the round
rocks in this example the total load is
136 okay so you notice that support beam
along the north side of the platform are
damaged to ensure the platform doesn't
collapse you should calculate the total
load on the
North support beam so first of all you
need to calculate the total load on the
North support beam on row number
one okay but then eventually you need to
the total load is the sum of the
load caused by all of the rounded
rocks Okay so
so there are two things I'm not
understanding first of all for each row
I don't understand what's their load
this number doesn't
compute second
secondly if you add all these numbers 1
2 3 4 5 to 10 they don't total to
136 so this means there's something I
I'm not misunderstanding
okay but am I missing some like
description of the problem I don't think
so because all the above is irrelevant
rather so the most important thing is
really first of all you move the
zeros okay you move all the zeros
to the north that I understand how do
you program
that uh I don't know but but anyway we
understand the problem but then the
problem is the load
thing okay it's already 36 minutes and
I'm not understanding the problem
uh support being on no side of the
platform are damaged to ensure the
platform doesn't collapse you should
calculate the total load on the North
support
beam what the is North support beam
that just mean the row number one
right okay Noob Noob says I think the
total load is a weighted
sum uh D Rock has a low to the number in
the side could that that be
right dash Rock what do you
mean you got a
TP uh okay so
we can we magnify this oh God
this Google Chrome so I'm on windows so
that would be that plus
where is
plus total so you are thinking it's some
kind of weighted sum
okay weighted sum each Rock has a load
equal to the number in the
side each Rock has a
load equal to the number in the
side okay something about weight
weighted some basically but
um but
[Music]
I'm so you roll the zero you move all
the zero to the
top and uh hello JN you roll the zero to
the top you move the zero to the top
then then you get this you know this um
picture okay then you you notice that
the support beam along the north side of
the platform are damaged okay to ensure
the platform doesn't collapse you should
calculate the total load on the North
support beams there is an S
there so maybe the north support beams
does is not just the roow number one I
don't know the amount below caused by a
single round Ro is equals to the number
of rows from The Rock to the South edge
of the
platform so here it uses the word Edge
while over there it uses the word
beam
so so North support
beams okay I'm not sure what that means
and uh I mean not exactly in the South
Edge the South edge of the platform the
that mean just the bottom
row including the row the rock is on
okay don't contribute okay so the amount
of load caused by each Rock in each
row okay I okay I don't exactly know
what you're saying but but you are
suggesting there's some kind of weighted
sum weighted sum
uh oh wait is some oh okay
oh okay so so for example in row
one for every weight or whatever you
have to multiply by 10 in row two you
have to multiply by
nine something like that okay
so let me let's Okay let me let me try
again the amount of load caused by a
single rounded rock is equal to the
number of rows from The Rock to the
South edge of the platform okay so you
count you basically count all zeros in
that
column including the row the rock is on
okay Cube shaped Rock don't contribute
to the load okay
equal to the number of rows is it n uh
number of rows or number of rows that
contains
zero you know this the of code is
really not the best puzzle you know this
got lots of English description problems
this this this white guy is got a
English
problems uh not totally logical okay so
in so let's just focus on the problem
including a row the rocky s so let's try
again the first
row one two three four five six
78 1 2 three 4 five 6 7 8 nine
10 one two three four five six seven
eight
n total load is the sum of the load cost
by all of the rounded
rocks
uh oh I I'm you know I'm having a
problem understanding understanding
this uh we focus on where focusing on
doing this problem okay not other
questions
today the top rocks at 250 so looks like
Noob knows what's going
on oh
five times
10 two oh no's got the answer so
it's so the number one is just 5 * 10 oh
so the number here is weight so okay I
got it oh I'm so
stupid so the number here is a chart the
number is just the weight you have to
multiply so for each row you just count
the number of zeros in it so the first
row is got five zeros five zeros * 10 is
50 okay the second uh row you got two
zeros 2 * 9 is you know
18 so by this way you
just that's why uh supposedly this
answer is 139 let's check I mean
136 exactly
fantastic thank
you okay so so it's just
wait oh so that's why he saying the
amount of load caused by a single
rounded
Rock okay so it's saying one each
zero has a
weight and the weight of that zero is oh
God it's so
stupid yeah so these numbers are the
weight and the way it's derived you know
it happens 3 10 9 8 7 it should be let's
just by spec because the second row
there are nine rows below it the third
row there are eight rows below it so
that's why the weight is eight the third
the fourth row there are seven rows
below it including itself so therefore
it's weight is seven then you know these
numbers are just weight so you just
multiply the number of zeros times the
weight and you get you get um the total
load okay
so in this case it's 136 okay I so we
now so far we understand the problem
okay TI the platform so that run rock or
Road North afterwards what is the total
load on the North support beam
okay now you see another tricky jargon
we didn't understand before the North
beams basically means the entire thing
it's not the first row so the north
support
beams is just the entire thing the the
whole thing is something called North
support beam okay something maybe we
missed you know we missed the
description uh oh yeah the north maybe
refers to the Santa Claus North
something like that
that okay so anyway so it looks like we
understand the problem so let's regroup
so you got a input like that you move
all the zeros to the to the north
then for each row you count of number of
zeros and you multiply by uh basically
the total number of rows minus the row
number the current row number so they
are total of 10 rows the current row
number starting count with zero so 10 -
0 is 10 so the weight is 10 you multiply
okay okay understand the problem I
understand the problem now so how do you
code
it okay so for the first problem is move
the zero thank you Noob Noob the first
problem is move the zeros
okay so ultimately you just want to
count
uh you know you just want to yeah
ultimately the problem is very simple
for each row you want to find the number
of zeros that's basically all that's a
gist that's a Essence okay once you got
that then the number of zeros multiply
by a number the number is mechanical
because it basically just row number
reversed that's a weight for you count
the number of zeros multiply by the
inverse of the row count the row number
then you got a number then you just sum
it okay so yeah so the ultimate problem
is count the number of zeros so but the
first part is that you need to move
zeros up North so how do you do this
programmatically uh let's
see H in interesting so this is some
kind of like you know if you have a
physical puzzle you just push it but if
you're going to do it programmatically
how do you do what how do you do
this so move zero
up you know of course we first you know
the easiest most simple way the naive
way the naive approach is
simply go through row by
row and for each row you check each zero
you check if the north side of the zero
is a DOT if it is you move the zero okay
then you can like you know you can
continue then you have to
repeat you can then repeat and repeat
until
there's no more
change this is the most Elementary so
basically first of all you create the
Matrix now you can do this by just uh
lines of string you know multiple lines
of a giant of a string or you can
convert it to
Matrix and use the column number and and
row number to determine the
neighborhood so which way is easier it
looks like Matrix is easier okay so you
convert this thing to
Matrix then to move zero you just check
you know if it's you know if it whatever
above it is
um uh is a DOT okay then you move so
that means you reset the Matrix then you
start
over or you can continue until you reach
the end entry then then start over you
have to repeat this until no more
changes are
made okay that's one
way uh now another way there's a trick
you can transpose The Matrix so that you
don't have to you know if you want to
check the north
neighbor you don't have to go to the
previous row you because if you
transpose The Matrix then all you have
to do is just move zero if there's a DOT
before it just move
it okay so yeah that's definitely
easier so you transpose The Matrix and
move if you move zero if whatever before
it on the left side is a
DOT
okay uh so much talking and no coding
this is my style okay analysis of
problem then code one
shot now it's already 50 minutes I don't
think I can do
it it will take another hour so anyway
so yeah so
you so is it absolutely true that you
should transpose Matrix first
yes okay now transpose The Matrix is a
solution so once you transpose so then
the problem becomes instead of moving
the zero to the north you just Mo move
all zero to the left which is much
easier because we are dealing row by row
so for each row you move all zero to the
left
okay but how do you code that um let's
see yeah well you can okay so for each
line you can split the string you know
suppose we transpose already so for each
line is a
string then you split the string by the
pound
sign okay
then then inside it you know then for
each list you move the zero if there's
one you move all zero to the left you
count number of zeros and you count
number of dots then you can construct a
new list where the left is all zero the
you know number of zeros and right is
number of dots okay then you put back
the the pound
sign yeah so the first step is just move
these zeros okay so transpose and yeah
we okay so so we got the algorithm
now you
transpose uh in fact uh yeah so you know
yeah you transpose then you move them
all the zeros to the
left yeah we yeah okay basically that's
a that's the
algorithm so once you do that once you
got that what's the next step then then
it's becomes trivial then you just count
number of zeros and multiply by the
reverse of the r number okay we got the
algorithm okay uh now start to code I
guess
got
sh okay so we got a today's you know
actually today's input we already copied
it before so here is today's input it
looks like
that okay so we are ready to code and uh
and today from past experience we should
really just code it quickly and don't
worry about you know fancy coding or
using patterns or whatever because that
you'll never
finish uh the the best way for a live
stream is just simply you know do
whatever you can to solve the problem
okay so but before we do anything yeah
so let's begin with this
um this input totally
input okay let's let's just do as we go
okay and we're going to take a break in
about 10 minutes okay
something uh input equals to got okay
so so that's input the wolam language
code I'm using wolam language mod so
where is
it uh wait something is
wrong
what
okay why is this not working
wait what what
uh okay this cut delete that okay so we
should be here okay run
it that just a string string input now
how do you turn it to to a matrix now do
we want to work with string or Matrix
yeah we want to make a matrix because
otherwise for a string it's harder to
transpose yeah okay let's turn it to the
Matrix okay
so string
split okay string split we're going to
split the
string uh okay so X
input and by default it will uh Do It um
split by y space okay so we got that
then you want to for each line you want
to turn it into a list okay uh of
characters okay so I believe the command
name is characters
check the
documentation wolm language
documentation
characters give a list of characters in
a string okay magnify
good okay so characters for example
let's try that do that that run
it so now a string becomes each one
becomes character so you want to call
this function for each of the input okay
uh
rows okay row string equals to
that okay and uh you want to for each
row string uh you want to map okay
map row string a list of rows and we
okay and and uh what do you want to map
uh you want to map the characters
function to it okay uh so this is Matrix
okay so this is actually
Matrix run a Cod let's see the
Matrix there it is okay now this is a
matrix we got this is the first row um
go anyway this is a matrix and each
entry each ENT H God each entry is a
character okay a string okay so we got
the Matrix and what uh and now transpose
okay uh
transpose completion transpose X
Matrix okay uh transposed
okay let's say Matrix new equals to that
okay now copy the whole code let's run
in wam language so it's like more
beautiful so you can see there it is
okay now let's magnify so we can kind of
see
better okay so output seven so output
can be
uh what
shift so that means output seven so we
want to do it in a okay there it is okay
so that's a matrix right uh and
transpose right output seven is already
transposed so that's X Matrix new okay X
Matrix
new
Fantastic so what's what's next so we
got a transpose now we just need to move
each each one of them okay move the zero
so let's pick a a
row uh let's pick uh let's see okay this
let's see this one so this one because
this one we got more things to do so
this row now what we want to do is for
any zero we if there's a dot in front we
want to move it to the left okay so for
example here's the input we we going to
just to you with this
input how do you do that so okay so move
to the um
left is Trivial pattern matching the
super power of patter magine
applies yeah good idea Noob Noob Noob so
we're going to move the zero to the the
left how do you do that pattern matching
okay so let's say uh
X so wait so what uh so what do you do
is okay you call replace all replace all
and the input is that and you want to
replace by certain pattern this pattern
will
[Music]
be um so this pattern will
be so the pattern will be something uh
string with a DOT and then something of
a string of zero now that's not zero
that's actually
o okay I got confused all this while
yeah that's a capital letter O so it's
not zero so o Capital so you want the
pattern such that let me show you the
pattern okay so zero or more three low
line means zero or more anything okay
and zero or more anything followed by
one dot followed by one zero then zero
or more anything okay so that's a
pattern so once you found that pattern
you want to change it to this Arrow so
you want to change it to so we need to
uh give a name to the zero or anything X
and Y okay let's say
front uh back okay uh head 10 head and
tail that's a common computer science
Jon head and tail okay so once you find
that pattern
you you replace it
by head is uh the same head
okay tail is the same tail but but here
you swap them
okay
okay so I think that works I think so do
you think so yes I think so and we can
try it
do
it okay so originally we got dot pound
do0 dot okay now pound zero dot dot
worked fantastic and
beautiful okay so you see p the power of
pattern matching if you're going to do
this in Python it'll take you a
day oh hasc than
hcal uh Maybe not hascal maybe they can
do the
same but you have to apply the pattern
multiple times correct so what we have
to do is uh we call replace
or you're getting a ahead of me Noob
Noob
fantastic uh replace or repeat it
something like that
um I forgot what's the name okay uh
check
wam tutorial pattern
matching okay so just go to wam Language
tutorial go to scroll down then on the
left pattern matching syntax transform
functions pattern syntax there okay we
want syntax transform functions there so
these are functions that allows you to
do this transformation so replace all
one of them there are several of them
so you got replace all right here then
you got replace repeated okay so what
this do is it will do replace or just
like before but it will repeat until no
more changes okay so that's uh that's
what we're going to do replace
all repeated completion wait what's the
name replace repeated okay not just
there it is okay so basically we want to
do the same thing except instead of
replace or just replace repeat it okay
now in this particular example it
doesn't do anything because it only
takes one step to move the zero so you
want try let's let's try it okay so
dot zero okay let's try that one so if
you use the replace all for example
you know this zero there are two dot
before it okay so if you try
that paste
run did it even work no it did not even
work what's going
ont pound dot do0 okay here the output
is do pound dot do zero no change
what something
what uh wait algorithm you know
pent we got we got stumped
uh all the happiness before is
mistaken okay so dot pound dot dot zero
oh not zero it's oh stupid this
this this stupid Advent of code
okay not zero it's O Okay so let's
let's make
sure okay so if you try that let's try
that
do it do it you see it
worked pound dot do zero now it becomes
pound do0 dot now if you do it
again you know with the output
above then you got do pound zero dot dot
you see so you have to repeat but now if
we do this replace repeat it you'll just
do it for you one
shot so the input
is pound dot do o oper is pound o dot
dot fantastic and
beautiful okay so we got it so that's
the that's the main thing we're going to
call okay uh and we want to do this to
all rows okay so very easy so all we
have to do is just match map okay so
let's do a
map
um wait so what oh in fact we in fact we
don't even need to map to each row
because by the power by the dent of
pattern matching we can simply match the
whole
Matrix you see this oh
fantastic took one hour to understand
the problem but now we making some
progress so replace repeated the whole
Matrix why do why would it work why
would it work
because uh let's see let's see whole
Matrix you know we transpose it right we
transpose it then we
um we transposed okay so why um so if we
met if we match the whole Matrix where
is the Matrix The Matrix is
here will it work yes why because you
know each row is not DOT and is not zero
so this will not match a row I mean I
mean it I mean it will this rule will
only
match when this rule matches it will
only be inside the row put it that way
okay so if we do this let's let's just
run it shift enter okay so you can see
all the zero has moved to the left
fantastic and beautiful you can visually
check all the zero has been
moved okay so now all you have to do is
transpose it back
okay trans uh transpose
and uh we use a add sign add sign is a
shortcut Syntax for the for the square
bracket it's like a prefix notation so
you don't have to go back you know go
over there and put the end bracket you
know so this is so we can do that okay
so try it do it so compare these to the
original input let's see let's compare
to the original input
okay
uh so is it true that all the zero has
been moved okay so this is hard to see
so let's TR
here all the move all the Z all the O
moved
up oh yeah we can compare actually
there's a example here so the first row
0 0 0 0 Z correct second second row 0
0 correct third row 0
0 0 0 correct okay so we got it correct
okay so close that so now all we have to
do
is um count the zeros okay
so yeah count the zeros so okay
so so this
line is move or o to
North okay now next we want to um count
the zeros okay so okay so you new
Matrix uh
what so this is the moved result
okay uh let's say they all
moved okay I got a uh wait where is oh
okay oh
God something okay so this is a new
result all we have to do is count count
each row count the number of zeros and
multiply by row number okay so we're
going to do a
map we're going to do a map okay map to
this thing okay uh Matrix and you know
that basically map to the row however we
when we map the row we need the index of
the
row because we because the index of the
row when you know they it serves as a
weight okay so but we want it reverse
but the gist is that we need the index
so we use map index
so map index map is a functional way of
doing a loop and map index is a
functional way of doing a loop when you
also need the index of each item okay so
you map you say map
index okay so you want to map to this
thing
Matrix uh and uh and what do you what is
what is a function you want to map okay
uh function write a function you want to
so X is the row okay so X is a row here
uh and you want to count the number of
zeros number of o in that row okay so
you just
count okay double check look up
documentation the count
function count gives the number of
elements in list okay imagine a pattern
again we are using a pattern so we want
count in x and the pattern is uh uh not
okay so capital
O Okay so once you count
then okay the map index require the
function needs two numbers okay uh let's
say VAR and index okay I believe that's
the order so let's look up map
index map index map a function to a
expression and the fun function is
given
uh part specification for each element a
second second argument okay so here is
the index okay it's
actually a least because it's positional
any anyway so you got a count you got
count multiply
by uh total total number of lines um
Okay so so you need total number of
rows um in this case it's just 10 1 2 3
4 5 6 yeah well it's 10 we know but in
our personal input it it's not 10 so we
need to some kind of count okay so total
number of rows we need to count total
number of
rows
um actually we
don't yeah we do yeah because because
you need to invert inverse the row the
you know the row number so you do need
to know the total number of rows okay so
you need to find total number of rows
okay uh what God what
happened okay so you go
here uh you go here you need to compute
the total number of
rows uh Matrix is a row count is there a
row count uh
no uh wait how do you just length
Okay rule count okay rule count equals
to X
Matrix uh
length okay okay so you got that you got
that so R count is the length of Matrix
that's right so now you go back down all
the way back here so you want to times
the weight so what is the weight the
weight
is the weight is something about the
total row count the minus the current
index
so
yeah this index is is actually position
okay
so so you need to get it the first
element okay so total row
count minus the index that is away okay
so you multiply that multiply by that
that's that's that's that okay so this
is a function this
function okay then you need to summon up
so weight so this
function returns a count then multiply
by weight now did we get the weight
right is there some off by one thing so
let's see
[Music]
10 so this is the first row so wfam
language is one based index so first row
is 10 uh so you need to plus one
something like that minus index plus one
okay
uh plus one
okay so this returns a number then you
got then it's a list of number then just
say total okay
total uh total at this thing okay I
think that's it so let's try that I
think that's it we get 136 okay now
let's try the whole code let's remove
things we don't
need uh
okay yeah so this are just sample code
we don't need let's move sample code to
here
okay I mean that's
the that just shows it's a testing code
okay
but but now we go back
here so in fact we make them whole line
one single line
because that is a natural way to do
things in wam language you you put them
things in a single
line kind of like that okay so let's see
yeah so copy all go to F
language paste it we should have 136
let's try
it zero oh
uh
okay something something syntax
something okay so why is
that so double check is all moved
correctly so what is the all move
that looks
good then then the map
index uh
what let's try the map
index uh y zero
well let's remove the count okay let's
just return
for
now XV XV is the row okay and then X
index okay let's see what is actually
doing yeah so X Val is zow then the
index is
that yeah so when
we so if we extract the
index yeah so we got the you know the
index
um so why why why is this function not
correct
um this
part uh R count did we get the r count
correctly let's see R count R count is
10 that's correct R count minus the
index
what uh what does count
return count returns a number
right let's try
it wait uh we don't even get a matrix
okay let's try
that yeah it returns a number count
returns a number so when you count
it oh yeah okay so we change it to XV so
this is uh variable name is incorrect
how idiotic okay X Val okay so now we
can kind of copy the whole
thing do it
over
beautiful okay now we're going to try
the real input okay uh make a backup put
it back color syntax it showing browser
here's today's code uh beautiful you
know the whole thing can be become one
single line because we made so many
redundant
variables like one single line no
variables at all zero uh but let's focus
on the problem so we get got to get our
input so let's try to get our user input
the user input is this huge text
okay uh okay we can try to read string
uh how long is this okay 100
lines let's not rest string you know
it let's just put the whole thing
here okay make it
easier you know because Advent of code
they never cares you know they never
care if you actually think a lot they
just care about what is the answer you
know like the C C++
idiot okay okay so we back go back to
wam language okay go back to wam
language paste it so we got this huge
input okay so huge input let's select
all select all paste okay so this huge
input then we okay so
let's Okay huge input then
we you know then just just this one
single line okay run
it what is the answer one one
339 okay let's copy that
copy back to emac go to the bottom paste
it okay that seems good go to Advent of
code my answer is that are you sure yes
I'm sure
submit that is the right answer
fantastic okay so that's 90 minutes
close to 90 minutes uh I hope you guys
like it
fantastic thank you Noob Noob uh monkey
says I'm in my first year of mathematics
fantastic undergraduate studies taking a
programming
elective okay that's good and uh do you
have any recommendations to S to succeed
in this course in future IND
Divas it's in
C oh taking a programming elective well
it depends on what exactly is your
question
[Music]
so so you are in your first year of math
undergraduate and also taking a
programming elective I suppose that's
kind of like secondary course and you
are saying that the language is C
right uh yeah but what what is exactly
is your question that's kind
of you know mention several things so
okay just in
general uh yeah study math good for you
that's also my that's my obsession
especially when I was younger uh
mathematics that's great
uh uh for the first two years of math
usually you don't really need
um I mean you don't really need
University I mean well it helps but you
know it's not really necessary
especially today I'm just giving you
some
random advice okay now if you have
specific say it right now we're going to
close in in three five
minutes so in general today because the
internet is so Advanced so much
educational videos you know mathematics
and website there's so many good ones
that you can learn calculs by yourself
if you are really into the you know your
interest your
Obsession in the subject matter is the
most fundamental
importance if you have no little
interest if you if you study math
because your mom told you to or your dad
then your chances of doing GR in that
subject is not good doesn't matter you
go to school or whatever you do okay so
the fundamental important is the
wheel like it like the way they say the
wheel the power of the wheel okay if you
have an interes in math you'll do good
okay so so going to University you know
it's it's okay yeah you have to pay
though maybe your parents pays for you
the expensive
but okay so you go to school study math
grade and you have the interest
grade so you are saying but you are also
taking a programming course on the side
now in the same way programming today
you don't need University at all
especially programming more so than
mathematics because programming is
actually just hand on you know you know
if you graduate from
University and you go to a real life job
you can't do much you know because
real life programming is very different
from uh industrial actual real world
programming
in school when you study programming
it's a lot is kind of a lot Concepts a
lot theories some Theory you know this
section called computer science
theoretical computer science you may not
study it much until you you if you major
in computer science then you will later
on
anyway for programming you you know it's
even less necessary to go to school in
fact for programming I would recommend
you do not study at school you need just
you know just code start to code like
this you know for example you know my my
YouTube video today we try this thing we
try to do this thing you know if you're
going to try to do this thing from a
computer you know like educated from
Academia you have no idea how to do this
okay like there's
no oh oh this is matrix multiplication
therefore you do it this way there's no
someone telling you what steps to take
you just have to do it yourself so so
anyway for programming learning
programming uh it's not necessary to go
to school in fact it's recommend that
you you just code you you just you just
have to code a lot okay doesn't matter
what language you program in with a
language or Mathematica I mean or python
or or others or c
read read the manual okay well C in the
case of C they don't have a manual they
don't have
actually supposed the a menu but there's
a lot online okay so read read you know
you know the documentation of that
language read a lot code a lot that's
how you succeed in programming okay so
uh yeah so I suppose that's my you know
um my recommendation you have a great
passion for math that's great
and Mathematics and programming they are
rather they are very different things
okay mathematics and computer
science I mean mathematics and
theoretical computer science they are
they have a lot to do with each other
okay a lot to do with each other but
still they are kind of separate okay
because anyway I'm not going to go into
detail so mathematics and theoretical
computer science
there's a lot connection okay
but but if you go to university taking a
class called computer science they don't
teach that much theoretical computer
science they teach you what is operating
system how does networking works like
the internet how does like generally how
does it work what is operating system
you know when your Windows or
Mac how how you know what made it work
uh they may may teach you some CPU uh
you know like Hardware something you
know Assembly Language so you learn a
bit of what is a database you learn or
you maybe how to do game
programming uh all those are not
theoretical computer science so so in
fact all those are not science at all
but but they do teach that you know when
you take a computer programming
major so anyway so but for actual
programming which is not computer
science okay like what we are doing
today this is not computer science uh
you just all you need you know you need
experience you need reading a lot
programming language manuals okay like
I've read you know I've read wolam
language manuals
for you know since 1990s cover to cover
1,000 pages so that's why I Know It uh
yeah so read manuals and code that's all
you have to
do uh to get to become very good at uh
for real life programming and real life
jobs you don't
need uh going into a school learning
what is algorithm or what is database
you don't really need you know I mean
not for practical
job okay that's it today thank you guys
for
watching so if you like my videos you
know go to
kinfo and you can pay me okay I
request payment okay you can pay patreon
me Amazon gift card me or PayPal cinfo
at the bottom page thank you guys bye
guys uh so we're going to clean up this
code um
and uh put it in the web so you guys can
you know if you're going to code this
you can look up and and study the
problem okay bye