hello guys welcome to another episode of
s talk show today we are going to do
Advent of code
2023 day five okay let's begin now I'm
going to try to be very focused the the
focus is to finish the code don't worry
about efficiency don't worry about the
best elegant code uh uh and I'm going to
code it in wufan language which by
default is going to be the shortest code
of all
languages okay except APL because in APL
every function is one single character
so if you count the shortest by number
of characters then nothing beats APL but
the more proper uh counting of shortest
code is you count the tokens so in AP
each function name is one single
character and uh but if you count tokens
that's one single
token and in wam language then usually
they have Long Function names 10 or 20
characters but now it's just one token
so if you count by tokens as the
shortest code then wam language will
beat APL it will be every language okay
uh but anyway I'm going to try to focus
on day five finish problem part one and
part two my keyboard this is kesis
advant uh kesis
360 USB version okay and this is a
ultimate hacking keyboard fantastic I
recommend it go to
my keyboard blog website you'll see
video reviews and uh full uh full review
okay so let's begin coding so let's
switch to the uh so focus on solving the
problem problem okay I'm just going to
demo wam language solving the problem
okay so let's begin so let's begin if
you are here say hi okay I love to see
your comments don't like just hide in
the background say nothing okay uh start
a code wait so the Ping window shows all
my command names and the function codes
in emac okay so you can see command
names and the keyboard shortcuts okay
I'm using a keyboard and I'm using SAR
fly Keys which is a model key winding
for emac okay let's begin wolam language
code pop it out so there it is um so
let's read problem Advent of code day
four let's start to uh read the problem
so day five day five not day four so go
back Adent code
day oh God uh four what the f is
is
2325 uh okay day five okay weird way of
arranging okay focus on solving it in
within two hours okay uh in my line you
could just pass functions to other
functions and return functions they are
also Anonymous functions that can pass
to or return functions yeah
what do you
mean of course in functional programming
languages you can always do that
functions return as a function as a
expression and uh you can pass that as
argument to other functions that's what
functional programming
means okay
so day four day five okay uh
okay
okay let's see if I can finish
it again I'm I'm going to try to finish
it so I'm going to skip reading and all
that um okay you take the you take the
boat and find the gner right there where
they told you would be
uh managing a giant Garden that looks
small to you like a farm you take the
boat and find the gardener right where
you were told he would be managing a
giant Garden that looks small to you
like a
farm okay a water source island island
is the Water Source you point out that
snow Island isn't receiving any
water oh we had to stop the water
because we ran out of sand to filter it
with can't make snow with dirty water
don't worry I'm sure we'll get more sand
soon we only turned off the water a few
days weeks oh no his face sinks into a
look of horrified
realization sure we get more sense
soon I've been so busy making sure
everyone here has food that I completely
forgot to check why we stopped getting
more more sand there's a ferry leaving
soon that is headed over in that
direction it's much faster than your
boat could you please go check it
out now you barely have time to agree to
this request when he brings up another
while you wait for your for the ferry
maybe you can help us with our food
production problem the latest island
island AMAC just arrived and we having
trouble making sense of it the AMAC your
puzzle input lists all of the seeds that
need to be
planted it also lists what type of soil
to use with each kind of
seed what type of fertilizer to use with
each kind of
soil what type of water to use with each
kind of
fertilizer and so on every type of seed
soil fertilizer and so
on is identified with a
number but numbers are reused by each
category that is solo one two 3 and
fertilizer one two 3 aren't necessarily
related to each other okay so you got
[Music]
um you got seed you got
fertilizer
you got soil and you got water uh in
what
order
seed then type of seed each type of seed
has a type of soil to go with each type
of soil has a ferti a type of fertilizer
to go with and each type of
fertilizer has a type of water to go
with it okay so it's a hierarchy it's a
tree beginning with many seeds type of
seeds
seeds soil
fertilizer water
okay so for example can you see the
puzel okay so you need to move this
here
okay for example seed okay so here is
your input probably let's copy
it okay so here is the input I guess so
for example seed 79 14 55
13 seed to O your
map 5098 to 5250
48 this is seed to oo
map
okay seed to o your to so your map now
you have seeds 79 14 55
13 so how do you make sense of this map
it's got many numbers that's not in the
seed
except
15982 none none of the numbers are in a
seed how does this map work I don't know
so you got the seed to soil map then you
got soil to fertilizer map okay strange
numbers uh then you got fertilizer to
water map okay a bunch of
numbers and the water to light map okay
it didn't mention light before in the
story so this water different water
needs different
light [ __ ] L land then you have light
to temperature map so you have this tree
hierarchy okay then you have temperature
to humid humidity map okay then you have
humidity to location map
okay the the almanac starts by listing
which seed needs to be planted seeds 79
14 55 13 the rest of the almanac
contains the list of maps which describe
how to convert number from a source
category into numbers in a destination
category right that's what map means
okay that is the section that starts
with seed to soil map describes how to
convert a seed number the source to a so
number the destination that's right okay
this lets the Gardner and his team know
which Soo to use with which seeds which
water to use with which fertilizer and
so on right obvious okay but but how do
you in interpret the map list of numbers
so rather than list every Source number
and its corresponding destination number
one by one the map describes entire
range of
numbers that can be converted okay so
this is a funky
map typically a map is like one two one
correspondence
clear but this one is a funky map so it
this range instead so each line within a
map each line within a map contains
three numbers
okay the destination range start the
source range start and the range
length Okay let's see so here is a map
so 50 is
the uh Des uh let's see the destination
range start the source range start so in
reverse
order at least it begin with destination
range start then the source range start
then the range length
so the destination range start which is
50 that means the so the so your
number begin with 5 to something and the
seed number begin with 98 to something
and the range is
two okay so that means 5 to
52 98
to to
so
okay
so so 50 to 52 this is a
soil 98 to 100 this is the
seed C to soo map okay very
strange uh consider again the example C2
oil map 50 58 I mean 50 998 2 then 52 50
48 Okay so so how do you interpret
interpret 5250 48 so that means the soil
begin with
58 then 48 of them okay 52
toh okay to something 100 that's a
soil then
the The Source the seed is 50 to
98 okay something like okay then it says
the first line has a destination range
start of 50 okay a source range start of
98 correct and the range length of two
this line means that the source range
start at 908 and contains two values 98
and 99
right and the destination range is the
same length but it starts at 50 so its
two values are 50 and 51
correct with this information you know
that seed number 98 correspond to soo
number
50 that's
right okay and that se number 99
correspond to soal number
yeah okay yeah so the second line means
that the source range start at 50 and
contains 48 values the this corespond to
destination range starting at 52 and
also contain 48 values c number
53 correspond to solal number 55 that's
correct okay so far yeah I understand it
any Source number that aren't mapped
corresponds to the same
destination
number okay so
if if a seed number is not in
this you know this C map defined by a
range then that seed number correspond
to itself the number in the soil okay
the seed number ID correspond to the
same ID in the
soo ID okay so if it's not there it's
the same number
okay understanding the problem any
Source number they AR ma okay yeah so so
seed number 10 correspond to so number
10 because the number 10 is not in this
map
okay so the entire list of C numbers and
their corresponding serial number is
like that yeah this is a traditional map
so seed and soil you know so we first
job is to convert this idiotic range map
to a standard
map okay so you can use you can do a
hash table on that or a list of
pairs so with this map you can look up
so your number required for each initial
seat number blah blah blah okay I assume
I understand it already the gner and his
team want to get started as soon as
possible so
they would like to know the closed
location the closest location that needs
a
seed what using these Maps find the
lowest location number that corresponds
to any of the initial
seats what where is the
location so we got C2 soil soil to
fertilizer fertilizer to water water to
light light to temperature oh
temperature to hum humidity then
humidity to
location okay so you are given a seed
number
ID you go through these Maps eventually
you'll get a
corresponding location
ID which is the number and it's
asking what is it asking
find the lowest location
number that corresponds to any of the
initial seeds Okay so in from a mathem
mathematician's point of view you say
that you want to find the
minimum so given a bunch of
seeds Each One automatically correspond
to number that is a location
number identify the smallest
one then the answer is that particular
seat with that
location yeah so the location implies
some kind of Mile like distance you know
they want the
nearest
okay
uh so the low lowest location number
that that corresponds to any of the
initial seats to do this you need to
convert each seat number through other
categories until you can find its
corresponding location number in this
example blah blah blah I can skip that
because I presume I already understand
it I don't need to double check it's
kind of tedious to double check each one
so the lowest location number in this
example is
35 okay so the answer is 35 so
okay now this time the input is not just
one single text file is kind of
this jumbo mess okay so you you just
hard code it yeah I can I suppose you
can so what is the lowest location
number that corresponds to any of the
initial C number okay problem understood
let's begin coding it let me read the
comments hi quent hi M hi theago s says
hello
Kasa hi M
says well you have two pair of glasses
okay one is near cited one is uh old age
magnifying reading glass okay
so it's already 20 minutes okay now I
understand the problem let's begin
coding so a bunch of maps so they are uh
you know I can just
manually trans trans transform this
bunch of numbers to the wolam language
hash
table uh no you cannot do it because
it's a range so you you need to do some
coding but anyway so the
input ah this stupid problem okay so how
do
you I mean you can pass the input I mean
but if you treat the input as a one just
one text file then you need to do a lot
passing as I said said the Advent of
code doesn't care you know they don't
care about Elegance or completeness they
just care about the answer so this so
the fastest way is
um let's
see
okay not to code
this so you want to convert this to some
sort of input basically hard coded
it and uh for example we can you know
say
this map one equals
to
actually there's two of them so each map
you
have
uh you have several range okay so you
have several range each map you have
several
range yeah what the [ __ ] idiotic well
I mean that's coding right that's that's
kind of that's what coding
means yeah but now the problem is naming
of things how do you name this so each
map you
have a list of
range so you you know one one one way
you can do is that
you you know since it's a Le range you
just do like that okay manually convert
the the
input um yeah maybe that's
it yeah this is a stupid um kind
of okay so first of all let's let's copy
the like text input so in this case the
text input is
actually I mean let's put the text input
into
a
it's just like you know copy it there
original input then we create our kind
of
um copy
that then we create our okay let's just
do it manually okay so map
one so actually would would be better if
you if you just have list of lists
okay
so seeds Okay let me just type it
quickly
okay e max
power
WR okay Define a
marrow
then apply the mar apply the
mar okay now let's we need to replace
Space by comma
space so we get wve from
Syntax for least
okay
okay there's too many let's do a regular
expression regular
expression okay we want
to we want to copy 0 to9
space
0 to9
okay that's between that's number space
number okay now replace that
by replace that
by the first occurrence the first
capture comma space the second capture
okay do
it yeah do it there [ __ ]
stupid okay
let's do it
again okay that's kind of our input but
wait there there more so yeah so
[Music]
we need to group these two
together
okay
we okay then you need the comma after
the last
bracket No No
Yes actually no
yes yes yes oh actually there's a
simpler way but anyway let's keep going
no no yes no no yes yes no no yes no no
yes okay so it's kind of this this is
the
[Music]
problem actually so we have
okay so let me show you the final
result the final result is like that
okay okay let's
clear Maps
okay that's kind of your map let's see
let's see if we got the input valid you
know we can just paste in wfam language
paste it evaluate correct the okay
there's a new so that you got a extra
comma here we language you cannot have
extra comma in a list you know in
JavaScript you can but in wolfan
language you cannot have the you know
extraneous
comma if you do then that
means you got a extra element of n okay
so anyway so let's let's double check
correct so we got this bunch of
maps
okay let's see let's see if
that's yeah that's
good so we got a bunch of maps now for
each one for example this is one of the
map you want to convert it into actual
map
so this is a kind of exercise in
constructing hash table so dictionary
and uh exercise of
sequentially get the value of hash table
okay are you an yo are you a what
hia okay so far so good so we so we got
one of the map like that defined by a
range now we want to convert this into
uh into a actual hash table into a
actual dictionary in wam language is
called
Association okay
so so given this input you want to turn
this
into um
okay
range two
so let's see for example this
one for example 52 you want to turn
it yeah tedious yeah there a problem is
just
tediousness uh that's coding exercise
so so
50 and let's see how we do this too so
begin
and yeah so you write a
function
that so
each each of
the each line is
a partial map so each one each line
defines a
partial
map what if they overlap that's a thing
you see that's a tricky thing when you
have a range and another range what if
they
overlap you see that's the tricky thing
of Advent of code you know in the actual
puzzle then
you'll pop up such a example so what if
you have overlap in the
range well in that case I presume the
second ones override the
previous no the question to Q intent
ACTA no okay so I mean the answer to Q
intent have you programmed ACTA okay
so so range so you 98 so two elements
how do you generate
this we need to we we just want to get
this done okay don't worry about
efficiency or anything
so a range of two elements
50 basically you want this okay
something like that okay let's
see uh actually 50 two elements so 50
and 51 minus you know you don't so you
actually need to minus one
here okay
so let's
see so let's work on one of the range
first
okay here is a
function the source and destination so
first of all the function
Source
uh the source is the second part so this
is this is a function notation for for
the second argument which is the 98
because we want to begin with Source
okay so the source map
to wait not map yet so so we start a
range so we want to call range and the
source will be
that okay then
arrange
then okay so wait
so then that plus two minus what well
plus two the two came from the third
argument there so here the p two should
[Music]
be the third argument okay second
argument plus the third argument then
minus one that is the range of the
source okay now for the range of the
destination it's similar okay so the the
dation is the first element and uh then
the first element okay plus the third
elements okay and also minus one okay so
here we got a explicit list of list of
numbers in the source okay and this one
is a explicit list of numbers in a
destination okay and so once we got
that let me show you okay so we just
make them into a list and let's do
transpose and now translate
transpose okay we we just going to
transpose this list so instead of one
row of ID and second row row of
ID we got we trans trans transpose it so
it
becomes each row
becomes a pair the first element is the
source ID the second El second element
is the destination ID okay so that's
what transpose that's like transpose of
a matrix okay so now this thing is a
function okay so this thing is a
function now this function we apply it
to the first range of numbers okay let's
see like that okay let me show
you okay so this
means you see this range of number 58 9
8 2 it means 98 Maps 250 99 map
okay
fantastic
now now we don't want now we now we want
to turn these pairs to rules so let me
do another
thing
okay let me show you so you'll
see yeah okay Capital rule is capital
okay so the rule thing is basically W
F's notation to specify a pair okay wait
uh
what Ru yeah
so okay so
actually so rule you have the left hand
side and right hand side it simply
specifies a pair okay meaning that the
left hand side transform to the right
hand side okay so what that's what this
rule function means in wam language in
other words wam language has a has a
syntax to specify one single
pair it needs not to be part of the
syntax of dictionary or part of the
syntax of hash table it has by itself a
syntax to
specify you know left hand side right
hand side a pair then if you have a list
of rules that means that becomes a hash
table basically okay that's what these
rules do so uh but but something is not
working
here
[Music]
because let's try it
again there it is so now you
see now you can see it shows the arrow
that means like a
pair Okay so so in a similar way we can
do this to the second uh range you know
the second is a lot more so let's try it
here copy and paste so you can see a
list of transformation pairs a map okay
so basically now we got the function to
apply to each of these range of rules
okay now we just apply them to all then
that's that get us uh
this many Maps as a hash
table okay
so let me
see okay so
actually
actually we don't need
to let's see if that works
no
okay
so we got list of pairs now is there a
simple way to turn this list of
pairs into Association without us
applying the rules let's see you see
once you got a bunch of list of rules
you need to turn that into a hash
table
um yeah
but uh yeah okay so we all you have to
do is
you okay
yeah okay like this okay
so uh where is our
code all right
copy paste this is our code run it so
now here is a actual hash table
okay so this so okay so we so this code
let's make it one line one one line
would be
incomprehensible see uh okay so let's
remove that remove that
okay so now we got this function that
turns a list of ranges into an actual
hash table now we just apply it to all
of these Maps
Okay let me show you the power of wol
language okay map you never seen you've
never seen in your life in any
programming language okay so map takes
two arguments or three so the first AR
argument is the function so here is our
function okay the function okay here is
our
function you see this function okay uh
maybe you don't understand let me let me
rewrite this codes into a form you
understand okay so
function X okay so let me rewrite this
code so you understand
okay so that's basically
it so function takes one argument X and
the function body is this thing so we
take X you know the argument the second
part then then the second part plus the
third part minus one you know get the
range get a range then transpose them so
you got pairs at Leist of pairs then you
replace the list of pairs by the
rule then you got this arrow thing
meaning a pair then you put Association
function to the whole thing then it
becomes actual hash table okay
so it's a simple way I mean over here so
this part and this part are equivalent
it just shorter you know the first part
is I'm using this cryptic shorter syntax
and the pound
side but okay so anyway so here's our
function map map this function to uh
list okay the list is Maps Okay uh we
which is you know this a bunch
of maps of maps Okay we want to map them
to uh
to to level two okay we want to map so
so we so the maps is a list of list of
list
okay so you kind of do you understand so
we want to map it to level two let me
just show you okay so
map there okay shortest code possible so
you see now you got what you got is all
the maps so we we got the list of hash
tables that's the first one then after
you map this then you got the
second second
Association okay then you got the third
one then you got the third one has like
two three range of maps you see three of
them the
third so this is the first part first
range of things this is the second range
of things this is the third range of
things and together that's a third
map you can see here you see that's a so
to
fertilizer and so on so now we got one a
whole bunch now there's one more thing
we need to do we need to merge this map
for example let's look at the first one
so the first one is got got the first
one is got two lists two
ranges okay so once we do the conversion
we got two
hash table two dictionary so this is
first one very short this is the second
one we we need to merge them okay so so
we all we have to do is just
um okay so let's do one more step okay
so you map
again what what
happened okay so you just map again now
this time you map you want to merge to
associations okay you you are given a
list of associations you want to merge
them into one single Association so from
list of hash table to one single hash
table okay let's do it uh but what is
the function I don't remember okay so uh
well look up the
W tutorial
okay ex Language tutorial
Association uh Define a function data
structure Association list okay then you
have get value add key delete by key
check by key existence associate
Association to list Association filter
miscellaneous
okay uh M to values applied to keys
functions that applies to Keys functions
operating on list of Association they
are key Union that's what you want key
Union so what this function do is that
taken two dictionaries it
will merge them into a single okay key
Union generate the list of associations
in which each Association has a union of
the keys of the association 1 2 3 4 and
so on padding by inserting values
missing if
necessary uh
what what do you mean missing is
necessary let's just try it okay let's
just try it uh for
example for example let's see the first
one is a overlap 98
there it is wait 98 99 no there's no
overlap okay let's try the second
one
99 then here is
97 there's no overlap 52
97 and 989 98 291 okay the second one
there's no
overlap you see now the third third one
so your fertilizer to map let's
see 15 to
51 52 to
53 then 0 to 14 oh no overlap it's
actually quite adjacent what a tricky
[ __ ]
let's see the third one I mean the the
the next
one so now it's fertilizer to water map
to
60 11 to 52 oh
adjacent then wait 11 to
52 then 0 to
there it is overlapped CP wait 026 no no
okay 0 to
six then 7 to 10 no overlap
amazing okay let's look at the next
one 18 to 24 25 to
94 oh amazing no
overlap
then next
one 17
to
uh
67 45 to
63 wait 77 to
99 45 to
63 64 to 280 amazing oh wait there it is
overlap you see It's Tricky [ __ ] I knew
it you see this one wait so this one
light to temperature
map you see you got a 77 to
then then 77 appears here again wait one
45 to
63 40 64 to
76 oh wait no
overlap okay oh interesting
uh no overlap okay so next one we want
to we want to double check this because
it's it's kind of actually it's not
important you know I can just actually
merge them but you know I want to double
check 68 okay no
overlap 56 to 92 93 to
96 okay actually there's no overlap all
but I want to merge them
anyway okay so we cannot there's no
example that we can use right
away but let's do
it uh what is
the
okay let's see what this
returns so here
is trying to see what it actually
returns key
Union
[Music]
uh wait it doesn't
merge key Union generate a list of
associations in which each
Association has a union of
keys right
oh okay it actually it make sure it
makes sure that every Association has
the same set of
keys yeah it makes sure yeah yeah that's
what it does okay that's not what we
want uh Union Union is what we want okay
let's try Union not key Union
okay actually I'm spending more time
than
necessary uh Union yeah you need to get
rid of
the
okay there it is so Union is the
function you want you Union you know you
want to merge
associations so in this case you yeah
you just do a map
okay map okay the first function is uh
let's put that there the first function
is
Union Union the whole
thing okay and okay let me write the way
it's easy to understand
okay this way it's easier to understand
the list is whatever output of that okay
so okay let me show you so we Define
this bunch of maps but now we
we merge them so it's more
proper okay let me show
you there it is
Union so now you see this list got how
many items basically 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 eight
basically the number of maps they are
all merged so you no longer have SE
separate
ranges so this one is for
example this one is 98 so they
don't it's not
sorted we can actually sort them but
anyway anyway I
think you guys know what I mean
I'm kind of getting too slow now it's 1
hour
[ __ ] too much
explanation
okay okay need to finish this
quickly okay here is kind of explanation
code uh
map 3 equals to that
okay and here is explanation code let's
put the explanation code
here that's for those of you learning
wam language
okay and uh so now and uh put that
explanation code
here
okay so now our function is very simple
okay let's see copy copy copy copy copy
okay now select
all paste so now this is our code entire
code okay now run
it so it just basically
output out put this huge Association
okay now I'm ready
to do the okay so now given a seed now
the problem is given a
seed given a SE 79 what is the final
Association number okay so what you do
is you you want to go through map three
so let's
see so you
got a list of Association so you use the
first
one so you want
[Music]
to you got a list of
dictionaries you have a number you want
to feed the number to the first
dictionary get a value then feed it to
the second dictionary get a value and
feed it to the third one get a value and
so on Okay
so so you can
use
reduce that's right in wfam language
that's called fold okay let's let me
show you okay so
fold in Python and JavaScript it's
called reduce okay so fold takes two
things a function and a list okay the
list is going to be map three okay which
is a list Le of associations the
function is going to be let's write one
okay let's write one okay function takes
X so the
function and also let's add another
argument 17 uh 79 to begin with
okay so what is the function the
function is so you take the function
will take two arguments so X and Y okay
and the first element is the X it's a
number you want to apply the association
so what you do is the Y is Association
you Association of
X so that X is the key that's
right yes you get a key so you want to
know
the value of a key in a Association so
the key is X the association is y then
you get a value for example let's try it
out okay
so for example 78 you know for example
79 okay then what is the association
let's see the first
one okay copy it
so you got Association here then
Association at
79 which should be 81 you see there's a
there it is it should be 80 81 so let's
evaluate
that okay you can see this part is
Association and this is the key you want
to know what value is that
oh
Fu this
works this syntax Works only if the keys
are strings okay but in our case the
keys are not strings so what you have to
do is you have to say
key
okay evaluated there it is at1
okay in wam language the key of
Association or dictionary or hash table
can be any
expression typically it's you know in
python
or JavaScript us usually it's a
string uh in some languages it could be
any object which is true for python I
believe but not for JavaScript I think
but anyway so in W from language then a
key can be any expression but if that's
the case then you need to say key
instead of just
um you need to say key 79 okay so anyway
that is the that is what this function
do
here okay
so so let's do it I believe that's it
we should get a bunch of of we we we
should get the final value for 79 going
through these Maps so let me double
check you have a key you use Association
second argument that returns a value and
that becomes a key again for the next
associate that's
right
evaluated [ __ ]
ah
[ __ ] oh okay so if the result is missing
that
means after you go through all these
Maps as soon as it's missing you see one
of the problem specification is that if
it's not there then simply
return the same the same ID so
we have to add a condition here so let's
you know don't as soon as you find a
missing the key is not in the
association you just return the same
value okay so that way okay we can do
that how do you do that well there is um
you see in the
association let's see Association get
value so we were using this syntax to
get a value but there's a better syntax
more clear is look up okay so when you
do lookup you call the lookup function
two arguments Association and the key
and you can supply a third argument
which is default that means if the key
is not there what that's the value you
get okay so let's use this syntax
instead of
this okay so let me show you so copy
that so instead of this complicated
thing let's put this here look up Y is
Association X is a
key and uh and the default value is X
okay it's not there just return X okay
so now we don't need this function
anymore so let's try this
again there it is
so somewhere in these dictionaries it
stopped you just end up with 84 so let's
check uh blah blah what does it say does
it say 84 what c79 Soo 81 ferti 81 water
81 light 74 temperature
78 h Community 78 location
82 okay we got something
wrong
what
71 Jesus
[ __ ]
God it's over an hour and we are
stuck C 79 Soo 81 let's
see this is a
list okay we am this
is let me try to sort
this if the see if that
works I want to sort by key okay no so
back key doesn't work you need to sort
Association
yeah
what
what's the what is a function to sort an
association uh so you check
miscellaneous key sort okay so you got
key
sort yeah okay so let's do key
sort okay so there it is now it's better
you know so 50 so this is the first MTH
you have 52
51 let's check the original
input
[Music]
52 wait you have 50 48 of
them which is kind of
98 97 97
98 then you have 90 8 two of them 98 to
99 that's right so let's apply a key
sort somewhere in our code so we get
better
understanding uh key sword
okay so let's just put here key sort
okay
there it is
now now you have to do
is do
this now
you see this
is oh you need to sort after you merge
them okay after you merge the range okay
so not
there so
[Music]
you Union then key SW okay let's apply
that let's see if that okay you need a
parent
okay actually do better this
way you see so the first thing is 50 to
99 there the second thing
is the second thing is
99 what the
same oh wait we got that repeated it
[ __ ] you
see our input that's we [ __ ]
up oh that's why we are
wrong you see we got
it let's see the
original yeah we got to repeat it
idiotic okay let's do it over again so
now we are better
equipped select all paste so this is our
whole code
evaluate so this is our first hash table
second hash table the first is 550 to
99 the second is 0 to
53 let's check 0 to 53 okay kind of
makes sense
yeah 12 13 14 15 16 yeah the third one
is okay it kind of works okay now let's
just get the code
to um I mean our actual
code okay so
that's what does seven 29 get you 882
let's go back
here 82
correct now what does 14 get
you
43 correct what does 55 get you let's
just map them one shot okay so we got
this function then we just this is
argument I'm just going to start start
to use shortcuts okay because that way
it's
faster uh okay map
to uh map to what seeds
Okay seeds or seeds seeds Okay
so 82 43 86
okay 882 43 86 35 82 check 43 check 86
check 35 check check check the [ __ ] of
you okay that's that's our
code H we don't need this this this is
for explanation put it here so our code
is basically we solved it and uh now
let's get
our only personal input oh my God now we
need to turn this
into
[ __ ] okay so let's go back here create a
new
file save it as X
Advent
203 day
four
text okay yeah and we need to pass it we
cannot there too
much to process manually okay
yeah okay copy that close it now the
input which is make a backup let's go
back
here showing B what sh Bowser so you see
this is what we have so far uh now show
the wam
code now let's we need to input okay
input equals
to something okay so here's a file path
input equals to read string
okay this is our personal input but
let's don't use that
for now let's use the his toy input copy
it okay so the input is
a yeah God we need to pass this okay we
can do
that greetings from Russia what are you
doing is very cool keep the good work
thank you I need those comments okay CU
I would appreciate those people who
actually are watching what I'm doing you
know doing this instead of the random
comments okay so there's a question rule
at at at let me explain that okay so in
wolam language when you when you when
you have let me explain okay when you
have X at X that is equivalent to F
bracket X okay now when you have x
x when you have something at at X that
means replace the head of X by F okay
let me show you
okay so for
example okay so that
means that
means that is equals
to
um that okay when you have double x
which is a shortcut for the function
apply essentially what effectively it
does is that it just replace the X by F
okay for example let's run
it you see now if you have F at at at
x what means what that means okay this
is getting complicated what that means
is that you
apply
uh same thing same thing like double X
double add add but you apply to the
Leist each element so it we it's is this
so for
example let's see x two for example this
will be this will
become okay so you see that's what at
add add means so let's evaluate
it you see so it becomes
that is it complicated not really you
know like you just have
to because it makes very good sense to
me you know one one add two add three
add so one add remember one add is just
a shortcut prefix Syntax for the ET to
add is a shortcut for the apply function
you can look up documentation apply 3x
is
the the shortcut for apply ad okay you
can see all of them now if you go to my
wam tutorial you can see the
entire this a list of the entire this
shortcut
abbreviations by searching for
tutorial
uh symbols principles full form syntax
there syntax okay I explain the whole
thing okay and so now you are here you
can just search for triple ad uh or you
can see here there you see so triple ad
is just the shortcut for apply but with
the option at level one that means you
apply not just at the function head but
you apply Lev okay very simple okay
anyway uh I need a break I need to go to
the bathroom yeah
[ __ ] because we are already 80 minutes
so we need to now the problem is to pass
this uh input yeah that can be easily
done let me let me let me try to quickly
do it
okay so first of all let's
get the input let me just show you what
we are doing I hope it today it's
although it takes a long time but it's
all clear so here is a input you know
it's just a text file right we we we
want to pass this
into into a list like that okay none of
the English wordy map fun okay so how do
you do it okay so let me do
it uh so input so
you string split okay uh first of all
you split
by what you want to split
by uh you want to split
by oh God this is the tedious
[ __ ] okay yeah but we have to do it
because otherwise uh you know the users
input actually I can manually transform
this to the
L actually it won't take too long
actually let's just do it okay let's
just do it manually [ __ ] the V of code
because you know let me complain this
let me make a complaint if you try to be
like logical you know do a good job you
know the input supposed to be it doesn't
say it doesn't say it's supposed to be a
string or not okay so but if you try to
be fair you know like in a programming
comp competition okay you are not
supposed to like manually you know fix
the input then run your code you're
supposed to you know assume the input is
a text file you do the passing okay then
then it runs so doesn't matter whatever
input as long as it's uh in the same
format your code works
but the thing about a vent is that it
doesn't care it doesn't say what's the
input or not all all it cares is what's
the answer okay
so so right now we are facing with a
choice we can write a pass you know it's
actually pretty trivial too but it's
tedious because you have to remove the
first line what that's a seed then you
pass by this map word you know to create
a this you know so but alternatively you
just you just [ __ ] grab this and with
the power of E emac you just turn this
whole thing into a wam language input
right let's just do that [ __ ] the at the
end of a code
okay [ __ ] I despise this sloppy
[ __ ] yeah so this this emx let's just
turn the the whole thing into the first
of all let's turn this um
you know we already did this before in
fact you know this uh sequence sequence
[Music]
into yeah so let's put a comma there
first okay let's do the whole thing do
it all okay don't ask
me do it all don't ask me questions okay
then for each one you just
need bracket that's a seed
okay then this this
one what is supposed to be
uh each line oh okay so it should be a
line so okay the emac power of keyboard
marro let me show you okay so start
record do that that
that and record then select this
thing apply
fantastic okay
then select this
apply wait what
wait select this apply to each line
fantastic okay SE is apply to each line
fantastic Factor R of
code okay do it still TD we can we can
make a mar of Marco
actually but let's just say simple now
okay so now you got all this okay so now
you yeah so you copy cut that this is
whole thing is a list okay let's record
Another Mar no let's not
cut okay fertilize my
S temperature my
S
okay let's double check there's no
syntax zos okay and this part add
bracket add a bracket okay so in
fact double check it's double check we
correct make sure no syntax error that's
right that's right remove that that's
right remove that that's right okay now
we just put the whole thing into a
list
okay okay now the whole thing is a list
okay that's right go down here oh then
then you need a comma there okay comma
comma comma comma comma
comma okay so that's it cut the whole
thing and do back
to my wam
code and uh oh yeah the maps Okay
so Maps equals to that
okay so
basically that's it let's try it
again okay we have new
seed it's
uh so we got the Maps no that's the old
Maps so this is a new so the new is that
that that that that that that
okay copy let's see if we got the
syntax Arrow
not select all
paste and
uh
evaluate fantastic fastic so we got
seats we got Maps bunch of maps maps
maps and here's the
output which is correct syntax is there
any new in it because if there's a new
that means we got extra comma or missing
comma or something no there's no rule so
we there it is okay now here's our
solution copy that paste paste paste do
it why is it taking
so
okay
[ __ ] okay [ __ ] it's pretty bad so what
happened is that when I started to run
that wolam code the wolam code probably
something wrong so it Aid up all the mem
and my computer
froze so it ate up all the memory and I
have I have problems bringing up the
test manager it basically first my
computer eventually I was able to [ __ ]
the
computation uh but apparently it also
[ __ ] up the OBS so OBS stopped
streaming the
video
uh
yeah so and but I didn't know the video
is not back I thought everything is
still
going so okay so everything is good now
[ __ ] so what I'm trying to do I just
restart wam language and I'm double
checking my input you know we manually
crafted the input you know
the the input is supposed to be this you
know text file but we manually try to
convert it to the wolam language
syntax like
so uh but possibly there's some syntax
error you know some structure error the
syntax is still valid but however I'm
missing missing
a uh cly brais or something that is why
wam
language you know the code got the wrong
structure so maybe that is why it's
eating all the memory so right now I'm
double checking if
our you know the input is correct so I'm
checking you know this is our input the
length is seven that's correct because
it correspond to seven of
these input dictionary hash table and we
double check so we can use Shadow I mean
shallow
level four depth level four to see all
the triples each triple is a
range so it seems all correct okay so
now we can try our code again and hope
that it doesn't uh
crash you know it seems correct to me it
seems correct
okay let's let's do this okay so
copy the seed away let's put the seed
here let's
redo the toy input okay so that is a toy
input and uh let's
say let's see the to input yeah it's all
three that's
correct okay so the toy input and also
solution our solution is this just this
three lines of code we have not tried to
shorten it yet but it can be just one
single line but let's
see
what oh there's a solution 8
A2 A2 43 A6
35 he 2 4 38635 that's correct so it
works on the toy input now we just need
to try the real input okay so oh
[Music]
maybe this shouldn't you know use up
gigabytes of
memory uh so I don't know what is going
on really so now let's try the real
input okay so the real input is let's
see
seeds so that's a total input so here is
a real
input and uh we can actually copy the
whole
thing okay let's just select all let's
open a new
window paste it
increase the font double
check so this is the beginning of our
real input and
Maps Okay then just run the whole thing
and let's hope it doesn't crash if it
does that's not good because we going to
stuck for another 10 minutes or
so
but it shouldn't
okay I don't know why it was crashing
before you
shouldn't run
it okay let's go back to
monitor
memory okay it's sucking up memory not
something
is a video
back okay
so n Berry hey nber do I know you looks
like you are someone I
know okay so but is my voice all the all
this while going so what happened so do
you guys know what's wrong what happened
is
that each of these three
numbers no the problem is not about
missing comma there's no no there's no
missing comma the problem is that each
of these three numbers represent a range
of values so but there are hugee number
of them for example this one there are
124 millions of it you know the second
range this there's 1005 millions of it
the third one is
278 Millions so for each one of these we
are creating an array in fact we are
creating two arrays each one is you know
these few millions of entries then there
are hundred of the so obviously that's
memory is going to mapped out so that is
a problem the problem is that we do not
want to literally create
a uh
dictionary instead we
should for each of these three numbers
that specify a range we should just turn
these three numbers
into uh two pairs of pairs
four numbers total so the number will be
the beginning and end of the
source ID and the beginning and end of
the destination ID okay so once we are
given an
ID all we have to do is we check if it's
in the range of source ID if it is then
we find out what number it is in a
destination ID just by the count in the
index so that is that is um that is how
so instead of a hash table we use just
that you know beginning and end of the
range uh and uh so it's a tricky problem
kind
of yeah yeah I didn't you know you
should have thought of how large this
number is you know few hundred millions
but now I'm getting tired it's over 2
hours so to solve this it's still easy I
mean it's still take another 20 minutes
10 you know ideally it'll take just five
minutes but when you actually do it
maybe 10 or 20 minutes but I'm tired so
I think that's it for
today so far do you guys understand what
I'm
saying you know what was what was the
problem why is it the memory crash
it's all
understood so we just we just need to
change this
algorithm okay so but I think that's it
for today you know we tried we didn't we
didn't get it okay that's all right uh
I'll finish it offline then yeah then
tomorrow maybe day six we're just going
to push on okay so thank you guys for
watching that's it for today okay bye
guys so let's see what is uh is there
anything going on in Discord
some okay bye guys