good morning good morning good morning
welcome to another episode of Santa's
Show today is July 6th 2019 noon twelve
o'clock five minutes after and
California time so today we are going to
talk about some random updates computer
programming related and stuff so let me
get things ready okay so I'm alive yes
good so let's let's begin let's talk
about some some of the interesting
things so let's talk about it's not talk
show okay let me mention this book I
happen to be working on this you know my
page about math books so here are some
of the great greatest math books I
recommend now these are these are
introduction to mathematics for amateur
you know for no mathematicians for for
beginners basically you know there are
there are a lot math popular rage
popularization books they talk about
math but they are not really about the
real mathematics but over here these
books I introduced are Bo mathematics so
as especially if you are a programmer
it's a good to study then so one of them
is this book groups and they're grabs by
Israel Grossman and will hem Magnus they
are they were famous mathematicians they
I think they both had passed away like
few decades ago anyway so this this is a
book where I learned group Theory back
in 1990
for something like that 97 maybe so I
highly recommended
its introduction you know it teach
teaches you about group theory so that's
the interesting book then the the other
interesting book is introduction to
graph theory now if you are a programmer
you probably would be more interested in
graph theory group Theory doesn't really
have much applications in computer
science but it's such a fundamental
topic of math groups group theory is
part of algebra you know odd you know
modern algebra or sometimes called
abstract algebra group theory is
fundamental to it it you know it's the
most essential part so if you are into
math you want to pick up some math you
know real math you know you read this
book oh if you are you know graph theory
is also great pure math but it has a lot
operations in programming so if you are
Emma maybe you are interesting in this
book introduction to graph theory so
those are great books and actually let
me you know paste the link here so you
can you guys can see it and it's just
paste it here
[Applause]
so if you have any comments questions
any opinions so you know just post it
type it okay why is that
alright it okay never mind anyway so so
those are interesting math books they
are others but you know let's not go
over you know the you know you could
read it the page yourself because we're
gonna talk about a lot other things so
I'm going to talk about so let's go to
my website sorry dot info there's
something interesting about keyboard
this this thing we talked about
yesterday
for our so there is this interesting
keyboard this is lime lime forty
keyboard it is a do-it-yourself keyboard
from made by Japanese people the focus
of this keyboard is that you see there's
a video here
so so basically they designed this
keyboard so that the thumb keys to them
according to them they designed this for
small hands so if you are Asian or
Japanese or Chinese you know you know
South Asian this might be good for you
but I cannot imagine how this is good
because to me it looks like the thumb
keys you know it's like it's like you
have to you have to you know you have to
particularly put your thumb under like
you know so I'm not sure it's that good
I don't know you know I haven't tried it
but anyway so that's an interesting
keyboard from made by Japanese
do-it-yourself
keyboard now I don't think they have a
website otherwise you know I just like
some of these is so nude you know they
just post it on their Twitter that's
where I got you know these pictures so I
I'm not sure there's a website you can
go through in you know and see the
Specht of the parts where you can buy
and build it yourself so I don't know
anyway you can check it out so let's so
that's about keyboard then there is
let's go back to my website let's talk
about some of the other things so there
is the Egyptian Egyptian hieroglyph this
is really fascinating Egyptian
hieroglyph IRA guys there are so many of
them and they are intricate you know
they are pictographs you see this this
picture shows a guy being bound okay
that's that's a guy being you know bound
you know when you look at this when you
look at these ancient languages you know
their writing systems when you look at
anything agent from it you can infer you
know what
people are doing you know something
about human animals you know back in
2000 or 3000 years ago so you see this
Egyptian hieroglyph then you have these
so apparently this is a guy bound you
know so that you know that's a common
thing you know you bind people because
you know for many reasons you know the
the point here is that apparently you
know that is a common thing so it's
Egyptian hieroglyphs there are so many
of them for example this page is this
this on a second kind of so this page
just like go on you know they are like
so how many characters are there you
know all these spurts these how do you
call this spurt upper curse or something
anyone know type it so let's open the
page let's open the page let's go back
here let's make it link then go back
here they open the page so so this is
the Emacs you know my editor and for
some sad reason you know the characters
does not showing Emacs I have to do some
configuration that's a pain you know
that's one of the issue with Emacs you
have to spend a lot of time to configure
it yourself so you have cranes good
morning FMS so Egyptian hieroglyph so
this did it's fascinating you see so
yeah I was we are going to do how many
characters how many of these Egyptian
hieroglyphs are there so let's do a
count how many there's a command in
Emacs Emacs called how many you just
type the expression so there are a
thousand and seventy three of them in
Unicode at least so you see all these
sports hours this
looks like a eagle hours and this
peacock some kind of peacock but and yet
you see this Cobra then you have Korean
eating of fish you have crocodile
crocodile you have toad or frog you have
these what is is and you have this what
is is snail with a antenna so yeah you
know and puffy fish so it's and these
are Egyptian hieroglyph very very
interesting and these apparently some
kind of digits you know this is one two
three four five six seven eight nine and
there are several set of them like you
know if I you know if you look around
you'll see several set of apparently
digits for example for example you have
then this one two three four five and
and and more and also here one two three
four so you know so that's that's just
interesting so so let me see
and yesterday I this I found you know
like you have to look at them like each
one of them carefully to see what they
are like they are you know there are a
thousand a thousands of them and this
one is apparently a woman giving birth
and this is breast feeding and look at
this one you know you don't know what
the [ __ ] is this one here over here so
you look at them you know then you
discovered the interesting things so for
example this we
and woman giving birth and breastfeeding
so you can see you know it's common you
know like in modern society you forgot
you don't see it you know you don't see
breastfeeding except maybe you don't
even you know I was going to say me
being your family but you know the more
modern like affluent in a city you know
you don't see it maybe in rural
societies you know maybe if you live in
a podunk town then you see your your
aunt or whatever you know your family
your mom feeling yeah feeding your
brothers or sisters maybe but you know
you know modern society basically you
don't you don't see these kind of things
women woman giving birth but think about
it it's you know it's like it's so
natural it's fundamental it's you know
it's this is this is the you know basics
of human humanity human animals by the
way the so so you know Egyptian
hieroglyph you know so I'm just talking
about this random interesting things and
they have they also have animal
characters so you see these all kind of
pools and arcs and you see this is a
antelope feeding you know breast breast
feeding her young and pigs cat dog dogs
and you know giraffe antelope goat
elephant hippopotamus lion or cougar or
you know what is this rabbit
so that's interesting by the way so the
other day I found something interesting
so hi guys any any opinions comments
just type it okay anything happening you
know it's good so actually let me show
you
I discovered this interesting thing what
the English so let's go to my English
blog literature blog kind of so so I was
wondering why do human cook you know
because you know what like you know I
wonder why human animals cook how can
how we are not like cats just eat raw
you know that seems convenient you know
you know cats you know you seek as they
can just eat raw so why can't why Cannot
we do it you know it would be nice you
know I mean one of the question is can
we do it can we do actually do it can we
you know can you just start to eat
things raw you know meat you know cows
and you know eat them raw so that's an
interesting question
so so apparently this human cooking it
began like a million a few million a
million or two million years ago and you
know we have evidence of stoves
basically like a medium ago you know we
have you know because you know evidence
of stoves a medium ago but it's
supposedly you know we we began is a
Amelio to two million years ago so that
is you know why I don't this that's
incredible because I always thought yeah
so so because I always thought that
human animals you know I you know as if
you watch my videos or my writings you
will often see that I use the phrase
human animals often you know too hot
most to most people they would think you
you are strange you are [ __ ] strange
what do you mean human animals what's
the deal with that word and I explained
this a few times you know I use the term
human animals because in my view there
is no difference between any other
animal
there is no distinction there is no
distinguishing qualities not really
between human animals and other animals
you know like when you read you know
literature or the faces like they say
humanity or how humans are different
because intelligence or some you know if
you ask religious people we are
different because God created us you
know and you know so there are many
different reasons and and in fact it's
normal that most people they would say
you know they would say human you know
they wouldn't they would make a
distinction like we are not animals like
you you guys are animals cats you know
cats dogs horse or whatever elephants
you are and most we are not animals okay
we are different because these are that
so I never you know to me I never bought
any of that you know it's just stupid
it's it's like you know it's you know
it's it's it's it's not scientific so I
was thinking scientifically there is no
distinguishing qualities for example
people say well human are more
intelligent not really well
yes maybe we are more intelligent but
you know octopus crows they are they are
highly intelligent and yeah but we you
you know you can say that we are more
intelligent therefore we are different
but when you when you make a distinction
of things you have to you have to give a
criteria like so so why do you pick this
particular criteria to set us apart from
other animals for example you could say
Lions Lions are actually different from
all other animals
curse why because lions you know they
they've got they look yellow they got a
tail they got this Mane or the other
cats don't have you know so almost
everything you know you can say it's
different from all other animals like I
can say sorry I'm I'm different from all
other human animals because first of all
my name is Chris ah you know you
wouldn't find other animals that has
that name and also because I look like
this you know you wouldn't find another
guy looks like this so what so that
doesn't mean anything you know that
doesn't make sense anymore to say
something it's different from another
you know you you have to you know give
out the criteria what is your
distinguishing criteria so when you say
human animals are different from others
you know I don't to me at all doesn't
does not make sense you know you know if
you don't believe in religion or God you
know then you don't you know but until
and until I found this thing I found
this I discovered is like last week so
we cook you know we are different
actually we are different from all other
animals you know because you could say
scientifically because we cook you know
you will not find any other animals that
cook and you know so I started you know
I so because I put you know and then you
started to see some other articles did
you know there are articles on website
that discuss these and they say you know
some scientists believe they actually
say that you know human animals are
different the distinguishing qualities
because we cook now so what what what
does you know what does it make cooking
different you know it makes a big
difference because when you when you
cook it changes your changes or our
things
you know so we began these cooking a
million years ago so what does it mean
cooking
basically means a control you know being
able to control fire so we apparently
disk
you know we discovered how to control
fire then we started to cook but why do
we cook is because apparently when you
cook when you cook meat you know when
you eat cooked meat all the nutrients
becomes easier to digest and also it's
easier it's faster to eat them so for
example if you cook for example you you
just killed a cow you know you killed a
cow let's say a bull you know if you
cook then the same car we will ask you
for a month and for example or the
nutrient and all that but if you don't
cook they don't last for months
they last maybe for a week so the
cooking you know cooking you know after
you cook the meats the nutrients it so
happens that you can't adjust them
easily absorb they're more easy
something like that so therefore we cook
and and because it's sufficient because
it saves you time to you know hunt and
and you get more nutrition you know you
got no more energy so that makes so so
that what is my point I didn't want to
drag on about this but anyway so I did
this is a great discovery so what's
what's the point so why is cooking what
so so it seems since we started cooking
it changed our behaviors you know
significant country we got more
nutrition we got everything we saved
energy and we oh yeah we then we
developed brain our brain size started
to grow you know different from other
animals because I forgot what's the
reason but anyway then then we started
to have a aquaculture and stuff anyway
so I thought this is interesting so so
now this actually changed my mind so I
can no longer say you know I
to emphasize you know I use a phrased
humor animals because because first of
all I do not see any difference between
human animals and other animals secondly
I like to emphasize the scientific
perspective you know I don't like the
God religious perspective so you know
you could do you you know you could you
could just say humans but I put em on
animals after that to emphasize the the
scientific perspective and also kind of
like snub the religious you know kind of
they are their perspective and so so not
just humans but human animals but now
let have having learned about this you
know I think maybe it's time to change
that because you cannot I cannot
actually say human animals and think
that you know because I don't I'd no
longer think that there's no difference
between animals and human animals there
is a difference because we cook the I
mean it's significant you know I I fail
to explain why but I kind of my brain is
mushy right now
but anyway that that that is very
interesting so let's see four people
five people watching so okay human
animals and so what else let's go back
to let's see what other things we let's
talk about okay so so that's that's my
blog and what is is hero guys and let's
go to my website so let's go to my
website and that's keyboard programming
so it cheap Shin Hyeok life then there
is okay then that's it about that some
other interesting things about Unicode
here's another interesting thing about
Unicode you have this
linear be okay how long have I been
talking so five minutes I got a lot of
things to talk about anyway so linear B
is another Asian script so linear be
linear P was used for writing machine
Ian Greek about 1450 PC so that is three
point five thousand years ago it is
descended from the older linear a
undeciphered earlier script so you got
this linear B characters then you got
these linear a characters they are like
three 3,000 or 4,000 years ago so linear
a is still not deciphered you know
meaning that we don't know what it means
and you look at them you also find you
know just like the Egyptian hieroglyph
you find interesting factors for example
this one this looks like you know I was
mentioning you know this one is probably
a head of a bull or something so I was
talking about it
Egyptian hieroglyph you know you have
these different animals and today we
have you know we have emojis you know
like emojis you also have animals you
know you also have all these different
animals but but you know the interesting
thing is that they already in the
Egyptian hieroglyph you know so
so anyway so linear P then then you know
yesterday you know a few days ago I
discussed in Linear B you also have this
antelope this raining do antelope some
kind of an horse so this is like three
thousand years ago and but youyou found
this one this one this where is it this
character linear b ideogram p 162
garment so this this pictograph is
apparently is a garment
it's red it represents a garment and
this one is a armor so you can see that
you know this is how you take history so
you can see so you know they have they
have the concept you know they
apparently they have armor packing 3,000
or 4,000 years ago
you know you'll be interesting to learn
about these asian texts you know but we
got a lot of things to do you know
modern society you are busy with so many
things and then look at this this one
this one looks like a dick you know what
else could it be
and what the hell is this and by the way
also and and what is this and also in
egyptian hero life you have a character
like you have these penis characters but
by the way microsoft censors this
character you know in modern society we
have this crap you know like let me show
you okay so okay yeah so you have these
stick pictures but you know are
microsoft we
those if you view this page on Microsoft
Windows you will not see these
characters they are just blanks like
blank squares so you know it's
censorship you know it's amazing this
day you know at this stage of age you
want to censor that because you know
doesn't make sense anymore you know this
is Asian good morning for your Panora
but know it come on in Joe good morning
Boyer thanks for your amazing Emax
package thank you which one shall I kiss
thank you for that I you know I'm glad
always glad to hear about them so if you
have any questions by Emax feel free to
ask so so which package are you were you
happy using so it so yeah so unicode you
know interesting Unicode characters yeah
so I was saying it would be interesting
to study them you know Asian languages
but then you know you don't have time
you know you have so many things to
study computer science or math each one
of them can take you ten years and ten
years is not enough then if you want to
study linguistics you know there are
hundreds of you know languages then you
know it's a it's a deep hole so anyway
so let's talk about so let's go to the
next topic I want to talk about there's
this web dead you know I'm I'm holding
I'm hoping to I want to do a JavaScript
coding session where so so next topic
okay so let me just go through them one
by one this is web dev
there is a topic where oh wow you only
started I mean you just started DMX two
months ago and stuff like he's you are
using great thank you
yeah so you know i i've been using Emacs
for 20 years now and you know eyes so
new people are coming you know to use
Emacs but i kind of forgot you know it's
like even there for a long time you know
you you forgot there are new people
coming to use Emacs okay so anyway so
there's this thing i want to talk about
which is about where is it
programming let's see
programming web dev oh frame HTML
frameset okay this is interesting two
things to talk about so so so let me let
me begin so there is this you know if
you do a web dev or if you are familiar
with HTML there is this thing called
HTML friend set let me show you what it
is okay now it is your used by
JavaScript Java Docs so let's show
example of HTML frame set so you go to
Chavez Java documentation
you know the Java doc it's so so anyway
so so this is a frame set this is a
frame so what is a frame set it's
basically just HTML tags you can use in
HTML and it will create a interface like
this like panel like let me magnify so
you got this navigation panel you see
the the navigation panel on the side you
can click on a topic and you see you
know and you can also adjust let me
magnify you can also adjust the width
width of the panel in you know also
vertically or horizontally if you want
let's go to let's say Emacs packages you
know whatever you pick a topic so so
this is HTML this is called HTML frame
set and it's extremely useful it's very
useful you know because you pick a topic
on the left and you can you know then
the panel shows on the right and this
began it was invented by Netscape I
think it began in 1996 at least 1996 and
it's widely popular its until maybe
until around 2006 or 2007 it start
disappear why because because there is
this user interface guru you know he
wrote an article about how frameset is
harmful you know it's it's humph oh it's
no good so so basically he's opinion
about you know the reason let me show
you why let me show you the article why
HTML FEM said is deprecated it's
absolute okay let's see that okay that
yeah so you can see some of the Stack
Overflow articles about here so this guy
he wrote a article
starting in 1996 this this article he
criticized friend said friends okay he
said because you know he gave a few
reasons but but basically the two major
reason is that when you have a friend
set you cannot you know it's difficult
to bookmark the page you know for
example I'm looking at this page and I
want to bookmark it but I cannot really
and this not in you know you know days
because if if I bookmark the page you
know the URL the URL points to this
friend set page it does not actually
point through this one this particular
you know point in the frame said for
example I open a new tab I paste the URL
and enter you know you you you just go
to the beginning of the frameset page so
his point about 1y frameset sucks
is that one it destroys the bookmark
expectation you know the bookmark you
know the URL basically no longer works
you know it changed changes the meaning
of URL that's one of these reason and
the other reason is the unit of a
navigation way anyway so that's kind of
the primary reason you know the URL no
longer works you know you can you can
read the article for ease of the reasons
but but the thing is you know frameset
is extremely useful it you know to you
know so so starting so he he wrote this
article in 1996 but a lot of people you
know it doesn't have it did not have
practical effect back then because frame
said is truly one you know one of the
most useful things you know like you
know you have the navigation panels
everyone need you know to do so everyone
was using it you know back in you know
from 1996 to 2006 let's say a huge
amount of page you know have frame set
but they began to disappear when you
know HTML you know especially when html5
began because html5 so this the reason
is that basically they gave the reason
same as this guy basically came from
this guy this guy is actually three guys
Nelson Norman goof you can find their
names on Wikipedia you know how they
came to be they they came you know
anyway so so the html5 the reason given
for to absolute the frame set is that
they basically the same reason as this
guy said so they they they make it
absolute you know basically in html5 you
you are not supposed to use it and they
say they created a new thing called
iframe
let me show you what the iframe is HTML
iframe which is kind of the say me but
not really
iframe allows you to embed a HTML page
inside another HTML page so so many
people say that iframe can totally
replace the functionality of frameset
without all the drawbacks of the
frameset but it's actually not true you
know they you know people think today
with javascript you know CSS iframe and
javascript
you don't need friend set anymore
because because CSS iframe and
javascript they totally replace the
functionality of frame set but not
that's not true that not that's not true
at all but because if you look at all
the web today for example if you look at
let's go to javascript in depth okay
because for it for example i have been
trying to do the frame set you know with
CSS and javascript i tried so many ways
with iframe you know you know this tag
there's no way i cannot come up with
anything that's that that it has the
functionality of the HTML friend set so
yeah so let me show you so for example
let's see let's let's let's let's go to
an example let's say javascript
javascript iterator
okay let's it's just go to go to the the
Mozilla website you know so here's the
example
hold on a second let me do this let's go
to the Mozilla website and let's also go
to the w3 schools website which is you
know very popular so you can see the
Mozilla website they also have a panel
on the left you see a navigation panel
they don't use frameset you know all the
modern website
they don't use frameset and you look at
the w33 schools webpage they also have
you know navigation panels on the side
so so you see and they are not using
frameset neither and same thing we
thought was Mozilla website but you can
see there's a problem let me show you
what is a problem so here's a friend
said you know Javadoc fame said you go
to a page let's say I want to go to you
know Java is extremely complicated let's
say let's let's go
actually let's go to Java land ok go to
Java land then let's go down here let's
go to string builder let's see let's say
go to string ok so we are in Java line
panel and we let's go to a stream so
this page describes the string in Java
language ok so now okay so after you
read with that let's go to stream buffer
which is a different type you see so you
can see it's smooth you know that this
panel doesn't jump around it doesn't
jump up flash then you can scroll up and
down then you can pick another one let's
say system okay that's frame set now
let's try the you know modern you know
so-called modern CSS and and an iframe
and JavaScript ok so this website
w3schools
so you pick a page let's say you know
you scroll down you let's say you go to
dumb intro now watch the left panel you
see how they they flash and regenerate
that's very annoying that's confusing
you see let me try another one let's go
down let's go to navigator ok you see
that's no good that's you know that's
the behavior you don't want you know the
beat and and by the way in order to do
that in order to create user interface
you know like the frame said such that
when you click something the the the
navigation panel stays in this scroll
position it doesn't begin you know back
at the top in order to do that you know
for the navigation panel to stay the
position you have to use JavaScript
that's that's one of the first problem
you know you you have to use JavaScript
if for example in this this w3schools
page if I go to Firefox and and view it
I have JavaScript off here and you can
see if I go down I click on the Dom
intro you see the Left panel no longer
stays at where I you know I just clicked
I have to try to find where I was you
know that that's a major problem you see
I have to scroll again try to find where
I was let's see you know like yeah I was
here Dom intro and so now let's go to
you know JS browse the boom JS window
let's click there you see the left panel
again started a beginning because there
is no way to do it without JavaScript so
you have to do it with JavaScript but if
you use JavaScript then I mean then you
have it you still have the problem where
the Left panel will just like flash and
regenerate because it's trying to use
JavaScript to find where you were so
that's not good so that's a problem so
what I'm saying is that this essentially
that I think okay there is basically no
way there is actually to this state
doesn't matter you use CSS JavaScript
you know iframe there is
no it's impossible actually impossible
to replicate the functionality of the
frameset so that that is basically as
that that is my point now if you want to
learn about HTML frame said you can just
read my tutorial I mean let me post a
link here
so so what is so what is so what I'm
trying to say so the one thing I'm
trying to say is that with today's all
the technology you know JavaScript CSS
iframe there is no way to replicate the
frameset technology using HTML frameset
that is the that's that's my claim ok
but however if you go to all this
website like the common typical
programmers on Hacker News on the web
designers is this crap these [ __ ]
[ __ ] you know they will all say they
will all say open you know beginning
beginning in 1996 starting with this
guru [ __ ] this this web design gurus you
know they spread they tell you what to
do starting with this article you you
every time you meet people you know this
this elite programmers they will tell
you often said it's no good because this
or that but actually you know it's just
force you know like we have just
demonstrated you know that you know the
behavior on this w3 school is not the
same as the frameset and and also you
can try with the you know Mozilla
website you know Mozilla website they
are supposed to be the experts you know
they they create the Firefox browser
same thing you know same thing happens
this is it's just it's just clunky
without you know using frameset you know
yeah there it is you know let's see
it doesn't even try to you know move you
to the original position it does does
not it does not even try to do that so
so first up first up the problem is that
the frame said you know today you don't
you still don't have the technology to
do the frame set that's one thing the
second thing I want my point is that all
these you know elite programmers they
tell you what to do all the time on you
know hacker news or whatever you know
reddit or whatever the N
they will just cram offenses car
problems and they will claim that you
know the iframe replace all
functionality you as a friend said you
can see in this in this stack overflow
you know you can see this this guy's and
you know a question why our friends
deprecated in HTML and you can see this
best answer 57 votes up explains it
and there is another article somewhere
here for example you know they sometimes
they refer to each other but anyway if
you look around this Stack Overflow
answers you will see many claim you know
many will claim that oh you know a frame
said is not useful because you know this
is problems and and and the iframe can
do whatever it can that's just not true
that's not the [ __ ] Paden patently
false
okay but however it doesn't stop all
this it seems like this is very strange
you know that's what I'm talking about
you know some sometimes the programmer
communities they call me a troll so you
have this situation where all these
programmers you know all these people
say is one thing but you try you know
like we try to see it it doesn't seems
to be true and here's the thing you know
try to find any website you know try as
you can try to find you know try to find
any website see if there is I have my I
myself have not find a single website
that has the functionality of a frame
set but without using the HTML for frame
set you know that is a issue so you know
what's going on it's like everyone is
saying one plus one equals two three so
that's a problem
so that that is kind of wraps up about
the topic and that also kind of wrapper
wraps up about today's talk I think 15
minutes yeah so let's see the comments
so the comment so what do you think
about the shifting of the industry over
API SAS what do you mean well like like
I'm not familiar what do you mean so
what he says is a a s o
software-as-a-service okay you know the
my first reaction when I see these
software-as-a-service
and shifting to it if if that is true my
first reaction is I want to [ __ ]
flame that the open-source [ __ ] you
know the open-source fence you know why
so why so where's of service of course
because when the in a society where
everyone is crying oh you need to open
source open source the commercial anyone
cannot make money out of open source
then of course they they want to move to
as a service then you know basically
crowd you know basically it means stow
your data in their computer not your
computer and then you got all these
privacy you know abuse you know they you
know they didn't API everywhere when it
is not needed what do you mean you know
like I don't know what you mean like
yeah so you have to kind of explain like
because you know in programming all this
context you can yeah I don't know what
what do you mean every API everywhere
when it's not needed anyway my first
reaction about software-as-a-service is
you know it's just that corporations has
to do that it you know they do that the
the the the rise of the cloud is in my
opinion okay
I would claim it's true but you know
let's be polite and let's just say in my
opinion it's the major one of the major
reason why the crowd
rise up is because open source you know
open source phonetic fanatism from the
open source in the free software now
open those you know idiots you know like
the open source I talked about this this
is one of my main grant in my top in my
video talk show many times you know we
want you know what I want you know I
share many you know I'm a nerd like I
share many of these what this elite
programmers want you know I you know I I
like privacy I don't want you know I
don't like big corporations like Google
Facebook Twitter you know they [ __ ]
right you know they and I don't like I
don't really like commercialism I think
it's necessary and good and I and
basically I don't really like
commercialism you know if we can avoid
it but supposed to some of these open
source and free software facts they
anyway so my pony is said about this so
so open source you know because these
are idiots because they are blind they
become blind ideology you know
ultimately you know what we want is that
we want to we want power to small people
like you know weak small people we don't
want power that you know other power
belongs to big corporations you know or
few handful people that is the ultimate
goal the open source and free software
that's what I say okay more important
this disco is more important than
whatever you know the free software
foundation they are specific or the
open-source specific for example the
free software foundation there if you
ask them you know you read their you
know program Nate nations you know Jesus
that they want to share you know it's
essentially your communism idea share
you know we
share resources you know basically as a
same or Rob with a moral background you
know from the background of morality
they the free you know reaches home and
they want people to share you know
programmers you you have to share while
the open source is kind of like an
offshoot it's like a branch it turned
out you know its focus is that you know
software must be open so that blah blah
blah but basically it's it's just
writing off you know the free software
foundation reaches dormant so anyway the
idea is not so bad okay yeah why am I
not share you know and also they they by
the way they also allow people to make
money make you know not be mistaken
about that they do actually they
actually which is stolen you know he he
used to sell like you send me money I
give you my Emacs you know he sell he
does that they allow that you know the
money exchange for software but they you
know it must include a source code
anyway so but the more important idea is
like is that more important than this
specific is that you want you want the
power to belong to small people you know
it's like American what American you
know typical Americans are infatuated
with the concept of democracy we must
have democracy you know that but often
it's used in the word democracy is used
as a excuse to to violate you know other
countries so that Americans benefit so
anyway yeah so you want you know you
want power to be you know and you don't
want corporations to Evo in bad things
such as like Rush karach corruption like
they like they lie for example they you
know they take your data and they say
okay you know if you don't want that you
can say you know go to your preferences
and say you know I don't want to let
Google use my data but they they do
anyway you know that that's no good
that's a lie that's so that's let's
explicitly no good in any in any branch
of morality you know any any brand of
morality but that's what these companies
all do and I a poet Microsoft you know
all these companies Facebook so that's
what happens today you know so so anyway
so anyway back to the topic
software-as-a-service why does this
cloud things rise up because of the open
source ideology Fox when you and you
know the interesting things about this
is that you know all these most most
white people in America okay you know
they make money that life is too good
and they they feel guilty they want to
meanwhile they still they you know they
find the concept of helping is such a
great concept they really want to help
you know so so the open source idea in
free software becomes bigger and bigger
you know today it's like in all
corporations it's embraced by Google
Facebook Microsoft all corporations you
know in fact it is it is exactly this
evil corporations Google Apple Microsoft
Facebook they are contributing to open
source they are pushing the most money
they are pushing actually pushing the
idea of open source now and they benefit
nobody else not you little programmers
they benefit big-time now you know
billions of dollars and they they moved
everything to crowd you know like a
service you know so so what I'm saying
ok back to the topic is that the reason
the cloud rise right rose you know
because the open source ideology you
know because they are they can no longer
do you know proprietary you know
software once you have open source you
cannot base it essentially you eliminate
it
the vast you know basically your chances
of making money is gone and that's not
reality you have to survive you know I
write software you have to survive you
cannot so any
what most people most programmers in
fact vast majority of the open source
ideology Fox you know they they work for
Google they work for Microsoft they make
a lot money and this patent you know
there are billions number of patents you
know Oracle they work for them by day
and at night they do they sing open
source all its open source really they
live in comfort you know they they own
apples you know whatever Apple's latest
they talk about it they buy it you know
Apple [ __ ] open-source [ __ ] and the
leaners Linux [ __ ] okay so sorry
about my event I know actually you know
a lot my people you know my followers
are you know Linux fans and you know
open-source fans and that because that's
not that's the community I you know I
live you know even though I don't have
much money you know because I don't like
you know I don't like big corporations
you know so so okay let me give you a
point kind of a summary so I'm thinking
you know so you know so my point is that
you know if you want good you know if
you want for example the good ideas the
good essential you know the ethical
moral whatever ideas about open source
of free software you want to stick to
reality okay you don't want to blind
trying to be you know follower ideology
you know for example open source and
free software foundation so to me these
ideas are not bad you know they you know
you know yeah sure why not if you can
you know help other people you know but
things got wrong becomes wrong become
when they become an ideology you know
it's like a giant wheel you know it just
keeps rolling like you know the spice
must flow you know this you just wipe
out anything in its path that's what
happening today you know like you know
originally when Richard storm and all
these people they create open source
they are like anti-social right there it
has like P
other people will laugh at them you know
[ __ ] you open source you know this weird
guy just Roman you know why what'd you
create that because you know so we just
Roman so he's thinking so you know he's
the philosophy free software and you
know it's foam come from thinking but
that's different from today it's like
180 degree fever so like people all the
people of PV being open source let's
mainstream they'll see you know that's
people who don't think it's all your
open so open source open source you know
every time you say something they
immediately is like on Twitter you're
this hundred people they will come ou
can know that you are wrong we need to
open source proper brah you know and
they have no reasons their reason is
whatever you know like not unique
reasons it's common you know you don't
think they don't think so anyway so yeah
so I'm saying yeah open source free
software that's not a bad idea I mean
it's a good idea especially in the
beginning because it's it's counter to
the powerful corporations those greedy
commercial you know that's nothing wrong
with free trade commercial is good but
what is wrong is that they become let's
say corrupt you know where they lie
that's that's when things are that's not
good you know being a corporation is
good you make money you know you you
know I you know I sell something you
like it you buy you don't you don't like
it don't buy it you know that's the
thing
but then okay things you know gradually
change over the past thirty years then
you know today we have these
corporations extremely evil Microsoft
Google Facebook Twitter they lie all the
time they they are extremely powerful
and they are open-source they are the
you know they are the pushes for open
source ideology why because the work the
more they push the more power they have
because you as a programmer you have you
know they rub you all of your power they
force you open source they got
programmers working for them yeah you go
work for Google you make a lot of money
you know ten thousand dollars a month
then then they make you sing open source
at night so
you put your stuff on github so people
like me who do not open you know you
don't work for Google or Microsoft when
I read the program you I cannot survive
you know like because there are millions
libraries already out there you know
they and they have pictures like they
have designers creating logos nice logo
slice nice animations you know they they
wipe you out you know so Google benefits
yeah Google and all these programmers
they work for Google every day they are
singing oh we are helping from humanity
we are you know we it must be open
sources you know that that's what
happening that's that's the thing ok
yeah well that's another rant about open
source I think you know I I kind of do
this often but anyway that so that's it
for today
one now so any any other questions you
know I'm not going to you know show that
because Google is you know Google is you
know it ties to politics and other
things you know because as you know
today we have social justice and Google
Facebook they are or doing censorship
it's all you know you know so what I'm
saying you know yeah so you have to you
know so when things are complex in such
society you have to think about things
not blindly follow you know just follow
things okay but yeah so that's that's it
for today so yeah that's it for today
and yeah okay so last thing I want to
mention kind of a so my my video my talk
show is erratic like I don't have a
schedule and that has a being a problem
always like people want to you know
check out my talk show but they don't
know what time I'm gonna be on because
my sleeping time changes all the time
because and so I think what I'm going to
do is that I'm going to like announce
the next one like if you go to my
YouTube
so what what I should do is that every
time you go to youtube you will see your
live video like a template and I will
say when that one is going to be alive
so for example like right now I'll
planned so tomorrow so it looks like
tomorrow noon is a good time I will do a
video tomorrow so I will you know I will
then create a live video template you
know with the time stamp tomorrow you
know then you know if you subscribe to
me then you can see it
oh so next one is you know so basically
essentially you we are always you know
hopefully you will always have one you
know template that says wins the next
one and you can like subscribe to that
okay yeah so thank you guys for watching
hope to see you next time bye