good morning welcome to another sapphire
sapphire Keys another exit talk show
let's see if I'm
I'm about to be alive actually I think I
am already good morning and welcome to
another South talk-show in today's topic
now that's better
so today I'm going to talk about the
several subjects it's showing browser
I'm sorry I'm late
so today I'm going to talk about several
possible topics so I'm going to show you
some math books yeah some some math
topic I'm going to show you some math
books and I'm going to well I installed
Python anaconda that's such a stupid
name I installed that and I'm gonna show
you context dependent semantics a very
interesting issue about language design
hi guys
say hi and I'm going to talk about maybe
possibly complex numbers and I'm going
to show you a Mac Lee's sitemap how do
you use a Mac this to generate sitemap
then I'm going to maybe talk about mint
report set which is mathematics then I'm
going to maybe show you game of life all
of these are very interesting game of
life for example that's that's actually
computational kind of in the subject of
computation but both computation in
mathematics and the consequences of game
of life the theories you know it's
far-reaching actually it shows you how
deterministic systems is actually
unpredictable
now have you have you guys are you guys
familiar with that okay let's switch to
hey break the loop
good evening great to see you now you
say is if I want to learn math through
college style textbooks is there any
particular author or title you recommend
yeah I can show you
oh calculus yeah I can show you calculus
for example James Stewart
well you can get that book but it's very
expensive you know calculus it's like
that's tremendous so okay I'm
gonna talk about that so let's start
this get started so okay let me show you
calculus calculus books so I'm going to
hold on a second let me you know I'm
still kind of learning the streaming the
whole streaming thing and it's kind of
awkward that every time I show this
window to see the comments it's kind of
awkward so I'm hoping maybe there is
some way so you know I still need to
figure that out
something like that maybe now that
doesn't work because every time I have
to click this window but yeah but I mean
it's awkward to for people to see this
but anyway so okay let me show you so if
you just slowly dot info okay and you go
to the math section that's my math
blocks and on the panel you can see
several entries and what you want is
math textbooks okay by the way you can
also go to the way but you see that on
that on the nevermind
yeah so so this is yeah so from sorry
I'm being repetitive I'm trying to get
over that so sorry that info click on
math then oh then you will arrive at my
math block you know which is you know my
math block but there's a main entry if
you click the yellow box on the top left
so this is my all my stuff about math
but if you want cack calculus textbooks
you click on this over here so here is
several textbooks three textbooks that
i've collected and verified by that i
mean
you know I've either read it or I've
checked the author you know a red part
of it you know to make sure that this is
something you know it's good you know
let's say I approve okay so and actually
many of these actually I'm planning to
read myself some of the differential
geometry actually some of the okay
anyway so on this page you know is three
mass text books and they are mostly in
PDF now the topics on this page some of
them are kind of elementary so for
example if you never buy okay so if you
are if you are not a math major
you know most programmers or not you
know you you you are not a math major
then then this you can read probability
you can read you know without you know
just high school with high school if you
have a high school qualification so
probability calculus linear algebra okay
so this the first three topics the
probability calculus linear algebra you
any undergraduate and I mean if you are
a programmer you and you have some extra
time it's good to learn all these three
now all these three topics basically are
the fundamental the basics like every
for example if you go to a college
university for four years and if you
want to major in math then you get a
degree right so the first two years are
basically calculus and linear algebra
and differential differential equations
basically basically that for topics so
calculus usually they divide two
calculus one two three four I mean
depending on a college but basically the
first two years I mean every every
college and
every University they differ you know
their curriculum differ a little bit so
but basically all these linear algebra
calculus probability you can read and
and it's good for you I mean if you are
a programmer and if you are interested
because for any hard sciences if you
want to go to physics or if you want to
go to engineering
you know mechanical engineering or
chemistry you essentially that you all
require calculus and some probability
and you know and and and linear algebra
is very it is like essential ok well
anyway
oh this so far it's basically the first
two years of for math major ok so but
after so if you are majoring if you are
if you are a major in physics chemistry
engineering you know any of these hard
science classes then it is required to
take all these vineager or calculus
probability and usually they are covered
in first two years of a university now
however if you are a math major you know
your major is mathematics then the third
year and fourth year typically europe
start to study real analysis and the
complex analysis and abstract algebra
and and and and possibly differential
geometry and also possibly topology
that's the subject I mean again every
college differs but but I was but
topology abstract algebra and real
analysis in complex analysis they are
typical they are almost fundamental for
a math major if you are a math major in
undergraduate college you know
University for years so so basically the
four years of college for a math
major is you know all these yeah and you
know I got some other books some of them
for me to read you know logic for
example I'm very interested they are
quite advanced typically you know and
algebraic geometry is also typically
very difficult topic but anyway now let
me talk about this math subject so so
Rico I differentiated from the first two
years of college and the the last two
years of college for math majors so you
know for hard sciences or you know all
the you know mechanical engineer
chemistry you know if you want to be a
chemist or feces feces you know your
your oh you have you you all have to
take you know probability calculus
linear algebra instantly and sometimes
statistics statistics and probability
they are they are different subjects but
they are often studied together so
usually you are running to a book that
cover introduction for both of them
basically yeah even though they are they
can be entirely separate but anyway so
so that's first two years but however if
you have a math major now that's that
that differentiate mathematicians from
the other species you know
mechanical engineer you know rocket
scientists you know those are one thing
instant he's a physicist okay let's go
over there now mathematicians over here
so if you are a math major
beginning the third year of university
you need to take video analysis as I
mentioned before complex analysis
abstract algebra differential geometry
and topology these are typical and I
don't have differential geometry
differential equations basically you
need to take differential equations
before differential geometry
so these are typically covered in the
third and fourth year for for math
majors and basically for math majors
only you know a general I simplified a
little bit of course if you go into you
know if you keep studying physics then
you know if you study say our instance
creativity then you and also need you
know complex analysis you you all know
you need these especially differential
geometry you know it's like you know so
you know after after you got
undergraduate degree then you go for
masters or PHP PhD degree and sometimes
you know like the topics varies I mean
once you have an undergraduate then you
know some people take these first or
some that was and or some people never
studied this topic you know it's kind of
like that so but anyway so so if you are
just a programmer you never studied math
and you want to get into it so these are
caki so so I have like three calculus
textbooks let me turn on JavaScript okay
I read so I have like three calculus
textbooks
these are PDF you can download I mean
they are all open source I mean they are
awesome sort of you know creative
license or open source so you can
download you know I just put on my
website so there are these three
calculus books I haven't decided you
know which one is better you know
because I took calculus you know I was
you know I took calculus back in 1991 so
it's been a while for me but calculus
gets you started after you know yeah so
anyway so I have these three books I'm
not sure which one is better so you
might just read em and see I mean they
are all kind of similar you know they
are all kind of similar you can just
like pick one start with one see which
one you like some some of the them cover
a little bit more topics than your
and also what interests me I mean I mean
when I study math I mean let me mention
that on Wikipedia this huge amount okay
the the amount of articles are
mathematics for mathematicians not not
the basics which stuff I'm talking about
I mean even for mathematicians
professional mathematicians the quantity
and quality on Wikipedia you could say
it surpasses you know existing almost
leaks or existing literature even in
many cases even for graduate stuff not
not research though not research level
but yeah so so what I'm basically what I
mean what I'm saying is that when you
study these things for example this one
calculus book and let's see let's see
let's look at some topics and if you see
you know when I when you are reading
this book and if there's something you
don't understand you can always go to
Wikipedia it's it's useful however if
you never studied calculus before then I
reckon you know I recommend you start
with a book you don't want to just go to
Wikipedia because usually when you go to
Wikipedia they their stuff is spread out
and they have ton of things and you know
like one one article like let's say
integration you know well that's a basic
topic but you know anyway in general you
go to a Wikipedia for a specific math
subject you know or turn then part of it
is basic part of it's actually research
level but you know it's it's all under
that title so it's kind of you know it's
hard to for for you to sort of sort it
out for example if someone never studied
programming before and he goes to
Wikipedia he'll get overwhelmed you know
like all the languages and programming
paradigms
you know you don't know where to begin
you know you cannot tell which one is
actually you know the programming you
know the actor for picking
which one is what which one is
programming philosophy like idioms you
know and so on
Oh programming history you know UNIX
history like you know like you know for
example ask your mom or dad you know
maybe they are not programmers you know
they go there they don't know where to
you know they get confused so similarly
it's like that for math so yeah this
this calculus you know you can start
that and you know linear linear algebra
is great for linear algebra is one of my
favorite topic linear algebra and
complex analysis actually I want I can
you know I can go on and talk a bit more
about math because you know I'm you know
it's it's one of the topic I'm really
interested but let's look at the
comments so hi guys you know if you guys
have questions just ask it anything okay
having this nature of talk show for now
you know right now I don't have a you
know I I don't have a set things to
discuss a friend so right now it's just
like if you anyone you know when I say
something you have a question or comment
or your own opinions just say it so let
me read the question a bit you know
thanks for rings were you ever
interested in physics when I was younger
yeah but but not really I don't know
much about physics not and and
particularly not today I don't like
physics
I don't like physics like everything it
you know physics physics okay there's
you know this applied physics and
there's you know theoretical physics but
basically essentially every physics is
is reliant on math you cannot have the
math especially I mean okay this is
applied well physics there is
experimental physics okay and
theoretical physics
now the theoretical physics is all just
math all you do everyday is math but why
do they what do they you know
differentiate from you know math why
don't they just call it math because
actually
actually their main goal is actually to
study face physics you know theoretical
physics cosmology you know quantum stuff
you know you know the shape of the space
you know the shape of space there's a
book of banana me which is very good by
Jeff way weeks but I mean I can show you
but anyway so in physics basically every
physics is just math you are just
actually doing math so but actually it's
more than math because you know because
in when you study math for example like
the topics are covered like okay like
what you know I mentioned before the
first two years you have you know
probability calculus linear algebra okay
that that's you know basically that
these are the first two years and also I
forgot to mention also there's a
differential equations okay that's the
first two years of college for hard
sciences but why do I separate it so
what I'm saying is that the second two
years that's the real that's becomes a
real math but what's the difference the
difference is that the difference is at
the first two years of math what you are
learning actual practical stuff like
programming you know you are actually
learning you can think of it as like
learning programming where you actually
code and get answers you know it's all
practical you know you you do something
you know you get answers you know how do
you how do you calculate you know
suppose you have a circle what's the
area okay yeah that's easy you know PI
you know r2 something like that but what
if you have a curve you know irregular
shape like a swimming pool or something
you know exactly the each point in a
peer mentor how do you calculate the
area that you you do by calculus you
know you you're learning it's you do
that by calculus
okay these that's all practical you know
how do you calculate as the speed you
know the spaceship you
gravity you know it's so practical
however when you get on I mean but
that's not like real math okay that's
not you know that's not be your math you
know that's that's not mathematician
Smith you know today you know as far as
today is concerned because that's that's
that's that's practical you know for
engineers you know for physicists you
know the advanced the real kind of math
begin today today's you know what
mathematician studied you know I well I
might yeah you know I I call it real
math that's not a good name though but I
mean what the mathematicians today study
today is or basically they are also they
are studying formalized Matthew you
could say that formalized math so it's
it's say theory and logic it's basically
everything is kind of foundation logic
based basis so so for example let me
give you example so calculus after you
had this you know introduction you know
the first two years calculus then you
start to study Bo analysis what is real
analysis real analysis is actually just
calculus in fact as far as I know in
Europe they just call it like they don't
have two different names they should
have they just have one name like
analysis so anyway let me explain so
what's the difference between calculus
in Andreo analysis basically you can
think of calculus as the beginners
analysis beginners view analysis
you know that's kind of so the
difference is that in real analysis it's
the subject matter is pretty much the
same but however you start to study it
in a mathematicians way that is you
don't draw things so you know you talk
about speed or you know area you know
like you don't have that anymore almost
instead instead of you your subject is
all
of shacked like for example let's click
let's click it let's see you know
remember in calculus books you know you
can sum through they talked about how to
calculate area change of speed
you know derivatives integral which is
related to area and things like that
like practical you can every person can
kind of sense you know everyday life it
makes sense but in real analysis which
is kind of the beginning mathematician
stuff if you look at the topics you know
it's kind of you you don't it's all
abstract you see they mentioned
derivative here the Riemann integral the
continuous functions that's still very
basic though but anyway so what I'm
saying is that the subject matter is
it's basically the same as calculus ok
but however the approach the in the the
the whole approach and terminology used
is all different it's not like practical
oriented oriented so here they define
derivatives you know so you know they so
you start to see you know for example
you there is a website called math
overflow this is like Stack Overflow
except it's for mathematicians and if
you let me turn on the JavaScript and
let me magnify now let me look at the
comments of it
so for example this this website math
overflow this is like professional
mathematicians talking about math just
like we programmers talking about
programming stuff in Stack Overflow now
in so in math overflow if you look
around they are using mathematicians
language for example this question
comparing the definitions of K theory
and K homology for CR Cera's you know if
you never studied math it's what what
the is going on and it's like that
so that those are math jargons you know
Wayne's a map queen is a map of
topological spaces homotopy equivalent
to an algebraic map yeah so these are
math dragons let's read another one
intersection of three of fine sub
modules comparison with vector spaces
yeah so you see this math chapman jargon
so what do they mean like what do they
mean you understand what they mean after
you after you you know start after you
read this real analysis book you know
it's you see here the definition of
basic properties so it's not a
definition 4.11 it says that I be on
interval let let F I to R be a function
and and so on you know they started to
give you this math top the math the way
mathematicians talk so the real analysis
is so let's go back to the page so real
analysis is basically the real
introduction of calculus like
mathematicians version of calculus and
complex analysis it's basically the same
subject as reanalysis analysis except
that they don't deal with real numbers
anymore they deal with complex numbers
which is a extension of real numbers and
and complex analysis is my favorite
subject and it's beautiful yeah it's
extremely beautiful I'm gonna show you I
mean I can go on and on you know me
maybe you know if you like to see it let
me know I'll show you later okay let me
finish this okay so let me continue with
this so Rio analysis it's kind of a math
continuation of calculus you know in for
mathematicians complex analysis is is
like Rio analysis except it covers the
complex numbers which is very important
and abstract algebra now now algebra is
entirely different subject from calculus
okay
now generally in math classically there
are there are many ways to categorize
different math subjects but classically
it's character record you have three
categorizations you have analysis which
is a which is the same as calculus but
they we call it analysis so analysis
then you have algebra then you have
geometry so analysis algebra geometry
this is the classic you know roughly
categorization of math I mean there are
so many others you know like this where
does logic go you know logic is also a
big branch and and there's discrete math
you know there is no one way to you know
neatly categorize them all just like
there's no one way to gather categorize
or programming paradigms you have opie
you have functional but you know
functional languages they also do or P
something like that then you have you
know other you know languages you know
fourth logical languages so there's no
need way to you know characterize them
but anyway
traditionally math is categorized into
geometry algebra and analysis now what
is analysis remember analysis is just
like just calculus so the subject nicest
talks about the study is basically
continuous functions continuous funky
and limit for example let me give you a
very interesting example so suppose you
have a stick okay
suppose you have a stick you cut it in
half okay
then you cut it in half again then you
couldn't have again if if you repeat
forever the question is are you going to
have something left or Oh weird like
just disappear you know that's an
interesting question you know this is
like this is a root of calculus you know
beginning like three thousand years ago
also 2000 you know in Greeks you know so
the question is it is is this going to
be something left you know so
philosophers study did you know so on
but but that and that question can be
answered by calculus you know it became
so that's kind of the things calculus
study analysis so so anyway back to the
categorization of math so you have
analysis algebra and geometry in algebra
algebra is about structures yeah algebra
is about structures geometry is my
favorite topic so let me let me read the
comments let's see
so um yeah physics you know now I'm too
old to actually you know I would be
lucky thanked actually you know this
this math I want to study like
differential geometry I want to get I
want to really know the stuff and also
proof iya proof theory I don't have it
here but another another page yeah I
mean and you know there are some things
I want to study I wish to study before
you know before it's too late you know I
give myself like five more years the
least to mathematicians they are one of
the they are the top differential
geometry they are my friend they you
know they are my mentor like my good
friend and I help them to their website
yeah let me show you
so virtuoso you use search for virtual
math museum
so there it is 3d XM virtual math museum
so you go there so you have different
topics you have for example polyhedra
now this this is a topic like every
programmer likes you know because
because it's easy to understand and it's
elegant and you also called recreational
math because because anyone you know can
easily understand it so let's go back so
you have polyhedra and you have minimal
surfaces minimal surfaces is spectacular
it's really beautiful so these are
minimal surfaces basically what they are
is that if you okay here's the
interesting thing if you have a wire
like any any like paperclip
I mean suppose it's very long paper clip
you know just a wire you know a copper
wire and suppose it's connected so you
have a circular copper wire now you
twisted in any way you want you twisted
it to any shape now you dip that wire
into a soap film then you pick it up
then the soap film will you know they'll
cover you know they'll feel it you know
in in weird shape now that shape is
called a minimal surface why because
because due to physics I mean why does
it fit you know form a particular shape
but not others because that's because of
physics but in turn but from a
mathematics math point of view that
surface those surface has certain
properties
it's called minimal surfaces so all
these you see here are minimal surfaces
the most famous one and the earliest one
is this one hello Koide
hara code and catenoid
see so here's an animation showing they
how they transform but anyway yeah so if
you want to study this subject you know
minimal surfaces actually you have to
study differential geometry first so you
have to study calculus and analysis you
know basic analysis then differential
geometry so I'm trying to understand you
know I am trying to learn I'm learning
you know minimal surfaces so yeah so
let's go back to yeah and you know then
we have famous surface for example you
have Mobius strip Mobius strip is famous
because it it's a surface that has only
one side now now there's a lot of
significance to these two to these you
know people ask you know so what's the
point
okay you got a strip that's only you
that only has one side what's the point
this is significance let me talk about
it you know the a Mobius surface it's a
two-dimensional surface you know yeah so
it's interesting it's only one side you
know you don't it's you know it has only
one side now the point is why is it
significant because you see the surface
is only two-dimensional now we so if an
ant you know an ant or any insect
crawling on a surface you know you know
quo in one direction it will come back
but on the other side I mean what is
only one side like you know there's just
one side of it it's kind of curious now
however we live in three-dimensional
space you know how space is
three-dimensional
now is it possible you know if you have
a rocket you you know you shoot it up
straight it just goes straight you know
no bending at all just go straight now
it is actually possible the rocket will
come back to us like from our back you
know
why because of Mobius trip you know so
that that is the significance you know
because the Mobius strip is only
two-dimensional I mean it's a
mathematical abstraction I mean well I
mean this is least the pictures are just
a visualization but you have like
equations you know to represent it so
this is just one of the curious
interesting example but and it's only
two dimensional in the same way you are
you have three dimensional stuff and
four dimensional stuff in them and in
higher dimensions the the point is that
in think in three dimensional or the
dimensions you you you realize you by
equations you know you realize that it
is entirely possible I mean it's not
just yeah I mean it's mathematically
proven it's not just a you know it's
just just like the Mobius strip you know
such that if you go straight line your
head if you have a rocket you know going
straight you'll come back you know to
the back of your head and that's that's
the shape of the space why does it come
back even if you don't turn because
that's just the shape of the space in
the same way like on earth if you go
straight you'll come back yeah that's
that's a similar idea but but the idea
that here is more complicated because it
it will not only combat back but the
universe will be inside out like you
know is you know kind of like that yeah
so that's that's an interesting thing
about these you know interesting things
about these surfaces shape of space you
know and this conformal map that's so
that this is this is the subject of
complex analysis let me show you
animation so anyway so it's very
interesting and you know I'm helping you
know IP or this side
you know I'm helping the professor's you
know building this site let's see wanna
say yeah okay so nobody nobody's got
questions
yeah I'd learned I learned math mostly
you know by myself well I had two years
in college I finished you know all the
math they offer you know like I
mentioned before you know all the the
calculus differential equations in
linear algebra and probability intro to
probability and statistics basically
that's it and most others I learned my
on my own
so are you credited on any academic no
no actually my only credit is a drop out
of middle school can hang a mobius strip
exist in real life
yeah you know you just take a paper and
make it let's see I mean if that's what
you mean you know you have seen people
make it right you know so I got a strip
let's make it thinner
oh no you know it's I tell of the
so I got kind of a strip so if I if I
wrap it just like that that's you know
then that's an almost like a bracelet
you know but now I twist now I like
twisted you know may not glue these two
together then I got a mobius strip then
if you take a pen if you try to draw you
will see that you know it's just one
side actually you know there are a lot
YouTube videos about that they are loud
you know this like YouTube for
everything these days so I mean if you
want to study some math yeah actually
there's even calculus course on YouTube
though I'm not sure how good are they
but I believe some of them are done by
professors yeah so you know you can
watch so I mean okay you know when you
study math on YouTube many of them are
fun okay you know me mobius strip
remember you know so you can you can
watch them casually but know that if you
actually want to study math I mean we
owe that you know if you really are
interested to get to know math you don't
want to spend too much time on these
casual things because when I was younger
I you know I you know I studied them all
these you know there are lots of like
math popularization books you know I
read lots of them like Martin Gardner
Martin Gardner's books I busy I read all
of them basically so you know and but
okay so what I'm saying is that don't be
like me okay anyway just just kidding
what I'm saying is that
was younger I'm very much into meth okay
but I spent a lot of my time
when when when young guys I studied lots
of these you know like intro to math the
kind of recreational math stuff math
puzzles or these mobius strip stuff like
on youtube you know you'll see lots of
it lots of those kind of things and yeah
I mean you know you know like fun and
dramatic you know visual stuff so what
I'm saying is that if you want to
actually get into the heart of math what
mathematicians actually do you don't
want to spend too much time on these
kind of YouTube you know fun things like
you know Oh beautiful oh you can you
know you want actually to deal with you
know those math jargons and equations
like the kind of things you will see on
meth above overflow and and you know
also let me say you know math is kind of
a black hole and the only reward is just
self-satisfaction you know because they
are smarter people than you doesn't
matter how good you are there are
farmers matter smarter people who know
more math than you always doesn't matter
how good you are and and and you know
they they where do you find them they
are washing dishes at restaurant what
I'm saying is that okay no no what I'm
saying is that yeah math is is it's like
a black hole you know you can like you
can you know forget eating you know you
can devote yourself into it however one
of the sad thing is that it doesn't
bring you money you know you can study
math like everyday starting today you
know you you are really smart you are
you know and you study math full-time
for four years you know you won't get a
job there is no job for you
so it's very it's a in sharp contrast to
being a program you know if you program
you know you learn Python after two
years you know if you pretty good you
get a job you know lots of money and
that's not the same for math and so math
is kind of just rewarding for you you
know and if you are you if you if you
are I don't know how old are you guys so
you know maybe some of you are young you
know you think you are hotshot you know
you think you're high IQ you know you
know just remember there are a lot of
people far more smarter than you and
they are not doing well I mean if math
is such a subject that it can suck
certain people in and just just in some
sense wasted your life you know you know
you can study it for like 20 years and
get nowhere it's kind of like that but
why do people do that because there's
immense beauty in mathematics like you
know aspart Ron Russell say math is the
hard way what's what's the way he said
does anyone know how terrains you know
yeah let me answer this question you
know actually I need to answer the
questions above but let me just say you
know I'm not I'm not a professional
mathematician and my math is not that
you know at let's say you know it's
reasonable to say I have a degree in
math okay like on the undergraduate so
you you know you could say I have let's
say I have a master's degree yo you know
oh just bachelor degree in math you know
if I don't have a degree but I have
something like equivalent so so Terence
Tao I wouldn't I you know yeah I I've
seen his blogs but that's typically
that's not something I would understand
I mean I can well there's a lot
mathematicians I mean I for example I
met this
well yeah I mean so yes for example um
um um jeepers on Google+ you know Google
cured it you know quote you know it's
closing down in April I think Google
that's when Google started at Google+
that's that's about the day the year
that Google's became you know starting
to became evil from from from that day
on this is like seven eight years ago
Google+ but anyway one of the best thing
happened to me is that I met this
mathematician Chong pace I don't know if
maybe you guys have heard of him very
he's very popular so let me look at my I
just retreated one of his Street today
actually so so this guy John Carlos pace
oops wrong click this guy so he's a
great guy he taught me a lot math okay
he's a he's he's actually a physicist
he's a quantum physicist okay and he but
however one of the things he do is that
he he teaches math on kind of an you
know online casually by that I mean he
write blogs always in a expository
manner however there's a distinguishing
quality about his writing different from
others for example for example you've
seen those YouTube you know stuff right
the YouTube you know they are fun they
teach you some math you know like that
but they are not be your math I mean
they don't really you know these are
so-called math popularizing videos or
math popularizing books like on Amazon
you can find a lot you know the you
the story of e and you know so on this
is quite a few math popularizing books
actually I mean I should show my website
instead because yeah so anyway so let me
get back to what I'm saying so anyway so
yeah so so Jung face he when he teaches
some math he's teaching the Bo math okay
not not I mean he always teach it in a
very interesting way so so it's still
beautiful I like for example you can see
you know it's still beautiful this is
actually physics I think or sometimes he
talked about physics in chemistry but he
has done a lot math but anyway the way
he he also he makes the topic very
interesting but however he keep it as
real math not you know not not just
explaining something that phone a
mathematician he so what I'm saying is
that if you have an undergraduate math
you know background then you read him
you actually learn you know the real
thing many of the very interesting stuff
you know he started to use Twitter about
half a year or maybe a year ago because
you know Google+ died but on Google+ his
his stuff is far more better because
Twitter you know you know the charr
limit makes it very difficult you know
and also pictures are small but if you
go to his Google+ let's see
what
so he's got a he doesn't post to Google+
anymore though because you know Google
first is closing down that's too bad but
anyway you can find he's just such his
name on Google+ you'll find his great
posts let's see if I can find it
yeah Google press is really a sad story
and it's also a story where how Google
became evil evil empire but yeah anyway
you'll find it and you'll find that
people you know I'm following him but he
you know I'm I stopped using Google
pressing also he also stopped using
Google+ because and because it's
shutting down you know in a beginning
there's lots of people then it's just
kind of going down here and down here
anyway yeah such you know you you you
always follow him on Twitter his Google+
stuff is far better than Twitter because
on Twitter you just can't do much you
know okay let me get back to the
comments so let me see
so the multi-dimensional discussion
reminds me of the book flatland yeah
flatland is a great book great so you
guys have seen it yeah I read that too
you know I actually read that book three
times yeah let me show my website I read
it three times two in different years
first time is like 1993 or something
then then you know sometimes in 1999
three or four times then you know five
years ago again I think there's also a
Chinese version by the way if anyone
from China is coming here so this is the
book it's a great book flatline and by
the way many mathematicians has written
sequels you can see I list them some of
us here flatland introduction
so people have has written sphere land
and also flatter land in space land now
I don't know about the guy who rose fear
land but the guy who wrote flatter land
I've read like half of it it's pretty
good by Yeon Stewart and Rudy Rucker I
know that guy
we have where you know many of the
mathematicians I've you know emailed to
you know talked very raka is also very
old now his 70s I think he was space
land I never read space line land and
but also remember like remember what I
said before the
all these books these are kind of math
popularization I mean including flat
land including flat land they are great
you know they they introduce terms they
introduce you to some math subjects but
but but they are not math okay they are
not the real thing
if you are really interested you want to
spend time in the real thing you know
that like the textbooks like the
textbooks I I have here you know
differential geometry so you know that
Richard Richard palace guy is my friend
from back in nineteen back in year 2000
back in 1999 I think that's the first
time we met he invited me to Japan Tokyo
Japan and to Taiwan the university you
know to give a talk and stuff so he
taught me a lot he is 70 something now
yeah so he's got a introduction to
differential geometry a modern course on
curves and surfaces so this is back in
2003 and this is written in Taiwan you
know I was with him you know actually he
invited me to go there to teach a course
to graduate mathema math students and
I'm there to teach the programming of
visualization of geometry you know as
part of the project for some summer
cause course
so anyway Richard Paulo is a very
interesting guy and actually I went to
his house two years ago let's see
so he's now at UC Irvine he's retired
I mean he's retired long you know for
you know ten years or something so let's
see let's go to keyboard where do I find
ok keyboard guide
so here I went to a lie do I have a
picture I don't I don't have a picture
of him in 2017 he gave me the Mac he
gave me this iMac yeah in any way so he
is married to a Chinese wife who is also
a mathematician differential geometry
Julian turned so this is her book I'm
reading it I haven't finished Chilean
book yeah and this is also in Taiwan so
this is written back in 2004 so anyway
differential geometries so
Thank You school well my SAT score back
in you know 1991 is what is it is it's
it's it's like I forgot what's a number
but it's like 1990s percentile it's like
within top ten percent and that that got
me through into Mensa actually is a goof
because one of the qualification is that
you know in the top 10 percentile if you
of your SAT score Mensa is kind of CV
you know so this means a club but
actually you have to pay yearly fee and
this is so this is smack in 1992 or 1993
and you know back then you don't have
internet like today so they have like a
monthly Club like you know the mains
means a crap local club newsletters it's
kind of City you know actually yeah and
you have to pay membership fee so I you
know I quit after a year so that's kind
of today I talked for hour but
originally I was gonna talk about
well yeah math that's a good topic but I
was gonna talk about complex numbers
Mandelbrot set game of life it's very
interesting and also oh yeah Python
context dependent semantics that's this
one so this is you know so this is a
example of context dependent semantics
in Python so for example in Python
you can do from a import PB ok or you
can say import cc now if you look at
this let me magnify if you look at this
you see both them both of them contains
the line
the import something you know but
however the import something in these
two lines actually have different
meaning in the first line this import
something that something is a function
in the second line the imports something
that something is a module name so here
is a example where the same syntax the
exact same syntax has different meaning
it in other words its context dependent
well that's that's another topic you
know I you know I can talk about I was
going to go into so any questions today
I know man hi Pantha haven't seen you
haven't seen you guys before so type
questions questions questions
so if no questions I think that's it
today
Oh regular expressions are you are you
not using them you are a programmer
right I have like I have lots of
tutorials on regular expression I have
one for Emacs let's say okay let's see
regular expressions
okay I actually have a pea have like
maybe 10 pages about regular expression
of different languages more than 10
pages but let me find you know wait
[Music]
so there's Emacs one XML is not s
expression you know back then when XML
was like a craze this is around 2000 to
2005 XML is a craze everyone wants to do
xml like there's xml language you know
based programming language there's xml
database like the entire relational
database is going to be kicked out
instead they want to go they're gonna
have a xml database and also all the
configuration files in unix or mac you
know they or windows you know they
changed to to the xml format so that you
know xml kind of died today but one of
the constant consequence a relic of the
xml craze is that in the mac on the mac
you can still see many config files are
xml that that is from this era there's a
whole crazy everything you know like the
entire computer computing word is going
to switch to xml but back to my okay let
me show what what do you want to talk
about regular expressions
the basics
okay the basics like are you are you you
programming in Python JavaScript
okay let me show you then so okay go to
go to sorry dot info so let's open up
JavaScript
let's open up Python okay JavaScript and
Python and let's open up Emacs okay so
for the basic introduction let me talk
about Emacs first so you know if you
just go to my Emacs tutorial practical
tutorial then you have rejects tutorial
here at the bottom in a Find and Replace
box then on this page I show you the
basic Emacs command for you know there's
a query replace rejects and least
matching lines they are like 10 more
than ten commands Emacs commands that
uses regular expression for example if
you want to list all matching lines for
example you can for example on this page
I cover the command let me show you
so if I call the command actually you
know this matching lines then it's going
to ask me to type something let's say I
type Python you know so it shows all
lines containing Python and I can just
click it and you jump to the location in
a file of the current buffer so so there
are lots of Emacs commands that uses
regular expression like you have to give
the regular expression as argument and
so this page is a introduction to the
actual regular expression like like what
does it mean you know what what pattern
you know what character what syntax
matches what so first of all I see spam
what's the difference between wild wild
card you know wild cards you know you
have asked the risk you know and in
question mark when you like when you
list files in the command command line
you can use that let's see CD to web CD
to web
let's say okay so I'm in this directory
and I do LS you can do LS star HTML and
that we our list all files starting with
you know starting with any character and
end with HTML so that's called glob you
know in UNIX job and that's a UNIX
jargon code glob
so that's really useful and you know a
star sign matches 0 any any character
zero or more characters a question mark
just stand for any character but but the
usefulness for pattern matching is very
limited you know so I give you some
examples so then I start to introduce
you to regular expressions and here is
the list of the most commonly used
regular expression patterns so anyway so
this page I give an introduction to
regular expression okay so that's Emacs
now if you are no that's so let's go to
Python similar for Python so in Python
you go down here is a regular expression
basics so this code is a simple use of a
regular expression for example you have
a file that file contains many emails
email addresses and you want to list you
know all the email addresses you can run
this code you know just save this in a
file and run it as an example you know
just show all email patterns so that's a
you know very basic example of using
regular expression then you have you
know find and replace you know you can
learn so this is an introduction to
regular expression you know and then you
have you know another example of you
regular expression to split lines and
then you have regular expression
reference Python rejects reference now
let me talk so regular expression is
extremely useful okay if you wanna if
you are a programmer you want to be very
familiar with it because it's it's super
useful but however you know when I when
I first learn the expression regular
expression it's fairly complex so the
thing about real expression is that you
want to persist okay you want to persist
you know you know start with an example
like you know the Python example I have
here maybe you code in Python or maybe
you code in JavaScript let me let me go
to JavaScript so this is my JavaScript
tutorial and you can see at the bottom
the JavaScript basics at the bottom is a
regular expression basics so it's you
know so you can copy this in a console
you know in the browser console and you
can start to run it you know so that's a
basic example and here here is another
example of matching or email address
patterns so you know file you can you
know extract or email addresses
it's another basic example so I give you
some basic examples but then okay so so
in different languages you have a
function that you know that tries to
match strings of finding replace using
regular expression now regular
expression itself has a particular
syntax for example in Emacs I've shown
you know here is here are examples of
common regular expression syntax in
Emacs
and in Python you want to go to the
Python rejects
friends here is my my my my my
documentation
I wrote it you know for the Python
regular express expression so regular
expression it has a syntax
okay the syntax is you can see here
rejects pattern syntax okay so this is a
Python example rejects pattern syntax
now let's go to the JavaScript now the
JavaScript on this intro page at the
bottom you will see also a page on
regular expression syntax and on this
page I explained you know I give you the
syntax you know basically all the syntax
for regular expression now when you do
expect just just remember when you're
learning expressioned regular expression
it takes takes time okay you cannot like
understand the whole thing in one week
it takes you know many months you know
or maybe even a year oh to you know
constantly using it you yo get to you
you get used to so you know just
remember that you know it's it's kind of
confusing at first you just have to get
used to that's that's one thing okay the
other thing about regular expressions
syntax is that different language they
differ you know slightly a little bit
but basically they are all the same now
Emacs regular expressions is kind of
more different than Java or Python
well anyway Python Java Perl job
JavaScript Ruby :
the audio regular expression is kind of
almost 100% identical so you don't
really have to worry about you know
which one to learn so you know just
learn the one whichever language you are
using just you know
so I only have one for you know
JavaScript and Python but basically they
are all the same for any language you
know you know one you know the other
except except Emacs the Emacs
this the Emacs version of regular
expression is slightly a bit more
different so you know you know it's yeah
so I think that's that's it for today so
thank you super thanks I'm glad I'm glad
I did I can explain it so I see you guys
hold on one more question web standards
are too complex that's true
exactly browsers almost impossible to be
you're from scratch yeah yeah you know
we are the web be replaced
oh the question we are the web be
replacing a couple of decades now I
don't know it would be very hard because
it's so much technology has been
invested you know the web you know like
you are exactly right about the browsers
so they are extremely complex I mean
it's not like you know a same person I
mean doesn't matter how good you are you
know you cannot write a web browser in
three years I mean a full-time you know
let's take you know whoever the the
greatest coder at Google you know
whoever who you know let's for example
pick the greatest coder at Google you he
cannot you know you will not be able to
write a browser for in three years you
know well he can I mean you will be able
to but your browser will not be
comparable to any of the Google Chrome
or Firefox you know what they do they
put programmers like the top programmers
the billions here millions of dollars
to do all kind of possible hacks to make
it fast you know it's beyond just good
quality code you know you know suppose
I'm a genius and suppose I'm a Superman
and suppose you know I know oh you know
the protocols you know the computer
science or the you know by heart I write
a browser it will be very slow he'll be
slower than you know Chrome or Firefox
or Microsoft edge you know because what
the cooperate you know the Google you
know they what they do is they they have
to hack you know they try all possible
ways to hack you know use assembly
language or many tricks they're like
hack that is you know to make it fast
that's what happens today and in fact
that's happens in lots of things so you
know it makes it impossible for you know
average person's a software programmer
to compete with any of these companies I
mean that's just the state of the thing
so anyway so web browsers I don't think
you'll be I think I I don't know if
something will replace it I think you'll
be hard not in five years maybe not even
in ten years Oh next couple of decades
decades yeah maybe
yeah defecates definitely maybe after
ten years yes I'm pretty yeah I'm pretty
positive about you know can pretty
certain after ten years something will
happen they'll replace the web browsers
yeah I'm pretty sure like so maybe
virtual reality or something I didn't
you know that's that's my that's my
guess so anyway thanks thank you guys
for coming by that's it for today bye