hello welcome to another episode of
startup show
uh you are watching star talk show and
we are going to do emac this session not
d magnus but emacs workflow emacs
you know i'm going to work on emacs
using emacs working on my website
and i'm going to work on the my website
about emacs initialization setup
so you go to
you know
the search for xadi emacs tutorial
you'll find these main topics emacs
tutorial emacs init and emax keys
and emac beast
then
in the emacs init section
you have you know several tips about
initialization
you know emacs initialization is one of
the biggest thing when you use emacs
because you have to set up lots of
things
as opposed to
vs code or microsoft visual studio where
everything is set up for you yeah i mean
there's no
you have you don't have to learn extra
things but emacs you have to
so
so on this tutorial all these are
about emacs initialization
uh
many tips
about how to set up tab and space how to
set up automatic typing of the
parentheses
uh set up
search white space you know you can
press white space you know space bar to
stand for any of the hyphen underscore
or tab
you know so these are very convenient
emacs setup
and you know i've been working on my
emac website for for 15 years 17 18
years
and
there's a lot to do so i'm going to
improve this emacs init setup today so
this section
so let's just get started so today is
march
march 22nd okay let's begin if you have
a questions emacs questions
uh
post it okay and uh pay me
super chat or patreon or um
paypal amazon gift card i have you have
you can find the links on my website
okay let's begin so so today's talk show
so yeah we're gonna i'm i'm so this is
just emac session i'm just going to work
on my uh
my website so you're gonna watch my
emacs workflow and i'm using soft light
keys sapphire keys
which is my package uh
and uh
vora keyboard and you can see my
keyboard
keyboard okay so vorack keyboard which
is kinesis advantage to keyboard so i
have a full review here you can see all
those photos i've been updating my pages
so that's my old picture four years ago
and
full review here and the ultimate
hacking keyboard which is
which is which is right here full review
there so
okay so
vora keyboard ultimate hanging keyboard
for rack layout and let's begin okay so
in in setup so
so i have let me tell you what i'm going
to i'm doing okay so i have all these
topics i need to
so first of all emacs init file i tell
you what you need you need files all
about in emacs
so hold on a second let's go to
powershell and
toggle dark theme so this is a command i
wrote you can see
some powershell tutorial
and advanced and the script examples set
docker dot set dark theme so this is the
code i've written so you can see i just
say toggle dark theme
and it's fantastic the power of
powershell
okay so for the video i'm gonna use
white theme
so okay so
back to the tutorial so this page tells
you all about what init file is about in
emacs where they are located
then the next section
here is a collection of small init
uh setup
for example how do you make
you know the key
copy cut paste undo to be ctrl c control
x ctrl v ctrl z the tradition the
windows tradition
and mac tradition and you and linux
tradition only in e-max is different on
e-max today is the only application that
uses different key binding than all the
others
emacs and vim
you know so you can but you can make it
in you can make emacs use the
traditional keys if you want but there's
problems any anyway so this page is
miscellaneous setup
then you have you know how do you make
typing type over selection you know in
any
editor since 20 years ago when you have
a selection and you type something it
will erase a selection that's a standard
uh behavior standard since 20 years ago
but emacs again is different so
for these reasons emacs is difficult to
use you know
and i don't think it's a good thing they
should just
have this on by default but the emacs
people refuse to
so you so in order to
override selection you have to put this
emac this code in your init file so for
example let me demonstrate
so uh so i something okay now
let's turn off the highlight okay
something right something i now i make a
selection i select it now i type
your type over it your eraser selection
but if i don't have this on let's uh
for example delete selection mod let's
say
zero zero means false okay evaluated
now
some
thing okay thing
now i select it
now i
type
you see it does not erase it so this is
what emacs init is about okay
uh now let's turn it back to on okay
evaluate it okay good
now i type something it overwrites
fantastic
okay now
what is this powershell okay close uh
well
okay
i want to copy the link close it go to
sauce talk show go to today's talk show
and paste the link here so
linkify it make a
list and show in browser so we have a
notes on what we did today okay
so now close that close that close that
close that close that oh
and close that let's go back to uh
go back to init okay so
you know i'm gonna stop talking about
you know i'm gonna stop teaching about
units because my main thing today is i
need to work on this so let's start to
work on my
work on them uh so let's do something
different today so because i've been uh
talking about emacs tutorials and you
know
in info for two years so today
let it just be me working on my website
okay
i'm gonna try to talk less and just walk
on my website you know i do this every
day uh so you kind of see focus on the
workflow my workflow every command i
type in emacs
and the keystroke i press you can see in
the pink window so whenever you have a
question you can just actually search
the command forward word or you know
search for example start open file fast
copy it you can actually you can search
it right now okay so press the key
you see
i press the key and it searches so here
it is
open file fast here's a code you can use
it too you can learn what it is about on
the ping window everything so okay so
let's work on my
let's just work on my um website okay
doc theme close
so i have these topics on the side
so on this page is a bunch of
miscellaneous small
init file
tips
and i want to make them
on a page by itself so each one of these
small tips
for example set default file encoding
refresh file automatically
on
and how to set down arrow key to move by
screen line
or by a logical line
and how do you adjust margin how do you
stop emacs from wrapping you know the
word wrap or line wrap
so all these minor tips
right now they are all collected in this
one page so there here is another init
you know how do you have fixed scroll
so normally when you press up down arrow
you move the cruiser but when you have
fixed scroll
it will
move the screen instead so let me show
you so let's call
scroll
lock mod okay now i press up arrow you
can see it moves the screen
it it moves the screen first
then then
when it reaches the bottom or the top
then it moves closer you can see
uh wait move yeah you can see uh
interesting so i don't want that though
so let's do it again turn it off
okay so so all these little tips
i'm thinking of make each one of them a
indent
independent independent page a page by
themselves then you can have a
you know you can have them in the table
of contents in the index panel
that way
it's more logical
uh
okay so i need to uh do thinking uh so i
need to okay
so
you know
so there's a lot to do
uh make typing over so
yeah so i need to do this so
so
so let's go to it okay so wait
any setup
initiatives that's this page
and
okay so
so let's first of all let's have an
overview what are they so make typing
override selected test select
make typing overwrite selected test
text
okay set default file encoding
you know it's really hard to organize a
tutorial um
okay let's not digress let's focus on
this so
set default file encoding okay so that's
going to be so this is a lot issue to
think over because
if i'm going to make this
section a independent page by itself
then
i might have repetition because
let's see
unicode basics character set encoding
utf-8 and code point okay that's a
tutorial about unicode everyone should
know you should learn it you should read
about this page right away if you are a
programmer
then what is this unicode tutorial okay
this is a tutorial on unicode about how
do you deal with unicode in emacs okay
so this is
different this is about
unicoding emacs
okay such as how do you type all these
extras you know you know called
characters or emoji how do you find
their names in emacs
how do you yeah type them how do you
type them by their code point by
hexadecimal or decimal how do you um
yeah so many how do you type chinese for
example input systems in emacs how do
you find a character's hexadecimal value
or name
given a character so
so this is about unicode tutorial
unicode emacs tutorial
for for dealing with working with
unicode so and here is the unicode
tutorial itself
so
okay so this page can be your
independent page
yeah so
let's begin it okay let's just start to
work on some of these instead of just
talking uh a lot
so first of all
first of all open
let's go to my emacs blog okay
create a let's let's shrink this a bit
now create a new section here
paste this thing
emacs in it
okay then
uh then what is is emax in it then you
want to
you want this home page to
[Applause]
okay
so these are the main pages we're gonna
work on so i need a new file
let's see so a new file let's see
okay
a new file name
e-max init
file encoding okay
so that needs a new page
uh
standard copy cut paste keys okay that
needs a new page okay
copy cut paste keys okay
that needs a new page
combine these two into one that's right
uh and put them on new page make typing
override
tv select delete selection okay that
needs a new page
okay my convention is to use underscore
not dash for file names okay and set
default encoding okay that's there
already
set default encoding a new page refresh
file
okay refresh file yeah that should be a
page by itself
emacs refresh file and line margin line
wrap line spacing spacing that's a
complicated issue because there are many
convoluted
concepts related but different
so you have
visual
line mode visual so this is about moving
lines
have a down arrow key moved by screen
you see
uh i'm not gonna explain i'm not going
to explain them
i'm going to focus on working on the my
stuff so
so have the down arrow key move by
screen lines should i
down arrow key because you see some of
this page is really small i mean there's
just one line
so if you're gonna have
a page by itself it's kind of
silly in some aspect
but however
that way it's more logical be just like
a book you know you have chapters you
have sections you have subsections
then each thing is about one topic
so if you want movie move lines by
visual lines
and there's a lot related things okay so
so where does this belong to i mean uh
move lines visual lines this is related
to line wrap okay yeah
okay so move by visual lines
okay so i
suppose so let's put it here
so let's do describe variable let's see
the value is true already so
uh
let's say neo okay let's make a neo
let's see how it changes my experience
you know i've tried them long time ago
for for years for you know but i haven't
i haven't been um
trying that in the past
five years or so ten ten five or ten
so
okay let's make it a page by itself
move line visual
what's the proper file name so now you
have to
think about the proper file name you
want the file name that's short that's
not too long and uh
easy to
understand what the topic is about
so in this case you know there are many
ways to go one of the easy ways simply
use the whatever the emax command line
the command name
for the file name so in this for example
you'll say emax
line move visual
you add emacs in front in to indicate
this is about emacs because you have so
many other topics about javascript or
about whatever
so but the problem with
using the emacs command name to name
your file is that emacs command name
are oftentimes not intuitive
so for example the line more visual
you know what it is what does it mean
like one of the
way to test whether a name is
intuitive is that you
ask random people on the street
in our case the context must be
programmers right it makes more sense
because if you ask random people they
don't they have no idea what you're
talking about editor you know they don't
know what the is a text editor
so let's limit out
you know the question to programmers you
ask a bunch of random programmers you
know you know you just say line move
visual what does it mean
you know if they answer kind of correct
kind of you know correctly about moving
the arrow key
whether it's a visual line or not
then
then you have the good name otherwise
you don't
but do you know what move line visual
means let me show you okay so for
example you see now i have a long i have
a multi line you see this this is a you
know very long line
it spans several lines visually
because this the window is not
the width of the window is not big
enough to accommodate
these
you know 1000 character lines let's see
how many uh characters are there
300 characters okay so if you magnify
you know the window it's still two lines
okay so now you have a long line now the
question is if you move the arrow key
you see right now my arrow is here if i
move it up would it be here or it will
be
actually moving the whole line like like
over here or the beginning of the line
you see
so if i now i press up arrow you see
right now it moves the whole line it
skips the skips the internal let's let's
make this longer than your c you see
up down arrows
move by a physical line biological line
a logical line is determined by
you can see the space
the line return character so a logical
line is determined by that you see it
just move the
whole line but however on the other hand
if i have the
move visual
line move visual true
evaluated now i move the down arrow
you see it goes through internally go
through
them
uh let's say for neo for now okay so i
want to
i haven't tried this for a long time so
now let's uh what
now that's the logical line you see so
that's what that is about now back to
the naming so what should what it should
be the name so if you say
emax arrow move line visual that does
not make sense you have to say arrow
down then that makes a lot more sense
emacs arrow down
move line visual you know name is
heart not now this name is getting long
33 characters that's too long
ah we stuck on the naming of things so
emacs arrow down so let's quickly make a
decision now and we can move on i can
change it later on arrow down move line
let's just say move by line okay
let's just say that's the name i want
turn off the space turn off the white
space next
adjust margin okay this is not
this is not really a init this is rather
a customization command to allow you to
adjust the margin on the fly so
this
section actually needs to be somewhere
else
okay we skip that now this
is make lines not soft wrap
okay
[Music]
so let's
that's another topic
emacs
line soft wrap okay
okay that's another topic
then next
format lines okay
now this is about hard wrap okay this is
about hard wrap they are
related but different okay that's why
many of these issues are confusing
and both of these issues are related to
the arrow down move by line okay so
let's just say hard wrap so we have uh
quite a few topics already new page
now make sentence end
make sentence ending by a single space
that's another esoteric setup
because normally
by convention
sentence
ends with
let's say
one space
new sentence here
you see that's one convention
the other convention is too space this
is old convention this is
typewriters you know type typewriter
convention you end in two space
but modern conventions since
1990s
typically universe
it becomes uh
one space
is far more common
so emax has a
setting you can tell emacs to
to assume
that a sentence ends in once one
one space after period or two
why why is this important because
yeah because when you call a command
that automatically reformat your
paragraph
it will automatic automatically fix
whether you're gonna have one space
after period or two
so
that's why this
this setting
uh
that's where these settings
uh becomes an issue
okay so emacs allow you to set them so
so should i have a new page um
no
so this will be part of the these
so it will be part of the hard wrap page
okay
so
fixed squirrel
ah so fixed squirrel fixed scroll will
be part of the
arrow down okay
it'll be part of the arrow down page
let's turn on the highlight line okay
and then okay this is small okay but for
now let's just start to do this
okay let's let's start to do wait how
many
windows i have three
greetings from california arnold
greetings okay so let's begin to
to work on these pages okay
so first of all make the make sure they
are all
underscore
so i have a command that easily
fix the underscore so add html
so let's see so let's try a command okay
okay so let's see open
so i have a command that automatically
create a file
is that what i want
uh
not exactly
because the panel is incorrect
okay so let's fix that so delete that
file so i'm doing you know i need to you
know in order to for you to understand
what i'm doing i have to explain lots of
things
okay let's look at the command okay so
the command is outside new page because
outside new page then
then you go to
okay let's not use this command so
so the command i want is this okay
so uh let's just create a command by
myself okay so first of all open the
init setup let's show okay that is
that's a that's the content i want copy
the content select all wait
select or copy
then create a new file create a new
paste the content here show in browser
yeah let's close
let's say
tdt
its name
tt okay
is that right yes and we don't want the
we don't want this topic box
okay that's a template for this
that's a template for
all the files i'm going to create
that's correct okay we got the template
uh and you need to rename this
okay you need to rename them them
properly let's do that later okay so
okay but anyway we got the template so
let's let's open let's do them quickly
so let's open that's good so this one
it's copy
put the content copied okay
okay let's make a link
make a link
okay
now open each one of them
open
create
paste
showing browser fantastic close
open yes
create yes paste close
save
create yes paste close save
open create yes paste close save
open yes
paste close save open yes paste close
save okay
now what about this
this already exists
delete that make them into a link
now showing browser fantastic we have
just created these
files each one is kind of a template
okay
now
all we have to do is split the buffer
let's make the content let's now add the
content okay
so emacs misinit tips okay open that
showing browser
yeah this miscellaneous init tips
so
okay let me work on this so that
so that um it's good let's go to here
okay so
miss init files
go to emacs blog
so
copy cut paste keys okay
open it
show in browser that's empty that's
right so
here
yeah so
select that
okay
fantastic we have moved the content here
fantastic that's
almost done you know we need to modify
edit later
now
now uh delete selection okay copy it
delete selection make typing override
selected text okay
there it is
you want to paste it here
okay fantastic close
next
emacs init file encoding okay
set default file encoding cut
paste
fantastic
close okay next
emacs refresh file okay so refresh file
automatically fantastic let's go to here
fantastic okay close
now
move arrow down
e max arrow down move by line okay arrow
down move by line now that's um
okay so that's about
line margin line line wrap line spacing
okay move down arrow let's just copy
that
what wait uh
where are we
what
oh we don't have the html okay we need
to fix something so you see
the file name is incorrect that's why
you don't see the coloring because the
file name doesn't have the extension
therefore it doesn't kicks in the html
mod so first of all you
rename the file look at this magic so i
just press a key
change the file name on the fly
i don't have to
i don't have to go to diode and change
there so but anyway so now you open it
showing browser fantastic
so now this is about
uh
what is this one about move down arrow
by line yeah so cut that
paste
showing browser fantastic close
adjust margin okay let's ignore that now
or just margin let's put it here okay
you know that
next
make lines not soft wrap
uh
okay soft wrap yeah here
cut
make lines not soft wrap
paste here showing browser
fantastic
close
and next
hard wrap
okay hard wrap so open that
open that
cut
the format lines
okay so yeah so this is the section we
want
reformat lines
paste it here
and make sure you put the title there as
well
yeah you don't need that so reformat
reformat reformat lines okay
then you have a section make sentence
ending by a single space okay that's
related we talked about let's
go back here
okay
show in browser
fantastic okay now we have these
fantastic comments and questions
hi hi frenzy frenzy
are you the frenzy i know fancy from
from
belgium
uh
so next
so let's okay so next
close that oh we done we done so
showing browser
now show this window in browser
let's see what's left
so adjust margin that's something that
needs to go somewhere
line margin line wrap line spacing
uh
well most most of the content for that
we already moved to somewhere else
so
line margin line wrap line spacing okay
it's kind of related okay
now fixed scroll where should it go
it's related to the down arrow that's
right so okay so fixed yeah so let's cut
that
and go back to here down arrow key move
by
visual line okay and paste here and show
in browser
so it's kind of related so put them
together there
and in fact this is also related to
highlight current line you know like you
are looking at right now highlighting
line
yeah
so in fact the highlight command line is
very inefficient so this here is a
little digression okay because you know
i think
you see
now let me turn it off okay turn it off
now you see this is default emacs you
don't you don't highlight the current
line
however in some editors you know
starting around year 2000 some editors
has a feature
that
the current line is always always
highlighted i you know i didn't like it
but
i started to use it about a month ago
and it's okay
but in imax look you know it's
inefficient it actually slows you down i
mean by
you know by a fraction of a second
let's look at the source code you know
let's do a bit digression and look at
the source code of the highlight current
line so what you do is you describe key
then press the key i have set up for
that command so you can look at you can
see
here's an inline documentation for the
command
global high line mod okay and now you
can you know
for me i said the key to f7 into f7 is
uh
is actually just this key
wait is it f7
what why is it f7
it should be f9 i don't know how it got
f7
okay okay that's some bugs i need to fix
in one of my packages or something
anyway so let's
so highlight global high high line mod
so let's jump to the source code you
know it's gonna have a lot of code
uh you know it does you know
so let's let's read
this a little bit so the documentation
so
toggle line highlighting
in all of us okay because in if called
interactively enable global high line
mod
okay
okay that tells you how to toggle it
okay now if
global high line sticky flag is
the neo
that's that's the emax this jargon very
unintuitive it should be banned they
should just say true and false
you know but because of emac these
technicalities they have to say neo or
neo
but to a typical programmer what the
is neo and neo you know so
the proper way or better way
it should systematically in every image
this documentation documentation
change all this wording of the neo just
to say true t-r-u-e you
know if something something is true then
something if
if this flag is true or false then do
something you know that's a much more
intuitive documentation
but the emax phonetics the the hacker
types you know the unix linux you know
the c coders you know they'll say oh but
that's technically incorrect
because that's ambiguous because in emac
this you know
there's no boolean
but you have t you know and neo you have
because well emac this everything
that's not neo the value neo neo is both
a symbol and a variable fairly complex
okay
in emacs you have the literal value of
neo in il okay literal
and and that neo is both a symbol and
both a variable it's both okay so it's
getting in so i'm talking about getting
into technical details so in max this
you don't have a boolean value okay but
rather you just have like neo
the neo in a boolean context is means
false
everything else is true so
the integer one is true
you know the the the
you know zero is also true
you know any string is true
a empty string is also true
except the only thing that's new is neo
itself and
empty list okay that's that's false
so that's a technical technical detail
that's why
the emacs documentation says you know
global highlander blah blah blah is the
neo now if it is neo then something
something that's why they use the jargon
the neo you know that's the dragon they
use so i would say i would
simply say true and force okay for the
e-max for those people who understand
emac these technicalities they know they
know what true and force means okay
anything that neo is true
and empty list and neo are false very
simple if you know if you are uh imagine
this programmer you know it but if you
are not you if you are just an emacs
user you can still understand it okay
true or false you know
so anyway that's that's some you know
some technical details about emac this
uh documentation improvements i i would
say so anyway so the global highlight my
sticky flag
global highline sticky flag if this
variable is
the new if it's true then global high
line mod highlights the line about the
current buffers
point in all live windows
oh okay so this is there's more
complexities you know so what it is what
it is saying is that if you have
two windows you know emacs call them
frames
another edlc but anyway so if you have
two windows both of them show the show
the same buffer okay for example right
now
you see let's go to the top okay let's
go to the top let's go to the top you
see so this
this page is emacs init tips okay same
thing here they are the same buffer okay
just
emacs can do that you can show them in
you know
two or more
uh windows
so
so what that
highlight you know this flag this
variable is talking about is that if you
have
you know the same buffer should they
should it highlight you know
both of them
you know so so if that flag is on if
that flag has a value true it will
highlight both of them you know we can
try it let me show you okay let's just
digress it's uh try it
set
that to true okay evaluate it
now let's switch to this window
you see
you see over there you see
now they highlight both because they are
actually they are the same buffer you
know so it's a technical detail so which
one do you prefer that's the question
essentially that's what this flag is for
you know e-max is meant to be you know
for
every possible preferences they have
they have a way so that's that's what
that is
and it should be new okay that's you
know the default you know
it's kind of silly you know good
it's not it's not bad to have lots of
options
uh
yeah but anyway that's emacs okay so
so then it says global high line mod
uses the function global high line
highlight okay that's a function it
actually calls okay
and uh
in global high line maybe a highlight on
post command hook that's a great
content this line
is actually telling you how this how
this works okay so basically when you
have it on
then
well then what happens is that it adds a
hook
to it adds this
you know these two commands to the hook
post command hook
so do you know what is a hook let me
explain okay maybe
so people here fantastic hello yup
that's me hello frenzies great
thank you for coming by
so
this disney says hi as a guy who knows
chinese can you deduce some stuff on
these
bless symbolics what are you talking
about
are you trying to be smart
are you trying to be
a smartie like
hi as a guy who knows chinese can you
deduce some stuff from
bless symbolic what you talking about
i mean without any prior study of
blessed symbolics and i have no idea
what the what what is blessed symbolics
okay let's search for it
oh
let's see bless symbolics communication
international
you know they're back what the is
that
magnify okay
actually i don't want to use chrome
browser you know right now you are
looking at chrome browser nasty you
don't know what it does google these
days you know they they can they can
have like
things inside the browser you never know
they know everything they they looked at
all your photos your your bedroom photos
on your computer you know they have an
option right there you know like you
click on the settings
you know
and uh you click on you know this is
chrome browser you know google empire
you know they they run usa basically
today
you know
like uh like 30 or something you know
then then other corporations you know
all your companies and
you know big companies spanking they run
usa so you know you go to chrome browser
then you go to um
search engine security and privacy okay
then clear browsing data cookies and
other site data security say browsing
yeah very safe very very safe
google knows everything about you make
sure nobody else knows
you know then this there's a thing i
want to show you okay
oh there it is
wait
chrome can help keep you
chrome can help keep you safe from data
breaches and back bad extensions and
more check now
you know if i press that something's
gonna happen i'm not gonna thank you
google thank you for your help i don't
want it
but
but there is something i want to show
you advanced okay
system
where where where this
reset and there it is
there it is reset and clean up
restore settings to the original
defaults okay
then there it is this clean up computer
this is browser this is google chrome
browser now it's gonna have a it's it
has a option
to clean up your computer let's click on
that
the easy
find find harmful software you know so
the google chrome browser
now is becoming a virus checker for you
thank you google you know they are so
helpful they're gonna check virus
they're gonna check your whole computer
for viruses
that yeah that's google
uh
well we getting into politics you know
getting into
politics uh let's not go there you know
i you know i don't let's not go there no
so
so yeah so so we are looking at the
global high line mod so you see
you know what's a hook you know
um
exactly
so
naraja
you know
said what is a hook okay so hook
in in normal programming languages in
javascript it's called event okay so it
basically such as event
so
so what
what this global highlight high line mod
is going to do if you turn it on it's
basically
whenever there's an event called post
command okay basically whenever a
command is called in emacs you know in
emacs everything is a command you know
even if i press
arrow key
that's a command you can see
oh i i remove that but anyway that the
the arrow key command let me show you
okay describe key then i press the right
arrow you can see
it's calling the command command right
cha okay it's not showing up in the pink
window because that's filtered out
otherwise it's you know the moving
cursor is gonna spam
the command lock that's why i filter it
out but anyway the emacs every key you
type is a command
so red arrow does you know it calls
right right chart that's a command
so in emacs everything is about key and
command you type something
it that you know whatever you type
that's mapped to a command even if you
insert a character let's say i type t
you know that's inserting a character
that's a command okay for example let me
show you that's that's called insert
insert
uh char okay for example
ctrl h
k for describe key now i type t
now you can see
oh yeah it calls the command self insert
command you see so in emacs the
fundamental the most important principle
is that it just
intercepts your keys and whatever you
you're the key
is mapped to a command it is then it is
a command the command will be called it
is a command that actually do whatever
insert the character move the cursor
close a window delete a word or whatever
anything you do so emax so that's why
that's the most fundamental principle of
emacs that's why the original you know
that's
that's inherited from
you know that's what emacs was you know
taco it was called taco you know
basically key marker system
and it
evolved into emacs and with the entire
emac base language but but the
principles still remain it's
key macro you know it's actually just
kim aqua
okay so
so we
so here so so let's go back to the um
to the global highlight let me explain
what's going on there okay global high
lines okay so you so everything is a
command so
the post command hook
that's emacs jargon that means
that means post command event okay so
whenever a command is called
after the command is called
it will call the function
global high line
highlight
or the function global high line
maybe on highlight
okay so basically
every command you know
every command you type everything you
know because emax is all about commands
every key you type it calls a command
then that command
then then it will automatically call
highlight or on highlight
that's how this works
and this is very very
inefficient fairly inefficient you know
whenever you add whenever you add you
know to a hook especially this one post
command hook
that means almost every thing you do
it it does you know it has to call
another command
so that's that's how the
that's how the highlight command line
works
okay
i mean yeah the global highlight
mod you know
and let's we can go to the actually go
to the
you know go to the source code and look
at the source code so here is the global
high line mod so you can see
here's a code you can see it just had a
hook
you know it adds to not not not just the
post command hook not just that event it
also adds to change major mod event
uh
yeah uh okay two of them two events and
that
inefficient okay that's that's fairly
inefficient
so i can
so is it it's it's possible to
to write a global high line mod
without
um
well you can reduce you know you can
make your site here more efficient but
the problem is that when you switch you
know when you switch window
anyway so so
yeah so it um
you know adding to the post command hook
is not
you know it's it's somewhat inefficient
okay
so for example we can look at the value
of the hook post command hook okay so
describe
variable
okay and show it
expand window you can see post command
hook is a variable defined in css code
so that means this command is written in
c
so it's its value is
uh
wait
yeah okay so for you know
there's a cur the value for the current
buffer and there's a value for the
global
uh
globally so for the current buffer the
value of that hook is this
function
jit lock anti-blink post command okay
no idea what that is
but the global value is you know uh
jesus you see the this
many commands okay let me show you what
that is okay so copy that
copy that open a new buffer paste it
magnify and uh
you know that's one long line hard to
read so let me call excel command to
split them into
a word per line okay
so you can see
so the post command hook has all these
things right now
so that means every key you press
every command it's gonna call this one
two three four you know eight functions
what are they so far luck mod czech
buffer uh jesus
eldar jesus
display line numbers smart check buffers
jesus global exam math input mod check
buffers oh jesus
i don't want that that's that's my
that is my mod math input mod
why does it have that because it's i
believe it's a minor because it's a
minor mod whenever you have a minor mod
emacs automatically create this
then global command log mod check above
us that's this one you see
yeah that's that's how it works because
every time i call command the command
shows up in the command log
so it relies on this
post command event
okay then global high line maybe on
highlight you know that's that and
global highlight
high line highlight you know it has to
on highlight because in order when you
when you move the cursor it has to
unhighlight the previous
line
so uh and and there is the clm zap
recent history i have no idea what that
is
like
what clm zap recent history
oh god command log mod command log mod
is also not good i've been wanting to
rewrite it
myself write my own version
so anyway so
in general you don't want the you don't
want this you know so
so what i'm going to say is that
so i was kind of claiming this is you
know the way global high line mod works
is a bit inefficient
it's not
optimal
but
is that is that claim justified you know
is that claim justified for example in
vs code
in visual studio so let's open vs code
for example
okay so that's one of my commands open
ev in vs code so your you know in
vs cody which is um let's see if we can
magnify yeah we can fantastic
so vs code
you know you also have the feature
let's see let's look at vs code let's
see
it automatically highlight the
matching pairs
okay
so in vs code
i'm pretty sure you can also set up
set it up so that it highlights the
current line okay you go to the settings
um
okay let's do it shall we preferences
settings then okay then
got so many so
text editor workbench windows features
so
what is
text editors what is is commonly used
okay auto save font size from family tab
size
cruiser style
multi-cursor modifier insert
spaces uh
insert spaces when pressing tab okay
word wrap that's what we were talking
about in emacs word wrap
file file is exclude associations
okay
uh text editor
oh god so i we are looking for the
feature of highlighting the current line
so cuz okay it's probably related to
cursor okay so
auto closing brackets auto closing
delete
control whether whether the editor
should remove adjacent closing quotes or
brackets when deleting oh okay
auto closing over type
guard
auto surround
code lines control where the editor
shows
code lens now what the is that
that's that's uh jargon code lens
so color decorators column selection
where so where do i find
the
folding highlight where do we find the
highlight current line so let's see
what
multiple implement
multiple definitions okay well oh god
this is so long
okay let's click on that see what
happens
cuz cruiser blinking cursor smooth
correct
animation
who's a style line control the cruiser
style okay
cruiser surrounding lines control the
minimal number of visible leading and
trading lines
surrounding the cruiser known as
score off or score of set in smaller
control the minimum number of visible
leading and trailing lines
surrounding the cruiser
what
let's say one let's see what must be
your number let's see one
okay
okay i believe that set let's go back to
e-max i mean two here no
control when closer surrounding lines
should be enforced
yeah i'm not sure that what that is
return it to zero
okay i don't know where it is there's a
lot of settings to go through so this is
this is the visual studio you know the
vs code
analogous to emacs init
and they are saved
by a json file actually
so the emax init
uses emac lisp
as the configuration
the but vs code uses javascript json
format
so
um
you know we could right now
open up the json format you know i have
to search i don't know where it is so
you can search it and you can find where
the
file location for the json format
okay i'm rambling over so
i think we should stop and that's it for
today so
so okay where is the line let's see
where is the feature of highlighting the
current line where is the setting so do
we have let's look quickly
uh testing debug terminal task problems
output comments
application
security
extensions okay i don't care about
extensions
there must be somewhere in the course
blink
okay let's search okay
pass
what what pass
what pass okay let's let's quickly
search
vs code
highlight column line there it is
how to highlight color line number
in with
in in vs code how to highlight a line
number
what
oh
they want to you know it tries to
highlight the current line number
oh
okay you know there's a feature it
highlights the current lines number
uh but that's not
exactly what i want
what i want is
how to highlight current line
there it is that's the settings
okay i don't i don't know let's forget
about that
so
what i was saying is that
the global highline mod you know we are
trying to determine
whether we could say that the way emacs
implemented
implement implement it
the way emacs implemented
it
whether it's inefficient or not
you see the thing is
in order to do that from a
general algorithmic point of view is
that
you have to know
every time you move the cursor you have
to tell it because
you see
the gist of that is that highlight
online is that whenever the cursor is
moved doesn't matter by what means even
switching window whenever the cursor is
moved
you have to you know that's the event
you have to tell it
so that it can remove the highlight then
highlight somewhere else
so that is essential this event is
actually essential
so
and emacs is doing exactly that you know
the is exactly the
that so
so actually but the problem with emacs
you know the reason i say it's
inefficient is that it's actually
because the way the the e-max hooks
they are not very low level they are
kind of a bit high level so it involves
lots of
coding functions and that's not
efficient so i would
imagine
in vs code
you know how however they do it
essentially they also have to check the
event whenever the event happens moving
cursor happens
then it does the highlight you know
but but i would imagine in vs code
this is done
in a lower level
okay so i don't know for sure but that's
that's
that's my guess
because in emacs you know i know from
experience whenever you have this hook
you know post command hook especially
post command hook because that happens
you know every
multiple times per second you know like
right now i press the arrow down
you know
it repeats you know 20 times per second
and that means the post command hook
every function in it is called
20 times per second
for each and every function in the post
command hook
so and i know it's inefficient because i
run emac this
script that processes thousands of files
and whenever you have a
hook on opening file it slows down
tremendously
you know for example one minute jobs
becomes four minutes
or even more you know in that case in
the in opening final case
so anyway so let's go back so that's
that's it for today okay that's it for
today
we shutting down
and so
yeah so we shut down in in in three
minutes
yeah so i talked uh for
2 13 so we talked for 70
minutes
okay that's it anything else
let's shut down then okay so
we we talked about a bunch of things so
let's
make it to the
gold paste them in
the
what's going on
paste in today's code
you know what we talked about close this
window back here
global high line mod okay so we kind of
talked about global highlight mod
so go to talk show
uh
today's top show
close that
paste it here somewhere okay
actually
paste my tutorial
paste the link to my tutorial on global
highline mod okay so let's do that
so because now we have let's go to emacs
blog so we have
did we actually have a page on global
highline mod oh my god i didn't
okay let's do that then
oh yeah so we have a lot more stop
cursor blinking
set cursor to ibm
set up emacs so that each file opens in
a new window yeah you can do that
but where is global highline mod
what
copycat paste keys delete selection init
file encoding you need file
encoding
okay this is should not be named init
file encoding so let's change the name
it should be just code file encoding
so let's see
if we already have a name like that
no okay so
let's rename it what what's going on
uh
emacs blog okay so rename this file
press a key to rename it
file encoding okay
emacs file encoding and
okay and we need to rename the titles
okay
then
refresh file arrow down move by line
okay and
line soft wrap
yeah we don't have we don't have global
high line mod okay god
let's search
okay i'm getting tired i need to get off
so let's search my emacs tutorial about
the word global highline mod so
i will find all my existing
page about this
so you can see i blocked it multiple
times in the past
2012 2015
then what is this then
then this is 2015
indeed file tutorial
and
[Music]
oh yeah we do have this page yeah there
it is so showing browser
yeah highlight color line
so
so this is already part of the emacs
init so we already have a in the
independent page on it
that's good
okay so copy that copy the link
copy the link go back to talk show
today's talk show
and
replace that by my
link to my tutorial
showing browser
fantastic
okay now let's let's now let's go back
to
finish something we need to do we need
to rename this
uh
you know rename this tt you know
let's finish that
okay so open so what is this uh
emacs copycat paste keys okay so let's
rename it
emax
copy cut paste keys
set up standard copy cut paste keys okay
let's show the pink window
let's
turn off the multiple
frames
you know multiple windows
change the title
show it
okay
then this one open it
make typing override selected test okay
so let's
call command
type overwrite selection
fantastic
because
open this one what is this set default
file encoding okay
fantastic
now open that one
refresh file
okay
refresh file automatically showing
browser fantastic now we don't need the
we don't need the section we don't
we don't need a section
okay because that's just one thing
okay next
open it
down arrow key move by
screen lines or logical lines okay
down arrow behavior so what what should
you name this
this
page so
okay
e-max
down arrow
screen line
or logical line okay
set up down arrow
key
for screen lines or logical line okay
showing browser
okay that's kind of
uh yeah
okay so
by the way that's a new feature in emacs
23 and emacs 23 came out in 2009 you
know i've been writing this emacs
tutorial for
for for 17 years
um
okay close that so there's a question
i'm gonna answer it can you sometimes
maybe talk about
collaborative editing in emacs there is
a mod but never tried it
there's no no such thing i mean that
that's not a emacs thing emacs doesn't
you know this doesn't um
really do that
so i mean so
this related feature i can tell you okay
let me finish rename it rename these
things let me a few more okay
then we let me answer that question
so make lines not soft wrap okay
okay so this page will be named
um
let's copy it
let's show the pink window so you can
see
what commands i'm calling
line is not soft wrap
okay so let's rename rename this to be
for now set up softwrap lines you know i
add a word set up there because you know
that's a tip about naming of things
because when you have the word setup
because the word setup is a very general
word meaning you know
configuration setting up things sets up
you know alternatively but but however
setup is not the
conventional word to uh used by emacs
typically the ema the way emacs way
the emacs way of talking about any file
is is saying customization you know
customize you know so the proper title
for this page by the emacs
community would be
how to customize
line wrap
you know
yeah that would be the title
by the emacs
kind of community how to customize
line wrap display or line wrap
appearance you know
but if you have that you know people you
know but that's not broad you know like
people who don't know emacs yet
they don't know
the world they should use the word
customized to them they just need they
just know set up
how do i set up how do i make how do i
make emacs show the line wrap in certain
way you know they don't know the word
customize
so anyway that's some of the details so
some of the analysis
um so
now we have now this page
uh let's say hot wrap lines okay for now
okay so now
we have changed the title to each one of
these files
they have a proper title now a better
title instead of just
using the h
the file name
so now we can we need to rename i mean
not rename but
make the links
make the link text use the title okay so
one easy way is to do that is that i
call command
to extract all the links okay
in the block okay now i paste the link
here
now i do uh
now i actually just re-link them okay
then i create a list okay now i'll show
you in browser so you can see
here are the old
and here are the new
okay now i can just
delete the old showing browser
fantastic
okay almost done so now
we begin you know
in my tutorial the init setup we begin
by moving out
lots of these miscellaneous tips
to become independent files by itself
so
so now
go back so now let's go back so now we
need to put each and every one of these
links
into
into the side panel here
okay you see what i'm saying
so let's do that so then you know why
not it's you know because that's what i
need to do so
so copy the link again you know extract
all the links in this block okay then
open the
root page of the emacs init setup that
page okay
now
paste the link here
yeah now i need to link them okay link
them make a list show in browser okay i
need to put these links in the panel for
each and every
of the page okay so now we
so essentially that means i need to do
find replace on on this panel text
for all files in the directory
so
this is the panel text i copy it
then i call command
start find replace okay
now paste it i want to replace this code
this
block of text huge block of text that's
the panel okay and enter
and what is my replay stream okay i
don't know yet so i cancel it
so now let's generate let's create a new
panel for that includes you know
includes these new things
so in order to do that let's create a
new panel let's i mean let's modify the
panel first of all i need to delete the
word emax because that's repeated
you know people already know this about
emacs
so
refresh so it's gonna be like that
then i'm gonna for now
let's just add it
let's just add somewhere here okay i'm
gonna work on it later but now i'm just
gonna show you my kind of workflow so
now
okay now i just cut this
now i call
something replace again
up arrow
up arrow up arrow
what wait
okay undo okay so
this is the text we want to find replace
copy it
call suffer and replace paste it
okay enter
cancel let's
then the new text i want is this okay
let's do it again up arrow yeah up arrow
replace this text enter
now what's the new text okay
of arrow again the same old text
but now over here
let's insert the new one here there you
there you go
okay
enter
then in all this directory yes
file path regular expression dot html
yes
minimal directory depth 0 yes
maximum directory depth 99 okay
write changes to file yes
fixed case in search yes
fixed case in replacement yes
make backup yes
done
now you can press down arrow you can see
all these files changes change changed
no now you can do
these matching lines and type users and
you can see
that's all the files that's changed
you know that's
about 50 files okay
but now you can close this and go to the
browser refresh
you can see
there they are there it is
fantastic
these are the pages we created now the
next thing i need to do is to
move all these into the appropriate
category you know
whether that setting is about text
editing
or about
files auto save auto backup restore open
file or is it about appearance
such as global highlight
highline mod you know i need to
make do this change again but i was just
showing you my workflow okay that's it
for that that's it for today
my my tutorials okay that's what i'm
here for by my tutorials emacs tutorials
great information
you know uh and emac this okay pay me
patreon
here's my sponsors okay my sponsor says
saudi
and i'm gonna talk for five minutes
about this patreon amazon gift card
fantastic and paypal and bitcoin
where do i host my site it's an old
classic
uh
host website hosting it's called 1n1.com
they got bought by some other companies
so it's no longer one-on-one but it's
called i'm not i'm not gonna promote
them but you know there's a lot you can
choose today
uh
so i that's it for today you came in
late so there's a question i want to
answer even okay so can you sometimes
talk about the collaborative editing
yeah so collaborate collaborative
editing you know it's
um you
you don't really i mean that's not like
a
feature of text editors i mean that's
kind of just a
more more kind of a
zuma's movement
you know because
well yeah i guess because the kovid
pandemic
you now work at home
and uh but before in the office you can
[Music]
sometimes talk to your co-workers and
you can work together on the same screen
you know like
thank you oh flamio
okay so so you know so you have like um
you know you you have uh what what the
extreme programming you know you have
you know
so
now you work at home
so how do you do club so so
collaborative editing became kind of
thing so
the you know the
the thing you want is that you can
work remotely with someone and editing
the same file so basically what you do
is you you go to the init okay let me
cut down the chase get to the point
uh what you want is um one of the
feature you want to turn on is um
okay the file section auto revert okay
oh wait that's something we did today
yeah refresh file automatically
so you want to put this into your init
file so when you are editing the file
and if someone also
you know if you have the file open in
your e-max buffer if someone is also
edited it
your buffer will automatically
detect
that it's changed and your refresh okay
so you want this feature it doesn't
always work
it does not always work so that's why i
say
this is not actually not a strong point
of emacs but however you know how so how
do you collaborate so you
you use emacs your friends your
co-worker use emacs both of you
log into a server
where your company's you know code or
whatever and you can both work on the
same file and you know while
uh sharing your screen you know or you
know discord whatever you use you know
zoom
you know you can talk to each other and
then so that's how you
i you know i suppose that's that's how
you do collaborative
editing
okay so you can you know you share a
screen and you can you know so
you guys can chat and work on the same
file
okay so that's it so basic so turn this
on and that's
that's basically
basically it and you also of course you
need to learn
how do you log in remotely so i
um
you know that's so that's a feature
called um
you know actually i don't have that a
tutorial for that feature it's called
there's a name for that you know it's um
you search it you'll find it you know
okay so so what one there are multiple
ways okay
there are two
main ways of using emacs to work on a
file a remote file on a server somewhere
on a machine somewhere okay one
way
is you use ssh okay
this is the way i prefer okay so you go
to a terminal
like right now you are looking at my
powershell you know the windows terminal
you ssh to a server
then
then you can start emacs okay so then
you can start emacs within your terminal
okay so let's see
let's see yeah so there is my emacs
command
and let's see let me show you uh running
emacs in terminal okay
now today's been a long session now it's
90 minutes
thank you luis trump is the word okay so
there are two ways to work
on a remote file using emax one way is
using ssh
which is the way i prefer
the other way is which i
i haven't used much okay so
ssh let me show you okay so you you just
access ssh to a remote server then all
you have to do is um
dash enqueue that means
run this in terminal
run emacs in terminal
oh god in the windows version you have
some issues got okay so wait hold on a
second let me and let me show you okay
foreground uh god okay so i'm in
powershell i'm not in bash so
the foreground doesn't work so i don't
know what happened to that
so so what you have to do is you instead
of calling run emacs you want to call
emacs yeah there
okay no window okay so this will run
emacs in terminal okay there we have it
okay
uh let's see do i have class soft like
he's a god
how do i switch to
okay so i you know i haven't used emacs
in terminal especially on windows for a
long time so how do i switch where is my
meta key
yeah god that's pops you know
okay
wait wait wait is my meta key god
escape
escape space
space
and control key way
okay so i
i'm
i was going to okay let's exit okay
control xc
now um
what what is
god
insert mod
wait what what is my us keyboard okay
control x c exit okay now let's do it
again
and now let's not load my init file okay
now here is x this here is uh emax
default gnu emacs in terminal
now you want to open a file for example
let's open
web
sorry info okay
x22 okay and
starting for emacs okay
uh blog let's see emacs
okay so you are looking you know you are
in terminal so
okay so anyways this is one way to
work remotely you know you ssh to the
machine you rely on that machine the
remote machine have emacs installed okay
that's one way the other way is
i'm not gonna add you know
you can just look up you'll find um how
to
transparent remote file access multiple
protocol yeah that's uh
i used it for a while but
it's over over 10 years ago
but something
there was something i want to show you
i want to show i want to show saffly
keys
in terminal it works okay but
that's it for today okay bye guys
yeah i haven't i haven't run terminal in
emacs for a long time so
in order first of all i need to
i need to not have a black background
because
let's try it again
so soft like keys
the command delete backward that's right
so let's see
control space control space runs the
command soft like keys command mod
activate okay great
so let's activate command mod
what
oh it works it works look now i can move
cruiser if i would you see without
holding ctrl alt you see
now i can delete the the word you can
see
or dd the whole line
delete the whole block
or
select copy it paste it paste the whole
block
paste it
and one key to expand the window do it
fantastic so soft like keys my friends
so we can actually
open my init file so let's let's open
the file so go to
web
so this is stuff like keys
in terminal in windows terminal
so ergo emacs uh so go to xrd
info
e-max okay e-max
okay emacs
actually i have my you know instead of
typing the path i can just
call myself open file fast you know
let's do it
fantastic
this is so you are looking at
you are looking at
you know my emacs blog you know you are
looking at
where is it
yeah you are looking at that page that's
the terminal that's uh you know let's
scroll up you see
emacs fantastic okay oh wow the the
background
also works now you see something doesn't
work
the unicode characters
you see
that you
this part you see u2211
that's supposed to be the summation sign
you can see over here
uh but
so why is the unicode not working in
windows terminal windows terminal
supports unicode
so i suppose this is a clock
between
e-max
and terminal somewhere somewhere
somewhere
went wrong e-max and terminal but anyway
so let me show you unicode okay
so let's see yeah so
so you can see unicode emoticon okay
they are not showing properly
you see these are unicorn emojis so
let's see
can we show in browser
yeah
okay you can actually press a key to
show in browser you see
so you are looking at the source code
for this page my unicode page all these
are emojis but somehow
when you run emacs
on windows windows terminal application
they
the emoji does not show up correctly
let's see let's try to find out what's
wrong okay
okay so it looks like it's a found
problem
it's not an encoding problem it's not
any encoding problem it's simply a font
problem so apparently
so i think the way to fix it is that in
windows terminal
you have to do some special settings to
tell it
to tell it to use um
appearance you know to tell it to use a
unicode font you know normally it works
it's just that inside emacs it doesn't
work for example let me open a new
windows terminal and let me show you how
the emoji actually works so you just you
can just go to
cd
let's go let's go to the same page okay
cd web
study info
and study info
emacs
e-max
oh wait we we need to show emoji yeah so
it's gonna be
comp
and unicode what's the name
unicode emoticons
what
why is the completion doesn't work
let's just enter for now
what
the
okay you can see all the files
let's try again
oh yeah
the completion doesn't work because
that's not a directory because we were
using cd now we want to
show the content of the file so that's
cat
okay because cat
is a alias let's see it's magnified okay
cat is the edius for get content okay so
cat
unicode
there it is
so i have a lot of files so unicode
emoticon
okay
so
you see it's cutting that file and you
can see let's go to the beginning you
can see
there is your emoji okay there's a lot
so this demonstrates
that unicode
works in microsoft terminal
without me having to do anything it just
works by default so that means you the
windows terminal can
display unicode properly
but the problem we have here is
emax specific
so for some reason
emacs is not is unable to find
the emoji
found
when inside
windows terminal
it works fine when you are in gui for
example let's open that page
you see
so here's a page that's magnified so you
can see it works fine here but not in
windows terminal
okay
bye that's
bye for
good