good morning welcome to another episode
of XR talk show today is Friday 10th
2019 and we are going to do a lecture
closure the concept of closure and I'm
going to show you what it is and I'm
going to code it in eMac Lisp in
JavaScript in Python okay so so yeah so
let's start let's go to talk so talk
show and closure and we're gonna put
that here
so closure okay JavaScript eMac this
title I'm gonna show you what it is
closure and other things okay so
Oh three people watching great so if you
are here say hi and I'm going to go
straight to closure let's see if my if I
have my windows set up correctly see I'm
talking and my hands that's good
and so let's let's start so let's go to
sorry
closure okay I have several articles
about closure and this is the main one
what is closure in programming languages
and I'm gonna show you JavaScript
closure in JavaScript and in Python and
the emag this Python 3 okay
good morning break the loop so break the
loop says I finally got the mouse I'm
happy with thought GTECH g90 3 worked
from not my left what works for my
left-handed has million buttons infinity
squirrel and true programmable binding
oh that's great
so g90 3 now which one is gene 8:03
let's go to make you what let's I'm glad
let's get back to closure but let's look
at this just quickly g90 300k this one
this one is expensive fancy Mouse
Wireless and super light well not super
light but fairly light compared to all
the other wireless ones and it's
dedicated you know it's it's designed
for Wireless Gaming Mouse
that's great I didn't like this one in
particular I mean not yet this is this
one it's not my idea because the number
buttons are not that much because you
know you have to on the left side and
two on the right side and I don't like
ambidextrous mouse wait you know they
have ambidextrous mouse is a fancy
jargon using the mouse
scamming community they called
ambidextrous ambidextrous means it means
is a characterization characterization
of people's ability to use both right
hand and left hand so you know some
people are right-handed
some people are left-handed and some
people is said to be ambidextrous
meaning that they can use either hand
equally well actually I haven't I'm not
sure that is actually true or what
percentage of people are actually like
that you know I actually I haven't
thought about this thinking about it now
but anyway that you know the ability to
use both right hand and left hand that
concept has always fascinated me and I
always tried to do that but naturally
I'm right-handed but I always try
everything to you know I learned
something with my sometimes with my left
hand at first you know sometimes I use
my left hand to wash my teeth and I've
learned to write with my left hand not
where I haven't been practicing it but
you know I try to do everything with
left hand as well you know because the
idea of ambidextrous meaning you know
it's a capability you know in a sense
like a Superman you know if you can do
everything in so well with both hands
you know for that is great so I've been
trying to do that but anyway back to the
mouse you know ambidextrous so that word
actually describes a the ability to you
know the suttas kind of natural ability
to use either hand but in the mouse
communities is simply useful as a jargon
you know most it basically just means
the mouse is symmetric you know you know
symmetric now I don't like symmetric
Mouse's because when you have a
symmetric Mouse that actually
practically it just means you know
whatever it buttons on the other side
you'll never use it or you know you it
because you won't it won't be optimal
you know it won't be your it will be
hard to use you know so
you know if on the other side whatever
number buttons they have maybe you can
only use one of them you know so I don't
like ambidextrous Mouse's you know and
it got you know these three buttons on
top this button you know that this
button you know one of them is
controlling the spin way we are let me
show you yeah since I'm ok I'm going to
get back to the closure okay but this
mouse is just the fast main topic let me
show you on a second it let's see let me
point to as Windex that's some mouse
right so you got this button
okay this that's the you see now it's
spin mod it stings if I press that now
it's creaky it doesn't spin so it's it's
logic Logitech mouse has this feature if
they call it hyper wheel I think the
mechanism it's pretended you know it's
patent you know so I think because you
don't see it anywhere because they have
guests they have a paid animation but
anyway I spin wheel is absolutely
necessary because let's see let's show
for example you can see spin query in
action hold on a second you see I can
again you know it's spring query action
you know it's fantastic now especially
in linux especially if you are linux
operating system because linux operating
system is suck so bad in every way okay
because because it doesn't have excel
accelerated wheel you know in some
browsers you might have it but it's it
doesn't have a system-wide acceleration
of scrolling and you know when you look
into it you know on website on dark
linux side oh you know that's idiot
linux people this
oh you cannot be done oh it's difficult
to do all we don't want it because the
third button is because for this or that
you know this is stupid
Linux people you know that that is why
they never get anywhere the Linux system
although it's open-source it really
should have already been wiped out
Microsoft you know Windows so whatever
it's free you know three people but the
the system is just so badly that's why
in general Linux things and these hacker
types kicks us in your sense never go
anywhere
I mean this this without scrolling who
your acceleration it's patently stupid
okay because on Linux you know we if you
don't have a squirrel acceleration like
right now you know I see look look at
the actually Emma on a Mac because on a
Mac you have a acceleration you know
building and on Windows there's a
Scorpio acceleration on Windows the last
time I looked at which is about four
years ago or five you do not have
Scorpio acceleration by default okay but
if you buy any Logitech mouse or
Microsoft Mouse then you have Scorpio
acceleration without it's extremely
stupid like right actually you know you
know it's like then you have to use page
now and the problem with page time is
that you know sometimes you like page up
like this is half way like you have an
image that's half way you page down your
holy see the other half you know so it's
it's this so it's not good okay you want
then then you have to use arrow keys
like you know just a little bit you know
it's really stupid but on a Mac or
Windows when you if you have a Scorpio
acceleration that means that means for
example I actually turn it off because I
have spin wheel but let me show
you when I have a smoke wheel squirting
queer acceleration turning down so I'm
turning out wrong
right now so I can go to like any page
by any position in this long page by
just the flick you know like I can go
slowly like Grenaa I'm going very slowly
or I can flick you know all the way to
the bottom you see you see how that is
you know like like this this this page
is 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
you know it's like 20 pages 20 screen
pages now with queer acceleration I can
go all the way down okay
1 2 3 you know just 3 wipes now if I do
not have acceleration it's it's like and
this by the way I think when you turn
this all the way to the left is still
have acceleration so it's actually this
is already actually working well but on
Linux it's like use it doesn't matter
how fast you try to score it's like each
time it's like you know it's it's
extremely painful okay so this is one
another example of the extreme idiocy of
the Linux people the hacker types you
know I know a lot of you they all say
every time we talk about need not say oh
well I have no problem with Linux Venus
works great for me yeah that's all you
are not actually you you are you are
delusional you are not actually you know
you are pious you don't see so many
aspects of things any I mean let's be
concrete this is one concrete example
try to tell me that you know accelerate
accelerated score doesn't matter try try
to say that you can't not you know and
also a lot of people Linux for example
in this case then they might say oh I
don't need it because you know I page
pitch down you know pay chip works fine
for me I actually know because a lot of
us it is it's simply your habit like
right now like if today I don't have
spin wheel I don't have Logitech mouse
and suppose I don't have a you know
Elena's I just you just get used to it
you know that's how flexible adaptation
humans ah you know like we went to the
moon fifty years ago without you know at
the time we don't have computers we
don't how computers you know it's what
what's the memory size one g one
megabyte size you know we are still
using slider rules you know but we went
to the moon that's extremely complicated
engineering you know but we we you know
human you know we we you know how
difficult something is it's all relative
you know we just work we just walk
through it so we can almost overcome in
a sense overcome anything you know you
know people in prison you know there are
great mathematicians who are in prison
you know like all their life or
something or you know for decades and
they created you know some of the
greatest theories or you're not even
mathematicians you can see you know some
of the people in fictions or in movies
you know people in prison they just do
things they get creative you know and so
you know sense
back to today you know we are all kind
of very spoiled you know we we leave our
social networks you know and anyway back
on back to the acceleration so I turned
the acceleration off because and because
I have spin wheel so wheel I just
when you have spin wheel it's best not
to have external acceleration because
the speed you scroll the page will be
solely depend on how fast you spin a
wheel so you can you can control it you
know more precisely for example this is
my email page I can spin it lets show
let me show you okay let me let me show
you okay you see right now even in email
I turned off acceleration you can turn
it off by if you just such Sally Emacs
Mouse okay yeah
sir the Emacs Marseille that you can
find how to set up the acceleration in
Emacs okay not not this one
how do you change keybinding computer
Emacs mouse setup
well it's here you know you just go to
the keyboard setup and you'll find a
link to the yeah there how to set mouse
buttons
how does make masks we will not
accelerate yeah this page so anyway that
that is about mouse acceleration now
let's go back to yeah so this mouse
again you know hey I always have each to
buy another mouse even though I have you
know I have you know quite a few they
are not ideal but you know so this was
great because it's wireless but it's not
ideal to me though because it's
symmetric but it's you know it's
Wireless the one of the great thing
about it isn't it is Wireless there's a
lot of things about you know I in
general I don't like Wireless things
because when you have wireless it's
prone to you know hacking you know they
hackers they can listen to your your
mouse devices they you know whenever you
have higher wireless it's always prone
to that risk and doesn't matter it's
Bluetooth or or you know customized
radio wave it always prone to being
hacked and you don't know yeah I mean
you can know those things so let's get
back to the mouse is so let's see let's
get back to the comment so I got eight
people watching so feel free to you know
comment like I say anything opinions you
have so break the loop break the loop
are you smart squeal I use mouse wheel
lean left and lean right for two more
buttons okay yeah not sure if that's
right okay
and I refined those two DPI buttons
below mouse wheel to other functions
total you have imbalance not easy press
too difficult okay yeah the other thing
not ideal to me about these
Logitech mouse is you see the middle
buttons it's kind of like two tiny small
ones in the middle you know so that's
not I mean it's not ideal that is all
but you know we like when you look at
people who are obsessed about mouse or
keyboard
you always find people like they always
complain yeah I looked at all the
hundreds of keyboards or Mouse but they
are not ideal because this one is
missing that you know each person has
always have differences little
preferences so anyway so I'm glad you
find you know the idea Mouse for you
yeah so of you guys out there you want
to buy a mouse go to my website ok sorry
just search for my mouse page I have
tons of reviews and buy it for my web
web page so let's see where's a mouse
mouse mouse trackball you know here's
another interesting topic you see this
Apple scums Apple and Google you know
these companies comes you see this this
mass this is you know what that is that
is a Unicode okay that is a Unicode four
three button Mouse now when you are in
Mac OS you know when when you are in
your apples platform you know I follow
you know Mac that they show the three
button Mouse like that so what so this
is a situation where the emoji you know
the Unicode character emoji has become
very politicized and commercialized you
know the idea the idea of Unicode aside
for communication you know it helps or
human animals you know you have one
encoding and you can have you know you
can express Chinese English Italian and
French you know o in one language you
know Germany or Japanese you know in one
encoding so you have multiple language
and and then you have emojis you know
it's supposed to help us communicate or
fulfill you know but today you know it
seems about five years ago
they these emojis become political
political eyes and they are also users
or commercializing marketing tool so
because for example let's go to Unicode
okay so here's a Unicode page and you go
to the tech okay these are a bunch of
technical technology called devices that
has a emoji representation now you see
this character is three button Mouse but
if you are on a Mac it shows like that I
mean does that look like three button
mouse - you know but of course Apple you
know the Apple wants you to think you
know Apple or Mac Mac fans you know they
think this is superior this is their
version of three button Mouse you know
with touching or that you know they like
you but it's not it does not communicate
you know first of all if you look at the
mouse population you know the the mouse
market you know people what people think
when they when it comes to three button
Mouse you know the vast majority are not
not Apple Mouse you know it's just the
elite you know the well thing you need
facts so but you know so it does not
serve the purpose of communication
anymore you know that these companies
each company they just use it to promote
their own product their own platform so
you know how Mac OS 3 word of mouth
looks like that and you know so you have
this this one is called one-button Mouse
this one is too bad a mouse emoji you
know so it's like political you know it
doesn't you know it does not serve the
purpose of communication and the same
way for other emojis you know and also
Google Google is one of the most evil
him in there emoji as well you know like
these emojis when you are on Android or
Google Chrome book you know Google
platform Chrome OS they here
they all these emojis look like androids
android heads you know like with with a
used tray of antennae but now they
remove that it looks like extremely
creepy you know it's like this blob you
know this this semicircular plop
actually I have a article on these
politics of emoji Unicode for
programmers emoji equivalents
I don't I don't have it linked there
because it's a emoji politics let me
show you this page okay then there is
the social justice aspect okay we're not
going to talk about about that today we
talk I talked about that before but
anyway look at these are Google's emoji
for smiley so you know what they'd look
like this creepier is you know it's a
matter of judgment but this was not what
emoji Smiley's common conception of
Smiley's with this you know
semi-circular
blob you know and it really looks creepy
to me it looks like that because it was
you know the rip it was represented by
Android you know the android logo mascot
for Google's Android phone you know with
kind of part you know robot with antenna
you know Google's logos and mascot has
always been very cold and very ugly and
very for some reason Google you know and
they become an evil empire so somehow
reflects actually their their choice of
emoji because look emoji and logos
because look at google chrome logo you
know it looks like a UFO like like if
you look at all Google's logos or their
products logos oh one exception : okay
there is my exception : : has this cute
mask mascot of a
you know gopher so this is one example
exception : but all kugels product you
look at their logos they are they are
always kind of cold the void of any
humanity the void of any you know
humanity or animals or anything like
that it's always like you know just
coding machine when it's machinery like
you know like you know google chrome
logo so for some reason you know
Google's logo has this kind of neck has
this kind of situation across Google you
know and this is even before Google
became evil so for some reason I I'm not
sure why I'm not sure maybe there is a
company-wide
you know thesis about you know what
their logo should be too you know maybe
they have a internal publication you
know to all the logo designers but I'm
guessing parties because Google has
always been very engineer driven you
know company you know at least in the
beginning in the first ten years
everything is based on statistics
measurements you know so they are like
in a sense inhuman that's what you know
that's what that word means in human
because they you know human or being
human is not necessarily a good thing in
many respects because human as human
animals we have we have prejudices we
have biases you know it's building you
know in our brain it's actually just
building and so we are you know our
emotions in the good parts the bad parts
you know empathy our connection to other
people love in hate you know it's all
part of us that's what we call it human
you know its humanity you know humanity
the human issue you know that's a big
unsolved and almost undefinable issue
with
you know that's humanity that's that's
the thing about humanity you know so but
but Google has been always machine and
engineering statistics statistics driven
and by the way also it
we actually it's impossible today we
don't have a way to define what humanity
means actually in any precise or
mathematical way so that's also part of
the problem so anyway that's digression
ok that's let's go back to the Commons
then we're gonna then we're gonna start
to talk about closure I'm gonna I'm
going to talk about that project that
subject for sure because there was what
was promised
ok so Hugh Jones zen says you it then
says I cannot buy this in China I cannot
buy this in China maybe you can add
promotion link to some Chinese online
store I don't have a variation with that
I don't have anything like like that so
I don't know actually
those Chinese you know online shops they
have they have affiliation I haven't
looked into so you know if you are in
China just I guess buy it from China but
actually if you are in China then I do
not recommend you buy this American not
eat a go you know or European things
because in China this logitech orders
they are you know extremely expensive
you know they are more expensive than if
you buy it in US and on the other hand
why are in China you have tons of you
know almost equivalent you know and they
are like five times cheaper so actually
in China I would recommend you just buy
a you know spend some good money buy or
Chinese ones in China
because that way the ratio of quality
features over the price is much better
than if you buy a logitech so break the
loop says I require ambidextrous miles
because I'm left-handed
yeah that's that is true you know there
there are left-handed Mouse's you know
there are a few of them they actually
they are rare but but I have a page you
know that show a few left-handed but
then it's real then you know the
features are not comparable because the
image some of them don't have wireless
some of them are you know not gaming you
know yeah so so yeah just got with the
ambidextrous mouse or rather the
symmetric shaped mass yes infinity score
is good so do you do usually have it set
on smooth yeah I always have a set on
spin spin mod yes smooth but you know
occasionally I find clicky better I mean
occasionally you know just occasionally
quickie is better for some sometimes I
want quickie but usually I'm just too
lazy to switch to quickie but also when
you switch to creaky then I want the
acceleration but then I have to go to
preferences to say that up oh you know
so that's too much trouble so usually I
I just always have it on spinning mod oh
yeah
so but I used to you know I usually have
another Mouse on my left hand you know I
I always use two Mouse's so on that
Mouse or something sometimes it's a
trackball that Mouse is creaky so
whenever I want to quickly I just use
that Mouse so no man says I know man
infrared Wireless is close to impossible
to hack unless you are in the same room
well yeah of course you have to be in
the same room you have to be in a range
right I have always found a Google
design you are aesthetically aesthetic
ugly okay hi can you explain why Emacs
is bad with big files it's just it's
just because green Dex asked that
question that's just because I don't
have technical details but I'm pretty
sure I know the answer the answer is
just because that's the way Emacs was
coded the design of the you know how it
is coded in the beginning thirty years
ago yeah you know so I don't know the
technical details i you know and i don't
actually know much about low-level
programming but I suppose you it has to
do how do you implement you know like
you have you know in the in a case of
Emacs when you read okay here's a reason
when you read a fire when you open up
fire into a buffer in Emacs it has to
read it has to load the whole file you
know from the first character to the
last character into memory okay
that was what Emacs has to do and that
is I know that is not the case in modern
editors I don't think so
so again I'm not sure about details but
I'm pretty sure that is the reason one
thing I know for sure is that when you
open a file in Emacs it it becomes a
buffer right it has to load the whole
thing into the buffer and also the other
thing is that Emacs Church kusa position
by is called the point you know for
example I guess a point point point
point to register anyway so you know for
example I can code is command describe
cha and you know tell me what position I
am on so the position is just for
example the beginning of buffer if my
kusa is that at the beginning that kusa
position called point is what okay
with one for example I call describe key
describe cha and you can see he says
what here so the cursor position is you
know your where your cursor is and that
when you called eMac so every command in
Emacs and you know moving cursor or
whatever it's it's actually coding eMac
this command and eMac this command in
turn is working with kusa positions so
it has to know so in other in other
words the maximum file Emacs can open
depends on you know the maximum integer
Emacs can represent so a few years ago
almost 10 years ago now so Emacs has a
limitation you cannot open any file
larger than few hundred megabytes
something like that this was 10 years
ago because because the maximum integer
it was to raise to 28 or something I
think to raise to 28 today something
like that anyway so integer he has to
you know the maximum number of
characters must be less than the maximum
of number representable integers anyway
so that was the case today I don't know
what is actually we can find out by just
calling max into it
let's see switch to eMac be smart max in
touch okay so wait control max anyway
there is a variable that shows you what
is a maximum integer and that is
basically the maximum file size you can
open basically something like that
okay let's go let's go talk about crow
sure so let's talk about closure so
first of all so what so I'm gonna tell
you what is a closure okay now remember
these okay carefully closure is a
feature programming language closure has
nothing whatsoever with to do with
theoretical computer science it has
absolutely nothing to do with
mathematics now some of you advanced
people may not agree okay when I say
closure has nothing to do with math you
may say oh I disagree because you know
well that's up to debate okay so anyway
I'm just going to give you my point of
view now first of all you want to
understand what closure is right closure
is kind of advanced you know we would
call it advanced concept in programming
or programming languages so if you are
you know if you are beginner programmers
you know if you have just two years or
something
you may not know what it is but I'm
teaching you what it is okay first of
all understand that closure is a feature
a specific feature of programming
languages so that means in some
languages you you know for example in
some languages a function can take a
function as argument you know and return
a function as a result you know some
some programming languages can do that
Haskell can do that Lisp cannot do that
in general but you you kind of other
walk around a JavaScript can do that you
know a function take a function as input
and as argument you know in return a
function as result so JavaScript can do
that Haskell can do that Mathematica can
do that you know some programming
languages can do that some others cannot
well you know programming languages they
have different features you know so
that's you know that's you
Frances in programming languages so
remember closure is just a feature of a
specific feature programming language
some language some languages supported
some not and also you know when you have
a feature in particular language some
people some programmers love it you know
like it you know some some other
programmers don't care for it you know
some programmers Nico I never used that
feature in fact I think that feature is
harmful you know some people may say
that deviant depending on what feature
it is depending on who you ask
depending on what what programming
language it is so first of all remember
closure closure is just a feature
programming language you know a specific
feature some people like it some people
don't
in C you know you don't have that in
general you know imperative programming
languages you don't have that in C C++
Java you know I'm I might be wrong today
because they might have added that in
the past five years because in the past
five years you know a lot of functional
programming concept are introduced to
the imperative programming languages
such as Java you know they they began to
have lambda you know and okay so again
so it's a feature okay now what No okay
so some people like it some people may
not like it and it's is it necessary no
it's not necessary
again again it's just a feature and it's
not even necessarily okay in my opinion
I don't even I don't like it okay in my
opinion I do not like closure okay and I
never use it and I will never use it
basically period okay I will I do I have
never been programming for 20 years I
have never used closure and I will never
basically I will never use closure
unless you know if one day are working a
company you know when you work with you
know companies project you cannot just
do what you want you know you have to
follow you know already you know maybe
there's already closure you
you know the what what's already
existing style you know and you follow
the company's guidelines you know that's
when you work in a team but personally I
will never use closure I will never you
know recommend it I don't like it okay
and you know and to me of course it's
it's obviously not necessary and in fact
I think it's harmful
you know when use the way I look at
other you know is this is a matter of
opinion okay
some people may agree some people do not
agree I don't like closure okay that's
it I don't like it I'm gonna tell you
why I don't like it you know after I
explain what it is and so on but first
of all and first of all I want to try to
teach you any of you new programmers
okay what closure is let's see okay now
again guys don't don't host anything
that can get me banned okay so so back
to closure so culture is a feature a
specific feature programming language
and of some programming languages and
the JavaScript has it Python 3 has it
Python 2 does not have it okay python 2
you cannot do it but python 3
you know it's a new version version of
Python you you have you have it you know
you can do it and eMac please has it ok
so but it was introduced about three or
four years ago so before that you don't
have that you don't have closure in eMac
this book but they added that ok so
again it's a feature of programming
languages some languages has it some
doesn't so what what what is it what
does I do okay now the other thing
important too
now I'm going to give you itemized
things I want you to remember I kind of
you know I tend to be repetitive you
know repeat you know myself but but I
kind of think that's also important
because because when you go out read the
online where
sites you know the you type closure you
you'll find hundreds you know of
articles what is closure you know they
tends to be in my opinion they usually
tend to be confusing and they don't
capture the gist of things and also
today half of them is just clickbait you
know companies they they want to make
money so they want to create write up
articles so the people can't go to their
website they so you know they get money
from their ads even though they don't
care nothing about programming languages
they just copy-paste your phone
Wikipedia or other things you know they
hire cheap labors you know in China or
whatever you know they pay you five five
bucks you know how to so you as a
beginner program you copy and paste you
know information for them and you create
an article and then they put on their
website you know what is closure you
know the ten things you need to know
about closure things like that you know
they are tons of web websites like that
that's one thing but then another thing
is that a lot of programmers they don't
really understand well you know they
don't understand for them you know we
just including a lot of these elite
hacker types they you know like for
example Perl people 20 years ago they
have yeah I'm gonna show you they have a
article in their poor documentation
official documentation they tell you
what is closure let me show you this is
so funny kosher okay this is this is
what Perl people say what is a closure
20 bout 20 years ago 15 years ago in
their official documentation let's see
if I can find my article for Unicode
tutorial PostScript to check HTML face
product maybe it's you they are that is
the one this is Perl talk you know Pro
Fe o / FAQ seven
okay I might be it's so here it is per
doc / FAQ 7 what is closure closure are
documented in put out here okay close
your document in / ref okay here the
page you are looking at is Pearl FAQ
okay frequently asked questions that's a
common turn through our 1990s but today
you probably may not be familiar with
FAQ you know that means frequency ask
questions but here is the official
Darkon closure let's let's see
yeah okay let me just show you some of
the you know you read this and you can
see you can get the context you know the
idiocy of these people this this are
considered elite hacker programmers you
know remember we are looking at pearl
red / dark / if you know that's the one
of the official documentation pearl and
the paragraph is a chapter on pearl
references the concept of referencing
okay this is official documentation of
pearl and the other page here / FAQ 7 is
also a visual documentation of pearl
they talk about you know they trying to
tell you what is the closure let's be
the few paragraphs no so here's a here's
it is what is a closure closure are
documented in paragraph okay but let's
keep reading on closure is a computer
science term which closure is a computer
science term with a precise but how to
explain meaning usually closures are
implemented in pearls anonymous funk
subroutines with lasting references to
lexical variables outside their own
scopes lists lexical magically refer to
the variable that were around when the
subroutine was defined deep binding this
is this is complete idiotic nonsensical
and they don't know it's like convoluted
they don't even know what they are
talking about first of all closure is a
computer science term wrong closure is
has nothing to do with computer science
okay closure has no foothold in in
theory theoretical computer science
closure has no foothold in computer
science period rather closure is a
computer engineering kind of thing
aspect okay closure is it has to do with
practical programming closure is a
computer programming language feature
that exists in some languages but not in
others it so it you know is
just a pract it's just a computer
engineering issue it has nothing to do
with computer science and you know look
at this how they tried they phrase it
you know the way they write it means you
know it means they have no understanding
what it is this is typical of
programmers this is typical of
programmers understanding when they when
they try to explain something in
programming even for something they
think they know well okay this is
typical this paragraph about you know
people trying to explain what closure
this is you know and what I'm saying
applies to this or all these UNIX
this UNIX you think they are
you know you think they are smart the C
programmers like they actually don't
understand what they are talking about
because they don't they don't have a
clear mathematical grasp of what's
actually going on instead what they have
instead is the programmers that you need
hackers they call blog you know there's
some stupid job it's like they
grow things gr okay it's like it's like
some kind of empathy that they they feel
like like the the UNIX philosophy
the Eric yes are Eric Raymond
you know the guy who created past
bizarre and Cathedral you know it will
who wrote that crap
so so this UNIX philosophy type of
people they did they like to say they
croak it's like they've they feel they
feel how things are they didn't you know
they K that that is what this probe
people is doing this is a very concrete
exhibition of these UNIX this
idiotic elite hacker type of programmers
I'm giving you a concrete example you
know and I'm showing you my opinion and
he is example I say this is an
exhibition of their this is an
exhibition of a illustration of how they
you know how the situation of where they
think they understand something and how
they try to explain it okay
so they say you know crochet is a
computer science term which is incorrect
then they say then they say look at the
way how they how they say things crochet
is a computer science term with a
precise but how to and how to explain
meaning that is stupid you know first of
all the first sentence describing
closure they are actually not trying to
define what closure is but however they
are trying to give you a flavor of what
they think closure is you know it's a
they say it's a computer science term
but and they say it's precise but hard
to explain it's it's almost like
mathematically that's self contradictory
that means they don't understand you
know they either don't understand what
it is or it means they are unable to and
explain what it is like that like they
do not understand something fook fully
100% but they but they kind of
understand it and you know that's what
they say you know with a precise but how
to explain meaning what do you mean
something is precise about how drink
spread okay let's take it for face value
yeah there is it is true that something
could be precise but sometimes hard to
explain okay yeah let's say so let's
accept that okay then they say usually
closure are implemented in Perl
as you know anonymous subroutines and so
on that you see you can see here
immediately they switch you know they
kind of switch the approach you know so
instead of turning you what closure is
in general this immediately tell you
what closure is implemented in Perl so
they are not even telling you what
closure is in Perl but they tell you how
closure is implemented in Perl as a way
to kind of explain what closure is this
is their method of trying to explain
something you know so they don't know
what closure is maximal
you know mathematically you know with
not
they don't know what closure is in
computer science they don't know what
closures is in general they are they
fail to explain it they are unable to or
they choose not to okay
then they start to say they start
directly to go into how closure is
implemented in Perl and usually with a
qualification usually closed you are
implementing in pro as anonymous
function subroutines and so on so they
don't even try to directly explain what
closure is in pro the language you know
because you know again as I said closure
is a specific feature and in different
languages and also they the way they
close your exhibit you know behave in
different languages also kind of differ
so again like I said before closure is
not a mathematical concept it has
nothing to do with math or theoretical
computer science this this kind of proof
you know is it proves my solidify my my
point that closure is not has nothing to
do with method theoretical computer
science rather it's computer engineering
thing you know different languages have
different language designs some has
closure some does not does not end of
those languages that has closure they
actually do you know the way they kind
of the semantics is a little bit
different you know they kind of you know
so anyway back to the pros so they try
to East they try to convey to to the
readers you know this is frequently
asked question they try to answer the
question what is the closure by by the
by the ways of trying to explain how it
is usually implemented in Perl that's
what they that's what they are doing you
know as anonymous subroutines with a
lasting reference and look at the way
they explain things you know as
anonymous subroutines with lasting
references to lexical variables outside
their own scopes let's that's just a
full mouthful now the dyslexic not now
granted that closure is not a it's it's
it's it's not a simple concept
it's act
slightly complex then then is dyslexic
us magically referred to the variables
that were around when the subroutines
was defined yeah then you know see look
at the way you know they drag in the
world magical you know pro people like
nerves that you know they love the world
magic begin you know the things like
that okay then second paragraph closures
are coaches are now if you keep comments
coming okay keep the comments coming
typed a beanie your thoughts your
comments let's get back to the pearl I'm
trying to do I'm trying to finish this
quickly I'm trying to get to the main
dish where I began to explain what
closure is to beginning of beginner
programmers then I'm going to go into
why I don't like it you know so um so
the second paragraph of these sales Pro
people say Scotia are most often used in
programming languages where you can have
the return value of a function be itself
a function as you can in Perl know that
some languages provide anonymous
functions but are not capable providing
proper closures the Python language type
a language for example this is this is
one thing Perl people love to do you
know they want to you know while they
are trying to explain to you what
closure is they may also mix in you know
mixed named propaganda they want to tell
you how great pearl at the language the
language is then they want to drag in
Python because you know Perry and Python
was you know the arc enemies you know
they want to drag in Python and slide
you know you know like Polito Python a
little bit you know so here they are
trying to say basically what they are
saying is that this this is actually
isn't wrong you know well basically
is party your own party incorrect you
know they are saying Crozier is most
often used in programming languages
where you can have the return value of
function P itself a function that's act
that does not act actually address what
the heart of the thing but you know it
is true that you create a closure by by
having a function that returns a
function that is that is what they are
trying to say okay and that is also why
closure is just no good okay I did I
don't I close okay anyway then you look
at the so you see as you can improve
that that's how they want to drag in you
know that's how they want to put a
little bit of promotion of pro when you
do when you start to do these did they
do these throughout their documentation
okay I've read the entirety of Perl the
entirety of Perl documentation basically
what forward you know the entirety of
product okay that's this a book I've
read the entirety you know several times
and in fact I've read all books Pro in
the 1990s all of them right you know I
have written a review of all the books
power books survey 2002 okay from - from
1998 to 2002
I have read all basically the top five
per books they exist and this is my page
I talk about you know I give you a
review of each and besides you know
besides this book I've read the entirety
of Pro talk you know several times
word-for-word every every word of it so
and and then then then the photographer
nation then they drag in Python they say
you know Python cannot do it that's true
in Python - well Python three improved
it okay and I'm going to show you
so the let's go with let's go let's go
to a third paragraph so in human terms
it's a funny way of passing arguments to
a subroutine when you define it as well
as when you call it in human terms it's
a funny way of passing arguments to a
subroutine when you define it as well as
when you call it what do you mean it's a
funny way of passing arguments to a
subroutine I'm a little bit unfocused
and I'm quite sure what it means I'm you
know I'm getting tired now it's useful
for saying you know anyway yeah
anyway that's their explanation of
closure in the Perl
oh wait hold on a second actually yeah
we are back here so anyway yeah so this
is pearl effect queue and we go to the
paragraph and Pro ref says anonymous
subroutine address closures with respect
to my variables that is really quickly
visible within anyway so that is Perl
official explanation of closure okay and
I'm going to tell you what closure is so
let's read a comment of it let me drink
and take a break so are you guys--you're
here say something six people
so normally is asking a question and
that question is probably a bit advanced
and but I want to finish my beginners
tutorial on closure but let me just read
out a comment for now so Norma says what
do you think about closures that aren't
returned from their containing scope for
example if you create a local helper
function local helper function in the
parent lexical scope in the parent
lexical scope
what do you mean like so are you so
nested function right and I don't quite
understand the question so let me know
what exactly what you mean in order to
close as far as I know in order to
create a closure you have to have a
function that returns a function but
again the definition of closure is a bit
depending on what we mean because we may
not be using thinking of the same
definition closure so what what do you
mean you know so no man so explain you
know let me know what what do you mean
yeah I'll get to it so let me get back
to so what is closure okay let me
explain what is a closure closure is a
feature of is a specific feature of
programming language closure now that
the the closure function closure is a
feature of a function okay it's part of
a function you know it's it's this
feature is tied to function so what what
it means in a sentence is that okay
here's one way to put it it here is what
means the the best explanation of
closure in one sentence of the century
of humanity of the whole history of
humanity this is the best summary of in
in one sentence what closure is okay
closure is a function is a function in a
programming language you know crochets
of is the functioning of programming
language that the functions local
variables walks always just walks that's
all okay that is the best explanation of
closure of the entire history of
humanity okay what is closure
Crozier is a function in a foreign
language kosher is a function such that
its local variables always just walks
okay okay that's that's what it means no
okay so the that kind that may be
personal what do you mean to always walk
of course local variables always walks
what do you mean it always works I mean
are there examples where local variables
does not walk I mean you mean if that's
a case that's a bug in the programming
language right oh it's a you know it's
yeah it's a book how is it possible what
do you mean you're a local variable
doesn't work what what do you mean
always walk well let me show you an
example where a local variable does not
work let's make sure that's let's begin
the journey into closure okay this is
this is a this is a journey into closure
you cannot refuse to and not understand
you will understand your you'll see step
by step the gist the nature of closure
why it arise you know what is the
original problem why does it arise okay
so let's let's use JavaScript and let's
yeah because this arrow function let's
see actually I can do it you know I
haven't done this before
let's see so are you guys always with me
give me something feedback you know
three people okay I'm losing people fast
you know it's like I'm kind of
discouraged oh yeah okay let me try to
get over this quickly so we want to
define a function so we define a
function f okay f is a constant function
and okay a constant function that takes
a value of x and returns a value let's
just say return okay so let's say
return X okay here so we have a function
that returns X and let's call it let's
say three and let's run it okay save it
save the file as that and let's run it
and we got the answer three so we have a
function we defined a function this is a
lambda function anonymous function it's
just a function expression okay function
takes a variable X and we just return
and let's say we turned X plus 1 so we
get some difference so you know it
returns for so and we assign to a name f
so f is a function so f3 you know
returns 4 okay now we have a function
now let's define some local variables
okay it's local variables let's say okay
so we let's try to do that so let y
equals to 3 okay yeah y equals to 3 and
let's say X plus y okay now we have a
function that has a local variable Y
okay and this function returns X plus y
okay let's write 6 that's the right
answer because we give it 3 and the
returns 6 because 3 plus 3 is 6
okay so so far so good
so we have a local variable now what I
want to show you is a situation when
local variable does not work anymore
the it does not work anymore that's a
tricky situation okay ok let's do it
so in this function I'm going to define
another function inside this function so
it is kind of a nested function you know
inside this function so let's do that
let's just say let okay
that's in in RF okay it's kind of you
know let's say if - yeah let's call it f
- then so let's call the first one F one
so we have a inner function f2 and this
inner function let's say it takes no
argument okay and let's say it returns
three okay this is just for now it
returns three now let's let's do that so
that we so we get in ten take
indentations so actually
okay so anyway so we define a function
f2 inside inside this f1 function and
this f2 function takes no arguments and
it returns let's say now it lets it
returns 3 ok let's say it returns 2 and
now let's run it it returns 6 that's
still good because you know nothing
changed we actually we define the inner
function people we did nothing we didn't
call it or anything so it still so so
far so good now let's do something else
now let us return now let the main
function returns f2 let's see how our
second we were we want to create a
situation where a local function a local
variable in a function no longer works
so a local variable in your function no
longer works so let's add a local
variable here
okay so let's see let's return Y okay
yeah let's just return that and we've
done f2 so what I'm doing here is you
see the F Y is a function it has a local
variable Y and it also has a local
function you know a function f2 inside
this function and this function returns
the local variable Y and this f1
function actually returns f2 so this f1
function actually returns a function and
you know returns the in of inner
function so what happens if we call f1
if we call f1 you know it's actually
just returning f2 so let's try to run it
so you see it returns the function f2
now now there's an interesting thing
here this this variable Y is is is local
to f1 ok let's do this ok so if so let's
let's let okay let's let F 3 equals 2 f1
okay now remember remember f1 returns a
function so what we are doing is that we
whatever it returns we assign a name f3
you see what I mean so we can write
so whatever you'd be turns it returns a
function you know and now we give it you
know we assign it to f3 so now we can
call f3
let's call f3 and let's see what it
returns it returns 3 you see what
happens here is that this
f1 returns a function what does a return
it returns this function f2 here and
what does this f 2 to F 2 is actually
taking a variable Y that's defining f1
and they just retired so so so that
that's why this f3 returns 3 so it all
works but what's a what's a deal so
there's an interesting interesting thing
going on because when you return why you
see this Y this Y is part of f1 but f1
is already done for you know
over here when you co f1 is always
already finished but now when you call
f3 that why came from f1 but however it
kind of you know it kind of still is
still there so so this is actually what
this is what I'm trying to say when a
functions local variable no longer works
actually I it was a incorrect statement
what I'm trying to say it's not it's
it's not about the local function no
longer works but rather a variable used
by the function you have a situation
where a variable used by the function
can sometimes no longer exist because
look at this f2 is a function it uses
the variable Y but Y is defined as a
local function in f1 so in many
programming languages when f1 is done
after its code the Y variable is already
gone
so the f2 you have a situation this f2
has a variable that's already you know
doesn't exist anymore so so in some
languages you cannot have the situation
like this so it's an issue you know this
so this is actually why this is a
complicated advanced issue about
closures so what I'm saying is that
so so designer Landry language designers
and implement you know who implement
this have have to come away so that when
a function is going away but however if
it's variable is still used by some
other function you know it's still used
somewhere it should still work okay so
this is why so this should still work
and this situation where a functions
variable whatever variable it uses is
guaranteed to always walk this is called
closure okay this is what closure is
okay so yeah so that that is what
closure is okay it's is that clear or is
that you know it's a little bit
complicated so actually my that one
single sentence explanation
you know closure is just a function
where it's the variable it uses always
walks not local variable that's a
mistake so it's so closure is just a
function such that all the variables
such that such a it just always works as
expected
you know that's one way to put it almost
specifically the variable it uses always
just walks but there's a problem here
when you have a closure there's a issue
for example let's see let's say
for example let's say let's do y equals
2y plus 1 okay let's do that we run that
so it returns 4 right and let's run it
again you can see we run it several
times you see the result is 4 5 6 7 why
because it actually maintained you see
this variable Y is a kind of a internal
variable nobody can access this variable
Y because F Y is already called but
however it's still there it's maintained
it kinds of maintains it comes with the
F 2 function so closure another way to
say what closure is and this is an the
most standard way to when people say
what closure is is that it's a function
that that has its own lexical
environment that's how people say it you
know it has its own lexical environment
it just means that you know all the
variable uses it still come with it you
know it's like you have an environment
it's still you know you have a bubble
that comes along with a function and you
know and it's enclosed you know that why
is it called closure because it's some
kind of a enclosed thing you know this
whole thing the whole variables that's
used with the function f to come with it
you know wherever you return a function
whatever variables it uses always stay
with the function so any when you define
a function in a language that supports
closure
it means whenever whenever you have a
function it just maintains you know all
the variable environment with the
function that is all it is you know so
that the reason it's called closure
because it's like a enclosure actually a
proper term is Mexico enclosure okay so
what so I you know you can you can read
this article you know I'm doing video so
I'm kind of verbose and but you see my
visual facial expressions and you kind
of get to see
you know my process of thinking through
it you know I hope that's helpful but in
you know if you are impatient you can
read this article because I have I have
several articles I have one in
JavaScript and in Python 3 I show you
how to do closure like this article in
Python 3
you know I show you how closure is done
in Python 3 and actually I also I don't
have an example in eMac list and I was
thinking of coding it in real time but I
probably talked for too long I spent too
much time on the rental closure on the
from the Perl people so I was thinking
of doing a real time coding of closure
showing you how closure is studying emag
Lisp which is anyway so I think let's
keep that but anyway so so you can read
this are code that that explains several
issues about closure ok for example
there is a I'm going to get to some of
the items so the better name for closure
is lexical in closure
okay it's called closure because it's
some kind of enclosure because it when
you define a function it encloses
everything it uses you know it comes as
one package you know so but the most
important and practical consequence the
most important thing people use closure
for is actually the state function that
maintains state that's what people use
it for that's the gist that's the the
the consequence that that is the use of
closure you know it's not about you know
the enclosure or think that that's just
technicality that's just computer
science technicality
when programmers use closure what you
really want what do you want this
feature what you really want is
you want a function okay you want a
function to have a internal state you
know like our example you know it can
you call it multiple times and it
returns multiple different values
because you know there's a change of
state you can change the state or you
can change Y to something else that's
what closure is useful that's the
manifestation of closure that the actual
use of closure maintaining a state and
also because of this closure is no
longer technically closure is not a
function anymore it is not the math map
mathematicians ideal concept of function
because it has side effects
because the functions return value no
longer depends on the input you know
because right now we have a function we
cover multiple times each time the input
is the same you know no value but
however the return value changes is
different each time you call it so so in
a math sense in a function of pure
functional programming since closure is
what is you know it's a it's the thing
you don't want because it has side
effect you know it's no longer pure
function this is the reason I don't like
closure and okay so let me get let me
get clear let me summarize a little bit
it just creates the the one hours of
talk first of all closure is the
programming language feature some
programming language it has it some
doesn't okay some people like it some
doesn't it's not really necessary you
know because it's just a programming
language feature now crow sure what
closure is is actually it's a function
such that it comes with a environment of
all the variable it uses so that you
know the function still works as you
would expect you know people's people
would say you know it's a function with
its own lexico environment that's what
closure is now why is it called closure
it is because it's some kind of a
enclosure you know it's like close you
know it's
he says it's a it's a house it's a
circle you know it's a pub oh it's a
lexicon enclosure that is why it's
called Crozier now now why now let me
talk about why why I don't like it I
don't think it's good thing okay in
competing in programming what no no wait
hold on a second now let me talk about
why why is it useful why people like it
the reason people like it the reason
that the the it's use is because it
creates a situation where you can
function that maintains state you know
you know and there's a consequence you
can also have a function in fact this is
the heart of object-oriented programming
okay when you define your class what
does class me class is a closure that
says that is the technical essence of a
class of object-oriented programming the
class concept in Java in Python in Ruby
okay a class technically speaking is
from the perspective of computer
language design class of olp is a
closure okay that's what it is because
of the feature programming language
feature of crows closure that is how you
can define class otherwise class is
impossible you know because of the
closure feature the lexical in closure
you know
therefore you can define a class in Java
in in Python okay so but why do people
want to use closure what is it you store
that used for now that basically the
only reason that the reason is that it
allows function to ever state such as
when you sting over P for example when
you have a class you have you know sorts
called fields you know member members of
the class you have methods those are or
local to the function the class so class
in oak yes in your case is kind of the
outer function
and the methods are the enough inner
function such as the f2 here and the
fields or members you know member
variables static variables of a crisis
like the variable y here so that's what
you know oh he came from they came from
you kind of came from the functional
programming kind of okay this this is
not real history okay I'm just saying
technically speaking okay anyway so what
what's the closure useful it's used for
the state you know for function to have
a state now if you don't have a closure
can you still do that yes all you have
to do is just use global variables
that's a simple way so you just have a
function that uses global variables you
know each function can use global
variables then you each function can
have maintain a state you can do
whatever you want you can do whatever
you want to do with closure so if you
have a language that do not have closure
that's good because I don't like closure
because everything everything possible
you know doesn't matter what a closure
can do you can do it with your function
just by using global variables now you
might come friend oh yeah but but but oh
sure global variables is bad because you
have different functions they may stamp
on each other that is true well how do
you solve that you can solve it by
creating a scheme such that the global
variable names used by each function is
like a random systemically random and
connected to the function such as you
know cryptography you know public
encryption you have terror of keys you
know that's one way to solve it and and
you know anyway that's that's that's
kind of my steam towards those people
who like closures in those videos ok
programmer the hacker types they don't
understand what it is but anyways what
I'm saying about this global variable
use is actually it's actually true that
is the practical equivalent of closure
you don't need closure it is from a
functional point of view functional
meaning it
meaning that what your program actually
do everything that's with closure you
can do just by using global variables
such a simple idea you know this you
know this is nothing you don't need
closure at all now the next pub in last
part why I don't like closure okay first
of all the reason I don't like closure
is one it's not function it's not
mathematical function anymore you are
getting into Opie oh you are getting
into you know a function a pure function
by definition is such that a function
output always depends on the input it's
a map
okay same emote input always have the
same output but that's another case when
you have a closure when you have a
closure you you start to have you know
you know it's almost like anything flies
anything can fly you know you can have a
function that returns a function that
returns a function that has you know so
many levels of inner variables you could
you know I can we can actually start to
code it you know you can have you can
have not you know what what opie class
you know you call class you know class
variables you can actually have several
levels of class variables you know you
saw so you are in you I have like
several levels of a closures so when we
say closure we can actually talk about
you know closure closure level and level
enclosures you know it quickly becomes
bizarre and complicated and in an
extremely useless you know so that's
what you know so first of all I don't
like closure because it's it's not a
function anymore and also because it
gets you can get extremely complex you
know when you have when you start have
closure because you know the reason
mathematicians of pure functional
programming the reason we like the
concept of pure functional programming
is because functions has no side of it
closure by the very nature but at very
definition it's a function with side
effect it's no good okay so that's why I
don't like Roger secondary secondary
the second reason is that when whenever
you want to create a closure you cannot
just say you know you cannot just say
define closure like different closure
and you know define your closure you can
that's not how it's done
you always overall the language I know
of Python job well I don't know about
Java but Python I know eMac this
actually I don't know
anyway job at least JavaScript in in
Python ok at least JavaScript script in
Python I don't know at the moment about
email at least I have to think about it
but anyway at least Python in JavaScript
when you want to create a closure you
always have to do the way the only way
the prototypical way you create a
closure is by defining a function
defining a inner function and return the
inner function that is how you create a
closure after you do that then you have
to assign you have to code a function
and assign it to another function just
like the example we have here so so in a
sense it's rather extremely complicated
in fact when you look at this form this
is how you define class and how you
create object it's almost identical you
see this F 1 here is a class you know
and this F 3 here is the instant
instantiation of a object from the class
f1 you know this is the or engine you
know so anyway when you want to create
query closure this is almost like like
the only way you do it this and PI and
in fact by the definition of closure you
can see that this is just there's no way
out because closure by definition is a
function that comes with its lexical
environment and only if I oh I think I'm
I'm not sure theoretically theoretically
but I think only via this way you know
having inner functions that's how you
can create closure ok so you can see
it's fairly you know very extremely
complicated thing
I don't like it okay so I think that's
kind of conclude actually that concludes
what I have to say about closure 19
minutes talk okay so if you if you guys
have a comment type it you know really
within 10 minutes and we can go over and
I think maybe that's that would be it
today Lots meant today about closure
because you know it is it is one of the
big rant he might you know twenty years
of coding in the first five you know in
the first ten years I actually don't
quite understand what it is and then but
you know anyway so let's see what so
type your comments and so I'm gonna go
through the comments hey hey George
so Roman says so again okay hold on
sugar shack heart keeps this web page
what this web page is about
we are fi view large files okay that's
about how to view large file related to
view large file open large files in
Emacs okay you guys can read that thank
you for the link in Norman says what do
you think about closures that aren't
written okay yeah the week in Norman
says not only the local variables always
work but each closures variables are
independent of other made it the same
way yes that is true
well anyway yeah so Norman is mentioning
about anyway so next question is is list
was learning well that depends that
depends on a lot factors but if you just
plant the ask me that question my answer
is no you know because a lot my
followers is actually list fan they
follow me because of my you know my this
excellent expertise
and also you know we you know suppose
supposedly we like to promote Lee's well
actually so anyway that depends on a lot
of things you know whenever people ask
you know which language is worth
learning and there's an answer usually
that just it's just nonsense you know so
I can tell you I mean if you ask me it's
Lisp was learning I say no
yah you know there's no much meaning to
that you know forget about that but so
it means a lot of things like what's
your call you know and what's your
personal situation for example what's
your goal
do you want a language that actually
gets you bread if if so no no don't
learn this okay now if you are
interested in history of artificial
intelligence you know suppose that is
the specific question you have strong
interest then then then absolutely you
have to learn no learn please because
that is the this is the kind of the
entire 30 years of lisps artificial
intelligence history okay then if your
question is you know you are interested
in programming language design or
concepts in programming languages is it
what is Lisp was running then the answer
is yes I would say so among others you
know at Haskell is also a good choice
Haskell F sharp or camo you know those
are all good choices or Idris or
you know there's AMI
there's fourth you know and there's
mercury logical language okay Prolog for
example mercury Prolog in terms of
languages so if you are interested in
maybe some some kind of programming
language design yeah Lisp is you know
one of them you know and let's say top
two you know you you know you learn Lisp
is a good thing you know you learn the
parentheses nested parentheses it's kind
of unusual but you also learn the
concept of kind of a systemic systematic
syntax
and how they can be transformed you
start to learn markers lists markers
which is extremely easy attic okay but
but however it's a jump point to the
much more important concept of pattern
matching not her scalp and imagine but
symbolic pad imagine okay in Mathematica
this Marco is a step is a step you know
it's a jump point to get you into the
beautiful world of symbolic Pat imagine
which in turn is a step towards
understanding
computer algebra systems in
understanding implementing computer
algebra systems or how they work such as
Mathematica maple and a bunch of others
symbolic meaning that you can solve
symbolic equations symbolic derivatives
or integration drip in in symbolic forms
a symbolic computation that's
Mathematica in this okay so let me
summarize so this yeah this if you are
interested you know one of the things
you may learn from Lisp is this Marco's
which is idiotic concept freak most
frequently cited by whispers in common
lisp as made knows those people are
idiots
okay sir says sorry says but however
least Marco's is a stepping stone to
understand symbolic pattern matching
which is not in Haskell not in in Okemah
not in you know the other ones they are
in Mathematica okay symbolic pattern
matching
now symbolic pattern matching is a
stepping stone to understand how
computer algebra system works that is
symbolic solutions to you know
integration derivatives or manipulation
of formulas and so on
okay so that that that is kind of my
coverage of which is least worthwhile
okay in general you know if most people
asking questions then you know you have
so many criterias
is it good for looking for a job it's
good for bread is it good for you know
interesting you know so many is it still
relevant
you know least today is really not
relevant not even relevant in artificial
artificial intelligence today okay this
means totally irrelevant you know have
no basically no place
it's practically correct it's correct to
say please today
practically has no place no position no
footprint in today's artificial
intelligence computation community okay
they are not done in this you know this
has no place so so that's another point
for you to church whether you want to go
into this you know this so so in my
opinion if you the blank question is no
but anyway so yeah that's my take so
Erland so okay so let me go over the
comments I gotta go to a bathroom too so
we'll be done so so home right George do
you like my answers is it good is it
does it answer or does it yeah let me
know because I you know I always of
course you know people like to know if
I've did good you know let me know
so normal say it's for fun or personal
interest maybe for work or practical use
no yeah that's so good I would say it's
I agree with that the new says this was
using Aryan to your end of 1980s yes up
to 19 yeah up to 19 early 1990s yeah
it's kind of way I winter as they say
Daniel says the progress development and
evolution of Lisp was tightly related to
the other progress development and
evolution of AI that is correct
Norman says
I didn't appreciate how good had a
matching is until I had known Olin okay
I have a question mr. Lance is Islands
Panama Jane is a symbolic that is my
question because in my learnings I
learned that Haskel symbolic has cow you
know pattern matching or camel may of
had a matching is entirely different
because they are a symbolic so they are
not when you and because of that it's
entirely different thing from languages
with symbolic pattern matching because
we are matching by values you know this
is a huge difference the nature is their
power their computation nature is
entirely different so it's all an
alliance pan-dimensional is about
symbolic because when you have symbolic
pattern matching what it means is that
what you have is like is it specific
basically transformation of syntax or
transformation of source code list motto
is like very puny it's like impractical
you know it's just a little bit of that
transformation of source code like if
you are into lists you know if you read
into common list phonetics they like to
say all this you know this whistle
language that that can language that
trance or Scott returns source code that
programs that modify itself is the least
common list they are idiots the the the
the least mark and the reason they said
eyes because this mark was you know but
actually please Marcos is actually in an
ineffectual it's like it's like 5% of
you know fact yeah five percent of real
symbolic pattern matching feature a full
symbolic pattern matching feature in
Mathematica and other languages this
this others okay of obscure but anyway
Mathematica is that from everyone so the
so why is this people like EDR like
idiotic like that common is because it
the reason I say is that because you
know I've been fighting with commonly
Spurs for over 10 years they call me a
troll okay you I've seen professor
Stephen professors they may make the
extreme idiotic and incorrect
you know the expressions about comedies
the reason they are like that is because
the common list was I mean in touch with
is mostly since 1990s by 1990s this has
already gone down here you know as
already is not the head of this okay so
the people after nineteen eighties that
you know enthusiasts you know the
phonetics
they list has become this you know
mythical language and you know at least
this has already died maybe it becomes
common lisp okay he has already fell out
from the hate of language research so
instead of you have this common list
which is extremely ugly in late late
1980s extremely ugly language that tries
to you know merge all the commercial
versions of the list was a kind of they
try to you know go go forward as a
standard you know because back then in
1980s list there are so many lists
ireland's and they are at war you know
see serious language war like each other
fight you know just like today we've I
call you an you are you
know because you are at least why you
know I'm the best I'm this X okay and
somebody least pieces know you guys knew
to are idiots
this P is the best people are doing that
back then I because I read history I've
seen it I've seen it I didn't you know
until I read at the moment I read her
iMac I was I was going like oh my god I
didn't even realized you know you have
to take history because once you dig
into use so so many things you don't
realize you know yeah we you know I only
read a little bit but I did realize you
know it was like that you know but
anyway by 1990s the lispers you know
they most people just just
like everyone this was they are not they
don't dig history into that deep well
what they are actually are rather just
the phonetics just like today on Hacker
News you know you have average
programmers they read someone wrote
something and they get excited and they
from that day are they tell everyone oh
we always should we all should do
patterns X you know oh you know from now
on something something is good something
something is bad
those are idiots okay agile you know
that and UNIX philosophy as well that so
the list first
you know communists but i from what i
see by 1990s they are not original I
mean just just like any other
programmers they they are prone to fall
into fads and fashions and beliefs and
you know they want to believe you know
they want to believe that Lisp is these
great wonderful things and in turn they
don't get into something in detail I
mean also even in 1990s compared to Java
ok Java you know this please leaves this
was mainstream but by 1990s by 1998 it
was not mainstream it's kind of the
niche ok the main streams are Java C C++
okay
so in comparison this is still better I
mean in my opinion better than Java you
know so to a lot lispers back then when
they talk about these things they are
thinking of you know their mindset is
comparison in comparison to Java
therefore list be superior that I agree
ok that's my opinion because I like
functional programming I despise you
know the imperative you know so when
when these lists phonetics they are
saying this is so great or superior they
kind of also they are in comparison to
Java you know see you know they are not
really you know thinking about symbolic
pattern matching you know they they like
they
they don't know Mathematica they you
know they they didn't take into
specifics of things they are just
following trends just like average other
programmers so that is why you know I
think a lot of these lispers but you
know when you read a lot I mean even
today you have a lot phonetics you know
they say good things about this and to
me their ideas basically they are you
know they are just incorrect they are
just you know factually technically
incorrect they are spreading incorrect
information but those are informations
you know people want to believe you know
just like religion you know if you are a
fan of this you know where are your
families because it's kind of niche
right because it's kind of all the
parentheses because you know it's
unusual and you are and you are you know
you are an unusual guy so you want to
you we are in this group of you know the
mainstream so we want to we like it I
like it too you know first of all
compared to Java Perl absolutely I like
this but it so happens you know I also
tends to you know I don't like you know
I you know I don't I tend to be non
conformal even in the nonconformist
community but anyway that just made me
okay
so although Mathematica had imagined so
enormous is all the mathematics cause so
so tenuous a sleaze problems lots of
dialects lack of well-known libraries
that is true even today we are syntax
that does not contribute to abstract
people in dynamic typing act that is
also true I mean one part for example
one problem along this line is that you
know in Lisp you cannot have a function
that we turn a function you know you you
can but you have to go what you can you
have to go around things you know it's
it's not practical so on the other hand
in JavaScript and Python you can
trivially in
you do it all the time have a function
that returns a function you know but in
this it's easy you know it's a problem
and it's so therefore it's not a idiom
so you know so that's one of the problem
teneo mention about this issue you know
I think you know I think that's what you
are saying part you know I suppose so
so Norman says although mathematical
spanner matching is probably more
powerful I think Daniel says notice that
programming language might not be very
important okay good answer
great thank you George can you explain
symbolic Fanta matching that's that's
another topic ok I hope it I did cover
that it's just like least Marcos but but
actually designed for it yeah I hope to
show you actually um if you like to know
that right now I have an article sorry
problems I have actually pattern
matching several articles I have one
specific article that tries to teach
yeah anyway maybe I hope so maybe next
time I'll explain that because I have
like over ten articles about that about
pattern matching so you get you know you
can read just such folks are the least
pattern matching so Norman says Orleans
phantom answering does not involve
source code transformation it matches
the shape of data okay using no more
type syntax so I think that's
value-based pana matching yes so I think
that's I I don't know for sure but I
think that's the same class as hash
Scouts or or cameras have imagined so
you know they do match structures and
and also they match values and type as
well did you know that the type of
values and structures so George says
program predicted wrong when he said
that list will be the next big language
yeah I mean a lot of these big people
you know I mean the job program you know
when you list a lot of celebrities they
always have you know big things to say
for example Bill Gates you know he's he
was with richest people in a world he
always have opinions and whenever he
said something all the people is going
you know oh yeah this or that they
follow him and similarly a lot of these
celebrities they always have big things
to say and all the programmers is like
following them and kind of once they say
something and all the program means
programmers you know is like believing
and the you you began to have a fat you
know program is one of the guy who's who
kind of began a fad about common lisp
know about least in in 2002 also because
of his you know article about lisp
because he wrote a list so to yahoo for
millions of dollars anyway what i want
to say about that is where whenever some
people famous people they become famous
for a reason mostly because they are
they are successful in particular thing
they are doing for example Bill Gates
what is good he good for he's good for
running a company he is expert in that
no doubt he's a he's a expert in
entrepreneur and so therefore if he has
an opinion that's related to
entrepreneurship about stardom listen
okay if he has opinion about anything
else it's probably good to ignore he
because he don't know about it
including programming he is not known
for as a great greatest programmer
rather you know his successes came from
his ability to run start a company and
sell the company same thing as an
example program what is he good for he
is good for you know writing the common
list program and soda to Yahoo for
millions of dollars he is good for that
so he so whenever he has opinions about
Common Lisp or lisman general we listen
about programming okay technical
opinions not about whether Lisp is a
good language or not that's kind of a
different field you know the he you know
that because to speak as an expert in
about which programming is better than
others you actually have to be well
known as a programming language designer
and also expert in all these languages
also you have maybe wrote several great
you know well-known programs critical
programs in in different languages then
we can accept you as someone who is
expert when when you have a comment
about which language to learn but
program
go ahead Graham is not really not that
you know he might know he of course he
know other languages but he is mostly
well known for expert comedies
programmers who has written his this
program Webster and he's also known for
really starting a company you know he's
known for an entrepreneurship so
whenever he has a opinion about these
specific topics
I think the
good opinions but otherwise screw it
okay same thing you know a lot Nobel
Prize winners politicians you know
whoever you know they have all sort of
ideas you know whatever they say all you
know celebrities like stars
you know the today's singer so movie
stars you know they have opinions about
politics or how a country should run do
you actually believe them do you think
you should believe them you know judge
for yourself okay that's it for today so
thank you guys for watching now if you
like my show you know I have patron and
PayPal on any of my blogs you can go to
you can see there's a link to my patron
and also my PayPal pages my PayPal you
know it all Amazon gifts so drop a few
bucks that will be appreciated and
otherwise hope to see you next time link
to my blogs link to my talk show spread
it there'll be a fish you know that'll
be great thank you see you guys next
time
that was two hours stalkers bye