good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today is 2019
January 7th Tuesday vo o'clock in the
afternoon San Francisco time welcome
welcome everyone so today we have tons
of things to talk about and I'm going to
show you my breakfast and this is my
breakfast this is not spread whole wheat
bread and left over from my roommates
cooking they cook I eat and then this is
photo taken in front of my door my
apartment door you know where I show
this picture to other people they say oh
my god this is beautiful well this is
Silicon Valley and I'm I live in this
poorest neighborhood but I guess it
looks good it's mv4 most other places in
the world so this is California
this is Silicon Valley you got lots of
trees if you go to Google Maps and you
look around you know you go to a street
view you will see a whole lot of trees
in seekin Silicon Valley than other
places in a world so I have quite a few
topics to talk about and I'm gonna so
let's begin one by one and mostly today
I'm going to talk about JavaScript
good morning Cathy good morning Justine
and good morning Dan and I want to show
you and Freddy Freddy is going to sleep
good night Freddy Freddy is in Germany
Germany and United Kingdom and de Moraes
is from Brazil am i incorrect and sorry
if I mixed up Brazil right Brazil msri
Justin has been to msri me too
[Laughter]
justing is the greatest well is a great
method mathematician okay and I happened
to show you guys Justin's curriculum
vitae this is Justin's curriculum vitae
now let's have a look now of you
programmers ignorant in mathematics have
a look at real mathematicians resume
okay
so Justin curriculum vitae who Justin
scarf a young ok PhD of math the
Department of math University of British
Columbia okay and you can see education
we don't care about education okay but
see mathematical research interests my
main research interest lies in number
theory in particular in the following
three different areas okay let's we need
to magnify this okay so number theory in
this area's analytic number theory now
that's kind of a branch of number theory
using analytic methods meaning calculus
so basically in layman's terms that
means you study number theory using the
techniques of calculus so analytic
number theory and harmonic analysis I
don't know exactly what's harmonic
analysis so we can look up so so and it
says pounded gaps between primes okay
that's a big problem sieve methods okay
zeroes of L functions Hardy little would
circus method okay
and then I was sawa theory in Galois
representations Taylor wire method and
Beyond Brock cattle tamagawa number
conjecture perch and swing Stern dire
conjecture ok these are kind of advanced
number theory stuff you don't know what
they are unless you have a graduate
degree or you know
you have a yeah graduate degree in
number theory then you know what they
are about then a rhythmic geometry and
auto morphic forms ok very advanced
topics
rhythmic arithmetic geometry which is
basically using geometry to study number
theory like cubic curves something like
that you know there's a name I don't I
don't know these things so so that's
just in scoff I our friend our friend
just in scarf I hear testing good more
interesting Jones Brazil yes stains from
Brazil Brazil okay so that's just in
special may ends in seminar talks and so
on so you know you can you can go to
Justin's homepage you know ask Justin
okay just means right here just come on
interesting and someone sent me this
soft like his cheat sheet for ago docs
keyboard using Commack so as you can see
here so this is a godox keyboard now
either you don't know you do you know
what is Oka docs most of you know half
of you know half of you don't know so
you see because we have lots of topics
lots of different people some people are
don't know about keyboards but let me
show you okay so ago Docs is this very
popular keyboard that that is originally
a do-it-yourself keyboard it is this one
but however you can also buy it it comes
in two foam forms one is this with the
wrist pad together as one unit and the
other form is without risk pad so you
can see this is so this is without this
pad this is a godox
okay
oh go Doc's keyboard in actually let me
post a link so you can go and buy it
okay so close this close and go back to
talk show and let's start to pose we're
gonna talk about JavaScript today
actually but we're gonna get into that
so and for those of you Emacs users as
usual look at my key commands on the
Left window you can see all my Emacs
command and you can search on the web
and you'll find a code okay so so here
is Google Docs keyboard link you guys go
there and buy it in which yourself
increase your productivity
okay so let's pop this out and let's
move this window to the right and stop
this and let's close down a bunch of
okay so anyway so logo Doc's let's get
back to ogle Docs
so show in browsers today's topics ago
dogs where is it
Oh dots keyboard so you can you know
this is do it yourself you can buy the
kit and build it yourself or you can buy
pre build they it cost about $300 fairly
expensive if you wanted pre build I mean
even if you just buy the kit it's like
250 270 dollars so you know it's good
but they are better ones okay so these
are you know so they have one two
companies that sells them when it's
called oh go ducks easy which is this
one and the other company that makes it
is a go ducks infinity which is this one
the ago ducks infinity has the lead you
know kind of a little this way on each
side and you know you can you can buy
them pre-built so that's a go ducks and
you know you can read my reviews and so
on so so
hold on a second
yeah I started to play that video by
mistake because I have Auto click on
then I hear something is coming on I
didn't know what's going on so someone
who is using a bodachs
and who is using some fly keys now if
you don't know what's off like he is let
me show you fly keys ok so actually so
that's for Emacs of you Emacs users
supply keys is a efficient key binding
system more efficient than vim ok and
it's one of my most popular package soft
like keys and ok so let's copy it then
says show us your dress roommate ok I'm
gonna show you my resume my resume my
resume is just my website ok yeah I
don't have much okay I can let's maybe
we talk about it later
I need to go fast because we have I have
a lot of tons of things to talk about
today mainly I want to talk about
JavaScript so remind me later ok if you
still want to check out my resume then
we talked about that let me tell you
about stuff like he's first so cuz I
like he's you know it's one most popular
package efficient key binding system for
Emacs so as you can see Oh Mike you see
this pink window Emily's favorite color
this purple you see you see all the keys
on the left side those are the keys are
type you will not see a control
something Omega something I don't press
those keys so this is sapphire keys the
most efficient you can you can edit
paste cut and do copy the kernel I paste
the kernel I add add return magnify
lowercase you see all single key press
there's no code however sometimes you
you you might see a code here that's
weak
I'm using Marcos but actually I'm just
pressing single keys so I talked about
this many times
socks are flaky so someone he's using
over docks and using some fly keys he
created this layout picture which is so
let us I need to perhaps I need to add
this somewhere so let's do it
okay let me show you some Emacs workflow
demo so where is this picture at wait I
want to find the location of this
picture Oh downloads
okay so downloads so I'm going to rename
this file I'm gonna add X I'm gonna add
a e in front of it okay so it's renamed
now I go to my Emacs I go through my
Emacs block let me show you the keys so
I call my bookmark command bookmark
command e be for Emacs block enter
that's my Emacs blog showing browser
okay now I want to add that picture here
so I go I go to here press three keys
then I get a section then press two keys
type a directory and there it is oboe
docks Commack okay so let me change the
name o go ducks comat Commack layout so
soft like keys okay you see there it is
it adds this block block of code show in
browser there we have it so now this
this is in my Emacs blog I need to add
this I need to move this image somewhere
to my you know to to the south like ease
section somewhere but I'll worry about
that later
but who who sent me this I forgot the
name I need to check my email but I
don't want to check it right here so I
need to add a name you know that's the
workflow I need to say Oh someone you
know the name who sent me this cheat
sheet you know but for now I'll do that
later okay
and for now let's go to the go to isha
okay let's call some interactive a brief
so we got a sink magnified enter and do
a password and now it's updated to my
Emacs blog any questions so you can see
this is the things I updated on several
pages and different websites so let's go
to for example now we go to sorry
Blagh okay let's go to block you can see
the picture there now let me also
mention so I just created a new version
of my Emacs tutorial so you guys spy it
okay it's a according to me it's the
best Emacs and emag this tutorial you
will not find the quantity or quality
elsewhere including printed published
books in the history of humanity you
will not find a better one I in fact I
would say mine is flaw like far better
by a gap because Emacs it's not
necessarily because I wrote that I write
the best tutorial but actually because
Emacs is a very niche topic they are not
many people you know book publishers
they will not publish Emacs book because
there's no cell so you don't get much
Emacs books unlike for example
javascript javascript c c++ this one
thousand books but Emacs emag Mississppi
in particular eMac this my eMac miss
tutorial is basically the only one
basically the only one in in existence
in a world okay not counting the eMac
this manual there is one introductory to
eMac this but that's like that one is
for people who have never programmed
before so that doesn't really count
I mean that's like like that book let me
show you okay so anyway you go you go by
my Emacs tutorial ok go by it and let me
just type the things in my talk show so
get the link and stuff so here a it here
is it okay so there is a link so
let me tell you about the Emacs
the Emacs thing Emacs let's talk about
Emacs a little bit so yeah there's a few
things yeah so we were talking about
Emacs Lisp books they are no basically
there is no eMac this book that exists
there they are a few like published more
than 10 years ago by all righty there's
one like one and they doesn't it doesn't
even begin to cover eMac B's it's just
some kind of very short intro so anyway
and the other so what I'm saying is that
my eMac this tutorial is almost
basically the only one so you go by it
and now let me talk about this book this
book is somewhat popular because it's
people cited all the time on reddit you
know eMac places so this book is by
Robert JH a so he died about he died
three years ago and he wrote a book
called introduction to programming in
Emacs Lisp this is the guy he looks like
that he died three years ago
at age 17 and his book you can you can
find it it's bundled in Emacs so you go
to you control H I you see this is a
command ctrl H I goes gets you do to
info okay then you you you tab to the
there this one eMac this intro a simple
introduction to eMac this programming
okay so you open it okay the so there is
a book you can actually expand out with
Emacs
you can actually start to read it now
this book is designed for people who
have never programmed before that is it
will spend pages and pages to
what is a variable what is a function so
for those of you who already programmed
you know this this is a very extremely
tedious book because when I was reading
it like 15 years ago you know I was
thinking oh I'll just skipped the parts
I know you know I know what's the
variable I know what's the function I
know what's a subroutine I know what's a
loop you know I know those things so I
think ok I'll just skip it quick quickly
and just get to the you know the the
parts about Emacs Lisp the language that
so I can learn something but it didn't
work out because it's so annoying so you
have to turn tempeh you have to scan 10
pages to learn one sentence about emag
peas you know then and you don't know
where because you have to actually scan
each page you scan scan scan you spend
five minutes then you find you find one
sentence then you have to I mean because
it's interwove and so you cannot simply
just read that sentence and get it you
have to read what you have to know a bit
what's before what's after so this book
is not good if you have any programming
experience already this book is worth
less okay it's worthless in the end so I
read a few chapters in the end I just
there is a one function okay let me show
you so I'm going to actually so this is
about a review of this book so hold on a
second let me let me show you something
about Emacs
okay so review of this book so let's go
to my Emacs blog and let's copy this
line Robert Chesser died okay and it's
pasted here so we have a topic and also
back to the blog are you guys still here
talk talk so any questions comments
positive posted okay
and so this arco is about is my review
of that book
and also about shoot a beginner
programmer learning emag B's so you can
read about that okay so let me copy it
paste it here so that's kind of today's
topic we talked about so so about that
book you know if you never programmed
before it's good but if you have some
experience it ain't really no good so
that is about that book okay
you mice your life twelve people okay
I'm still alive good just in scarf I
okay so what's the next topic so let me
show you the next topic so you go by my
Emacs tutorial and what what else let's
see
okay so let's let's clean up this page
and let's upload it okay so replace find
replace do that show in browser now
that's better
and now let's sync again so now it's
synced to my website and now this is the
today's talk-show link
so Justine says what's the link to his
resume I don't have the link handy but
it's on discord so you guys if you
haven't already joined this code let me
show you the discord link okay go to the
talk go to the top search for discord
and here's a link so you go there
there's a link so you go there and you
go to you go to the general section and
you scroll up squirrel up like 10 days
then you'll find just in scarf ID what
types of search okay
J s see there just in scarf I so so here
is Justine's posts so you can find
you'll find his resume somewhere there
the link next topic show us how to
program oppa I don't know how to program
Hoover or space X after how do I know I
how do you program uber you know how to
program space X you show us you you know
you are a mathematician you show us so
next topic so let's go to next topic so
who are here taste Cathy Cathy say
something Cathy so next topic I think
I'm going to go into JavaScript let me
show you JavaScript in I want to do this
today and you know I know my resume is
more dramatic topic people like to know
but but let's let's do maybe let's do
JavaScript
okay let me show you about my JavaScript
thing close that safa keys close it
oh go ducks keyboard did I put the link
here yet
yes close it
programming blog okay lots of things um
close it okay now let me do let's do
JavaScript let me show you what's going
on what what I want to do okay
bookmark j/s copy the file path close it
and post it here okay this is my
JavaScript in depth so Kathy says yep
here I'm reading the seasoned schema
while listening to your stream because I
know nothing about JavaScript okay
seasoned schema are you getting into
scheme not recommended and the seasons
schema I do not recommend that book
neither
although the author of that book is one
of the most prominent computer
scientists in fact he his specialty is
programming language design that books
author
so let me show you guys okay in case you
don't know I mean many other do not know
because sorry let's see if I have the
book somewhere maybe I will link to it
so did you read Casa Kathy did you read
the sixth book sicp structure and
interpretation of computer programs did
you read a book you know that's one of
the most famous book among dispersed
among hacker types
so I I don't have a article on the
season schema but but I've talked about
the author in my blog but let's show you
sicp wizard book this is the most famous
wizard book so you have read it okay
Kathy has has read this I read this book
in 1998
this book has four chapters and I read
three of them you know so this is very
this this is the book that's kind of
become has become a meme so you see all
the people making a meme of it the
structure and interpretation of computer
programs and there is a sequel a sort of
sequel called how to design programming
languages I you know that came out
around 2004 and I have not read that one
but you know as you get old these books
come in gold you know there's always new
books you cannot read them and also when
you are young you read them but when you
you know after 30 years if you ask your
CEO like reading these books you know
after 30 years you should be you have
written a book you know instead of
talking about Oh which one is the best
book you know that's City after 30 years
you should say okay here's my book I
recommend this book my book you know so
I'm too old to tell you like oh this is
so this this is a great book or that is
not good
great book things like that but anyway
so I read this book like 22 years ago
and I think it's a great book
and so what what am I going to say good
morning Thomas whoa
so I'm going to check to JavaScript
actually the JavaScript I'm going to do
is not about Caesar schema okay wait
hold on a second I want to I want to
tell you about something about season
schema the book okay because that guy
Mathias Mathias is something you know is
one of the great computer science
scientists on programming language
design
so let's go to goal and paint not goal
and let's go to find : script so this is
my goal and script and I want to copy
the file path here and put the file path
here so I'm going to search all files
inside the info directory you have
thousands of files 10,000 20,000 and I
want to search for season schema se a s
o-n-e D that's just search for seasoned
okay so actually such it he will come
back in few seconds there it is
we have several results
there it is so sapphire output mod so
now we can see
seasons schema by Danielle P Friedman
okay that's not a guy you know they are
part of the Rice University team so in
this article I'm talking about this
infix syntax survey this okay this this
is actually a good article and very
dramatic to you know I've been talking
about these things for twenty years so I
kind of get tired of it you know yeah it
doesn't excite me anymore but this this
article is one of the most dramatic
thing among whisper this language in
these programmers because it comes up it
comes up every year about whether list
should have a infix syntax and in fact
it is a pen in this because you don't
have an infix syntax now like I said
before this is a very dramatic topic I
can go on about this this thing for
hours and you'll get a bunch of people
say oh I don't agree oh I you know they
have strong opinions which but usually
that they know nothing okay so what am I
going to say so there it is so I
mentioned this book so racket Liz ok
racket Liz so they have this guy okay so
the guy I'm talking about is Mathias
Valencian fail fail a listen this guy
he's very old now he is like 70 or 80 so
he is you know I always get confused of
him and the Daniel guy Daniel P Friedman
okay okay wait Daniel P Freidman
is the is even older Daniel P Friedman
yeah is even order so the mathias feel
insane is is a student of the neo PP
Freidman let's see I mean they
collaborated often
yeah so Daniel P Fredman
is spawn in 1944 so now he is 76 years
old okay and he and Daniel P Friedman
and the matheus fell insane I always got
confused of these two people I thought I
got confused who is who who did what but
they they often collaborate you know
they are in the PLT scheme team PRT is
you know the group for racket you know
down it's named racket then Friedman is
older okay right so la casa la casa we
form I forgot let's see let me read the
comments okay
so yeah so my comment about that book
you know they they wrote a bunch of
books and it turns out I didn't like
none of it although I respect their walk
however they they created a bunch of
books you know they how to design
programs very popular that's by them
this this book how to design programs is
supposed to be a sequel the sequel for
the for the computer interpretation you
know for the sick for this book
structure and interpretation of computer
programs is supposed to be a sequel
this one the sick book is written in
1980 1980 1990 or 1980
I think it's 1980 something so it's
pretty old so they have this how to
design programs which is a sequel okay
then they have a bunch a secret they
have a sequence of books like little
Java a few patterns I read that book
it's incomprehensible I don't like their
style I don't like the way they talk you
know this books this okay let me let me
read the names the lead a little Java a
few patterns okay in 1998 then the
little m our 1998 ml means meta language
which which which you have Oh camel you
have camel you have standard camel you
have F sharp for Microsoft those are or
ml meta language you know vampire lect
and Haskell is kind of similar Haskell
borrowed a lot from ml meta language so
he wrote also a little Mao and they also
wrote a little schema then they also
wrote the seasoned
schema so I read I read you know one
chapters scanned them I don't like them
yeah I don't like those I don't like
their books they they write in a style
such that they try to
tell a story in a you know they are not
in a typical programming tutorial style
where they say okay to do this you need
to do this or they explain data types of
a language then you explain you know
loops control structure then they
explained they have examples you know
things like that
those are typical programming language
tutorial style of books but there are
there books the little something little
something is is unusual they don't
follow that they try to kind of they are
go I mean their intention is that they
try to tell you some kind of story
such that such that you just read and
read them and you go to ously got your
quad really understand the important
concepts okay that's what they are
trying to tell you that's what they are
trying to do
am I correct Kathy so so I saw so that's
what I'm saying I don't like they their
books okay I even though I respect you
know they these two people I rather
prefer their you know I preferred you
know pure raw logic you know like
mathematical logic you write a book like
a mathematical logic extremely cold and
austere no joke whatsoever every line is
symbolic logic that that that style I
actually prefer oh so they call it the
soak Socratic way like a conversation
right yeah two people can't converse so
let me check the comments the sick takes
a lot of time to do the questions very
painful yet enjoyable to read
so Justine says I enjoyed SiC a lot of
numeric problems but I think that's okay
for prospective programmer okay yeah I
didn't help a lot in read real-world
walk as Kathy says even doing machine
learning there is almost nobody writing
numerical approximation or matrix
multiplication by themselves what do you
mean you mean you mean they those code
already exists in libraries right nobody
there is almost nobody writing writing
numerical approximation or matrix
multiplication by themselves yeah they
already exist in libraries you know the
numerical approximation and matrix they
did you know actually if you dive into
them in detail there's a lot of issues I
mean it's not trivial
I mean it's trivial to create such a
program but it's completely non-trivial
to create a very efficient and accurate
program for doing numerical computation
because you know you in fact you have an
entire subfield numerical analysis you
study for years numerical analysis to
learn how to write efficient algorithms
numerical computation so just in says I
guess because he was from MIT they can
be very numeric focused
can we change to automatic
so just in scarf I always have the idea
he told me that he won't talk to be
automated Theory improver but you know
Justin he's very he's a mathematician
I'm not you know I don't know you know
I'm not qualify I'm just under
undergraduate degree equivalent but
justing always have very weird ideas it
seems to me what do you mean
what do you mean making to be
automatic because as far as I know
automated theorem proving that is the
goal of humanity humanity since 1960
okay since seven since since sixty years
ago automated theorem proving so we want
you know we want to create a system of
computer programs such that just let it
run and you it will create all theorems
like relativity or whatever or the
fundamental theorem of the universe you
know the computer will just run because
after all it's all just logic if it's
just logic why not just let the computer
run you know you just create the system
and let it read you just create all the
theorems you possibly will ever know in
the future you know you don't need human
mathematicians anymore so that's a core
that that is you know that is of course
the ultimate core but we tried and tried
and try it we can do it there's turns of
problems because when you dive deep into
logic you find that your systems doesn't
work you you run into lots of problems
so you know incompleteness problem where
if you have a system you cannot prove
certain things you can prove that you
cannot prove certain things so you run
into a dead end then you try to modify
that then you have different logic then
you have type theory oh that doesn't
work so we need types you know because
if you have this system you run into
Russell's paradox because this sentence
is true if it is not true you ran into a
Russell's muscle power paradox so you
try to fix that then you create type
system type theory you have hierarchy of
types then you thank you infinity
problem so you know so all the logicians
and mathematicians the ultimate goal is
to create the automated theorem provers
but when you dive into all these details
you find problems problems you know you
fix them
and to this day we don't have you know
it doesn't work ok well we have a lot of
progress but as far as a automated
theory improved system
that's still a dream that's far down the
road dream we have no way of tackling
that problem for example another you
know I'm not really qualified to talk
about this but I know a little bit about
it so so you have so many systems and so
right now the current the hotshot system
is the univariant math foundation or
homotopy type theory you know many of
you has especially asked our people just
in Jones you must have no you know
homotopy type theory and and then
there's also category theory ok so you
try to e so you have all these systems
and you know first order logic symbol
you know second order symbolic logic and
you know there's so many and so far we
don't know we don't you know we we are
far from far from a automated theorem
proof system so since you know 20 years
ago mathematicians and logicians they
stopped they abandoned abandoned the
goal they understand that that's a pipe
dream we are not going to do that
anymore so they abandoned it it instead
they have a what's called a theorem
proving theorem proving assistant
programs you know theorem proving a CSUN
system assistant system that means a
computer program that helps you prove
systems prove theorems help
mathematicians help logicians prove
theorems it means you know you
it's a program you don't you know it's
not just that it runs by itself you have
to actually it just help you you know it
helps mathematicians to create theorems
and is one of them coq okay I let
me show you article okay sorry
theorem proved
prove us I wrote this article ten years
ago because I was trying to understand
the thing okay state of fear improving
systems 2008 is one of them and you
have several others you have many of
them are written in oak ammo you know
the meta language the meta language you
know we talked about in this book so let
me copy the link okay so let me show it
okay so you know they are trying to
write you know so that you have these
proof systems whole light this one is
written your camo meter is written in
Pascal I think and is written in Oh
cam Oh Isabelle Isabelle is written in
Pascal meter is returning I forgot what
and you know so you have these systems
and by the way there is also one written
in Common Lisp not popular so you know
you can actually each one of them has a
Wikipedia article you can you know read
let me just put let me post my link pin
so that that that is what I know I think
so I don't know just in scarf I what are
you saying about automated system
because this mathematician has stopped
doing that they instead they have proof
assistants they renamed their system to
be called proof assistant systems but I
you know I don't know I don't know the
thing but just team scarf I knows so I
so you have to teach us
you know just in scarf is saying okay
just in sci-fi says
my sir is first-order logic okay my sir
is first-order logic okay so so I don't
understand what do you mean by automated
theorem you know I think Justin told me
he wants to he has idea of creating a
system that's automated automated
definition creation system that means
you just let the program run and we will
create all definitions automatically
that that's kind of beyond me so I don't
know I don't know what's your question
yeah I mean I I yeah so
so actually I talked about ten hours how
long have I been talking 13 people
watching we have 10 more minutes they
mean to 10 moaning minutes but Amala
okay la casa is from Guatemala right
great la casa I have to remember la casa
it's a Spanish name so Guatemala
so yeah just in scarf I says there are
people walking on automated automates
mathematical definitions I don't know
what's the context so I don't yeah you
have to tell us
okay so let's next thing let's talk
about 10 more minutes and we shut down
and I want to do this javascript thing
essentially it's a that's a book those
are the people let's close it refresh so
I want to yeah so this syntax away cuz
it okay so let me show you JavaScript
okay so you go through my JavaScript
in-depth and you can see so I have you
know JavaScript in-depth I spent two
years albeit by my book okay that's what
I'm going to say just go there and buy
it you go to paper and buy it
it's a in-depth JavaScript in my style
okay I teach JavaScript in-depth so
we're gonna do ten more minutes and
they'll be it any final questions or
comments say it now
okay let's get a drink
Rockstar Energy Drink
sugar free
and one maker
turn of apple juice golden apple juice
Mikey this is spicy core lock
justine says some of my messages don't
get through here that's correct because
google is doing censorship and stuff if
you do not if you do not a let me do
this okay I want to paste okay let me
explain what's going on so I create so
let me let me show you
Emacs workflow okay so actually the
season schema this is a go script cause
it actually close it close the window so
let me show you what I'm doing I'm going
to copy the file path of this buffer now
it's copied and you see you can see
always remember to check the left window
it shows all my comments so copy the
file path paste it here edit it so that
the HTML become text txt okay now I'm
going to open the link and it says the
file does not exist do I want to create
it space well yes okay now I go to here
select all copy go back to Emacs paste
so this is today's chat now why do I
want to paste well I want to save it you
know so we can have record okay you know
this is no secret information this is
public so so copy the file path so now I
want to link a fight so I just press a
key it becomes a link and press a key
becomes a paragraph and showing browser
and scroll down so we have a link of
today's chat now I want to do it there
because you know so just in scarf I says
tell us why Google saying
you know it just means a very you know
it's a mathematician and so his view is
very focused on math he study math like
20 hours a day so he doesn't doesn't
really see things what's going on you
know why do go sensor that's a big topic
because Google has become very evil
because look look at what you just
posted that line is censored you see can
you see that you know you you typed tell
us why Google senses and Google sensor
that one because Google don't want you
to know they are doing censorship and
this is going on right now in society
and you know we call it wow it's just
going okay maybe maybe you don't you
know once you know the more you know it
the worse it get you know it's not good
so let me show that so let me try to
switch to live chat so let's see if I
see any post that's not here anyway so
let me show you JavaScript so go to
JavaScript so this is my JavaScript in
depth and you can see these are the
topics so first of all on the left you
have JavaScript in depth you have HTML
tutorial you have cascading style sheet
tutorial then you have JavaScript in
depth then you have JavaScript object
references you know this is this is
references for JavaScript object then
you have Tom now dome is is what you
need to do when you when you want to use
JavaScript to program websites they are
separate from JavaScript so you
need to study dumb then you have SVG
tutorial SVG is a graphics system that
allows you to create dynamic animations
such as clocks pie charts statistical
charts stock stock charts business
charts things like that so this is my
tutorial and then you have my blog about
this related web programming stuff so
you buy it you buy my JavaScript
tutorial you get all of them ok now what
I want to do is you see you go to my
JavaScript in-depth and you scroll down
there's a video ok this video is my live
stream teaching you how to write a
interactive rotating polyhedron so
anyway you look at the index okay so
this is my table of contents page so you
can see JavaScript basics so you you
have basics here or these are basics and
JavaScript variables then JavaScript
string topics then JavaScript functions
or about JavaScript script functions
then all about JavaScript object
properties then about object and
inheritance then about array then about
lots of other things so if you go
through each one of them let's say let's
go to JavaScript function let's click on
it so you see I tell you all the
possible ways to define a function in
JavaScript that's this page now you
scroll down at the bottom you will see
this navigation box again now again this
box is all about related to JavaScript
function so you can move on to the next
topic arrow function so this page
discussed in detail everything you need
to know about arrow phone
which in this community is just called
lambda anonymous functions okay so good
morning Matt and okay so arrow functions
so again you go to the bottom then you
see the same navigation box again about
JavaScript function arrows everything
about JavaScript function now I like to
make a change I like to make a change so
that all these little different
navigation boxes become one big
navigation box so in other words what I
like to do is you see let's go back to
the index page you see all these
navigation boxes I want to make them so
that there is one one big like coherent
navigation box so that's what I'm to do
in the next five minutes that's two five
minutes okay let's try it then we shut
down good morning George we are about to
cross style you so late well you it good
morning to Australia it's very early
there so what time is seeing Australia
and thank you for coming by so Australia
is 7 o clock 8 o clock in the morning
he's alright Australia Perth you know on
the west side of Australia so it 8 o
clock in the morning right so anyway let
me go
let me start to work on the JavaScript
let's just do it ok so before we do
anything let's go to the directory saw
the info then git status you know I'm
using it if you don't know get just
search for sorry get you will find my
kid tutorial for version control
so this is the so it tells me of this
file has been changed and all these this
aren't a new file so let's just do it
okay let me do this quickly so get add
to it then get commit committed okay
then let's call Kassar interactive a
brief okay and let's type back and what
you get is the delete backup command
command line here okay I say enter so
that we are delete or Emacs created
backup files okay it's done so now I
want to make a backup I want to do a git
commit so because right now I'm going to
do a systematic Find and Replace on
hundreds of pages so if I make a mistake
I can revert because I have I just have
a git commit I can revert to the version
before so now we have that okay so now
we are going to make a change let me do
this quickly okay so first of all go
back to Emacs
yeah Google Google censored my very
important message what's what's your
message posting quarantine zone Oh
George don't post anything sensitive not
sure what is that don't was anything
sensitive so let me make a copy okay
make a backup of this directory done and
the command is that then I want to copy
this okay copy this okay I want to
create a new file paste it here save it
xx today's date okay and so this is the
what we're gonna do okay so actually
open a new buffer so so I'm going to I'm
just gonna walk on it okay so let's just
watch me walk find and replace replaced
by nothing that okay showing browser so
now you can see we have one huge
navigation box okay
and the miscellaneous actually I want to
include the miscellaneous so let's go
through the miscellaneous showing
browser let's go down there it is
miscellaneous part of the huge
navigation box now what you want to do
what I want to do is let's move this
here okay set background color seashell
okay and I want to copy this line copy
copy this block of text go here I'm
gonna hold on a second let me show you
this okay for you Emacs users I want to
copy this entire navigation box text and
I'm going to press a key so now it's
copied to my register you can see the
command is a copy to register so now so
I have this text block of AB available
to me anytime now I want to copy this
copy yet so cokes are fine replace paste
that this is a text I want to replace
then I want to replace by that whole
navigation box so I paste it easy and I
say okay and in this directory yes and
in HTML files suffix yes the extension
name yes my change is to file yes
fixed case in such yes fixed case in
replacement yes make a backup yes
okay now it's done it's done - tensor
files it's a simple okay so now close it
now let's do this again so now
javaScript variables
okay then now javaScript strain
okay then now javaScript function
okay now abject poverty
okay then now what is this object and
inheritance then now JavaScript array
find it replaced by the full nav box
then now JavaScript constructor in
classes find it replaced by the fou-fou
navigation box then now JavaScript
iterable which is a new thing in
JavaScript find it replace by the full
navigation box okay let me try it again
then no JavaScript regular expression
now javaScript number
now javaScript miscellaneous actually
miscellaneous is there is no navigation
box so we don't need to do that so
actually this is Orton
so now let's view in browser you see
beautiful full navigation box let's see
if we American fine it's magnifying okay
so we have JavaScript let's click on one
of them let's go to JavaScript function
define function now scroll down you see
now we have the entire fool JavaScript
box here you see you see the green shows
the current page now let's jump to
JavaScript object property poverty
overview now scroll down now you have
the entire navigation table of contents
again so you see so this is fantastic
actually it's done now what I'm going to
do is just to sync to my web server so i
go to i go to the shell again
yaow and saw interactive a brief rsync
enter upload to my web server so now if
you you see all these files has been
updated about 200-300 files 250 files so
now you go to sorry JavaScript and we
are done today okay thank you guys for
coming so let's see sorry JavaScript or
such for JavaScript in depth you can see
the fruit of today's walk you see the
the index becomes 1 the table of
contents contents let's see JavaScript
constructor class let's click on that
this binding very complex
in JavaScript so that's it for today
okay so Google better make your video
safe for work Matt what is quarantine
song tell me on discord okay just in
scarf I the quarantine song is my is a
Mac sorry discord it's a channel it's a
room for discussing sensitive topics
basically yeah so Kathy says it's
originally set to discussing
controversial topics with heads-up
warning so that they can focus on the
discussion without falling in pickering
offensive argument that's true that's
true okay thank you guys for coming
thank you for watching that is it for
today's top talk show and hope to see
you tomorrow and hope to see you on this
code by my tutorials okay emac this in
depth in javascript in depth bye guys
and thank you guys for Kathy and many of
you who has already donated