good morning
everyone welcome to another episode of s
talk
show we have 10 people Welcome All Today
Is
2020 December 18th Friday 1:00 in the
afternoon San Francisco time today we
are going to do emac lisp nothing but
emac lisp and maybe other programming
related topics or maybe keyboard a
little you know maybe uh if you have
comments comments questions post it okay
I love to see your comments any of your
thoughts why do you have Marissa on
preview okay that is a interesting
question let me show you okay Marissa
from the anime fan from the anime club
so this is my emac blog so you can see
scroll down this this this anime
character okay this Japanese anime
character Marissa and uh she turns out
to be a video game she's from a video
game kind of a shooter video game and
our member our family Emily is very fond
of uh and I found this icon on uh for
chat actually so I just you know uh I
just post it I you know it seems
interesting although this is not my
thing uh but this one is okay so her
Chinese name
is okay something like
thata I I don't remember exactly what's
the first character or my so that means
foggy fogy and
Rain morisa means uh Magic and something
okay so that's her name uh it's a
Japanese
character uh and if you I did look into
the uh you know you can just search the
name and you'll find the game and lots
of information who created the game the
company it seems to be either Japanese
guy or Chinese guy in Shanghai uh and
this game is extremely
popular but this is uh Beyond you know
this
is this is um
during the time uh I think beginning in
2000s something like that I'm not
familiar with So today we're going to
talk about emac list emac and emac list
coding and related stuff so comments
okay 10 people watching
comments okay let's see let's check if
my video is going check video check
audio check okay so what are we going to
do uh I'm thinking either just talk
about some of the interesting stuff so
so I can talk about uh some interesting
stuff about emac emac documentation you
know emac documentation they need to
change
to they need to change to the HTML
format emac documentation is using the
um let me show you okay you know uh if I
started to talk about that then it's
going to be nonstop so I have it
somewhere here
here so there is a lot changes I've been
coding emac list for the past two days
uh I haven't been doing that for a while
and that's fantastic iMac
this okay let let me just begin talking
about random okay emac related things so
uh first of all I so here this page emac
list function frequency so I so here is
the frequency of the functions used in
emac dis so for example you can see set
Q is the most used of all emac this
functions set Q is the most used and if
is the second most used uh uh obviously
it's uh understandable defund is the
third most used defend of course you
need to define a function and let is uh
fourth most used let is used for
creating local variables so obviously
and is also frequently used of course
that's a logic operator and you know
conditions condition you know usually
used with if you know if something
something something condition are meant
you do something so that is and or and
then you have car car is a leis thing
basically it means the first element of
a
list and the name is got a long
history that that's one of the least
idiocy it it's one of the idios
syncratic thing in lisp language and uh
whenever there's a ideosyncratic thing
of a language that is unique to the
language then that thing becomes the uh
the legend the myth the you know it
becomes the identity so whenever you
hear people talk about Lis you'll hear K
you'll hear that and also also Lis maros
and also you know symbols K maros uh
that's that's the thing you hear in
parenthesis of course because those
things are unique kind of unique to the
language and and uh they become the
representation they become the identity
thing so that's so so car is one of such
thing in lisp language in emac you also
have that for example scratch buffer
meta every time you hear emac people
talk they'll talk meta scratch buer how
it is supremely useful and all that crap
it's a complete garbage Okay the reason
like I said the reason they become
popular the reason every time you know
uh people talk about emac they will have
mention meta they will mention scratch
bu buffer they they will they will have
like a a unnecessary is like these
topics will come up and up again again
for 10 20 30 years and almost
unnecessarily and triv
like nobody needs to know something
about that but people will start to
mention it why because it is precisely
because this items they they are
idiosyncratic to this uh tool or
programming language for example in emx
meta scratch buffer
um uh what are the other things you know
super hyper keyos as well you know so
and and EM uh yeah the most mostly these
things and also emac do you know emac
and do is very unusual uh it's almost
unique so people will constantly mention
it
uh as I said the reason is that because
they they are idiosyncratic to the to
the application to the tool and they
become somewhat become identity and it
becomes a code issue it became a code
icon so people will constantly mention
it and and unnecessarily almost like
idiotically and every time you know you
mention maybe you should change that you
know people will become it'll become a
flame world that is why because they so
for example I mentioned so for emac it's
meta scratch buffer uh meta key Super
Hyper key scratch buffer okay that's
emac for for lisp the language in
general you have uh of course the
parenthesis then you have K and kada and
you know con cells then you have the uh
Lis marro okay Lis mro is also has been
unique in programming languages for you
know for for 30 years 40 years so that's
Lis and python too you know python also
python is also a Cy language among the
open source so for python the the
indentation okay the indentation that's
a big thing every time uh when python is
talked about the indentation indentation
issue will come up always almost always
because that's kind of the idiosyncratic
to python is and it gradually and
becomes a you know identity uh
issue so python is indent indentation
then
uh you know and uh and and so on and and
also other things other languages uh I'm
not going to talk about so comments okay
good evening good uh good to
know VW
uh v96 K good to know thanks for the
answer what answer I became a wee uh
Weeble okay wee now weeb is a corruption
linguistically speaking the word weeb
web is a Corruption of the word weable
of the of the slam weo uh we a b o how
do I know because I looked up and weo
means
it has an interesting history atmology
how it how it became so weable it means
basically someone usually Americans okay
American or white people who are uh
obsessive about Japanese things anime
and
stuff you know inter interesting uh
atmology uh linguistic aspects those are
Slants and and
Slants also languages slans they
reflect the culture they reflect the
community you know so so when you
use jihani when you say I became a
weave other people can tell you know
what it means and other people can also
tell probably your age your age group
you know you are probably under 30 let's
say or under 20 not above 50 for sure
you know so it language you know the the
the diction the choice the diction the
choice of word words you use they
reflect uh you and and your personality
and also the community and also it
reflects in you know at large they
reflects Humanity you know the whatever
American country you know as a country
or Chinese or Russian or Japanese you
know the language you know even or
French they reflect your culture in lots
of ways uh
so what I'm what I'm going uh what I'm
going into I don't remember so anyway
um so
Earnest says maybe another aspect that
it came that it come up a lot is that
new people are wondering what the
idiosyn syncratic thing is yes it's
almost like a viscious circle for
example emac meta you know emac when you
talk about emac you have meta and
scratch B so people will constantly
mention it and if people mention it the
new New Comers they see oh what what is
that they don't know of course so they
so they are look you know they'll start
to learn about it then they will become
there we start to uh mention
it oh answer about Marissa oh oh oh yeah
okay so uh Marchin
says marching was
wasak uh I think I know you from
somewhere do I are you the M thing I
know I think I think your name sounds
familiar are you the keyboard
guy uh hi I would like to ask about
latch do you use any compiler in emx
thank you for being here sorry to use
emx uh about from about your channel oh
well lch I don't use it anymore I used
it in
1990s and I use it for a year you know
on and off uh in 2000s uh I haven't been
using
latch for the past 10 years
do you use any compiler in emx what do
you mean by compiler do what do you mean
like Java compiler JavaScript compiler C
language compiler or what or you mean
compile emac what what do you mean do
you use any compiler in
emac okay answer that okay so we have 20
people watching okay so back to the
topic iMac this function frequency so
this this is interesting because I wrote
a program so you can see there I I list
the top
500 top 500 most used functions in emac
lisp the language and the way it's done
is using I wrote this python
script uh this you know I did this in
2006 you can
see in 2006 so you can see the old
version here in 2006 okay 2006 that's
emac 2 three so here's a list of the
most frequently used uh emac functions
in emac 23 but but now I rewrote
yesterday I rewrote the Python program
it's amazing python so I wrote this in
2006 python 2 and it worked it still
works but I upgraded you know I I
modified it to be Python
3 so you can run this script uh yourself
to do the same to get this uh you know
to Tad this uh function
call count so the way it's done is just
uh you know you just um read a text file
or emac source code then you split you
you read the whole thing as a string
then you split by the left parenthesis
okay into you split it into a array so
for each array you find the first word
that's how this is done now now perhaps
you know technically there may be better
ways actually this is this is very
practical and also by doing this you can
find some weird things you know for
example you find
four so you see you you find there four
you see uh item 453 so let's go to emac
uh let's show you
okay so apparently you find
uh so apparently in some emac emac list
source code you have this line now four
is not a EAC list function maybe they uh
you know maybe let's see describe
function so there's no function named
for no is there a variable named for
described variable so it's not so that
means apparently maybe they wrote a mar
or something but anyway that's a that's
a side effect of interesting things you
find in this um when you do this okay
that's uh one of the thing okay so this
is the this iMac this function frequency
and by the way if you don't know already
I also have a uh wait I also have a emac
command frequency statistics so you know
in emac every keystroke is a command
call you know essentially every
keystroke is corresponding to a uh emac
list command name so so so that means
you can you can get a statistics of you
know the most used uh frequently used
commands so the reason I do this is is
so that when you want to design a
efficient keyboard layout for emac you
you need to know which command I use the
most for example um each one has a
command name so this down arrow actually
I use a shortcut so down arrow means
here's a table so down arrow means one
you know the command next line or the
command diet next line or the command
next history element they they are all
down arrow key you know
so and uh the return key we are call the
command new line or or return or or
return inent or some other you know
depending on which major mod you are in
so you have to kind of do some kind of
trans translation a little
bit uh in order to create this table in
a sensible way because my goal is to to
find out which um
which command I used the most often for
examp anyway so I'm not I'm not going to
go into details but anyway you can see
so here is the you know the emac command
ordered by their frequency of
use anyway you can look at this page uh
in
detail so let's go back let's go to
let's just talk about something
interesting random okay so I'm thinking
I'm going to do some this coding
any okay so M's
question is for export from export from
latch to
PDF oh that's uh that's pretty easy I
mean is that a problem you need to solve
or is that are you asking what's the
best way something like
that uh I use emx for writing o file
spash script and programming Ruby okay
so anyway anyway I haven't used latch
but basically I know these days today
what you do is basically you just write
them in OG
mod I don't use o mod that much I don't
use it basically so yeah but you can you
know you know you if you use OT just use
o mod and you can have latch uh
expressions in O mod and when you export
they will become for uh Rand
that's
I yeah that's what most people do uh
today uh few people you know back in the
90s or 2000s well of course before
before 2008 also Oak mod was not there
yet there's no Oak mod uh but
anyway today most people just you know
if you need some lat or math formulas
you do it inside Oak mod but before you
but you can still do it in pure latch
you know you can uh there's there are
there are quite a few latch you know
mods for lch just for latch but I
believe I believe fewer and fewer people
do that because it's it's kind of you
know you can just do uh use it in O mod
much
easier okay ER says another good thing
to do would be to see most command uh
most common commands after some command
uh yeah you mean command combination you
you well what why do you want to do
that I do not use o mod so I what do I
use I talked about this many times in
fact it's a frequently Asked question
because all the people all the oak fans
they see me you know writing uh raw raw
HTML and they are wondering why don't
you use o mod what kind of uh static
website system do you use I talk about
this many times I use I code
inl talk show okay let's go to talk
shows page so let's let's magnify
magnify and show in browser all single
all single key press so this is today's
talk show and let's turn on
JavaScript uh okay so you can see that's
is today's talk show search for YouTube
so that YouTube video is this text block
okay so so I'm I'm showing you some of
my workflow in emac so I comment I just
press a key to comment without showing
browser one key press and it's uh it's G
so uh one key press back to emac you see
one always one single key press okay
again I need to show you my
um my keyboard setup okay so this is
kesis advantage to fantastic I recommend
it and this is a ultimate hacking
keyboard
uh by the way uh version two just came
out and I wrote a Blog about it so but I
use my ultimate hacking keyboard for all
keyboard markers so I show this many
times so this is the last window uh last
window and this is uh previous page pre
previous tab next Tab and this this page
is Optical key switch keyboard they are
pretty cheap so if you want a a cheap
mechanical keyboard I can recommend that
okay so but anyway so I want to yeah
talk show so you can see uh okay so go
back to here hide this so you can see
I'm uh so show the pink window the pink
window is all my emac commands Okay
close this all single key press you can
see that I
code every uh
everything in raw HTML why because I
grew up with HTML I learned HTML since
1995 HTML
version uh that is that is be version
two around version two or and CSS is not
was not even B yet CSS began around 1997
or
1998 and when it began CSS nobody is
using it people are using you know
people are embedding let me show you
okay so for
example uh let me show you okay so so I
uh for example let's put the CER on the
let's magnify okay magnify show the pink
window and uh I want to add a span
okay span and uh class let's say
bold uh uh let's say class whatever okay
uh okay so you see it automatically
added that okay and show in browser show
in browser there's no change because
because uh
whoops uh so instead of class I just say
style font size let's say 3 e r m okay
showing browser you can see the raw is
big and if you want color you just say
color red okay showing browser so that's
what I do that's uh everything in row
Edge HML because I know HTML in CSS so
well uh in fact and witha keys Anda HTML
mod which is what I'm using you can see
in the mod line so for example I do uh
hold on a second show the pink window
describe variable okay wait describe
variable uh major mod now major mod is a
building variable in emac now when so
you can see describe variable and will
it will tell you what mod you are using
so you can see I'm using S HTML mod uh
because why because I uh well since I've
been using emac for 20 years and coding
emac list for 15 years so I wrote almost
uh lots of things by
myself and in fact that's just
convenient and natural for me just
because I used it for so many years if
you use emac for you know or coding emac
list for 10 years you'll do that too
it's actually easier to to write your
own then than than using someone else's
package and learning about it yeah so
here is my HTML mod uh a total of uh
almost 5,000 lines uh and uh so I claim
you know because I built everything
myself in emac so it's actually if you
count keystrokes to create the same
documentation using you know HTML in
HTML versus in O mod I claim
okay with s FL keys that you actually
the keystroke needed is act will be
actually less than oak mod okay so to me
using HTML is actually more efficient
than oak mod and I don't have to export
nothing uh and I have full control I I
have full control control of it for
example here is my CSS uh
file you know all this CSS F it's not
template okay it's not template or
framework it's all this this is all
Cod coded manually okay created manually
over the years so my CSS is CSS is 200
lines they they are very extremely
efficient okay these CSS because I know
every uh word every uh uh style I create
there's no fat link
okay so anyway that that is why I do not
use o mod I actually I tried to use Mark
since 10 years ago it just um I prefer
HTML I you know just because I I know it
so
much
um okay that's about that
so so let me talk about the things okay
so uh perhaps there exists an auto key
assigner based on such uh statistics but
algorithm would not be too
trivial uh no well so you are saying you
know to create a more sufficient layout
for emac first of all let me mention you
know a lot of people okay uh today's
topic is beginning to become not emac
because I was thinking to talk
about uh emac LP coding because I wanted
to code some emac L emac LP there's a
lot
hashtable uh uh find replace you know
yeah a lot but anyway okay keep minding
okay let me let me tell you about key
bindings okay
so so keyboard layout so I I talked
about this many times so you know there
are many keyboard layouts right so there
is a quy layout uh there is the vorak
layout this this is a heat map by the
way the the bigger the circle means that
letter is the most frequently used so if
you go to quy you can see they are
scattered all over but vorak most of
them frequently used letters are on the
home row and same thing with uh comac
comac DH Workman you know they have
different philosophies each each person
created a different layout Norman asset
cap
whale qfm L Wy and minimac minimac is a
anyway so so these are letter layout you
know people you know most programmers
are a lot of them are obsessive about it
but what they did not know you not
you'll rarely find any study is the
shortcut layout okay now let me show you
some Shortcut layout so you go to my uh
keyboard page so all these articles are
about layout okay those are letter
layout okay keyboard layout design this
all these articles are about letter
layout for example uh which one is the
most efficient uh which one motron
versus vak you know motron has a special
keyboard you have the e letter e on the
thumb key very interesting so I you know
I comment on on that you have coac
versus Workman you know coac versus
Workman why is workman invented so so
all these are related to keyboard layout
and they are letter layout remember that
this is important now we go to this
section this all these are about key
binding now what's key binding key
binding is you know when you are in emac
you have meta X control something you
know old something or uh cut copy paste
you know control X control C control V
and do and if you use Photoshop or video
editing you know you have hundreds
usually 100 keyboard
shortcuts uh keyboard shortcuts are in
fact essential you know because almost
in any application you for for example
switch tab is uh depending on what
usually it's control Tab and control
shift tab but on the Mac it's something
else and you and be 10 years ago 20
years ago each browser have actually
different Keys uh so anyway so so this
see you see these are shortcut short
shortcuts are critical you know almost
in any application you need to use it
okay let's go back
to uh shortcuts are critical in fact
when I studied the the the thing I
showed you know the emac statistics it
turns out if you are a programmer okay
let's say you you are a programmer you
log your keystrokes it turns
out on average you know if you average
out all the programmers at least okay or
more than 50% of key strokes is actually
shortcut keys you see if you measure if
you lock your key comp and if you do
that for let's say one 10,000
programmers it turns out out most of the
keystroke are are used are part of the
keyboard shortcuts not typing okay you
see that this is one of the critical
things I I I I found when I study the
key the when I did the emac
statistics it depends on the person
though but on
average so what I'm saying is that you
you actually you know the you your
fingers type on type keyboard shortcuts
more often than than when you actually
insert letters so that means the
keyboard layout the keyboard shortcut
layout is actually more important than
than the keyboard letter layout so this
is an interesting finding so this is
another reason I I I I um I
despise the the hackers because when you
look at the keyboard Community you know
there are a lot there are thousands of
people obsessive about this letter
layout you know they created so many
Vari ities and even to this day people
are still debating you know trying to
find statistic which one is better you
know oh but but home Row versus you know
a different kind of scoring system uh
Comon you know finger row of the Workman
and so on but they but you never see
actually there's something else more
important that's a shortcut layout but
you you not find one
these hacker types you you'll not find
them talking them talking about that
I did okay I did like it's like 15 years
ago
now so you know I I don't I you know
swearing and you know hate is my
personality okay hate defines me that's
how I have I am you know due to reasons
so you see me swear a lot but but in uh
in general okay
I the problem is not um so the problem
I'm in General criticizing is just uh
the common you know the common the
masses you know the masses in general
they they don't think they are
not you know that's a you know that's a
masses including programmers you know in
each field you have the mass of people
they just follow they they are not
thinkers you know they don't think they
just follow whatever other people are
saying and they it becomes hip you know
they follow Trend and fashion you know
you go to Hacker News or you follow emac
community everyone will say oh you
should change control to Caps loog or or
you should you know V or what whatever
you know the these
people they are actually they are not
you know they they they become Elite
they tell you what to do but actually
they are not they are they are not
thinkers they never do anything they
never actually think uh about
things but however uh many of them they
form a Cod you know such as the python
code the python code the Lis code the
emac code and among this code you you
have Elite leaders they tell you what to
do and and half of half of the time is
just incorrect um for example in Python
code they'll tell you about edms they
tell you how you should code your you
know lots of EDM pep you know stuff
anyway I talked about python in one of
my
video so anyway so well that's that's a
bit too much of a rent I guess okay so
so anyway back to the important point so
the point is that shortcut keys are
actually more frequently used therefore
more important if you are concerned
about you know your keyboarding issues
your RI or whatever
so so in this section I talk about all
you know uh keyboarding for example one
here's another thing hacker idiots okay
here's another thing about hacker idiots
how many keyboard shortcuts are there
you know the hacker types you know emac
all programmers every every one of them
they you know you'll see them talk about
oh you know they they want to you know
map hyper hyper you know meta keys for
example let me show you some some uh
some interesting thisis
keyboards lisp key keyboards you can see
I talked about this many times okay so
so sell keyboard is a granddaddy the
root of all this keyboard This is a sale
keyboard Stanford AI lab in 19
1970 uh this lab is created by m John
McCarthy the guy who created Lis the
language and uh on this keyboard sell
keyboard you see it's the first keyboard
with the meta key and it is also this
keyboard you know on today you have you
know on the Mac you have command key on
Windows you have window key they are all
derivative of this meta key okay so it
is this cell keyboard that created the
first one that created the concept of a
meta key other than control and shift
control and shift was there
before so anyway this is l l keyboard so
what my point is you know I I want to
mention the you know the
the okay let me mention I talked about
this many times space cadet keyboard you
know you see on Hacker News on keyboard
uh groups or in emac emac community
you'll see lots of you know
uh fan phandom of this you know they'll
get excited about oh Meta Meta control
old you know they mention that all the
time so remember I said before keyboard
shortcut is more important so now you
have this keyboard so control meta Al
you know control meta Al hyper and top
you know Greek you know so many uh
modifier keys so wouldn't you think that
would be that's fantastic right that's
you know that's more you know um
modifier keys for shortgun so that's
good right no actually that's bad that
this is bad okay you don't want modify
modifier keys so how so without modifier
Keys how do you
shortcuts so back to the key binding
article so so this article I talk about
you know modifier Keys versus key
sequence so what does key sequence means
for example let's say uh let's say copy
okay control C for copy right now on
windows by the way you can also do copy
by old uh by
old uh old space
C I believe or was it old EC F10 EC okay
I forgot which one exactly I'm not on
Windows well my Windows machine is
outside anyway you know you know on
Windows you can press alt release it and
then press space then press W to uh C to
close the window okay instead instead of
the old F4 so that so anyway that's an
example of key sequence and on this page
I talk about how many
um how many possible
shortcuts are there if you use modifier
keys or if you use key sequences it
turns out key sequences you have far far
more modifier Keys than than the same
number of keys for if if they are
modifier Keys far more okay so that
means that so that means you know when
when when it comes to list keyboard you
know all the Nerds will they will say
you know they will get excited oh my God
on this keyboard you have eight modifier
keys so that means you can have like
10,000 or 100,000 combinations you know
they all say that you know you go to
Wikipedia you can read you know a
sentence about that almost anywhere they
talk about this uh they they get excited
excited about this space cect keyboard
you'll see that but that idea that
concept is actually idiotic you know you
don't want that you you don't want you
know so yeah okay so you can you can all
have you can have all these combinations
but all these
combinations in fact you can do the
exact same you know combinations without
requiring all these modifier Keys you
just need two or three
uh keys that is used as a leader key of
a key sequence not not as a modifier
Okay so that's my point that's that's
one of my point about you know that's
what this page is about you actually
start to calculate how many
possibilities using key sequence
compared to uh keyboard
shortcut okay so what's the point here
so the point here well so is and and
also you can compare which one is easier
to press suppose you need to press
control alt meta C okay suppose that
versus let's say function seven function
function eight function n both of them
are just you know one of them is Four
Keys Control Alt meta C Four Keys you
have to hold three of them together then
press the other one then release the
other one then release the other three
okay that's kind of complicated control
control
meta out then see then release and
release this then you got that okay so
that versus let's say a sequence key
let's say f F7 AB okay F7 a so which one
is easier you tell me okay one is three
keys one is four keys and the Four Keys
part you have to involves complicated
order and you know thinking so these
idiots these hacker idiots they never
they never never they never saw this
they never even thought about
it so so what is so I found this so what
is the practical application well now
you know that so you can start to uh
rebind your emac keys you know to find
out which one you know to get a better
system or better way so that you can do
things faster more efficient and less
finger Sprint you know less repe
repetitive strength injury okay that's
just one of the article there's quite a
lot so why am I mentioning this okay so
I me I'm mentioning this because we were
talking about
uh I forgot what's the question you know
um yeah I was mention it because yeah
because uh well someone mentioned about
yeah an algorithm to automatically
create the most efficient keyboard
layout okay that
idea that idea is a great idea but
um it's not so easy okay there are many
issues for example the is issues I just
just talked
about so if you are going to do do that
if you you know it's certainly possible
to write a program that first of all you
know based on the most frequently used
emac commands then you want to map them
to uh the most frequently used keybo
shortcuts but it's not trivial to do
because first of all what kind of
shortcut are you going to use are you
going to use modifier keys or keyc
sequence you see normally you may not
even thought about key sequences that's
a problem you see that's a problem with
the most programers hackers they don't
they don't think but but now you know
there's a key sequences so maybe you can
you can think about maybe the program
should map them to key sequences as
opposed to uh key code by the way there
are more issues about key sequence and
key code now one problem with key
sequence is that you cannot use them to
repeat for example with key key code
suppose you want to
um uh suppose you want to do something
um move coer okay let's
see so you see I can move CER you see
right now I'm moving CER by paragraph
you can see one paragraph down one
paragraph down I can hold it and move
all the way down you can see the my
command on the on the right on the Ping
window window okay so that command is
Kasa end of line or
block I'm using CA flag key so you see I
can hold down one key and it keeps
moving or similarly I can move by word
right
now this you can do with a key code but
if you use a key sequence you cannot do
that because you cannot just hold it
down you because every time you have to
press the key sequence I also talked
about that in here okay one of the one
of the article Bank codes
okay so the so these are the issues you
have to dive into you know so anyway
that's a Segway that you know that's um
so back to the to your point about
writing a program to automatic
automatically create the most um easy
shortcut you know map the most easy
commands through shortcut that's not
trivial because then because besides all
these issues I just mentioned you know
key code or key sequence you have you
also have to come up with a scoring
system to determine which key code is
easier for example let's say let me just
ask you is control C better than old C
which one is better should your program
automatically you know which one is
better control C or C or or or shift
C you know if I ask you that it's not a
simple question because first of all it
depends on what keyboard you use you
know I'm using this Batman keyboard is
fancy so there's one answer for that but
for a traditional keyboard or for a
laptop top keyboard the answer is going
to be different so you have to make a
decision you know then maybe you think
okay so you have to base on the keyboard
that most people are
using right but if you do that then
whatever outcome of your algorithm will
not be good for people who are not using
a traditional keyboard for for example
any person who use ergonomic keyboard
then your system will will not be
suitable because your system will
actually create inefficient layout for
them so it's not a trivial problem
okay uh okay so that's uh um okay also
if you want to the you know it it also
has to be app dependent because for emac
for Photoshop for inkscape for any
application they have different
shortcuts you know different command
commands so anyway that's um that's
about
[Music]
that oh so I watched your talk about
this before it's the thing that inspired
my comments okay thank you yeah I well
you know uh excuse me I rent a lot so
I'm going to read the comments okay
let's see what comments I want to maybe
we should get back to emac or emac this
coding I want
to uh let's see what's my emac blog this
you know this quite interesting uh
things
about okay if you like my stuff PayPal
me okay PayPal and patreon and Super
Chat me CH Ching you know I I watch
other people's video I'm I'm I'm this P
sub and I watch other you know people's
video when they do when they do a talk
show it's like the the chat nonstop fly
through and every few second CH Ching $5
CH Ching $20 and you I look at them you
know they say oh if you want you know uh
pay $5 or pay something you know if you
want me to answer your question I'm
going to read read your question so I
should do that too so if you want me to
answer your question pay you have to
pay okay that you know in general that
is my that is not my thing I you know
that's not
you know that that's uh that's a normal
that's actually a normal way to do
things that's most people do but I'm not
that kind of people I'm not you know I
just do whatever I want to do I'm not
focused on making
[Music]
money okay sorry I can't join you guys
today hey good morning Scott you have to
go I guess I have another conference SC
okay so lots of uh okay let me follow
let me finish the reading
the
uh reading the
comments
uh hi everyone this one probably a bit
out of topic what's your thought on the
wolf and physics project oh wolfan
physics project that's very interesting
I have by the way I I wanted I've been
wanting to do to read that
uh but I haven't had time
to yeah I I yeah so wolam you know wolam
turns out I he is the in computer
science okay among computer scientists
he is a guy I respect the most of all
computer scientists for example Donald
GTH I don't like Donal K his stuff much
at all I don't like you know I don't
like latch he created I don't I despise
literate programming I think it's a
useless idiotic literate
programming I don't like latek I you
know I I think latch is the worst
harmful you know I I there's a you
know just search for while lch s s on
you know search for I have article on
that you know and he's art of computer
programming uh well I guess that's a
fine book but it's you know it's not my
style and he uses you know Assembly
Language so I you know and anyway stepan
wolfan he is a guy and I respect the
most and also I find that the style of
thinking you know the thinking about
things the way people thinks I you know
I find him I share you know with him the
most about how we think about things
stepan wolam so he recently wrote you
know each one of his blog is tremendous
it's so much material uh you know just
you know just go to stepan wufan blog
and he so recently about few weeks ago
three weeks ago he wrote three articles
about
combinators and those articles are
extremely fascinating and also another
aspect I I I would like to say I share
with stepen
is that when he write he write in the
most clear no jargon nonsense way
possible so when you you when you read
his and each one of his stuff is article
is very long okay take you one hour even
just to skim
it uh but but no Jons you can understand
everything in detail okay but but why is
it long is because there are so many
it's very dense there are so many things
he talk
about uh uh
but there's an interesting phenomenon
that that you know his articles although
it's tremendous it's fantastic it's well
written well written and the
illustration it's like impossible you
know you you know today on the web you
have JavaScript Java you know Java D3
JavaScript library or the fancy Graphics
or scheme you know scheme list fans they
have fancy libraries all the processing
you know language for doing Graphics you
know all those comparison in comparison
they all those are you know Stephan
wam with Mathematica language you can in
one day you can create Graphics that
takes the other you know D3 you know 10
years to to write it's amazing and each
one of his Blog has so many you know
tens of those Graphics so so this is
about visualization you know
visualization is another kind of topic
you know is somewhat becomes a code but
anyway stepan wolam okay so so he wrote
three articles about combin combinators
and those that's uh that's one of the
that's one of the great topic in
theoretical computer science so I highly
recommended recommend you do you go go
read that okay now he recently about a
few months ago he started a physics
project I wanted to read it but but I
don't have time also I'm getting old so
I don't know much I don't know that much
you know I don't know much about physics
so for whatever time I have I want to
concentrate on mathematics you know and
proof proof
Theory so anyway he's yeah yeah so I
haven't read it you know I he's talking
about um I believe he's talking about
some model for cos for physical
cosmology that is the the fundamental
structure of the universe okay uh and
you know he's got his ideas you know
seven wfam he's a he's very um bombastic
you know he's very uh arrogant guy um
you know so a lot of mathematicians you
know the great greatest mathematicians
or computer scientists they don't like
him because of that but I don't think
it's a big deal okay it's I think in
fact I despise many of these you know
this these mathematicians
uh you know I have articles about
that you know about arrogance about
arrogance as a personality trait there
you know there's quite of quite some
interesting thing to say about that
because that's a issue we talked a lot
about too because for example in
programming Community many people uh
flamed lenus lenux to you know the guy
who created Linux you know he is
also he he's uh uh U not not arrogant
necessarily but he's you know abusive in
his language that's not the way to put
it he he's just um you know he just
swear a lot like me you know
these idiots you are idiots you don't
know
nothing you know I noticed YouTube
started to censor you know they they
started to be more tight you know before
you click on the dollar sign they
require you have they you have a they
have now a giant list one of the list
says in detail that says that that you
know your video does not swear much you
know it's all a lie because you
know YouTube you know the rap you know
the social justice people the left you
know politicians in USA they love the
black R rap you know for example the
Jack the Twitter
CEO Allan okay Allan listen the Jack CEO
they they you know all these people they
love the black rap but when when you
actually R uh watch the rap songs of the
black people it's swearing and
the most abusive language you know not
just swearing abusive to women uh and
violence gun violence every
every in every sentence the rap black
black rap songs okay but meanwhile all
these social justice people saying you
cannot swear but they they love they
love the black people rap
songs it's a h HP
HP you know hypocritic to such a extreme
degree you know on YouTube for example
all the rap songs with all the swearing
they all make money you know they are
not sensor they all make tons of money
but for average people you cannot swear
or you can I'll say some you know it's
amazing so that's the collapse
of collapse of am America collapse of
white
Nations oops today is supposed to be a
technical top you know talk only not not
politics I really violated that
okay so uh
okay this I guess we just talk where we
go and how long have I been talking so
let's
see uh 57 minutes oh my God we should
close now we should close down
now I have a question math I thought
about today that the same sign is symbol
is used for negative number and minus
this may just be Swedish idiocy but it
it seems very unintuitive there's a is
there a logic to
it Lucas asked that question I have the
I have a question about math I thought
about the today that the same sign is uh
useful negative number in minus yeah
they so that's a topic about math
notations okay there are there there is
a book you can go by that's that is a
history of math notations now on the
topic of math notations that's deep
that's that's a deep as you want to go
because because when you talk about math
notations it depending on how you dive
into it it it it can it certainly can be
related to
the to the foundation of mathematics the
foundation of logic okay because why
because logic okay or Pro systems proof
Theory today we use computer to do that
because humans cannot do you know we
formulas formalism formalism logicism
that's a philosophy of of math I'm not
you know I talked about that before I'm
not going to go into detail but anyway
in philosophy of math you have formalism
you have logicism you know their are
philosophy about uh math foundations and
math foundations as it progress over the
past 100 years you know more and more
you know we we we we first of all before
computers We Begin mathematicians begin
to use symbols instead of English words
so you want to use symbols to represent
things equations or formulas or
whatever why because words is too loose
you know symbols you know logical logic
symbols for example you have and or uh
not you know you know lots of symbols to
use symbols instead words but now with
computer
is is one level upgrade so you use
symbols but then you use computers to
use those symbols so it's like
programming right when when you write
programming it's all code but for math
if you are doing proofs you know autom
automated proof system it's all symbols
so symbol what so what are symbol
symbols are notations you know they are
so what's the relation between symbols
and notation well symbol is part of
notation you know not you know so so
there's a huge amount of things dive
into when you talk about math notation
for example your
question your question is specifically
about the minor sign uh you are saying
it's kind of you know you know it's used
to negate a sign of a number and it it
is also used to um uh for uh minus
operator so it's a it's
a you know it's a it's a operator or
it's also a uh
it's operat with a single oper you know
there are different ways to look at it
so it's it so it kinds of um it can go
deep into what do you mean by a number
so you so any number you can think of it
as a group inverse of you know any NE
negative number you can think of it from
a abstract algebra point of view you can
think of it as a as to represent a
element that is the inverse of of the
positive of of another element okay you
know group Theory inverse so in that
sense the negative
sign is not even operant it's a negative
sign plus the number that the whole
thing represent one single
thing a single element in group
Theory so that's one aspect to it you
know that's kind of one way to look at
it then so anyway so there are you know
lots of details to look
into okay so maybe I think that's it uh
that's about it today uh any more
questions
[Music]
so Luca says what is good starter key
for making sequence then old space yeah
you can do that or you can pick a a
function key F7 again it depends on your
keyboard and again it also depends on
how you know your habit you know like
how how frequent you
know and if you have a model mod then
then you can just use space you don't
even need o o but the disadvantage of
Modo mod is that you have to switch to
command uh mod first so they are you
know they are uh pros and cons you know
so that's a big question to look into so
I I wrote a lot about these issues so
you just you know you want to go to my
keyboard blog and read you know you can
read the whole thing about key
binding uh shortcut systems and by the
way shortcut systems is also very much
related to input
systems so what do you mean by math
input systems for example uh you know
you have so-called dead key or you know
or on the Mac you can press the option
key and some other key to create a
unical symbol
right
so so inputting math math symbols or if
you are you know if you need to type
Japanese or Chinese or Korean or or uh
yeah and then you need a you need a even
a entire input system so all these are
related so there's a lot to say about
that you know you might check out my U
blog
[Music]
why there are no good emac
clones uh
so question uh when softly keys will be
available on vs code if you pay me it'll
be available okay I would ask
um I ask for
$300
okay start your donation $300 so you
know or if you work in a corporate
company no don't need to be sad okay if
you work in a company you make a lot of
money you know you you Sil can you you
know some of you guys work at Google or
Facebook you you know $300 is penut to
you you know you you work for five hour
a day you got three you know you pay me
I'll create s flag Keys the official one
uh for vs code
[Music]
you know I've noticed there are people
doing that you know that's the nature of
Open Source you know they they look at
and a lot of people in emac they look at
soft like Keys you know and for one
reason or not they don't want to use my
they want to create their
own part of the reason is that uh part
of the reason people do that you know
especially emac people and and you guys
too because we we want to you know we
always have the um you know we we kind
of want to create our own you
know so a lot of people just you know
look at my key binding choices and they
they they use other framework they
create their own and also I've noticed
someone has supported to that editor you
know that editor from you know what's
the name famous for creating the Java uh
in Teddy type no not intell types you
know there's there's a Java you know
there's a company that created a bunch
of editors for PHP for python for Ruby
uh intell J I think it's intell intell j
for their Java editor anyways people has
ported s FL keys to that platform and I
think there's also one for vs code you
know if if you search you'll find it
how do I feel about it no I'm not too
happy I mean nothing you know that's
just the nature of Open
Source
because if I have money you know I
happen to be not you know someone in
poverty okay I'm doing much better now
but I was in I don't have money to eat
okay in a very dire
situation and I called and I
called yeah J brains yeah jet brains
there's a there's a version of s fly
keys for jet brains someone put it it I
think there's also for vs code someone P
it P it it I'm not sure how how good
they
are
um so I guess I'm happy you know so how
do I feel about that you know there's
nothing I can say you know on one hand
I'm happy you know someone that means
they appreciate my work right they they
like my work but other on the other
hand you know I'm here dying for lack of
food and other people just you
know uh you know do things out of my
work you know get you know take my work
and I get nothing for
it so that's the nature that's the
nature of Open Source that that is
why I you know there's many problems
with open source okay
so for most open source you know for a
lot people you know they work in a
company they usually you know they work
for Microsoft for Google for Facebook
you know proprietary company uh and they
you know they seeing the sones of Open
Source so they make a lot money they
have comfortable life you know they have
they have fancy cars they have a house
you know they have money you know then
then at night they write code they say
oh you need open source you know it's
all free
for them yeah maybe open source is good
they think you know they think they
think they are helping Humanity these
you know they live a
comfortable life they work for
proprietary company they they and they
rob all other programmers who do not
work for proprietary
company and I still know a lot of people
including I I guess many of you guys you
know they are you know they they are
open sour Fanatics I find that a major
problem
today so for them you know if you are
you know you are comfortable yeah open
source but but open source today means
that any
programmer they either work for Google
or Microsoft one of they become a huge
Empire you know they work either you
work for evil empire or or you have no
way to survive because everything you
write if it it's not open source nobody
will use it because all these
these rich tell other people
to not use it that's what happens okay
and if you criticize open source they
will distance from you like like me like
my emx blog for 20 years you know a lot
of people you know hate it you know say
like on Reddit every
time I'm not going to go into this
another rant about that but anyway these
are problems with open source
okay that's it for today so I've been
talking for one hour that's it that's it
for today 27 people okay buy my stuff
okay one
last one last
um yeah I've been talking for one hour
one hour and 10 minutes and I should
stop so we okay by my tutorials byy my
buy my stuff bye bye bye and buy my
JavaScript in depth okay bye
guys I don't know about Scola okay next
time bye