hello welcome to another episode of s
talk show today we're going to talk
about programming stuff wolam language
and uh Python and many other programming
issues I'm going to give you an update
of what I have been doing programming
wise if you are here say hi hello
sprinkle night and if you are not here
skip around play at 1.5 speed you are
watching SAR talk
show uh I'm a artb programmer okay I've
been programming since
1992 so recently I took a photo that is
there not dead yet this is Happy
2025 guys it's been a while so I think
this is the first video in 2025 okay
so again ask me questions hello Enoch
okay so if you have any questions post
it now I'll get to it uh otherwise I'm
going to talk about uh kind of randomish
programming related stuff so first of
all let me show you my
keyboards this is important this is
ultim I mean this is this is Ultimate
hacking keyboard okay there are two
parts the other part is over here H I
need to adjust my camera a little bit I
guess so that
okay ultimate hacking keyboard and the
white keyboard is glove 0 keyboard
that's my main keyboard
fantastic and uh the other thing I want
to show you is
this sve board okay uh SV l b o a r d so
this is
a uh fancy input device very expensive I
haven't got to it yet so I'm sorry you
know so I will be just talking about
this until one day I actually use it so
I'll show it in every one of my
video okay my alarm clock went off let
me get to answer that so glove 8
ultimate hacking keyboard and uh let's
turn it back and
and if you search for SAR keyboard block
you can see all my reviews about this
keyboard SAR keyboard blog just search
for it you'll find it SW board okay swab
board and uh lots of others uh and and
by the way so there's a keyboard news
this one can you see it
yes so this one is new this is nulia
from China one of those China Chapo and
uh so they modeled it based on the
Kensington uh Kensington slim blade very
well-known track
Boo and but they added two squore wheels
so this is fantastic because on the
kington slim blade blade hold on a
second
I have to turn off my alarm clock that
is my timer so basically every 1
hour reminds me to get up and
walk because otherwise I'm just going to
be sitting
here all day so back to the
nulia track board this is new so they
added two uh squ wheel so this is
fantastic because
otherwise
the the kington track ball so let me
show you okay so kington track
ball you can see all the all the classic
best track BS here now let's see can you
see
it uh yes you can kind of okay so this
slim blade they don't have a score wheel
the way you scroll is you rotate it like
Earth you know you rotate it over a
vertical
axis uh and uh one trick to do that is
that you just put your finger on the
side and you can swipe it that will
function as a squirr so it is not
actually it's kind of physical but the
sring capability is tied with
the uh with the pointer movement
you know they tied into one so that is
you know that's not the best so now this
people added
um let's see track b reviews go back to
track b reviews go back to keyboard
guide go back to S keyboard plug so they
this this newa they added a square wheel
so I think this is a fantastic device
but how ever last time I checked they
are out of um out of you know they don't
have any anymore so oh I don't have a
link I need to add a link so anyway you
can check on Amazon I think this will be
a great track
B okay so and this we talked about in my
last uh video live stream this is also
good this is kesis mwave okay and uh
then what Okay so that's about keyboard
so you know check out my keyboard blog
you search for it keyboard blog you'll
find
it okay post your questions okay I'll
get to it n people watching
fantastic uh and okay so let's
see sprink Cod nights says I've been
using both VOR and program vac and I'm
used to both however I'm not certain
which one I should should go with on my
regular staggered 60% keyboard sell me
on on this one okay that's a good
question and that's um uh kind of common
okay and I have a article on that just
search for keyboard
search uh search for vorac so you have
all articles about vorac and one of them
is programmer vorac versus the vorak so
you go there I tell you the difference
so the you know so first of all vak is a
keyboard layout so you can see they have
the vowels on the left hand side a o e u
and the most frequently used
consonant uh Conant on the right side
htns so on the home row so I'm using a
borak okay you can see I'm using right
now I'm using uh you can see on the
corner Microsoft
uh keyboard layout you know vorak layout
now there's a variation called
programmers vorak so what they do they
you know they made a few changes so the
first critical change is that change
they change the number row they
rearranged the number the number
Arrangement okay so instead of 1 2 3 4
they they change it then they also
changed the symbols position such as
parth Anis pound sign
ENT percentage sign they also change
that they position but not not not just
that also they swapped the shift row
okay so before on normal keyboard when
you want to press eight you just go up
and press eight but on this one if you
want to press the numbers you have to
shift eight so shift eight get you eight
if you don't press the shift then you
get the you get something else okay you
get the symbols okay so they swapped the
number row with their
symbols and this is
actually uh this on French layouts or
French based layout uh they they call it
what anyway on French layout that's true
on all French layout so if you want to
press numbers you have to press shift
otherwise you get symbols okay so is it
better and by and also they made uh they
made two key swaps of the of the
apostrophe and the semicolon they
swapped it okay so is it better or not
so I made a study I dived into detail
the essence of knowing whether it's
better or not is to know the key
frequency okay so for example here is a
standard keyboard layout then you can
see the number are arranged just
sequentially 1 2 3 4 5 you know which is
not efficient because the most
frequently used numbers is one and two
and zero by far like usually they go a
curve you know one two and zero is used
like 90% of all the rest of the number
combined so on a normal keyboard when
you want to press one to you know that's
your pink keys if you are normal typ you
know that's your pinkies and ring finger
and zero is the pinky that's not good so
this normal Arrangement is not
good okay so so so on the
vorak uh let's go back okay so on the
programmer vak you can see they arrange
them in a in a more much more efficient
number order okay so you see one is your
index finger and two is your your you
know index finger to and zero is is well
zero is a bit far but anyway it's better
okay so you got the number
Arrangement then you have the question
is it better to swap the number row with
the symbol row that again depends on the
frequency of use let's say if you work
for a bank every day you just type
numbers you know this account got 3,000
$942 and minus that you know you type
numbers all the time or if you are a
mathematician or scientist like me I do
scientific
programming so if you type numbers all
the time you don't want to press shift
all the time to deal with the numbers
okay but on the other hand for some
programmers not all but for some
programming languages you don't type
numbers all the time you type this
parenthesis square bracket get plus
minus brais all the time so if you are
this type of programmer for programmers
then you probably and you don't type
numbers much you don't you know you
don't do scientific programming vast
majority of programming are not
scientific programming you know we do
web programming we do Linux kernos Linux
drivers you you do web dev
JavaScript uh uh goand R whatever they
are usually not scientific
programming the industrial programming
so for that type of programming usually
you want this pound sign % dollar you
know
parenthesis so you don't have to press
shift so that's better however not
overring are like that so I have
actually a
detail uh so this
article keyboard layout is inverted
number row better is it better or not
depending on which you know do you use
numbers more frequently or the symbols
so it turns out so you can see here's a
chart of statistics of the symbols and
numbers usage so you can see in
programming languages the Paran are used
by far the most in all languages then
you got the star asterisk then dollar
sign then zero then pound sign you
know so that's the average industrial
code however if you are doing scientific
programming like x squ minus 2 uh plus
something Square you know if you do
numbers a lot then you want numbers or
you know if you are Financial Officer or
something or
accountant so is is the inverse number
row better or not that really depends on
what kind of text you type
okay uh so that's the second point the
so first point the number Arrangement
then you have the question about
inverted row number or symbols then you
got other questions such as um semicolon
versus
apostrophe why because on the programmer
forac for some reason this guy this is
this guy is a creator of the programmers
for act his name is RO R Roland kofman
okay when I wrote this article like 15
years ago he actually sent me a email
saying that uh I forgot what's a comment
but
anyway so he also swapped oddly the
semicolon and the apostrophe positions
why so apparently he belied
that's better but on this question you
see both of them if you use the
traditional type typ of uh method they
are both typed by Pinky Okay so now you
have the question is Pinky going up
better or pinky going down better on
that question the answer is kind
of in between okay there's no clear
answer whether the for the pinky okay
for the index finger usually going up is
better okay than going down it's much
more ergonomic if you go up but for the
pinky then it's not it's not so clear so
he made this swap you know that's kind
of kind of odd so you can see um this
article semicolon versus apostrophe
frequency in computer languages so the
first thing we need to know is their
relative frequency so there you have
it so in summary which is better so if
you code C C++ or Java then semicolon is
far more frequent but if you code python
Ruby or bash then apostrophe is far more
frequent if you code PHP Pearl
JavaScript then apostrophe is slightly
more frequent so it just depends on what
language you use then you know the
frequency then you know then depends on
your personal preference of whether
moving up is better for the pinky or
moving down then then you kind of make a
decision so overall all the things
considered is programmers vak
better I think it's really it's not
definitely better for sure okay it is
better if you use certain programming
language and you code in certain uh
field not scientific you know then it's
better otherwise it's not not better
than vorak so I don't use programmers
vorac I use the kind of the standard
vorac layout this one okay and the other
thing is programmers vac is not common
so if you want to use programmers vac
you have to like install their layout
and every time you switch a machine or
you got a new machine on the Mac or
Linux on Windows you have to install you
know it's not available on the system by
default meanwhile
the the standard the standard vorak is
available by
default okay so that answers that
question did I sell
it did I make a
sell uh do you have thoughts on PL p
track B yes some but I don't have the P
py track B therefore I my opinion is not
that good since I never actually tried
it but however I do have op well I have
some opinion because I've I've watched a
ton of videos on all these track bards
so let me show you what is the proy okay
go to track boo
reviews uh
okay track b reviews then there is
um py okay py that's do it
yourself there you go do it yourself
track B and uh and here is the classic
puy now puy they you know
so by
Design they modeled their track B by the
Microsoft soft trackball Explorer this
one very popular okay so this one this
is a lot of people say this is the best
track B uh this track B begin around
year 2000s like 25 years ago and they
stopped making it Microsoft stopped
making
it uh around 2008 or something I
forgot you know so a lot of people want
this uh so that that's how you that's
where you got the proy okay so uh let's
go
back so that's the poy they it's do it
yourself they also sell it so you can go
to their website so this is like this
picture is this picture is very old this
picture is like from py begin 19 uh 2019
okay about about 2019 so this picture is
from around 2019 when they just
began creating this so you go to their
website you can find the website link at
the bottom py. Co okay then you can buy
it you know you can buy it you can buy
the parts and do it yourself assemble it
or you can buy you know the
complete
preassembled it's a bit expensive like
over $100 so anyway this is their
original model proy then over the years
over the past six years they created um
they uh created Ploy
adapt and also Ploy mini so several uh
different track BS so among them I can
tell you one one I find very interesting
I would be very much interested to
try is this proy adapt okay so there's a
video I watched it you know I watched a
lot of this uh videos so this is so this
guy Tyler Ren now gives a very good
review about poy adapt he compare
Compares it to slim blade okay and he's
got several other videos on tracko you
can you can check out uh by this guy
okay by this guy Tyler
Rell so proy
adapt this one is the one I'm
interested uh I'm not too interested in
a classic because I don't like any track
bow so this one by the way this this is
nulia nulia n l EA I bought about six
months ago uh China Cheapo made in China
so reasonable fairly good uh cheap you
know $30 something $30 and you know so
I'm using it fair you know Fair good but
one thing I don't like I don't like the
track boards that where you use your
thumb to press the buttons the side
buttons okay can you see
it so you see the side buttons here so
when you have side buttons that means
you need to
exert
Force via your the muscle in your
fingers so as supposed to if they are
top down you don't have to exert Force
you can like put your finger like a nail
you hold you you just like almost like
uh VR gravity you know almost like a
like a pen you don't exert Force except
your the weight of your arm if you if
you put your fingers straight like that
so if you do a lot work on a computers
like me like almost more than eight
hours a day every single
day then then this becomes a issue you
know to most people it's minor you know
because they they only use computer half
an hour day or 1 hour a day even if they
work in a company because am I doing
good say hi is my if is my life stream
is still streaming or am I
dead
okay uh you
know say fantastic post okay so let's go
back to track B so
I have never tried
P but the thing the one thing I'm
interested would be this one p adapt I
believe is
$100 okay but right now I don't you know
I'm doing less and less of the keyboard
and track board
reviews uh
because
why because it doesn't make me money you
know I
mean so you know go to C website Kali
info so let's go back to keyboard
keyboard
blog uh so I have 1,000 articles about
keyboard track boards
Mouse pen devices you know I have
reviews or
here uh you spent trem I spent
tremendous time in the past like 15
years writing this and uh today by today
you know like 10 years ago some of the
ergonomic keyboard are novel you don't
see them much but today it's so common
you know for example here's another one
China
Cheo they are like $8 or even
$70 reliable mechanical
Keys you know for more Americans you
just buy it you don't spend like 10
hours to to see which one is better than
the other well except a few you know you
know these these are real fancy the one
I have right so so I do review on them
but today I I got so many keyboard so I
don't need to worry about um
them this my keyboard Obsession began
when I don't have money like zero like I
you know a keyboard is $30 I don't have
you know I only have $30 and for 10
years I need need to buy one so I need
to I I check which one is better then I
spend hours hours and I write notes you
know because I'm a nerd so I
am fastidious you know writing notes oh
but this one got that feature that one
you know I read all like us hundreds of
Amazon comments for each
keyboard so but I don't have money to
buy so you know so I keep doing this
like for 10 years kind of like that so
that's how I began this
project keyboard okay so 10 years ago
you know let me tell you I told I I
talked about this so many times before
so the
first uh as as for the ergonomic
keyboard the first one it really began
about 10 years ago so one of them it
began by truly ergonomic keyboard okay
Begin by this one in
2013 okay this is like commercially made
mass produced okay this is this this is
this is I would say the first or one of
the first that
began the evolution began the evolution
that
made this kind of fancy ergonomic
keyboards popular so this is one of them
the other one
is uh the the other one
is where is it okay so you need to go to
Ergo keyboard the other one is erod
Dos it also this one began as a do it
yourself okay and that made it became
hugely popular so then since since then
you
have you know you have like hundreds of
varieties do it yourself it came with a
time when 3D printers became very
popular so people started to design and
then you started to have have a track
with the keyboard This one is from Japan
of the Japanese St yourself Community
then you started to have these th
profile mechanical key switches which
also became very popular and which is
better okay in my opinion the theme
profile mechanical switch is better than
the
traditional uh
mechanical switch such as the Cherry
MX okay so I've done like over 100
videos about keyboards in the past three
years so um and I'm not doing too much
keyboards today because it kind
of you know it's it's no longer
a uh novel topic because you have all
these cheap ones on Amazon mechanical
keyboard became so cheap cheap $40 $30
on Amazon and tons of
choices uh for example let me show you a
few uh normal ones for
example for example this fancy you know
RGB light socalled RGB light and with
you know there's a novelty here this one
got a score bar at the bottom that allow
that that is actually for changing
volume wheel now it would be interesting
if it can control other things like
function is a s wheel but I forgot
whether it's programmable oh
programmable okay so anyway so my point
is you got so many keyboards
today and uh so I don't blog about
keyboard that much uh instead I blog
about programming a lot like like like
programming that is real important topic
okay like make America great again you
go into Sciences engineering study math
physics programming then we're going to
have Rockets okay if you're going to
just talk about politics and stuff and
and
memes America is not going to be great
again so you want to work on mathematics
programming which I you know and and
that is actual science there endless um
things uh ways to go as for keyboards
there are still
um interesting things such as such as I
talked about this
um you know this this uh swoard input
device but it takes some time to learn
so let I showed before you can watch my
video so you see each one of these key
is magnetic so you have four
ws and you can also push down magnetic
so it's superb okay I'm going to get
back to this so I'm going to review and
also for the thumb you got one two three
and four and five and six six is when
you hold it down I mean press real hard
so you got to click you can press it
down that's one key press it down oh
press it down and and push it down so
that's another so you see so this is
this this this is a real novelty so I'm
going to get back to show you know to
gon to try to use this okay so but you
just have to
wait meanwhile you guys donate donate oh
speaking of money CH Ching who is that
Hank thank you Hank Hank is
great uh I don't like the term cyber
deck nor do I I will go with home brew
instead
oh home brew
uh okay so I guess you talking about do
it yourself related stuff okay so
anything else I guess we just talked
about keyboard then I was going to talk
about some programming so let's
see next
question so the the question do you have
thoughts on PL tracko yeah so that's my
thoughts
um yeah if they send me one to review
and let me keep
it I would be happy I'll be actually
using a daily so maybe I should send
them a email yeah but I got so busy by
the way few days ago I got an email from
Razer okay from Razer they ask me do you
want to
collaborate so usually that mean means
you know I do videos for them you know
you know reviews for them and
they I'm not sure they going to pay you
or not they may but they'll give me the
things you
know yeah but
uh yeah but you know doing video do
doing this keyboard reviews is is not
really sign significant for me because I
want want to do math okay that's more
important Juan says how can I game with
it you mean with a CL uh track
ball uh that depends some people game
with it but not
many now sprinkle KN says if a person
wants to see a review of a keyboard you
should send it to Kar
directly yeah well now I'm picky not
noral keyboard you know even if you give
it to me I wouldn't have time to um to
spend time to play like this you
know I can do a review one shot but I'm
not going to use it you
know so
anyway yeah razor you know because I
have on my
website uh bad mousing razor you know so
here's article you know you got all
these keyboards you know these are
normal keyboards okay I mean the normal
form
factor and you go you go down you go oh
there's razor never buy
razor so but now I'm going to be become
a partner I don't know maybe I should
take their offer I I don't
know uh
because why do I not like razor because
they you know they they they create this
Cloud thing like normally a programmable
keyboard like gaming keyboard you can
program the keys to do what you want
right and normally there's a b memory
chip on the keyboard so you can unplug
it take it to your friend's house or
plug into a new computer and your marro
keys are there but with the razor you
you know they're going to move it to the
cloud so you need to install the razor
program they have a fancy name like
razor something like bloody or gun you
know the for the gamer idiots you know
so like you you need to this you need
have to have this RoR program running
and then you need to create a razor
account on their website then you can
you know Pro you know program your
keyboard if you bring the keyboard to a
friend's house it doesn't work you know
you have to install the razor and and
log in your account it's not
good but for the gamers you know get
most of the gamers the gamer idiots they
don't know nothing that's why they made
you know that that's why they made this
gaming industry popular like that they
they don't know nothing they idiots they
light oh yeah I like light colorful you
know
RGB and every
gaming every gaming software like
normally a software you have standard
user interface for example on Windows
you know every window you got this you
know on the right corner you got this
course uh to close the window and things
like that you know standard user
interface but every time you run a game
or or turn on Logitech or raise a you
know they keyboard config software it's
like a bunch of crap like you don't know
which one is butt or not everyone is
different you know you have to try to
click it to see if it's a it's a button
or not because the gamers you know the
these gamer idiots you know they they
want you know fancy oh Hightech it looks
beautiful you know and the text is so
tiny like on Windows one of the standard
user interface is you press control hold
down control then you scroll then you
magnify then you okay scroll down you
zoom out zoom in and zoom out okay on
gaming so software that doesn't work you
know like you you can't the text so
small you
can't magnify
it idiotic
extreme but but but the the gaming The
Gamers the gaming industry made the
mechanical keyboard popular you know
that's the thing
what if you had a
microcontroller always attached that
pretends to be a
website yeah that might work
um yeah anything else let's see what how
long have I been talking 42 minutes
maybe I should shut down okay because we
talked for 40 minutes about keyboard and
track boards any anything anything about
keyboard track Wars questions you ask me
you can ask
me then tomorrow then I'm going to start
to do my live stream again tomorrow and
then it's going to be wolm language
Mathematica or emac you know so let me
separate programming topics into
programming that would be better you
know when I talk about keyboard which is
more common topic more
popular uh a lot of people watch but
when you talk about programming it
became more esoteric this people
watch that's a phenomenon okay anything
else sprinkle says removing on board
memory is the worst Logitech is slightly
better
yes yes yeah Logitech that's why I still
I support Logitech you know
they yeah anything else okay I'm
thinking of closing yeah I'm going to
shut down
uh meanwhile let me tell
you uh so on my Twitter if you have not
followed you might want to follow me and
I'm starting to do a little live stream
on Twitter you know I'm experimenting
so because Google is not good YouTube is
not good so I'm I've been starting to do
some little um kind of voice recording
podcast or a little broadcast 5 minutes
you know for example this
one hello
hello I think you seen it but anyway so
um so this video is talking about
personality disorders so I give you a
overview of what is schizoid personality
and histrionic personality and
borderline personality and
schizotypal personality very
interesting uh and there's also
schizophren frenia which is not a
personality disorder but it's a rather
up brain so anyway you can follow
me on Twitter and check
out uh what's going on with my live
stream and for political topics you know
I'm going to started to do more in more
uh Twitter live
stream uh but not maybe not for
programming for programming topic maybe
still YouTube okay like I said before
that's probably um how things will go
anything else hi hi J
Jolly uh let's see what is the best
keyboard to play pubg mobile now I don't
know what is pubg mobile
okay I'm not a gamer so I don't know
what are the Jons pubg
mobile bug CBU I don't know what is
that okay anything else so you guys go
to donate me okay go to kali.
info and go to the
bottom donate me 50 bucks
okay
PayPal if you work at Google or a
programmer you know send me 300 bucks
just send me one shot every every year
or so okay PayPal or buy me a Amazon
gift card so click you need to go to my
website s. info scroll to the bottom and
click on this link because
otherwise Amazon Japan Amazon Germany
other Amazon cannot get money even you
paid it you sent it to me but I I can't
get it so Amazon ate
it okay so send me some gift
card
support you know things you like pay is
is a
thing only interested in computers why
not uh why don't you live stream on be
be well that's a Chinese website and you
know that means I create a new
account
uh that would be good if I talk in
Chinese only
so yeah so BBD is a China video platform
okay it would be good if I do my Chinese
uh talk show there but I don't have time
I you know I got a lot math to do and uh
lots of
math and there's a rumble there's also
Rumble I'm thinking of going on to uh
you know so every time you switch or you
know takes a lot of time to go
into Chinese tutorial series when you
guys pay me you know like a lot people
ask me about things oh you should do
that oh can you write a tutorial for
rust yeah the people ask but no money
you know they actually actually if I
actually do it nobody watch it neither
you know they just you know at the
moment it feels like you know can you do
it can you write the r tutorial but if I
actually or you know go to BB if I
actually seriously start to do it nobody
actually nobody
cares on people will say can you can you
do this something else you know it's
just the way you know the common you
know the the the way things
are so you appreciate what you already
have you never know how important things
are when you miss it not me though but I
mean for example your legs
your you know your your brain your legs
your body or whatever like what you have
right
now okay I think that's
it yeah let me shut down anything else
let's
see
uh hi
hi okay bye
guys close poy close Amazon gift card
close so let me just put the links I
talked about to my talk show
page
uh so that's track board we talked about
and we talked about vorac keyboard
layout okay then we talk about semicolon
versus uh inverted number row we talk
about efficiency layout for numbers we
talk about programmers for okay copy P
Link
Link close slim blade track SL slim
blade track
ball okay by the way there's one thing
about proy is that showing browser one
thing or we close it slam blade so let's
go back to track B um
track ball you want to go to
py one thing important about track ball
is the mechanism how the ball rolls so
one of the good one is by a roller um
hold on a second let me find the bluey
oh do it
yourself okay so paste it there so one
of the important thing is the rer
mechanism you can see it here okay so
this is the best picture you see this is
one of the most important thing about a
track B is the mechanism of how they
Rose so this guy studied you know he's
doing it you know creating track boo
design so he studied the different type
of uh roller mechanism what's what's the
technical
name uh those are called uh
anyone know I forgot that moment those
are called bearings okay so so for most
track BS they don't have actually moving
bearings like that what they have is
just
um just rubber okay so let me show
you and see my multi
Mouse so if I pop this B out
yeah wait let's turn it
off so there's a
button turn this off
now press to Pop the ball out so you can
see they get dirty hold on a
second so you can see three dots there
you know those are just plastic so
there's dust let me drop it
off so anyway so you can
see yeah so that's one dot that's that's
a lead okay that's a optical uh
Optical so these three dots they are
just
rubber so they don't move okay so
but you know but for some track boards
so let me tell turn it back on turn it
back
on so for for many track BS including py
they have this roller ball bearings so
what this do is that with ball bearings
you can like push it and you'll roll for
like five or 5 second or more you know
so that is a very good thing to
have but usually with B barians it's
more loud louder anyway bye
guys sorry for bothering you I want to
buy your e this tutorial but you are in
China uh is there any other payment
besides PayPal or Amazon no not really
yeah some people ask
me uh
yeah you know I've been thinking of
creating a Chinese you know some kind of
Chinese money account but
it's but it's more trouble than worth
because not many people buy my stuff but
every time people pay it I have to like
prepare it and email it and
write
so I can send you a copy okay you let me
tell you what to do go on to
Discord okay Kar Discord you can find
the link the invitation link on my
homepage kali. info so join Kali Discord
say hi then I'll send you a copy okay
stand stand up I I'll just send you a a
zip copy zip the zip file okay bye guys