one I'm going to do a Emacs demo in this
video and in this video I'm going to
update my blog my Emacs blog I did want
yesterday today two days ago that is
similar but today I'm I'm hoping to show
you something new I hope so
this this is not planned so while I'm
walking through it I'm you know I might
I probably will come up with something
I'm doing and some ideas and okay I can
show you so this is this is my Emacs
command my Emacs blog you see there are
many pages like right now one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
it's like 30 pages is too long so I need
to break it up put the February February
to a archive so but before we do that
there's an idea there's another idea
that there is a Emacs package that will
show you what command I'm coding so
let's try to install that
so these packages I believe the command
name is MWe something om e WM e W so
let's see let's search for key okay it's
not there I wrote about it before so
let's let's try to find it on my Emacs
blog on my Emacs website so Emacs keys
how to key tips pinky
such notations
I don't see it here but okay let's go to
search then Emacs log keys something
like that
and w/e I'm sure I wrote it too full
so how does that Keys minor Keys major
major Marquis minor Keys priority define
key sequence menu super hyper key
transition okay it's probably Emacs
practical Emacs miscellaneous don't I
manage windows what's the difference
repeat command no it's in keys so I
don't know let's go to the directory MWe
Amy W not no not me so key now that's
too many
sake board okay it's keyboard knock he
max he's fakie there it is
so wait where is this file so let's
that's the directory and this is the
file name show key and command okay sure
key and command so that's that one copy
the path it's open it so the package
name is MWe log command it's a weird
name I remember there's the new a
package that kind of replaces this one
so well right now so there's another
task coming up I want to find out where
is this this file linked so let's do
that
as such that's using my package to such
one of my package because I find so
Emacs Keys miscellaneous index so indeed
it's there
okay so over the years I have so many
Emacs articles it's a problem to
organize them so so this article is
something that not general so I guess I
don't have a link to it from my main
index pages but let's try to install it
install and MWe
and really okay so it's not even in mail
path that's it's probably outdated
excuse me okay so the name has changed
so this one is last updated 2017 github
so it's made by now the new one is made
by a Chinese guy I think it is Frankie
it's a github
command log mod okay
Michael Weber was so what happened -
what happened to this guy
so last last update is 2004 oh that's
pretty old so anyway let's try this one
day in command log mod and it's such
command log mod let's install it switch
panel tap install
yes okay it's installed okay now we need
to figure out how to set it up
that's always a pain because then you
have to read stuff and something may not
work so here's quick okay there's no
quick intro I hate that you know many of
these packages this like I just want to
know how do I start to run it like what
minimal setup I have to do or what is a
command to turn it on so it doesn't show
any of that okay so maybe it's command
log mod so it's just to that command mod
command log mod enabled in current
buffer okay but I don't want the current
buffer I want global so you see it
doesn't show anywhere so now I go to oh
my god I have to list my buffers
basically right now usually I would just
list all above us and see which buffer
this output might be because usually
it's output into a buffer
okay let's try switch buffer
okay there's no
how is it different okay make mine a
mobile minam on now okay well there's no
documentation so let's go to let's read
the source file source code
it's the help to everything so 300 lines
that's okay made a mistake 300 lines
that's not much much to the 2003 Nick
Faria updated by
yeah whoops the weights output I just
want to know the output it's trying
again enabled in current of yeah but
where is the heck new buffer neighboring
current buffer but show me log so as
least
all lines containing buffer that's
probably too much oh this one I guess to
see the log call Amex open aquifer open
command block buffer yeah that's stupid
now this is no good because you know
it's trying to what is is so this this
is actually a split pane so okay the
buffer name is command log you can see
it here okay so let's get a new one
cross this buffer switch to command dog
okay this is another bad thing because
you see it does not show when you switch
buffer since we have the this buffer you
know exist command log but when you try
to switch it it does not show here
compile oh yeah so this is really stupid
because you know what what it's trying
to do is basically you know is trying to
show you a split split pain you know on
the side and he's trying to hide it I
mean the idea is that is that you know
you're just gonna go into sure there so
the problem is that no it's not general
you cannot switch it switch to it you
cannot place it anywhere you want so
it's no good but anyway so we have so
close this buffer close so okay we are
already times up so let's just to the
Emacs stuff Emacs blog
so I go to the bottom of the panel open
the panel and copy that paste I know I
want to do one for February so copy HTML
move it to top and open it so section
you see so this is a new file it's empty
so close it close it save now I just
grab my blog February to there
save open last saved hope and I saved
pasted showing browser there it is
so and okay and there's one more thing I
need to do open the January copy that
I need to update the title you see I
want to show you know the full title so
close I close that and that's and
basically that's it
so we come back to Emacs blog and go all
the way down its February 2008 2018
February no i refresh and browser you
see it's March and February is here so
okay so that's that's good um and see
what else
oh so you see this sucks this this this
package sucks donkey ass you see because
you'd when you enable it it only enables
for the current buffer but I want to
enable it for global you well typically
you know you want to enable it globally
I mean what's the point of just current
buffer so you know what happened is that
all the command I did you don't see here
because I forgot to turn it on so
another method to see what command you
have been calling no typed is is this
and it's close it because it so the
command name is view loss is this tube
stupid name but but I have the key on
delete hol and I'm using a variety board
so that's actually the Barack H help and
I'm using a Kinesis advantage to keep
so the Delete key this is actually the
key on my left stump that's for delete
key
so anyway call that command and expand
window you can see all the command I was
using see Sonic's window that's just W
and that lets me to either switch pants
or if there's no pains switch the window
of the frame previous line next time so
anyway ok I think let's wrap it up for
this one I haven't updated my Emacs yeah
well I mean I mean to sync to the server
so once it's synced to the server you
can see it on my blog I'll go Emacs
yes sir too big ok that's no more see
February is there now it so I maintain
in my Emacs blog or manually that's
Richard Stallman he's still looking good
he's 65 yes he's 65 now so my Emacs bug
it's all it was all manually done and
everything is manually typed there so
this page is still pretty long usually I
keep I used to keep it only for 15
screens but you know how technology
advances so these days is doesn't matter
unless I have lots of images but anyway
so go back here down so March March is
like two months ago
ok that's that's ok
so usually what I do is February now
it's up there usually like kind of scan
through this page actually and when
whenever there's a long article for
example this one
Emacs scribe no grab problems okay
that's not significant I mean usually
you want to when there's a significant
article opinion I mean this one is just
a little little rant it's not
significant but but whenever if I wrote
something some opinion I think that's
worth saving I create a new file for it
and and create a link you know like
these you know so it's small permanent
because few people you know read all
these old archives does go back so go
back here so what what else you know I'm
trying to find something else to do okay
so anyway so this command this command
log mod it's problematic you know needs
to you see a global let's say
global command okay there it is
okay I'm stupid oh that's good okay girl
welcome everyone
now Michael Weber now who is that guy um
[Music]
what so what else did he do I think
there's something but I can't remember
right now so how long we have okay so
this video is 15 minutes let's stop it
now