Hello guys. Hello guys. Good morning.
Welcome to another episode of S talk
show. We are going to code JavaScript.
Today so JavaScript we are going to do
tool two tips. So let me show you. So
you see creating a tool tip. Uh I'm
going to live code it. So move the mouse
here. Hover over me. Then you see a tool
tip. Okay. Show today's talk show. If
you are here say hi. If you are not
here, play at 1.5 speed because I
ramble. Okay, so we're going to code.
I'm working on my website. So this is
uni code. You got all sort of unic code
entire collection annotated. So you can
see each unic code name and uh you know
name and character uh unic code uh ID
called code point and so on. So th those
are done as a tool tip or also known as
a balloon bubble. Okay. So that's what
we going to work on. So okay let's
begin. Are we here? So say hi. Hello.
Hello. Hello rice wine. We had a great
chat yesterday on s discord. Ah time
out. Uh you know this this uh cloud fair
is a nasty organization.
So okay so let's focus on two tips
JavaScript coding. Okay. So first of all
I'm going to show you how to do it. Uh
it's very easy. So here is the entire
code with the HTML and the JavaScript.
So you can copy it and uh then you have
it. So just search for JavaScript DOM
create tool tip
on.info. Okay. That's like uh that's
like all you need to know. Uh but we're
going to go over so so what are the
technology involved in order to do this?
You know here's the code. So what is so
first of all so the principle is that
you going to use CSS cascading
stylesheet. You are going to create a
um an element
HTML. So you you you are you you have a
HTML ML element then you use C. So
actually I have a summary here. So use
JavaScript to
create HTML element. This will be your
tool tip box. Okay. Then use the uh
cascading
stylesheet CSS to make visibility hidden
so you don't see it.
So then the next step is set the two tip
box on its own layer. So using CSS
position fixed so that so that when you
make this element visible it doesn't
interfere with the your current layout.
So it'll be like a separate layout.
Okay. So that's using
CSS by the way. So all the
CSS how to is here. So this is uh how to
use CSS to make it fixed on its own
layer. You see that's what tool tip is.
Um and uh then how to make a element
invisible that's just that okay
visibility
hidden okay then so you create a element
by default make it hidden using CSS then
assign function handler to the mouse
hoover and mouse out event for element
that you want to tip to appear so that's
using JavaScript so using a JavaScript
you can set the element such that when
the mouse is hovering over that element
the browser will fire
uh fire an event saying that the mouse
is over that element. Okay. So you
create that um so that code is
um you see here document get element by
id the tool tip which is the id for that
element then add event listener. So
whenever that event happens when mouse
is hovering over that element
then so then the click is uh named
click. So when people click it then you
just call a function. So whatever
function you write. So finally you just
have to write a function to activate the
tool tip. So how do you activate it?
Basically you just change the CSS
visibility to
visible. Uh okay. And that's that's it.
That's the essence of how to creating
the tool tip using different
technologies. CSS, HTML to create
element, CSS to hide the element, then
JavaScript to make a event. So when the
mouse hovers, the event fires, then set
that event to your function, the
function will change CSS from visible to
invisible from invisible to visible. So
that's how two tip works. Okay, so you
can see so okay that's the basics of two
tip. But what I need to do you see I
have this unic code page you know all
sort of unic code entire
set
and you know so used to be when mouse
hoover that tool tip is right under the
mouse
but over the years I kind of changed
back and forth. So because when you have
a small screen phone like
that and when the tool tip is right
under the mouse it kind of blocks the
half of the page of the phone. So I
decided to make it just on the side. So
the tool tip always show on the
side. But that is got a problem because
if your screen is wide you know like on
desktop then every time you move the
mouse you have to look at the corner
like like you know look at corner. So
we're going to change that so that the
tool tip will be right under the mouse.
It's a bit tedious because because what
happens for example if you if your mouse
is on this flower emoji that's near the
bottom. So the tool tip will show below
it but you can't see after it because
that's hidden. So So what you need to do
then is you need to find the mouse
position and check if it's it's near you
know it's close to the bottom or to the
side to the right or the left or the top
you know depending on your two tip
position. Like if this is a point, your
tooth tip can be upper right, lower
right, lower left or upper left, you
know. So you want to detect when your
mouse is near the windows uh view port
border. If that's the case, then change
your to tip. Normally it's below, you
make it above. So things like that. So
it's a bit tedious. That's why I I
changed it to always just show it on the
corner so it's e easier to code that way
and it's predict predictable. Okay. So
lots of emojis. Fantastic. Okay. So
let's see if we can you know actually so
let's see if we want to fix that.
Uh maybe not because every time you
decided one thing then when you actually
change it then you decided oh you know
that's the reason I don't want it that
way because it's a tedious code. Okay.
So anyway, so today's talk show, let's
go to uh Unicode stars. Search
for There it is. Open it. Show in
browser. There it is. So let's see the
code.js. So this is a unic code popup.
That's the source code. Okay. So you go
to a directory. In fact, it's a
TypeScript code. So I got the
TypeScript. Open that. This is
Typescript. Then it compiles to this
JavaScript. So for example, let's delete
this JavaScript. Delete it. It's gone.
You see? Now it's gone. Now close this
page. Now this is TypeScript. Now you go
back to the browser. Refresh. The tool
tip doesn't work anymore. See, because
the JavaScript code is gone. Close that.
You see this? This code is gone. So now
you open that. you open the TypeScript.
Let's compile it. So the pink window
shows all my Emacs command course and
the keystrokes command course on the
right, keystroke on the left. In any
command you can search the web uh more
than half of the time you'll find my
source code on.info. So you can copy it
and use it. For example, I move cruiser
forward one block or backward one block.
So you can see those are the command
names.
beginning end of line or block 10 times
beginning of line or block four times.
So, so okay. So, command name on the
right, keystroke on the left. I'm using
a Vora keyboard layout and I'm using
SFly keys, the most efficient key
binding system for Emacs, more efficient
than Vim. And here is the website for it
and that's available on GitHub free of
charge. And there's a video you can
watch introduction. Softly key is more
efficient than Vim. Meaning that if you
measure the key stroke for doing
something uh for a month or for a year,
it's going to be less than if you are
using Vim or Neo Vim or whatever more
efficient than Vim. Okay. So anyway, go
to Sunfly Keys, copy the file path,
close the source code, close that, close
that, close that. Uh unic code star show
in browser close it
showly keys make a link and the show in
today's talk show there okay now go back
to unic code stars unic code stars open
JavaScript file open it it's empty
that's right now go to TypeScript
where's the TypeScript here open it now
press the button now watch the pink
window okay now uh wait press this
button it says Running
Typescript compile successfully. Show
messages buffer. You see? So now you go
to the directory. You see there is the
now refresh. You see unic code
popup.js freshly compiled out of the
oven hot. Now go back to the browser.
Click on stars. Now you can see the
popup. The two tips works again. Now by
the way this thing this user interface
called two tip on Windows for example
you can you
know like they they used to pop up on
Windows you know that's what you see you
see this pop up this little box on
Windows that's they call it tool tip but
on the Mac it's known as balloons okay
so balloons is actually a better name
you know text you know balloon it was
called balloon everyone since like
1990s. But anyway, window is far more
popular. So, two tips becomes the more
well-known name. Okay. So, let's go
let's look at the code. So, we got the
JavaScript code. Close. Close. Uh, now
here's the TypeScript code. Let's look
at the TypeScript code. Go to the
bottom. So, it's only 200 lines of code.
Can you see
it?
Yeah. 200 lines of code. So we want to
so you can see array unic code font
change 23 array from uh what is unic
code font change search unic code font
change
27 variable is document query select all
so all input element with unic code font
change and that's not what we want
that's that is actually this box so you
see we got multi-function in this one
file. So that box is for show unic code
name. You see? So let's go to smileys.
Okay. Now you click show unic code name.
So this allows you to easily have in one
glance all the unic code emojis names.
So for example that one is smiling face
with sunglasses. This one is smiling
face with halo. So then you can use
browser search hello. Then you can see
uh you know you can use browser search
to find the characters you need. But if
you actually need to find a character
just go to unic code search. So you can
search by name and other ways. So anyway
back to the emoji page. So you can see
so what is this unic code font change.
So that's getting all uni code. Um well
that's actually so that is about you
know show names show names don't show
names and show them as symbols or show
them as emoji that will have an effect
if you are on on page like this for
example show them as emoji you see that
some of them became emoji show them as
symbols
uh let's try a different page let's say
stars
Show them as emoji, show them as symbols
because there's a complexity with Unico
because certain
characters, certain characters, certain
subset of Unico characters, they have
dual raw. So they can be shown as emoji,
they can also be shown as plain text. So
for example this star of David
uh you click show a symbol you see now
they become
symbol. So this happened about 10 years
ago they they they they basically they
added the emoji they kind of merged the
emoji purpose with the text purpose. So
that's a very bad change. Okay. Anyway
that's another topic. So that's why you
have this show us emoji or show us
symbol especially you know it's very
annoying it's a very bad um thing uh
that happened to unic code for example
this page um this is uh circle numbers
let's go to
the circle yeah okay circle numbers then
you got circle alphabet okay I oh I
forgot actually um yeah this okay so you
go down. You go down. Circle letters.
Circle letters. You see now if you click
on show us emoji, you see some of them
become emoji. That M circled M. Why is
that? Because because in
France that circled M stand for metro
which means subway in USA.
So you know Unico is supposed to contain
all characters of the world all
iconograph or icons or he he hero life
of Egyptians everything you know so
that's why they have these characters
circled M for metro in France or or such
but then they started to merge with text
so whenever you have text now it becomes
circle if you want it to be text then
you have to add a invisible character
after that very extremely
uh nasty um thing that happened to
Unicode. So if you want to know the
details about that the issue we we we
are just talking about look at this
uh look at this article. Okay. uh
difference between emoji emoticon
pictograph emoji versus text this
article you see so I was using unic code
I'm a fan of unic code because I'm a fan
of human writing system symbology all
the symbols so I was writing about
keyboard okay fantastic you got this
symb now you have unicode symbols to
represent some of these multimedia keys
in keyboard okay so I wrote
Then after a few years the page becomes
like that the [ __ ] speakers you know
some
like the keyboard symbols become like
funky
cartoons okay that's so that's very bad
h happen happening and then when you are
I'm writing mathematics because I love
mathematics so you have these arrow
symbols you know uh left to right arrow
and double left to right arrow
Then one day it becomes emoji
incompatible with the other arrows. You
see not all arrows become that. Not all
this kind of um gly or pictograph or
emoticon or
uh
um there's another word for it um icons
and or
um golife and
uh symbols. Anyway, there's another word
I forgot at the moment, but anyway, so
not all of them become emoji like just
some of them like extremely
idiotic. So for so when you are writing
mathematics, some of your arrows become
emoji, some of them not. So this is
extremely bad. Okay. So then the next
step you want to know is that how do you
know if a unicode characters is has this
dual
rule you don't know well there is a
documentation for that for example this
page I'm documenting it so just search
for unic code emoji versus text and it
turns out if you want to know if a
character has this dual rule then you
have to like there uh you know then then
you have to so here's is a list of all
characters that has only
um that has both emoji and text
representation but they default to
emoji. Okay, so you got this set of
characters. Then another set of
characters they can be both emoji and
text. However, they default to text. So
you got these characters. So you can you
can see now if you if I click on this
uh show
symbols you see all these become symbol
show emoji
uh you see so let's see show symbols you
see these characters can be both emoji
and s or or symbol but they by
default according to the spec they
should show as text. Okay, then another
set of characters. These are emoji only.
There's no way to make them, you know,
they don't they never show us text. For
example, let's try again symbol. You see
none of them then. Uh yeah. So, but then
another complexity is that browsers do
does not respect this default to
whatever you see. For
example,
um yeah, browser does doesn't respect
it. For example, uh for example, let's
go to this box. Can be emoji or text.
Default to text. But now, if you copy
this and paste in Twitter, they all
become emoji. Let's try it. New post.
Paste these
characters. Live stream. Okay. So post
it
now. You see they all become
emoji. [ __ ] disre respect the unic
code standard. By the unic code standard
these
characters is supposed to be default to
text not emoji. You see? So you are
[ __ ] in either way. You you follow the
standard doesn't work. You don't follow
the standard doesn't work. He got [ __ ]
in all ways. Okay. So this page
documents that this this problem problem
of the techn [ __ ]
created. That's us. That's us my
friends. Let's show something wrong. Try
reloading. What the [ __ ] Okay. So emoji
versus text. That's that's about this
topic. Now copy the URL. Close it. Uh
what is this? Type script. Yeah, we
digressed. Okay, but we'll go back. Uh
unic code stars. Close. Show today's
talk show. Go down. U keys. Paste a
link. Linkify make a list show in
browser page down. There it is. The
emoji versus text problem of the uni
code.
This happened around
2018. Okay,
2018. Okay, so we digress. Let's go back
to the topic. So, we were going to code
the two tips, right? Two tips. These
stars, we want to move these two tips
right under the mouse. Okay, let's try
that again. Now, go to go to Unicode
stars page. Open it. Open the
typescript warning typescript exist.
Yeah, we opened it. Okay. So you
see this is JS. When I press enter,
it'll open the file. But if there's a
tscript that already exist, it'll open
the typescript instead and we'll tell
you a warning. So that command if you
look at the pink window that would be
kasa html open local link that is part
of kasar html
mod there is a source code and uh that's
about that's about
10,000 10,000 lines of code s html mod
get it pay me. Okay. Pay me to get it.
Uh so we Okay. So we uh we let's let's
start to um let's start to code this uh
for real now. Okay. So typescript. So
this part uh the bottom part is about
you see this you know about 20 lines of
code that's
about this show us text and show us
emoji. So let's go here. Close that.
Show us symbols. Show us emoji. Show us
symbols. Show us emoji. Show all names.
Hide all names. Okay, that's that's
that's this part. But the the part I
want to fix is
uh what
Okay, let's just get to fix it. Let's
not digress. How are you guys
doing,
Sam? Uh, okay. So, let's see.
So that's a function to pop off to
remove the balloon and uh then add event
listeners key down key if it's escape.
Yeah. So you can also use escape key. So
you see so that's a mobile phone. Let's
press escape.
Fantastic. Okay. So but we want to
change Yeah. We want to um Yeah. Here.
Okay. There is a function function pop
up on that means show the balloon.
Okay.
Now, okay. Show the balloon. Let me go
you over. So, event target then title uh
get char info. Yeah. When you show the
emoji, you need to know what emoji it
is. the emojis, the unic code characters
name and the unic code characters code
point. So that's why you got this title
um uh data character info title.
Okay, then you have to kind of clear the
cache and that's why uh so so then xchar
first child not value xchar xar name. So
that's getting the unic code point. So
for example, this one is 1
f45. Okay, let's go back to smiley. So
this one is 1
F603. Okay, so God kind of. So then here
is the char name
charit slice title last index of okay
that's get then what is this part? This
this part okay this part is
where yeah this is this part is where
the about the position of the balloon.
Okay so you see visibility make it
visible. So when your mouse hover over
it makes it visible but but before that
you need to set up the position of the
balloon. Okay get bounding client
rectangle. Okay
it's complicated. Don't
[ __ ] viewport width, view port
height. Okay, so you got a bounding box.
Okay, make it visible.
Then yeah, so
actually let's uncomment it. Yeah,
that'll probably just work because I
it's so tedious to figure this out.
So
style.lft. So we add a CSS style to make
it align to the left. And how much we
align
uh complicated for so view port width
minus position x position plus popup
width. If it's greater than zero
then align left to the position of the
left which is this one. bounding box
lift. Okay. So
if you see view port width so when it's
wide and you know blah blah blah and
otherwise otherwise view port width
minus popup width minus 35 pixels dot
two string plus
pixel. Okay. So you make it a line left
and make it a line right. Let's compile
it. Okay. Shift C compile the TypeScript
code. Successful. Now back to browser.
Now
refresh. Now move the cursor to
the emoji. There you go. Fantastic. I
don't even have to think about it
because let's leave it like that.
Okay.
Yeah. Yeah. I don't want to think about
this because this bounding box very
fairly
complicated. Okay, so far so
good. Quick question. Are you into bug
bounty
hunting? Uh not really.
Uh not really. So like for for example
what show you know type and you
know tell us what is Microsoft or Apple
or Google is offering bug bounty how
much like tell us like typically those
things are not easy to do I mean yeah I
mean even if you are expert then then
it's because it's very very
niche
Um
yeah so okay so that's about
that.
Um so type script. Okay so let's show
yeah so we got that. So what if
the you see now it works very nice. You
see
normally this balloon
bubble is below your cursor. You see
it's below your
cruiser. Now, however, you see, however,
you
see when you don't have enough space
below it, they become they show above
the cursor. You see? So, that's why you
got those bounding box thing. um you
know that that that's why you got this
this these two lines which require this
these bunch of lines above okay that's
about
that yeah that's what I want to do but
what if we are on a phone you see that's
a thing so if we are on the phone shift
control I
uh then show the mobile phone mod so
shift
controlm Then let's say right now we are
on iPad. Let's
say
Android Galaxy S20. You see now we are
on the phone.
Now click. Oh, you have to click.
Okay. So you have to Yeah. On the phone
because it's, you know,
touch. Um now let's let's try iPhone.
Okay. iPhone
11. Touch
refresh. Touch. Yeah. Okay. I'll just
use That's not too
bad. But what happened to my
um Oh,
wait. Okay. So, actually my window is so
large now. So that's why it doesn't show
the hole because my font I my I made my
font so large whenever I'm doing live
stream. Uh that's what a good tip by the
way. So if you are going to do live
stream one day doing coding remember
make your font like
22 at least 22 size to you it's going to
be huge but to other people who are
watching your live show that would that
would be actually normal okay because
because otherwise it's tiny impossible
to see so anyway that works so let's
leave it okay so yeah so we finish one
thing unic code popup
window. So we talked for 40 minutes
already. So let's do next thing. I
there's some other things I want to do.
Okay. Add unic code replacing that.
Okay. So let me show you. So go to
JavaScript. Uh actually go to go
to info. Um
uh let's
say get okay close that actually.
Okay. JavaScript get status. Can you put
a dot there? Yes. So that shows those
page changed. Okay. CD
above. Then get status. Okay. So these
pages change it. Changed. Okay. Let's
get
commit. Okay. No
messages. Fantastic.
So we com we committed git. Now I want
to do some massive change on thousands
of of pages. Let me show you what. Okay.
So you can see JavaScript functions. So
it's my convention whenever there's a
page that shows my own function instead
of a building function of JavaScript or
emac lisp or wuam language or whatever
language python ruby
golan if it's my own code for that page
I have a rocket showing up there you see
so that's my convention so that way you
can easily tell for example this topic
box of all JavaScript array Okay. Topic
you can easily see. Oh, this one is a
custom function. Custom function range
function for array. See? So that's
rocket. So but what I want now is that
you know I'm thinking let's change the
that emoji to something
else because rocket is kind of lame
because every everyone is using it. So I
wanted to change it to um change to this
this this character. Okay. Uh so this
character is named
sparkles. So let's see. So
um so if you know usually when you do
that you have to check on iPhone you
know on Apple on on Mac on iPad on
Android or on in browsers because each
platform their emoji shows up they have
different you know pictures for
emoji. So you want to make sure the
choice whenever you want to use emoji
for your website you want to make sure
that that's the one you like across
platforms. So for example then you can
go to my emoji database you can so for
for our purposes we want some kind of
icon to represent custom functions.
Okay. So you could, you know, you could
use a flower if you want, if you're into
that. If you or you could use a sun, you
know, smiling
sun or you can use a comet, a shooting
star. That would be nice. That would
that would that would suit my character.
So but or you can use a money money
bag. Um yeah. So, but I was using uh
transportation. I was using the rocket.
So, where is the transportation? So,
let's see. Office tech things. Office
um clock miscellaneous flag culture. So,
culture is also rich uh kind of things.
Show us emoji.
Um then you got
um places, buildings, church, hospitals,
vehicles there. Okay. So you go to
vehicles, then you got you know trains,
you got airplanes, then you got rocket
or you can use
UFO. So you have to decide a symbol you
want to use. Now for me my style is kind
of more austere
austerity. No funny, no smiling, no cute
things. So I would pick something more
mathematically associated such as uh any
one of these
punctuations. And in fact I would pick
any of these shapes. You know some of
these shapes are colored. You don't have
to color it by default. So they are
colored. So that's one thing nice about
emoji. So I was thinking of using that
diamond. We can try. But you see then
you have to try it on the Apple devices.
This diamond on Apple devices they show
like a a
gemstone you know. So so you have to
pick a symbol you make sure you like.
But anyway let's try this one. Okay. So
what I want to do is we want to
uh let's just try it.
Okay. So just put this here. Show in
browser. Let's see what it looks
like. Okay. I'll do that. Yeah.
So
So now you have to do this change for
thousands of files. Okay. So what I want
to do is basically copy
that now
call find replace text. Look at the pink
window it says there. So search for all
of that character. Enter. Replace
by that. Enter. Then what directory? So
let's
say.info. Okay. do that all HTML files
regular expression yes write changes to
file let's say no so if you say no it
just show you a report of the results
then you can look at that and then
decide yeah that's what we want then do
it again and it'll be
done so the first run it has to go over
a few thousand you know like 30 uh 30
50,000 files of which
about 1300 13,000 are HTML files then
you have to search those files so the
first run will take like 30 minutes
because most of the time is loading the
file even though I have a flash drive
but after the first run it'll be like
three
seconds. This is coffee with
honey.
Fantastic. Luxury of middle class
American. And this is tea.
Mhm. You see these are all the
results.
Fantastic. So you see there
are 29,000 lines of code. Okay. So you
can now show all the files.
So 78 files. So all these files contain
the change.
Okay.
Then if I decided that's what I want to
do, just say yes, run the command again
and you'll do it. And we can list all
the changes. So all we have to
do list matching lines that character
show. So there are
2,972 changes.
So you can quickly have a glance. You
can see there's tons of
it. Okay. So there's like tons of
it. Does it looks fine to me? Do I want
to make this change? That's why we are
making a git commit. You know just in
case we want to revert. Actually I don't
need git commit because with this find
replace command I can undo it.
Yeah, that looks fine. Let's let's make
the change. Okay. Are you sure it is
going to change like 10,000 files? Yeah,
let's do it. Okay. So, to repeat the
command, there's a EMAC repeat last
complex command. So, I can call it
by Okay, that command name is repeat
complex command in Emacs. So I can just
call it then up arrow. This is the
command we want. Cut it.
Cancel. Show a new buffer. Paste. So you
can see this is replace text
command. Uh so let's make it easier to
[Music]
read. Okay. So that's what we have. So
that means change this string to this
string in this directory via this
regular expression pattern for file
names. Uh directory depth 0 to 999 write
to file new. Okay. Uh actually we want
to write to file yes. Okay. Run
it. Fantastic. You see three seconds now
you know. So for each file you press
enter to open it. So you can see show in
browser. This this is about programming
blog archive 2022. Okay. Uh it's a long
long it's a long file. Okay. But there
it is. PowerShell rename files to file
hash string. I believe we did a live
stream about this one. We wrote this
live live. Okay. So you can see the link
is changed but however the file title
has not changed yet. So we're going to
do that. But anyway, but for now we just
checking all these. Um let's open this
one. What is this one? Uh blog archive.
Okay. Let's go to the next file.
Okay. So, Emacs, Emacs, uh, validate
matching brackets. Let's open that one.
Show in
browser. Okay. So, there is Yeah. custom
command. Yeah, that looks good. Sparkle.
Okay.
So, yeah, that's good. Yeah, I do. I
prefer it over the rocket. Yes. Okay.
Let's go. Let's go to the next some
next. I don't want to. So let's say this
one emac bisp compile typescript which
we just demoed
today. So you can copy the code then you
can compile typescript in
emacs. Okay. So you can see there's a
bunch of custom custom command. Now
click on
this emac command. So all of them got
that. Fantastic. I like it. So I decided
I want to change it.
Okay. So now
uh now let's do one more thing. Okay. So
let me show you. So let copy it. Go to
the talk show. Go to today's talk show
here. And uh let's
uh paste that link list
show. There it is. Okay. So, actually
there's
a Okay. So, we did we did that. Then go
back here. What is this? Show
co
show close
show. It's today's talk show. Okay. We
run this
again. You'll find one file. You see
this one single file.
Now it's changed. Okay. Now the so let
me show you a command. So I have this
command because now since I adopted this
I want a way to easily type that. So
normally I call this command. So this
command is insert unic code. You can see
in the ping window. So now I can choose
you know some of the unic code I use
often. So you let's see let's say angry
and annotate it with a unic code uh
information and make a paragraph show in
browser page down. There you go
angry. So now if we call that again
there is no sparkle. Okay there's no
sparkle. So let's add that. So let me
show you. So describe key this key go to
the source code flag keys open it insert
uni code it will insert a choices among
this unic code list which is a list of
choices you can customize so let's
add let's add so let's add that sparkle
okay paste paste paste paste paste paste
we add
there. Okay. So, this name
is sparkles.
Okay. Okay. Now, evaluate this function.
We have it. Close it. Save it. Make a
backup. Close it. Now,
call spa. There it is. Oh, I already
have it.
Okay, that's good. Okay, then. Okay,
reopen
that. Delete
that. Search
uh sparkles. Yeah, I already have that.
Okay, eval close. Close. Okay. Now,
now
change or
title s find replace.
Wait, change your title that change to
sparkle. Okay, do it.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Right. Change
to
file. Fantastic.
So these all files there you are show
160 files
changed. Fantastic. Close it and uh jump
to it. Open
it. There's one more thing to change
because you can see we changed the title
but we didn't change H1. So now let's
change H1. Okay. Now repeat complex
command. Cut,
cancel, close,
close,
close. Now paste. So we got this. Okay,
let's paste it in here. So actually cut
all. Close close. And uh add a
JavaScript uh emac code block. Paste.
Pop it out. That's our code. So now
let's just
purify. Okay. So now, yeah, that's a
title. Now I want to change the H1.
Okay. Copy that. Paste it here. Now
H1 that. Okay. So change it all in sai
info. Yes. Do
it.
Fantastic. Okay. Turns of it. Now put it
back. Syntax color show in browser. Page
down. Page down. So that's the we did
that. So now all files I believe is
complete. So you see title H1. So you go
down run current file then go back to um
show uh let's say is here Emacs there it
is emac compile typescript file then
click on emac command so all of them is
sparkling fantastic that's it for today
thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff pay me.
Okay. Go to
kasali.info and uh all the way
down, Patreon, Amazon, PayPal.
Okay, let's see what anything else I
need to do.
So, insert unic code. So, let's
see. I think that's it. So sorry insert
unic code. You can get the code
here. Copy the URL. Close. Close. And
let's paste it the link
there. So I insert unic code. Okay.
Uh and something else I need to do.
Okay. Bye guys.