word order you know and then you can say
okay let's let's try again animal a cane
hi him oh there's no there's no Unicode
whose name continued animals so let's
say Pig
now let's say poor be you hell hell okay
that's all the characters that contain
contains the word pool including high
speed train with bullet nose so so it
also we also got lots of bullets so
let's say meth okay if you type map it's
gonna be huge
you know these well anyway so this is
JavaScript and also if you click one
food you can mouse over and get the
Unicode name so that's in JavaScript you
know so you know and other things so so
that's why and I want to you know start
to write you know this SVG crock you can
see but it's VG so that well so one
of the reasons is because I write I you
know I do websites so I need JavaScript
site it's good for me to master it the
other thing is that I have been trying
to you know get back to working in the
industry so I was thinking you know get
on to Java
I mean JavaScript because javascript in
the past 10 years has become almost the
number one language I mean it has become
I mean in terms of popularity you know
it said that the number of libraries the
language with not the most count of
number of libraries is JavaScript today
so and you know Microsoft and you know
they today you actually you you can
write desktop applications using Java
you know that's how things
moving in that direction but so you know
one day you know I know a little bit a
little bit of JavaScript
since 2005 you know but but back then I
was treating it like you know like Perl
or Python you know just the basics like
loop you know strings and that's it I
don't know much about it but I find it
interesting because because of the
behavior of object JavaScript object it
has some kind of dynamic behavior so I
found that you interesting so I so you
know I just took a dive and started to
you know study JavaScript in depth so so
now I know a lot about it I would say
you know excuse me for saying that but I
would claim my JavaScript in depth is
the number one the most easy to
understand and the most in technical in
depth detail about JavaScript on a web
the number one including you know
counting Mozilla stock or Microsoft
stock or you know they are they are a
few a handful JavaScript considered
javascript cards
you know JavaScript survey parties
should I name the names you know there's
a few well anyway I know I basically
yeah of course I know them you know I'm
not going to you know you can if you are
in the on you know you know JavaScript
community you probably know you know
they're it's like Richard Stallman you
know he's a the guy most famous in the
Emax community and few other people too
but in JavaScript community also there
are a few who has written books and so
on but so I am confident to say that my
JavaScript book is number one okay
actually I wouldn't technically I
wouldn't say no
one you will be number two number two or
three because I know there are other
people who is better than name then what
I have what I have written but anyway
but yeah oh the other thing I'd really
want to say is that you know so I spent
two years writing job JavaScript but
yeah it's really what it's nobody is
reading it actually it's kind of sad but
you know really nobody is reading
reading it it's the reason is because
you know the reason is because today
there's so much marketing you know yeah
because they did you know there's so
many so many there they are websites
that focus on you know varying tutorials
and writing tutorials for the masses and
they are like they are like small
corporations you know they it just
dedicate their time into doing it you
know they hire other people cheaply
you know - righteous basics for the
beginners and they they market massively
you know with Facebook Links you know
and please slightly space you know and
you know and spend span it to Twitter
and Facebook 80 you know they do that
that's how things are today so in quick
baits of course so on Twitter for
example if you search for JavaScript
every day you are bombarded with all
type of like garbage and SHR
okay every day is like well we have this
new library this library is the best and
so on we have a new new version of
something something you know you see you
know funny and daily and diving deeper
in JavaScript object my ass you know you
know if you look at them they are not
they are like sometimes they are wrong
or just they are just averaging so often
usually they are bad you know bad
javascript you know it's that way
because javascript is very popular not
because it's a good language it just
happens to be very you know the most
popular language right now and you know
when something happens like that people
drop it there's our money basically
money is driving driving everything so
people wants to you know get money out
of it that's why you know you know this
now there's a hundred days of code
hundred days of code my ass yeah you
know QA stuff you know JavaScript not
okay so anyway that's a situation of
JavaScript and you have lots of
frameworks and it's very bad you know
you JavaScript the language is very bad
it's bad
in well you know I can go into details
about why it's bad you know there's
Sigma aspect but one of the most
important aspect javascript is bad is
that because okay it's because the
syntax you know Java JavaScript is a
dynamic language much like clear much
like PHP or Perl Ruby Python okay it's
dynamic so it's not static it's not like
Java or C so it's dynamic it's and it's
very flexible and you got this object
system JavaScript object system is not
like Java no like Python you know or
Ruby it's not nothing like that
JavaScript script object you know just
think of it as a hash table in in Ruby
or Dictionary in Python okay just think
of it like that so it's a key value
pairs now any value can be another
object or another hash table you know
and each object has a parent object or
parent hash table so and at any time you
can change the parent to something else
or change their children to something
else
you can delete key of values at any time
and
so so so that's that's that's
essentially the JavaScript's object
system and you know javascript also
support functional programming like a
function is a first-class object you
know you can pass a function to another
function as an argument or a function
can be returned as a return value and
JavaScript has a very flexible syntax so
you know you have multiple ways to write
one thing but they are not very
consistent so basically what what
happens because it's so flexible and the
syntax is pretty loose and you know not
consistent in any scheme you know in any
way it's it's very extremely hard to
read in fact it's harder to read in them
perl and different person have different
styles so and also javascript the
semantics is very complex it's extremely
complex it's it's it's it's one
up it to begin with
and they try to fix it however they
didn't fix it by removing the bad parts
you know they always try to be
compatible so today's JavaScript you
know the es Eggman script 2015 and later
they have now they have a new version
every year so today's version you know
since the 2015 version is all compatible
all the way back to JavaScript almost
like JavaScript version 1 like 20-30
years ago so there's a lot of garbage
there and because the language the
semantics is is extremely complex so the
people who program JavaScript you know
you have beginners to expert right but
but even an average the vast majority
they do not know the technical details
so they usually write something and
actually it's technically wrong you know
so you have a piece of code that
that works like 99% percent of time but
this 1% more time it's the code because
the code is just wrong you shouldn't do
it that way but people do it that way
because you know there's a massive
momentum you know JavaScript the
language they don't understand that you
know how exactly things work so that's a
situation of JavaScript but you know if
you if you lived in a mm you probably
know the story you know nobody likes
JavaScript then not Jay s came along
then you know the older corporations
pushed for it Google pushed for it
because foam because you know there's
some money you know there's funding then
you have the you know ACMA script now
you know new version each year it
improves you know so so you know the
massive number of advertisement
marketing you know so today's new new
generation they you know some people
will say they will say you know I love
JavaScript oh I love the Chalmers will
be such a great language it's nothing
you can do you know the you know the
generation just move on and it's kind of
you know so it's like Java Java in the
1990s you know you know that's massive
marketing and you know object-oriented
you solve everything
the the last language you know the one
language you know great ones you know
compile every worker you know that's
supposed to solve everything Java is the
last language you know it has this you
know it's so many languages today so
anyway so
[Music]
so yeah okay I cannot see that you know
it looks like the the chat is
disconnected that's bad because okay so
that's it for today thanks for coming by
and talk to you guys later another day
next next next time bye