hello guys welcome welcome to another
episode of sound talk
show we're going to code wfam language
Mathematica today on Geometry plain
curves so this is me hello guys WFAN
language if you are here say hi if you
are not here play at 1.5 speed and Skip
around because I talk randomish all over
so let me show you so wam language okay
uh PL curves so this today's topic
mathematics PL curves we are going to
use wam language to
create some of these Graphics okay for
example this is beautiful Graphics of
conic sections you have a cone and you
slice it their intersection is a called
conic sections uh one of Parabola elisp
or hyp
okay reach history you know this conic
sections uh has a history back to uh 2
2000 years ago Greek one of the Greek
math ma mathematics and one of the first
uh kind of pure mathematics okay so all
these curves these are plane curves
curves on the plane these are called
conic sections so we're going to do this
Graphics today and uh can you see me yes
video audio check and we're going to try
to do some of the uh recreate these
images this I did about 20 about 30
years ago
1997 okay so you know back then this is
Cutting Edge technology not so much
today because today you can do you know
you have lots of programs anyway this
one is generated by po Ray using Shadows
of a ball to illustrate conic sections
you see these Shadows are conic sections
this one is hyperbola and this one is
elisp
fascinating okay that's we what we going
to do wolam language let's begin it okay
uh let's begin wam
language did we start Okay so
there it
is
cheers some
y uh some red
wi okay so are we ready yes wam language
start a new notebook okay so we just
going to code it
okay three shift enter to start the
kernel and magnify so you can see
better okay
so we ready hello d v hello wam language
content fantastic always fantastic thank
you so I'm using so if you don't know so
let me do one minute intro okay so if
you don't know already uh wolam language
you go to search for Wam
C wam Language tutorial you'll find it
and you can download it download the wam
engine for free so you can use it but
however if you download the wam engine
free you do not have the graphical user
interface so you cannot you know Show
graphics like that you have a terminal
okay so for example let me show you wam
language terminal okay let's put that
here here W script okay so wam script
okay there you got uh
what
activate license related
problems that shouldn't
be and because because I'm running in
this W language because you can let's
try it
again there it is okay you can only run
one instance actually I can run two but
for some reason I don't know why so for
example
table so this is uh wolam language uh
actually we are digressing I want it to
[Music]
um x² for example then and you say X
from 1 to
5 okay so you got that uh I want to show
some something
pretty okay so let's let's let's try
it next a function 1
/x and uh okay next the function nested
three times now let's see the
documentation of Nest uh not that
documentation of
Nest so we starting to do Wam language
Nest function expression n okay so
function uh uh Nest it three times let's
see what is the
result uh it's not a file save it first
okay so let's go save it first so talk
show uh create wam language paste it
there pop it out run
it and go so I need to exit this is
annoying so uh because for some reason I
can only run one instance right now
usually it's
two okay so next you need a function
okay so next a function
X and then I want one /x so that is a
function okay run
it uh why okay so next so 1 /x and over
X okay so one over um let's say X
plus plus one okay run it
there you have it okay I don't like that
output but anyway let's try it here so w
from script can you see
it am I good say fantastic okay so paste
expression there contrl V uh control
shift V uh not
that can you
[Music]
see so we want want to run this function
nested three times contrl V there it is
that's what we want that's what I want
you see so this is wolam script you can
download for free and let's run it in
wolam language okay I mean in wolam
notepad
exit so let's uh
let's open it
three shift
enter paste the
expression shift enter there it is
fantastic okay let's make a screenshot
of this so we have a record of of the
Fantastic things we
did and similarly here it's too big okay
you
cannot
God uh
okay so make a screenshot of
this open
it so you can see wolam script which you
get for free wolam notebook which you
got this typ set mathematics which you
do not get for free but however you can
download the Jupiter notebook okay
Jupiter notebook that will allow you to
run Graphics uh with the free wolam
engine wolam script okay jupyter
notebook so all the information you need
you just go to um sari search SAR wolam
Language tutorial click on download you
can download it you can then what's the
difference between wolam language
Mathematica wolam engine wolam script
you can find it then I have a link to
Jupiter notebook so this is what
notebook looks like Jupiter notebook and
you can you can download the Jupiter
notebook which is uh open source free
okay so that's a introduction to F
language uh so now let's we don't need
this this this is just showing off what
we want to do is is doing the um plane
curves okay so so let's begin okay
showing browser so go to conic sections
showing browser
fantastic zyd Hello read your article
about Fibonacci they are merely
coincidental correct article math Mystic
math mysticism is Hurricane shape yeah
that's interesting topic
cheers so we are talking about the Fe
foni
spiral that's one of the
um
um how do you say
um kind of like a um you know like a
stupid
myth so let me show you show you felazi
sp spiral okay so when people talk about
Fibonacci spirals they actually they
kind of mean the equal angular spiral
which is this one now this one is
probably the most famous
spiral in mathematics okay there are
many others for example this lus now now
this is interesting because it is the
model of the violin um you know the uh
what the squir you know this part is
called scroll you can see it in violand
and also in Greek architecture columns
you know they have technical names for
this uh kind of uh spiral and you can
see so anyway so that's one of the
Spiral this one is called lus and there
are others this is aredian
Spyro uh and uh then
am I am I am I like uh am I streaming
smoothly so anyway then there's K spiral
so the most famous spiral is this equal
angular spiral now this spiral is most
popular because it occurs in nature the
most so let me show you a example for
example in
seashells and in this uh even happens in
this exotic fractal cauliflower you can
actually buy this
uh it's kind of popular I think it's
more popular in
Europe and in seashells okay so sea
shells so you can see you see all these
spirals they are called they are like
kind of modeled from equal angular
spiral or also called logarithmic spiral
okay so but when so you know you can see
a bunch of seashells all sort of
seashells here okay
so seashells beautiful sea shells are
fantastic and beautiful all types so
they are all based from mathematic
mathematically they are all based from
the equal angular
spiral okay so why is it why is it equal
angular because if you draw a line from
the center of the
Spiral you draw a line out you know
array
that line will intersect the spiral at
certain
Angle now the interesting property is
that doesn't matter where is your line
it will always
intersect the spiral at a same angle so
80 for example in this image it's
80° okay always doesn't matter where is
your what direction is your Ray and
doesn't matter which you know which
part am I good am I streaming
good test test is my streaming healthy
H this the
stream is my stream healthy
now uh I need to fix
this no longer buffering okay so it
seems good uh let me double check
because we need really need to fix
this uh very annoying problem
okay so am I
good this is not going
away now seems good okay so let's let's
move
on so we got the equal angular spiral
now what about the original question
okay it's good thank you guys now
original question about the feei spiral
okay now Fibonacci okay so let's go to
math s math blog you can find my math
blog and go to the math articles
index so you scroll down you find an
article where I criticize the um Mr
Caesar
of the brainless people talking about
the feon naazi
spiral okay so where is it uh let's
search
feeo okay
there you see this is a common so-call M
okay
today you know for for example they will
say the
hurricane forms the Fibonacci spiral now
what's the name for this this it's a
kind of like a m seism but there's
another word okay so Fibonacci you know
why is it called Fibonacci because it
relates to the Fibonacci
sequence now what is Fibonacci Sequence
okay uh I can show you
okay okay there is f Oni uh there's a
building function in wam language fibon
okay
it's basically a sequence starting with
one the second term is also one then you
add the previous two terms so you get 1
+ 1 is two so one one two okay then you
add the previous two terms so 1 + 2 is
three 1 1 2 3 okay then 2 + 3 is 5 1 1 2
3 5 then 3 + 5 is 8 1 1 2 3 5 8 now that
sequence is called Fibonacci Sequence
okay so you can so wam language has a
building function so
um so let's see so foni sequence um for
example do do they start with zero okay
so
um one uh shift enter one is one
okay uh the second term shift enter is
one
okay the third
term is two because the previous two 1 +
1 is two now the fourth
term shift enter is three because 1 + 2
is three so you can get you can kind of
get the table okay so let me do this in
um
H hold on a second okay so uh what this
is Con sections okay so let's add it
here so we got a link uh then we got the
link about
the mysteries of the Fibonacci
spiral uh you know we kind of digressed
but anyway these squares you see squares
within Square they are based off from
the Fibonacci sequence okay so uh let me
do it again
again Fibonacci okay so you just say x
Fibonacci X and you want a table a table
of
it Fibonacci and then by the way I'm
using wolam language mod in
emac so you can
see this W language mod it allows you to
code wolam language in emac editor okay
so it allows uh so so you can see it you
can download it for
free you know if you are emac user you
can download it for free okay so it's on
GitHub so it allows me to code wolam
language instead of using the wolam
notebook I can much code easier you know
like with a power of emac okay so we are
going to do W uh the Fibonacci so
Fibonacci x x from one to five so run
it you see here's the
answer one one two 3 five and let's do
it let's do it uh one two uh let's say
10 you see that that's the answer you
can also run it in
Notebook uh so let's paste it shift
enter to run
fantastic now is there a
um like is there a function that
directly show the Fibonacci
sequence like I want just uh
uh no okay so you you just run this okay
and you can write the function to
compute it
yourself you know but wam language has
it built in but you can write it in
Python in Goan in Java whatever your
favorite language basically you just add
previous two terms okay starting with
one and
one so and you can look up Wikipedia
Wikipedia will have tons of information
so let's actually uh look up Wikipedia
so there it is Fibonacci okay so he's
talking about the Fibonacci guy kind of
mathematician from
1863 so you click
on okay you click on Fibonacci
number then you got you you see the
Fibonacci sequence and they started to
show you this Fibonacci squares so and
they they started to show you this
spiral which is the Fibonacci spiral
which is
um okay I'm not going to explain this
how this rectangle forms but it's but
but this spiral is basically a
approximation to
[Music]
the to this equal angular spiral we are
talking about it's kind of a
approximation okay now but the thing
about about this thing you see this
Fibonacci thing there's a coat uh what's
the word um okay so let let's do uh code
let's see synonyms let me just
um there's a sect religion persuasion
Faith quedo Doctrine Dogma no
um uh let's see the synonym for m
season okay there's
not
mysticism there's no the thesaurus how
can
you anyway this kind of this thing you
know where typically they are from non
mathematicians so like typically they
are from this kind of people they are in
to UFOs they are into aliens oh my God
aliens gra gra
gravitic propulsion
system which is on the news China from
China you know these type of people they
are the type of people they talk about
this all the
time you know how how all these things
everything everything is Fibonacci
spiral you know because there is like uh
Illuminati because because UFO because
alien bu it because you know that's why
you know this type of people
idiots okay and this picture you know
Fibonacci spiral from a girls you
know uh you know that's making fun of it
okay uh for example so this is kind of
very popular if you if you search
YouTube You'll see a ton of it like
mysticism numerology you know like oh if
you take out a dollar bill you you see
these numbers you add the nth digit and
they form
666 that that's this type of people
talking about this okay they are crap
they are not
mathematicians and uh there's a
video yeah so let me show you a video so
there there is this video very popular
very very well done high quality on
YouTube they you know they they kind of
talk about this
Fibonacci um spiral beautiful actually
it's a beautifully made
video you know
300,000 views 14 years ago okay let me
just skip around you
know like they visually show you how the
Fibonacci numbers you see one 1 2 3 5
you know 8 13 21 they form this this
so-called
um
Fibonacci uh squares something I forgot
Fibonacci rectangle but anyway it's a
very
beautiful video and they show you how it
connects to the
seashells uh and nature and all that
okay and and the
and the sunflowers you know the
arrangement of
sunflowers lots of okay but but
mathematically it's just crap
okay uh okay so that's that's about that
okay I'm not
um so that's my answer to your question
CH Ching thank you
Crystal okay Crystal uh thank you
Crystal hold on a second
let me just put the uh
links anyway we I want to go back to
working on mathematics this Fibonacci is
just like a stupid thing so Crystal
asked appreciate your contribution to
Wikipedia conic section thank you yeah
Wikipedia you know that that's back in
2003 that's the first time I became
aware of of Wikipedia because they
linked to my website these conic
sections you know because I have you
know refer you know like who linked to
my website I have like web blog Apache
web blog so I saw wait oh Wikipedia you
know the conic sections that's the very
first the beginning of
Wikipedia in 2003 you know in the
beginning there's only like 100
articles so that's a beginning
so by now you know Wikipedia they
probably removed my links and stuff they
copied stuff and remove that's the
nature of
Wikipedia okay cheers some
wine let's get back because I I you know
I need to like you know improve this
Graphics so crystal says what curve you
want edged on your tomstone you asked
that before you you forgot you asked
that few months ago maybe four months
ago and I
answered uh there's no like there's no
particular
ones that I would want to etch on my
Tombstone if I'm dead if I'm
dead there's a question you know what
would I what would I like like to Edge
on my
Tombstone or is it pronounced
TB well first of
all I'm not sure what that would be a
thing for me because I'm dead I'm dead
okay I'm not a Christian I'm not a Islam
believer or Judaism believer I'm not you
know I'm not
a believer in
God okay so for me I'm dead and dead you
can feed me to the
dogs you know doesn't like doesn't you
know I maybe you shouldn't you know
because unless you hate me but I'm dead
I'm dead
okay uh
so so what about my Tombstone I don't
know you know maybe you just burn burn
my body burn my dead body
I don't know so but if I'm going to have
a
to you know that pretty much that
depends on whether you are beli believer
of one of these mono God religions
Christianity for
example uh if you don't believe it then
you are not too much
into about what happens when you are
dead well I mean even in Chinese
Buddhism Chinese Japanese Korea or
Vietnam a bunch of South Asia countries
they are mostly Buddhism okay a variety
of buddhismspiritual
[Music]
Traditions about the
dead but anyway in East Asia we are
mostly Buddhism we do bury our dead and
we respect we have early we you know the
one of the most important thing in
eastern Asia Chinese Japanese Korean and
South Asia our tradition our thinking is
that we must
Respect the Dead your parents your
ancestors your grand grandparents and
and and your grandparents and
grandparents you know so yearly we have
a day uh
called I I don't know what's it called
in English some sort of memor Memorial
day where we visit our dead parents
grave graveyards okay so we do bury our
you know dead
parents so we every year we go clean
their Gra WAVE clean their uh uh
to uh yeah that's how it you know that's
a Asian
tradition uh anyway let's go back to
mathematics
okay so let's go back to mathematics so
uh did I add so yeah I don't have you
know I don't I I don't have a
particularly favorite curve uh because
many of them are extremely beautiful to
me uh okay so let's go back to conic
sections okay let's do some real
mathematics let's see so first thing I
want to do is let's plot this um this
one okay so in order to plot it you want
to know first the first thing you want
to know is is that is you want to plot
it as a equal angular I mean if if you
want to plot it as a parametric
equation parametric formula
or uh as a implicit equation so as a
formula of functions or as a equation
so
uh so I have a bunch of notebooks
uh hold on a second not M okay so I have
actually a bunch of notebooks
here that I
um let's open them okay so there's a lot
bunch of
notebooks okay wolm language notebooks
is quite a few okay but they are like
old okay okay so for example opening
this
one in wolam language notebook so it
says you open a notebook with an old
default style we have updated your
notebook's appearance yes continue okay
so this is this notebook is
done like 30 years ago
so these packages they are kind of uh
this is my
package and this extended Graphics is
obsolute so it will require actually a
lot work to uh to rewrite
this so which one is this one this one
is a uh fancy illustration so this
notebook is creating this images okay 30
years ago now you have to remember this
is 30 years ago
so 30 years you know uh a lot things has
changed so this will not run as
is uh so actually that's what I'm
supposed to do today but but this one is
a fairly complicated
um yeah I okay I'm not going to do this
because it'll take an hour okay and very
technical detail Advanced wolam language
uh so I'm not going to do this so let's
look at the next
one so this
one okay continue with the current book
this is a general package for conic
sections not this Mathematica not book
is
from
WWW project you know this is
oldfashioned www means worldwide web
which basically today just a website
okay from the www project a visual
dictionary of special plan curves
copyright 1995 to
2000 okay so this is one of my package
and this is my package this is my
package and this one Graphics implicit
plot that's obsolute now that has been
built
in so again it will take some time to
update this um
notebook so you can
see it generates these Graphics uh
yeah and this is a very interesting
property that is if you
you know so let me explain this one okay
maybe I'm we you know we are not going
to code but let me explain this one so
you have
repulse suppose you go to a a pound or a
lake you drop two stones two small
Pebbles one after the other so drop one
first then drop the other
one they will form repos going out
right then so you drop one then you drop
they start repos then you drop the other
you know that starts repo basically
circles okay concentric circles going
outwards then they will start to
intersect now the property here is that
the intersections the the set of all
intersections they form a
curve and you know they form a curve so
these curves are hypol
okay fascinating so these curves are
hyperbola um this one okay I need to
regenerate this Graphics so it's bigger
and
beautiful uh hyperbola okay so for
example let me show you
hyperbola
um let's
see so conic sections uh hypera okay
that's those
in fascinating
property okay hyperbola has so many
properties
um you know anyway so this is the old
notebook I need to update and also if
you consider the intersections in a
different way they are elip ellipses
okay another conic
section okay so there's different
Graphics uh then here's another uh very
interesting Graphics this is about
intersection of parabas
okay okay so here is the code for this
Graphics which I need to update
okay so conic sections with different
eccentricity so let's copy that
copy and paste make a copy and
now control shift n to make it to make
it typ set okay so use the same code
same code but over
here over here is kind of asky style
where if you are programmers you are
used to this you know just plain asky
like Tab and and you know Tab and
indentation for alignment you know
idiotic here it's a exactly the same
code but formulated you know but type
set automatically you just press the key
you know type set it you can
see
beautiful and another thing interesting
is that you can change the width of the
window and the type setting will adjust
accordingly can you
see can you see this parametric
formula you see with fractions you see
the type setting adjust according
accordingly this is in sharp contast
contrast to the python idiots or the C
C++ idiots or the Java idiots or the
Goan or the rust idiots because these
industrial coders they are used to
manually dle each line you know you need
you need to set up your emac
configuration for indentation oh I
prefer tabs or I prefer space I need you
know indentation should be two space No
it should be three you know these
arguments but in wam language that's why
this is one of the reason wam language
is
like uh a magnitude more advanced and
the concepts and thinking you know so
this automatic rendering
of mathematical formulas began in
1998 okay so by now it's almost 30 years
ago automatic and you don't have like
not it's not like te or L you have to
type you know like idiotic you know
like code to to to to type set your
format no you just type whatever you're
supposed to be um you know just type
normally press the key it formul it
renders your
um your expression
automatically okay and in real time you
know as you change the window with they
they they smartly re render
it so anyway I wanted to originally my
job is to modify this code
um so that you know to update this 30
years old code
yeah but um but for
example yeah so this is 30 years old
code um
so in order to do this actually can I
actually do
it yeah actually so I don't need
this okay now there's some technical
details it will take me too much time to
explain but let me just walk on it shift
enter let's try uh
no okay we got a
problem uh because 30 years old code um
so what is the
problem display function identity
deleted
um so you got three curves curve one two
so let me finish this and that'll be it
for
today Jack says uh GCS says do you use
Mathematica or wol
one they are the same thing okay so if
you read my article about
let's go to wam Language tutorial okay
so if
you search
for wolam Language
tutorial then go to
download download wolam language free
then you have article difference between
wolam language Mathematica wolf Engine
with from script click on that that
explains the
differences uh in fact they are they are
basically the same thing so they are all
just wam
language but why do you have them like
the different thing because
well they B they are the same thing okay
well because you know then you got phone
you got online you got Cloud versions
wolm alpha wolam one so they they
started to have different product for
different people some people today the
Zuma generation they don't have a
computer they don't have a laptop they
just have a cell phone so for those
people when they want to use W language
you know they you know they need the
cloud
version uh for some other people you
know they are not programmers you know
they are not going to write you know I'm
a programmer I'm a hardcore programmer
we C we code C Java python uh Ruby
JavaScript you know we coding is our job
but a lot of people coding is not their
job but they but they also need to do
technical
computation so for them what they want
is some kind of like a cloud version
they do have a laptop or a computer so
they but they don't they don't want you
know they are not going to code this
every
day uh like like the way we do hardcore
programmers they just want to sometimes
simply you know like find out something
about art artificial intelligence neural
networks or
statistics uh things like that or
students you know University students
they need to do homework they need to
find derivatives or integral
so for them there's a wolam cloud
version called uh you know this wolam
one wolam alpha you know so it's kind of
like related to marketing thing that's
why you have these different things but
basically wolam research the company
made sure that all of these are the same
thing so it's not like one version you
have you know some features but not
other features no they are actually all
the same more or less okay so if to
answer your question what exactly I'm
using uh I'm
using let's
see um well you can you can't even see
it I'm using I think Mathematica okay
that's not important
anyway so anyway so you got this so
let's try to fix this and let's be it
okay so it's complaining about range
specification parametric plot okay so
let me fix this okay
so control shift d to split it so let's
run this okay this is wrong oh that's
why because we have we don't have the
conic
defined well let's let's let's get
it okay so that's one of my package if
you go to salw and blog you can see 30
years ago I wrote many of these uh
packages PL
[Music]
cve PL tiing PL curve plot transform 2D
PL curve generator okay uh there's one
called formulas do I have it
here there there it is so I forgot to
include that so you know so this package
basically Define the formulas you know
the math formula is for for
about 40 curves so every time you want
to plot for example conic sections you
don't have to remember exactly what's
the formula you you can just type
Conex you know so this in so again it's
on GitHub or this my packages is on
GitHub you can download for
free uh it's here and
uh so uh what we want to do here so
let's
see okay so you need to load uh
either load it or just type the formulas
directly okay
so uh so what I want to do okay
so not math okay so hold on a second so
we got
formulas some talk
show fam language language
packages and uh
formulas
uh there it is okay so there it is so
that is my package you can
see these are the
result okay
so and
uh where is the code there okay so just
search for
conic there it is there it is and here
is the
documentation Search Search Search
Search Search
next that is the definition
okay so copy that close it close it back
here you need
to Define
it
okay uh and uh
let's okay let's Okay so there it
is so you got now connects now evaluate
this okay something is
wrong now this is correct okay so this
is
correct uh then
next shift
enter okay something wrong here
so next
question but is it really a fair
comparison with wolf and say C+ Plus or
rust uh because the application is
vastly different yes obviously so C and
C++ are system languages
meaning that those languages are
designed for for writing operating
systems or embedded devices like your
microphone or you know the chips on your
keyboard am I doing
good you know microphone chips on your
keyboard keyboard or mouse or you know
embedded devices C and C++ or Real Time
stuff like game engine so
that's that's what those languages are
good for C and
C++ Now wolfen language is not like that
so you cannot use wolam language to
write a Linux kernel or operating system
that would be CD because the source code
is like just one gigabyte something
actually is like five gigabyte or
something I
forgot but if you
want like if you want you know W
language is kind of like
lisp the lisp
mentality it's one system one
programming language to rule them all so
one way to think of it is wolam language
is one single language or
system what w step wam calls it a
technical comp Computing okay it's not
just for programmers it's
for you know if you wanted to do Finance
physics chemistry
anything like you you got this one
system that does everything
possible that is possibly done by human
on a
computer that's in wolam language okay
including artificial intelligence
including any kind of visualization
including machine learning artificial
intelligence neural networks uh crypto
you know Bitcoin
crypto
currency uh chain blockchain for example
all this technology it's all in
wolam or crypto analysis or decp encryp
you know like
like or image conversion like all histor
Al exist image format like today we have
jpeg PNG jpeg 2000 we have H EIC image
format you know we have like hundreds
GIF you know GF the very old image
format so every possible image format
that
existed wam language can Import and
Export or convert it or transform or you
know do image processing like every you
know like the things you do with
Photoshop okay that's image processing
then you can do 3D you know there's so
many 3D formats for AutoCAD for uh alas
wavefront for for you know all kind of
3D modeling for animation in Hollywood
animation industry or for actual
architectural design if you're going to
design a cathedral or a building you
know this is 3D FX you know so so
many so any 3D format that ever
existed wam language can Import and
Export
it so that's some of the I'm trying to
give you some illustration of
the of the mentality how incompass it is
one
system to rule them all that is the
mentality
of course there's a price you have to
pay first of all it's few gigabytes okay
then secondly you have to pay for it
it's not free okay it's not like the
open source whatever you know let's just
you know open source grab free load and
then figure out things it doesn't work
you go to GitHub you go to stack
Overflow and then you post Drama Oh you
need to fix this no we refuse to fix and
and LGBT EQ please put put code of
conduct you that's the drama and
the Linux distro which drro is the best
than one 10,000 dros each fighting each
other that's open source and which been
thed by controlled by giant corporations
Google Facebook you
know so wam language is not so you know
so it's one thing to do them all one
giant encompassing system not just
mathematics you know but fance image
processing everything okay including
neural network research you can create a
l you
know I don't have time to show you I can
type you know
L neuron network uh system you know for
example you got large language model
synthesiz configuration example function
function you know like you can set up
all these any research any type of
research you you're going to do or at
research level or student level
okay so it does you know all sort of
things so that's the mentality that's
the philosophy of wolam language which
is like the lisp which is basically the
lisp philosophy one system that does
everything like the list
machines uh back in 1980s or today's
emac
okay so that's you
know I can show you any you know any you
know I can show you but it's GNA just
take hours and you know it's going to
take days to show you but you can one
way one easy way to to look at
it is just
by uh let me show you okay just search
for wolam
documentation okay there you go wolam
language documentation
turn on JavaScript so this is where you
see the incomp passing nature okay so
wait so visualization data manipulation
core language features machine learning
symbolic computation and and numeric
computation higher mathematical
computation this is only you know this
is for if you are specialized
mathematician you know you do you know
algebra tensor algebra linear algebra
complex analysis real analysis deset
calculus iterate you know so and
probability Theory or you know random
you know processes discrete math number
Theory group Theory so so each of the
category um you know so visualization
for example you got data visualization
then you got like 10
20 uh functions or you go to functional
visual you know that it's
like so much you know I cannot cover you
know a fraction of it so that so my
point here is just to show
you the philosophy the mentality what is
this wolam language is about okay one
system to do everything and anything
that has has been possibly done by
computer in computer theoretical
computer science or practical computer
science or you know everything okay for
example data man manipulation and
Analysis
um you know this this is uh like um then
then you got you know so too much okay
so
but I hope that answers your question
question uh you wouldn't do a game in
wolam language that's correct okay you
can write a toy game like the like the
blocks you know the blocks falling
what's that called Tetris you know you
can do kind of like that but if you are
talking about real 3D games like
Minecraft or the gun shooting games no
you don't use wolam language for that
[Music]
uh it is now it is a general purpose
programming language okay it's in fact
far more General than rust it's just
high level okay but
anyway uh there's a question Frank says
what do you think reverse polish
notation that's fantastic okay that is
is actually my first programming
language H you can search my website for
hp28
calculator I wrote the my first my first
program before I even know what is uh
you know what is programing my first
program from scratch is a solution to
the eight Queens problem using the HP
stack programming language on HP 28s
okay you search for HP
28s then I believe you will see my
website uh except this this
crap over Road you know they
they s you know CEO and the
scums they took
over okay but my website is one of the
first inform
about HT um HP 28s
okay
this you know these grifters
and uh let's say
well let's go to Google okay because
Brave search is is not as good HP 28s
let's see if my website shows up there
first
hp20s by the way Google beginning about
a year ago they stop if you don't have
JavaScript they it won't even
run okay not on the first
page not on the second
page not on Okay so type type eight
Queens eight Queens
puzzle Fu up my
website yeah just just sry
okay there it
is so uh what no a
dark okay so
anyway there it is okay that's my
website so this is my first calculator
and also my first programming language I
bought this calculator in
1992 for
$200 and uh this is also my first
language and you can can see my eight
Queens program solution here using this
HP stack programming
language before I read anything you know
I don't know about what's algorithm and
all that this is just Brute Force you
know kind of learning about programming
and I also wrote a music code program
like major code minor code augmented
code
HP 20s calculator it can play sound of
different frequency so you can you know
be you can play a
song uh and you can program it to play a
song and you can not just single note
but you can have a Cote like two notes
two or more notes at the same time uh no
I don't wait maybe not but I play them
sequentially uh which in music jargon is
a pedo okay so anyway so you can you
know you can play random notes or um you
see I wrote this when I was studying
music theory in 1992 at fill college so
when you study music one of the things
important is to recognize cord by
hearing you know someone play a cord on
piano or guitar you you you can tell oh
that's C major uh uh C major you know
something so that's one of the skill if
you are a musician you have to train for
it so I wrote this program and many
others okay so that is my uh so you
asking about RPM notation this HP
calculator is most famous for rpn
notation uh which I'm not going to go
into details but you can read Wikipedia
and so on I think that's it for today we
we uh digressed so much okay we didn't
um actually I want to finish
this uh shouldn't be hard to fix okay
but something is
wrong range
specification t0 Ox
sign okay why is it
so you got uh AR go
sign
God yeah I I I need to fix this code
somewhere is
wrong so we've been how long have we
been we've been yeah we've been over an
hour now so I think we should
stop any other questions Okay so
okay I think that's it
um yeah that's it
I so
today the original intention is to
is to you know is to recreate this image
which we didn't do uh and we were going
to recreate images like that we didn't
do but we talked
about uh quite a few other things
related to wam
language okay I think that's it maybe
that's
it so so if you like my stuff okay
always donate okay so just go to
c. code you need to
donate uh c.co the.info go all the way
to the bottom I got lots of tutorials
for you uh you know many programming
languages they are the Style No Nonsense
okay to the point and
correct uh some of some of them in depth
such as emac LP and
JavaScript uh and so go to the bottom
pay me uh patreon me or Amazon gift card
or PayPal
okay so thank you
guys and
uh yeah that's it for
today C mysticism
uh close that Fibonacci yeah you can
learn about Fibonacci okay
Fibonacci kind of the code Cod
thing
uh okay so this is about wolam language
uh so why is it
okay so anyway bye
guys join my Discord if you haven't
already we shut down in two minutes okay
join Discord you have you haven't
already now f freny is a friend online
friend we you know we know each other
for three four years by now I think long
time on Le Discord and uh we talking
about artificial intelligence
spots uh that's it bye
guys I'm also on Twitter okay so follow
me on
Twitter uh and follow me on S Discord
you can find the links on my
website blue three hi blue
three blue three is a