Hello, good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Kusa Talk Show. We
are going to code emacis today. So this
keyboard is ultimate hacking keyboard 80
U HK80. Fantastic. Okay, I did a review
last week. So check out on my YouTube
in-depth review. And now let's code emac
lisp. There are two things we want to
do. I want to do. So one is write a
emacs lisp command that moves the
current file or current directory into
the parent directory. So I just press a
key and it'll move because otherwise I
have to split the window.
Let's say I want to uh move the Pascal
theorem. Okay. Not Pascal theorem. Let's
say AI morality. Okay. AI morality. This
is a podcast. Uh this is oh two years
ago 2023.
Uh it's showing you know it's it's it's
it's aged because AI is changing every
day. But anyway, I was talking about
AGI, artificial general intelligence,
strong AI, sentient AI, and AI
alignment, which is a code word for some
kind of ethics of AI. Stupid by the, you
know, western western society's
thinking. So anyway, this is aged uh but
but I think my central point still stand
still good today. So anyway, so there's
this file. I want to move it to the
parent directory. So, normally you split
split the window. Uh then you go up one
directory. So, uh that's correct. So,
you go up one directory, then you press
shift R to move. Then you just say okay.
Then you see now it's moved there. Now,
if you want to move it back, shift R.
Then do it. You see? Now, now um wait
override what? No, let's do it. Uh what
which did I move? Oh, what? We moved
Pascal's Theorem instead. So, let's move
it back. So, shift R.
Do it. So, now it's back. You see? So,
move the current file or directory to
the parent directory by just pressing
one key. That's what we going to write.
Now the other thing if we have time
is uh let's see uh HTML icon linkify. So
that is creating a link with the icon.
We'll uh talk about that when we are
there. Hello aspiring window com
composer. [cough and clears throat]
Are you the um combinatorics
guy who is going to study combinatorics?
Hi. Um so close that. So okay so close
that show in browser. So we're going to
write that. Okay. So this is for you
emac coders and play at 1.5 speed. And
if you are here say hi. Okay let's begin
coding. Let's not waste time. Let's
begin coding. So ping window shows all
my Emacs command course name and the
keystroke on the left. I'm using a voya
keyboard and I I'm using softly keys the
most efficient key binding for Emacs.
More efficient than vim or vi okay or
neoim. Okay. So let's start emac this
code pop it out. So what we want to
write uh move to parent. Okay. Um okay.
So define
uh define the name uh move
uh to parent
something like that. Okay. So
um it's key that's a key. Okay. So that
that that that. So today's date created
version number give today's date and
let's just write it. So the first thing
you want to do you want to so in the add
right now we are looking at what's
called diode. Uh let's delete all the
backup. Let's let's not worry about
that. Okay. Everything is good.
Uh that's me. Hello GCS. Uh yes that's
me also. Bookshot. Yeah I know. Fukensha
we are debating about
uh kind of the ethics of software um
license you know that you know a lot
fans they are in you know they they like
open source or free software foundation
anyway that's that topic I talked about
a thousand times especially in the early
years so I talked about like one hour of
a thousand times so anyway and basically
I think open source and free software
foundation free. Okay, let me let me do
one one minute summary of my view. Okay,
Richard Stman, Richard Rich Richard
Stoman, the guy who created Emacs, he
started free software foundation back in
1980s as a legal organization because in
his opinion he has a ideology. He
believes that software whenever whenever
you write software the source code like
what we are writing today it must be
shared okay it must be it's ethical if
you do not share your source code he
consider you to be a bad person in fact
to the degree that if you if you you
know if you don't share your source code
then you cannot make money you'll go
hunger your family will not be able to
survive He still says you still need to
share so uh the source code. Okay.
Anyway, that's Richard Stman. So in
1980s he began the free software
foundation and with it is the uh is the
so-called GPL general public license
which is a license that that legally
says that you know whatever software you
write you cannot hide the source code.
You must share the source code. if you
use you know whatever uh software he
wrote. So anyway, then in 19 in 1997
about that there Eric Raymond Eric
Raymond known as ESR and another guy I
think Bruce Pin and maybe another guy
they started a open-source
foundation. Okay, which is a spin off or
split off splender group from the free
software foundation because back then
they they they believe that Richard
Storman his moral you know ethical
stance is too strong that the commercial
software world uh don't like that you
know have a problem. So they begin they
they started the thought let's remove
the ethical elements let's remove the
moral elements all we ask is that
software must come with a source code
but let's not focus on about
whether that you know this is ethical
you know which is kind of communist
ideology okay so free software
foundation of Richard Stman is
essentially a communist
uh communist
uh ideology because you must share
everything. You cannot keep it to
yourself, you know, you must share. So
anyway, then then the open source
foundation group people came up. They
they are they are not that good. Okay,
they are kind of like a thief, you know.
They stole the idea and and anyway, so
this is 1997. [snorts]
Uh, and the Eric Raymond, the guy, one
of the guy who found it found found it
is kind of a a very uh [ __ ] Okay,
he's a [ __ ] Aggressive racist
[ __ ]
ESR. His name is uh Eric Raymond Raymond
or something. Okay, you can ESR. You can
look up ESR and Richard Stman. IMS. You
look up, you'll see their name. they are
very popular but today both both of them
are little known by today's generation
zoomers okay but they they founded you
know the open source you know Richard
Stman founded the free software
foundation and in in 1997 the open
source foundation was created and they
are at warman
do not like the open source people they
he think they are [ __ ] basically
okay so they are at war today people
don't know the the you guys younger
people open source idiots. Okay, so
that's back then and then fast forward
to today after 20 years of open-source
movement or after 30 years of free
software foundation movement
both of them pretty much died today. You
know the Richard Stman free software
foundation basically died nobody know
who the [ __ ] he is. Okay. And he became
this he you know he's became this guru
you know kind of fat and uh unckempt and
uh you know picking his feet in public
and eat it you know [clears throat] not
not a good you know leader quality. He
became that sort and he got all sort of
problems you know he's not doing um that
he he you know in my opinion he's not um
contributing to society
that much even for contributing to his
own free software foundation he became
kind of a damaging figure you know
Richard Stman that's on one hand and
today nobody knows Because the entire
open source has been taken over by the
deep state. What does that mean? Deep
state. Deep state means kind of uh
certain group of people they want to do
war. They are associated tightly with
the military complex you know making
missiles. You know you know let's not
get too far into that. Okay. So we have
Ukraine war 3 years ago or four and then
there's another let's not mention the
name going pretty bad and before that
there's Afghanistan, Iraq and all that
you know they and right now currently
Trump is doing Venezuela. Okay. So this
this people is so-called deep state in
USA. They they do wars.
What for? Well, so they become richer,
richer and richer and we American
citizens become poor and poor as most of
you know the state of USA today. Okay.
So open source got taken over by deep
state
you know deep state is not just you know
they they have like massive branches
universities you know like nonprofit
organizations so taken over by Google
Facebook uh by
you know by and then Microsoft you know
so today open source is basically 99.9
entirely funded by this commercial
greedy organizations such as Google and
Facebook, they are very greedy. They
have 1,000 lawyers. They have have 1,000
patents, okay? And their software is
proprietary, you know, like some of it
is like open source, but the real Google
Chrome browser is proprietary. Okay? You
idiots. Yeah. Go use Google Chrome.
What's a Chromium, you know? Oh, that I
choose to use the open source one when
it comes to, you know, VS Code. Oh, I
use VS Code Vinium because that one is
open source. You know, these kind of
idiots. That's you guys brainwashed. You
know, you don't know a thing. So anyway,
the open source movement has been
basically to taken over by the deep
state, fully funded by the deep state,
fully [snorts]
controlled in every way by the deep
state. like the GitHub you use, you
know, you love the open source, you
know, entire repository is bought by
Microsoft
[laughter]
and the the the open source idiots. Oh
god, uh GitHub got bought by open
source. let's switch to the you know git
fox or whatever you know like every few
years they do that you know that before
that there's an example of the star
office you know the open source
uh word processor then it became switch
you know it became something and before
that there is also the story of um
of
what what so many you know like uh all
the database the MySQL you know open
source opensource
Then it got bought by Oracle then oh no
that no let's let's switch you know
let's use uh what's the other you know
like Miranda database whatever and this
happens you know this happens all the
time because if you are today you know
like if you are a big open-source
fanatic you know everything you do must
be open source you know you are ethical
but tomorrow Microsoft comes to your
door hey you know we got this million
dollars. We don't have much use of it.
Would you like, you know, we give it a
million dollars to you and you sell us
your fantastic open source? We'll keep
it open source. And you're going to say,
"Oh, yeah. Yes. Yes. [laughter]
[gasps]
And uh you you you become a you sell
out. That happens to everyone
essentially. Money. Okay. like every
[ __ ] including you know uh then few
years ago the Linux Linux tovert he got
bought out you know so how is open
source sport uh being taken over you
know look at uh code of conduct
do you accept
that men are men and women are the same
do you accept that men can get pregnant.
Do you accept
that we are going to put a tampon in
men's bathroom?
Okay, you have a choice. If you say no,
you you know you'll be cancelled. That's
code of conduct which today is in every
software any every major you know known
open source software code of conduct.
Okay. Is this code of conduct you know
uh created by Richard Stman? No. Is it
created by Eric Raymond the guy who
started open source? No. In fact they
are against it.
Okay. But they have no choice. They have
no say.
You [ __ ] idiots. You you know younger
generation idiots. Okay. Then I know
what you're saying. I know what you're
thinking because you are thinking open
source. we must be open source. You
know, there are so many advantages. You
know, if a corporation dies, the source
still there so we can fork it and blah
blah blah. But the reality is look at
what's going on the society we live in.
You become puny nothing. You know, you
you you survive by becoming a none. You
go to online social network, you know,
you you are a none. You don't dare to to
have a name, you know. Then you post
memes. You you chirp a little opinion
about how things should be open source.
That that's the state you are in. You
have no idea what's going on. Okay. So
open source been taken over 100% funded
by you know the um big greedy
10,000 lawyers corporations and
proprietary and 10,000 patents and
whatever trademarks. Okay, including
Firefox,
like you guys don't know a thing. In
Firefox, you know, they give their money
to Antifa,
you know, the Black Live Matters burning
buildings across USA major cities
that burned alive many people. Uh
remember, you don't you probably don't.
Um but anyway so open source being taken
over and if you are a coder there's
nothing you can do if you are oh you
know you know you decided not to work
for Google whatever you try to make a
living by yourself you can't because
Google they hire you know they have
minions or these coders who take money
from Google every month a lot you know
like if you work in Silicon Valley here
every month you got like more than
10,000 10,000 minimum if you are
software engineer but you but you accept
men can get pregnant you cannot say
anything to that then at night you turn
out open source code you tell everyone
you pretend like you pretend open source
is good thing you take the money from
Google proprietary you know nothing you
can do and you at night you turn out
open source code oh I code this for
hobby puppy, look at my uh GitHub or
whatever. You know, these scums, they
don't even know it. So if you are fired
from Google, you know, if you dare to
say no, men cannot get pregnant, what a
[ __ ] idiot idiot idiocies that you
get cancelled and you cannot make money
because whatever you write, there's
already a million open source ones and
nobody like you people like whenever you
have a closed source, you you refuse to
use it like you don't want it, you know,
because you think, oh, that's not open
source. No, no.
So,
so in summary, so what you know what,
so, so, so Richard Sman his idea, you
know, his kind of communist communist
idea ideology of about the software
about sharing or code
is not necessarily a bad one. Okay?
Because before Richard Stman was born,
we share software. We, you know,
typically people, nerds, scientists, we
just share our code. We share our code
without like I did I shared my code in
the 1990s written in Wuam language. You
know this code, you know, feel feel free
to use it. Uh, by the way, I don't have
any legal responsibilities if it doesn't
work, but otherwise feel free to use it.
That was my license
back in the back in the 90s. Okay. And
lots of others.
You don't need like oh you need a
license like you know it's so funny you
know in the past 20 years you have
license wars MIT license artistic
artistic license Apache license uh GPL 2
GPL3. Which one is better? Let's argue.
Endless argument. you know these [ __ ]
idiots [laughter]
then then okay so Richard Sman his ideal
ideology of of kind of communist
ideology on software to share you must
share
is one of the opinion it's not too bad
okay but it's not freedom it's not
freedom
Richard Sman by the way also abused the
word free because his free software
foundation. When he says free software,
what he means is that software according
to his ideology,
it does not mean the software is free
like you can give it to me free. Nor
does it mean freedom.
Okay? Because freedom means I can do
whatever with whatever I want with my
software. I have the freedom to release
it as open source or not. It it is my
freedom and you have the freedom
to to choose what software you want to
use. You know you know if this is does
not come with so uh source code you have
the freedom to not use it. You have the
freedom to use only software that's
come with source code if you want if you
want it that way. Okay. So, so in my
opinion, Richard Stman's um ideology
is not necessarily good, nor is it
necessarily bad. It's just like, you
know, one of the one of the one of the
many
freedom opinions in society. Okay, you
if you know, you can believe whichever
you want.
Uh and Richard Sman is not a bad person.
He's relatively pretty much an honest
guy and not too greedy guy. Okay.
So, but anyway, he started this ideology
and uh then it got taken over by the
open-source
people. Then they got taken over by the
deep state
and uh the consequence is pretty bad
today. Pretty bad. like you you you you
power in your little hole and no power
to do anything you know deep state
control everything.
So that's one thing. The other thing is
that so what what should be better in my
opinion? What is better? Okay.
If you have a software that does not
have the source code, then how can I
trust it? That's your question, right?
How do I know? You know, like I sell you
my software, but my it's closed source.
You know, you pay me $100, you get it,
and I don't give you the source code.
How do you know my software is not
looking under your skirts? You know, how
do you know? Here's the answer. You
know, in human animal society
what do you do with thieves? Thieves or
robbers? You cut their hands off
then you will not have thieves.
Okay. So Google, are you going to like
sneiff, you know, [snorts] like have
back door or whatever go to jail?
We have law in America. America is a
country by law.
Do you guys understand? You go to jail.
You don't scam a million dollars or do
whatever like today the Google,
Facebook, you know, Mark Zuckerberg and
whatever. They can, you know, they they
can they can do almost anything they
want.
Okay, that that is that is my story. So
that is my opinion. So basically law and
older
we don't need open source. Most people
cannot you know they are not coders. You
also you have to think about other
people not just yourself. You are a
coder so I can I can use Linux. I can do
DNS. So I don't have you know I don't
have I you know I don't see the scams or
whatever. So why don't you use Linux
these [ __ ]
Okay,
most people are not coders.
It's not just about you. So you think
about you know the society you want law
and order
pe people can buy software or or free
you know without source code most people
don't read it can't unable to understand
it to make any use of it anyway
but if there's a crime if they did
something nasty in their software you
know like like stealing your your
password or or or sharing your bedroom
photos or your privacy whatever they go
to chair people will know
okay it's not like nobody can find out
we have lots of people you know like you
guys security security you know you are
studying security or whatever you know
cyber security you know it becomes a
profession by itself today because it's
so bad you plug in a USB and you don't
know what you know there's no the USB
just you plug in a virus That's all the
situation. That's what happened. That's
what you guys get.
Like you have no power. There's nothing
you can do.
And then then there's today's crypto
scams all over. Like you go down on on
Twitter like every account is crypto
scam.
Why does that happen? Because in part
because you open source [ __ ]
You want force like you you you have
like like you think you have you know
you by mob force you force these
corporations to release open source you
know all code must be open source
instead they went to the cloud that's
another reason cloud become popular you
know instead of storing your information
in your computer they store it on their
computer and they call it cloud
computing cloud service all of a sudden
you know that took off.
Why? Like for example, Twitter,
why can't I, you know, everything I
browse, why why is it on my, you know,
all the post I posted, why is it on not
on my disk? They can easily do that.
But so many way but you just don't never
you don't see it. You you can't you you
don't get your own data. You know few
years ago they have like project going
to release release Twitter but actually
if you actually download that they give
you [ __ ] you know like like cryptic
complex like you cannot view your own
post things like that similarly today
for uh Gmail
you know like 10 years ago
there's you know still some good people
at Google's that created a project you
can download your own email or whatever
today it's like all rotten you know it's
like it be got worse and worse okay
um
so where where was I so I was saying so
so the situation is pretty bad and in
software that's in in large part because
of the open source [ __ ]
okay let let me read the comments and I
think that's it for today we're not
going to code this
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, because coding is boring. Okay, so
put this back. Let me just read a
comment. And today is going to be a
independent complete rant on the
opensource [ __ ] because this comes
up every
like all all the time. I already talked
about it a thousand times.
So let me address all your questions,
all your you know opinions. You think
I'm incorrect? Post it now. Let me
address them. Okay.
Someone mistakenly referred to Richard
Stoman as father of open source. And
Richard Sman replied, "If I'm father of
open source, it's created from
artificial incimination using stolen
sperm." Yeah.
Um yeah, that he said that. And there's
another video that someone you know
invited him to speak and the introducer
you know the guy introducing Richard
Stman in the beginning say something
about thank you so much Richard Stman
for your contribution to open source
you know and then Richard Sman got very
angry
[laughter]
you know it's a video I I probably have
it on my website actually I collect ed
some of them. So, kali.info info no s in
HTTP okay because Google today's browser
they become so nasty let me let me let
me mention this another thing okay they
become so nasty like if you go to your
settings there is one option
do you want automatic https
okay I demonstrated this before this
year okay so uh where is the https Okay.
Privacy and security. Um,
passwords, whatever.
Uh, payment methods, address, history,
permissions, fire collection, use
security,
HTTPS only mode. Okay. They give you a
option don't enable HTTPSON mode.
So however starting about three month
ago they ignore this
they ignored this this personal
preference an explic explicit setting
they ignore it they going to add s
anyway this deep scums scum and scams
like you people don't know and and by
this so they basically Google you know
Firefox they basically now
kind of uh semi-inforce the HTTPS. So,
but that means they instantaneously
censor 20 million websites
because I checked with Google you know I
also have it on my website this article
I talked about this many times but
anyway so there are 20 million website
that doesn't have https but basically
they are instantaneously censored
who are these website these are
typically old website they talk about
things like the The history of internet,
you know, in the 1990s, in the year
2000s
and even in year 2010s,
okay, all this website history, they
talk about things happening at those
times. They are going
instantaneously wiped out by this by
these, you know, HTTPS
scums.
You know, in theory, the Google and you
guys idiots who got brainwashed is that,
oh yeah, we should have HTTPS because
it's safer. I want my data encrypted.
[laughter]
You want your data encrypted. Did you
know, do you use a phone? Every single
thing you do, every photo you take
is, you know, Apple and Google are
sniffing it. What the [ __ ] with your
encryption? You know, like every do you
use a phone? Everything every every
movement where you are, where you slept,
on what date, what time, what time you
spending where and whatever photos you
take taken is known
by Google and Apple.
Okay. And but then you care about oh but
I don't want my you know which website I
visit uh to be known by others because
they are hackers
[ __ ] idiots. Every website you visit
no is known by Google and Apple. Okay.
every
and then and then
and you know this HTTPS you know
originally it it is meant for if you are
doing credit card if you go to Amazon do
some shopping then you need HTTPS
because otherwise the credit card
information is easily um sniffed by
hackers potential hackers. Okay. So if
you do if you you know post your credit
card you know to some website then you
need that but otherwise if you just want
songs
but but you guys okay you today's
generation you know the like those who
follow me these idiots tech nerds idiots
they they got brainwashed you know they
they they don't know what is what
uh so they when they see this they you
know when they see when I tell claim the
fact that
Firefox and Google blatantly ignore an
explicit explicit setting.
Their reaction is like, "Oh, well that's
bad and that's interesting, but but but
you need to get your website to HTTPS."
they still, you know, they they like
their brain is already
twisted, you know, they they don't know
what they doing.
Um, so that's a bad situation. So that's
one of the example, one one of of the
hundreds of example. Um,
so let's look up, you know. So I have
actually documentation of Google crimes.
So you can look
uh the documentation of all the things
happened. You know I started this only
starting around 200 yeah 2010. So you
can kind of see all the history
but
remember Google with this HTTPS enforced
basically
insta censor 20 million websites.
It's already bad enough because today
you know the internet in the past 20
years ago is supposed to be so many
websites you visit you know but today
you like you you you your whole life is
just 10 websites
you you don't know what other website
your whole life is just Twitter Facebook
Google you know like YouTube and and few
other you know tube or you know like 20
20 websites you [ __ ] idiots.
>> [sighs]
>> Okay, I think that's that's about it.
So, let me answer the questions.
[laughter]
Oh my god, $100. Thank you so much.
Uh, thank you so much. Okay, so let me
see if there's any questions and that's
it.
>> [sighs]
>> So, by the way, Richard Stman has been
struggling with cancer. Yes. Oh, yeah.
So, let that reminds me. I wanted to
show some Richard Stman um pages I have.
So, anyway, Google crimes index. So,
that's worth going through. Okay. So,
let me post to today's talk show. Uh
let's not write the pro uh let's not
write code that. So let's delete um
so Google crimes. So when you have time
you can feel free to check this out you
know group so many let me mention one
one more okay anti ad block yeah so let
me mention one more the deep state okay
the meaning of deep state what the
[ __ ] scam they are doing some of them
are actually legal like for example
Google has been sued for the Google APM
scam you know APM is a technology like
like new web you know new HTML
supposedly to make your web your website
faster but in fact it's a plot to ent
trap all publishers so every publishing
must be done via Google like you guys
don't know you know and this is like
public this this Google has been sued
for this so you can read the details
okay Google am lawsuit okay and lot and
lots of but let me and sabotage Firefox
and in fact actually Google sponsor
Firefox Firefox is alive today
because of Google because Google is
secret secret Google doesn't want
Firefox to die okay like you guys don't
know because if Firefox dies then Google
become oh monopoly
then then you know so Google wants
Firefox to be alive so they they kind of
fund Firefox okay and Firefox give money
to Antifa so let me mention another you
know one one thing I want to mention uh
and Google censorship white couples, you
know, that's all news. So um
so many okay so many these these [ __ ]
crimes like but we don't know like when
it happens oh it's big news but but by
tomorrow you forgot
but because the open source idiots the
open source
[ __ ] now if you are you know not
fanatic that you are fine but those
fanatics you know they they
you can't blame them because they are
young you know they don't know a [ __ ]
Just like I was young 30 years ago back
in 19 in year 2000 I was a big fanatic
for Richard Storman
and Free Software Foundation. You can
see you you know I can show you my
articles. I talked about this in my live
stream before. So let's not do that.
So but anyway so I want to just show you
one thing. Okay. Uh it's about YouTube.
Um,
you know, Google removed the likes and
dislikes on YouTube. Like it became
unpublic. That's a big thing. It's um
where is it? Let's search
YouTube. Remove sort video. That's
another thing. They they they restored
it back. And here Google YouTube hide
dislike 2021. Why did they do that?
Because whenever the US USA government
such as Ben,
you know, when they post, you know, when
they have a video, then you got a
million dislikes.
You know, you got you got 10 likes but
the million dislike for any or for this
for example for this her gun you know
like whenever she talks like a million
dislike the [ __ ] Google
people can see we got eyes we can see we
don't want your crimes
but then to Google decide oh that looks
bad oh let's hide let's hide the dislike
[laughter]
to to this day This is still the
situation. You know, imagine the like
and dislike. Do you know the history of
the like and dislike it? It began by
Facebook scum. That's another story. You
know, it's a psychological control. So
you you want your post to be liked. So
every so so you got glued to social
networks. You know, you post you see
someone like it. Oh, who who is the who
is the guy who liked my stuff? Oh god.
Then you started then it started to
change your behavior because you started
to write in a way you get more likes.
You forgot about your brain.
Okay, that's a psychological
specifically psych psychological control
created by Mark Zuckerberg of the
Facebook scum. then it spread to all
other websites, YouTube, Reddit, Hacker
News or whatever, you know, because that
that gets people glued to your site. You
got more traffic, you got more money,
you [ __ ] zoomers
idiots. Okay. Then so you got likes you
know then the way they say it is like
you know you can so you can you know if
you are a YouTube creator you can see
how many you know you can see how many
people like your stuff or maybe they
don't like it so you can adjust you can
you can make more money you know it's
also good and happy but then but then
[laughter] this happened oh we decided
to hide the like and they have good
reason you know they they tell you why
you Google's official Google official
announcement on removing dislike.
Why? Why are we decided to remove it?
You look at this pretty boys [ __ ] face.
Pretty white face. Pretty boys. You know
they go to on stage Google IO conference
yearly. You know they tell you good
things. We going to save Africa. Our
goal at Google is to save Africa and
help women. You know this [ __ ] face.
Why they tell you why they they decided
to remove dislike? Oh, because that way
we can help women and children in
Africa.
[ __ ] them. And to this day it still
happens. But the but you guys, you know
the you guys who or those who live on
Twitter or whatever like you don't know
a thing. You you happy you go on, you
know, go on with your lives, you know,
being a non and all that.
Okay, that's about Google. Okay, so now
let's go search um so copy that.
Okay, now let's go search for Richard
Strowman.
Uh I got lots of articles. Okay, so on
Richard Strowman. So Richard Stman abuse
of the word freedom.
You see
his idea of freedom you know his use of
the word freedom is his ideology of
freedom not the common people's freedom
about software freedom is what I can do
whatever I want as long as I don't [ __ ]
you up that's freedom that's free trade
okay his idea of freedom is that you
must do something to your software like
share it you cannot like own
[ __ ] Richard Stman. But overall, he's
not, you know, he's not a too bad guy.
Okay, so but anyway, so let's go to uh
one of the article on Richard Stoman.
Uh so
you know there's fun, you know, there's
fun things, there's bad things. Okay.
So, let's for example this Richard
Stoman when he's younger. Uh, and I have
a collection of his uh Emacs fun. Uh,
okay. So, let's go to So, let's go to
Emacs, my Emacs homepage.
Then let's go to um Emac this tutorial
packages miscellaneous
uh technical essays miscellaneous index
there.
Emac controversy index. Open that.
Okay. Emac controversy index. Open that.
There it is. Okay. Richard Strowman got
cancer 2023. Okay. he got, you know,
cancer. So,
uh, and, uh, history of Le Richard Stman
stole Emac source code from James
Gosling. That's kind of controversial,
but to some degree that's true, but but
I mean, it's controversial. It's it's,
you know, there's no I don't think
there's a correct answer. It's just
history. Okay. Um so go back to
controversies.
Richard Sman resigned from free software
foundation. Why? Because he got forced.
He got forced by the social justice
warriors deep state [ __ ] faces. Okay.
And you guys don't dare to say a thing.
You know you open source fanatics don't
dare to say a thing. You you you you can
all you can do is remain quiet and and
but I said something here. I collected
all the [ __ ] faces, you know, here.
Okay. This women, this [ __ ] women,
Salam G, she kind of began
Richard Stman got kicked out from his
own foundation, free software foundation
2019.
Then then Richard Stman at Microsoft,
that's you know then then uh the Okay.
So this um yeah anyway so here's a
collection of the
articles about Richard Sman. Okay. So
overall I don't think he's a bad person
in society but however his his movement
which got
you know taken over by open source which
got taken over by the deep state and and
h has a huge negative consequence in
society.
Okay that's it. So, let's see. Uh, any
more questions? I'm going to answer that
and that's it.
HTTPS is more secure. Yes, of course it
is. Here's a bribe for you not to cause
false people idiots [laughter]
for at least a week. Okay.
It's not dollars cuz it's Indian rupees.
I'm not that rich yet. Uh, sorry to
disappoint you. Okay. Uh oh [ __ ] Indian
rupees. Oh [ __ ] I thought it's pounds.
[ __ ]
Okay. So uh Ha, I hope you're having a
good day. Uh Dosamer Bellum
long time no see I think ever speak
about the Fedverse and all the
alternative copycat platforms
alternative Reddit or alternative
Twitter. Yeah, of course I know that.
But that doesn't work. That's, you know,
that's one of the like idiotic things
the nerds do, you know, like we're gonna
start an open source, you know, like
little project here like, oh, like you
you you can see it over the past 20
years, okay? There's lots of it come and
go like they they amount to nothing.
They they you know, these nerds, they
think they're going to create a like
they they they you know, they they don't
know society. They don't know how
society works. They are unable to talk
you know they they cannot function
socially you know so what they but they
can do what they can do is they know
code so they their idea of fixing
society is to create like these projects
you know like a new new browser new open
source browser or new MySQL database or
new whatever open you know that's what
they do but they don't understand how
society works that is the reason we got
into this bad state. Okay, this little
project, you know, that
doesn't, you know, worth a flying fart.
There's no impact to society except just
you little nerds, you know, like 10 of
them. 10 of you like we're going to do
this Emacs, you know,
that's that's what happens.
So, yeah. So those you know if you want
to fix society
you gota you you you know it's you know
it's not about technology
okay technology like you you are
thinking you know technology war you you
you you get technological escalation you
got honeyotss you got spam bots you know
you you got like filters you got basian
filters you got like oh you know this
trick or DNS rewrite or whatever ever
you can do. But on the other hand, you
got they got spam farm. they got, you
know, um, you know, you what you get in
into is a technological escalation like
Rob versus cops
and uh um so what you should do if you
want to fix society
you need to fix human okay it's not
whatever technology you can do it's the
human
you want to get what whoever Google who
is, you know, who is doing nasty things.
You want to get them in jail,
okay? Not by diddling with your [ __ ]
software.
Okay. [ __ ] [ __ ] This turned out into
a rant and Okay, that's it for it. Bye,
guys.
Any more questions? Okay, one more
minute then I'm going to shut down.
Bye guys.
Let's see. Is there anything uh else? I
think that's it.
Bye.