Good morning, everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Xah Talk Show.
Today we're going to talk about Emacs
live coding, Emacs Lisp live coding.
Good morning, Alan. Good morning,
M Hester. And good morning, Alan
Prestige. So Alan says, "Prestige for
the elite keyboard warriors, the run of
flawless typing made by the mythical 72
open source contributors in the depth of
Google."
That's a
Let's say that's a verse. That's a new
verse. Okay, so we we are going to do a
Emacs live Emacs Lisp live coding. And
the task will be
This will be the task, okay?
Modify xah-html insert br tag. So it
inserts at the end of line and put
cursor to the end of next line. I'm
going to explain, okay? We are going to
modify that code, but in fact, let's
write it from scratch. I'm going to
explain why we need to modify it. I
mean, the some design issues, the design
issues of a command's behavior, okay?
But first of all, let's talk about the
background image Prestige Elite.
Now this is IBM Selectric ball. Now if
you don't know, if you are the
millennial generation, the new
generation,
the Pepsi generation. Well, Pepsi
generation is the is the um
boomer generation, I guess. Yeah.
Anyway, so
So this is IBM electric ball. Now that
that is a chapter, a big chapter in the
in the history of keyboards. Uh
um
typewriters and and keyboards, of
course. Type Typewriters is the father
of computer keyboards.
Now, this ball Now, IBM Selectric,
that's a model's name. That's a brand
name, okay, from IBM. Uh this is around
What year?
Uh let's see. Okay, so let me
let me say what year.
IBM Selectric, okay. The typewriter
looks like that. I mean, and this is the
most popular and the most beloved
typewriter, electric typewriter. And the
novelty The novel thing about this
invention is this ball.
You see, it got this ball. So, this the
the way this ball works is that it will
twist and
it will twist and tilt to the right
character and and hit.
So, this a video if if you just search
my
go to
search for Xah Lee IBM Selectric, you
will arrive at my page, okay? There are
quite a few pages online about this
typewriter.
So, you know, I collected some of the,
you know, interesting things. The Here
is an ad of the IBM Selectric.
And there's a video explaining the
mechanism. Okay, here's an ad.
That's how it works.
Okay, so and there are some other
people's videos and also explanation of
the mechanism, quite interesting and
very extremely well designed. So, that
is the background image. And now we
shall begin
Emacs coding.
Uh because I That's what you guys are
here for. Then after that, if we have
time, we go back to keyboards, the
fascinating topic of uh of keyboards,
okay? The keyboard history. So much
history and so much to do, so much, you
know, I'm going to toy your and maul
your hands to death on writing these
pages.
There are in fact so many more to write.
I I haven't got time to do it yet. So,
my life is jumping around Emacs, Emacs
Lisp, JavaScript, keyboards,
and mostly these few topics in the past
month. Okay, now let's begin the Emacs
Lisp coding.
So, what I want to do, you see, so what
I want to do is sometimes you have HTML,
right? Okay, so on the right window is
the pink window, you can see all my
commands,
call the command names and the key
keystrokes I'm using. So, as I move
closer, you can see or as I delete
character or if I undo, they will all
show up on the right pink window.
So, if you don't know what I'm doing,
you can look it up and chances are the
source code you'll find the source code
on my website. Okay, so what we so
Here's what we are going to do.
Sometimes
sometimes when you write HTML,
uh you know, technical documentation or
tutorial, sometimes you want, you know,
there's paragraph, right? You can
make a paragraph.
You know, that's the P tag for the
paragraph. Magnify.
But sometimes you don't want the P tag.
Sometimes you actually want a break, BR,
okay? So, let me show you what's the
difference, okay? Hold on a second.
Undo. Copy the whole thing. Undo, undo,
undo, undo, undo, undo, undo. So, we are
reverting back to like that previously.
Now paste. Now here is the new version.
Now, let's show in browser.
See what's the difference.
You know, because I am using CSS, so
they kind of, you know, So, here's the
difference. So, here are two paragraphs.
Okay, let's magnify.
Uh okay, I I I want the the
Okay, so, here here are two paragraphs,
and here is one single paragraph with
the uh break
in between. So, it's more more compact.
Sometimes you do want that. You don't
want, you know, you don't want
everything to be a paragraph.
And sometimes, okay, sometimes if you
have an address, okay? My home address.
I mean, let me talk about and what I'm
doing is telling you the utility of the
BR tag.
The utility of the BR tag
So, my address address is
uh
Phantom Street.
Number one, okay? And uh the city, let's
say San Francisco.
SF, San Francisco, California. And the
zip code is uh something uh 94
something.
333, okay?
So, if you have that, now, how do you
format that? Okay, so, one way if you
know, you make it a paragraph,
it does not look good. It looks like one
single line. That's no good.
The other way
is let's try it, okay? So, make a
paragraph, but you want a BR there. BR
BR. So, go back to browser, show in
browser. Now,
that's what you want.
Of course, there are there are other
ways. For example, you can make the
whole thing a list showing browser. You
see
Here Here is a list.
Uh that's not what you want. So, you
want the BR tag. So, BR tag that's the
use of the BR tag.
Now, so uh So, if I if we are given
Let's say if we are given this, we want
to add a BR. It's tedious. You You need
to move the cursor to the end of the
line and type BR, you know, type BR um
You know, uh uh
You know, you need to then copy it and
then then do it again. Then do it again.
Uh that's tedious. So, we are going to
write a command that do it one shot. We
can select the whole thing.
Uh wait.
We can select the whole thing and uh in
fact, I've written the command already.
So, let's call the command. Okay, show
the pink window. Let's call the command
insert
uh insert BR.
There. C-HTML insert BR BR tag. There it
is. Okay? Now, that is when you have a
selection.
Now, if you don't have a selection you
you need to move to the end of cursor
and call the command. Do it. Then move
to the end of the next line.
Call the command. Do it. And you know,
uh
Okay. So, I have this command written
already. So, let let's show the command
name.
So, describe function type the command
name and here it is. C-HTML insert BR
tag. And uh it's in this file C-HTML
mod. You can get on the Git
on my GitHub.
Uh and here's the source code.
Okay, so I've already written it. So,
let's copy the name, close it, back to
the talk show page, paste it here.
Make it a corner bracket.
Embrace it with corner brackets.
brackets and make it a list, okay? Then
remove that and show in browser and you
can see that is the command name and we
want to prettify it. So, code the
command, okay?
Back to Okay, so code the command, it
becomes the code tag. You see the code
tag there, code tag there. And go back
to browser, show it. So, it becomes red.
So, anyway,
so we are going to write the command.
So, this So, so
I already have the command. Uh but what
am I going to do, you know? Why Why
do we need to modify it? Okay, let me
explain. So,
so sometimes, you know, the reason is to
to make it even more efficient.
You know, that's a design issue. So, so
so for for example, sometimes my my
cursor is here.
You know,
like I you know, one way is to select
the whole thing and code the command and
and do BR. So, so there we have it,
right?
But the other way, sometimes you
um
the other way is you move to the end of
the line and code it and insert it,
okay? So, what what I want to do is when
the
So, to eliminate the need to move the
cursor to the end of the line. So, if my
cursor is here,
I code the command. Right now, if I code
it, it'll just insert it there. That's
not what I want. I want it to
automatically move to the end of the
line, insert it, okay? Insert it, then
move to the end of the next line, okay?
So, I can readily execute that command
again.
Then you'll move to the end of the next
line. So, you know, I just repeatedly
call this command several times
interactively.
Okay, so let's do that, okay? Let's
write from scratch, shall we?
Any questions and comments?
Alan
D Z D 0 X, I don't know what that is.
Okay, so let's let's code it. Okay, so
let's stop the video playing here.
Double check my video, check my audio,
check and my dog, check.
My friend's dog is here.
Uh okay, so let's write code it from
scratch, okay? Beginning, just open all
you have to do is open any buffer in
Emacs, okay? So
you can just open any empty buffer. So
but the way I do it, since I have HTML
set up, so I I do that. And there is our
new buffer, okay? D for defun, okay?
Expand to the uh
define function. So this is a template
for writing Emacs Lisp commands.
I'm using xah.
Elisp mode, so you can you can do that
you you can use that use that if you
want. So the command name will be xah uh
let's just say insert
br, okay? So wait.
Insert br, that's that's the command
name. Insert br, so doc string
insert a
HTML
br.
Uh I want the I want the slash, you
know? So what's the why do you what's
the difference between a slash or not?
The reason is that in XML or
XHTML, which is XML XML, you need that
slash backs you know, slash.
But in HTML, you don't need that.
Um but
Xah, are you Chinese? Si de, wo shi
Chinese. Si de, wo shi Zhongguo ren.
I'm Chinese blood.
I'm American citizen. Which version and
build of Emacs are you using? I am using
let's show you, okay?
Control you
meta X
version. You see, I'm using GNU Emacs
version 27.
Okay? Now, back to the code. Let's
finish writing the documentation. Insert
a HTML uh a HTML BR tag at end of line.
And
move cursor to the end of next
line. Okay, that's our documentation and
version today's date. That's my
convention to give it a version date.
So, let's begin to write it.
Okay, so first of all, move to the end
of cursor. That's easy. That's easy. Um
end of line. There it is. Let's see,
describe function. What does it this do?
End of line. Uh
Move point to end of current line.
That's what we want. Optional, we don't
need that, okay? Move in Move point to
the Move cursor to the end of line, then
insert BR.
So easy, so trivial and easy. So, insert
um BR tag,
then I want a backslash, okay?
Then
Is that done?
Basically, that's already done, okay?
So, eval the buffer eval last sex.
Go to the talk show page. Uh let's open
a new buffer. Let's go to the talk show
page.
Okay? So, we can test it out.
Okay, so
So, let's say, okay, let's test it out.
So, let's put the cursor here,
then call the command. What's the
command name? Insert BR. Okay, copy it.
So, let's try it.
Call it.
Insert BR.
Yes. Oh, you forgot to move that to the
next line. Okay, let's fix the code. Fix
the code.
Uh
then next line.
I think next line. Yeah, I think.
Yeah, there is a command next line, but
I'm not sure that's what we want. Okay,
describe function. Let's see what it
does.
So, let me explain uh
ex- excursion into uh
explaining Emacs Lisp intricacies.
You know, the the function that works on
a line,
there are many functions to do that.
Like, sometimes you want to move to the
beginning of line, sometimes to the end
of line, sometimes you want to move to
the previous line, sometimes you want to
move to the next line.
Sometimes you want to get the position
of the of the beginning of line or end
of line or
you know, so
there are quite a lot uh commands for
variations because what do you mean by
line? Because there are visual line and
there are uh physical line, for example.
For example, let me show you a example,
okay?
For example, here is a bunch of text,
right?
A bunch of text.
Now, you see
we have uh we have
we have one we have one two three four
five five lines.
But, you can you can uh join them into a
long line. Now,
so, this is one single physical line,
but however, when it's displayed,
this you see, here is the first line,
and here is the second line. You know,
this is you know, if you consider it a
visual line.
You know, so so so what do you mean by
end of line? End of physical line.
Mostly, that's what we want.
So, anyway, there are a lot variations.
Okay, let me explain it. So, go to my
Emacs tutorial.
Uh let's go to it.
Practical Emacs tutorial, practical
Emacs. Then,
uh we want to go to practical Emacs
Lisp. Okay, then you scroll down.
Let me explain the fine details about
commands or functions that works on
lines, okay? Uh then you have
Okay, you go down uh
somewhere here.
Editing commands basics, mark and
region, get buffer string, work on work
work with lines, this one.
So,
so in Emacs Lisp, there are lots of ways
to move by line or grab lines. Here are
some functions or variations that are
related to lines. It's somewhat
confusing if you are beginner, okay? So,
you have line beginning position, line
end position. You have move line
beginning of line, move end of line.
Then, you have line next line, previous
line, forward line, search forward,
search forward
the line end character, that also does
that. You know, that also does moving to
the next line. And you have line move
visual.
So,
so there are, you know, like uh lots of
ways to do one specific thing, but
however,
given a task, there usually is one
command that's the most suitable. For
example, if you want to um
get the line beginning position, then
you want to use this command, line
beginning position. You don't want to,
for example,
uh
you don't want to um
you don't want to move to the beginning
of the line and get the point. You know,
that's that's kind of uh that's less
efficient.
So, I've I explained some of the
differences on this page. So, anyway, so
back to the uh back to our code.
So, close that. Uh so, we
So, right now, so right now you see we
need to move to the next line. And I'm
not sure that's the right command.
You know, when when you code Emacs Lisp,
usually one thing I pay attention is
that whether the command is written
in in C or in Emacs Lisp. In this case,
the next line command is in written in
Emacs Lisp, we can see,
you know, it's defined in this simp
simple.el package.
So, usually I prefer functions that's
written in C. If it's written in C, you
know, you'll say here. Because when it's
written in C, then you know that command
is more fundamental. It's more core.
It's more essential. And also, that also
means that command is faster.
So, avoid
Well, you don't have to avoid it, but if
you really
uh
if you really
want very tight code code and efficient,
you
uh usually it's it's preferable to use
the C uh you know, the core function.
So, anyway,
so that's one thing to pay attention,
whether the command is written in C or
Lisp, okay? Now, the other more
important thing to pay attention is that
in Emacs Lisp,
almost every command is also
interactive. You know, every function is
also interactive. So, for example, you
will say, you see, next line is a
interactive
blah blah blah, okay? That means user
can call it to to move the cursor to ne-
next line. Of course, nobody does that.
I mean, if you want to move to the next
line, you just press down arrow, right?
But I But actually, you can actually
call this to do it. For example, let's
try it. So, let's say my cursor is here.
I want to move the cursor to the next
line. So, you call
uh you call eval-expression. Look at the
pink window. You see, you call
eval-expression, then you type the
expression, the Lisp expression.
So, we we say next line.
So, we do it. You see, it it you know,
it's like
you're calling the command to you you
you you are calling you are running a
Lisp code to do something in your
buffer.
So, that means so when when a function
is callable interactively, that function
is called interactive command. Okay, we
are digressing digressing so much. Is it
confusing yet?
Okay, so next line, what I want to find
out is if this is the command I want.
No, that's not the com- command I want.
For example, there is another one,
forward-line. Now I remember. Yeah, this
is the com- command I want. You see,
you see, in C-
it is mod, the the mod I'm using. When
it's green,
that means uh that means I think that
means it's written in C. So, let's call
describe-function on that.
forward-line. You see, there it is.
Forward line is an interactive building
function in C source code.
Now, I don't have the source code. I'm
on a Mac. I don't I didn't download, but
on on Linux, you can press enter and you
can look at the C source code. So,
anyway, forward line is the one I want.
You can read the describe function, uh
you know, when you if you want to, but I
know for sure this is what I want.
Uh so, forward line
So, that moves to the next line, uh and
it moves to the let's see.
Move N lines forward. Precisely, if
point is on line, I move to the start of
Uh yeah, it moves to the beginning of
next line. So, that is, you know, that's
what we want. Anyway, try it. Eval last
expression. Go back to HTML. Put the
cursor somewhere here.
Uh somewhere here, okay, and let's call
the command. Insert BR. Fantastic.
Okay, this is fantastic.
Call it again.
Fantastic. Now, let's let's um
do the do this over again, okay?
Let's say we have so many lines.
Call it. So, the cursor can be anywhere
anywhere, okay? Call it.
Fantastic. Call it. Fantastic. Call it.
Fantastic. Now, there is a command
called uh repeat.
Okay, uh let me what what is the
command? I remember the key, but not the
command name. So, the command is called
um
There. Repeat, okay? Let me show you.
Hold on a second.
So, in Emacs, there is a command called
re- called repeat. Let me show you,
okay? Let me just show you.
So, let's do this over again. Let's copy
it, paste it here.
So, call the command. Okay, It insert
the BR. Call it again. Call it again,
okay?
Now, it's tedious. Every time I have to
do MX enter, MX enter, MX enter. I want
I want it to be even more faster, okay?
So, we can do
you call repeat last command. You see?
You see the pink window, you know, I say
repeat.
So, now I just press one single key, T.
You see?
That is the beauty of this uh thing. And
And that is the reason, you know, when
we talk about designing of this command
behavior, insert BR, that's that's why I
want this.
So, actually So, that is done. That is
what uh
that is what we want to do. So, now we
can do clean up, you know, you know,
clean up meaning that I get the code,
put it in my HTML mod, but that's you
know, that's essentially uh oh oh
We're missing one behavior. You see?
Okay. Now, you see? Now, what what if I
want to select the whole thing and do
it, you know, add add it to every end of
line? So, we
we need to modify this command to do it.
So, let me read the um
Let me read the comments first, then we
quickly finish that. That'll be finished
in 2 minutes or 3.
And I have been talking for 26 minutes.
Fantastic.
So, which version Okay. So, uh Brent
Brenta cause Brenta cause says we'll
have to watch this in slow motion later,
okay?
Um
Is it possible to get a list of C
function available in Emac Lisp?
Not
I'm not sure there is a convenient way.
Uh but
I'm not aware of any convenient way to
do that.
Yeah. So, you can do that, but you have
to write a Emacs Lisp script, I think.
Uh okay, Gregor says, "What are pros
What are pros of learning Emacs Lisp?"
The pros of learning Emacs Lisp?
Okay, don't learn it. It's useless.
You know what you What language you want
to learn? You want to learn JavaScript.
JavaScript is the number one most
popular language. You want to learn
Java. You want to learn Go lang. You
want to learn Python. Python is the
number one most popular language. You
want to learn a language that will make
you money. You'll be rich. You'll live
comfortably. You'll have a Tesla car to
drive, you know. Haha. You spend 2 years
on those uh you'll be good. You'll be
good uh for food and housing and uh
and the prevention of suffering from
hunger.
Now, if you want to learn Emacs Lisp,
well, so what's the Emacs Lisp? You
know, it's useful. It's uh it's actually
the most useful text processing
language, especially interactively.
So, when should you learn Emacs Lisp? If
you are a Emacs fan, then learn Emacs
Lisp, okay?
Hello Moto.
Okay, I got a phone call. Um
I got a phone call. I I I I need to pick
up.
Hold on a second.
Uh Let me finish Let me finish, okay?
Hello Moto.
What's your opinion? I I I got to I got
to pick up the phone, okay? So, be right
back in 1 second in in 1 minute.
Google, come here.
So, I'm back and uh
I'm showing you my dog my friend's dog,
okay?
So, let's let me read the comments and
see what you guys are saying. Okay,
comments.
So, learn Emacs if you want.
Oh, yes. I forgot to put my on my
headphones. So, that's my friend's dog.
So, learn Emacs Lisp if you want to um
you know, if you are a Emacs Lisp user.
And Emacs Lisp is actually the best
language for text processing.
Uh but uh but it's a bit slow, you know,
it's like five times slower than slower
than Python, Ruby,
uh Pearl, JavaScript.
You know, but but it's actually the best
language for text processing.
Small-time text processing. We are not
talking about If you need to process,
you know, 1 million text documentations
like at Google, you know, then Emacs
Lisp is not good. But for a programmer,
you know, if you have a
if you need to, you know, interactive,
you know, if you are coding, you know,
if you need to refactor, if you need to
if you are a blogger, or if you are a
book writer, or novel writer, Emacs Lisp
is actually the best text processing
language. You can and you can make it,
you know, it's the most easy way
to write some text processing, you know,
some transformation of text.
Interactivity, that's the important
thing.
Because in Java, in Python, in
JavaScript, in PHP,
you can do that, but it's not
interactive. You know,
you know, but Emacs Lisp you can do you
can write them on the fly. You don't
have like I don't have to create or or
compile or things like that. You write
it you do it and if you don't like the
behavior, you change it right away.
So, the
in that regard, Emacs Lisp is
worth learning.
Uh but not for bread, okay?
You you if you are a Emacs Lisp expert,
let's say you are the world's number one
expert in Emacs Lisp,
you will not get a dime. You know, you
will get a few dimes like me.
No job.
Uh so, what's your opinion on
uh
keep uh
case versus
uh what's keep up keep up case versus
snail case versus camel case versus
function names in different programming
languages. Thanks Thanks insert BR
versus insert BR versus insert BR. Oh.
Well, uh on that topic, that's a
digression. I have an article on on
that, of course. You just search for
Xah Lee
uh camel case versus
snake
case, okay?
Google.
Actually, not Google. DuckDuckGo. So,
you'll find my article and I talked
about this
in one of my previous uh talk show. So,
I have read
all
articles on this issue online because
I'm obsessed about these little details
of programming
uh programming conventions, idioms,
uh things like that.
Uh in summary,
in summary, so which one is better?
Camel case or snake case or some other?
In summary,
there's no definitive scientific
um
There's no definite
It's
They are all basically they are the
same, okay? There's no definitive
uh
say or prove which one is better. They
are quite They are a couple scientific
articles on this issue, but they are
kind of inconclusive. You know, you go
read my article.
And I have my own opinions, of course.
But anyway, it's not important.
My opinion is that, you know, I am I'm
obsessed I'm obsessed about this issue.
So, I always try to find, you know,
which one is the best.
Of all reasons, of all um thinking and
philosophy,
there's no ac- you know, this issue is
there's no one way that's best, okay?
You can You can just go read the
article.
Um
Okay, so that's about it. So, let's
finish this uh code and that let's
that'll be it, okay? Now, we want to add
a behavior so that if there's a
selection, it
uh does it to the whole selection. Okay,
so that's easy.
Add a if statement. If uh use region P
use region P Okay, that means if there's
a text selection, then do something
something. If there's no text selection,
then do what we did here, okay? Copy it.
Okay? So, what to do if there's a text
selection? If there's a text selection,
then um
let's say let's make two variables,
position one, position two.
And position one will be
uh
region beginning. Okay, that's the
beginning position of the region text
selection, okay?
And set P2 region end. Okay, that's the
end position of the selection. And what
you want to do is you want to go to uh
that you want to um
narrow to region, okay?
P1 and P2. And whenever you call narrow
to region in this code, you usually want
uh save restriction, okay? If you don't
know what that is that is, look up
describe function. Uh you know, call
describe function to look up. So, narrow
to region, then go to go to char point
min. Go to the beginning of the region,
then
while
uh then
then while, okay? Uh
search forward.
Okay, search forward for end of line
character.
Found.
Nil, no error, true. Okay, search
forward.
Okay, then, once you found it, you want
to replace match, okay? You want to
replace match by
Okay, replace match by that.
By a new line and a break.
Actually, break first, then new line,
okay? Then, option fixed case, we don't
care. Fixed case, yeah.
Okay.
Pretty file the code, shrink it a little
bit. That's it.
So,
shrink it.
So, if there's a region, then do this,
okay?
That's it.
Okay, let's just eval the buffer. Let's
try it. So, let's um
Oh, wait.
Okay, so here, we select the region.
Okay, call it insert BR. Fantastic, it's
done.
So, now it's done, let's copy the code,
delete the file, paste the code, okay,
and show show in browser. But, before
that, we
remove the Okay, show in browser.
That's our code.
And that's it for today. Thank you,
guys, for watching, and let's
syntax color the whole thing.
Go back to browser, refresh. So, syntax
coloring, fantastic. That's from x html
mode.
You can use it. It's on my GitHub.
Okay, so if you like my stuff, go to my
Xah Lee
uh Practical Emacs Tutorial. Of course,
you know how to find it.
Pract- Practical Emac Lisp and buy my
tutorial.
Support me.
And that's it for today today, okay?
Uh I'm going to read the comments and
let let's be short. 39 minutes, okay?
Okay, there's a question. Is it better
to write an Emac Lisp function if a
keyboard macro can do the same?
Not necessarily, okay?
Now, let me explain about keyboard
macro. If you don't know keyboard macro,
okay? You go to um
Okay, let me explain keyboard macro.
I I did a video on keyboard macro
before. That's long ago. So, you go to
Emacs tutorial.
You go to uh Emacs tutorial. Magnify.
Magnify. Uh search for macro.
Okay?
Uh near the bottom. Emacs efficiency.
Keyboard macro. Keyboard macro lets you
record keystrokes and and uh
run them.
Okay, so
So, the question is whether if you can
do something in keyboard macro, is do
you need Is it worthwhile? Is it better
to write a
E- Lisp function? Uh no. Okay. So, if
you can do something in keyboard macro,
just use keyboard macro because keyboard
macro is actually much simpler. You
know, you don't have to know Lisp.
You can just do it.
And in many cases, keyboard macro You
know, it just it will do the job, okay?
You don't need
You don't need to write Emac Lisp. Emac
Lisp is actually much more faster and
allows
uh uh more detailed control.
Other than that, I mean, if you can do
something with keyboard macro, then just
just use keyboard macros, okay?
Unless you want
if you need to do it 1,000, 1 million
times, then you need, you know, then you
want for efficiency reasons, you you
write the Emacs Lisp code.
Okay, that's uh that's about it, okay?
Actually, I I have a
I answered that question
here somewhere. So, you know, go read
this page, okay? Keyboard macro.
Yeah, I tell you how and I tell you why.
How to record a sequence of keystrokes,
most useful keyboard macro commands,
uh save keyboard macro, and keyboard
macro demo. There it is, my video.
And um
There is an article or somewhere here.
There are more examples here where I
explain
I believe I explain keyboard macro
versus Emacs Lisp. In fact, there are
certain instances, there are some cases
where
it's trivial to do a keyboard macro, but
actually it would be
fairly
complex to write uh the
uh Emacs Lisp code.
Okay, that that's that's it. Uh let's
see next question.
Why Emacs is my favorite editor?
Greetings, Sergio Ser- Sergio.
Uh
What is your secret of having so much
knowledge? How do you keep up with so
much information?
There there's no secret, okay?
That's what they say.
You know, I remember there's a movie
uh a they uh
um a described a uh,
British guy in Saudi
Arabia, you know, back in 1960s or
earlier, 1930s, I forgot.
What's his name? The British guy, a
famous British guy who lived in Saudi
Arabia and went through some war. And he
kind of led the Saudi Arabia people to
do something.
What's What's the guy's name? You guys
must know.
So, one day,
uh,
you know, I saw that movie
30 years ago when I was 13. So, you
know, he lights a match and he just put
your put his finger on it and extinguish
it. And the other guys are asking him,
"What's the secret?"
And the secret is just to endure the
pain.
In my case, I know a little bit
something.
How do I know? You just spend all your
time on it. That's That's how. You know,
you just be a nerd. You don't You don't
do nothing
except reading math and stuff.
Okay, bye guys.