good morning welcome to another episode
of Soph talk show today I think today
we're going to talk about eMac lease
let's focus on Emacs
we haven't done a Emacs session for a
while and this is just going to be a
Emacs session so so let's change the
topic let's select all delete go here
actually yeah go here copy cut go to
Emacs and paste today's date cut save
switch paste or one single key button
press so I'm going to let's do something
about Emacs today and while I wait for
people to come in
it's showing browser let's copy okay so
Emax focused session so today is
Saturday 2 o clock p.m. in California hi
guys say something so today I'm going
we're gonna do a Emacs focused session
so ask me any questions about Emacs or
email is or we can do a just the emag
this session like i'm going to teach you
immigrants you know type your questions
here type your question type questions
here let's do a Emacs focused one okay
but let me start by let me start by I
have some tasks here to do actually let
me just copy that copy switch back to
Chrome and paste it here go down paste
okay
so Emax session so what we're gonna do
Oh actually the spam we covered already
yesterday so let's put it here well okay
so on the Left pan you can see all the
Emacs command I call so if you are
wondering what command did I just call
you can just look at the left pin and
usually it's on my website just such for
the command so that's gonna do it's
going to do a Emacs treated session so
are we here yet
say something we got three people
watching say something so let let me
just start then okay there are some
things I want to show you in Emacs Emacs
demo delete cone fire okay that one
Emacs demo chokes are line to list that
one Emacs demo create a new Unicode page
yeah we can do that and Emacs time awoke
on converting python tutorial from
python to 2003 we gonna do that quite a
lot topics all those you know this fall
v will fill up one hour an e max demo
using sulfide and to replace that it's
it's two dead start with that hey good
morning guys great to see you guys aaron
break the loop web dog and wagner so
we're gonna do a Emacs its to a Emacs
focused one i mean any topic related to
Emacs so since since a lot people are
following me for for my Emacs stuff so
I'm gonna start doing one demo one of
the packages let me show you so yeah I
know what to do so let's go to Emacs so
keep the comments keep typing a comments
okay anything I talked about you have a
question or you have a comment or your
opinions just put it there so I can use
like it serves kind of like your facial
expression so I know
you know whether I'm doing good so let
me begin by going to okay going to my
Emacs blog you can see this is my Emacs
blog now there is something I want to do
there and you can see that's open a
Emacs article let's say this one it is
is the text too small or should I
enlarge it like this is normal
open the file this is enlarged should be
enlarged or normal type it type it let
me know so I open this Emacs font setup
page now this is how it looks in browser
and you can see all these are Emacs HTML
structures
I called HTML manually by hand with the
help of Emacs of course so you can see
there is the main tag so you can see
there is a main tag and if I press if I
call this command which is such TM l
skip tag forward it goes down to the
closing tag now so you can see this is
the end man and this is a type type tag
so I go up again submit but what I want
to do so so it looks like this let me
show you split new buffer paste go to
HTML mod so this this is the what I have
blah blah blah blah and I wanted to
change it to to these Wow let's just do
it this way let's say type that mean so
I want to change it to that so let's do
that so close this window
I want to change for all files in my
Emacs directory so there's going to be
like 500 files
hegemony Norman Norman is in East Coast
so it's like 5:00 o'clock Saturday
something you did just now made
texts blurry unless it's just me okay so
anyway so never mind yeah okay so so
this is tired I want to do the change
for the whole directory so is this going
to be like 500 files let's go to so this
goal of the directory find name find
name anything HTML so you can see there
are like Oh mm files yeah mm files but
you know 1001 thousand about 1400 of
them Emacs Lisp and Emacs manuals so you
can see all these are you max menus so
my own pages about I'm gonna change that
so let's do that so let me just show you
how I do that so I'm going to copy this
code okay let me show the window copy
this call Safa and replace text paste I
want to replace that text enter and what
is my replacement
the replacement should be that just
meant so okay before I do this let me do
a backup so here's what I normally do so
let's go to the Emacs directory again CD
up get status so I'm using it get I'm
also using match it but magic match it
has a problem that when you have
thousands of files it's very slow like
it takes you know it takes 10 seconds to
to do anything any any command you call
it takes 10 seconds to update but I
think they improved let's try it so
match it magic
wait I believe this is wait huh match it
status I haven't used magic for a while
okay magic status
so so far so good anyone what did you
guys have for breakfast for lunch
so you see okay so I open the magic
Heidi on great to see you Dianna thanks
for the patreon so I opened up may match
it so these are files that I need to
commit so in magic you just do
let's not use magic let's go back to the
command line so git status okay git add
add them all git commit do that so now
it's all committed so if I'm making any
mistake I want to revert everything I
can do that so now let's start to do the
saw find reface file so I I won't find
that and I want to replace it by ah
what's going on I want to be placed by
let's try that again
so find that text preface by men okay
and what directory I want to the Emacs
directory so do that so file path
rejects HTML that's correct right
changes to files yes fixed case in such
yes fixed case in replacement yes make
backup yes so take like five seconds
okay it's done so once it's done you can
press the up and down arrow to see all
the changes faces you can see all the
yellow ones are you know so there are
thousands of them so that's done close
it and you can see the file already
updated now if I go to the bottom of the
file there is another face this text I
want to change again to so let's call
the command so I'll find replace text
paste enter and I want to change it to
men that okay so do that directory file
extension right changes fixed case fixed
case make backup
okay so it's all done so it just changed
you know over 1,000 files you know if my
cursor is on one of the highlights I can
press ENTER and it will just jump to the
file you see right here so for example
this file that's looking a browser oh
okay so it's it's gone bad because I
didn't change the CSS file so let's
close the changes go to the top of this
file and here is my CSS let's open it
and go to the top search for main and
here is the the main part here so I need
to change my CSS file so that you know
this will not be scrunched together so
this is a CSS file let's look at all
occurrences of men okay just one place
so all I have to do is just replace this
line by min so first of all I make a
backup then just say that I think that's
it save it go to the browser reload
beautiful okay so that is the that is
that that that is you know basically
author and if I go to my entire
directory and refresh you can see all
these backup files you see all those are
backup files and you know but basically
it's good you know if I look at you know
some of my some random pages you know
they are all good you know they they are
working so but in case you know I want
to revert everything I just get get
revert some command you know I don't you
know remember the older kid commands but
I have a tutorial on git
sorry get tutorial
get basics so if I want to revert them I
can just call revert the file weaver the
director you know get checkout head you
know the full path but actually it's all
good
so what what I want to do now is to
upload to my directory my server so
let's do that
a sink yes past walk now you are see and
you view the source code you will see
that it's using the main yes I just did
find and replace across you know one
thousand files in in directories you
know directory in directories so
actually so that's done so so let's
let's it's just open that close it open
that back to Emacs close it open that
back to Emacs close it open that so okay
so you know so all these are ten so let
me show you the the the command that I
just used so it's one of my command saw
packages right here and that one is
Suffolk is look at find/replace
so this one so you can use it it's on
Melva okay so that finished that
finished one demonstration of you know
me using Emacs to update work with my
website now the thing interesting about
that is let's go to HTML I have a HTML
tutorial and you can see there are these
this this is a list of all HTML tags now
that main tag that main thing is this
one and that is actually new in html5 so
it's new you know since html5 maybe six
years ago and I remember I try to use
that but some people come friend because
when they view my website in a forum or
on something it doesn't you know it
looks scrambled
because browser doesn't support that yet
but that that was like three years ago
so you know I'm pretty sure they support
the main tag by now you know force for
at least couple of years by the way if
you work with HTML or web you probably
know there is a website you know if you
want to know if you know what which
browsers supports you know which new
HTML tag or CSS new you know new CSS
stuff or JavaScript you can see you can
go to can I use so the website is King I
the the name of the website is King I
use so that's the website you know you
can go there and find out let's see
let's turn on the JavaScript because the
the site kind of neat JavaScript so for
example if I type main it will tell you
you know which browsers supported now
and since when
so anyway that's that's that so let's
see what is this file so Emacs frog
close it okay we don't care
anymore now let's go back to talk saw
talk show the list of topics we just
finished this topic so I did that for my
Emacs website I have other website sites
like sorry that info I need to do so I'm
going to do that offline then so there
are several other topics let me do let's
do that so any questions so far let's
see no man says recursive operations are
mini files in tired seemed seemed quite
slow is that Elise problem or diet
problem what do you mean like like I
don't think it's fast I mean I don't
think it's slow I mean so depending like
what do you mean exactly like usually
when you access files
that's super slow but the problem is
caused by hard disk you know if you are
using flash drive you know then that's
much faster but if you are using hard
disk which is you know I'm using a iMac
mini Mac and that has a hard disk you
know spinning heartaches that's like you
know 10 times so hundred times slower
than the flash drive flash and the the
mini Mac actually has a small flash
drive they have an integrated
proprietary system but anyway if you are
using hard disk if you want to you know
walk or directory like thousands of
files or ten thousand files usually the
first time is slow because you know the
operating system you know needs to
access every file load them up but
usually after the first time if you do
it again it is very fast because the
operating system these days they they
put fire stuff into memory so you know
the second time is usually like 10 times
faster
so okay okay so you are saying when we
recursing directories in Emacs is slow
but not so when you are in shell I think
that may be caused well it's not - it's
not very slow to me I mean in shell I
mean depending on like what you do like
for example if you go to a shell well
you know Oh terminal for example and you
if you use square that is much faster
than whatever Emacs command eMac this
because you know because Emacs if you
are using Emacs you know tired you know
anything involving you make this to do
things they have lots of you know
features and packages so it's it's
absolutely slower than crap I mean when
you use web command in Emacs for example
their web commands you can use that
usually cause the shell grab command you
you know your the Emacs cause the shell
grab or silver or something there are
several others today and they so they
call the shell command when when a shell
creates the output let's say grab
something that's let's try so CD up so
let's grab and it's grab so that's
square for let's say house car because
it's that's always fancy go to grab so I
want to grab let's say grab so yeah so
here I have a great command it's not
using eMac this with just shell grab
command and I press Enter okay well this
is not a good example because when you
call grab initial each Ayesha will
actually pass the output so here's the
output and you see the highlighting you
can click it and you'll go to that
website that file because I shall
actually process the output but if you
do this in in terminal
then you it's fast I mean when wherever
you Maglis tries to process the output
and color color it it kinds of slow it's
slow things down fairly a lot I mean if
you are doing you know 10,000 files for
example if I if I do this in in you know
it's a little bit faster yeah so if you
see slowness either it's hard disk or I
mean you're Emacs is actually personally
processing it also if you are if you are
using a lot of the packages you know a
lot of people use lots of packages they
you know that's why I don't use much
packages every package I must look
exactly I'm very careful you know
because packages you know they they
usually add lots of hooks you know to
lots of places and so so the goal for
them I mean they enhance the operation
to a user it seems you know a lot
features coloring and stuff but it also
slow things down so you you might to
look for whether especially hooks you
know a lot of packages they add hooks to
find file command fine file command is
the command that opens file so whenever
you open a file it actually runs lots of
things you know checking whether you
think have changed or whatever you know
they have lots of hooks that slows
things down significantly so any any
other things dams and so ok well maybe
yeah let me well ask any questions
otherwise I'm going to do another demo
right you know I don't know if you guys
are interested in that one but they now
just go ahead and do another demo
because if you have a questions to ask
me that I can go into that topic
so um okay Emax demo account converting
python tutorial two to three now let's
let's show that let's look at how long
I've been going 24 minutes which is good
okay so let's go to Python Python one of
the language I do not like okay let
let's view in Safari let's view in
Safari because Safari has JavaScript on
and when javascript on you can see you
see you can see on the Left panel it the
highlight sticks so you know which page
you are so anyway I have this python
tutorial and I've I decided to convert
or Python to to Python 3 I think it's a
right time to do that
please rant about why Python sucks
are you are you serious because I can
actually I might just go into that
okay so let's finish this
Emacs thing first opening then maybe
maybe we talked about that a little bit
so I did so I decided to convert Python
two to three you know today in the
industry Python 3 is used about like 40
percent you know roughly you're 50
percent you know it's really super slow
to convert why because okay I'm already
starting to rent
okay so here's I have a page on Python 2
in Python 3 differences
now how many programmers are Python
people here so the reason you know
Python 2 2 3 it's I mean first of all
it's incompatible language changes but
basically 90% of language is your same
so the nature of Python the language I
mean most of the code looks the same
they I mean they you know if you don't
code in Python you cannot tell you know
whether this is pattern 2 or Python 3
but however so the the major reason the
park I told in the guy who created
Python he want to make the change
because he was because a Unicode you
know in Python a string is just a
sequence of bytes basically that's true
for almost all languages but so Python 2
added support for Unicode but it's kind
of like a hack
so potato wanted to create you know he
he feels like you know he want to like
he have a vision of perfection so he he
wants to he wants to make Python 3
unicode from the ground up so that that
is the original intention the the the
reason why we have Python 3 so in Python
3 a string is no longer a sequence of
bytes it's no longer so it's actually
each one it's a sequence of Unicode code
points or unicode characters so that is
a major change I mean this is the the
bulk of python 2 and 5 & 3 differences
and this is a primary reason however
then Kaido actually started to change
lots of other minor things you know like
when you create a language you know or
even if you wrote a program you know the
first version you find you know after a
few years you got the experience you
find lots of things you are not happy
with so traditionally you just patch it
you know but maintain compatibility but
but Godot decided you know he want to
fix all a little you know to him he
seems like he's to me you know he is
getting things better so pizza beside
the Unicode change which is which is a
major the harder Python to n3 change he
also changed lots of things for example
print is now a function instead of a
statement the version changed you know
map returns now returns an iterator and
you know X range function scan file
function is control input is you know
like lots of little things you know so
it's not trivial at all to actually
convert
- even a small script you know what
depending on how small but is in general
it's not trivial to change is it's not
it's not trivial I mean it's that
significant because it's not just the
same thing tactical change you know you
might think oh I just changed you know a
few syntax here and there I just change
you know add parentheses you know it's
not like that because some you know for
example the strain change from byte
sequence to Unicode that involves lots
of internal you know methods and
internal stuff so you can just change
your string syntax you know it's not
like that
so when you do the conversion you
actually have to dig into to know I mean
it's like a semantic change like your
whole internal semantic change to the
type change so so that's why you know a
lot of people still don't like Python
including some of the famous Python
coders you know they including Eric's
Eric's Rayman for example he has written
and a huge article about Python how to
deal with the Python two and three
yeah so anyway so of course if you ask
Python fans they'll tell you oh you
should switch input to Python you know
just like every you know you leave
hacker groups they always you know once
you push you into a certain ideology you
know they but you know so it's been like
10 years now and Python 3 adoption is
it's like you know 50 percent no sorry
Python 3 adoption so let me get back to
Emacs so so I I got an article here
that's about Python 3 the adoption
officially Python 2 will be deprecated
like one more year in 2020
I mean they already extended that you
know for like 5 years you know every
year they extend but you know nobody is
switching so but now it seems like you
know 2020 is the last year that Python
we'll be officially supported but it's
likely that Python 2 will be you know
keep going for quite a you know number
of years so anyway so let's go to let's
let let's get back to the what I want to
do about the Python so most of these my
tutorials has been converted you can see
they're all Python 3 code loop through
least you know map function to list you
know they've been converted to Python 3
code well however they have they are
about 10 10 % I still need to do the
conversion so let's do this one so this
one is a copy nest at least shadow deep
copy yeah you know one thing I don't
like languages programming languages in
general is that when whenever they have
the reference that they have the idea of
reference or pointers in a language but
basically almost basically all
industrial languages has that concept
you know they want you why because well
the simple obvious reason is that when
you have references in your language it
makes things faster because when you
have a list you know if you are signing
or list to a variable that variables
value is actually just a reference like
an address you know in in some internal
you know CPU structure is just a number
but however in mathematical oriented
programming languages such as
Mathematica APL MATLAB actually I'm not
sure about melih but in G but but in
general in math oriented languages or
scientific languages you don't have the
concept of references yeah let me show
you then some of the articles so why not
because then you can look into let me
check the comment to see if I'm going in
the right direction
ok so I'll talk about Python I why I
don't like python or a bit that's going
to be like one hour so
maybe just a little bit today I dislike
Python a little before but sighs making
me hate it I'm a good um I'm good a
Python by force I hate it Ruby is much
better yeah in my opinion Ruby is much
more Ruby is simpler more elegant more
well-designed simpler and also easier to
learn actually and yeah and they are
about the same speed as Python you know
for programming language opinions each
one has their opinion right and if you
are a Python fan if you are Java and C++
fan you get offended you hope of course
I mean everyone loves to defend you know
their opinions so I'm just giving you
mine the other thing I want to say is
that my opinion is the best okay not
really but I what I want to say is that
you when you give an opinion about some
programming languages I mean well
everyone has learned opinions about
everything when you drive a car you have
opinion about cars which car you like
you know you all programmers has lots of
huge amount of opinions about computer
keyboards you know but what I want to
say is that when you you actually have
to spend time to study you have to they
say no pain no gain you actually have to
spend dedicated time to study a subject
then your opinion is more valid so
everyone has an opinion about keyboard
like we all use keyboard you know you go
on everyone will tell you what keyboard
you know how they are like this all
right but nobody almost nobody ever
concentrated focus you know just sit
there and think about some some keyboard
issues for one hour then never you know
you almost never see that in the same
way but there are people who has you
know I have studied a lot about keyboard
for example and there are some people
who you know other keyboard experts you
know just there are some keyboard expert
on key key switch mechanisms there are a
lot hackers that that be on keyboard
you know when you be your keyboard you
actually learned you know you you become
an expert on electronics on a components
on a design on the arrangements of the
keys and so on and some people are you
know history
they studied you know they have written
books that for example there's a guy
massing something they wrote a book on
they researched keyboard history so and
what I saw what I'm saying is that when
you when you want your opinion on
something if it if you never you know
actually put effort like this you know
even one hour and do nothing else you
know just thinking about that thing when
you do that then your opinion is it
becomes better once you know it's better
opinions so same thing with programming
languages you know like almost every
programmer every programmer gets old
right so eventually you have ten years
experience in programming you know so
you got a million to millions ten
millions people or have opinions on
programming languages what they like but
but very few of those people less than
one percent you know actually you know
spent you know let's say you know
actually spend time let's say a month to
study you know actually think about why
they liked it compared to what languages
you know what languages are there you
know in a word you know history of
language what kind of language are there
what there are there you know
philosophies you know then it's these
kind of people I think you know you you
want to pay attention to their opinions
that because you know not from just you
know every every program I you know has
10 years of experience they will tell
you their you know stuff anyways it's
kick it back the topics all right
maybe um yeah so let me do this Emacs
thing first so I want to show you this
Emacs thing so so let's go back to the
okay show the Python tutorial in browser
and let's go to complex numbers copy
nested based oh yeah so I was talking
about references all the industry of
programming languages has references but
not much in math oriented languages the
concept of the reference so why why I
don't like I do not like references
because references the concept you know
the reference it's what I would call a
computers a computer engineering by
product by product by that I mean it's
something you don't want but it kind of
happens it's kind of like necessaries so
in other words it's some sort of hack
why is it necessary because it makes
things fast because if you don't have
references every time you pass a pass a
parameters to a function you need to
copy it you know so references the
conference's make things fast and
practical which is you know a valid
reason you know reasonable but however
references they create huge lots of
problems conceptual problems teaching
problems programming books lots of them
for example in this article copy nested
list shadow you know the concept of
shallow copy and deep copy is very
confusing you see that almost every day
in foreign languages they people get
confused you know why do I copy this you
know for example I copy your list to
another variable then I change the other
variable and in some circumstances the
original also changed you know but in
other circumstances the original doesn't
change why that happens because of
references it the thing things becomes
very complex and this is also part part
of the reason why the function of
programming especially Haskell they they
want you know they want no side effects
so they don't want any of these
so Haskell is the language
that has a way to avoid this problem but
I don't know technically I'm not a
Haskell programmer so I don't know how
they solve that I don't know technically
in Haskell they still have references
probably I don't know for sure and any
any task our programmers here YouTube
what what is that youtube link don't
post anything bad okay I don't want
Google to be me
so anyway so reference is yeah that's
the idea so so let me let me do this let
me just finish this in five minutes then
then let's go on about other other
topics so what I want to do is you know
I'm going to convert this to this these
are Python - I want to convert to Python
3 so what I do first of all update the
date also make a backup copy so I'm
calling Southside update article stamp
you can see this article stamp has been
updated and also it automatically
automatically makes an up back up so you
can see my back up here okay close that
so now I press a button you see all the
span tags for syntax highlighting has
been removed and that command is HTML
dhtml eyes pre-code buffer I'm using a
excit ml mod you can see at the bottom
it's on github so now I can now I want
to replace oops yeah so now I want to
replace I want to replace all of this
copy that replace it by replace that
replaced by Python 3
so okay I'm calling query replays so do
I want to change that one yes yes yes
yes yes yes yes so if I view in browser
you can see our I change everything of
that to Python 3 now there is a so
basically okay here's another command so
basically what I code is this command
you see this one this one's query
replace the free code pre-code with
utf-8 encoding declaration to Python 3
here and without the pre-code
declaration you know in Python 2 you
need that if your source code contains
Unicode in Python 3 you do not because
in python 3 any source code should be
encoded in utf-8 so I did that now I
want to press a key so it puts the code
into a new buffer and then runs him in
python mod so I'd run it so so that
command you know you can see all my
commands on left panel so that that is a
command I just called besides Jimmy I'll
get pre-code make new file so let's look
at this file so if I run it it's not
going to work because print is now a
statement you need parentheses so let's
try to run it start doing current file
so you see it says missing parentheses
what you need to do is that now I run it
seven four five it's good I don't want
okay so seven four five is good copy key
or the buffer phase it here and kokum
and two to spend syntax highlight
everything so now I've you in buffer so
you see this one is good but the others
I haven't run a command yet okay but I'm
going to do it now so but I'm
to do it quickly without talking much so
first of all I need to change
so query repays space pound sign
replaced by return pound sign do that
yes yes yes yes yes yes yes yes yes yes
yes yes so what I just did is to put
account
comment in a separate line I do that
because then I'm going to now now I'm
going to add all parentheses to print
statements like these so I'm going to
create a macro so start macro search for
print PR int space okay and Q line to
the end and backspace one and put a
parenthesis parenthesis paste the
content back and that's it now stop mark
well okay the macro is recorded now I
just call a macro again couette it's
done yeah
couette it's done now I can call this
repeat as command so I can just press
one key quickly so let's do that dude do
it do it do it do it do it do it do it
do it do it that's it
so this one is a mistake because it
shouldn't be happen okay so that's it so
now I look in the browser everything's
got parenthesis every print statement
got parenthesis now I can just start to
run a code syntax error invalid syntax
okay so I don't know oh this one I
forgot to put parenthesis okay so that's
done
paste it here now I'm gonna run another
one run it false and true okay that's
good and I want to you know wag my
update a tutorial I also want to update
the style a little bit so make it
simpler so remove the redundant comments
because people can tell from the context
you know so learn that so that's good
cue it paste it here then this force and
true okay okay let's put the cap case
cap case comment cut paste it here and
we got two more to go print force force
and true okay
paste and last one I think good so let's
separate the line oh one more okay one
more okay so that's I think that's it
yep and I press a button that will spam
syntax highlight everything again
ensuring browser and it's done then
usually you know since I'm redoing my
tutorial usually I have to read through
and you know check you know maybe
rewarding something you know possibly
and but basically this is you know one
page done and I go to
yah-ha sync and it's uploaded to my file
so now now I copy the file path close it
go to my programming blog go to the top
search for section create a new section
paste the path here make it link and you
can see I've got a new entry so let's
say update it so okay to Python 3 okay
so now I'm going to add it to my RSS so
I just did that
close it save go to Esha again passing
so now people we all see you know that's
how you know I create a new element
I mean new DLC you know an update on my
my python tutorial so that is that let's
see what else here Python by example
yeah so so let me so that one is done
let me locate comment
okay let me read the comments Deon says
I earn my bread with Python but I have
gotten a strong sense of what the limits
are because the fast because because the
first language I really learned was
scheme
yeah scheme is kind of scheme is known
as the most arrogant language so Norman
says welcome using mostly Perl Python C
so using Perl Deon says in Python has
nothing comparable to macros or
anonymous functions yeah Python
anonymous functions really sucks because
okay so yeah let's talk about that
Python because I I really don't like
5,000 so I have a collection articles I
wrote giving reasons why I don't like
Python but one of the sour point about
Python is its lambda you know why
because Kaido you know he doesn't like
functional programming at all so
anything you know functional programming
he doesn't like he you know he don't
like it and he doesn't like he doesn't
like you know logic oh you know you know
like a regular or systematical uniform
syntax he doesn't like that neither he
doesn't like functional programming so
you know if you have any idea from
scheme this war has cow he doesn't like
it so whatever he do in Python is almost
like the opposite you know he prefer he
prefer the imperative you know or
command command style and as far as
syntax goes he prefer you know he
doesn't like uniform in his any sort of
idea of uniform or you know
mathematical syntax he doesn't like that
he prefers like irregular English like
you know each each semantics has a
different syntax you know kind of like
English like if he prefer like that so
it's you know just you know I jumped to
Python from pearl because I want to get
away from
pearls you know those pearl people
sloppy you know kind of attitude UNIX
stuff but Python is not really the
choice but Ruby is actually good
Ruby you know Ruby is really elegant so
I got a bunch of articles you know
that's a you know that's Python it's
problem so you know and we can you know
cover some of that okay so one of them
so okay so before we go into that so
Python you know so besides the language
you know which is which sucks okay I
don't like okay but the documentation is
really the worst as well I mean the one
of the worst in computing industry so I
have a collection of the articles here
for example let's go you know in Python
documentation you have this keep this
under the pillow what the you know
so Perl in the UNIX people you know you
UNIX philosophy and elite hackers in RFC
and UNIX jargons and Pro people there
are more than one way to do it you know
one of the primary you know adventure
virtual a program as laziness you know
Perl state of the onion you know per
mangas you know they like that you know
those UNIX people they like this swap he
kind of like you know a hacker kind of
the code community but Python is Python
you know also Kaido the person he tends
he like formality you know it seems like
he when you look read his writings he he
always like formal but but the thing he
creates and the writings and order the
whole system you know is full of it's
really bad this for example let's look
at Python documentation for example I'm
gonna
you know so Python documentation so is
bad in so many ways I mean you know it's
a topic I can go on for you know several
hours so Python the documentation in
almost every aspect it's very bad it's
not practical you cannot find anything
you want to do and the writing is
extremely lousy the like writing quality
the many reasons the organization you
know the organization organization of
various topics the tutorial is extremely
bad and there's author author
masturbation like you know you know he
wants always to tell you you know so in
many ways you know I can go to detail
into that I mean this is this is related
to technical writing I mean that's a
discipline by itself but in general
programmers know nothing about it but
they all think they know everything
about it
you know that's the problem but also
these kind of problems it's not a
problem I can speak up and people will
listen in church and think oh that makes
sense no because usually pythons some of
the languages especially these elite
hacker types Python Perl Emacs eMac B's
you know least common lisp Haskell in
clean haskell Python Pro yeah oh this
language are kind of the elite types are
supposed to PHP or JavaScript they don't
have this kind of Association at least
when they began 14 years but anyway the
IDI languages so that you got these
hackers and they oh yeah so whatever is
what I was saying is that when you talk
about documentation you you cannot go
anywhere because they because the code
mentality wiped out any any any sense I
mean there's no sense like like every
year back back in 2000 every year there
are people complaining about Python
documentation in Python new schools and
mailing lists every like every one year
or two years and in almost every one or
two years people have created a
alternative
a wiki and they posted there they they
say hey guys so you know I I created
this maybe it's better than you know you
see in some way we can merge it or you
know they are trying to help for somehow
complained some helpful but every year
it happens then the Python people a
bunch of priests you know they are like
that because they they are guide or
followers and basically you know like
people gather together you know so guy
kaido's followers or his minions change
to be you know we have agree with him
you know so anyway so you've Python has
this you know organizational community
you know they they tell those people no
no they don't you know and in order most
of the you know the hacker types you
know say me new scoops all day they tell
you know shut up I don't talk is the
best I've ever seen
and then another says oh if you want to
change Python thought please go to pep
you know the Python created this pet as
a process procedure because he like you
know he kind of like formality you know
you have to go there fire come friend
and you know went through the you know
process you know so this happens like
every one year or two years i I've I've
seen it I witness it you know in fact
you can see you know the new scoops
postings I've many of these like all of
these like for example this this article
collection about Python documentation
like most of them half of them are
originally my pet on mailing list new
school posts I don't actually post to
Python minionese I opposed to comp Tod
Lanter Python new school because that is
like more public I don't want to you
know I'm not like going into a
particular community like going to
church and say oh god don't
God doesn't exist you know that's not
what I want to that that's not what you
know I'm doing I'm posting to the new
scoop that public discussion but however
the pattern new scoop and the
Menominee's
they are like synced so anyway so a lot
of people call me a TRO and song you
know but anyway so all these you know I
documented you know Python documentation
problems you know I'm not sure where I'm
going because if we're gonna talk about
this topic then I'm I can or I will you
know go into a specific item for example
then I'm going to give you reasons like
why you know why this doesn't work what
this rewriting is so bad you know what's
no alternative you know maybe the
phrasing is bad
maybe the organization is bad you know
then you know you can like you can like
you can think you know you can't judge
for yourself
so look but right now I'm just giving
you the general many of the issues about
Python so let me read the comments okay
and let's see where we are going but in
a minute but but previously we were we
were talking about lambda lambda in
Python you know lambda pattern is a big
sour sour point for Python because many
functional programmers you go to Python
you know you just find it problematic
you know the Python lambda and Python
the guy Doe himself actually has have
written several articles about lambda
like he is defending lambda for example
this this article made a huge joke I
mean it becomes you know it become
widespread among the functional
programmers who have who laughs at the
guide of so you know so you can read
this article in detail offline you know
basically Kaito wrote an article about
why you know why he doesn't like by
lambda you know and if you read his
writings okay I I accept I accepted pato
however but his original poses here if
you know try to go read it you you will
see a typical way style of his writings
he he says such a guy he has the
mentality such that he always like
you know I don't know how do you put it
but he has an attitude that like that
like you know it's like best described
as passive-aggressive you know he think
you know like hidden there you can see
he thinks like he is the he is the
proper you know the best language
designer you know you can see that you
know it's apparent I mean it's not like
you have to take you know just you try
to read it it's apparent then so he
wrote this you know block this is back
in 2005 he still does that I mean I'd
know and then like a few months ago I
still see his writings and it's very
still like that so he wrote this article
you know his blog and the scheme people
the PRT scheme community which is now
known as racket you know they they made
the Lampoon of it you know and I also
you know I also wrote a huge criticism
on his I mean if you read his
article on this one on Python pie lamb
dying in Python you just see if you have
a functional programmer if you have you
know computer science background oh you
know anything you know if you are fan of
functional programming you see that he's
he's just growing opinions but we mean
well the thing about Cato is that you
know when he everyone's got opinion you
can you can show your opinion so that's
that's alright and you can you can say
this is what I think and I think it's
the best period that's what I do you
know you read my articles usually I
think I say you know all you guys are
idiots
I'm being direct okay you can take it or
you can leave it you know that's up to
you you be the church but Godot is not
like that on one hand he think you know
he's the king of design his idea is the
perfection of everything meanwhile he
doesn't say it directly but anyway when
you read it is hot his articles you see
his point it's like what you know like
he doesn't know what he's talking about
about functional programming like I mean
if you just have if you just don't like
functional programming that's fine
say it you know you prefer imperative
style you prefer OFI that's fine but he
doesn't yeah I mean he he's got you know
his way of talking and you know then you
know then you know it's funny like you
know for like if you go back to read
this article at the end he says at the
end says okay let's go let's go to his
article okay here the the fate the fate
of reduce in Python 3000 wait did he
change the title okay no that's good you
know so look look at this I'll go first
of all he's this is his blog okay back
in 2005 this is his blood first of all
he has a summary you know like this is
like a academic I read every tower paper
he first of all he give you a summary
like you know you see I I received an
email from compatriot yeah that's that's
his the addiction you know also pay
attention to the words you know the
choice of words he used I received an
email from a compatriot lamenting the
planned demise of reduce in lambda in
Python 3000 and also know the name
Python 3000 you know it's like he's
going to create you know the the glory
that you know the end of the time
language Python 3000 know then he
continues after a few exchanges after
you know it's after a few exist I think
even he agreed that they can go so he's
telling you a story that even a fan you
know like he's got fans you know by the
way I got lots of fans I have a pumpkin
compatriot and after we exchange you
know he actually admit that it's
actually I am right you know the reduced
should go that you know then he says
here is a summary including my reasons
for dropping lambda map and
yeah he wants to drop drop them that map
in theatres then he says I expect turns
of disagreement in a feedback Oh from ex
Lisp or scheme folks then he put a
smiley you know so you know that's kind
of like typical of his style you know
you can you can see it then you know
then he explained you know a bunch of
garbage you know I so I criticized you
know like paragraph by paragraph you
know I dissect his point but then you
can see this the okay there's another
part I want to mention but it's not in
this article but this you know he has
written another blog article that at the
end you know he like he he he he
grumbled you know he ranted about
something his opinions at the end he
says Oh on the other hand you know about
that issue that's another installment
that's not enough you know he's gonna
give you another installment like oh
yeah I have you know I have the perfect
idea on that topic as well but that's
gonna be another installment so you know
it's like hi guys you know today I
haven't done with Python yet you know if
you want me to talk about Python my
opinion about Python my my perfect ideas
about Python you know you're gonna have
to visit the next installment of our
talk show so anyway that's fighter
that's the guy door guy okay so but the
one thing I wanted to that gave me that
game East that got me started on the
lambda thing is the the lambda Y lambda
is broken and cannot be fixed why Python
lambda is broken now I wanted I want to
show in the opinion that is I think
that's kind of you you might say Steve
of my opinion which and from from my
point of view it's it's seldomly Express
almost never in the in the overall
general programming community language
design community okay I'm gonna talk a
little bit few minutes about that okay
so it's over one hour so that maybe
they'll be here today finish that then
maybe they'll be here today but let me
go back to read the comments a little
bit yeah so sure yeah actually you know
I have lots of you know I haven't began
yet you know why it sucks you know I
haven't began yet because there are each
there are some things I want to talk
about you know it just happens to us
last week about pythons writings in
let's go through my programming tutorial
so if on my programming tutorial you
have okay that's old rant yeah this
section 2019 March 17th you know so this
another so this is also another big
issue I want to talk about because I
think the issue can you know if I
explain it you know in person like with
facial expressions then it can resonate
I mean maybe you guys will see you agree
maybe you guys will agree I mean on
Twitter some other people agree you know
with you know I think it's obvious I
mean it's something I want to talk about
but let me read the comment first so ok
quite a few comments
did you just such a vase and sand I'm
serious i am i braid with python okay
I prefer Ruby Python does have lambda
but it's sad admitted yeah that's what I
want to talk about why pythons lambda is
limited the reason is because actually
it has to do with syntax I mean this is
a to me it's very critical idea you know
because I am always a poor syntax guy
because I I think and I hope to convince
you guys that syntax is you know usually
there's a common belief that semantics
is more important than syntax I mean
it's actually you know spewed out by by
the rackets one of the racket professor
you know PRT on language design one of
the book you know in the beginning
chapter or something there but quote you
know semantics is far more important
than syntax basically the idea is that
you know programming languages oh the
syntax doesn't really matter it's
actually the semantics that really
matters because that is actually the
heart of the language it you know it
controls what it does you know syntax
can you know just changed you know to
one way or another or Lisp syntax I
disagree okay I think that that is 100%
completely wrong that's a idiotic cut
you know that's a idiotic idea to spread
that's a 100% wrong and I'm going to
give you lots of and I'm going to
explain to you why you know I have like
you know over over like tens of articles
about that issue Python sucks if you go
to syntax soup you know like you know I
have like few hundred articles here
syntax roof on this syntax tube and
semantic noodle if you read you know
let's say more than ten of them
dedicated dedicated you know if you
spent not a lot of time I think you
might see my idea but that's what I'm
going to explain so syntax soup
let's see see Nexus semantics complim
perving you know syntax is the most
important aspect of programming language
okay that's what I think the quality of
a programming language can be judged by
how much of it can be explained by its
syntax alone now this is just to sum two
sentences it's not even a summary but
it's okay
I'm not going to go into that right now
so let me read the comments but what I
want to say is that the the reason about
lambda tightened the Pythons lambda why
it sucks is is has the sig you know the
significant reason has to do with syntax
because of the Python syntax that is why
the Python lambda cannot be a full
lambda syntax is the primary reason that
drives where your semantics of your
programming language goes okay that's
what I say
yeah that is the point I want to make
and maybe on another day I'll talk about
you know that why and and in a nutshell
this is this is kind of like related to
the history of math notations now if you
have studied the history of mathematics
especially the history of math notations
you'll know that the math notations
drives the direction of math in a future
for example the the the the the
algebraic notation that that created the
abstract algebra you know in a nutshell
okay I'm simplified things you know the
matrix notation drove you know created
linear algebra without the matrix
notation without the algebraic notation
we are familiar with you know like x
squared plus 3 equals to 5 solve for x
you know we don't get that you don't get
the philosophy of formalism neither you
don't get you know it's the it is the
syntax that drives that that drives your
language you know the development of
your language so the idea of that
semantics is more important that's like
that's like a trivial concept you know
it's like a yeah anyways that's so
that's another topic so okay I almost
covered you know I almost yes oh yeah
that's almost that's that's the heart of
what I want to say so in the same way
that is happening about that is why the
the lambda in Python sucks and why Kaido
you know well partly because he doesn't
want to change it you know he doesn't
like functional programming but partly
because because the syntax because he
cannot change it because the Python
Python language uses as you know you
know uses what's cost so called layout
oh you and it's syntax so anyway so
let's see the article wipe wipe I
thought lambda is spoken okay so let me
just finish this article then then then
let me read the comments okay so white
pet Python lambda is broken cannot be
fixed so one of the here's a quote from
a how absent Q&A interviewed by peter
savio Peter Sabo is a old writer for
programming languages you know right
like back in from 1970s to he's not much
active today because he's you know video
maybe 70 something but he wrote a lot
books on programming languages since and
you know for industry back in 1970s you
know because I remember when I was
studying UNIX history in 1990 I come
across a lot of his books and stuff
anyway so he back in 2011 he was trying
to create a website called code
quarterly that interviews programmers
and so on but it it is it shut down you
know it so anyway he so one Bronco is
how absent QA how absent is one of the
guy who wrote you know the very famous
book structure and interpretation of
computer languages so how habitants
when it comes to Python you know you
have to contend with pythons broken
notion of lambda but other than that
it's not really that different from
teaching computer science using skim DS
so this is in context when MIT you know
the university switched from teaching
scheme to scheme to using Python to
teach their programming classes so
anyway so here we have how a person
saying lambda is broken you know I want
to quote that because because any kind
of criticisms when you almost on any of
these elite kind of languages you know
like Poe Python you know these companies
email based you know these kind of elite
hacker types or UNIX you know philosophy
UNIX people or Linux they'll be shut
shouted down you know nobody you know so
I want to you know put a quote they
abide by this famous Albus and then
people start to say people start to like
pay a little attention
oh oh that famous programmer oh that guy
say that ad you know so and the reason
so but he doesn't you know this guy how
habit a boss and he didn't give reasons
why anyway here's my opinion about why
lambda cannot be fixed
because because okay let me just read it
out then because of the syntax so let me
read it out syntactically
synthetically lambda is a way to define
a function which may be arbitrarily
complex you know in functional
programming is programming languages you
know we use lambda all the time
especially pure functional programming
languages in pure functional programming
languages you oh you don't even have
different you only just have lambda
which all function you know then you
assign that function to a variable name
that's how you create a variable name
this is so for Okemo but they do have
like syntax sugar so anyway let me get
back to the topic since
ethically lambda is a way to define a
function which may be arbitrarily
complex but due to Python syntax choice
of indentation so for lambda we all need
indentation and thus cannot be in line
argument to other functions so that is
the heart of why I think you know you
have problems of actually introducing
you know reowww lambdas in the Python
language yeah because in you know in
Python you know you know so let me
elaborate a little bit so lambda you
know is the is a function in in
functional foreign languages lambda is
like the representation of a function of
the idea of a function and a function as
you know can be arbitrarily arbitrarily
big you know it can be like it can be
ten thousand lines in theory but in
general you know sometimes it's just one
line sometimes it's five lines sometimes
ten lines you know it's is typical to
have a function to have ten lines
nothing unusual about it but in Python
you you kind of cannot do that because
because in functional programming lambda
is a function so you you you use lambda
everywhere so even in the middle of your
code you can have a lambda you know
especially in good functional
programming programming languages like
Haskell okay mo F sharp Mathematica so
lambda a function can be anywhere in any
expression like in functional languages
everything is the expression so it just
can be up here anywhere but in Python
because it's not expression based
language and also because you know it
the syntax is like blocks of indentation
so it's not expressions so whenever you
want to use M de you cannot you know if
it's longer than one line it has to have
more intense but when you have more
intense then it can know
no longer kind of be part of the in the
middle of you know between other
expressions so that's how you know
that's why you cannot have you know it's
it's difficult oh you know is it's it's
it's ugly to have you know real lambdas
in Python so that that is my reason for
that okay so let me read the comments
and let's see they'll be here today
let's see how long I have been talking
Wow one Wow in 20 minutes do I regret
learning Borak no I love work why would
I regret it it's the best you know I
should talk about keyboard in another
talk show you know this is my Canisius
keyboard and it's still my yeah I would
say it's my favorite so if you guys
don't know go to sorry sorry keyboard
and you can review you you can look at
all my reviews I have like five thousand
five hundred articles about keyboards
economic keyboards you know which to buy
which is best for your hands and so on
so this one is I'm what I'm using and if
you buy it from the link on my website
that would be appreciated so yeah
Canisius so far still it is still my
favorite among among the several fancy
ones I have I have this one I have this
one I have this one yeah so let's go
back to let me read the comments and
that'd be it for today you know it's
nothing okay about macros I don't like
Marcos that's another topic but in yeah
that's a topic
okay yeah okay so that's why that's link
okay let me see I can see it YouTube
okay papers we love most beautiful
program ever written oh I heard of this
tossed around but I never read it I
never seen no check it out in Haskell I
think everything is copied no reference
yeah okay thank you wave dog for that
for that tip I didn't know so that's a
good thing to know
so Deon says link is for the most
beautiful program programs they were
writing okay
Bojo johnson hi Bo I love references the
speed and flexibility they offer far
outweigh yeah I mean yeah I I get a
point I mean I see the point um yeah but
so what I want to say you know is that
people have to understand that when you
have a reference you have to understand
it's there not because it's actually
elegant it's there because for practical
reasons and for actually for efficiency
of implementation you know for practical
reasons in fact basically every language
has references you know this is that's
there's an interesting point okay some
languages the reference concept is
explicit now this is patchy particularly
so in C C++ in : in Python and I think
it would be too I'm not sure about Ruby
because I haven't really coded Ruby but
however in other languages the concept
of reference I mean it's there in the
language but it's not explicit meaning
that the programming language Specht the
documentation never almost never talk
about it
when they talk about it it's only for
the implement a ters for the compiler
writers so javascript is a good example
of that the JavaScript language do not
have like explicit concept of reference
but of course it's you have you know
it's you know every list every array is
a reference
you assign it to something but however
it's never you know explicit brought up
to the programmers so you know so that's
an important distinction you know I mean
that's one point I want to make the
reference concept in some languages it's
explicit like CC first person so on :
including Golan which is my favorite
language in some other languages it's
not explicit that's one thing another
thing is that in mathematical languages
it's it's it's it's almost like it
doesn't exist
okay it's it's well in implementation of
the language it's almost inevitable to
have references it's almost inevitable
because even when you go down into the
CPU level you know memory stuff it's
it's inevitable but however in
mathematical or scientific oriented
languages it's the reference concept and
and its consequences it's almost you
know I would say almost okay its net not
there now most programmers when they
talk about hold on a second sama
Nakamoto
sorry my roommate came back hey they
just knocked my window just for fun
yeah so but let's back back to ya
mathematica so most people in the when
we discussed programming languages vast
majority pilar the industrial
programmers they are not the scientific
programmers in the scientific field you
know the typically the scientific
programmers or math oriented programmers
they are in scientific field they are
typically you know mathematicians or
scientists told you know chemic
chemistry researchers chemistry
engineers academics or researchers on
genes you know those are like the
scientific programming community and and
that's not typical programmers when we
when we are go online and Python or Ruby
and you know whatever those are
industrial programmers they are very
distinct like several different
communities so most programmers you know
we hear about references or whatever
topic about programming languages almost
exclusively from this industrial
programmer types so you know so what I
want to say is that I came from a math
background you know I was kind of into
math first you know math is my primary
thing so so okay suffice it to say that
the about language design about language
design issues the program the industrial
programming community and the scientific
community what is I do is totally
different okay so that especially with
regard to the reference concept that is
like deep deep seated in every
industrial programmers like every every
you know person you talk to probably all
of you guys most of you guys the concept
of reference is steep steep seated like
it's like like you say is it possible
for a language that doesn't have that
hungry
let's get out of here you know that
that's what these people they think when
we ever you know language design issues
come up but ever that's that that that
is because the industrial programmers
then they have never been exposed to the
you know scientific programming groups
you know mathematicians type types for
example so anyway that's another another
topic so I guess today's today is good
I've been talking for like 90 minutes I
think ninety minutes okay let's finish
the comments a lot of references the
speed and flex its it's practical I mean
it's almost necessary thing yeah the
thing I want to mention but once you
realize that okay they are you know they
are different ideologies okay it's it's
it's yes it's net references it's almost
essential practical but once you are you
see the other perspective then it
changes your language your language is
design with regards to how it uses
references that that is the critical
point I want to mention because if you
never thought of you know you if you
never had the perspective you know from
the scientific community you know types
you don't see it you you you implement
you the way you use references in your
languages is it's like the C C++ Python
you know and and you know : this is kind
of limited to that you you you have not
seen the other ways to use it and some
of okay Julia where let me mention
example Julia now the language Julia is
extremely fast okay it's comparable to
see
however Julia is a math oriented
language so that the language Julia
belongs to the scientific computing
group okay that's over there so why do I
mention it because here we have an
example of a language that's not
industrial however it is
it is the scientific community however
it's fast it's faster than Python Ruby
you know JavaScript however it's math
oriented language
the design is entirely different from
what do you know okay and now I don't
know how Julia reference you know come
up in Judea so I don't know so maybe
some what does someone know that you
know type in the comments let me know
and let other people know so you know
anyway so yeah yeah just so Haskell mo
mo a leo says did I pronounce that right
Maria says has cows references but but
the beauty of functional languages is in
that values are immutable yes
if values are immutable but you do not
need to copy by value good point yeah
good point
Deon says is it possible to package
Marcos together what do you mean
so that you could have a Python 2 to 3
converter that was purely a group of
Emacs macro running no it's not possible
well it's not possible because
converting Python 2 to 3 is not a
systematic
syntactical change it involves actually
changing a semantics of your code you
have to do a lot of things that is why
you know a lot of people don't like the
change
Daniel Lang law is hi Daniel
I think the code doc would be best
helped by more code examples exactly
good point
that's for Python you know Python dog
the other thing about Python dog is that
you know Kaido they don't give examples
because you know you I cannot tell why
but I can infer you know I inferred and
I kind of guessed why because keidel as
I said you know he's this passive agrees
aggressive he don't want to get like he
don't like you know it ends up
that you don't see much examples actual
code examples sprinkled out in the
Python documentation because he you know
the way he thinks is that he wants you
to know everything like his language is
so beautiful that he thinks that
everyone must know like ivory tower you
you must know every brick you must know
you know what's on top of it so you know
it's like to him it's like a huge Tower
of hierarchy so that when he explains
something here you already know you
should already know everything else so
in his documentation it's like that you
know it's pretty bad the Python dart dog
so so I'm listening very carefully to
everything you're saying oh my god that
scares me so daniel says he gives his
reasons for dropping lambda map theater
in reduce
he didn't anticipate the rigidity of
resists resistance from the Lisp and
scheme folks I don't think it's dropped
you know in Python three you still have
you know it ends up still have lambda
map theater but they'd he discourages
people using it you know he want to
people he want people to use the list
comprehension you know which is another
idiotic thing in Python let's see this
comprehension so I have a see
so I have a tutorial on list
comprehension and I also have a tutorial
I mean essay about why list
comprehension is the worst thing list
yeah why this comprehension is bad if
you guys want to read it you can read it
offline but the gist of that is the gist
of the reason is list comprehension is a
little language it's an exception in
syntax and semantics like yeah who enter
here all rules don't apply
so this comprehension is like that in
general
it's a it's a little language embedded
in a language so in that little
expression it has its own meanings
everything has its own meanings you know
it's kind of like that I don't like this
kind of thing because what I like is a
uniform syntax each expression syntactic
stick a syntactic syntactic form of ice
everywhere in anywhere so you only have
a few simple rules you understand few
simple things you understand the entire
language that's what I like and least
syntax and Lisp semantics is kind of
like that you know you only need to
understand a few things you understand
the whole language and colon is another
kind of like that you know you just have
a few simple syntax a few simple
concepts then you understand the whole
language you and it can create create
different situations by you know just
combinatorial you know combinations of
different syntax you know it's you know
so Mathematica is like that least
languages is like that : which is like
that Ruby is also like that so you can
see I have give you several examples of
very different languages however they
they all have kind of this philosophy
where you have just some simple ideas
you combine them together you form the
greater whole on the other hand
the opposite extreme is Python Python C
well C is very small but C++ okay Python
C prospers that's that's almost the
complete opposite what they and what
they like is that they like every little
detail like every new syntax seeing
every you know part of the language you
know everything is it's like that so he
did not anticipate okay so this
comprehension the gnosis list
comprehension is a complete substitute
for the lambda function as well as as
well as the functions map filter and
reduce I mean yeah it is I mean it is
but I don't like it well for word
reasons you know huh exactly Dion says
you cannot compose these list
comprehensions exactly that is the that
is the the gist of the thing you know
when you have these little things you
know you cannot you cannot compose it
also it's an insult to functional
programming so you know because
composition is a primary thing the
primary power in functional programming
you compose functions when you have list
comprehension is just like one blob of
you know syntax special syntax to do
just one thing okay the gnosis for
aren't comprehensions about getting away
from imperative okay so well well that's
so I mean I I'm kind of I'm kind of
dragging on so you know I want to like
end today but it's one hour forty
minutes
okay so I think that's it for today and
some of the topic you know maybe we can
continue our next one so thank you guys
very much for coming thank you a lot I
enjoy it very much and if you like my
show you know subscribe and donate thank
you bye