good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's show today's 2019
October 28th Monday 3 o clock p.m. San
Francisco time put my key away and today
we have a lot quite a few topics we've
prepared and who is here good morning
Bart is Bart still here good morning
Bart
it must be midnight in Germany come on
in cool for school good morning Freddie
and ok ok so let's let's begin the talk
elesif Alesi Wow Lessig money or less a
good morning but good one is it wrong
crazy your voice was the scream reminder
I had your scream tab open in the
background yeah ok great
good morning Cathy thank you guys for
coming and today we are going to have a
great great talk show and ok stop that
stop that and turn on live chat as you
do movie YouTube videos you get more
experience on what to do you know it's
all about experience experience matters
so Emax I'm the king of Emacs let's
start command log summer log mod I am
the king of Emacs you are the king of
Emacs we are the king of Emacs you for
me you know that's that's what you want
to say so extract the URL of that URL we
just did extract it paste it here that's
a full path then we link a Phi oh ok so
so that is October 27th
that's yeah that that was yesterday
and yesterday we did JavaScript live
coding so open the file and copy this
and modify the title okay and modify the
title showing browser now you got the
proper title live coding JavaScript plus
SVG prod math curve that was yesterday
okay wait the date is incorrect
yesterday is 27th that's right
showing browser correct now close that
extract a URL paste the URL here and
link a fine now you see he got zapped up
it got the proper title now make it list
copy the list and paste it here so we
got yesterday's talk right here and now
that this DD DD DD and today's Santosh
oh good morning Amy good morning Matt
zatoichi Oh today state okay let's do
this using saw talk show today's date
and it's a new page okay now it
automatically creates a HTML page now
link a Phi and copy the link and paste
it here and show him browser page down
you see now that is today now today we
open it this is today's notes while we
are talking we're going to make notes
and today we are going to focus on two
topics first of all I mean that's one of
the two topics we're going to talk about
so I remember last time people wanted to
ask question let's see my description so
here's a description this tiny box
I hate these tiny boxes you know close
to phobic in this user interface you
have these tiny tiny box you have to
scroll like it's amazing now okay we are
starting to digress digression is good
we are getting into recursive digression
now you see this tiny tiny UI box this
is common okay this is the Microsoft
Windows
incredible okay now I'm going to try to
be to be pleasant and melodious okay for
you guys and let's not get into a giant
rent okay it's not even it's not even
changing our voice dynamics too much so
we are going to I'm we are going to try
to do this video in a present and
melodious manner so makes people happy
makes me happy
and avoid too much sarcasm okay okay so
what we were talking about yeah we were
talking about the user interface so
let's let me show you a little bit about
the use of a interface the tiny little
box tiny little box so you go to XR b XR
code sorry dot info website then on the
left you will see the panel then you go
to you go to web design ok CSS is
awesome indeed awesome out of the
outside of the box cutoff and CSS is
awesome awesome indeed and let's see
look at this one peep show window ok let
me show you guys this peep show window
of user interface design I find it
incredible you know today as you know if
you follow the hacker news and you know
the reddit you know you have gurus you
have user interface gurus and today you
have a new jargon UX you know you I
stand for user interface but but but
since about 10 years ago you have a
brand new jargon UX that stands for user
experience
now the meaning of that is supposed to
be that you know user interface when you
design you user interface it's not just
about the interface ease of use but
actually is about
users experience like how they feel okay
so that's the meaning of the UX thing
you know the idea is that when you have
a great user interface easy to use but
but you have to also look at the aspect
of users feelings you know they are
thinking the meaning is that maybe your
user interface you know is so great
right now you know it fix everything
else so it's easy to use intuitive but
however you also have to consider
whether user feel that way ok that is
the UX the gist of UX idea you know now
that is a that is a not that that is not
a good idea
that is a very seedy idea because
because the user interface first of all
user interface includes all that
includes all that you don't need to go
into you know a special use UX like user
experience okay I feel like I cannot do
this Manoah but melodious face and talk
because it's like putting me in a box
I'm not going anywhere
I want to start to swear so let's look
at so so so you know so that that's one
thing we haven't finished about you know
I'm glad I want to rant about this UX
thing should I me because it's gonna
it's it's making me feel angry anger you
know but anyway let's look at the other
the you know let's get back to the topic
about the user interface you see this
user interface design peepshow windows
you know if you use windows you you are
familiar with this right right now I'm
not on Windows so I don't have this to
show you but this is particular in
Windows do a rant okay going to [ __ ] the
UX fact the UX people the the user
interface the UX design gurus you know
you have lots of that you know they post
to hack on you
they everyone is Oh from from this day
on everyone we should concern about UX
you know this this is crap they're doing
that for food for 20 for 20 years about
20 years starting and the the user
interface in the past 20 years they
become worse and worse you know they
become worse and worse and meanwhile you
have this fashionable thing every five
years use a UX okay so one tip for you
guys if you believe if you if you find
what I say slightly reasonable
interesting if that is the case from now
on consider never use the word UX or
user experience like eliminate that from
your vocabulary
never use the word user experience but
the fact is that no or or even the
jargon dress which is worse UX okay
don't use that just say you are user
interface that that that should be it
because you want to shut up so so okay
so anyway let's go back to the user
interface these peeps show windows have
you guys seen this you know this right
like you know you can still see this
today yeah pretty much you know this for
example on Windows even Windows 10 you
know you have these internet options
right you go this you see you see how
big how long is this window so you have
to scroll down these tiny boxes this
cross your phobic that's what it means
you know when I use this kind of thing
after a while it feels pain it's like if
it feels pressure this is you know the
Microsoft Windows imagine I mean even
though they improved a lot
it's far easier to use them Linux okay
fourth sorry guys it is Windows is far
easier to use the MINIX unless you are a
nerd who studied you know programming
language hardware stuff for years for
since you are ting like most of you guys
but you know as general population use
windows is 10
better than Linux anyway even in Windows
you know you have to realize what's
going on okay I have this tablet that's
active that's why the mouse point is
jumping around okay now now consider
these windows you know windows is the
most popular operating system used by
let's say 90% of the population and so
they need to cover you know not just
nerds they your mom your dad your any
any person in a world you know they they
need to use when they need you know
maybe they opens a store or something
they used windows before the phone I
mean even today people still need to use
Windows a computer so imagine Windows
Windows 10 we know that the the user
interface in Windows is really sucks
okay when it comes to user interface Mac
is the best partner okay no questions
Mac is truly just the best you know it
just walks and you know if you have a
Mac user for a long time you might have
lots of complaints you hear but you know
but still overall Mac Mac is far better
than Windows Windows you I kind of very
sucks but Linux is was like it's not
even in the game is out of the question
now but but but still you look at the
windows you know all the windows
programmers you know the experts you
know the professors you know they they
hire from university our user interface
professors you know human-computer
interaction experts you know they have
such people like that they you know some
of them get hired to Microsoft but
overall but but but you then you look at
this okay let me show you some of our
varieties for example this is Oracle VM
VirtualBox interface when you want to
install you see this tiny you see this
tiny window now the important thing is
that you cannot enlarge this window so
that everything becomes nice it's
impossible I mean this window is not
cannot be enlarged that's that's the
thing this window cannot be enlarged
neither so you are for
into this so you are forced into this
fixed tiny like the the computer screen
as technology progresses gets bigger and
bigger we have 20 inch we have 30 inch
we have curved monitors you know but the
software the software force force you to
have these two inch max Jesus I mean
that that is you know Jesus and okay so
I'm criticizing Windows here right i'm
criticizing windows but you know it's
very funny like when I post this I mean
a lot my followers or people I mix with
you know my circles are Linux users
right I mean there are also windows in
Mac but you you kind of never see the
Linux people criticize this like if I
post this like few very few people we
all like agree on your thumb but it's
but you know you know that the link in
Linux people you guys criticize Windows
every day like every day how we knock
this better this or that they stink
window sucks but the real actual in my
opinion are actual the real actual
problems of the of Windows when I post
is like the Linux people they don't they
don't see it they don't feel it's wrong
I find that I find that the very
interesting you know so that that is you
know so you know that's just so I don't
see things you know it is for reasons
okay I I don't know what they are
thinking okay this okay like maybe I
should VP I don't I don't know if I'm
being repetitive like you have the least
Linux group right Linux phonetics they
criticize Windows every day but a
situation like this which i think is
true a real problem with Windows you
know I'd wrote about it I put up but
when I show this to the Linux people
it's like they they don't they don't
they don't care when is my last you
of Linux I about that a few times
singing a few of my videos I use Linux
these three times well of course not
everyone watches all my videos but
anyway so repetitive this is part of the
nature of doing video if you do it every
day they could talk show so anyway so I
use Windows from I mean I use Linux from
as a desktop okay that's important as my
main machine desktop from 2011 to 2006
2007 for 44 years basically everyday
2011 to 2006 2007 okay but but remember
I need to also mention I I was a Solaris
UNIX um admin for for four years back in
1998 to 2002 so because every time you
know people want to ask you you know
when we wins last time you you know no
offense but you know people have a lot
of people we ask you whenever I
criticize Linux they all say well when
did you know when you don't even use
Linux you have a Mac phonetics they look
at my machine you don't even use the
Linux you don't know nothing about Linux
you know that's that's what they say so
I mention I use Linux for four years I
need to also mention I use I used Linux
before your dad used it okay UNIX
philosophy but anyway let's go back to
this you I think peeps your windows look
look look at I mean do you guys like
like every time I have these issues I
wrote my blogs I find it incredible like
seems like people don't connect with
what I see like like so so so what is
the problem is it because I'm I'm just
weird that is I'm stupid this is this oh
is it my criticism invalid like what do
you guys think I mean look at this now I
can we can do video right so so let me
show you ask you guys do you think this
is like a problem
oh you do it you think it's it's I mean
this is a problem right maybe it's not
too important but it's a it's a user
interface flaw right I mean you you have
the the the the physical screen gets
bigger but the software forces you into
this one inch two inch marks and you
have to keep scoring this thing do you
think this is a problem well you don't
think this is a problem
so message that's following me yeah so
okay so you know that's let me show you
more examples not just not just to okay
then you have Twitter you know Twitter
you know you can I go to Twitter right
now if you have a Twitter account like
when you want to post a message or
direct message let's see let's go to
Twitter okay let's go to Twitter good
morning Amy
Emily great to see you and Emily so so
let's go to Twitter okay it you know
this peep show window okay let me show
you so I have a giant screen great okay
so I can see everything in one glance I
can you know that's good you know
technology progress we have bigger and
bigger screens but now I want to treat
pink boom this this tiny box okay well
that's that's nothing but wait until
this is your okay because you can only
post 280 characters okay that's that's
okay but then when you go to the okay
when you go to the the the private
messages you see things like this okay
you see things again this window this
this popup window is not resizable like
you cannot make it bigger it false it
forces you to this tiny box and look at
the score bar so you have to scroll a
lot to see you know information this is
I cannot you know so this is you know
to me you know I am this my personality
or whatever you call it you know so this
is a thing you know so I think of when I
think when I see the issue like this you
know all these issues especially with
Twitter you know it gets you thinking
you know so what is going on
I mean first for example what's the
problem okay first of for example let me
ask the question first first first of
all do they to Twitter actually have a
user you know interface designer UX
expert you know and surely they have
because they you know you go to Twitter
they are fine you know we need we are
having UI UX UX expert things like that
they are concerned about that because
every time twitter has a new UI they
announce it right they have a blog they
talk about oh we heard about users
complain therefore we change this or
that is usually it's all [ __ ] anyway
so my question is like okay so there
must be I mean I'm sure there they are
user interface expert user interface UX
expert UI UX expert then they created a
thing like this I mean so so what what
is going on do they think they think
this is the best way oh is this some
other reason I mean what's going on
what's what you know like I want I'm a
very logical person maybe due to my
personality
maybe I'm weird okay whatever but
usually when I see your problem III need
to get a get it I want to I need to find
a logical resolution so is it because my
opinion are just invalid you know
actually all most people most people
love this small thing so they can focus
on one part of it is that is that a
reason now if that's a reason okay then
you know okay then then maybe I'm wrong
you know my opinion about seeing
everything is wrong people actually just
want to see the small part then then
that's it for this thing you know I know
the answer that's what people think you
know I may not agree but that's the
reason they they think they should be
this way so that's resolved but oh is it
because you know what is oh oh is it
because I can tell you another example
of reason it's because you see even
though twitter has UI and UX expert
however they design things not too often
optimize the Twitter app for the user
actually they design things to optimize
the clicks you know the you know
optimize whatever you know they have
lots of psychology they have a b.a.p
tests like they they put out two
different versions of UI and see which
people you know interact with it more
statistically you know trigger do that
you know they don't tell you but they
Google they all do that Google Twitter
Facebook if you read their blog you'll
see over the past ten years they do that
so so maybe because traitor
choose to have this kind of picture
window interface because they find that
this actually maximize you know maybe
people you know clicking around you know
get people busy you know maybe and also
there's a psychology aspect you know for
example some some psychology study we
all say you know even people the more
maybe you know follow the example the
more people get frustrated the more they
get involved with the app you know they
all know more about the app you know so
so in the end Twitter gets more traffic
is that maybe that's why you know so
they are you know I want to I need to
get this resolved what what the [ __ ] is
going on you know Twitter is an example
okay and another example this is Google+
now it's dead Google+
long live Google+ Google curate the
Evoque Google Empire this they began
around 2010 and it went dead it got
killed about this year this year April
Sunday all a CEO was a bass here so
here's a Google+ Google first do not
have character limits so you can you
know for example me I'm talk
I read a lot you know I just keep typing
before I start to give my opinion simply
the preface of the opinion is already
1000 words that's the situation with me
okay so this is Google+ so when you
start to post you again see these peep
show windows and you see this scroll bar
so you have to like you are reading or
essay but you you only see like that
tiny part of it what what is going on
with this you know it's like this so
it's a puzzle then another example from
Google+ you have you know messages you
know this close to a box you know this
you cannot see all the peoples comment
in one shot you have to scroll up and
down you know that's another example
another example this is more common okay
this is Stack Overflow you see when you
post a code you have this horizontal
school bus which is extremely idiotic so
here's the example from Stack Overflow
here is another example from a blog or
some tech website you know this is
common when you have code they they they
want to they create this horizontal
scrollbar so you have to scroll back
back and forth so you know in this era
where you go to Twitter how can use
reddit you know everyone is talking
about oh you I you are UX you know new
UI UX you know new ways to do things you
know how how they improve but it's so
crappy so garbage okay in my opinion you
like you know I I study them I look at
them to me it's like it's [ __ ] it's
all [ __ ] so you know it's like this
is similar to how I'm against open
source or or UNIX philosophy you have a
lot of people who are poor for it but I
don't I just don't see it that way you
know I see it's like every like we all
these things what I'm seeing is like a
view everyone is saying one plus one is
three everyone is saying it and there
seems to be no problem you know and when
you went when I posted this to folks
go to other places when I posted this I
tell them you know in my point of view I
say actually one person wise is equals
to two guys but like nobody sees see it
nobody everybody one is like it's like
am I crazy am I crazy
is this a is this something wrong with
this that's one example of the UI design
keeps your windows okay and there's lots
of others the other big thing is the
grey text on white background okay that
truly annoys me that's we talked about
that before but anyway let's not do that
so so next topic next topic is going to
be I have to JavaScript topic last time
topic number eight and number nine which
is about let me post it I mean copy it
so maybe I should we should talk about
that
and it's copy the whole thing you see
you see this this window this tiny
window is a problem you know I want to
try to copy number line number eight and
nine and I'm getting a problem already
you see you see now I can't I overshoot
or undershoot you know so I cannot
understand this close to folks
crap this these people I cannot possibly
understand you what wonder they are
thinking like so guys you know map this
point like register this register this
in your mind I mean really like make a
judgment like I mean you are watching my
show right so make a judgment of what I
said
do you think am I just crazy or what
what is going on what what is a logical
resolution so is maybe maybe maybe are
this you are UX expert are they just are
they crazy like are they are they they
they they are areas they came from space
or what is going on I mean what like
mark they smoke this you know not write
it down and tell me what do you you know
what's going on I I don't understand
because I have all these kind of issues
over the past 20 years it's like an
order oh you linux people oh you
programmers you know every day has cows
the best language Emacs is the best you
know Apple is the best VI you know this
the diesel or which which window
managers in Linux is the best do you
guys actually look at this problem I
mean of all you guys you know thinking
about this which language is the best
you know oh I love trust you know trust
:
the Hass cow you know name Julia you
know so but but do too you know for my
sake to think about you know this issue
I'm talking about today this this this
this peep show window like what is going
on I mean of all your Linux people you
are interested in which window manager
is the best right I mean I have an
article which is popular on Hacker News
on reddit every every - every fourth for
five years you know every four years on
fortune on you know on the channel champ
message board so this so there are these
Linux geeks who are very interested in
you know which editor Emacs was a dream
you know which which windows manager you
know this so can you guys look at this
issue I'm talking about I mean with
which is better like which is better is
this tiny you know fixed size window is
it a good thing or is it not a good
thing like put opinion on that so I'm
you know I I'm just frustrated by these
kind of things like it's amazing I don't
know what is going on with the okay so
that is that topic and now you can you
can buy this mug okay CSS is amazing CSS
is awesome okay okay buy it for my
website that's it
make my amazon link no amazon link okay
since we mentioned this let's go to
Amazon and get the link so you if you
buy that mug that mug is what fifteen
dollars ten dollars I get fifty cents
okay let's see CSCS s is awesome now
we're gonna talk about the other topic
right so let's get back to the other
topic of okay let's just copy the whole
thing and Emacs and paste it here and
actually number eight and nine so eight
and nine okay let's just paste it here
so this is the thing we want to talk
about
okay wait so that's the two topics we
can talk about but they may be the
comments and see where we go from now so
here is CSS is awesome I'm not signed in
so I cannot I don't have my personal
link now Amazon is Amazon's choice let's
pick that copy the URL go back to Emacs
paste it here link of Phi now I got a
Hamazon link okay shirring browser you
see beautiful button now let let me read
the comments and awwe som e mug okay you
buy you go buy it and let me have a
drink and read the comments and let's
see what is the next topic so if you
have a question for me or topic post it
now
hello beautiful people
hello beautiful people says wouldn't be
easier just send money to you instead of
buying crap online yes send it to me
PayPal you know you go to my website my
Saudi info you have my paper and patreon
links so that is today's sponsor you
guys okay go there pay Bitcoin thank you
guys so let's see what what is the next
topic let me read the comments then okay
good morning guys what's a good why the
good mood smashed an open source she'll
amazing a good mood right well usually
when I wake up when you wake up
that's better kind of
okay so let's see green spots hang some
Emily welcome Emily am I allowed to post
the link to your forum on this cord to
your forum on this called who
what are you allowed to post link to
your forum on discord who but wait but
has a forum on discord
how nice of you to ask thank you I don't
mind if being shared I wish I could set
up a firewall way but you have a discord
you didn't tell me where is my discord
wait dude so what are you on this code
and you are using some other name or
something no money being shared I wish I
could say but firewall against rows but
there's no way I can achieve that
drawers spammy I don't control mind
controversy topic opinions yes jorik
good morning George you can actually
type Russian on 40% keyboard checkout
Jean keyboard I don't think so well I
you know yes you can but you can do you
can go to the moon without a computer to
without even just electronic calculator
so jean keyboard what is where yeah you
know you the thing is yeah of course you
can and you know like i said you can go
to the moon without a you know without a
computer so so you know the the the the
thing we are talking about is you know
with 40% keyboard which means only 40
keys my cream is that it's it's very
hard to type Chinese Japanese Russian
with 40 percent keyboard it's in past is
it's like you are doubling your work
that's what I'm saying yeah you can yeah
but you if you if you need to type that
2 hours a day you you're gonna see
you're
within a month that's what I'm saying
mother you alright x axis um Saxon
so Z Tron crazy do you have a good idea
what I can do with astronomy in
Mathematica because I never write a
script and it's nude for me I need to
some inspiration okay so alright so you
are studying astronomy I think so
actually I don't know anything about
astronomy you know as you know it's it's
a it's it's a physical science which in
general have me interested but that not
that I mean was you know as similar to
chemistry physics for example cosmology
you know mo is kind of all interesting
but I never you know astronomy I never
am particularly interested about so
astronomy I know back in 1990s there is
there are astronomy packages but that's
like obsolete you know because back then
you know they are astronomy software
where you can see that the Stars
configurations charts chart of the sky
you can you know and for example
astronomy what do I knew know that big
people you know there's a big deeper you
see big deeper big deeper you say how
they call it Wikipedia okay so let's go
to images save such okay let's turn save
such wrong I don't want them being too
poem okay okay so you know you you got
these various stars okay let me show you
a page of mine actually when we talk
about since since we are talking about
stars
Saburo now do you guys know those star
how they call that stars configuration
or something some music support Sbarro
okay
some use in there this is a supreme song
by the Asian star now she's a king of
she is the queen you might have heard
she's a biggest star in Asia for the she
died she died in 2005 or something like
that but she was the biggest star in
entire Asia for the let's say the past
100 years she's the biggest star
she's from up from Taiwan and and so
this is a great song and this song is
composed and written by Japanese so this
this song has got very interesting
details okay I'm not sure I should talk
about this this is very interesting
topic because it involves astronomy the
plates you know in Mars history involves
linguistics Japanese and English
I mean Japanese in Chinese involves you
know the country's relationship Japan
China it involves history of astronomy
and involves history of Chinese
astronomy and geography for example
geography this there's a story and and
the Greek astrology quicker Asian
astronomy you know because you know when
you have stars orders constellation
that's a word you see all the
constellation names are they are
typically from Greek you know there's a
big history about how they are named so
there there is a constellation called
plate plates I'm not sure how you
pronounce that and I try to find it I I
was I was not able to you know so it's
located here it's a cluster so it's near
you know Aries Perseus you know you know
but I was never able to find it I
haven't seen
so it looks like that this play it's by
the way so anyone know that so so so z
trunk crazy so one project is to locate
player play it for me
so next video you're gonna tell me how
do i how do I look for this I want to
see these players conservation now
players it turns out is a very popular
in Japan this conservation and they they
have a brand of car like Toyota home dad
they they have one called Subaru you
know that's a Japanese name sub Subaru I
don't know how you call that in Germany
but have you guys heard of that company
I mean the let me check play deeds
played play these okay so it should
supposed to be pronounced play these
okay top Japanese I don't know Japanese
I cannot talk Japanese I won't study
astronomy but I need finish the school I
need finish the school so so ZZ trunk
crazy so you are not as studying
astronomy but so why do you need
mathematical astronomy stuff play these
okay play these sure I heard of Subaru
they are everywhere right okay wait were
you from hello beautiful people you are
AC and go talk Japanese Japanese but
Japanese is a entirely different
language from Chinese they do not share
any roots
however the writing system is like 40
percent the same because Japanese
borrowed the Chinese characters that's
that's why when well when I see Japanese
writings I can recognize like thirty
percent of the characters but however
the language the pronunciation is like
entire it's a completely different from
Chinese
it's completely different Zac the Czech
Republic Prague okay oh great so let's
say you should make saying hello
beautiful people a name your running gag
hello people four people so about
astronomy packages in Mathematica so why
are you doing it that's that's the
questions each one crazy I mean if you
are not studying astronomy why why do
you need a astronomy thing in
Mathematica so actually so I cannot
recommend to you what astronomy related
things in Mathematica yeah I can I don't
know what yeah I mean what what I can
show you is probably what you can find
easily we feel if we feel real on a crow
good morning I think I know you yes you
are the guy on Twitter and on Google+
if you row refugio on a crow we met on
Google+ talking about math so if you
Rihanna Crow is a mathematician guys so
so anyway so what yeah so I don't know
any package or exercise to tell you is
easy on this Z trunk crazy ZZ trunk
crazy say something yeah so okay so let
me keep reading the comments let's see
what what's these oh okay comment okay
yeah so topic 11 Firefox new logo this
is incredible well not incredible but
Firefox got a new logo let's magnify and
see let's go here I think it's worse
okay so so doc I need to turn on
magnification wait
magnification max hey
you see there it is five Firefox Firefox
got a new logo I think it's worse what
do you guys think it's worse than before
I you know that's that's yeah five bucks
new logo I don't think it's good I turn
off the magnification I don't want that
so back to close that so thirteen
newpaper the tech pestilence let's talk
about that the tech low tech pestilence
yeah so Z trunk crazy you know your
question what can you do with astronomy
Mathematica it's like tons I mean so in
1990s there is a strongly PAC PAC
package that that allows you to chart
the stars like did we show it here yeah
like like I mentioned for example yeah
if you wanna know you you know you it
will plot these stars and you you can
also plot for example after 1 million
years how they how the constellations
will change you know because it changes
because the earth rotate he owes him in
many different ways the galaxy moves you
know things like that so the
constellation will look different in 1
million years so they will show you in
the animation you know how the
concentration changes you know today you
have not you know that software becomes
common you can find that even on your
phone I think and this it's it's free
it's amazing you know I remember someone
showed me an app you just take your
phone point it at the sky at night and
it will tell you what are the
constellations you are looking at so you
know that's technology so today you have
lots of that but back then 19 in 1990
someone this guy Alan something I know
he's very own now I haven't talked to
him for thirty years he wrote a package
for astronomy you know you can do all
also of that so yeah but but the exactly
like like like what do you want so I
don't know what to suggest about
astronomy so when did you ask for
anything so I gave a point but that
bothers me anyway but I bother Bonnie
anyway so there here is another buzzword
that explains UI choice mobile first
okay Mobile first
okay I haven't heard of that but I can
see it is a trend yeah because because
mobile is is has more traffic it's
taking
you know computers desktop melodious boy
is okay we we are we already scrapped
that melodious voice you know for that
to work I need to do one and midnight
like over here then I'm forced to be
quiet then you know the things change
these people are staggered keyboard
pinky pushing and touch typing and geek
nummies bathroom you says they do not
understand your United computing path
art says I actually agree with all your
comment on UX you just talked about
great Allen says the matrix is mobile
first you have seen the cracks the
matrix what matrix
okay I don't know what is that Juno Juno
is a recent Jupiter mission and Jared
wrote some software to associate to each
pixel 3d coordinates on the planet's
surface that is for where every color
channel in every pixel hook okay I don't
know yeah I don't know much about
astronomy okay so the next topic is
random I guess so how long have I been
talking let's see 15 minutes the next
topic is
13 okay love tick okay let's talk about
non-tech so you go to search for why
kick sucks here the tech pestilence wide
tech latech sucks by the way if you
don't know tech and low tech the X is
supposed to be pronounced you know it's
like voiced edge that's you know that's
what Donald Knuth says you know Tech and
that hey not text you know not text in
that X so anyway so I have this I have a
giant huge humongous elephant I went
against tech you know I think when is
one of the worst garbage on the in the
universe the worst technical markup
language the worst [ __ ] that that has
done tremendous damage to the math
community okay that's tech now I
actually did a video on this few months
ago so we are not going to revisit that
you can read my articles you know so but
what what what is new is that someone
showed me I think it's George or is it
someone show me a new article from
researchers that damages that damage is
you know take here is here is the
research article it just came out like
what year did this year or last year so
he says an efficiency comparison of
document preparation systems used in
academic research and development okay
bye Maka's north and jelica not jazz
Mick okay so it's from Department of
Psychology experimental psychology and
cognitive science university of geun's
and gay guys and something
grace and Germany okay where is that but
or ends it Ron crazy and Matt you German
people why is that so anyway so this
Arco abstract let's read it the choice
of an efficient document preparation
system is an important decision for any
academic researcher to assist the
research community we report a software
usability study in which 40 researchers
across different disciplines prepared
scholarly texts with either Microsoft
Word or latech the probe the probe texts
includes simple continuous text text
with tables and subheadings and complex
text with several mathematical equations
anyway umbrella we show that latex users
were slower than word users were less
text in the same amount of time and
produced more typesetting although
graphical grammatical and formatting
errors most measures expert latech users
perform performed even worse they novice
what users latech users however more
often report enjoying using their
respective software we conclude that
even experienced latech users may suffer
a loss of productivity when our text is
used relative to other document
preparation systems individuals
institutions and journals should
carefully concealed carefully consider
the ramifications of this finding when
choosing document preparation strategies
or requiring requiring them of authors
so it's a damnation on logic here and I
applaud [ __ ] UNIX [ __ ] Linux so what so
what do you guys say
now again
you know I know you know as you know we
in but bosses in Germany yeah I know
it's in Germany he says they are the
universities in Germany like but we're
like which it's in Henson rather in the
center of Germany okay so this face okay
so so you know anyways you know I know
many of my followers because we I mean
open source community right the Linux
you know the Neelix free software so a
lot of people love that take you know
the it's it's like a obsession it's like
you know Emacs you know Tech see Tech is
the worst [ __ ] and now the now we have
these research papers you know put put
out a damnation online text and I'm sure
it has no effect why it has absolutely
no effect or view Allah take you love us
because why because the reason you love
you
you are phonetic of low tech tech or the
reason you are phonetic of Emacs or the
reason you are finicky phonetics of
Linux is not because each of these is
the best tool you know it's not because
they are great towards even you claim to
say that it's because fanaticism and
ideology that is why you know that is
where your your fervent your your fervor
attached to you know and and and the
result is that you keep saying Linux is
the best that heck is the best
Emacs is the best the actually that's
that's not your concern yogi yeah it's a
belief okay it's a code it's a belief
system so what I'm saying is that this
article will have no effect first of all
you will not know this article exists
you will not see it you know well you
watch my video you see it but you will
now see it mentioned or when whenever
it's mentioned for example if someone if
you post this on
canoes or read it you'll be voted down
okay
you'll be you're not be widespread okay
for example if you post under how I can
use maybe you got some votes up
okay maybe okay most likely you know is
there's a good chance you'll be all over
the way hold it down therefore nobody
will see it
okay but even if it's even if it has
some uploads it will not spread that's
the thing you see because you don't want
to spread things you don't you know that
that damage is your ideology your belief
that's why just like religion so you
will not this article has no effect and
of course someone will see this and you
know they will read abstract abstract
and they will say oh that's [ __ ] oh
they made that methodology is wrong you
know they will happen so anyway so is it
so so what this so about this study
itself what do I think is it valid is it
true I don't know you know I haven't
read it I'm not going to read it you
know it's not it's not important it's
just it's it's like politics this these
kind of things goes on you know for the
past thirty years
you know Linux Emacs you know the good
point you know bad-mouthing it or you
know it's it's just fight but their
conclusion in my opinion is valid you
know I'm not going to spend the time to
read it you know and you might say oh
you didn't read it but how can you say
it's valid or not I have a heavy
experience okay I you know I've seen
this a thousand times so I'm not going
to read it I I believe it's likely true
okay it's it's it's in fact you can I
believe it's true because you can
actually easily see it yourself you know
like tell your mom to write a formula x
squared
you know x squared with a little square
on top you know your mom you know
whoever your dad okay we have you know
they they can do it in Microsoft Word
after they say one hour they can talk to
it we
protects after 10 hours they don't know
what to do
that is that that is a key okay so that
is about that topic okay so anything so
helpful beautiful hello beautiful people
what what is exactly is wrong about
unix/linux
and see could you point out some bad
practices that were taken overall bad
influences I talked about that in the
past half a year
it's almost every of my video contains
huge amount of that so I'm not so you
know I'm not gonna talk to that again
the most recent is like okay check out
this you know if you are interested
beautiful people beautiful people if you
are interested let me show you okay
yesterday is actually two days ago it's
a this I think it's a good one
okay this this one this one the title is
why open source Linux phonetics can
never create good user interface now so
this is saw talk show 2019 October 26th
this is like two days ago so you know
human you might check it out you know
you know he to if you are if you are
interested to see my opinion this is one
of them you know I've done so many this
this is reasonably a good one kind of
okay so I started Safari by mistake
close it
I started by mistake because I have Auto
Creek I you know so it's going random
because my again I put my pen on the
tablet
that's why
so Ruth how do you pronounce your name
roof roof you real review real we feel
real says tech is a turbo programming
language yes but there aren't many
alternatives if you prefer a source code
like the way to edit math formulas you
know you can collaborate with kit I
think there are a lot a lot alternatives
there is Mathematica there is asking
math there is in math ml you see the
problem is that there are a lot
alternatives but they were killed they
are all cut they all got killed by the
tech pestilence you know but by this
ideology phonetics you know who just
want to push tech so when they whenever
they see they will not promote any
alternative they will say no stop it we
just want text okay stop you know they
will flame you on on Stack Overflow and
hacker news everywhere so they basically
just like UNIX they kill any alternative
that's the thing so you don't think you
know even few years okay so so so that's
what I'm saying so even you know so as
everyone is singing a song subtext to
attack you know because because it's
part of the open source you know kind of
trend you know community it's is that's
why few years we few we oh okay I like
see I wouldn't write anything of
importance in it oh my meat Doc's think
of few years anachronism
okay so bar says what's your favorite
syntax type so Freddie Freddie Freeman
so actually we are out of topic now so
I've done this topic and that's that's
like that's it about that and now let's
see how long I've been talking okay
maybe we can get ready to shut down
maybe five minutes ten more minutes so
if you have questions for me type it or
comments opinions on what we talked
about if you want me to comment on it so
by the way why is refugio why is your
name in gray box like you have a
checkmark like are you in some way like
verified or something that's interesting
did I try key Mouse are you the guy who
asked me that before no I never tried
because someone there's someone I don't
remember the name sorry but a month ago
he because of his single sub he's
verified because of single sub I don't
know I got verify doing Google+ times oh
okay great so okay so the question is
about key Mouse so a month ago maybe two
months ago someone asked me about that
and it turns out he actually has it so
he made some great comments let me try
to find it if I can find it so so
where's the key Mouse yeah so key Mouse
is called do it yourself so key mouse is
this one I never tried it and I'm not
likely to buy it
I think they sell for 500 dollars even
if they sell only for 300 dollars I
wouldn't buy it and if they do it for
200 you know because why I don't you
know it I don't particularly like this
idea because this for my own preference
I find it too pokey you know I don't
want to my hands to move the entire
thing like you know that doesn't seems
doesn't attract me I don't feel like you
know I don't doesn't attract me this
idea and this kind of you know I feel it
feels like ugly and awkward but you know
but that's just my
and I never tried it apparently this
some people are buying it and you know
and so there is this guy let's see if I
can find it let's go to my talk show
search for key mouse someone made a
comment about that and it turns out he
actually has it ok this guy yeah
Marge massage what toe which so he says
for example let's see highlights phrase
hold on second highlight phrase
highlight his name ok highlight in
yellow so he says you know I have been
using this device for eight months
took me about one month to remap it to
make Emacs easy I can give you more user
experience details so he has tried it
that's all I know about that
yeah but it's not something I yeah I
don't like this kind I think it's kind
of pokey Oh
so here's a photo of the you know key
Mouse and various others comparison you
can see so here is Kinesis which is what
I use this is what I use you guys go buy
it buy it now ok Kinesis my hand here
and so that's Canisius and then you have
the this this is the tactile which you
can buy for 350 same thing of 344
Kinesis and the key mouse I think is
$500 so you can see the key Mouse is
actually much pokey yeah so I think
that's about it for today that makes
your conversation so interesting and a
bit of effort to be Siva what's your
favorite syntax style seems like you
like what sir hates Hank I found of a
camo ok so this will get interesting
review Rios's I'm quite fond of all camo
or any ml dialect dialect for that
matter yes
so refugio is a expert of oh camel he
has you know correct me if I'm wrong
he's actually a you know working for me
or camo for for you know for for living
but I don't think its syntax is
beautiful so forth is kind of beautiful
so is this he's really big he's really
nothing against you personally what
why ignore me name the real-life example
so what what did Freddie say okay
Freddie says please consider the example
of having hundreds of images wouldn't
you agree
inserting this in a document using a
Prague programmatic way is much more
effective
what would crash and take forever to do
please consider the example of having
hundreds of images in latech so so you
are saying so if you have latech you if
you are preparing a documentation where
it involves hundreds let's say 200
images and so you are saying latech in
that case it's better than Microsoft
Word because Microsoft Word will
probably crash ok so first of all I
don't know if that's true you know maybe
it's true let's suppose it's true okay
in this case Microsoft you once you have
like 200 images you're just crash so you
can use that take yeah even if I agree
to that
the tech is still sucks by a magnitude
you know you cannot use this one
specific example you know because you
have to you know like okay I'm not going
to spend much time to start a rant about
that because I talked about this too
much there's a video I talk about a lot
here because you know to think about
your mom you know someone named prove
non-technical like I said before like
consider this point okay I know when
when it comes to religious issues when
you talk people don't listen like they
whatever you say just fly by just fly by
then they're gonna counter with with a
question that you you just answered you
know they it's like I say you know this
is like that way
comes to like ideology or you know
things like that when you are leaving a
coat you don't you don't get it is
whatever the reason people say just just
fly by and they then you immediately ask
the question that is just exactly talked
about as so you also consider this point
Freddie and you know I'll assume you are
you know like like I don't know what
exactly is your opinion or maybe you
know you are half joking maybe you are
half joking right you are maybe you know
I don't know you are maybe you are
trying to help my channel gets busy but
anyway let's let's suppose I mean
consider this point okay my my why I am
you know one example again is not take
and take why I think this sucks
just like Linux like like I mentioned
before ask your mom to type this okay
let me show let's show it and it's close
this and I actually open it copy it
close it go to today's talk show open it
and paste this talk show link there and
then let's do this okay so I want to do
x squared
okay so let's magnify okay so you can
see we are about done we close down in
two minutes
so I want to render this okay so in HTML
what you can do is what I can do is like
sup okay
sub to okay so okay so show in browser
you can see X square you see now ask
your mom to do that to do that okay just
a document with nothing except that okay
so let's open a new buffer switch to it
HTML mod then enter okay template so we
have a new HTML h1
add an h1 tag and let's say that okay so
let's uh you know ii see so they're not
showing browser okay save it save it
okay showing browser now you see that x2
ask your mom to do it and see how long
does she take ask her to do this in
latech see how long it take the
difference if she can do this in one
hour figure she can figure out within a
dark or whatever in one hour how long
will she take her for her to do this in
tecala tech i would say it's in ten
hours maybe
okay in two hours it's a it's a
magnitude of detail of difference that
is the point that that is the thing you
should okay it so so I'm presenting this
point to you you have to answer so
Freddie answer
what's your reply to this you know I'm
trying to get you to what's your reply
okay so Freddie's reply is obviously she
would need to look it up since it's a
language then it is just one command
yeah so I mean that's your excuse I mean
that that is like you know when you say
Linux can do this or that then in ox a
so actually you can you just read the
[ __ ] you just need to read the
[ __ ] documentation then it's just one
command yeah but the fact I mean we are
now concerned how you how simple it is
you know the question is your mom you
know and my mom can do this in one hour
but she cannot do this in latech you'll
be 10 hours that that is the point then
you reply oh yeah but the Unitec is just
one simple command to understand the
concept of command she know what is the
command you know like Linux then you
start to mention oh you all you need is
is a kernel
they becomes Oh
just open the editor and modify this
config file that's it you know it takes
five minutes open start of lean startup
in edit one single one line just change
one character that's it that's so simple
Linux that's that's what I'm seeing your
replies like did you like do you get my
point
so as I said it's not mean for everyday
document document setting is my point
no I disagree okay well yeah you know
you see now you change the question so
now you are saying no so it seems okay
from your response I get I'm seeing now
you are saying that okay latech or tech
is better than a Microsoft for certain
documentation now you see you kind of
changed like before the latech phonetics
is like hola Tech is the best best
better than Microsoft Word for sure but
now it's like once you you know no no
it's like a lot egg is for some
documentation in spreader after we talk
about it then it becomes Ola Tech is
only for some technical academic people
then it's better than what you you see
it modifies but when when you are you
know selling that tech you know on
Twitter and you don't mention that so
Freddie says no not change definitely
nothing in our tech is the best but it
does have its space that is all I'm
saying
yeah I agree that it does have its face
that's everything else has its place you
know so what I'm saying is is you see I
am kind of attacking this kind of
ideology finesse ISM that exists in
Linux in a tech that's what I'm saying
what I'm saying is that all the good
things you hear common like you hear it
every day at hacker news on stack over
for you hear it almost every every week
for sure like we can go there stack
overflow you will see you know
everywhere they they say how great it is
lot egg is much better than would you
see that and yeah I seen that for 20
years at least 20 30 years since 1990
side in 1990 so I read everything about
that take Oki I also do lot take back
then you know and so you know so you
hear this I mean what I'm saying is just
lie you've been lied to for 30 years and
you don't realize that that that is the
thing I'm trying to push I'm not trying
you know
then you I'm not I don't mean you again
you know I mean the general my my follow
is my friends my desuka I mean you know
these linux people they say you know I
take is the best everything should be
detect oh and it's open source so what
I'm saying is that I'm not just simply
arguing oh maybe Microsoft is better
that that's that's already beyond the
point I'm saying you've been lied to for
30 years and I'm trying to tell you to
realize this discrepancy that you don't
see that is my point so you know like
stop stop you know like going to need
picky details
oh but but actually latex is actually
better than word for this or that that's
that's not my point my main point is the
fanaticism and ideology of the
unix/linux
you know latech oh this open source is
been lying to you lie lie lie blatant
black and white lie force force
information spread misinformation spread
by this fanatism i'm pretty sure most of
you are good people but you are pushing
a lie
vennett because because of fanaticism
because you really want to you know
believing open source you know good for
the people you think it's good you know
you are thinking it is good so you are
pushing it you hate Microsoft
so therefore everyone's you know DC
Microsoft so what my point is that you
guys are making are doing lies lying to
people miss the information
we feel real you know III you know as
most of you know you know I have lots of
controversial opinions and you are
saying I'm a fundamentalist that's
questionable okay you as am i you know
I'm a fundamentally you guys are you
guys open source phonetics a
fundamentalist that's what I'm if you
really push me to answer for that
question you know like who is
fundamentals the leanest people anyway
it's not I'm not you know let's not get
start to I think that's it for today
because I've been ranting for every day
yeah I know I know you don't agree okay
we we feel real but we you know we're
gonna argue about that in this because
that's that's you know I've been talking
about this in my videos for so many
times but I mean so so I mean it's not I
mean I you know it's not gonna be like
either I'm right or you are right I mean
I knows you know if you know you know
the you know it's just conversation it's
just conversation you know I'm
presenting my ideas you disagree you
post your reasons okay you post you know
comment you know you post the reasons
and and that's good I'm trying to agree
every everybody don't be fandom and
fundamentalist yeah I I see what you're
saying you are right yes that's true
yeah this the word is not black and
white you know and I'm being dramatic
often so anyway so I think that's it for
today so yeah we're gonna shut down
should we're gonna shut down in 1
minutes I think let's see how long have
I been talking
14 people yeah so we shut down in one
minute let's see who is who is Gaius
Castile so we see or leg VI so it looks
like he is this guy how I am able to
make notes in mathematics
so ah ha so who is he so say something
or like so tell tell us who is he
Freemont great Freddy see oh yeah you
see thank you for coming by we furio's
thank you guys
he's a math guy so let's read about this
guy
Gil's Costello mathematics program in
piano aha
I have caught you browsing my profile
for what reasons I might be my dad be
feel free to drop a message I'm open to
all personal website Who am I I'm young
Dutch speaking Belgium who is interested
let's see
God Cora you know that you don't have
JavaScript they prevent you from
creaking you know this is okay so let's
quick more okay Who am I am a young
Dutch speaking Belgium who is interested
in math in programming in vim in piano
in dinners in typography in latech I
make my documents with latech I draw
diagrams in tick Z I made a basic math
tutorial here okay design yeah okay once
the questions some of my hands are like
this is a typical nerd he doesn't say
anything about himself really he's just
this bunch of tech things it's like you
know like like you see why you know when
you read a bio you want to get to know
the person not the list of what colors
he like which is typical of the Nerds
you know they just do oh I like this
programming languages yeah I want to
know that person what what you did you
know what
how are you married how many girlfriends
you have what kind of person you are
not your interest in philosophy you know
typically nerds are do that so he's a
mathematics mathematics student
immediately and he's a student the
university interesting in math you know
typically students when you are student
you
you talk a lot you have opinions about
the world but when you become professor
you you stop talking typically that's
the case that's a generally true okay so
I don't see anything special actually
you know I'm gonna thank you guys that's
it for today I guess
by Z Tron Z's from crazy Fredman paid by
Fred you know that YouTube has a thing
like once I caught a quick stop
streaming all your messages will not
show in the YouTube
so anyway bye guys