good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show
today is July 12 2019 four o'clock p.m.
San Francisco time and that mean they're
not ready yet so let me prepare me tell
people that I'm live
okay
starts now it's hot here today I just
took a shower and this is a fantastic
song ok I'm not I don't have a topic
today
today's topic is random okay so let me
starts tell people to start now and this
is master Dan
you know master Dan has been kind of you
know the it's like fringe he's dying you
know the open source idiots they think
this is gonna you know they think this
is going to take over Twitter it's like
they they are thinking Linux is going to
wipe out Microsoft from like 20 years
ago it's not going to happen it's not
going to happen because not because open
source doesn't have the force so free
software foundation the same before
speaker but rather because this is open
source or free software fanatics are
idiots you know for example master then
you know like these people I mean maybe
it's because of the young people the
generation like human animals like human
good morning tenyo tenyo ylang-ylang no
micro is how are you doing you know so I
was saying you know the Linux people
free software or open source phonetics
they are not they are it's almost like
they will never ever be successful you
know what they want you know so what do
they want in general they want they want
a society where you know people have
power you know every you know small
people
it's like democracy you know small
people have power you know software like
we are not controlled by big
corporations and you know everyone is
good people we share you know we share
what we have like software that is the
that's kind of the essence of the free
software open source the tenets the the
force behind them it's not actually it's
not the force but it's it's the ideal is
the it's the heart of the ideology
behind them you know so that we will
have a society where you know everyone
is good we share stuff we share in
particular you know software you know in
software free software foundation and
open source it's you know they are about
software so we share resources and Linux
you know it's free open-source software
you know covering system so we can all
share we don't have to be we don't have
to be slaves of cooperation you know you
look like Google or Microsoft you know
Apple where they could it did whatever
whatever they want they do bad things
such as you know when Apple for example
when when they have a new phone coming
out they intentionally make you know
they have software to make your phone
slower so it calls you into you know
buying a new the ladies you know another
phone things like that and Microsoft you
know they do things they sell and Google
you know Facebook they sell your data
you know even if you turn off all the to
know the privacy controls they say you
know I don't want my data to be gathered
but they do it anyway illegally they can
get away with it because they are more
powerful and this these states these big
corporations are they are trampling of
open-source because it benefits them but
then bad but then you have this bunch of
idiotic facts in open source and free
software phonetic state they are singing
open source every day for the benefit of
the corporate the corporations exactly
the opposite of the what they want so I
was saying you know so you know like
mastodons you know we were looking at
mastered its trump its trumpeted trumpet
it you know in its son you know it's
supposed to be you know other geeks
saying oh this is great this is
you know this is gonna finally the power
the information is to the people this is
distributed yeah same old story these
idiots they never saw so I was saying
they don't Nick never going to get
anywhere
you know this Linux that like all this
or you guys okay you know this the the
essential cause of these free software
open source I support you know I want
that as well you know power to people so
you have you know each person have you
know some power you know it's all
together like there's no one centralized
power that controls everything you know
tell you what to do so I want that as
well but but so what I'm saying is that
but this Linux this open so typical
typical open source and free software
phonetics they are just idiotic in so
many aspects that so I am saying that
they will never almost never never get
near even even close to the situation
where where the software for example is
not centralized by these giant
corporations in fact these days it's was
it's you know so the is so you know it's
like we are you know let's predict the
future what will happen after 10 years
you know go go sing your songs about
open source causing your free software
sports you know this has been happening
in the past 20 years 20 or 30 years
depending on how you count and I you
know I you know I'm old enough you know
to have observed everything you know
from the beginning from the from the
from the beginning of open-source in
1996 also and you know free software
foundations began in 1990 1980s 5 or
something like that so anyway so you
know if we you know if you are
open-source fan you think about the
future you know let's say you know think
about in 10 years we are you will you
get what you want you know
your ideology your thought your
enthusiasm for these oh we must be open
source must be open source this or that
you know you think about after 10 years
what will happen you know if you ask me
it's gonna get worse if things keeping
the way they are so why does that happen
so why is that I mean I mean obviously
so if you are open source you know open
source panel free software foundation
fan um you know so you you seen the
stones every day about free software you
know you are fanatic so why does it why
why does the society why does it has no
effect or rather reverse effect you know
so why does this happen so in my opinion
this happens because because you did
okay okay well seriously because you
know when you want something to happen
you know Society it's in a sense it's
complex okay it's not just because you
want to push something ideology you
chant about something every day things
will go your way it's not like that you
have to you know in a sense you know
some people say you know you have to you
know know realities it's not whatever
you say hey good morning George are you
the judge using stuff like this so
anyway so I was ranting about free
software foundation and you know
open-source the phonetic as you know
those phonetics so because we were
looking at master done you know what
master done is you know for those of you
don't know master done is you know it's
like Twitter okay it's a technically
it's called micro blog you know it's
like Twitter so you know I have my
account here I treat every day it seems
you know mastered and I have account
since like three years ago so about
three or was it two years ago two or
three years ago master you know someone
created some open-source idiot and he is
actually the millennial generation he
actually you know he created the master
den and they are quite a few before
master then you know sorry mate anyway
back to master then so what is it it's a
micro blog micro blogging software and
it's distributed so it's not centralized
control meaning that you know each one
person can run a server for example I'm
on this server by the way if you want to
get our master then I recommend this
server so this server you know em STD
and dot IO
so you can see this server is is in
France and so why this one because they
do not do any any censorship you know
they are you know they do they don't
they don't do any censorship
so anyway master then began like three
years ago and all the left you know so
millennia so you know they think oh this
is finally disease this is a platform to
to get away from the anyway it's getting
political you know they are talking
about you know certain political party
in Germany you know it was you know they
think Mastodon is a new platform to get
get away from you know that and that's
just the giant lie
in fact Macedon was is I'm getting into
this topic you know it's not like that
at all but anyway so then you know I
have a lot followers and also friends
like I followed like you know many of
them a lot of them huge amount like mod
majority of them are of course they are
all open source offense open source
whatever and you know so wherever I have
you know I [ __ ] about open source many
of them don't agree of course sometimes
they are you know like we taught oh yeah
but you know Linux is great in this add
that I cannot I cannot take that idea I
cannot tolerate that they you it doesn't
matter if you are following
me okay you a friend or not you know I
you know I I put out my opinions what I
believe is true even that is truly you
know I truly believe it you know I all
things considered if I take that to be
true and so the way the way I think
about most of these open-source
phonetics okay the extreme part about
them open source of free software
phonetics they are just they are just
they are they are like Flat Earth you
know Peter he was that's that is my
opinion so when he told I shoot back
right away like I can I can type
non-stop like it happens the few times
with this guy Jeremiah okay he's a
friend he is a he also actually he knows
this and Mathematica he so you know in
this so every time you know my followers
sometimes I treat bad things about open
source or gayness Linux and then they
will retort and I we told right away
and of course often they will respond
right away to so we we start to argue
you know like a flame war but I'm I'm
relentless you know yeah like if you
want to argue with me you lose you know
you have no chance I type faster than
you and I have you know 20 years of
rants fighting with this what a [ __ ]
Firefox you know [ __ ] Firefox Firefox
they donated money to antifa they are
dying and they are killed by Google and
Google is doing these devious things
every day to to wipe out Firefox yeah
and also you know Microsoft browser and
now Firefox is like oh you know you
you've got the latest browser now gather
as a [ __ ] Firefox they want to
register they want you to register
account so that they can get info from
you and they can sell your data
[ __ ] Firefox and if you don't know by
the way they the Firefox guys they
donated money yeah I mean they had
several disasters in the past few years
and one of them is that they donated
they donated money to aunt Eva okay
this violent group you know and you can
if you want to know you know just go to
youtube in such for Firefox aunt Eva
donate to aunt Eva but actually today it
since about a month ago you go to
YouTube you cannot find you such it's
heavily censored you cannot find you
know anything anymore
I'm not sure you can even find that for
example let's try it let's go to
youtube.com okay I digressed so much so
what's my topic before it's a bit it's a
bit hot you know I actually because I
have my doors closed and the sun is
shining so if there is some greenhouse
effect I guess so that's why I'm I'm
topless it will have more effect if I'm
a girl you know sometimes you see girls
they play piano on YouTube you know
connage hole or this face you know the
girls play piano and it's like they are
naked
they are topless but actually they are
wearing you know women has this you know
how do you call it tough tablet you know
it's like how do you call that you know
it's like a you know formal dress but
they start to cover only you know in the
beginning of their breasts so but it
almost looks like they are topless so
strapless yes that's the right word
Firefox so it's this search for Firefox
donate and Tifa it was big news okay you
see aunt Eva okay let's see if we can
still find it no it's gone yeah you see
you these are not should not be the
so it's team for the [ __ ] Google you
know so these days you cannot the day
okay so so finally we found one mozilla
funding and Tifa Hanako communists rise
up in there are several videos you know
so this so this happened one year ago i
thought it's like almost two years ago
now wait so yeah so you know so you know
firefox is its it who's hold on a second
box so you know this month's box is one
of the social justice fake news every
day extreme box is one of the extreme
social justice lie you know lie everyday
lie lie that you can verify in this sky
[ __ ] okay I don't know if they'd lie
you know they'd they'd lie all the time
they rely on the fact that most people
do not spend time to take into
information so they can you know all
these Guardian guardian New York Times
Box vice they did you know today just
like fake news every day Fox Fox News on
the other hand is you know the right
wing you know you could say it's biased
again is you know from the right wing
but but Fox is striving you know like
the you know like right now older CNN or
the basically many most of the left-wing
you know the social media I mean the the
media the mainstream media they they
lost viewership you know drastically
dramatically and Firefox is the most
popular now so anyway why so I was
talking about this close that so I was
talking about you know five bucks anyway
so so I what we were talking about
we were talking about
masterda you know I just happen to be
honest then because you know random
BuzzFeed's feed yes BuzzFeed is one also
one of the number-one fake news numbers
on the number one fakes news New York
Times BuzzFeed the the Vice you know the
company vice or whatever the motherboard
you know and and aj+ something like AJ
Presley you can see well you know they
they spirit like you like you can verify
like each instead its incident you know
whatever every day on Twitter they are
you know anchor every day big big and
small incidents every day you can look
into and you know they and the ditch in
general it just you know it's just
typically typically it's a left can the
can stir and anyway so so yeah I was
talking about I was ranting about again
is the open source free software of
phonetics so you know we were talking
about master then so master then is this
micro blogging software it's you know
it's distributed so it's not centralized
and all the people there is like oh
please you know oh it's you know go to
Macedon so it's not controlled by
Twitter you know these these open source
free software fantasy you know dreaming
fantasy idiots needs of [ __ ]
you know idiots because they make our
life what was they make their life their
own you know like they have a core you
know we have a core we want a better
society we want a better society we want
people to be good you know we share
power to the people
but but the open source [ __ ] and is
free software what they do every day is
that they they they're they are humming
that goal you know they are making it
far worse they are making Google
Facebook and Twitter more and more
powerful by these these open-source
[ __ ] so you know so this
you know the mestan Midna often they are
geeks
okay nerds you know where is where my
community okay so they they they you
know so they have these they want these
but you know they tell people to go on
to Master Dan but but every but as I
said you know like if you look into ten
years I can imagine try to be a future
futurist you know try to try to in you
know picture the future what will happen
you know so anyway master then you know
these people wishing thinking that you
know message is gonna take over Twitter
it's not happening in fact the master
then since three years ago it's strained
out and drained out it's like and
Macedon is not the only case they are
like they are civil before they are cool
social okay before and Oakland also show
is right now it's connected to master
than the guna so show there's this is
another one there's there are quite a
few before and this open source
brainwashed fanatics they don't see it
they don't see you know they just just
like any average normal people they get
brainwashed into believing things they
even things they want but you know they
did they don't get it they don't you
don't see and also so what wise master
then we are not pick up they are there
are many reasons okay you know part of
the you know there are quite a lot
reasons and part of the reason is the
technology itself the design the design
of every aspects of a software including
Linux they influenced how popular it
will become now many net many tech you
know tech kickers we all think oh it's
just you know software depends on how
you know the technical quality it is no
not that's not it's not you know what
how good it is it's not that's that's
that's not what you know you know the
what decides it's going to make it or
break it
break
you know but for example let me give you
some examples of the master than idiocy
it's I'm not sure I should do that
because because there are so many and
you know I wasn't prepared to talk about
this but you know so I don't so you know
but for example if I start to post
something I start to post a picture of
something I have examples and I can tell
you but without doing that I you know I
wasn't prepared I don't know what so
anyway I was just mentioning about
master dance so this this is master then
okay so if you want good to go to master
then you know I recommend this instant
instance this MST D and dot IO is from
friends okay they don't they don't do
censorship you know and okay so master
Dan has several problems you quite a lot
problems first of all it's insecure you
know these tech idiots they think they
think Macedon is so secure it's far more
insecure than Twitter and also whatever
you post your data you know it's far
more likely your password will be stolen
okay because first of all master Dan is
distributed meaning that any Joe can run
an instance I can I can run an instance
and you have no way to know that they
are running the exact same software you
know the master then you know the open
source one the I can modify it people
have done you know all the instances
instances people you can you can modify
the code and so when you register master
master then you know you type of
password
today you know whoever is running the
server can know protect potentially can
know all your passwords whatever your
private messages in and by the way there
was also a bug this happened about a
year a year ago like when you private
message someone okay let's let me
private message someone someone who on
our since who are not since
about you know like I'm not going to do
it but you know let's say if you private
message someone okay you know I let's
say something I I need to type add
someone ends and what's this stupid you
know this stupid interface okay that's
one of the proper [ __ ] CW right
you're one is oh yeah that that's
another okay here you see you can choose
to have I don't know if you can see it
can you see it it's part of the screen
covered okay so yeah you you you know
you can say follow only direct yeah
direct message you know that's like a
private so a year ago to that when you
send a private message to someone you
know other instances can see all your
private messages you know so I was you
know I was flirting with a girl okay
let's say let's say that okay so I was
working with a girl so we you know we
did say the private messages then she
told me you know there's this Macedon
bug what the [ __ ] you know so that's the
that's a problem that's just one of the
problem a student is you know it's got
lots of problems all these open source
anyway
anyway and in Linux anyway the same
thing with Linux okay I was going to
master then here I was actually I was
going to type you know I'm I'm live on
YouTube but now he rendered for how long
let's see half an hour so that's almost
like a topic by today that's so rameen
we then let's see check out the let's
check out the you percent of all the
smartphones in a word when our Linux
82% of the order smartphones in
award-winner Linux what
so do nine of the top ten per break
crowds so so what so what what you know
so with what what is the point you know
yeah Google Linux is popular on the
server especially you know on the server
it's almost like you know 90% old you
know hundred percent already Linux
server especially Google Google began
but why not because Linux is oh it's a
you know more raw morality or free
software foundation no nuts because that
because why does Google you know us
begin with Linux because it's free
there's some [ __ ] free you know you
take away the free the free like free
money okay you take away the free money
you know free software foundation all
the Linux all the open source we all die
within a day your video disappear on the
face of earth with the day you know [ __ ]
the Linux you know like the the the the
geeks typically this this this elite
hacker types [ __ ] yeah they are like
every day there's a oh yeah oh yeah
what's the face they say all free P or
be a versus you know what was the phrase
they say like when it comes to the word
free they have a phrase like you know
it's it's not like peer but it's when
was need I think the in this video I
have said [ __ ] for you know hundred
times ten thousand times yeah yeah so so
Linux is running everywhere so does it
does it help us does it does it help you
know individual powerless people like me
or like you do it does it help us it
helped Google for sure does it so what
what is a point about 99% let's say ten
ninety percent of all the servers are
Linux so all the servers are you know so
that they did help you
did did it help you fighting the giant
evil Microsoft in Google did did it okay
Daniel says seems to say something for
my sauce design and enthusiastic it
seems to say something for open source
design no it doesn't seem that way to me
it seems to me Google because Linux is
open source any is free meaning you know
money is that you don't have to pay
therefore Google chose the Linux to run
as their server and you know they become
this giant evil empire and and the
enthusiastic supporters I don't think so
yeah I mean sure they are enthusiastic
supporters you you guys and you counting
me if you want to you know but this
aside as I mentioned before these people
we hackers you know these kind of people
are fringe like like what percent of
society are these people are ours 0.0001
Oh zero what add another 0 ok that's us
you know so what you're gonna do
master thing is company yes and also
isn't a standard open-source project
what do you mean it's not a standard
open-source project good morning greens
pata pata Romeo Jas strapless yes
good morning colors are there and George
says and they they fired Brendan Eich
yes exactly they you know this social
justice they got problems the Brendan
Eich you know the issue you know I I
don't really I'm following him now since
like two years ago or two years ago so I
saw his post every day he is very
interesting guy he's a nerd okay he's
very he's very he's a nerd okay
now you see he's a great programmer you
know of course he wrote he created
JavaScript and you know he back in 1995
and he's you know JavaScript compiler
and and and you know he's he's you know
one of the great programmer and but I
was saying you but he's a nerd you know
because most programmers you know when
when they are that big like Brenda Ike
you know he's you know running you're
CEO of some companies when they get old
like 50 60 they of course they'd run a
company they become manager so you know
they are the founder of some companies
and they don't they don't go online and
talk about programming languages or
which language is better which you know
should we you know you know like you
should we use a for loop or should we
use a list comprehension you know they
did it they don't do that when you are
programmer when you when you become big
like you know the java the java inventor
what's his name Gosling you know order
although almost all of them when you
become big you you know you become
manager you stop coding and also you
don't you know I mean even you know even
if you still code it's it's it's rather
rare to find you know programmers you
know become who become big and still
coding you know like Richard Stallman he
haven't [ __ ] coded for like 20 years
10 years at least here he have no idea
what's going on like he's even posting
question question about what what is
male pod you know what hey you richard
stallman so anyway brendan is very
interested in guy because I follow him
since two years ago I wasn't following
him before I don't really know him but I
started to follow him because I want to
support the anti social justice [ __ ]
okay so that's why I started to follow
him and I started to use the brave
browser which is this one which
startup he he created I used my browser
since like a year or two ago and so I
started to follow him and anyway he is
an interesting note he's a nerd type
because every day he's still going go
around talking about language design
like which which which way is better and
things like that almost like you know
going to arguments with people about
JavaScript and stuff yeah that's so
that's unusual
rather rare you know not he's a nerd and
and also I've seen you know so since I
started to follow him I sometimes I
watched a video where he talked about
you know pretty browser or some issues
you know and he's good he's he's he's
not someone you know like today we have
a lot videos you know programmers you
know at Google Google IO whatever you
know they give presentations you know
and often they are very smooth you know
they but Brendan this he's not he cannot
give he cannot give presentations he is
like stuttering all the time or whatever
or say you know talking about some topic
for like five minutes but you don't get
what is what is his point you know so so
Brendan Eich is that's my that's my
impression of him so so when when so he
became famous because you know you know
like five years ago so you know when the
that's the rise of the social justice
scan you know you know it's like it's
very you know infuriating you know so
it's about the gay issue ok the gay
issues you know so you know a few like
10 years ago Obama you know with Hillary
Clinton and also Obama they don't they
both opposed gay marriage both of them
you know that like you can watch the
YouTube they talk about oh I don't
support gay marriage a and so on you
know for like for for the food for the
most of their you know political career
you can watch lots of you
tube about them they talk they say it
you know as part of their campaign so
the gay issue the gay marriage issue
that's an issue in society you know so
you know we have to decide so what you
know what do you want you know what
should it be legal or not you know
that's a question you know so we have
this question in society and people
start to vote and it you know it so
happens that I guess most states today
you know allow it you know says you know
think it's good you know it's it's you
know allow it so so you know we vote you
know like five years ago people vote you
know be you know knocks okay is now like
you can marry you know you're like
basically you know take you know let's
put it bluntly that's [ __ ] in the ass
[ __ ] yes it was used to be illegal you
know it's a sodomy so and you know it
now it's legal you can track it you can
get a certificate for [ __ ] ass that's
called marriage
you know but anyway so opinion what
about the opinions like what what do you
think you know so what i think i don't
you know i don't think i don't really
have a strong opinion about this
particular because this many issues in
society there is no right answers you
know so i am not gay
okay I'm not gay by the way and I tend
to have I tend to have a lot gay
following me okay and especially when I
was younger this or this case you know
the hitting me anyway so so as far as
marriage goes you know I don't you know
I don't really even you know the
marriage itself between men and woman is
that is that itself is you know not
necessarily not not absolutely necessary
thing like what do you want marriage
first of all you just you know to people
I think about you think about you know
humans and
was like 2,000 years ago you you see you
see two lions get together do they say
let's get married
no they don't they don't [ __ ] what
the marriage you know marriage that's a
social construct you know you have
marriage society you know you need a
certificate you know you get a
certificate Oh you graduate from this
University
so now you are knowledgeable you know
you need a certificate that's that's
what degrees are for literally that's
what you know degrees are for all these
certificate you know certify you are a
doctor or lawyer whatever so marriage is
a similar thing it's it's it's it's came
out of the society you know you two are
wet you know like there might be good
reasons why marriage developed you know
there they are my good you know because
societies you know if use our social
ologist you know you study how society
forms there could be good reasons you
know so that essentially you keep the
society you know thrive and you know
peaceful and things like that so anyway
we want you to come to marriage my own
opinion is that I don't think it's
really actually that necessary between
men women woman first of all so when it
comes to gay marriage you know okay okay
you wanna you wanna [ __ ] yes you know
my take is you know okay do whatever you
want okay and so but but then you want a
marriage okay she did be big or not you
know I don't have a strong opinion on
that okay so anyways so five years ago
we have this social issue you know
people decide then this [ __ ] this
social justice can [ __ ] heads they seems
to dig up they think of you know some
donations or whatever from you know the
Brendan Eich guys he he donated to
organization something like that that
opposes the gay marriage okay it's
perfectly fine you know different people
have different opinions you have you
know different political parties in
we need to decide this issue so some are
again is some are for you know and they
asked of photo nation's all the
politicians asked for donations so he
put his you know two cents or whatever
his money you know he he support you
know he G does not support idea then
people dig him up
so that then then then this this social
justice can [ __ ] heads they want to say
that he is he's a you know a bad guy you
know they use certain words I don't want
to mention so let's let's that's you
know that's that's not good that's
that's like a criminal that's a that's
the [ __ ] heads of society do that so
that's why I you know I don't like the
social justice guy and this you know and
they become so powerful there's this I
think there's I remember you know I
haven't been reading that news back then
you know that's when you know the social
justice can just like they started and
it so they so there was this the OkCupid
you know this apparently there's this
there is this website OkCupid for mating
you know for dating you know get men and
women oh-o-oh today you know whatever
whatever number Navy you are you know
gays or queers or whatever you know so
you know dating taking website so this
OkCupid they have a founder there you
know they so he you know he he is one of
the guy who started to create a problem
you know blend the the Brendan Eich guy
and but but Brendan Eich because no yeah
the issue was because Brendan Eich
Mozilla was looking for a new new CEO
and Brendan Eich people voted him up
then the you know the order you know
this issue of work out so I think then
Brendan Eich resigned you know he just
resigned by himself he just you know
he's not I don't think I'm not sure he
is actually I mean in a sense he's
forced out but I don't think it's
actually yeah I don't know the detail I
was I'm thinking that he if he wanted he
he could have you know stayed but anyway
I I think he he just resigned he decided
you know he don't want it so FMS good
morning you know I'm afraid did there
are so many facts in this video I'm
afraid this video is gonna be banned you
know so I'm thinking maybe I'll delete
it you know and after so Battle of me me
who says if you are ever interested in
supporting a video game company but I
recommend buying Kingdom Come
deliverance because the developers at
warhorse studio took a big stand again
again is social justice madness okay so
that's a if you if you are ever
interested in scoring a video game
company kingdom come so let's look it up
king the kingdom count deliverance
okay Wikipedia so let's go to Wikipedia
else first I wish I could play games you
know I'm I'm a gamer not really well you
know I'm I'm I'm the I'm a gamer type
you know I play video game since 1980s
when I was when I was like 12 10 like
addictive T like I I would I'm such a
guy that when I play you again it
happens you know throughout my life 20
and up to you know why I became habit I
will stop eating I will finish the game
like you know continue play from the
moment I wake up to the you know to to
to you know until I sleep and wake up
play again and and here I finished you
know past the final stage or something
so I'm kind of like that but but it so
happens that I've never actually played
any much of the modern you know 3d video
games like you know the 3d graphics with
3d graphics except second life second
life is rather different story I talked
about second life in my previous video
like a month or two or three year ago if
you interested you can go watch that
second life yeah second life so it's a
virtual world it's very interesting
things going on so anyway King Kingdom
can't deliverance is a action
role-playing video game developed by
warhorse studios okay good to know
okay so so anyway so about the social
justice situation okay you know society
changes the things come and go is
sometimes it's I don't think it's gonna
be forever you know but you know we I
don't know for sure what will happen you
know let's say in five five years like
let's say 20 you know 2025 2025
in five years you know you it's
interesting to think about what will
happen you know we are we are the social
justice situation with will it be still
you know I'm going on it's hard to say
really
I mean you know like I try to you know I
try to think say no oh I tried to say no
maybe you'll get worse but really it's
really unpredictable
okay it's like nobody can really say I
mean you look at for example I follow a
lot of people you know you look at all
the you know let's let's call them
influences you know like people you know
commenting on the issue including
I could academicians you know like
professors you know some anti you know
social justice professors you know you
know anyway you look at all the
situation I have you know I kind of have
I kind of have and basically nobody like
you know nobody knows you you know this
these things you know what we were
having in the future like really nobody
knows and similarly for technology
related issues such as AI you know for
example AI if you are a programmer you
are probably heavily interested you know
because it's on a new sort of every day
you know people think about oh what will
happen to society where people get you
know everything is automated you know we
are a I be become bad or things like
that and there are a lot Caruso pundits
you know they will talk about they will
write articles these AI experts you know
they will say you know give their
opinions but actually this expert so
called expose their opinion totally
usually don't they usually fail okay you
know you look at history
I think the opinions from this egg Expo
they usually further away from from from
people without this specialized
specialized expertise so anyway so so I
was saying you know nobody really know
you know this is how to say about the
future so let's keep reading the
comments hello hello Gabriel Philip how
are you I'm doing okay I guess yeah
what's the topic today's show today's
show it's random and it turns out to be
a rant against open source and phonetics
ok the phonetic you know versus in free
software we talked about Macedon we
talked about Brendan Eich we talked
about social justice
you know the phenomena and social
justice people so then you say switcher
stolen and milpa I gather that Mara is a
bit delicate a subject since it's not
gonna software yeah you know he didn't
say he did he did you don't know let me
show you limit let's talk about that let
me just show you let me turn this
episode into now let's turn it into the
rant against Richard Stallman you know I
have you know I can show you and you you
will be convinced you know just such
folks are de max okay sorry
max go to my Emacs block okay or you can
just go to other Emacs dot org so
practically max tutorial okay go to blog
actually just go to you know I can there
are several ways to get to the article
I'm going to show you but I actually
recently blogged about a series you know
a series
Primus of the richest omen here okay
expect a lot over the past 10 or 20
years so Emacs controversy okay this
quite a lot reaches doorman you know you
you read it like a lot of people don't
know you have to like all the issues in
society you know the like most people
don't know you have to like but once you
know it's like what you know oh my god
did he really actually did that or this
or that so anyway so you go to Emacs
miss you know go to you know you can let
me show you how to find out you know the
info like like oh go Emacs website you
go to Emacs miscellaneous okay over here
click on that then let's turn on
JavaScript so you can see the videos the
YouTube videos let's refresh so what is
this one
oh ye max this sucks yeah
Vick that's that's like two hours rent
so this section Emacs controversy so
let's look at them one by one you know
this is going to take one hour but let's
just quickly go over them so you know I
show you where to look you can look now
am I still alive okay so maybe we take
we talk about MMO minutes and that's it
for today
oh yeah the so the video the title is
even wrong
okay so so Richard Stallman you know you
next I run so this article so what what
is this one about basically there is a
developer very well known and very
capable is and he has contributed to
Emacs a lot Danielle colas Ian
okay he works for Facebook I think now
is how to summarize but basically reach
a storm and he you know you should read
it for yourself okay you know we did you
know just you read it offline okay you
know how to find it
so this is one incident basically this
one is how to summarize let's go to the
next one so that one is 2018
this one is 2017 Richard Stallman
pushing for GP are three kicked out free
software from fists from three software
platform so you can read the details but
basically what happens is that Richard
Stallman you know um you know he's
always supporting for GPL he wants
software to be GP a-- basically in the
entire history of richard stallman
you know his idea is is that he want
free software he do not want open-source
okay there's a big difference according
to him you know his idea a free software
foundation is about ethics about
morality he wants software to be he want
people to share he you know the way he
talked about is that the freedom you
know he want the freedom you know free
software the freedom for people to share
software freedom is a key word ok
freedom now open source open source
began around 1996 by this eric eric
raymond okay actually yesterday
yesterday or the day before this i did a
big rant about eric raymond you know you
can check on youtube my past videos to
yesterday out or one day a day before
that and esre we are ever agreement
anyway eric raymond is one of the guy
who began open-source the concept and
and the organization is an organization
and and and ever since there's a fight
between free software with richard
stallman and open source because which
yeah from you know richard stallman
don't like you know he's very much
against open source he think it's a you
know it's bad it's not his stuff it's he
he he think it's very bad because the
open source the the open source began as
kind of a mediator like to mediate
between which a summers
software that the very strong morality
based ideology so open source you know
so companies may not want to use free
software foundation stuff because they
are afraid you know we we don't really
want to get into you know morality we
just you know so open source peak you
know kind of right on on this situation
so they've created open source meaning
that you know so companies can do
software but just open source they
emphasize on the open source aspect you
know it every source code is open so
people can look at so you know according
to them you know you will have fewer
bugs because you know because it's open
so anyway that's all open source but but
but these two camps do not agree with
each other they hate especially Richard
Stallman hates the open source okay
that's first thing the richest aumentan
like open source okay they you you can
see a lot videos where he talked about
that he got angry when people say you
know he is open source when people you
know thank you for your contribution
open source he got he get extremely
angry now okay so so since since you
know 1990s you know so the richest Roma
always want free software now there are
many licenses out there you know today
you have MIT license they went through
several versions MIT license you have
PST license okay from from the Berkeley
UNIX BSD license you have MIT license
you have X Windows license you have then
today there's a lot you know then you
have apache license then you have you
know there's a Perl artistic [ __ ]
license okay from the pro people anyway
so you have a you know you have a lot
licenses but back then even back then so
to reach a Stallman from his point of
view he or he clearly defines like to
type of license
one group is GPL or any licensed that's
free software compatible that's one
group okay any license that it that he
does not belong to this group he attacks
he attacks all the time you know he has
fought with all a bunch like like a
bunch of you know open source project
you know KDE I mean Linux a bunch you
know a whole bunch of them he being
kicked out
kicked out or all these organizations
anyway so he like free software
foundation you know he like the GPL and
GPL compile compatible licenses he
anything else he doesn't like he he has
you know lawyers and you know decide
which one he like if you go to free
software foundation you can see a
explicit list where which license he
considered are good you know free
software compatible you know it's not
necessarily GPL compatible but the idea
is that certain licenses certain
licenses he in his point of view he
think is you know compatible with the
idea of free software you know like
freedom based where on the other hand
there are a bunch of licenses you know
may be open source or may be something
but in his mind is not you know it does
not prepare does not advocate the
freedom you know his his his his
perspective freedom for users for
computer users or programmers so he
opposed those and he constantly you know
over the decades you always fight them
you know tell say bad things about them
tell people to switch you know tell them
to change and he succeeded many times
you know in times after a few years all
those organized organizations they
change their wording in their license so
that their license now becomes you know
free software foundation approved you
know it happens many times so anyway he
wishes someone got this big deal about
licenses so although his life you know
in
past 30 years he has you know this this
is the major the big thing of what he
does you know he go around giving
lectures so it's oh my god I'm going and
I'm getting into so many so much details
at the end there are so many articles to
go through you know this there's so many
incidents that to go through anywhere
it's let's finish talking about this one
so that you know I'm already actually
giving a history of the licenses with
respect to Richard Stallman so anyway so
Oh his life he fight about licenses so
in general there are two to group of
licenses Free Software Foundation
approved and and not but those are
typically also open source
you know so what I'm saying is that in a
past you know up to you know this is
this happening in 2007 so all the years
before 2017 he has fought against all
these non free software foundation
approved licenses okay as a principle as
that that's important because every
whatever he say is always like based on
his principle he always talked about you
know that's a big thing you know freedom
of users principle principle based but
in 2017 you know he discovered mapa okay
male party's repository for all the
Emacs software Emacs packages mapa he
actually discovered it because he
doesn't know he doesn't know what the
[ __ ] is mapa you know there is a message
like he explicit he said right back this
is another one he said like he asked
people what what is my Appa like why am
i huh why are people you see Mel pie
what do you let me show you we're okay
here
okay I think it's this one okay this is
2015 from Richard Stallman subject be
Emacs least
future date 2014 okay okay so mm he says
okay someone says once Emax switches to
get I would guess the percentage of
people on this list who do not install
magic
we are shrink to a tiny number okay this
is this is an ague gnu emacs dev least
it's a mailing list where the Emacs
developers it's a main communication
among Emacs developers so someone said
that you know once Emacs switch to get
you know Emacs it was not using it
so once the Mac switch to get I was I
would guess that percentage of people on
this on this list who do not install
magic will shrink to a tiny number and
then Richard Stallman says what is magic
why is it preferable to use using VC and
why is it not in Emacs that's what he
says you know magic I mean if you are
Emacs user if you you know if you are a
Mac user and you pay your attention to
any blogs you know you know what is
magic you know is magic is one it's that
it's the most popular one of the top pi
5 most popular packages ok you can see
this chart this this chart is the number
of software you're on male part ok I'm
not going to get into details I'm not to
talk about you know what what is my PI
and what is not anyway you you get the
sense you know what what is going on
this this this I ended ok this email
from Richard Stallman so so people
answered thinking of emacs's and you
know people of trying to educate which
is Stallman you know trying to tell him
what is melba what is kid or what what
is the magic and what is mapa so he you
know the guy says think of think of
Emacs as an entire ecosystem most Emacs
is already maintained inter pendency
from either Emacs core or mu alpha so
people are saying that that you know
vast majority of Emacs package
Jews are actually not developed by the
Emax the new Emacs people they had a
visit by outsiders where people put it
on Melba
okay then we then Richard Stallman says
this is shocking statement is it really
true
these [ __ ] richard stallman like he
have no idea what's going on in a world
he he you know he's like you know like
living okay he has no idea this is 2014
okay this is this is 2014 someone is
trying to explain what you know the the
mapa you know did like he doesn't know
then there's another message I'm not
going you know you can read it yourself
so this is 2014 okay let's go back to
the other incident about the GPL three
about how Richard Stallman kicked out
free software Richard Stallman uses his
power to kick out free software that you
know software licensed by by a license
that he approves you know free software
for his entire life he fought for this
kind of license freedom software license
but he used his power to kick the kicker
free software from from a free software
platform mapa you know this happened in
2007 so he tell people um Mel pad to to
kick out people who are using GPL to
they he want to tell people to use GPL
three okay so this include this includes
my software you know I suffer like he's
and and my old my packages was using GP
out to GPL GPR to is a software is a
software license created by him and
approved you know sanctioned by him for
his entire life for you know for his
entire life he's fighting about he's
talking about certain moral issues he is
dividing of software licenses you know
like open source
you know among open source into two
camps one is those approved by his you
know like freedom oriented like he
approves and the other camp is not
freedom oriented even though they are
maybe you know pub you know public you
know that MIT or you know X from X
Windows you know he he fought all his
life you know he make this this
distinction of licenses that that
support the freedom kind of a aspect of
users in his opinion but now he's
kicking he he's he's not exactly you
know he's using his power to tell people
to force actually force people to switch
to GPL three anyway that that that's a
point okay that that is a situation
that's the incident you can read you
know how the whole detail here so we
covered so we are talking about we are
give we are ranting against Richard
Stallman we cover two things one thing
is this this incident in 2017 where he
you know force people to use GPR three
and we cover another incident in 2015
where he doesn't know what Majid is he
doesn't know what my Appa is OK to
incident there they are credibly a lot
ok but I'm not going to go into you know
you can read it you know there's and of
course they are a lot I haven't got the
time to write it you know every time I
you know
so that's Richard Stallman you know and
he's that's that's the situation you
know that's the situation we are living
in so ok I'm Kim Insco he didn't say
what mail pile but you get my point you
know let's not get into you know
technical details about what I actually
said or what I claim you know you get a
general point what what he he
you know he's like you know you get my
point you know whether you still agree
with it they were kind of you know what
you know you know take your opinion
whatever it is right now you know
important thing for Emax you know by the
way male pas it is we just you know Mara
is a you know repository you know it's
late
you know Mel pies like five or ten years
late you know all the other software
have opens have a all the open software
open source software you know including
pearl Pro is the first one back in 1990s
beginning with pearl you have you you
begin to have this repository of
software other packages or libraries so
people can all go there you know find
you know all the open-source libraries
for your language or whatever
it began with Perl in 1990s and it's
called Sipan you know like today it's
this like this is become history and
fewer few you know people know it now
but if you search for Sipan you'll still
find like Trey you know clue so you know
traces about see Pandy see pan is the
first most popular 14 for 20 years that
began this thing about oh you know open
source repository or centralized you
know website where you can find all the
libraries so so after seep and and Ruby
had then you know then then all the you
know then you know tech for example
donald knuth tech and latex
they have they have their stuff what you
call tech pan or whatever do they call
it let's try let's try to find but
anyway the the tech technology okay I
don't think that's it but the text
started to have it
CMC tech pen I don't think that's the
name but anyway so so anyway what I'm
saying so all the languages started to
have that now today it's very common for
example in JavaScript you have MPM you
know they don't call it pan anymore they
don't call it like you know
something-something pan anymore so you
have NPM but you know JavaScript you
have actually more than what you know
almost or every language has the Ruby
has their thing closure has their thing
Java has their thing you know like you
know and II max has milpa okay mal had
you know there actually there are few
but Mara is the most popular but anyway
so the point I was going to say is that
Emacs actually the idea of a package
system in order to have that you know
you had you need to have a system
building for you know packages and it is
it is Richard Stallman he refused you
know building a package system basically
he purposely turn you know refused it
because back in 1990s the ex Emacs has
you know has the package structure back
in 1990s you know I can show you sorry
just you can just search my old articles
about X Emacs I have a couple of
articles about that you know my
experience of using Emacs versus X Emacs
anyway so Richard Stallman I don't have
a article on that but Richard Stallman
intentionally purpose purposefully des
cailloux denied refused to build a
package within Emacs a package system
where people can just install you know
libraries of packages exe max had it
back in 1990s back in 1992 or something
l XE max headed Richard Stallman refused
to have that system in Emacs without
that you can
vampa you know in order to have an open
source repository first of all you need
to have a package system in Emacs we
should summon refuse that why because in
his opinion to have a package is you
know when you have a package system
where people can have all the open
source packages it detriments he's you
know he score of the free software
foundation of you know the you know not
open source because remember he's
against open source because open source
is only only focused on open source he
doesn't want that he wants people to
focus on the kind of you know his idea
of freedom in software ensuring software
therefore anyway so he explicitly turn
you know if you know do not allow any
package system well yeah you can find my
articles like sorry Emacs
let's say Emacs 23 News you know I have
you know I used to document all these
news so you can see somewhere new
features ok 2009 sometimes you know
either into Emacs 23 or in Emacs 24 I
think it's in Emacs 24 Emacs began to
have package systems
so let's you know you can check in one
of these article you yeah he max 24 so
in 2012
Emacs begin to have a package system
which allows you to install packages you
know as a thing then it is it is also
around this time around you know once
you have this then you can have you know
websites where that's package
repositories like ALPA and mapa yes yeah
so this is in 2012 you know so it tooks
Emacs
almost 20 years - for him for Richard
Stallman to allow to this to happen he
did he doesn't want it because you know
it's a threat it's a threat to his you
know free software idea and indeed it is
you know then we see the Memphis
situation where the package are just
striving you know all the pain you know
imagine all the package are thriving but
not the new then he started to kick
people out you know he he falls he used
his power to force people into GTP l3
and stuff you know you know and you know
stuff okay that's it for today I guess I
know it's one giant huge rent
so anyway any you know sighs hello hello
brother Xia okay yes so anyone have
comments continue well then you as a
comments you know Q come on D it's good
don't worry
so anyways got comments so Beth hello me
me oh says where you do your next stream
and yeah actually that's a good question
so I don't know people have always you
know my schedule that's a problem
because basically I'm basically like
whenever you know I feel like that's no
good no for you know so that is no good
for audience that's also you know I
because I'm right you know I've been
writing blog for twenty years so I also
look into see a CEO and all that stuff
you know how to get popular in one of
the most important thing is that you
must follow a schedule like there's some
you know you don't have to do it every
day but follow a schedule stick to it
like every let's say every Friday you
know my new blogs come out or you new
video you need to do that that's one of
the most important thing but I don't I
don't do that and I haven't you know I
tend to
I just don't do that instead I do I
write a lot every day and also videos
every day but I tend not to follow a
schedule because you know it's just like
I've I tend not to follow a schedule
because that's kind of half of it half
of the reason it's hard it's harder
because once you have a schedule you
know like when you have a schedule that
means you have to plan then you know
everything right so I tend to just you
know free flow you know wherever and
keep keep pumping information so I don't
know it's also so here's the interesting
thing
so this is like when you talk about
programming you know this is like there
is the issue when you're talking about
streaming whenever there's an
information communication there's when
whenever whenever there's a flow of data
okay there is this issue of there's this
kind of contradictory issue one is
called let's let's put let's say let's
talk about that when you have a pipe
when you have a stream there's a data
flow and okay my brain is tofu right now
let's see what what is the what is a
term to measure the data flow guys so
what what what are the you know we can
find the terms by following this article
by going around an article a little bit
then we'll find it stream processing
data flow streaming message passing
process continuous function data flow
diagram data data stream
packet flow pipe line purity data
hey dick
so this is actually interesting thing
yet um throughput okay one of the term
is called throughput okay so Mike my
concern when I do video when I do when I
write my blogs or what I do
video I kind of like conveniently think
of think of my stuff as measured by
throughput okay yeah stupid you know
throughput through thr ough
oh I spelled it wrong okay you know I I
like to think of as throughput okay
there it is throughput you know that
measures how much data you pumped out
pump out during a period of time so you
can average it you know and you know so
throughput you know is how much data you
pump out now there is another rather
critical concept of measuring flow what
what is that guy's throughput and which
is time-sensitive good foot and overhead
and bandwidth no I don't think it's been
with it's the it's like how fast you
need to for example I can like for
example if I want to I need to send you
some data I can save it into a hard disk
and I can mail it to you by a truck you
know by UPS for example maybe your take
a day but you got you know let's say one
terabyte of data you know that's you
know if you measure throughput that's
huge one terabyte per day but however
that's not instantaneous you have to
wait for the whole day
you know you have to wait for the whole
day then the whole day now arrives like
the you know like instant on the other
hand if I stream it to you for example
if I start to stream like right now you
get instantaneous what he said
so that so that's another term you know
you don't want sometimes it's not
throughput it's not you know how much to
put you need but rather bitrate not
betrayed but so do you guys I'm am
pretty sure of you guys know what I'm
talking about but you just need someone
to I don't think we just Roman is lying
and yeah but what so yeah so then yard
so what are you saying Richard Stallman
I don't think he's a he's he's not the
type of guy who would lie he does not
lie
and I do not think he's incompetent so
daniel says let's not Jacko's deriding
him as incompetent I'm not saying he's
incompetent he is very incompetent he's
very competent but however what I'm
saying you know like my r and again you
see me in the past
now also in the past 20 minute 20
minutes is that he is out of touch first
of all as a leader you cannot be out of
touch you know when you are out of you
maybe you are too old maybe you are too
busy whatever you cannot be out of touch
as a leader you want to maybe pass it to
someone else okay when you are out of
touch you are not you are incompetent
yes
so okay in that sense he is incompetent
he should be out okay so he saw that out
of touch that's not all that's just one
of the things also he is
you know his behavior we got for example
on that GPR you know forcing people to
use GPL 3 instead of GPL - that's
immoral
ok by his own standards by his life
lifelong behavior that's that's immoral
that's not you know in a sense he's he's
pushing people to specifically use GPL
not just that people are already using
cheap yeah but he's pushing people on a
project mapa not his project map I
started by all the people who are not
particularly on the side of GUI Max or
free software specifically because the
may of our people all the contributors
they are specifically not for you know
free software foundations camp of
software you know that's why my Appa
becomes so popular but but but but
Richard Stallman are forcing people not
just using GPR but forcing people to do
you use GPR 3 anyway anyway I'm not
going to argue the details we were
talking about throughput versus anyway
tomorrow
ok so address sorry about that 3 also
the question Dec ways
tomorrow I think that's - so tomorrow
where I will be what's a good time for
you by the way if you are still here
say it then let's they'll be on tomorrow
I don't know what I'm telling you so I'm
thinking tomorrow at the same time you
know like three o clock San Francisco
time
so anyway I'm kind of getting tired you
know - I you know I'm gonna get you
something to eat so today it's a long
rant so long like thought flow random
things about you know yeah so so see you
guys so uh yeah it's a big long rant and
usually Randy's fun and people actually
you know it's it's kind of strange but
when you do a video or whatever usually
the more traumatic you you got more
people want to watch it - you know
that's not necessarily a good thing but
that's just the fact you know that's why
you see all the quick baits you know on
the youtubes or the you know drama but
anyway I have a good day bye bye guys