good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show
today's topic is Emacs Lisp so we are
going to teach Emacs Lisp in conjunction
with Python so the plan is I'm going to
show Titan code and how do you do that
in emag peas so we are this is going to
be for beginners so this is so you can
see if you know Python you would like it
because you know I'm going to show you
how do you how do you do you know loops
and so on in Emacs Lisp variables and so
on and so let's let me see if I'm
nobody's here yet I'm surprised I make
sure I am live okay
that's strange
because I've set this up yesterday but
anyway so okay so let's to eMac this so
let me start saw Emacs saw start command
knock mod so you can see all my Emacs
commands on the left window here such as
forward backward backward move kusudama
browser up or beginning of a buffer or
such things like that
all the commands will show up on the
left panel so finally we got people here
this wrong crazy good morning been a yak
good morning Pano's group good morning
Orlick good morning good morning guys so
we are going to do a Mac PC Mac this
great eMac this tutorial with Python
again keep your comments coming okay so
because that way
see it gets the chat more fun good
morning Oleg good morning Seema's so who
who was it asked for Emacs Lisp with
Python so anyway so II make this with
Python
you know let's begin you know it's
always it's always a bit hard to to to
like where do we begin
okay so eMac this with pythons of
surface why I guess I go to my website
practical email list and I'm going to
show also my Python tutorial website
Python tutorial so I have this python
tutorial this is great for beginners if
you don't know Python you know check out
my tutorial you can just search for
sorry python tutorial my name and you'll
find it and similarly for such folks are
the practical eMac list okay so so
that's the that's the python tutorial
and that's we're gonna start some talk
show today focus on e eMac basement
Python so today is going to be technical
very technical you know technical topic
it's you know restrict ourselves to
technical topics so you have if you have
questions or even Emacs questions feel
free to ask me okay you know just type
it I'm talking and I don't have a plan
so how shall we begin so let's see let's
see that let me show you how shall we
begin you know beginning beginning is
always a Python three basics so Python
as you know you have Python two and
Python three and Python three is gaining
traction
it's got like 60 percent usage in
industry so it's good time to start to
learn Python three but I think I assume
you guys already know Python
because otherwise I am I'm kid you know
I'm using Python to teach you eMac B's
somewhat like that what about these
schmuck was okay I don't actually
useless ma close myself because I don't
like it and anything basically almost
99% of things you can do in any
programming language you can do without
Marcos Marcos is one of those things
that's dramatic you know people always
like to oh this has Marcos you need to
use Marcos and most of the time I would
say more than 50% of the time when you
see Marco code in emag B's that's
necessary it's it's better to do without
so I'm not going to cover mark Wells
because it's kind of more advanced I'm
going to give a basics about images for
beginners for those of you have never
seen you Mac these people so okay so
let's let's just start above emag nice
so we we start a eMac this buffer let's
say we can do message message equals you
know it's let's say this is how you
print in eMac this so I just run it
alright I run it and you can see the
answer at the bottom it says one okay so
let me start another buffer and this
buffer I'm going to switch to the
message buffer so message buffer when
you print something in Emacs it prints
to the message buffer so you just you
know the buffer name is star messages
star so you can switch there usually it
will print in the mini buffer but then
your disappear after a second or so but
you can always see the whole thing in
message above message buffer is they
score off so you know it's kind of like
just not it's not permanent and of
course you can print to another buffer
if you wanted permanent permanent but
anyway anyway so this so first of all
before we do anything I'm going to base
on you know kind of my tutorial this
talk on my on my own pages you know my
python tutorial and my email is tutorial
so in this image this tutorial this
folks first section eMac this basics
that's where you want to begin okay just
like you know after the talk you can
read them like they have the solid
information summarized you know
imprecise and summarized form so oh you
can you know you should take notes you
know so this is like a lecture you can
take notes and let me try to you know
let's let me try to you know be prepared
you know get on track and let's start to
talk about it
so eMac these basics so okay first first
thing and before you learn eMac this you
know if you are using Emacs you are
public for me the first important thing
first first thing to know about eMac
this is the miniatures right notes how
to eval functions or how do we Eva
eatest code okay and let me just write
it up and the function that the describe
function let me show you some of the
most important Emacs commands you need
to know you know because you are going
to call them every every tank every
every minute every few minutes okay when
you call eMac this
so the first thing you want to learn is
how to evolve over how to evolve a lisp
code so there are several ways so one of
them is the most important is evil as
sex I'm going to show you how to do that
and then Eva buffer okay okay Eva buffer
okay so let me know Eva
this is text hello close that switch
switch switch switch Evo that
okay this so evil as sex evil buffer
does this to an evil region let me just
type it up Eva Eva region these three
are the most important thing you need to
know these are the ways to evaluate eMac
this code because you know you need to
evaluate it so Emacs knows about it and
description describe function is the
most important command whenever you have
a function for example what what is the
verb of you need to know then you code
describe function then you know type IVA
buffer then LLL tell you the
documentation for that function so this
is critical you're gonna you need to do
this every minute when you start to
learn eMac this so this wave function
and and let me show you another command
that's all critical so basically okay so
it let me just continue eval is code so
that's all covered here you know there
are several commands you can use to
evaluate the function you know what to
evaluate it but the most important thing
is what I said here eval eval has sex
IVA region eval bhava and the describe
function okay yeah let me let's just
cover this this describe function is the
most important it shows the
documentation of a function and there's
another one called describe variable it
is also useful because when you have a
variable let me show you let me just
show you then let's say set Q okay set Q
x equals to 3 now let's say eMac this
code you set 3 to X okay now you want to
run it they are two ways there are
several ways they are there is evil ass
sex
let me just demo that evil ass sex
that's a command you put the cursor at
the end of the parenthesis and you just
call it
Eva last sex you know that that is can I
just call it now you see the bottom is
h3 let me switch for third you see it
says in a message before you can say you
can see it says three so that means you
know Emacs know now X is three so that
is a demonstration of eval asks X X now
in Emacs many commands has a shortcut
you can call this skype function to find
out a shortcut for example let's let's
disco describe function you know we are
going we are demonstrating several of
these things here so we are let's call
describe function okay I have a shortcut
describe function let's type IVA last
sex okay and you see here is a
documentation for evil as sex and it
will also tell you what are the key
bindings so I'm used you know so
whenever you see a eMac eMac commands or
eMac this function you can just call
this web function then you can learn
about the shortcuts in my half it may or
may not have and the documentation you
know by the way if you know when you
start to learn Emacs Lisp you know
sometimes you don't quite understand
what what the documentation says because
it uses many jargons but just keep going
just you know just read a lot then you
gradually you are know this is you know
common issue you just keep reading it so
so we have showed we have demonstrated
evil ask set eval last sex now let me
demonstrate and we have also
demonstrated then demonstrated eval
function let me demonstrate
eval variable so you see we have defined
x equals to 3 here now if you want to
know you know suppose you have thousands
of lines you don't know what the
variable value is you want to know so
you call describe Wow
okay describe variable enter the
type of variable named X okay enter UK
you see now it says it tells you X value
is three documentation no documentation
is variable you know that's that's no
more because we don't have documentation
here so if so that is a demonstration of
described variable so again you know
this web function and described variable
very useful the the two most useful
commands you want to know and okay so so
that's cover that now let's go back to
how to evaluate emag this code so we
have showed Ivar last six let's try it
again so let's let's try it let's try
something first three four okay now I
move the cursor to the bottom of the
code and I call eval asked says six I
have a shortcut okay I press it and at
the bottom you are C seven so it's
evaluated you see okay now what about
eval region that's another way to to to
evaluate you know you Magnus code let's
say for example let's say for example
set x equals to four now I have several
lines of code I want to evaluate them
all you know so I can select them all
and coeval region eval region okay
enter now it's done its evaluated okay
and now now if we call describe variable
on X again described variable of X you
see now it says four so if our region is
another useful command then the last one
I'm going to show is eval petha because
now I have this butter it's already
saved as a file name you see any one of
these you don't have to you don't you
know for example if I open a new buffer
which is not saved you know I can say
I can say set Q okay okay you know I
came for example I go to this buffer
let's just go through my HTML file so I
can say here set Q X equals to 99 okay
now I can evaluate that evil ass sex
nice s 99 you see and I can do evaluate
buffer eval buffer that is when the
whole buffer is eMac this code you want
to just give out the whole thing so I
call it it's done it just evaluated the
whole thing now if I could describe
variable X then it says for again
remember we just we just made it 99 but
now it's back to 4 and this eval Bertha
is very useful by the way for example if
you are let's go to my Emacs in it okay
so I have so here is my email in it you
know it's you know it's my image in it
you know it's I got a bunch of eMac this
this is very useful these eval functions
you know you just added some you know
setting and you don't want to restart
Emacs so you can just say for example if
you want to you know suppose I just
added that ya suppose if you just added
that you can just now call eval as sex
then Emacs will evaluate this you don't
need to restart Emacs usually because
usually simple settings you don't need
to sometimes you need to restart Emacs
well because there are other code
there's older you know just because once
the once you run this some others you
know it overrides others things like
that but in general if you just added
some settings you can just say if our
last six or selected you know suppose I
just added these two selected then
coeval region all if you just created a
new you know complete new in it you can
say eval buffer okay that's how you
evaluate them without restarting Emacs
usually we start in Emacs is kind of
more cream because it so so that's
that's about some of the critical you
are going to use these all the time so
let's move on actually so you know we
have not began to talk about Emacs Lisp
actually yet but okay so those are those
things are the critical the most
important now this actually one more
thing I want to show you so let's type
it here so this one is about how do you
find out what functions are there for
example you want to you want a function
to you want a function that that gets
the file file names extension for
example you have an image my cat dot jpg
you want to get the jpg part so what is
a function name well normally you you go
with the eMac this documentation 900
pages you know I have a link here
somewhere so for example for example
let's go to Elise basic functions file
the path so here is about file directory
path ok file path functions file name
directory file name none directory file
name extension this is the command you
want so normally you go read Emacs this
documentation you can access that by
calling info you know MX info and that's
you know eMac this info you know then
you can just go to eMac this
documentation let's see
so that's eMac this stock documentation
I have a HTML prettified HTML version so
anyway you can read it is documentation
but usually it's long and it's hard to
find so there is a way to find a if you
forgot you know you just remember
there's a name called file name
something you don't remember exactly you
can call
this is how you find functions how you
search functions stock lookup wait not
search doc okay so you want to call a
purpose command actually yeah okay so
let me show you a purpose command you
want to press control you first then go
apropos command around second so so this
is the great function you need to know
apropos command this is for for finding
release function press see you then
MX a pop-up that's how you do it okay
you press ok so you want to press
control you first
that means universal command then you
tell you you call papac's command Y
because that way it will search or
functions that contains the name so
let's do it
so for example I press control you then
I do met-rx then I say fire - name you
know there's some function that I don't
remember name but I remember there's a
file - naming it so I press Enter
what shadow marking being able I don't
know what is a shot shot I came that's
miss let's do it again control you meter
X proposed a PRP OS a propyl apropos
command okay
enter then you type the name now I typed
fire - name okay now Emacs will show me
all functions that contains whose name
contains file name you know the word
file names
now you can look at this you can scan it
and you can see you know you can you can
find you know all those related
functions for example the one we want is
file name extension you know you can
press tab to go there
press ENTER that's you know then you are
the in the describe function box then
it's a documentation then oh that's the
one I need so he that's how you've such
the how you find function how you know
one of the ways to find function and one
of the most useful way but otherwise you
can you know there are other ways you
can for example you can start to search
you can start to search eMac this
documentation you can see on this page
I'll show you how to do that but
typically your purpose it's useful a
proper command if you do not press the
control you first what will happen is I
will only search commands like
interactive commands it will not list it
will not beasts file name extension that
function because file name extension is
a function meaning that it's not a
command meaning that it's not something
you can call meta X you know you if you
commit IX and you type file name
extension there's no such command no
match because it's not a interactive
command it's only for it's a dysfunction
you using images so that is why you need
to press control you before you call a
purpose command otherwise the purpose
command with just such only commands so
these are actually the most important so
let's begin let's begin to actually show
some eMac this so let me be the comment
let's see if we are 24 minutes already
you know you say it's this takes a long
time to go over
happy to be here so let me read the
comments how about this smoke was yeah
okay so greetings everyone
describe function describe function yeah
you can could do that as well yes that's
how you call that as a emag this code
yeah you you are you are advanced so so
Seema says if equals to three message
true message yeah so okay so so they
speaking dead speaking with the actual
code then okay let's do this then let's
go over the let's try try this style
let's you don't go over Python code then
let's see how how we do that in eMac B's
okay so Python here is this okay strings
how do you assign a string E string is
super easy set Q say Q is how you create
a variable okay SEC you then just stream
something okay that's how you do it and
in eMac this remember it's always double
quote there is no variation so always
double s he quote and there's no single
quote this doesn't work here always that
so I let's evaluate evil ass says you
can see in a mini buffer you say
something okay let's go to the message
before you can also see here by the way
a shortcut to message buffer is ctrl H
ctrl H H let's try I don't remember the
default Emacs keys because I'm using my
own let's try ctrl H edge
no that's incorrect ctrl H M view Marta
what wait let's try it again
I forgot what's a default Emacs command
so it's just let's let's call this
squared function V lost let me just
describe key okay describe key because
I'm familiar with my keys okay describe
key then I press my my key for describe
what are we talking about a view message
sorry I did so describe key I press my
key for for the command to pop up the
message buffer then oh yeah the command
name is view echo area messages that is
the command to switch to the message
buffer of course you can just not use
you can always just use no more
switching buffer command that that works
as well
but this one is dedicated the command to
to switch to the message spa and the
default key is och II that's right
control H II so let's let's try it
control H II yeah you know it the pops
of the message messages buffer okay so
so yeah so yeah so that we got the
string now in Emacs strings just
remember always it's very simple it's
just double quote and if you want a
double quote inside you just escape it
with a backslash
okay so let's avoid and let's describe
variable X enter then it says x value is
X um you know it's a stream then we can
print it let's printed message let's say
X okay now let's give our hold on a
second now Eve our buffer you can see
you know it's printed
yeah yeah okay so message is a function
we want to print something
so that's strings you Maglis so
substring okay substring is easy this
substring substring is actually not a
function you use often in images you can
see this the functions here substring so
substring you give it a string let's say
let's say a b c d e be okay
from - okay from 0 then optional - let's
say - now let's give up give our last
six you can see the result is a B a B
that's the substring you know actually
going through Python to show to teach
eMac this exactly he is actually not
efficient way to learn email is actually
because because you know Python is a
general-purpose language so an email is
not when you use eMac this typically you
want to you know the purpose is that you
you want to manipulate buffers you want
to manipulate strings in eMac beasts you
want to manipulate kusa position whose
the position you know move kusa delete
the current line you know inside the
line switch to a different buffer now
those things are not in Python you see
because in Python those are those are
not Python is not a editor you see so
when you learn when you go when you try
to learn Emacs we we are the Python
things you know you are not you are not
learning what you need to do most of the
time in Emacs Lisp because you are not
dealing with buffers and cruisers and
forward or delete current word things
like that those those things are
actually the most useful to to typical
Emacs programmers email
these programmers in Emacs because
that's what you most people program us
you begin with that then you can create
a major mod you can create a minor mod
you can create a shell you know that's
but those things you know create you
know font if I you know syntax coloring
a buffer for a new language those things
are not in Python you see so teaching
eMac this free a Python is kind of you
can we can do that but you are missing
you know it's not proficient that that's
the point you know because if you read
my tutorial here you begin right away
after you learned about how to evaluate
code you know what are the basic syntax
you know you know the basics in task 4 +
- you know with medics for converting
flow to integer for true/false you know
the basic concept and how to look up
documentation and so on then then you
immediately begin to learn about cool
suppositions the concept of kusa
positions let's immediately it's called
a point point point you know that's a
function it returns to the kusa position
in every buffer the first when when your
cursor is at the beginning that position
is 0 now think of a cursor is between us
between characters that's that's a
technical way to think of kusa position
it's actually between characters so when
when the cursor is at beginning your
cursor position is 0 and the the
function point will tell you what is
your current position let's try it ok
point you know a point and okay we have
it eval above a weight have our last six
now I say 777 you see because my kusa
position right now it's 77 another way
to show that is describe char so I'm
going to call describe char you see now
he says position 77
of a77 because that's actually the last
position you know so point is the
function that returns kusa position so
anyway so these are commands that's
actually the most useful when you begin
to learn new Magnus but the all these
things are not in Python because python
is not dealing with you know it's not
dealing with editor things so at this
point should we continue with the Python
style you know let's you know go through
Python you know it's this can be fun but
maybe we should just continue just you
know because just you know so type your
comments okay opinions comments type it
Christiaan I don't know my dudes DeYoung
hey DeYoung so you hear the CMOS says so
why is that Q not corset okay you know
one thing about emag beasts we said when
you start to learn you have all these
questions very valid questions but
actually they are not practical things
to know because you know if you actually
like suppose if you want to really want
to be efficient you just you know you
want to spend you know let's say 20
hours do you want to in these 20 hours
you want to learn the maximum practical
emag beasts you start to write that you
know you start to write a major mod or
something or some command to manipulate
to refactor your code you know most of
you are programmers to refactor to help
you do something you you want to be
efficient in 20 20 hours then what do
you have to do well the best thing to do
is actually just just start to read this
you know don't ask any questions that's
not there just this is just you know set
you you say set Q just to set you but
okay that's that's one way okay but
obviously a lot of people we all wonder
you know what why said Q okay why say Q
why not set and why not you know for
example another question about
what is the other question we just came
up you know but basically yeah eMac nice
you know it's first of all it's a list
is so kind of different from other
languages but then there's also lots of
things like big becoming started to
become technical details I mean you can
code actually you can code for one year
and you don't have to know what Y said q
not set because that that gets into
technical details okay let me tell you
why why because set because okay to to
explain that track saying e track tracks
in the concept of symbols in this
language in this language you have the
concept of symbols which is not in any
language or basically not in XD well I
guess the only one I know is Mathematica
okay Mathematica is considered Lisp okay
so in this family you have symbols but
not in a any other not not in Java C C
sharp C++ JavaScript Python Ruby pearl
shell
Fortran Haskell okay mo F sharp just
they don't have symbols okay they you
know for example in Ruby you do have
symbols in JavaScript you also have
symbols but they are like a specific
particular type but not not nothing like
this this every variable everything you
know but right now you see the set Q X
the set every function name every
variable name is a symbol so you know so
if so we can start to explain what is
the symbol for example so actually so we
are digressing so much but it's good
okay so practically maybe if you go down
you see I put it at the bottom it's
actually kind of advanced like you can
you can you can do a Mac this
practically for one to three years
without actually understanding what the
hell
he's symbol okay that's that's true you
know if you want to be practical and
just get on with your you know just you
know get on with it
on the other hand now if you are the
type of you know person who are
interested in programming languages in
computer science you know which is kind
of like me and maybe you guys too then
of course then you are interested in
what what is symbols you know that's so
fascinating why is it you know like
these kind of questions said and versus
ed Q yeah but okay that's that's good so
I'm trying to give the eggs you know I'm
trying to give you the picture why you
know the the place of things you know
those are not actually practical things
that those are things when you want to
learn about you know this esoteric
language you know why do you know you
what aspect in computer science you have
symbols
I mean how it relates to lambda calculus
those kind of you know you go that way
then you learn that you know that's kind
of like like that a little for example
you could learn you know the the sick
the the you know book you know that any
anyway that's not exactly practical
things you know if you want to be
practical that's you don't want to do
that but anyway is in for symbols what
is a symbol you see at the bottom you
know my tutorial you can learn about
symbols I explain what is a symbol what
what is the concept of eMac this symbol
and what are special forms then you know
what what exactly is a function you know
it's you start to get into those symbols
so in order to define what is set was a
set cue you you know I don't even have a
you know expansion for set because
nobody ever you actually use it but but
anyway so for example let me show you
this okay so let's say set Youth set Q 3
another way to write it to do exactly
the same thing is like this
set q ' X 3 X these two have exact
hundred-percent exact outcome so you
have to so say set Q is like set quote
so it stand for said quote so what is a
said quote quote is a mechanism to get
get get a symbol or itself not the
symbols value okay so set Q said quote
actually just means these so actually
this is a shortcut for let me show you
okay quote okay so let me show you okay
so these three okay these three this is
this is a this gives you a clear idea
what what are the differences so in a
beginning you know in the beginning you
have this okay said quote X 3 what does
that mean you want to set something the
first argument must be a must be a
symbol so you say quote X Y quote why
not just you know like why can't you
just say say that because when you if
you say set X 3 then X gets evaluated
eMac base tries to evaluate X X may have
a value of 4 or it's undefined you know
Neal you know undefined you know it's
something so when you do that X becomes
4 then you try to set 4 to 3 it doesn't
work
so that's the problem so what you need
to do is set quote x3y quote because in
this you have the the concept of symbols
everything is you can have a symbol
itself or its value so now when you say
quote quote means don't evaluate it
basically yes that's the essence do not
evaluate this symbol you know just just
return the symbol itself so now
so when you say quote X now you are
trying to set you know the symbol X
now now that you know it works you see
so for example we can ship we can
actually run the code for example let's
do it you know so if our last sex now
you can see the value here for you know
then we can describe variable X it says
for you see now you see now if we can
let's do it again let's do it again
somewhere okay so let's so let's say if
we try to run this set X set x3 let's
run it arrow you see debugger entered
arrow this arrow run type argument
symbol P for what what is trying to say
is that it wants a symbol but he
actually got four because he Mac this is
trying to run the function symbol P on
the first argument so when you run
symbol P on four you got arrow because
symbol P returns true or false
you know symbol P if it's a symbol the
instru symbol P argument if it's the
argument is not symbol it runs force
so essentially says symbol P returns
false and that's that's wrong because it
wants a symbol so you see that's but so
anyway this is an example of a Mac list
arrow you will encounter this very
frequently when you learn emag piece you
know at you know and it shows the error
in this kind of strange way you know
just keep going you'll get used to it
you start to understand you know after a
while so yeah so you just you know you
see that often so anyway so now that if
we do this now remember let's to
describe variable for X now current
value of x is 4 so now let's run this
okay
no wait okay let's run this so let's run
it then you see it's 3 again so so you
see so this is actually so this 3 code
that that's what this 3 code are
equivalent these 3
lines of code and they they are about
the concept of a symbol so you see
nobody ever you know practically
speaking in fact in eMac this code you
will not see these okay you will almost
never see set then quote X you know you
will not see that you will not see this
either you just see set Q X is three
that's you know that's that's practical
so if you want to get into about you
know eMac these technical details that's
that's that's you know that's it's
actually not a practical thing and also
about Marcos yeah I remember the Marcos
thing you lease Marcos you know at least
Marco is a dramatic thing everyone is
like oh what is this Marcos everyone
start to you know they among these
fanatics they often say this Marco is
you know you are you're here it you know
and other proportions like everyday on
Twitter
we need this Marco Solis Marco is so
powerful it changes the world but
actually it's not that great utility
okay and this mark was and to understand
this Marcos you have to understand this
simple symbol well with our list symbols
just just like the example we explained
but you know here you need you need to
understand these symbols very well then
it is possible with our lisping symbols
you can now it's impossible to have
these markers after you have lists mean
symbols you can have a concept of Marcos
which is about holding evaluation we
write basically like rewriting anyway
four days ago I did entire hour about
list about list Marcos about this
language okay just such you know go to
my YouTube five days ago something like
last week one hour about this Marco's
you know you can try to watch that
because
if you are interested in computer
programming language you know language
design that kind of thing
miss Markos then you understand you you
get a lot understanding because this
marker then you have pattern matching
you know then you have what's called
symbolic pattern matching then you have
what's called computer algebra systems
which you need symbolic pattern matching
which basically you need the concept of
symbols and in turn this marker is kind
of like part of it is a small part of it
anyway so that's about these symbols you
know then more technical detail is about
this symbol cells because it's simple
it's not just symbol and value it this
has symbol cells that's when you get
into you know anyway that that's that's
not practical okay so so this so that
that's symbols we so that's a giant
digression so 47 minutes we always so at
this point we can you know either
continue with trying to teach Python I
mean trying to translate Python code
where is it a Python code yeah we can we
can continue with this how to do this
Python eMac this may be we continue that
road so that you know today is just you
know in this path and also I did a
tutorial on eMac this you know I did a
few a few months ago you can also check
them out one hour
you know I as I do this live live you
know tutorials I get better so so the
next time I do this I will immediately
skip those questions so we actually get
onto useful you know we get into useful
actually useful
practical stuff you know immediately
skip those questions so where are we
these symbols yeah so actually all these
close close then because what's a
function curse because yeah so those are
advanced you know you want to get
practical you want to you know start to
learn about cruises yeah so anyway so
let me read a comment and maybe we
suppose your questions anything you have
and and maybe we continue on a road
about Python in this so nick says how
can you start creating a functionality
like go to definition for Python with
lit for go through definition well what
do you mean like what do you mean go to
definition like go to like you you mean
the programming construct go to a Mac
this Nick so answer okay so Dion says I
found out why logical operators for
control flow is bad by the way okay
great so yesterday we talked about that
yeah you know something why why I'm
talking I you know I said that why I'm
talking with people usually I don't do I
don't do well you know I'm but I'm
getting better
Dion says chase down that disclosure
quote you had on your site conditional
control flow makes program deviation
from post conditions and preconditions
difficult yeah and and it's also its
abusive operator because when you read
you know when you you know programming
languages almost everyone it's I think
it's almost unavoidable that they have
words that that is why you have
programming style guide you know they
try to put you in in a right path you
know because almost any programming
language you can you can writing a
convoluted way you know that's
the essence of those the reason you you
are it's possible to write something up
few stated or convoluted or golf way is
because programming languages you can
abuse them you know and achieve the same
result
you know algorithms algorithmic we at
the end maybe you achieve the same
result but the path leading to it can be
convoluted in arbitrary ways that is why
you have a few stock Asian golf or
programming style guide things like that
so when you want to do flow control like
if something true or false do this or do
that you can do it in a way using all
operator because all operator because
one of the issue is that they need to
programming languages not formal logic
therefore you need to specify the
evaluation order you know once you run
into something is true you evaluate that
part you actually don't need to evaluate
the rest of it so oh so the or operator
now becomes actually can be used as a
flow control you just evaluate something
you know once you evaluate and that is
true you know don't evaluate you've had
you know don't run the rest of the code
the rest come where other commands you
know so people do that in shell all the
time and people start to do that in
Python you know in Python JavaScript you
know like when you have a variable you
don't know if that variable has a value
if it doesn't have a value you can just
say oh then give a default value you
know that's a that's a idiom you know
but that is they abuse of the or
operator it becomes so common you know
people don't think that's that's
actually abusive or operator because for
programmer you know a lot of people into
oak mods you know you are thinking good
news news
you know literal literate programming
the purpose is that you community you
communicate to programmers as priority
not communicate to the machine
you know you communicate to programmers
humans a lot of people into that but
they've they fail to see the operators
abusive you know these typical
programmers they don't understand the
thing you see when you use all operators
as a as a you know as a idiom to to to
to see which one you know evaluate and
you know to see your variable has
already as a value that's abuse that's
abuse of programming language okay
that's abuse of programming language so
you see in terms of a communication you
know the source code is a communication
to human animals you know to human that
that is not communication you know the
proper communication when you want to
you know control flow is if statement if
you know this variable equals to new
doesn't value then assign it a value you
know that that is actual communication
you know if something you know you tell
a human being that you know the if then
we want to assign otherwise assign it a
default value color equals to red here
you know but when you say Oh color then
if it's not true then red that is abuse
that that's not communication that's
that's logic operator
you know that's formal logic or operator
means which one is true you know that's
just by chance by side effect you know
youíve add you know you are using it as
a control flow that's that's my point
anyway we digressed against so much okay
so but see oh we did the explain so many
monkeys so let's read let's read on
about questions okay so okay so actually
okay next time you know I learned you
know sorry improve rest your life
check test test okay I guess I am okay
let's read the comments
why caught my car and not first why not
okay that's you are joining me
oh my camo this digressing for so much
it's a new tag on social media his new
tag on social media translating - oh my
god you are awesome I'm learning a lot
with website in videos thank you what is
difference between message and print
okay semen semen ask what's the
that's okay that's that's kind of also
advanced but that's a good question so
message now message just message is the
one you want to use the most of the time
especially when you are starting to
learn eMac this it just sprint to the
message buffer okay now message buffer
is a special buffer for output but off
but but sometimes you want to use print
okay is it's a print is a print is
actually the proper way okay print 20 is
actually more proper when you want to
print something now typically when you
say print print sum you know something
it also prints to the message buffer you
can see you see also print - message
buffer but however you can with tempura
okay so with tempura let me show you for
example you can print to a different
buffer for example with temper images
show some something within buffer create
a temp of evap of a body
let's try that okay this stretch is just
when let's see what happens with temp of
print something okay let's burn the code
okay it still wind goes to the temp of
but anyway I have a tutorial here but
anyway so the print is actually when you
want to you can target above it how do i
how do I explain this with Tim buffer
with Tim buffer you need okay so with
Tim buffered they are circumstances
which basically they are circum actually
when you actually need when the
circumstances when the situation comes
up you will know because when the
situation comes up you know you don't
want to paint to message buffer then you
know you know you know that's when you
want to use print and by the way I also
have a tutorial you know in my image
just you know there's a print print you
know print and output so this article is
explains message insert insert is a
function when you actually to insert
text in a buffer that's actually more
useful so message and insert is the most
useful print and variations you don't
you don't actually use that much you
know that's actually you know I have you
know you don't use that much but message
use it all the time and then you use
insert all the time insert is for insert
into the current buffer XYZ okay let's
run it you see now I got XYZ so you can
say switch to buffer let's say let me
show you let's just show an example
let's go to my exotic okay let's let's
say here let's see what what is my
current position let's say describe cha
so the current position is six eight
eight - okay here six eight a two so now
close that so we want to
let's try this so switch to buffer okay
switch to buffer the buffer name the
perform this buffer is okay so the
Puffin aim current buffer let's just
show you some practical let's see ivar
buffer okay I got a buffer name so let's
see what's it prints in one rebo
unreadable way I guess no that's a
perform your duties so I'm going to
switch to buffer kiba string then ii
talk show the optional optional we don't
care we don't want optional parameters
okay then let's say then let's say go to
cha wait go to cha go to cha 6 8 a 4
okay which is right here okay right
right right here okay then we say insert
XYZ okay now we want to run these three
lines now remember there's a command
eval perfe all-important so we do that
we select these three lines we call eval
buffer now I have a shortcut but let's
just called meta X eval we evolved each
enough of a give our region okay now
watch watch that sound talk show buffer
you're getting inserted watch that do it
you see you see that gets inserted so
that's you know that so that so that is
about the command
that's about the command insert so it's
a way to print in a way you can say it's
a print function so message is most
important and the insert is the most
important okay there's also print not
actually used often but you know you'll
get to it when you need when you when
you you you will know when you need it
okay yeah okay so yeah I now remember
there's a there's a with Tim proffer
there is a command there is a command
let's there's a command called with with
temp output buffer okay yeah let me let
me let me do this let me do a demo of
that there is a Emax function called
some something like with temp output
buffer so what that function do is that
is it's like within buffer okay what
that function do is that within that
code when you print something that's
something we always go to that buffer
you see so that is a way to to temporary
temporary you have a block of a code
every time you print when you use a
function print something it will print
out to that buffer so it's kind of like
insert now you know it's kind of like
insert but when you use the insert
function
it always inserts to the current buffer
so you need to you need to switch to
that buffer first then whatever you do
insert insert to that buffer but
sometimes you don't want to switch to
you know other buffers you you you just
want to call a function that I always
just just you know insert to that buffer
so that here's how you let's see let's
do some demo of that
so the function I forgot the name you
see so that's that's you know remember
there's a proper command that's how you
find a function so let me do that ctrl C
then call a proper apropos command
there's okay then we call a proposed
command then type a string so that
function is something called with temp
output buffer okay so let let's type
with temp okay enter then your list all
functions with that as part of the name
so
it's not here so we have with temp of
with temp of a window with you know
magic and with temp message okay that's
not that's not what I want so let's try
it again
control see let's try it again control
see metallics apropos command so I
remember the function name contains as
the word output so output type output
enter now let's see let's see
without put there there it is there it
is
with put to temp buffer so this is the
one I want this is the one we want so
let's tap to it and enter and do show
the function documentation so he says
with output Tim buffer is a lease Marco
okay then it says this construct maced
makes buffer buffer named empty before
running body okay it it does not make
blah blah it it then says basically the
the important thing is general you know
anything
so instead instead of buying standard
output to that buffer so that helpful
generate with print and similar
functions will go into that buffer
that's basically that's what it is okay
let's try this so let's try this let's
do a demo of that close close so we want
we want that okay so let's keep a buffer
name let's say let's say your random
let's say let's say ABC so that's that
will actually create a temp of a named
ABC okay then the body
okay this odd so let's put the body here
so let's in the body let's say print
raining today okay
so here's a code we're gonna run it so
this you know so let's so look at let's
try to you know look at all the windows
you know let's see what happens so evil
ask sex okay let's call it co-ed there
it is so you see it actually created it
generated a new buffer you can check the
buffer name ABC there it generated a new
buffer and it just sprinted what we
wanted you know tween you know raining
today so that's how you use print that's
how how that's how you do it
okay so maybe that's it for today today
we have some random random email list
stuff you know it's still interesting
random stuff so any income any questions
so we got no more comments you have been
watching comments guys comment and I
think maybe that's it for today we could
talk another five minutes
jump to definition so forbidden says so
okay so yeah so Nick says like I'm
editing a Python script and I want to
jump to the place it defines it okay a
function of a variable well in Emacs
this that's already building you know
that's that's already building so let me
show you okay in Emacs this for example
you want to go to the definition with
tempo feh
I mean with tempo with tempera is
already building it's a building
function but you this works for your own
code as well so you want to know you
know you just call this web described
variable I mean this work described
function okay let's do it
describe function with ten buffer
enter then it shows you see it shows the
documentation but it also shows the file
where it is defined so you just move
kusa there you press tab you press tab
to move the cursor they are enter then
it it opens the file and put the cursor
on the on a source code where it is
defined so here is you know where it is
defined this is part of coffee max so
you know it's and the better way so this
is one way to learn emag least to you
can just look up any function it will
jump to the élysée code you can see you
know how they do it but usually this is
not for beginners you know for the first
half a year you this is nothing not a
good way because it involves quite a lot
of things you know yeah so anyway that's
how you jump to function it's already
building just you know the function name
is just describe function you know
that's how you jump to source code so
you do not have to write it you for
yourself that's already building if
that's your question
yeah let's ease same thing with variable
for example let's say for example we
have already defined X room remember we
already defined X so let's say I mean a
different buffer
let's go sleaze temple across that let's
go and cosine hello
let's go to yeah so I mean my talkshow
page I want to know I want to let's go
describe variable X okay okay then it
shows X is something something but it
doesn't show me where the where X is
defined you know suppose I want to know
where it is defined I can do that
it doesn't show me right now because so
far we have been using eve our last six
to evaluate this x that's why it doesn't
show you know but for example let's do
this okay so that's let's comment all
this out and let's come and all this up
okay comment it out so we only have that
now let's let's say let's say the
sixties wait okay 66 now let's do eval
buffer okay let's do IVA buffer okay
give our buffer is done now let's switch
back to my talk show page now let's you
know let's say I'm doing something I
have one hour after coming back from
lunch I want to know where is X defined
okay described variable X enter x value
is 66 he still doesn't show the buffered
it doesn't show me the fire so actually
let me call you var buffer directly so
because I was using my own command let's
see
MX avow buffer okay enter okay close it
now described variable X enter is still
doesn't show okay so let's let's open
that again so if let me show you another
way tip me let me show you another way
you know for variable it maybe not but
you usually does for functions but let
me show you another way
so let's go to diet let's go to diet
yeah the current directory so this is
the file this is the file and now let's
press capital L what capital L kept
capital l will call the command and load
load file which is kind of equivalent to
evolve over okay so first of all we can
let let me show you describe key so
let's call describe key then I press on
a second I call describe key I press the
key capital L then he says I all runs
the function tired to load Elrond's the
function tired to load okay basically
loads the file okay so let's try that
again
so let's go to diet now I press capital
L he asked me to if I want to load that
file I press space for it yes okay it's
loaded now like now now I go back now I
close this go back to my talk show page
now let's go describe variable type X
enter okay it does SEO doesn't show
variable where it is defined the setup
actually does it show yes yeah I know it
does I guess it does not because okay
let's let's press on let's get that to
work we need to get it to work so let's
try this okay load I'm gonna do hard
call I mean let's go listen we need to
get this to work
phase this okay so so we are going to
call the load command load command is
when you want to load a file like you've
avowed a four-hole file and we give the
whole full path okay then we don't need
the optional parameters okay so we're
gonna evaluate this okay so even last
if our last sex
so it says era hello fire and there's
error on number of arguments oh okay so
run number arguments so what I what I
was I doing
what wrong number of arguments but let's
try it again
evil ask set last sex recursive load oh
because well hello this it tries to
load this file then it's loading that
fire that nya get bigger seem duct okay
so now they did but but actually it's
already loaded okay it's already loaded
so let's try that described from
describe bow again so let's describe law
type X enter it still doesn't show the
you know it doesn't show the file where
it is loaded so let's try you again so
remove this low line create a new buffer
paste a low line here but meanwhile
let's change this to 67 so if it
actually loaded then we know you know
the value becomes 67 so let's now avow
this okay now we can just evolved a last
sex do it it's done now describe
variable type X enter it still doesn't
give us the file name it normally it
does okay now maybe there's some details
I forgot this is getting into details so
Whitney went why is it not for example
let me show you a variable I mean let me
show you why it it does for example
let's go to my Emacs in a fire okay
let's go to my Emacs innate file go to
the directory then search for settings
so this file
Emacs settings is all my Emacs Co
settings for example for example I have
some setting of variables let's see
there it is okay set Q global Mochrie
max 5 okay so global Mochrie is a
variable okay and you know I've said it
in in this file when Emacs starts it
loads this file so when Co describe
variable on this variable it should it
should I think you should show me this
file okay so I can jump to it so let's
let's try it
so describe variable global marker min
max enter okay yeah it so it shows you
know it shows global mark grogg global
Mochrie max is variable defined in this
file
simple DL and its value is final its
value is 5 or in general value is 16 so
I know what's going on now so let's jump
to the file you see it's there okay so
basically Emacs will remember when if
it's a variable Emacs we all remember
the file location if you are using
define different de Foix let me show you
okay therefore okay close this closes
wait this is closest okay here is here
is when it will remember the fire
location so suppose we want to do depth
depth Y okay actually this video is
getting long we want to define variable
y equals to 2 e maybe you do not need to
declare variables but usually you if you
are writing a mod usually it's a good
thing to define
to declare a variable the way you do
that is you use the file
de Foix okay Teflon so you say def Y
then optional in the initial value is 2
and then you give a Docstoc string this
is my Y okay so so suppose that now you
can evaluate this so let's do it
evil last six evaluated done now let's
call describe bar let's go ahead type Y
enter made so okay it works by snowed it
doesn't give you the file location well
that's maybe because let's try to load
file let's try load file loaded
yes load the file and it's described
variable Y enter no now it does ok now
ok finally Y is a variable defined in
this file now you can just press ENTER
to jump to it you see yeah so now that's
a run about that's ok that's that that
that is so so if you want a variable
such that Emacs jumps through the
original definition location you have to
use devoir
and also the way you evaluate this you
know evil as safe sex doesn't work
because that's usually used for
temporary purposes when you are working
on you know eMac this usually when you
use load file whenever load files code
that will remember any deflower location
you know that then then you code this
sky bar it will show you the location
you can jump to but you see this anyway
so that's that's you know that's a
little details
so let's see see so maybe so that's it
yeah so comments you know type your
questions you know you have 30 seconds
then we close down in 30 seconds maybe
yeah so anta's stash says Nick do you
try to find a library function okay so
it's addressing Nick you should install
package LP yeah there's some packages
you can use help you go to definition
well in Emacs that always work okay you
can use describe function okay yeah let
me explain that in Emacs if you are
coding eMac this described function
always work provided provided that you
are loading you know you are using load
file like if you are like me temporarily
coding something then like if you are
always calling eval region or evil
purple or evil ass sex those those
commands are for temporary functions
kind of so so so if you do those then if
you call describe function Emacs may not
show may not know what the file or
buffer it came from because you know
those are perfect for me hopefully it's
not permanent it's not a file but when
you do load like you jump to the tire
tired fire location you press capital a
capital L to load the file then Emacs we
all know this is a file then when you
call this scribe function will show the
file name okay so this always working if
you work in a Mac this your walk now if
you are working in Python you want to
jump to some functions location then of
course describe function doesn't work
describe function is only for eMac this
code then in those cases yeah you need
some other packages LP LP go to or
something
yeah and how
do you write that how do you write that
you can you know you can look into a LP
go to but you know we can I don't know
if and you you have to think about it
I'm kind of tired now so so Seema's say
this Simon Says the dis the describe
wasn't working before causing the buffer
wasn't written to disk yes yes yes and
also you have to use teflon sake you
won't walk you know you have to use that
yeah that's extra do you have to you
also you Steph devoured f custom II let
me let me say that so you Mak this set
you you know is you walk but if you
actually try to write something a
project you don't you typically don't
use set you you never use set you okay
you use let let okay X then well then
then set you x3 okay you use that or you
say let then x3 something okay
you do either that or oh that so you
typically don't use set you okay you
don't typically you don't use sec you
said queue is like you know fold for
learning this that's great okay but
usually so let is creating local
variables
you know once this is code next X
doesn't exist anymore let's say let's
say H okay for example that let's do
this message H okay and let's run it
rennet you see it's three now let's say
describe variable H it isn't there is no
such edge okay yeah because let creates
local variables set Q is kind of create
local a create a variable for the
current session but however say Q is
tremendously useful when you are
starting to learn eMac this yeah so you
know so let me make make a point it is
tremendously useful because when you do
H you know when you use local variable
you cannot see it like right now you
want to see described variable H it's
not there it so you know it's local it's
already gone you cannot see it so when
you actually start to learn e eMac B's
you do want to use lots of set Q so you
can then you can say you know described
variable or you can you can just let me
show you another trick
okay very useful you can just type X
here then call that evil-ass 6ko it it
shows the value 67 so it's tremendously
helpful you know it because all the
value stays you can see you know what's
going on you know because when you start
to learn you Maggie's error message is
syntax error you get confused so you
just do everything you know global say Q
and so on so you can you can you can get
idea you know maybe something is
overriding something things like that
then when you are good
it once you you know you write a
prototype of something you want to do
then you start to you know then you
start to you know defund for example D
fun then let X you know pack then you
start to refactor and pack all your code
into a function and with Papa let and
because by that time you already know it
works because you've tried as so many
times with so many frustrations there
now finally you have this beautiful you
know command with you know cream input
then you put this in your
so yeah so that's about set Q and let
and if okay so what about de Foix now
deep tefa
is actually one level up now as we
mentioned you know you can have def tea
fun that's clean right D fun that's a
time when you have a difference
something you put that in your uni file
then that's good
that's good for you but now level up
when you want to write your code for the
public for other people usually you
don't tell them to oh just for this in
your uni file just put this command you
know just for this define your any file
because then everyone has thousands of
difference you know they they crash and
things like that so next level is when
you want to write a package you know
then then in a package when you have a
when you have variables that's intended
to be global but sometimes you need that
you know that's when you use def law you
know when you use Stef are you actually
declare a variable to be part of the
package actually Scoble because Emacs
Emacs does not have namespace everything
every packages package is actually
global so when you so you want to use
teflon my prefix and something like that
okay def variable global for your
package name then initial value if if
it's appropriate then a documentation
then this is when you actually have a
documentation for your variable you know
it's not not like let you know let
doesn't doesn't have documentation this
is when when you call describe var or
variable it actually have a
documentation you know so it's kind of
like permanent and not temporary so yeah
so when you do packages when you write
packages that's when you want to use
death law and there's more there's also
actually
let's let's see what are the others
they've come death because they've
custom okay deaf custom is a way my son
column wait okay the Deaf custom is
another way to define a variable for a
package in a package you know for public
consumption so what's the difference
it's it's very similar to de Foix the
difference is that when you use staff
custom then people can use people can
call the command custom people can call
the command custom group then type your
package name like some major mod make
like my my Elise MA or Java screamin you
know then people can type a major mod
name then all those deaf custom
variables will show up you know so so
this is a way you know custom group is a
way for people to customize a package
without knowing or the you know these
details they can just see oh these are
the variables you can you can you know
customize you know their values they
have documentation so that so that's
about deaf custom so these are the
different ways to define variables you
know baby was and did have this more
actually so this is local there's a
buffalo CO variables and anyway
so yeah so that's it for today I'm
getting hungry now I gotta go eat and so
I've given up on vim and not sure what
he max is using so yeah okay if you like
my tutorial you know go buy it you know
I'm you know I read I dried them I sell
them no I working on them you know go to
my website sorry Emacs tutorial and buy
it you know as a token you know that you
are going to you dedicated you are going
to actually you know as start to learn
you Mack this and that's good for me so
anyway thank you guys for watching
that's for that's it for today and
tomorrow is probably going to be the
same time twelve o'clock noon San
Francisco time in tomorrow
[Music]
the topics it could be I think what's
the topic tomorrow
you know today so tomorrow let maybe do
something else something else goal and I
don't know pay the piper
yeah pitiful thankful so I don't know
what's the topic yet but you can always
go to like let's see it's not talk show
life this like this you are you know
YouTube siik saris like that usually
walk like I have to go say that up you
know I have to go so I'm going to
schedule it sometimes later tonight now
sometimes later so by tomorrow morning
you'll see it you can go to that you URL
you'll be you know it will be your sake
coming up you know it's certain hours
yes and then you can type topics or
whatever so that's it for today so okay
now you guys for watching bye