good morning guys
welcome to another episode of SCI talk
show so today I think we might try to do
a non-technical talk show
then technical you know because we being
here we had technical talk show you know
talking about JavaScript about Emacs for
a while and you know it's fun to do a
non-technical hi Isaac
how are you you seen on technical topics
you know it can get very wild and also
you know when you talk about non
technical topics your audience becomes
like literally 1000 times more because
you know literally you know you know
there are 1000 more than 1000 times more
non-programmers name programmers so when
you talk about programmers programming
stuff very few people I as a Isaac so
how are you
what would you up to so for
non-technical I you know actually I
don't know what to talk about today I
haven't yeah you know I don't have a
plan so I wrote out today you know the
April 6 today six we we can talk about
YouTube so here's some topics topics
YouTube some page of my wordy blog
learning language great just been doing
homework all day okay what homework have
you been doing so are you using
university college students or and
what's your major you know I always ask
people that you know what's your major
so we can talk about learning languages
okay listen speak read write like
learning natural languages like Chinese
or English or German
Oh French computer science in
engineering great let's computer science
engineering
you see I oh wow UC Irvine my professor
friend is there that's in Southern
California where you have a beach what's
what's the beach called you know a
beautiful beach they're computer science
and engineering so what should we talk
about so I was you know I have some
subject here so talk about YouTube talk
about what he broke my English English
writing literature you know grammar
writing style and linguistics related
stuff ok this is quite a lot over there
actually for example let's and and
YouTube of course YouTube is you know a
wild thing I mean they are like a
billion videos you know of all sorts and
some of them and a lot of them are
really good actually almost like any
topic you want to look for Sawadee so
let's begin ok so you know you know III
don't know what topics so so there's
also go over my Twitter so because
Twitter I post every day you know this
always interesting things
Java's to Aqaba script object system
javascript es2015
although those are technical so maybe we
don't do that today you know maybe I you
know then there's a math algorithmic art
that's saw math
this is a great topic actually
algorithmic mathematical art so we have
to start somewhere you know it's like
every time I mention a topic I almost
like immediately I can just start to
talk about it and I'm going to dive in
so you know before you know as soon as I
mentioned the topic then you know I can
talk about that then I never get get
back to you know what we were saying
before what English so what English blog
is here let me show you yeah the word in
English there's a literature that's
quite interesting interesting there's a
Shakespeare okay let's go to Shakespeare
let's go to literature classics okay
wait a minute
my website is slow let's quit this brave
then quit brave literature there is this
let's say Socrates Shakespeare the
tightest the tragedy of Titus Andronicus
now this is this is actually
Shakespeare's first walk and it's it's
extremely bloody it's the most bloody
play you have ever seen more bloody than
whatever movies you watch today you know
like when you watch movies today you
know the Friday the 13th or whatever you
think that oh that's cool and stuff but
this play on Titus Andronicus by
Shakespeare 1594 is more bloody than
that and and I read you know so actually
I read the whole thing more than once
and I annotated that so you know so for
example I act 1 scene 1 and you know
Saturnus
and you know I annotated it
it's the JavaScript yeah you know
there's lots of words and lots of stuff
so anyway but you know so it's it's the
most bloody it's that the tail is
incredible and and it has become my
favorite literature of all times one of
let's say you know let's say top 5 or
top 10 Oh
Shakespeare yeah I love his just love
his stuff you know the way you know he
writes you know like you know when you
mention Shakespeare especially among
programmers it looks seems like you know
he did and Holte like oh he's talking
about Shakespeare you know but I think
actually it turns out I really do like
it I mean it just I just you know it's
incredible the writing and so I read
this you know multiple times and I I
took one year you know one whole years I
spent one year to annotate the entire
thing you know you can like you if you
go to you know you can you can buy books
that's annotated Shakespeare play let's
say Hamlet or others you know
Shakespeare's play they have an
annotated versions you know you can buy
and usually the annotator is some kind
of you know professor or Shakespeare
expert but you know I I went ahead and
annotated the whole thing odds by purely
by just reading up dictionaries and
encyclopedia so that's first past you
know so I not annotated the whole thing
they are let's show some examples you
know the Act one Scene one is quite long
let's see Act two scene two so you see
all these gray boxes
those are my annotations so Olympus you
know Olympus is the mountain where gods
recites that's from Greek mythology then
you know there's a link to Wikipedia
fortune fortune is a fortune is a
goddess of luck and fate
in Las Vegas you you'll find a lot food
for tuna and for me Thea's and so on you
know it refers to a lot quick old woman
you know mythology garden goddess nymph
and so on and you know so there's a lot
so I ended you know I annotated them but
but after year I started I started to
read a professional annotated version by
you know this this is a Google ad Google
ad is becoming incredibly annoying you
know it's not just me putting on my
website I mean like it's this is no
let's not get into Google you know did
they become evil phantom Beach do you
still have the same tired from York's a
log well that depends on which one you
refer to because I think I wrote a few
times but but my lab but my diet is
pretty much the same I mean it well not
like before though I actually I you know
I so I don't remember exactly which one
you were reading but basically I used to
in my thirties I used to you know I want
to be a Superman so my diet my diet is
tends to be very scientific based you
know I want to eat you know whatever the
latest scientific findings because I
really wanted to be like super MELAS as
in the greatest athlete or whatever you
know yeah I can do anything so you shy
so I I don't eat any fat I don't know
mostly don't eat any fatter I eat
protein rich food and I usually I eat
those protein bars and putting powers
when I was younger I did a lot of those
and fruits and banana
but not in the past ten years let's say
and I realized most of those is kind of
trash
I mean basically we've been lied to you
know you know how diet you know like
people you know people say oh you
shouldn't have fat you know like 20
years ago for for like 20 years you
shouldn't eat fat you should eat this or
that and today I just found her you
shouldn't eat vegetable all yours so
called vegetable overs so this is this
guys that says vegetable oils it's
actually all a lie they began by you
know we only started to eat vegetable
oils like como yo you know como you're
canola or your batter a canola there is
no such plant called canola the canola
oil is actually rape seed okay that fan
is called rape seed and of course that
word is sensitive you know is that was
cut problems in Western society in white
people society so they changed they
invented this word canola which stands
for Canadian and something you know they
so they created this word canola oil way
but anyway so back to the topic so yeah
so I tend to be my tire tends to be very
healthy based but but not necessarily
like you know I I don't
I'm not against meat of course I eat a
lot meat actually I am not against
genetic engineered food you know a lot
healthy type of people they they don't
want genetic engineer food they want the
you know for example there's a whole
food store in California in which your
they or this right you know geeks go to
very expensive then there's you know
they don't want genetic engineered food
and
they don't they want this there's a code
soak so-called organic this stays very
popular organic oh it's still rapeseed
in Germany you see how Google is evil
this this [ __ ] Google and it's social
justice can you know that you cannot see
you cannot say rapeseed these days
because so you know Google is asking you
to proc it anyway so organic you know
organic food becomes very popular these
days because they listen and actually
there's no scientific basis for anything
you know organic is not it's not
necessarily healthy the only reason
organic you know the only reason organic
thing is good is because is the
possibility where they do not use
chemical like pesticide and stuff you
know if you use that sometimes they
contain you know they there's a residue
on the food you know and that's no good
because you know that's about the only
thing good about organic you know is
organic is basically just and also you
learned you know doing all these years
you learned actually all these companies
behind it they are actually just they
just want to make money all these evil
companies for example the organic
organic food whatever the craze you know
they are companies behind them you know
they want to push it get you to buy it
supposedly you know good for the planet
and so on my ass in fact if you know if
you if you eliminate genetic genetically
engineered food ok if you suddenly like
if you are God you eliminate it right
away the whole world is going to go into
hunger ok you're gonna you know half of
a population is going to die you know
this organic fantasy you know by this
rich elite people of course most of them
are a lot you know basically all
programmers in California for example in
working at Google Facebook this this
[ __ ]
kids but anyway so organic food so I so
I was talking about my diet you know
basically the idea is that I want to be
scientific you know whatever science
says it's healthy for you know human
animals I want that and so I kind of
followed that I eat salmon I eat you
know whole wheat bread yeah I always eat
holy holy bed and and spaghetti
you know pasta and stuff and and also I
I don't eat fat like this especially
like saturated fat to such a degree I
mean in my twenties and thirties to such
a degree I think I actually I may have
I'm risking damaging damage to my liver
because I was reading you know it was
it's said that you don't need fat
because your body can produce it what
you need is 14 so you know I tend to eat
just 14 and not your almost no fat and
that and so that's pretty bad because
when you eat when you eat 14 you know if
you don't eat fat your body your your
liver has to do a lot work on protein
and they actually can damage your
protein in fact there's a story called
rabbit tired you know in the early days
of America where people they don't have
nothing to eat except rabbit rabbit meat
and you develop problem so like sickness
because a rabbit meat is pure lean meat
like no fat but you you get sick from
that
let's see rappy rabbit meat so so what I
was going and also I'm into the idea
where I can if I can just take a pill I
don't have to eat nothing anymore just
take a pill that would be good you know
like astronaut
astronauts in space you just rabbit meat
there's a phrase okay let's go to Saudi
diet then because I probably saw the
diet I have written about it then I
remember what to talk about meal on
appeal diet of Saudi meal on appeal okay
okay yeah I'm as good as dead
not yet I'm not dead yet
oh yeah this this one is a new article
actually this this I just wrote a few
months ago that that's interesting topic
to go into Mille ampere and dialogue
sorry so this article is you will refer
referring to right yeah I pretty much
eat this I still eat a lot of these I
mean well it because no I don't have
money so I don't even have money to buy
many of these now so you know it kind
it's kind of like that yep I haven't you
know had broccoli like that for a while
so this is this is like six years ago
oh seven nine nine years ago Wow and
that is the same desk as this one I'm
still sitting on it yeah so that's my
diet
yeah but basically these article
describes my thinking my philosophy you
about tired and I I don't really do that
I don't really think that way that much
anymore because because I think you know
basically a yeah I'm not
I mean as far as me doesn't have really
haven't changed it's just just the same
but I was I'm not as severe as I was
before about about it because what you
could say I'm still the same yeah well I
mean I'm like for example before you
know I would never drink whole milk you
know milk I always drink skim always
like hundred-plus always I never drink I
don't even drink you know have skimmed
you know I always drink you know 100
percent scheme non-fat nonfat milk but
now I drink fat milk you know you know I
don't think it's the the the idea of you
know not drinking whole milk at all is
actually I don't think it's necessarily
good I mean well it's oil all depends on
what else you eat you know but I was - I
was quite a severe in in a way for some
period of time in the past so I I drink
you know I eat pork
I eat fat you know these days I eat
anything right sometimes my roommates
they work in restaurant they they work
in Chinese restaurant so they bring me
whatever I just eat them so yeah all
these Wikipedia articles I was reading
them I still eat oats cereal yeah okay
let's show that so the food that's the
food milk and day-old bread one the full
milk and day-old bread oh I think you
are referring to another page anyway did
this this is the page I talk about my
diet what about Chinese food I eat them
I mean you see I I don't really strictly
follow any diet I mean I don't really
have a diet I just have a tendency you
know like to to always eat health
healthy and scientific based you know
science-based nutrition based you know
science-based
food and also but also this idea is is
quite different from the typical you
know San Francisco Green Party or
whatever you know they want they want
organic they don't want genetic the
engineer food they want you know they
want green they want trans whatever I am
NOT into that also I'm not with big
vegan or vegetarian okay
I again it's most it's strictly based on
science in fact I wouldn't mind I eat
genetic food I don't have a problem with
that at all because you know it's just
it's just it's engineered in fact I
would I wouldn't mind you know if I can
just eat appeal it's completely
synthetic human made not natural natural
at all you know just appeal as long as
you know as long as we know you know
it's it's scientifically good but again
you know also note that you know we
don't fully actually understand
nutrition not at all so even today you
know they have you know they have okay
so they have this kind of thing
Soylent you know it began it became a
fad kind of among geeks
you know programmer geeks you drink
these this is supposed to be scientific
based nutrition like all about nutrition
you know human diet although everything
we know you know in your bottle you know
you just drink this one you know one a
day or two a day or three a day or
something like that so we got these
today but actually let me tell you we we
actually don't know there you know as
far as today's today's science goes we
don't actually fully understand exactly
what's going on
so if you survive on these for a month
that's okay for for two or three months
you get sick you know you cannot survive
on these four also the other thing I
learned is that if you don't chew if
your mouth do not chew you're gonna have
problems with your jaw whatever you you
you you know you develop problems so
that's a few things interesting
oh you are talking about the video no
well I mean since the video since since
the video I have you know I have been
living with my roommates and they they
work in restaurants so you know the
sometimes they bring me food and stuff
and now I'm making some no I'm surviving
on some ads Google ads okay so so that's
kind of I kind of rambled I want I want
so how many people are watching here how
many people here seven cubes I just
closed it back you see this is the
stupidity with the with the mouse and
aiming you know you have this mistake
first of all yeah it takes time to em
you know which tab you want to then
let's close that let's pop this out
again
sorry
what okay now it's getting super slow
curse that
chat settings I don't want chat ceilings
you're still on your live chat okay here
pop out
okay hey break the loop never apologize
for rambling you for happening is why I
subscribed okay that's good good to know
so what about food okay anything I guess
that's it for food
we still Jewish talk about food I was
going back to the the the tragedy of
Titus Andronicus okay I want to say so
there is a film ok this film by Julia
tomoow okay directed by julietam oh you
should check it out it's fantastic film
well I mean you may not like it I mean
it's it you know it depends on I mean if
you you know you might like it okay
that's one of the sayings but anyway so
you if you like Shakespeare kind of
based film you want to get this one this
is incredible
I watch it i watch it it so many times
it's you know art and stuff and there's
a trailer and yeah this is you know
that's the goal scene you see that yeah
it's pretty bloody so it's it's it's
about revenge basically this phrase
about revenge
yeah this is this is this came out in
1990 nice sometimes around there I think
yeah I don't remember but yeah okay so
Chinese food Chinese food is good it's
delicious I eat it often because you
know my roommate works in restaurants so
they bring me I haven't tried soil and
soil and stuff now but soil and stuff is
something I would be very much
interested like things like this ready
to eat me out now this thing is popular
this this thing is popular among certain
subcultures you know they you know that
like they are thinking the world is
going to collapse so they buy a bunch of
these this this is made by I think it's
made by US military's yeah but it's
supposed you know it's it was intended
for soldiers you know you know you got a
whole bag in actually there are people
there are people on YouTube that review
these kind of food and this guy is funny
he actually shows you an experience and
he actually his whole channel is about
reviewing this this so called
EMA he ready military ready to eat you
know his whole channel as bodies so
there are these EMA is made by US
government made by UK and you know and
some of his videos he is showing you on
mie that's like 50 years old you know
from World War you know from Vietnam war
something you know he actually got that
and shows you it so you know it so bad
of course it's come bad but he he shows
you that so yeah so there are people
into that and actually so you know I'm
not so much into this
things but these kind of things has been
has been my ideal meal you know it's
like this this is the ideal diet I would
you know so when I was younger in my 30s
and 40s even I very much into 20s in my
mostly twenties and thirties I'm very
much into these kind of things so so
these days you know maybe five years ago
you have this Soylent I never tried but
however before before this you know I
was drinking slim fast slim fast and
there are others you know you know I was
drinking those often you know again you
know when I talk about my meals usually
people get confused you know something
some people they they project you know
they think they you know I mean to vegan
well some other people think you know
they are you know you are into organic
you know fashionable you know you know
California programmers organic stuff you
know healthy and green stuff then some
people think you are I'm tired because
of some reasons you want to lose weight
or you want to you have some you know
diabetes or some problem now I'm not any
of that I'm into I'm kind of you know I
just have you know I'm into scientific
you know like I'm a nerd you know in the
extreme so I want my food to be you know
I want to type into computers of my food
you know decide my food choice is kind
of going to that direction I don't care
about agreeing organic stuff I don't
care about you know you know so you know
the only thing I care is like
functionality you know you know like the
book you know the perfection so anyway
so I haven't tried Soylent so yeah
that's that's that's that about this
food stuff and just create something
the rise of robots stupid so what what
else
netsy souland is convenient but a little
pricey yeah I think you can you know you
can just drink
slim-fast there I mean there are several
if you go to let's say Walmart okay you
go to the place where they have slimfast
there are several other varieties okay
not necessarily slimfast and I used to
drink that you know for like over 10
years you know regularly every week or
at least once a month or something you
know
so prick the loop says I wonder if you
would like black mirror the show has
interesting ideas know what show is that
yeah mie okay but you wouldn't eat them
every day I think if you eat everything
I mean basically yeah if you eat the
same thing every day you get sick with
sick of it you know I was thinking you
know like when you when you eat
something every day like sometimes like
pizza for example usually it's good
right but if you eat it every day you
know every single day for a month you
you get sick of it I mean you don't like
it you don't you don't want it anymore
and same thing with Chinese or any any
other typically thing so I was wondering
why do people feel that and my and I'm
thinking the reason is that it's
actually a natural reaction because your
body you know you don't want the because
you want variety because they are you
know different nutrients if you just eat
the same thing exact same thing every
day you get sick I mean it's like you
know you you naturally feel you don't
want to you know you don't feel you want
to eat that anymore and I was thinking
just there's a biological reason because
you know if you keep eating that you may
actually get sick physically because you
your food you know do not have the
variety of nutrients
yeah they you know they my roommates
they work in restaurant I you know I was
I know them I was walking through this
joint okay that's about that's about
food I guess
yeah the scientific food so yeah so my
food you know like I said before like a
nerd I don't care about you know almost
it's like I almost don't care about
taste neither you know for most people
you know you care about taste like oh
that's not tasty for me it's like you
know it might be a trend effect you know
like it's like over the you know past
decades I trained myself to become this
way because one poem for me it's like I
don't care about the taste however
however I do enjoy the tasty food like
you know if you go to a restaurant yeah
I love them you know it almost any
restaurant you know any food from any
restaurant any type of food I love them
better than you know my noodles my
spaghetti at home of course but however
you know if I am NOT going to restaurant
if I don't have the operation you know
opportunity if I just eat at home that's
fine too you know so you know in one
word I think you might the the word bog
might just capture it you know that's
where that's what I'm thinking yeah food
okay let's close that oh yeah there's a
so I was talking about you know you
cannot eat lean meat all the time
because you'll get sick actually I have
written a article about that oh they are
yeah rabbit meat poisoning so I was
reading about this yeah so one day I was
looking you know at what's the
difference between between rabbit in
hell oh how do you pronounce that ale
hail I think here then I then I found
out about this rabbit meat poisoning
let's see yeah
protein poisoning yeah that's called
protein poisoning from eating just
rabbit meat so another interesting thing
is you know rabbit starvation okay there
that's the article all called protein
poisoning basically when your diet is
just lean meat such as rabbits your body
cannot cope with it this is quite
interesting because my whole life I've
been infatuated with with a fat-free
diet I thought that that since the body
can generate fat from protein and
carbohydrates and protein in general is
the best as mean those protein rich
diets advertised by body builders I have
since realized that this is quite
dangerous because many essential
nutrients are in fat only in a diet
without much fat and carbohydrates
stresses out your liver yeah so there is
this rabbit protein poisoning so you
know since I learned about this in
thinking back thinking back I think I
you know at some period of time I was
actually in risk of that because I
reduced you know I I kind of you know
eliminated any fat in my diet protein
poisoning
yeah is a rare form of acute
malnutrition thought to be caused by a
neo complete absence of fat in the diet
yeah so I was you know I was almost
doing that so there is that then I
discovered this thing you know like you
know Wikipedia is so big you know the
way that we Vidya is almost like entire
library of the 90s you know a local
library it's more information there so
you can you know if you guys just go to
Wikipedia you can this endless you know
articles in fact you know if you just if
you actually only consider the math
sections of Wikipedia like oh math
archives in Wikipedia
that's going to be quite a lot actually
I'm not sure how to it's like a room of
books or Raikou morning Rach well
actually I don't know but anyway so yeah
so anyway on Wikipedia I learned about
these three areas motif so basically
it's support you so basically it said
that you found this motif back to Asian
times throughout the world but we don't
understand why like we don't understand
where does this motif came from why is
that so that's something like that let's
see three years you know but some but
also note that sometimes we keep he diya
they got bad info first of all anything
on today's news okay anything related to
posit politics you know whatever on
appears on today's news the
corresponding Wikipedia
you know related people or places or
items is bad okay that that one is for
sure so anything related to politics be
sure you know don't trust Wikipedia
including for example today's chance
trans feminism women Wonder Woman you
know like the Wonder Woman article the
it's got entirely be written from ten
years ago actually I have you know it's
like it's Wonder Woman entirely erased
you know the history of Wonder Woman the
the comics it's just good instead you
got the you got the social justice point
of view you know what Barbara academic
jargon but I actually won a woman is
interesting because it began with a
touch of bondage you know that founded
by this guy you know it basically was
just a nerd yeah you know it's like a
pornography you know for for kids for
young boys that was what what what
Wonder Woman was you know and I remember
when I was small like maybe eight years
old or 10 years old back in Taiwan I
love Wonder Woman it's one of my
favorite superheroes even though I don't
know you know back then I was in Taiwan
I don't know anything about America or
you know I don't know English of course
you know I it's not like so when I was
like ten years old or eight years old
that person is completely different from
what I am today
I mean I mean things about things change
you know it is totally different
well anyway Wonder Woman was my favorite
superheroes and the other one is Batman
and spider-man okay and but today I
would you know I sped me I still like
spider-man I really despise everything
about the spider-man the character the
the the the you know the
anything everything about spider-man
spider-man is like you keep epitome of
American ignorance okay you know one of
the phrase popular popular popularized
by spider-man is something like when
you've got super power you have more
responsibility okay where anyone says
that run for your life you know only the
[ __ ] scumbags
you know the too powerful and they want
to control the world who says that
because they failed a guilt you know and
Americans love that you know like you
know so what's the word exactly what's
the phrase more responsibility
so anyone okay I'm not sure I mean
certain people here so what was the
phrase that's five Spider Man says and
this is interesting because one day I
was reading Eric yes are Eric s Raymond
you know the guy who started open source
you know the bizarre and Cathedral you
know he wrote that book in one of his
blog this is about maybe 10 years ago or
80 years ago I you know I was reading
one of his blog you know I don't read
his frogs but I was reading one of them
they he was quite he was quoting that
phrase okay am I still like a life guys
say something hate people watching oh
yeah there it is thank you guys
with great power comes great
responsibility
so I actually tried to look up you know
the source of that quote it turns out
that quote is not there's no exact
source you know
of the exact you know that that phrase
it just became part of the pop culture
anyway let me show you some of that but
anyways so what you know with that
phrase that that phrase is a phrase like
I don't know if you could say that the
typical American love you know they love
that phrase
you know like with great power comes
great responsibility
why do they love it because I think yeah
you know when you are you know when you
are at the top of the world you know
when you when you are the most powerful
that phrase is a comfort to you you know
like if I'm the richest you know a yeah
I would love that phrase with great
power comes great responsibility
it seems to tell me you know you know
like my power is legit
you know I yeah I'm a most powerful and
I should have great you know I should
have great responsibility you know it's
it's just good so anyway so so I was
reading Eric women you know he's back he
says that he says like what the [ __ ] you
know because he is the one he's into his
Pro Iraq war and and stuff well anyway
today the social justice which is more
evil than anything the social justice
can rose and he is he's opposing opposed
you know again you said so in that
regard I I support him so anyway so
there's this wonder woman you see all
this poundage you know this this sort of
sexual I mean if you see this is poem
back in the you know days you know I got
more pages I'm not sure I want to show
it but okay this page is still okay okay
I don't have to show the pattern but but
that's that's what it is you know look
at this is Wonder Woman you know the
origin of Wonder Woman you got all these
poundage things you know and bit and
also notice her costume is you know this
bikini
you know back then it's very
controversial I mean you know you know
the standard you know for how much skin
you can show in society changes right
today it's like you can you can be like
totally naked
but not back then this is considered you
know fairly very sexy so that's a
history you know that's you know that's
that's what
when a woman is you know beginning in
1942 1940s and also remember back then
in that era it's it's a Cold War era you
know you have the Americans and you have
the communists you know the Russia and
so a lot of the stories are tough are
fighting a communist but then 1970s you
know the feminism you know start to so
basically anything women is like a
famous feminist you know in any famous
you know female or girl is like becoming
associated with feminists so here we
have the Wonder Woman for president okay
and wicked is she is beautiful Lynda
Carter
cut Lynda Carter in 1976 I never seen
this this is 1976 I was I was I was
eight years old
yeah I never seen it I only I dug up
this information you know then yes then
you have you know so today you know when
you look at this you know covers of
Wonder Woman over the years you can also
see how the costumes you know the
standard of you know girls women's
clothing changes you know as with
respect to sexuality so basically you
just see less and less covers
you know then they become more sexy that
then you have that you know then you
have that this is 2003 one plot of meat
that's what it is in the end anyway
Wonder Woman so anyway so so let's read
the comments that's nice of your
roommates wait what do I do
my roommates work my my roommates work
in restaurants like down the street so
break the break the loop says the other
day I watched a video of a student for
tests at Evergreen college that happened
last year yeah and it was infuriating to
watch such stupidity yeah yeah they are
it's very bad I think you know this
right now is happening USA you know and
you know if you guys know I didn't watch
the Wonder Woman movie these days I
haven't been watching movies and I
wasn't you know yeah I haven't watched
it yeah so the you know the social
justice is happening it's very bad and
they are in power you know they are like
controlling everything including Google
they lie they plain blatantly lie you
know the Google fire the guy you know
James the more I studied you know in
many of these case you didn't know
nothing about it is this thing you know
that suddenly rose up you know in 2016
it's like all of a sudden you know I
could never imagine you know like USA is
very conservative you know it's like you
know God believing country you know
everything is you know on the dollar
bill or in coins we have In God We Trust
you know III don't believe in God okay
you know and I don't like the idea you
know In God We Trust but but it was very
strong you know that that notion but all
of a sudden you know around 2015 you
know over suddenly it's like that you
have a complete reversal of the
situation I couldn't you know I never
imagined that could be and actually
people are you know against you know
free speech you know like I've been
living in USA for like since 19 since
1989 okay vote for 30 30 years I could
never imagine that that one day
Americans would be against the idea of
free speech I mean it's impossible
because because before I was like kind
of ridiculous
we know ridicu in this concept because
because in America you have you know
yeah free speech is good but however the
the America you have this such an
obsession like every everything is about
free speech like this which this so and
constitution okay so I used to like make
fun of you know the of these ideas and
and you know and I was thinking you know
you should look around the world and
look around history you know like like
the the humanity you know it's not just
America you know it's not not just the
in the past 200 years they are few
thousands of years of history and out
you know before the there was America
before where there was a constitution so
so I my mind is thinking like that you
know I always like to view the world you
know the host history kind of way so you
know so
you know like 10 you know I make made
fun of many of these American obsessions
and the more more saying you know but
now it's entirely different this is
social justice can you know they did
they are like 10 times worse they are
you know I think there what happens is
that they are actually they are just
political corruptions you know like
people in power you know they got a lot
of money and they just want to do things
you know whatever things that make them
more reach that's why all these things
happen well that's part of the reason
because I've been trying to find the
reason so since 2016 okay
since 2016 around October when the
election is going about I began you know
I was like surprised by all these
happenings I began to read you know
spent maybe an hour to half an hour to
an hour every day
you know maybe around an hour every day
I've been trying to find out you know
where does this come from this social
justice you know this and all of a
sudden trans case you know I'm not by
the way I'm not again his case you know
trans trans is kind of new but I have
like I was a pretty face on my life and
in back in Montreal when I was 16 there
are case you know gays always like
chasing me you know they are games they
are their stole stories I would rather
not say but you know but anyway so
so since 2016 I was trying to find out
how did this all happen is seems like
over sudden then then so I started to
see and find you know realize some some
of the reasons for this for this
happening okay the the the major reason
is that the millennial generation the
millennial generation who are brought up
by mostly okay millennial generation
that's one thing they are brought up by
by the politically correct left
especially in Silicon Valley okay so
that's one thing
Millennials and the left-leaning
academia okay all the professors you
know they are there life is too good you
know they they feel guilty and and they
are always opened by white people okay
so academia they teach you know these
kind of things
academia since we always say since about
1990s
okay some millennial generation the the
academia okay and the power of
technology you know Google Facebook
since 2000 because most of these tech
people are not conservatives which
includes me kind of you can say that
includes me so you know for example in
2000 I you know I'm I'm I'm again is you
know the conservative believes you know
they believe in God and Jesus I don't
believe that in that so when I see you
know the Atheist movement I kind of yay
you know I don't want I don't want you
know In God We Trust in in the money you
know but but I I couldn't imagine it
turned out this way so so anyway so so
back to the reasons the political
character in it the Google you know the
technology group the other programmers
in Silicon Valley most most out you know
not conservatives you know they are not
believing people and Millennials in the
end and one of the most important is
social networks like Twitter and
Facebook they create these bubbles
because their goal is to make money and
and they do all they can to make money
and one of the things they do is to only
show things that's present to you
because you know you see things you know
only opinions you like that gets you
more involved you know you you might
post more and you know like things more
and what happened you know with that
then you start to have a division you
know between groups like you you start
to have bubbles like you only you see
the world only the way you like to see
it you don't see other side so so these
are the reasons I learned this from you
know there are so many sources you know
Jordan Pederson is one of the main ones
Camille Paglia these two I respect the
most anyway
oh yeah so anyway so so I haven't
watched the wondering earth movie I like
to so my favorite superhero I think I
think it would be Batman I you know when
I was younger I might test my favorite
because you know when I was like 8 years
old 10 years old I don't know nothing
about it I only you know when you are at
that age you basically just look at you
know their costumes and you know stuff
they are fighting and then you pick your
favorite but today I would say Batman
and basically nothing else I want a
woman I still like her but I only like
her body because he's you know she's hot
a hot girl and but in Batman but how do
you know this is something different
about Batman
because unlike other superheroes they
usually have some so-called superpowers
like they can shoot lasers out of their
eye or they can you know puncher like
hook becomes 10 times bigger or Superman
Superman is like the kind of the typical
example you know in basically the idea
of him invincible yeah you know nothing
can
kill him except then except they
invented you know that blue emerald or
something you know but anyway so but
Batman is a bit different because Batman
does not have any superpowers and the
story of Batman is basically a
psychological thriller
you know it's oh the the whole story of
Batman is based on psychology you know
he is he lost his parents when he was
young and his enemies almost all his
enemies he's also psychological freaks
you know you have the Joker
you have the penguin Joker is you know
someone you know a criminal but who
handsome guys mostly fell into you know
this chemical face and destroyed his
face and that creates you know that
creates your psychological problems
imbalances like the like the Phantom of
the Opera this is a common thing okay I
think in in stories where you have a
beautiful guy then your face got
destroyed anyway so Batman the penguin
penguin is a guy who you know who was
born deformed and his parents you know
discarded him so that's penguin then you
have a bunch of clowns like I guess
penguin
that's penguins clowns and code I forgot
what's the names but basically multiple
personality there's a name for it anyone
else what what's the term for that like
multiple personality so I supposed to
phase represent that so anyway so Batman
you know Batman is kind of you know he
doesn't have superpowers but he but the
story is all based on psychology so I
kind of you know I liked that would be
my favorite the other no not bipolar
there's this a bipolar is one of the
psychological
personality disorder but there's another
one which has multiple personalities
there's such void bipolar
means okay bipolar means maniac
depressive that was the word used for
bipolar before so so a depression is one
of the personality one of the disorder
okay
when you feel sad perpetually like you
know for prolonged period of time like
year after year
that's depression the opposite of
depression is there's sometimes you feel
you know like you had some I don't know
drugs you know you feel about the green
facemask that's a fun movie by Jim
Carrey you may check it out no not this
one let's go back
Jim Carrey the mask okay this yeah this
movie so this the mask that guy that
shows the maniac
that's called maniac disorder so so it's
it's like you get into a mood you can
you talk non-stop and you feel even
invincible that's let's go - okay so
let's go - okay hold on a second let me
go to the associative identity disorder
no I don't think that's the one
well it could be maybe they change the
name but that's not the name I'm
familiar with oh okay I guess they
change the name this this psychiatry is
like our Chico organizations they change
in the name you know every decades
okay dissociative identity disorder
previously known as multiple personality
disorder okay yeah yeah green deck hey
green deck
hey tea so piss off so anyway so there
is this dissociative identity disorder
actually you know this disorder I never
quite get it meaning that I never
actually can I you know I I don't
it's like I have a disbelief issue I
never found a person who is like that
you know except you know picture the
movies you know in movies that usually I
can picture what kind of you know psycho
psychological extremes but it's it's the
you know it's the movies you know they
exaggerate
but so for this one I never found like
multiple personality disorder I never
act you know I'm not sure I believe it
you know like I cannot find a actual
example or think of an actual real
example okay it's the other thing is you
know these psychologists and
psychiatrists psychiatrist you know they
they talk about these things but but be
aware that this is not this is not a
science like physics or math okay in
math or physics is absolute everything
Shin how do you get rid of that maybe
after 10 years oh you know we are all
wrong you know they change their theory
so you know there is that aspect so how
do we how did we talk about
oh yeah the associative motor multiple
personality disorders so I was thinking
that is the to face character
environment yeah so anyway so the fact
that the the superhero of movies they
know there they are like time a dime a
dozen so when I was younger you know I
used to actually read comics books you
know x-men actually there's another
series are more interested in which is
the competitor to x-men
it's called Teen Titans T&T ITA ns
okay now Teen Titans is I think it's a
DC C's version of the x-men you know
x-men became successful so it's from
Marvel's you know the company but the
other company called DC they want to
create something that's you know compete
in a similar kind of story and audience
but you know compete with the x-men so
they created this Teen Titans
these pictures are all bad you know they
are just this all these pictures are
from cartoon but actually okay here's
the original cover here and so back then
when I was 17 or so I was I was into
this chick Stardust on the left this one
her name is Stardust she is an alien and
this girl is Wonder Girl he's kind of
like a younger version of the Wonder
Woman and this is Robin Robin from you
know the bad bad means Robin anyways you
know you have these Teen Titans it never
became you know as popular as the x-men
okay so what else so how long have I
been talking must be well 70 minutes
that's enough yeah so anything else
interesting so you know the source the
superheroes are they they are you know
they are really ridiculous now when you
are a team you know yeah of course it's
fun but it's really they are just you
know they are just thing you know they
are just stupid comics 14 you know
because because you have Superman which
is supposed to be invisible invincible
you know nothing can hit you no damage
him then they had to create this you
know a weakness you know so that you
know because otherwise if he's just in
you know invincible then this end of
story
you know he just destroy you no way you
know you know in a Marvel Universe you
know the x-men or you know the Captain
America you know they then the incident
you have this super hero who can contain
then you have like multi universe then
you can so you can kill all bunch of
people then tomorrow they can all be
alive again you know like in another
universe so it's like it's like just
foolish it's like nonsense okay so I
think that's that's it for today let's
pop this out let's go here
so anything else anything else guy guys
say something so maybe that's it for
today
yep that's that's it for today thank you
guys for coming so we talked about
today's we talked about the social
justice scan okay see you guys bye