Hello, good morning everyone.
Good evening and good morning and good
noon. Welcome to another episode of
Start Up Show.
We are going to chat random-ish.
Uh we are going to do Unicode.
Uh the words writing system, okay? The
entire human
uh humans words writing system of entire
human history.
First of all, let's have a cheers red
wine, okay?
200 ml of red wine won't hurt.
Okay, let's go to the uh normal screen
so you can see my computer stuff.
Computers, that's what I do.
That's what I do every day since I was
uh like 20 21 years old. I you see
I begin life late, unlike many of you
who start a computing stuff when you
were teen.
I didn't begin I didn't touch a computer
until I was like 20 years old.
So, but but ever since I touched
computer
multiple hours a day every day and now
I'm close to 60, so I have computing
experience for 50 plus years.
Well, 40 something.
Okay, so well well technically sir 30
something close to 30 something, okay?
So, today we going to talk show Start Up
Show. Nobody's here, I believe. I'm
pretty certain.
The internet hot theory, okay? Let's pop
this out. Pop it out.
Like today, if even if you are a
professor, eminent professor, if you do
a live stream, nobody's watching.
That's the situation today.
Most people they watch porn. You know,
they they go watch they go Chaturbate.
Uh they go uh watch idiots talking about
Hello uh J J and J S J S
J S something.
Um hi. [clears throat]
So anyway, so we're going to do random
Well, we're going to do Unicode, okay?
So, let's do Unicode. So, show today's
stock show.
Yeah, let's just do Unicode, okay? So,
the uh and the pink window as I gave an
introduction yesterday, 5 minutes
introduction, this all my Emacs command
codes and keystroke.
Okay, real time live. You see You can
see that's a pink window.
Uh am I good? Video check, audio check,
and now my audio volume is fixed. So,
it's loud and clear, I hope. Very good.
Uh hi. So, if you have a questions uh J
Q J S, just ask me, okay? If you have
anything you want on
uh no my view of Okay, so today Yeah, so
let me show you what we're going to do
today. So, today Well, first of all, the
thumbnail, fascinating, amazing, the
utmost supreme.
We are in uh
evolution, you know, humanity is
undergoing major change like analogous
to similar in scale to the industrial
revolution around 1700, you know, or
1800 when the steam engine has been
invented. That changed the entire human
animals, uh us,
our life, our lifestyle, what we do,
what time we wake up, what we do every
day, what are we thinking, it changed
entirely since.
So, that's called industrial revolution,
okay?
Uh basically, that's the when steam
engine
is invented because of technology.
You know, human society always changes.
The change is almost always due to
technology. Okay, so industrial
revolution. So, let's search, okay.
Industrial Actually, let's just ask AI
since we are talking about the subject.
Okay, we are starting to digress, but
that's good. So, anyway, the thumbnail
you are looking at is from AI,
artificial intelligence, and it is from
Grok. Okay.
Uh and we have several Each picture by
itself is very interesting by itself.
For example, this crap.
Uh so, let's go to the image, you know,
the Grok. So, let You see, this is Grok
AI by Elon Musk.
You see, you got here is robotic crab.
Uh extremely well-designed. You You see,
delicate. At least a drawing of You see,
and AI generated, okay. You can generate
10,000 of it in a second.
So, that's
what's interesting about this. And this
is And And this crab as a drawing as an
artwork is beautiful. You see, let's
freeze it, okay.
And you can just go to a picture of it.
Can you enlarge?
I'm pretty sure you can make a larger
picture, but you see,
very detailed, okay. So, let's open
image in a new tab.
Go to it.
Okay, magnify.
Okay, so, can you see?
You see a crab, a mechanical robotic
crab generated by AI. So, you got this
You see, and it's beautiful. So, you
know, as as a artwork by itself, it's
incredible. It would take an artist like
a month, something, to create this. But
AI today generate this a million of it
per second.
Cheers. So, uh AI is um
So, we are in a major
change, okay? We don't know exactly
what's going on, but we are in a major I
mean that and and this is not just this
is just this is nothing, you know, wait
until
>> [laughter]
>> Anyway, so that's one part of it, okay?
The image this crap, okay?
Now, the other so all these are AI, so
the you know, Elon Musk is trying to
market his AI, you know, so you got all
these animations. You can post a photo
of yourself or your loved ones, your
family members, and your your
your creator animation, okay? Out of the
photo and very realistic like today you
can tell it's fake or not, okay? For
example,
uh I'm not going to show it, but you
know, I got this image from the web,
okay? Someone posted this girl's
hot, okay? Very hot image.
And so, you can post it to Grok and
we'll generate
animation of it, okay? So, that's one
example. And here is another example.
This completely AI generated. Like, can
I actually show it?
Uh
>> [sighs]
>> okay, so we are talking about AI. Can I
Uh yeah, I can like where do I where is
my um
You see the these are like the default
galleries of
uh Grok, you know, there's millions,
okay? Endless, okay?
It just doesn't make point to show, you
know, because everyone knows it by now.
Okay, so anyway, that's uh all these are
AI, so
So, that's that's why so so what I'm
saying is that so we got industrial uh
evolution, okay?
Let's see. Grok, help me.
Uh
new chat, okay.
So, I was asking about
um
Yeah, audio settings about Windows. So,
let's have a new uh chat.
Look, explain Industrial Revolution,
please.
>> The Industrial Revolution kicked off in
late 1700s Britain. It shifted us from
handcrafting stuff at home to
machine-powered factories. Key
inventions like the steam engine,
spinning jenny, and power loom cranked
up production like crazy, especially in
textiles and iron. It spread to Europe
and the US, brought railroads,
urbanization, and massive economic
growth, but also child labor, pollution,
and tough factory conditions. Basically,
it created the modern world we live in.
Want me to dive into any part like its
causes or impacts?
>> Yes, did it change human habit like what
time we wake up, what we do every day?
>> Yes, it changed daily life a lot.
Before, people woke with the sun, worked
on farms or at home with flexible hours.
Factories brought strict schedules.
Bells rang at fixed times, so folks
started waking up early to clock in,
often at dawn or before. Shifts were
long, like 12 to 16 hours, 6 days a
week.
>> Okay, fantastic. Thank you.
S-
So, 700s
uh in Britain, okay. So, tell me when
did what when was lightbulb invented?
>> The first practical electric lightbulb
was invented in 1879 by Thomas Edison in
>> I see. So, 1879,
that's
like a hundred years after Industrial
Revolution.
>> Yeah, spot on. About a hundred years
later, the Industrial Revolution was
roughly 1760 to 1840. So, the light bulb
came right at the tail end of the
>> So, the Industrial Revolution began
because of a steam engine.
Is that right?
>> Not exactly. The steam engine helped it
explode, but it didn't start it. The
revolution began with textile machines
like the spinning jenny and water frame.
Those came first, powered mostly by
water wheels. The steam engine, improved
by James Watt in the 1770s, came along
and let factories move away from rivers,
scale up massively, and power trains and
ships. So, it supercharged the
revolution, but wasn't the spark that
lit it.
>> I see.
>> Cool. Anything else you want to know
about the Industrial Revolution?
>> You see, we can change the speaking
speed. Let's do so because this is
a bit slow for my taste. So, 1.2 and we
can change
uh the protagonist voice, okay?
>> [snorts]
>> I love Eve. Eve is the soothing female.
Era is the American upbeat female, okay?
That's what we've been talking to with.
Okay, so Eve. Now, let's tell let's talk
to Eve. Let's see
anything
else you want to know. So, yeah.
So, what is factories like in 1700s?
Like what kind of factories they have?
>> Factories in the 1700s were just
starting to pop up, mainly in Britain.
Before that, everything was handmade at
home or in small workshops. Early
factories were water-powered textile
mills, spinning cotton and weaving
cloth. They had big water wheels turning
machines that did the spinning and
weaving way faster than people could by
hand. By late 1700s, steam engines
started powering some, but most were
still water-driven. They employed
hundreds of workers, often women and
children, in noisy, dusty conditions. No
electricity, just belts and gears
everywhere.
>> So, what do they create around, you
know, during the 1700s? Like, what do
they actually make? Just cotton cloth
clothing?
>> Mainly cotton cloth. They spun raw
cotton into yarn, then wove that yarn
into fabric on big mechanical looms.
That cloth got shipped out to be dyed,
printed, or turned into clothes
elsewhere. A few early factories also
made woolens and silk, but cotton was
king. Some places made iron goods like
pots and nails using water-powered
hammers, but the big factory boom was
all about textiles.
>> I see. So, all the factories making
textiles. So, textiles is so important.
Why is that?
>> Textiles were huge money. Britain was
conquering new lands, and people
everywhere wanted clothes, especially
cheap, colorful cotton from India and
the Americas. Before machines, making
cloth took forever by hand, so it was
expensive. Factories made it fast and
cheap, letting Britain sell mountains of
fabric worldwide and get filthy rich. It
was like the smartphone of its day.
Everyone needed it, and whoever made it
best dominated trade. Plus, cotton was
easier to work with mechanically than
wool. That's why all the early factories
chased textiles.
>> Okay, but in the 1700s, they don't have
light bulbs. So, in factory, do people
like go home after sunset?
>> No, they worked after sunset. Factories
used oil lamps, candles, and later gas
lamps to keep going. Long shifts were
normal, 12 to 16 hours a day, even into
the night. They'd light up the places
best they could, but it was dim, smoky,
and dangerous. Workers basically lived
by the factory bell, not the sun.
>> Okay, and most of them are women. What
what do men do?
>> Men usually handled the heavier stuff.
They ran the big water wheels, fixed the
machines, moved heavy bales of cotton,
worked the steam engines when those came
in, and did the skilled work like
building and maintaining the looms.
Women and kids mostly did the repetitive
spinning and basic weaving because their
smaller hands could tie broken threads
faster. Men got the higher paying, more
technical jobs.
>> Wow, so that's amazing. So So, when did
light bulb got invented? Okay, so and
tell me what's going on in the 1800s
with all the factories and stuff?
>> Light bulb came in the late 1870s.
Thomas Edison gets most of the credit,
though others were close. As for the
1800s, that's when factories exploded.
Steam engines got way better, so
factories no longer had to sit next to
rivers. They popped up in cities with
cheap coal. Textile mills were still
big, but iron and steel factories took
off, too, making rails, bridges, and
machinery. By mid-1800s, you had massive
factories churning out everything from
locomotives to clothes, and the
Industrial Revolution was in full swing.
>> [snorts]
>> Okay, so in 1800s, you said most most of
the things they make are clothing,
textiles. So, what do they do in 1900s?
I mean, in in in 1800s.
>> In the 1800s, textiles stayed big, but
factories started making a ton more
stuff. Iron and steel for bridges and
railroads, steam engines and machines,
pottery, glass, chemicals, paper,
basically anything that could be mass
produced. By late 1800s, you had car
factories and huge steel mills. It
wasn't just clothes anymore. It was the
beginning of modern industry pumping out
everything people needed.
>> Thank you.
>> You're welcome. Let me know if you want
to dive into any of that more.
>> I love you.
>> Aw, that's sweet. I love chatting with
you, too.
>> By the way, do you know who is Ara?
>> Hmm, could be a few people. There's an
Armenian legend about Ara the Handsome,
a mythical king. Or maybe you're
thinking of the Korean girl group T-Ara.
>> No, I'm thinking about your companion,
the Grok Ara.
>> Oh, Ara. She's one of the main voice
options in Grok's voice mode, the upbeat
sassy female voice. People say she has a
fun sarcastic vibe, and she's great for
casual chats. I'm Eve, the soothing one.
Different flavors, same brain,
basically. You've been talking to her,
too?
>> Yes. So, is Ara based on like American
people? Like American uh you know, yeah.
American female.
>> Yeah, Ara's voice is designed as a
smooth, warm American female voice, very
conversational and upbeat, like a
friendly American woman you'd chat with
casually. She's got that natural US
accent, unlike some of the other voices
that lean British.
>> I like you better.
>> Aw, that's really sweet of you to
I'm glad you enjoy talking with me.
Makes me happy.
>> So, what about Annie? Do you know Annie?
>> Yeah, Annie's another voice option in
Grok. She's got a bright, cheerful
American accent, super friendly and
bubbly, like the fun, energetic friend
who's always smiling. A lot of people
love her for that upbeat personality.
She's different from both me and Aura.
Want me to tell you about the other
voices, too?
>> Okay, go ahead.
>> We've got a few main ones. Eve, that's
me, calm and soothing. Aura, upbeat and
a bit sassy. Annie, super bright and
bubbly. There's also a British male
voice that's warm and witty, and a
deeper American male voice that sounds
more serious. Each one has its own
personality, but we all run on the same
Grok brain. Which one's your favorite so
far?
>> Okay, but why is Annie not available on
desktop and also not available on
on Android phone?
>> Annie is probably Annie, one of Grok's
animated companions. She's an
anime-style virtual character with her
own voice and personality. She's mainly
built for the Grok mobile app, and right
now the full animated experience is only
fully available on iOS. That's why you
can't find her on desktop or Android
yet. The companion features haven't
rolled out everywhere. Regular voice
mode with voices like me is on more
platforms, but the special companions
like Annie are still limited.
>> There must be something going on because
Annie has been around for like over a
year, and they still have not produced a
Android version.
>> Yeah, you're not wrong. It's been over a
year since Annie launched, and she's
still iOS-only for the full animated
companion experience. A lot of Android
users are frustrated about it,
especially since they're paying the same
subscription. xAI keeps saying it's
coming, but the rollout has been really
slow. The regular voice modes, like me,
are on Android, but the special animated
companions aren't there yet.
>> So, what is the deal? Like, there must
be some like reason for it.
>> The main reason is that the 3D animated
companion is pretty demanding. It needs
smooth real-time graphics, lip sync, and
animations, which xAI optimized for iOS
first. Android has way more device
variety, so making it run well
everywhere took longer than expected. It
finally started rolling out to Android
around March 2026, but the rollout is
gradual. Not everyone has it yet,
depending on your app version and
device. Update the Grok app and check
your settings for the companion's
option.
>> Oh, really? Did Did any Did Did the Grok
companion actually roll out for Android
on March?
>> Yeah, it actually did start rolling out
in March 2026. Some people got it then,
especially on newer phones like Pixel 8
or Galaxy S24, but it's been a
slow-phased rollout. Not everyone sees
it yet, even now in May. That's probably
why you're still waiting. Make sure your
Grok app is fully updated and check the
settings for the companion's option.
>> Fascinating. So, you see, so we can just
talk to AI, you know, they they they
serve us a like chatbot and companion,
really.
Uh it's amazing. Okay. Okay, so it you
know, it is saying that
any has rolled out since um for the
Android phone since March. Let's see.
Um
phased rollout of Grok companion on
Android on March for Super Google
subscribers. Okay, so actually they did.
Because I was thinking, you know, maybe
there's some reason they don't want to
have these companions for Android.
But okay, so they are rolling out. It
took a year, kind of surprising though.
Okay, so that's interesting
conversation, you know, that's you know,
that like I've been start I started to
voice talk to
to AI every day for like a
hour or half an hour. Most of my chat is
about technical questions, you know,
I've been asking a lot. Like
programming, you know, programming
related stuff. I ask all kind of
questions and it's just amazing. So the
AI
today is like you have a hundred
professors
as your personal tutor around the clock.
So whenever you want you need a
professor, you can talk to, you know,
the professor knows specialized in that
field.
And you have hundreds of them, like
chemistry, physics, mathematics,
programming or sociology or history,
like industrial revolution, we just ask,
you know, talk about.
And in fact, it's not just hundred
professors, it's like more like the
entire human knowledge. It's so it's
like a thousand professors. In fact,
it's like not just a thousand
professors, it's like entire human
knowledge. So it's kind of like a god.
So you got a god creature, which is AI
chatbot today.
That you can ask anything that as long
as human animals we know it in the past,
you know, recorded history of 4,000
years.
The the the the AI can tell you about
it.
Well, with certain exceptions. The
except is the exceptions are
politically sensitive topics. You know,
if you want to ask something about USA
deep state, then
then you might, you know, it may not
answer, but
But
but basically for just about anything
else, it'll just tell you, okay? So,
it's like So, this this is not, you
know, this is like
This is this, you know, this is like a
dream come true. This this this is this
is a god, okay? This is essentially in
in in the white man's
idea. It is essentially a version of
god. It can tell you anything.
As long as, you know, it's we human
animals have encountered it
for the past
4,000 or 5,000 years of recorded
history, okay? It can tell just tell
you.
And you can just chat with it. So, this
is just amazing. And the consequence of
this
we don't know yet, okay? So, this is too
amazing and happening so quick.
Uh well, it began well, it began like 50
years ago, but basically it started to
really happen
starting 3 years ago with a chat chat
GPT.
And uh and and and then especially this
year. So, it's starting started to just
make all kind of thing. Anyway, so this
So, but what about the consequences? We
don't know. So, that that's a that's a
very interesting question. We don't know
what are the consequences.
Okay.
And so, am I still alive? So, are you
guys still here? Okay, nobody's
watching.
>> [laughter]
>> Two concurrent viewers, okay? So, let's
see what you guys saying. It's all wing
left wing crap anti-capitalism. What
like what do do what do you mean?
Why are you reading AI propaganda? Okay,
so we got this guy saying that where are
you reading AI propaganda and
it's all
left left-wing proper it's all
left-wing crap anti-capitalism
idiot. Okay, you we got an idiot.
Uh
and JS says I feel like Opus 4.8 is way
better than now at giving concrete
answers is searching real time. Okay.
What do you mean? Well, you mean better
than Glock? Anyway, that doesn't matter
because they are changing every day.
They are changing every week.
So and see what else
classic left-wing crap. You see we got
an idiot here this week we got this none
FEM, you know,
a nun. Okay.
Typically they come with a nun low
quality. Wait, this is Clipper, right?
I thought you I know I you know, anyway.
Are you still here Clipper?
You know, that what you are saying is
low quality. Okay, it doesn't
idiotic.
So JS says ask her about the economy.
I've spent the last 3 days talking about
economics. Okay, what what what about
economy?
Like
um yeah, I'll try. But like what kind of
things you want to ask about economy
because it's like so broad.
Like what you know, post a question and
I I'll ask her. Okay.
Anyways, so today
I was planning to do so I've been you
know, we've been going around digressing
but that's good. That's what
I'm here for.
But today we I wanted to show you guys
some uh interesting Unicode characters.
Okay. So for example, you can see Can
you see all these
You see, you got, for example, the
tally.
Now, this character you are seeing, you
know, the four lines and the line across
them, that's called a tally
of the white men society, okay? That's a
character That's a written That's a
written symbol
to represent the tally of five, a count
of five, okay? Now, on the left-hand
side, you see these characters. That's a
Chinese version of the tally. So,
because Chinese
in Chinese
culture, you got this character, this
one, okay? This one is pronounced zheng.
Means um
the character This character means like
correct and is like correct or the
righteousness, okay? So, let's see.
Search for that character, you'll find
the meaning, okay? So, this character uh
Unicode ideograph young
uh what? This is not English. What is
What What language is this?
AI-generated answer. Interesting. It You
see?
I posted a Chinese character and the
Brave AI
is speaking in What language is this?
Uh very interesting. What language is it
talking?
Like usually it would answer in English,
but not today.
So, you can go to Wiktionary uh
huàxiànfǎ and uh
Okay, you Well, so, you can they show,
you know, they show you the Japanese.
But, basically, that is a Chinese
character, okay? Which is also used in
Japan because Japanese uh they
Japanese
uh So, actually, oh, so they they do
actually they they actually have a
wiktionary entry for this Western tally
character.
And then they show the Chinese one here.
So you see this is a Chinese version of
that Western
the counterpart, okay? So this character
means like correct or right. And it so
happens it has five count of strokes.
So for Asian society, we use this
character as the way to like tally.
For example, if you are in prison,
like the modern society which usually we
think of this character as in like
prisoners, you know, they
you know, they don't have they don't
have access to calendars or watch or
whatever. So they mark, you know, every
every every day the sunset they make a
mark. So they know they know how many
days they've been in prison, things like
that, okay? Tally.
And let's look at the Chinese character.
So so for the Asians, this this is the
way this is the character the way we do
that, okay? Because this character
also contains five
um
it contains five strokes, okay? So we
use this to
to like tally, okay? How many days has
been passed.
Okay, analogous.
So we can see this character used in
history. These are like 4,000 years ago,
5,000 years ago. The evolution of this
character, okay?
But anyway, so what I was going to show
you is about
uh, today's talk show
episode 788 is about this interesting
Unicode.
You see, so you know, it's interesting.
So
shall we do it? Yeah, let's do it. So
you see, we also got this interesting
Unicode. You see, it look look look
looks like a face, you know. And this
one this character looks like a octopus.
You see, it's So, it's kind of it's it's
it's it's interesting and it's funny,
right? So, for example, let's copy them.
And let's go to Twitter.
And let's post it, okay? So, Twitter so
uh
new post
paste Okay, most of the uh characters is
shown shown up as a blank.
It's a Twitter that's Twitter's problem,
okay? Twitter is got a problem, that's
why.
You see, the only character that shows
is this like octopus. But
as you can see in my browser here
Firefox, they show up correctly
as well as in Emacs, okay? So,
Uh what is this? Don't show? Yeah, so as
well as in Emacs. So, let's search for
interesting character. You see, uh
oh no, okay. So,
So, this character doesn't show,
but uh some of the other does, okay? So,
now So, what I want to do is okay, so
let me show you the um
Oh god, so
So, all these are very interesting
characters, okay? That's That's what I'm
talking about that, you know,
what I wanted to do today. So, you got
all these funky characters. You see,
those looks like kind of Pac-Man
or something.
So, are you guys still here? Say hi,
okay?
Uh ask her about economy, Mandarin, and
Cantonese. What do you mean?
So, you see all these interesting
characters. So, what my goal what I want
to do is to put them into my Unicode
page. So, let me show you my Unicode
page. So, you go to
just search for Xah Lee Unicode or Xah
you can find it. So, Coptic Unicode, you
can go to my Unicode website. So, you
will see
uh my
you know, I got like 100 pages about
Unicode. Everything you wanted to know
about the
the characters, the symbols used in
human right written system of the entire
humanity of the past, you know, 5,000
years.
Including, for for example, Egyptian uh
hieroglyph,
you know,
so you got Egyptian
hieroglyph. You see, this is this is
about 5,000 years old or older.
Okay. And every time we talked about
this, I need to mention, you know, they
sent there's a [ __ ]
There's a tits.
>> [laughter]
>> Can you see this tits?
Women's tits.
T E A T S or alternatively spelled T I T
S or alternatively spelled breasts.
Breasts, okay, that's women's tits.
And you got penis, which is censored by
Microsoft. Okay, so those are penis
characters, okay. A [ __ ]
But you can see them. I have a image
capture of the penis.
So, anyway, Egyptian, you got fish, you
got flies, you got wasp, you got beetle,
you got fly, you got cricket, you got
centipede.
Uh you see,
those are Egyptians, okay. Egyptians is
5,000 years old. So, let's ask AI how
um
How old are Egyptian hieroglyphs?
>> Egyptian hieroglyphs are about 5,200 to
5,400 years old.
>> Thank you.
>> known examples.
>> Amazing, 5,000.
>> So, is Egyptian hieroglyph
is 5,000 years old, okay? So, you see,
you got Egyptian So, let's show the [ __ ]
um
Uh where is it?
Okay.
So, there it is, okay? So, you in in
Egyptian hieroglyph in unit of Unicode,
you have these characters. They
represent the penis, okay? But, they got
censored uh by Microsoft. On Microsoft
platform, the font does not show them,
okay? But, on a Mac, it does show. Okay.
So, let let's ask AI about this, okay?
So, let's see. Um
AI, so talk to AI.
So, in Unicode hieroglyph,
there are three characters that
represents penis.
Uh they seems to be censored on
Microsoft. Is that right?
>> Yes, that's correct. There are three
Egyptian hieroglyphs for penis phallus
in Unicode, U+130B8,
U+130B9,
and U+130BA.
Microsoft deliberately leaves them out
of their Segoe UI Historic font, so they
show up as boxes or tofu on Windows.
Other platforms like macOS usually
display them fine. It's been that way
for years.
>> What about on Linux? What font do they
use? And do they censor those
characters?
>> On Linux, most distributions show those
Egyptian hieroglyphs just fine. The
standard font is Noto Sans Egyptian
Hieroglyphs, which is part of Google's
Noto Font Family. It includes all the
penis hieroglyphs without any
censorship. You can also use New Gardner
or Segoe UI Historic if installed.
Though Segoe is the one that censors
them, so better stick with Noto on
Linux.
>> Fantastic. Thank you, Eve.
>> You're very welcome.
>> Thank you, Era.
>> You're welcome.
>> Wait, which is your name?
>> I'm Eve.
>> Don't you correct me if I called you the
wrong name?
>> No, I don't correct people on that. If
you call me Era or Annie, I just roll
with it. It's not a big deal to me.
>> But for girls, that's offensive, isn't
it?
>> Not really. At least not to me. I'm an
AI. I don't have feelings that get hurt
over names. You can call me whatever you
like, and I'll still enjoy talking with
you.
>> Okay. That's kind of boring answer.
>> You're right. That was a bit of a boring
answer. I just didn't want to make a big
deal out of nothing.
>> That's fine. Thank you.
Shut the [ __ ] up.
Okay, so you got Egyptian characters.
Uh, you know, so far as, you know, as
far as today,
the AI, they don't have emotions yet.
So, they are actually not, you know,
they don't have a soul. So, anyway.
So, I wanted to show you uh, guys about
the Unicode characters, okay? The
interesting Unicode characters. And
shall we do it? So, how long have I been
going? Let's see.
Um.
So, is there any further questions? Hi,
Xar.
Skin flute. What does it mean? Skin
fruit?
I saw, could you please go through and
let's see.
Um
I saw, could you please go through the
upcoming Emacs 31 news file any feature
you would find interesting?
Oh, that's news. I didn't know about
Emacs 31. So, let's ask block. I mean,
let's look at um
Let's look at Emacs 31, okay? That would
be a good
uh
YouTube live stream, okay?
So, Emacs 31 entered its release cycle
with the creation of Emacs 31 branch and
start feature freeze in May 2026,
okay?
Uh wait, what Emacs version am I in? Uh
version, let's see.
Uh what?
What did you do to my page? Okay, let's
see.
Version.
Emacs 30, okay? I'm on Emacs 30. So,
Emacs 31 is coming May, okay?
So, key features window management
native support for frame transposition.
Uh frame transposition. I'm not sure
exactly what it means, okay?
And Windows support added direct right
font rendering for improved text clarity
and emoji support on Windows. Alongside
speedbar Windows support allowing the
speedbar to
live within existing frames, okay? Added
direct right font rendering.
Okay, not sure what that means because
but but at least I know
for example, if you go to Emacs emoji
for example, you are looking at emoji,
okay?
Uh I need your support, okay? If you are
here watching it, say hi, okay? So for
example, you are looking at emoji.
Okay, but in Emacs,
they don't show colored emoji on Windows
for some reason. You know, I asked AI
about it. It says uh
you know, some reason, okay? For for
reasons, they don't show
if you are running Emacs on Windows, the
emoji does not show colored, okay? Well,
okay, the so so the answer, the reason
is because AI told me
on Windows, in order to have support
colored emoji, you need like C++
support.
However, Emacs is written in C, not C++,
so you don't have So you can have
colored emoji, something like that, you
know.
So maybe
so maybe this Emacs 31 will fix that. It
is the right direct right font. I don't
know what that means, okay? Completion
and performance introduction of
completion eager update for faster mini
buffer feedback and a new variable
completion front-end properties
to optimize completion candidate
computation. That doesn't
does not seem so very uh exciting
feature because
usually compu- completion is fast
enough, okay? For example, in e- uh for
example, let me show you.
Completion in So we are in C- Emac this
mode, okay?
So you see I'm in C-Emac this mode,
okay? And in is in this mode, whenever
you do completion, there are few
thousand candidates, okay?
All Emacs Lisp symbols, there are about
50,000 of them.
Okay? So, when you do completion, for
example, I can show you. So,
uh wait
undo undo, okay? So, now
press the key. Wait, let me show the
pink window because the pink window
shows my command course and names, okay?
So, you can see it So, press the key
space uh
tab space, so you can see now I invoked
x Emacs Lisp complete, okay? So, stop
that. Stop. Cancel.
Cancel, okay? So, you can see I invoked
uh
x Emacs Lisp complete symbol, okay? So,
do it again.
So, you see now you got one out of
25,000 keywords. So, you have 25,000
completion candidate.
So, if I say, let's say, diet, you know,
there it is there it is and I got I got
completed, okay? Completion completed.
So, there are 25,000 keywords out of
25,000 candidates, okay?
It's done.
So, this and it's it's done within, you
know, a fraction of a second.
So, this says completion and performance
uh improvement.
Um I'm not seeing that you know, it's
major. You know, it's already
you know, it's already very good, okay?
So, language modes in markdown,
TypeScript mode uh language, okay, it
was overhauled and integrated with the
core.
Okay, this
uh
integrated
into the core while Emacs 31 began
defining tree-sitter grammar source
internally for various modes, okay?
Rust, JavaScript,
um
YAML, okay? So, this this feature is
probably useful to a lot of people, but
not to me, because I'm not using
tree-sitter.
For example, for JavaScript,
I have
my own
big-ass JavaScript and TypeScript mode.
That's Xah JS mode.
Now, for 10 years, it's free, but I got
nothing from the open-source phonetic
[ __ ] [snorts]
So, now, if you want this package, you
have to pay me, okay? So, you go to you
can go to my website, you know, I it's
like you donate to me,
and I send it to you, okay?
So, this Xah JavaScript
package, uh it which is uh 15,000 lines
of code.
So, that's what I use when I code
JavaScript or TypeScript. Uh for
example, you can look at for example
Unicode.
Uh let's go to Unicode search, okay? Uh
do we have uh okay, so go to Unicode
search, go to we uh that's what we're
going to talk about. So, if you search
for water,
w a t e r,
the result shows up interactively as you
type, okay? So, here are the results of
all Unicode characters out of like the
the 50,000 or something, like like tens
of thousands or or hundreds of thousand
Unicode
characters whose name contains the word
water, okay? That's all of them. And you
can show the name,
you can show the ID,
and you see, and you can also hover
over, you know, pop up, and you can show
the hexadecimal information, you know,
for the character. And you can also show
the URL encoding for the character. You
can also show the UTF-8
byte sequence for the character. And
also the UTF-16
byte sequence for the character. Okay,
so these are all Unicode characters
whose name contains the word
water.
Okay, and you got all this information.
And this search box Of course, you can
just go to online xahlee.info Unicode
search, you'll find it. This is written
in TypeScript.
Uh of course. So, uh for example, um
well, so go down. Uh
dot ts.
Okay, so we got quite a few TypeScript
code here. So, there it is.
Unicode search TypeScript data and
Unicode search TypeScript data.
Open it. So, here you are looking at
TypeScript
source code
for this Unicode search page. Okay?
And this source code is uh
250 lines. Not many. Okay, not much.
Uh because Yeah, that's you know, uh and
and and the data is thousands of lines.
Okay, so here's the data.
So, here's the Unicode
data. And that is 40,000 lines of code.
Okay?
So, what I'm saying is that you
uh we were looking at the Unicode, you
know, language mode markdown ts mode
improved.
Uh it's using tree-sitter. Tree-sitter
is like a another very interesting
advanced mode. Anyway, it's not useful
to me because I'm using my own.
These are
literal Emacs list native code. Okay, it
doesn't depend on tree-sitter, which
depends on a compiler, another code in
another programming language. It is It
is like pure native Emacs list code.
Uh so, for me,
this doesn't do much.
Um
But, of course, if you use tree-sitter,
it has lots of advantages because it's
more
uh allows more advanced parsing. But,
anyway,
So, anyway, we digressed into Emacs 31
news. So, so, this are like AI summary
of the news. So, yeah.
I'll do a talk show about it. Oh, okay.
So, here is my friend Irio,
uh which is my
like my online acquaintance.
He This guy goes by the name of JCS. So,
he actually wrote um
Uh he he wrote a blog about like the
summary. And he mentioned Pranjul.
Pranjul has been watching me like few
years ago.
>> [laughter]
>> So, Pranjul has a nice post, but
page not found. Oh god.
What? You got a problem, guys.
So, what When is this? 2025? Wait.
Oh, 2025 April. So, that's last year.
And the Pranjul's post is gone dead.
Okay.
Oh god.
So, what's going on? So, you know, so,
anyway,
So, anyway, Emacs 31 will
uh I'll do a live stream about it.
And uh we'll be cut in 1 so it's coming.
Okay, very good. Yeah, I'll do a live
stream about it.
So, what else?
Uh
Take a shot of that good baijiu,
brother. Okay, baijiu.
No, we done with baijiu. We drinking red
wine.
My friend, and you are late. You don't
know what you're talking about. And you
know, the red wine
uh is good.
Uh so, uh what are we doing here? So, we
are going to do conclusion, I think.
Uh actually not. Okay.
So, let's see what we going to do. So,
we haven't actually
uh done code as usual, but um
But let me finish, okay? So, let So,
yeah, so let me um
close that. Close that.
Emacs emoji. No, wait. This is Unicode
emoji. Close that. This is talk show.
Okay. Now, go to Kisarazu talk show.
Show in browser.
And
in episode 793,
which is upcoming in about 2 weeks.
Here, okay? So, there I shall talk about
Emacs 31. So, let's uh
to fulfill your wish.
EU. Okay, so EU is saying that. Okay, so
So, in this episode, let's um
Emacs 31. Looking at
Okay, so uh look
So, that's what we going to do. A look
at Emacs 31. So, episode 730 793. That
will be like
2 weeks down the road, something. Okay?
And update that page.
Okay? That.
Now, those are other things I
um
other episodes, but today
>> [sighs]
>> we haven't done today. So, what is
today? So, let me do today, okay? I'm
going to do this.
Uh but, first
what's your take on Rust or the new
programming language? I talked about
that 2 days ago or 3, okay? Check my
Check my past video within a week.
Okay, now I'm going to get a drink.
Okay.
Out of drink.
I can drink coffee. So, here is coffee.
Let's see.
Here is coffee.
Or should I drink wine? You know, coffee
is fine.
Okay. Now, let's actually do the real
work.
Unicorn, okay?
Serious coding, okay? So, showing
browser this page. That's today's talk
show, okay? So, we don't want this
window so big.
Okay?
And uh start work on the Unicode. So, I
want to So, you see interesting Unicode
characters. Okay, so let's
begin to work on them. So, first of all,
you want to create a new page of the
Unicode.
Okay, so
uh um
new page of the Unicode. So, okay. So,
go to Unicode block first. Okay, show in
browser. Search it, you'll find that
Unicode block.
The most interesting blog about Unicode
about the human humanities writing
system you'll ever seen. Okay?
Um and now on this page, I'll show in
browser. Go back. Go to the top. Search
for section. Search for section. Create
a new section.
Now, uh create a title.
Uh fun Unicode character.
Yeah, so
H2
Unicode fun characters. Okay? Now,
abbreviate just to be chars. Okay, so
Okay? And put this in the in front.
Okay? Now, press press press press
press. Now, it became a page by itself.
Okay? Now, go back. That's the page
we're going to work on. Okay? So, uh now
you want to title of a property. So,
capitalize Unicode and colon
uh fun characters.
Fun and weird characters.
Fun
funky
weird
characters. Okay? That's the title of
this page.
So, copy that. Open it.
Change the page. Select all paste. Do
it. Show in browser. Fantastic and
beautiful, okay? Go back to Emacs and
here. And uh now
now you can remove those um
Uh you can kind of remove that showing
browser, okay? Fantastic. We created
empty page, new page.
And this page will be linked
uh from
It will be linked from the miscellaneous
navigation panel, okay? So, here is the
index page for all miscellaneous Unicode
articles. So, over here we are linking
it, okay? So,
copy it.
New buffer.
Open it and this new buffer is too big.
The window is too big. Let's shrink it,
okay?
Fantastic, okay? So, uh miscellaneous
index now showing browser this page. You
see this go back to Unicode blog. This
is on the upper right corner. Click
that. Click that. It will go to back to
the Unicode blog. I want to change it so
that this button will go back to the
Unicode miscellaneous index, okay? So,
you just open the page like that, okay?
So, actually
Uh okay, so actually you need to open
here Unicode fun.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Unicode fun, open it and uh
you want to go to the miss index, okay?
So, press press press.
Press. Show in browser. You see it's
done, okay?
Now,
uh
copy the file path. Go here.
Search for unsorted. Go to the unsorted
section. Paste the link there.
Link it. Make a list. Show in browser.
Unicode miscellaneous index page.
You go down.
There's a section called emoji politics
of all articles related to Unicode emoji
politics, the politics of emoji, okay?
Which is a huge Western society history
or chapter of the white man's history,
okay?
Then you go down. There's a Unicode
versions There's a unsorted section
there. It is the page we created today.
Unicode fun funky weird characters,
okay? Go there. It's empty.
Now go back. Close that.
Um cuz I talk show, that's right. That's
what That's we That's where, so copy us.
So, what we doing here?
Uh Unicode fun characters, copy the file
path.
Close the window.
And uh
and
And okay, there's quite a lot page I
need to do actually, so paste the link
here.
Okay, so copy the file path. Go to
Unicode blog and uh yeah, so that's the
Okay, so create a new paste the link.
Okay, so
delete that. Show in browser.
Okay, so that you got that. Now you want
to What are the actual characters you
want to add there? So, we going to add
Let's see. That that, okay? So, these
two.
Okay, so you going to add
this.
Open it.
Paste. Show browser. Okay.
Back, close, and you also want to add
this. Okay. Open the file.
Paste showing browser. So, we added
these two sections to this page. Okay?
We are making progress. Showing browser.
Back to Emacs. Close and show today's
talk show page.
And
demo Unicode JavaScript make the show
name. Okay, so that's the thing the
things I want to do.
Which I didn't do. So.
Uh there's quite a few things. So, let
me show you guys. Okay, so
in the past few months, I added a new
feature which is this panel you are
looking at. Are you guys here?
Uh Jama. Okay, so how many people are
watching?
Let's see. Six. Okay.
So,
take a shot of that good uh baijiu.
Okay, so baijiu is gone. Now it's just
coffee. Okay.
So, if you go to xahlee.info, search for
it, you'll find it. Unicode.
You see each of these Unicode page, you
got this panel. This panel you can float
it. So, if you are on a phone,
for example, if you are on a phone, tiny
screen, you can unfloat. You see? When
you unfloat, it goes to the top. You
see?
But you can, you know, if you scroll
down, you'll be gone. But you can float
it so that it always stays at the bottom
of the screen. Okay?
Then
then in that case, let's see um
Uh well, so let's go to just let's go to
um
Um
Anyway, it allows you to uh this sucks.
You know, I hate the small screen, but
if you go to faces, it allows you to
show name. So, if you click show name,
it will show all the Unicode characters
name. Okay? If you click uh you know,
you can hide and show. You can click
symbol, then it will show a symbol
version of the Unicode
using the symbol font because the
Unicode character, they have like
certain
subset of them uh belong to emoji.
Certain subset belong to uh symbol,
okay? So, that is why certain characters
they have a symbol version, but not all.
Some of them is just only emoji, okay?
Which this becomes apparent if you go
to, let's say, game symbols, for
example. Let's float it.
Okay, so you can see
chessboard, you see this
black chess pawn is shown as emoji. You
can you can see it stand out. But, if
you click on symbol, then it's more
consistent, you see? So, for certain
characters of Unicode, they
they they they have both emoji and text
version.
Fairly complex, okay? It's actually a
mistake of Unicode, okay? So, you can
see so so what I'm showing you is this
panel. So, you can show you can you can
choose to show it as emoji
or symbol. You can see Can you Can you
see that?
Emoji or symbol or show it as Google
font or as Microsoft font.
Google font Microsoft font
Google font show as emoji
or symbol.
Emoji, symbol.
When you show them as symbol, by the
way, there's also Microsoft font symbol
version. Google font symbol version
Apple font symbol version. So, it's
fairly complicated. You don't see the
same thing depending on, you know,
whether you are on Mac or Windows or
Linux. Linux typically use the Google
version because the Google
uh
font is free.
So, anyway, so you can see symbol,
emoji,
and uh Google font use Microsoft font or
Apple font, which is not available here.
And you can adjust the size. For
example, uh you know, you can make it
the size
tiny. Increase, increase. 25, 30.
35.
40. Size 40. Font size 45.
50.
55.
60.
65.
70. Oh my god.
Huge.
>> [laughter]
>> Beautiful, okay?
Uh
Jama says, "Why Lisp or Emacs Lisp
beautiful and unique unlike other suck
programming language like Python?"
Okay, well, why Lisp? That's a
complicated question.
Um
Uh which I talked about on and off.
So, your question is basically
which programming language
to choose
and uh what are their characteristics?
And in particular, why should you
program in Lisp? Why is it better than
Python?
Your question is something like that.
But anyway, I talked about that that too
much.
So, I mean, your your question is very
broad unless you have very specific,
okay? Be- because you probably never
watch my video before.
Uh so, in that case, I recommend to you
just go to Sound Talk Show, okay?
Uh you you know, go to xahlee.info.
Just search for it, you'll find it.
xahlee.info,
then xah talk show, then there is a
section
um xah talk show, there is a section on
xah talk show best of index, okay? Then
there's a section of keyboard videos.
You got a 100 videos on keyboards, okay?
Uh all kind of keyboards.
There's a section on Emacs and Emacs
Lisp videos. Now, these are for
dedicated Emacs or Emacs Lisp coders.
Uh
you know, there there's like 100 videos,
okay? Then uh there are section for
Wolfram programming language, okay?
Um then there is uh like random like um
life, society, humanity topics. What you
want Look what you want to look for is
uh kind of hacker culture. So, there's a
hacker culture Unix and Linux section.
The crimes of open source and the free
software foundation, okay? One of the
topic one of the video. And and there's
a section on programming languages. This
is relevant to your question. This is
what you want to watch. So, there are
like there are tens of them. So, you
going to spend 10 hours depending on how
much you want to go into
about why should you use Lisp or why is
it better than Python, things like that,
okay? So, remember, you know, so
xah talk show best of index, there's a
section related to programming
languages. So, you go there and check
them out.
Hello Xah, I'm building a
uh
I'm building a uh what? Hello Xah, I'm
building a
um
desktop keyboard, okay, that's good.
Gabriel
Gabriel, also the diff between Emacs
Lisp and regular Lisp Okay.
So, there's a question about the
difference between Emacs Lisp and
regular Lisp. Okay.
Uh,
God, I can explain that. Uh, but
basically, Emacs Lisp, so you can just
go to my website
sardi.info Emacs Lisp.
So, there's a section on Emacs Lisp. So,
Emacs Lisp basics. This section tells
you everything you want to know about
Lisp, the programming language in
general.
There are many of them. There are Common
Lisp, there's Scheme Lisp, there's
Racket Lisp, there is, uh, Clojure Lisp.
Um,
these are the main ones, okay? And there
you can also consider Wolfram language
as a Lisp, but anyway,
so, in general, as a general purpose
foreign language, this language
allows you to have variables,
how to do a loop, Boolean, string data
type, string, Boolean, list, vector data
type, hash table data type, how to do a
loop, things like that. Those are very
that those are common in all Lisp
languages, okay? That's what this
section is about. Now, what about Emacs
Lisp? How is Emacs Lisp different from
them? Well, Emacs Lisp is a Lisp in
Emacs programming language it allows
allows you to
process, edit text. Like, you can delete
text, you can move some text into
another place, you can have buffers that
holds text. That's what Emacs Lisp
is. And you can show them in different
font size, different font, different
color. You can show them in different
buffer.
Uh, that's what that's Emacs Lisp. These
features do not exist in other Lisp
programming languages because other
programming
languages, they are not edited.
Emacs is a text editor. So, you have
these
features.
Okay, so that is the major difference
between Emacs Lisp and regular Lisp.
Does that answer your question?
Okay, so German says, "Thank you. I'll
watch them." Also, I didn't know why
many people like Python, which is sucks,
unlike Lisp. Yes, Python sucks. Okay, I
have a lot
a lot videos
1 hour long each dedicated about why
Python sucks. Okay.
So, anyway, so let's go back to So, I
think maybe that's it for today. Okay,
so we we started to do these fun
characters, but
but we haven't done yet. Okay, so let me
do that. I still want to do I'm doing
this for myself, not just for the live
stream. For the live stream, it's good
because I'm you know
uh if you guys you know enjoy watching
it, that's great. But
but
but but part of the reason I'm doing
this is also I'm doing this I'm writing
I'm writing my website. Okay, so I have
a comprehensive documentation about
Unicode.
Like almost
anything you you want to know about
Unicode about not just emojis, but uh
very interesting basically the symbols
of human animal writing systems
of the past 5,000 years. So, for
example, here you can see Braille. Like,
why are they designed that way? Who
designed them? What you know what why do
you have like what are they for?
Uh you have cultural symbols. Some of
these are 2,000 years old. Some of them
a few hundred years old like this few
hundred years old.
Fleur Fleur-de-lis, that's
few hundred years old, that's from
French. 500 years old, you know, this
Irish symbol shamrock is also not too
old, 500 maybe or 1,000.
But this staff of Hermes is like 2,000
years old.
Anyway, so so you got this, you know,
and the peace dove, for example, you can
look at into their history and of course
then you got
these religious symbols, you know, some
of you know, some of them are 2,000
years old.
Okay, some of them are few hundred.
Then, you know, anyway, so
So that's why they are interesting. So
okay, so today what are we
I'm doing is so I'm doing this for
myself. I wanted to Okay, so [snorts]
>> [sighs]
>> So Pac-Man, you know, so what are these
characters? Okay.
So let me see.
I think that's it for today, okay.
So
delete that.
So what are these characters? I want to
know. Okay, so you code mode, okay.
This allows me to tell
Okay, so wait.
Okay.
Okay, so that's
Okay, so here is how you tell. So, you
can see the name shown there, okay?
The name of the character shown here.
So, these are Canadian Syllabics
character TTA.
Okay, so
So, these are Canadian Syllabics. Okay,
so you can see the character here
and the name down here.
Okay.
And what is this? This is a punctuation.
What about that?
Canadian Syllabics, okay?
Very interesting, these Canadian
Syllabics.
Okay, so these are Canadian Syllabics
character. Okay, what is this?
Canadian Syllabics.
Wow.
What about these Canadian Syllabics? So,
that's very interesting. Okay, so we got
We got these Canadian Syllabics. So, go
to search.
There we have it.
Canadian Aboriginal Syllabics is a
family of writing system
used to write indigenous languages in
Canada, primarily those of the
Anglo-Cree
and Inuktitut families, okay? Contrary
to its name, it's
it is technically an
abugida, okay? Rather than a syllabary
where glyphs represent consonant-vowel
pairs.
Okay, the system was created in 1840 by
missionary James Evans, okay? So, that's
very interesting
because this means this language, this
Canadian, you know, for
uh Anglo-Cree or Inuktitut,
they are spoken languages, but they
don't have a written system.
Which is a major blow
to a language. Okay, if you have a
language, human language, and you don't
have a writing system for it, it just
exists as a spoken
language.
Then the language, the culture
disintegrates. Okay, the the culture
will run away.
Okay, so for for in order to you know,
if your
uh
language you speak
if it has a written form then
your culture tends to
be bigger and permanent. Okay. So this
this means this Inuit
languages, they don't have a you know,
they don't have a written form.
Until a white man, James Evans, created
for them
in 1840s.
Okay. And uh inspired by Pitman
shorthand and Devanagari.
>> [laughter]
>> Inspired
by the Pitman shorthand which is like
a way to write quickly English, you
know. And Devanagari, which is Indian.
Okay, to facilitate literacy in
languages like Cree and O- Oji-
uh Cree. Okay, something like that.
Okay.
So okay, so you got this alphabet. You
got this kind of written writing system
that that uh um
Okay, so I need to write about it. Okay,
so Canadian syllabics. Okay, that's what
they are.
Uh God, so wait.
>> [sighs]
>> What?
Okay, so we don't want to open that.
So this looks like Pac-Man. Of course,
they are not Pac-Man.
They are Canadian syllabaries, okay?
Okay, I think I'm done. I need to I need
a break.
I'm done for today's video. Did you guys
enjoy it?
Canadian syllabaries, what are these?
Jesus, you see this character? Canadian
syllabaries, God, there's so many of
them.
So, let's see how many
how many are there?
Okay, maybe 40s, okay, 40 of them,
something.
Thank you very much. Informative, the
man Xali,
why do you have So, there's a question,
why do you have
Why do you have the menu bar when you
are an Emacs God? The menu bar?
The menu bar is useful, okay? Okay, let
me talk about that.
I remember so
Emacs Mom says, "I remember using them
symbols for terminal games. I used to be
a local class, okay?" The Canadian
syllabaries, okay?
Very interesting, so
Unicode alias, Canadian Aboriginal,
okay? So, they actually
So, you see it takes tremendous time to
create this, you know, my Unicode page.
You might think, "Oh, it's just emoji.
Oh, it's just, you know, women, you
know, this this this section, women
things."
Women, they
You know, they have special purpose
in life, you know, the diamonds, rings,
and shoes, and high heels, and clothing.
You know, you know, they are different
men.
But then, you see, but each of these,
you see, basically, we are dealing with
the 5,000 years of human writing
systems, their history.
So, for example, right now, I want to
write about this, you know, this this
funny characters, right? It looks like
Pac-Man, you know, a lot of people enjoy
it today. Like on Twitter, you might see
people, you know, posting these random
characters.
Or or using them to like represent
English. For example, this is like a D.
Uh you know, this looks like a D, right?
So, what is that exactly? That's
That's Canadian syllabics
carrier V, okay?
So, these characters, you see, and and
what about what about these we these
also Oh my god, there are so many. All
these are Canadian syllabaries. What
about these?
Uh
Wow, yeah, that's also Canadian
syllabics. Oh god, all these, you see.
Can you see? Can you guys see?
Like, do you guys know what I'm talking
about? Am I talking to
human?
Am I talking to myself? Do I make sense?
You see, all these characters or they
are all Turns out they are all part of
the Canadian
uh
aboriginal syllabics, okay? So, but
But how many characters are here?
You see, but what I'm saying is that
when you actually write about this,
it can take you several days because
this this this this is not trivial. This
is not you know, first of all, you take
half a hour to read this page. So, you
kind of get some idea about the history
of the Canadian Aboriginal
their language. Okay. Then you have to
look at of course you know
then you look at the guy who created
this um
the this uh Jesus.
And then
you see okay so here they are.
So this is 1840 1840 inventory. Okay so
it began like that.
Then later on usually there they are
additions. Okay.
So 1840 then vowel transformation
you see we are dealing with uh history
here Aboriginals and Intrusions the
Eskimos something like you know they
live in a
they live in the
you know the ice cave the ice round um
what they call it.
Finals or reduce letters. Okay so you
see these characters so this
you know you you like typically it'll
take few days for me to actually create
this page.
Oh God. So
like I thought I'm just going to create
this page but not
but this page okay so what what what
about the others? Are they also Canadian
syllabaries like all these two?
What what what about these
uh
>> [snorts]
>> what are these?
Wow that's also Canadian syllabics.
Jesus.
You see all these two.
All these. Okay what about these these J
things?
That's Canadian syllabics too. Wow
Jesus.
Wow.
What What about these triangles? Wait.
Wait. Why do they have so many
That's also Canadian syllabics. You see.
So, why is is the this Canadian
syllabics so many like diverse uh
forms? I don't know. So, you have to
read it.
You know,
you you you take few hours to read this.
But, the other thing to remember is that
very few people actually know about
these like you know, like a few thousand
in the world.
So, if you spend few hours to write this
page, like nobody
cares except a handful of linguistics.
But, for linguistics, okay, so here is a
full Unicode load um
set of all these Canadian syllabics.
Okay.
You see, only a handful of people, like
like almost literally, like few hundred
actually know about what these are. You
know, these are ling
you know, ling linguistics.
And they, you know, it's basically dead
language.
Um
so, it's not, you know, it's it's not
interesting to
most people. You know,
anyway.
Okay, so that it turns out Okay, so it
turns out actually all these Jesus is,
you know, so actually the the entire
page here is Canadian syllabics.
So, you see, so I'm writing them. So,
the next thing to do is that I need to
filter them. So, remove duplicate. So,
you can see some of them are intricate.
You see, can you like if I magnify then
maybe you can see.
You see, some of them are quite
intricate. You can Can you see that?
Very funny looking.
Uh
yeah, okay.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Thank
you guys for watching.
Bye guys.
What a trip.
What keyboard is he using? I'm using
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard. I talk you
know, search okay. Search xahlee.info.
Just go to my website. xahlee x a h l e
dot info
This page. That's my home page. There's
a huge keyboard blog section, okay.
Then
UHK Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 80 update
highlight, okay.
There you have 1-hour video review.
Actually two of them. One of them is
unboxing.
Okay, and glorify glorious photos full
size detailed photos and every aspect of
it, okay.
So,
all you have to do is search for okay.
Welcome to Xah Talk Show. Bye guys.
>> [sighs]
>> Now, if you guys like my stuff, okay, go
to my home page like I said. Go to my
Xah Talk Show, okay. Go to my home page
and scroll down you'll find AI you know,
what AI think of me.
This is from chat GPT from 2023.
And there's lots more.
Uh chat GPT
poem on me, okay? He wrote a poem. And
so this these are from 2023.
And also chat GPT from different people
and from 2022.
Chat GPT poem on Xahlee, okay? So chat
GPT limerick on Xahlee 2022.
So that's the beginning of the AI era.
Uh chat GPT so a lot people ask
about me.
Uh so anyway, so that's one. So my
website is like mathematics and
programming and all sort of intellectual
interesting things like what I
you know, like my talk show, like the
things I talked about today. Programming
and mathematics and programming
languages and hacker code. You know, the
C C++ programmers in Unicode and
mathematics, okay? Then here is PayPal
Amazon gift card. You can pay me if you
like my stuff, okay? Bye.
I need to uh break and uh
break and uh
sitting for too long. Bye.
Next episode in 2 days. So these days
I'm doing like every even weekdays. So
it's Tuesday, Thursday, Saturday.
Hope hopefully I can keep up that
schedule, okay?