come Oni welcome to another episode of
sawed-off show ah
the video the screen the video capture
device is really not working well so
today I'm going to talk about a few
things
father the chat I haven't done the video
chat yesterday because I was thinking
for example I was thinking today we're
gonna talk about saw the geometric
inversion okay we haven't talked about
math for a while so I was thinking of
doing a math session and this is this
geometric inversion is one of the most
spectacular thing in math okay let's pop
it up pop it out and and let me find
another page stereographic projection my
my god my neighbor's is like they are
blowing the grass the blowing the dead
leaves on the street so it is making
huge noises now I believe this speaker
this headphone headset is a directional
headset so you don't hear it but act but
however my voice becomes very much
reduced anyway here's a on a second
stereographic projection I want to show
you the other links stereographic
projection and physical models and let's
go to Wikipedia okay let's see how many
people are watching zero
okay but anyway I was going to I'm
thinking of doing a talk on geometric
inversion and this is one of the most
spectacular the noise is very bad
outside so let me go turn off let me
close the window
so geometric inversion this is most
fascinating topic in geometry and you
can and and it also relates to so
geometric inversion also related to
Mobius transformation complex analysis
let's go to Mobius transformation so you
can see Wikipedia by the way Wikipedia
if you want to search something math
related go to Wikipedia never use the
wolfram mathworld okay the wolfram
mathworld
person is not a good guy let's go to
hold on a second let me show you so move
here is a master word wolf and calm it
which is from we from Mathematica wolf
and research now if you are doing
anything maths related I mean if you are
looking studying math or looking up
information about math always use
Wikipedia okay it's far more better than
the content quality and correctness is
far more better than the math world
wolfram mathworld and also because the
wolf and math world I have a personal
story with a guy Winston Eric okay Eric
Winston guy he is not well we we had
issues okay
so this was this is fact then you know
back then 1997 okay that is 1997 to 2000
there is no Wikipedia yet so woof the
math word it was enormous math word it
was not a Wolfram research project it
was actually Eric Eric
when instance it's called I regret
Winston's
treasure trove treasure trove of math
that's an M that's his own personal
project you know pretty much like the
way I do things like the way I write
about math everything I learned for
example this this visual dictionary of
playing curves you know so and he he
does math you know covers all sort of
things on math hold on a second let me
go back to the where's that page
how here so anyway anyway this is I this
is Eric
Winston's treasure trove of math now he
sold it to CRC press
he kind of made a contract you know
there's details it's um you know
originally it's a website but he made a
contract deal with CRC press
now CRC press is known for publishing
engineering or math related you know
books so he made the ideal and so it's
published in print
it's name is renamed encyclopedia of
math something like that inside
encyclopedic dictionary of math
something like that then then he he he
joined wolfen research and he sold
basically the the project became a wolf
and research project so and it's renamed
math word wolfram mathworld okay
but anyway it's it's pretty much a
single guys walk and he was a
astronomist i think he that's that was
his training he was he was APH PhD in
astronomy so oh you know i'm not sure a
PhD yet but anyway he was a astronomist
so anyway so he wrote this project you
know every quest and treasure trove of a
math it's immensely popular you know
remember this is back in nineteen
nineteen ninety-eight 1990 and 1998 and
my website is also immensely popular
because you know back then you know you
don't have Wikipedia and basically the
nerd the web is not popular pages are
not who who you know seriously write up
some subject and so it's you know it's
his own website then he made a deal with
CRC press
so there's a printed version but
meanwhile I think you know he made a
deal so that it's also online but
however part of the project becomes
offline I mean like like you have to
pass a paywall or something like that
only part of it is shown then he joined
Wolfram research I think big what mostly
because of the his math encyclopedia
project he you know he got a job a wolf
on research and he joined and this this
his encyclopedia then becomes a Wolfram
research project and a wolf on research
of course then everything becomes
available again you know so CRC press is
not happy because you know it's a
commercial publication they made a deal
so they sued and back then he was a big
news you know around the web and most
people's opinion is that you know you
should you know you should be free like
info should be free and so on you know
the open source people but a deal is a
deal
you know it must be according to law law
so anyway that was the history of the
math math word Wolfram that is a history
ok that's that's one thing that's that's
one thing now the other thing I want to
talk about is that I had a personal
problem or quarrel with this guy Eric
Weinstein ok originally we are friends
because we are the pioneers of the web
you know and we both love math so I
write a lot math he ride a lot math and
and my way my math website is basically
the most popular is was this one a
series this one not you know a visual
dictionary of spatial plane curves so in
his math encyclopedia
they are like 20 pages links to my plane
curves website you know for
simple when you go to an article conic
sections or parabola or any other plane
curves such as logarithmic spiral any of
these Fang cups then he has a link or
reference you know like you know
reference link to leaks ah you know
visual dictionary of special plane
curves so we were friends
you know we exchanged emails of a few
emails then then he made a deal he so to
CRC press
okay it's on Amazon then I made a
criticism of it let's go to Amazon
hi guys so I got two people watching so
if you are watching say hi you know say
hi in comment or opinions
so uh so let me show you see ah see
inside inside he and see why co-opt ia
math okay let me show you the book the
book now today is absolute
but of course but I believe you can
still find it yeah here it sells for 600
now you know but this book is long
obsolete
you know back in 2002 thousand two okay
here so CRC concise encyclopedia of math
actually you know anyway let me talk
about one thing at a time so I covered
the history of you know wolfram
mathworld then I'm going to talk about
the personal quarrel between me and that
guy so he he sold his encyclopedia to
CLC you know first so publish this book
impacting it also comes with a CD you
know so the online version is on the CD
you can you know obsess it buy a
computer if you like then I made a
comment negative review I believe you
can still find it but you know this this
is like twenty years ago okay so let's
see Co 25 reviews
such folks are not there search for good
not there okay so let me let me just
let's do a web search I'm pretty sure we
can find it
sorry and I've written essay about the
story as well so yeah that that you'll
find it there
printed citations
so let's see over here
there it is somehow it's not shown not
shown on the other page so this is back
in 1999 I said you know I made a
negative review one person's work are
very limited as an encyclopedia so
here's what I said you know this book is
quite impressive as a personal note but
does not deserve to be considered as
anything formal as being a dictionary or
encyclopedia the information are way too
idiosyncratic and contains too many
factual errors omissions and misleading
z' i strongly advise you not to buy this
first edition as of 1999 the definitive
math encyclopedia in English is still
encyclopedic dictionary of mathematics
published by MIT press
unfortunately that encyclopedia is
written for mathematicians and is not up
to date he was translated from Japanese
in 1997 1977 okay so it is quite
hopeless for such massive work as these
to be up to date the encyclopaedia gives
an a the MIT encyclopedia gives a very
dense outline and definitions of almost
all modern math areas each section is
written by an expert in that area if you
have an undergraduate degree in math by
the MIT encyclopedia if your math
interest is recreational then Eric's can
be enjoyable so I made this review and
you know it's is rather negative then
since then you know he saw this of
course since then we became enemies he
started he removed
you know this Eric Winston guy removed
all links from his encyclopedia to make
to my website however on my website I
also have links to his encyclopedia ok I
did not remove it because you know you
know as a manís of 3
I do not think this behavior is
professional you know you read the
Encyclopedia I'm free to criticize it
okay I'm free to give my review of it
and so my review is negative and he saw
that so he became he stopped being a
friend he became an enemy and in fact he
removed all links to my website that's
bad so you know he so this is a story of
me and him the issues okay so I do not
think he's a good person now let me talk
about the other the other subject about
the quality of the wolf I'm Ward okay
encyclopedia the wolf and ward or his
you know Eric Winston's
encyclopedia the quality is very bad
it's in fact it's extremely bad okay it
is nowhere it's not an encyclopedia it's
not even a dictionary level now for
example notice you know let me list and
it's full of arrows he's he because you
know partly because he is not a
mathematician at all I mean even even if
you are a professional mathematician
writing a encyclopedia of math is a
lifetime's work and you cannot unless
you are you know one of the top
mathematicians you cannot do it because
there are so many areas in math you know
even back in 2000 year 2000 or year 1999
okay you you you need to be one of the
top you know accomplished mathematician
and you need to spend no more than ten
years to actually write a you know
so-called encyclopedia of math or even a
dictionary because the topic is just too
many to bored you know you know a
mathematician I think always or when
something like that where no
mathematician said that to know oh math
is actually more difficult than learning
all the world's languages including dead
languages
you know because that's how diversified
math has become so anyway you cannot
read an encyclopedia you cannot even
begin unless you are like you are a
professional mathematician meaning that
you you know professional you know like
among mathematicians you publish you
know math all the time and you are well
known you know recognized accomplished
mathematician so you so but
so he's encyclopedia is very bad so what
is it I mean how I mean what how could
it is so just at what level it is
basically he's like he's like me okay we
you know we are interested we are nerds
okay he's kind of very much a nerd so we
do you know we learn math and we learn
things everyday and we write it down
whenever we learn something and we we
write it down especially back back in
1990s I was very much into recreational
what so-called recreational math which
means the creation of math is any math
that do not require sophisticated
knowledge of math to understand or to
appreciate such for example elementary
number theory basic you know many things
about geometry dissection or geometry
combinatorics you know there there are
many things like put in puzzles Ruby
cubes for example magic squares you know
they're quite a lot you know topics
that's recreational math by the way we
creational math does not mean it's easy
or trivial no is in fact many of the
most difficult and unsolved problems in
math you know the recreational math kind
of math but what it just it just means
that it's math that does it does not
require you know many years of study of
math to actually appreciate or
understand what the problem is about in
most math problems you you you you need
like you know five years study of math
to to even to understand what the
problem is saying so so anyway so he is
very he and me very much I am very much
interested in recreational math back
then in 1990s so I read you know at
houghton tons of it every day and he is
pretty much the same thing because I see
his walk you know it's it's pretty much
the books I've read he has read the book
he references you know I have read you
know because and the topics he covers
all kind of like recreational stuff so I
can understand the way how he he's you
know treasure trove of math walks
because just like me you know he read a
book he saw something interesting he
read it down and most most of them are
recreational in nature it's not formal
math it's not professional math okay by
the way what are some examples of
professional math usually they are like
dry and you know like topology topics in
topology topics in analysis or you know
like that and so so anyway so so he's
his treasure trove of math is you know
basically notes I mean he's still good
you know it's it's useful it's enjoyable
to read but it's nothing it's nothing
like a professional math and it's full
of arrows for arrows and and also the
writing style is nothing close to a
professional quality okay
for example we just run into this Mobius
transformation page okay he he gives you
know three sentences description now if
you look at Wikipedia
now Wikipedia the the math stuff on
Wikipedia is truly professional you can
see you know it's like how many pages
want to you know
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve
you know like 40 pages just on the
single topics and also also the writing
style the depth the breadth is fabia
you know I mean compare these streets to
sentences compared to this Wikipedia
version you can see 40 pages you know
half page versus 40 pages you can see
the major at least the quantitative
difference you know there's not much
information here and also as a
mathematician you know by the way Mobius
transformation is not it's not too
advanced I mean if you have studied
complex analysis you basically
understand what what it means so what
I'm saying about that so so anyway so so
you can see the writing style and the
quality and in quantity is you know just
there's an immense difference so what
I'm saying is that the you know math
were wolfram mathworld or Eric's
treasure trove is not anything close to
a encyclopedia and and and most and
often it's misleading his key is just
wrong completely wrong okay this began
okay so so he started this project back
in 1990s ok 1997 also you know just as
personal notes you know writing down
stuff and he saw two CRC you know see as
he tries to you know publish it as some
kind of encyclopedia then I criticized
no no this is not encyclopedia at all
then he saw that to Wolfe and research
and he joined goofin research you know
to work for them you know what why does
superfine research take this project now
I don't know the details because I
haven't been working a wolf and when he
when this happened I was a wolf I'm in
but I suppose you know back you know
wolfin is also one of the pioneer of the
web you know wolf and Wolf Mathematica
is one of the pioneers of computer
software you know is you know it's well
known among especially hip you know
programmers or people online you know
Internet one of the first so so whoo
fine I would you know it's it is my
guess they would be interested because
they would sell Mathematica because he
also uses Mathematica so when you have a
you know encyclopedia of math was hosted
by Wolfram research and with lots of
links to Wolfram research products you
know the notebooks that generates you
know this this subject it benefits
Wolfram so I suppose that that is why
Wolfen take it to be you know part of
the wolf and project so anyway so you
see wolfram mathworld build with
Mathematica technology the web's most
extensive mathematics resource is far
from it so anyway all these you know so
he joined into he joined wolf and
research and this happened back in 1999
or something like that okay around there
so what has been what has happened after
20 years it turns out nothing I mean
there's no progress there's like almost
no progress of this wolfram mathworld
project you know in the early 2000s okay
in early 2000 for example like in 2003
or 2004 when Wikipedia began you know
back then you know there's a concept
where you know the the the the swamp
intelligence you know basically you you
don't respect you know Authority or PhD
and
instead of you want to like all the
people on the internet create some
project like we would like Wikipedia you
know like wiki where you know that's
idea that that that idea is thriving so
so back around 2003 or you know you know
early 2000s the math world also tried to
do that so they tried to you know they
tried to make it a open project so that
any people can like contribute for
example then some people started to
contribute but minor like very few like
real mathematicians they started to
contribute some of narco but on the
whole it's very small you know and after
that after a couple of you know a few
years of that that stopped you know so
so the wolfram mathworld became stagnant
you know ever since let me show you some
example where they for example where
other people contributed for example if
you look up any topics that's advanced
math as I mentioned for example topology
you know if you look up any math subject
that does not have any aspect of
recreational math then you start to see
you know there is no entry in the math
world but there are some entries that
are added by professional mathematicians
other people for example let's say let's
see algebraic topology okay let's see
order topology now these are subjects
that's fairly advanced I mean like
formal kind of mainstream mathematician
professional mathematicians - not
recreational math okay but now if you
look at them I bet it's written by other
people there's a guy named Todd
something who contributed a lot so for
example so this this subject Archer
topology okay so this one is still
credit to him algebraic topology is a
study of an intrinsic qualitative
aspects of spatial object you know
that's that's that's you know
so so this shows you know if you read
this you can see you can begin to see
he's not a mathematician at all but
however he the way he writes things like
introduced some topics to the layperson
you know for example programmers okay
you don't know nothing about math and
you you know you if you find it kind of
easy to read but it's not professional
math at all okay for example this one
older topology now you know so you know
it's not written by him so it's it's
this Purdy McKay Thea contributed you
know back then when when when math world
is open to people's contribution so
anyway so what I'm so so for the first
few years into early 2000s math will try
to get people to contribute and that
didn't really happen then then basically
is just stopped any progress it remains
it remains back in like year 2000s but
you know but because it's associated
with Wolfram research and you know
basically I you know if I make a guess
there's not much much traffic to a wolf
a math world at all and also you know
Stefan Wolfram the guy who created
Mathematica I I don't think he's he and
he knew this for sure I mean he he would
know that the quality of math word is
extremely poor you know
it's it's like it's laughable okay is it
true to say it's a math resource is kind
of laughable rather it is a math
educational material okay the wolfram
mathworld you can say it's a kind of
like a educational website you know for
high school students for people who are
let's study math undergraduate you know
pretty much you know same thing with my
project you know special dictionary of
plane curves it's it's educational
material it's not it's not professional
math okay you would not call it a
professional math textbook or anything
close to a professional encyclopedia so
that is the story of wolfram mathworld
okay so you know this is this this is
like a algebraic topology
I mean you compare if you oh yeah and
this is not even written by him this one
is written by actually it looks like
it's written by this guy this guy
because the era guy he's not you know he
doesn't know you know real math okay so
what else so yeah contributors for
example if we look at contributors I
remember there's a guy whose name is
Todd who has contributed a lot I think
this guy yeah so you see 377 articles
yep Roland Todd
yeah you see so from what I can see this
subject you know these subjects he
contributed now these subject we're
professional mathematicians
subjects okay none of these you know
vast majority of these are not something
like recreational math you know so what
what is recreational math like if you
are a programmer basically all math you
know is recreational math is you know so
that's a difference that's a big
difference between programmers concept
of math you know then then the real
mathematician program I think oh you
know okay I got four person watching so
say hi say something here so what okay
so that covers the history I mean
basically that covers you know subject
we were talking about the subject of
wolfram mathworld
okay what is the next subject
so next subject playing curves yeah so
this is my plank of printed citations
yeah that is the that let's see because
this page cuz this page okay so I was
talking about so I was not going talking
about we are I was thinking of doing a
tutorial about stereographic projection
and Mobius transformation and wait they
don't have graphics here now Mobius
transformation is a fascinating subject
it's really one of the most beautiful so
I was thinking of doing a and here is a
stereographic projection by this
mathematician henri statesman I I know
him kind of say German Henri is a German
he's a English
person from UK originally then he
studied graduate or postgraduate in USA
and he taught in Australia for a couple
of years I believe he is in the
University of Texas right now anyway he
he created creates lots of recreational
math stuff but however he is a
professional mathematician so you see
here's a so what these things this thing
actually illustrates illustrates a
stereographic projection so what is
stereographic projection it's like these
okay you have a sphere you put it on a
tabletop okay then from the top of the
sphere you draw lines okay to the floor
so any point on the floor corresponds to
a point on the sphere now remember that
any any point on the floor corresponds
to a point on a sphere and vice versa
any point on a sphere correspond to a
point on the floor except at the North
Pole the North Pole on the sphere don't
have any corresponding point so anyway
so this way this way of associating
points on a sphere and on the floor is
called stereographic projection now
that's actually a stupid name but anyway
that's just how it is named we are not
going to go to history of it you know
the naming of things the history of
joggins usually is very convoluted and
they are not logical I mean when you
when you see the word stereographic you
think of you know stereograms right like
something 3d but that's not the case
it's it should be a better name would be
something like spherical projection
something like that but anyway
so this is what serial graphic
projection is now the interesting
question is so so since now every point
on the floor corresponds to a point on a
bowl on a ball then that means if you
have any any figures such as a square on
the floor you can also have the figure
on the sphere so a square on the floor
on honest on the sphere would look
something like that but so anyway so any
picture on the floor has a image on a
sphere and similarly any any image on a
sphere have a corresponding image you
know on the floor so this is interesting
because now you can just put any photo
on the floor for example a photo of
yourself and see why it looks like on
the sphere or you can have some pattern
on a sphere and see what it looks like
on the floor so so he this guy created
this actual 3d printed thing you know
this actually actual thing that if you
shine a light from the top it it becomes
you know you can see the image of it was
you know your signal turned on so you
can see you can see an image of it on
the sorry that was my roommate so you
can see an image of it you know you so
this is a demonstration of stereo
graphic projection it's pretty fun you
know you actually shine a light and see
the shadow so he made several of these
you know objects it's really beautiful
and the shape of the object shows you
that you know a certain you know image
on a sphere how they come out on the
floor so if you want you know a honey
honey honey comp pattern on the floor
this is what you need to do for the
pattern on the sphere and you know
similar way I wrote this I wrote this in
Mathematica I show you by the way he's
got a video so I show you here
Steve real graphic projection this is a
Mathematica application I mean a roof
and research Mathematica retaining
goofin language so if you start with
this pattern on the floor this is what
you get on the sphere and in the same
way if you want this pattern you start
with this pattern on the floor you get
this shape on the sphere and here's
other examples so that's Stevie OH
graphic projection so what's the point
about this so you might be wondering so
what you know okay it seems interesting
what's the point in fact this this I
mean this is very much this is one of
the advanced professional math you know
we are showing I mean it we are showing
the interesting aspect of it but
actually what you have just learned is
actually a very fundamental part of math
called very fundamental part of complex
analysis and in fact this sphere we
would call a Riemann sphere you know in
in in professional math the term is
Riemann sphere for example and and also
it relates to Mobius transformation and
it also relates to geometric inversion
so you know actually quite a lot very
highly advanced mathematics
related to it also a complex projective
plane yeah so let me show you so ie am a
sphere so here is a Wikipedia article on
Riemann sphere you can see
and here you can see a Mobius
transformation how the image is down to
small okay so well I was going to go
into the detail like teach you some math
about how all these are connected the
geometric inversion the complex function
1 over Z the Riemann sphere and how they
tied to you know steel graphic
projection and how they tie to all these
things are tied together so here is a
geometric inversion so the issue right
now is like what are we going to cover
because today we already talked about
it's already 40 minutes oh hey Peter
what is your opinion on category theory
as opposed to class theory you know P
okay let's talk about that so I think
about math that's it for today unless
some of you know if you ask me questions
you know if you say hey I want to listen
you know I want to so what is you know
geometric inversion other you late if
you are interesting that I just say it
in the comments because when I have
comments I get you know I get I get my
top becomes smooth you know because
because there's a goal there's an answer
you know someone has that I want to
answer that then I become in in leave
and you know I become alive and I can
talk about it go into detail about this
or that you know I get excited teaching
you you know that's what I enjoy you
know talking about things I know but
otherwise it's kind of you know I'm
going around things I don't know you
know you know like three people are
watching you know I'm not sure what's
you know
so anyways so okay so yeah so if you you
know want to hear some topic just as a
spoonful for it you know so the question
now the question is what's your opinion
on category theory of supposed to grass
theory the bottom line is I don't like
how to I don't I I don't have high
opinion category theory at all I like
well actually I cannot say I'm really
qualified to give that opinion so you
know take it as whatever you know as
grain of salt now I don't like the
reason I don't like category theory
because you know it's a month you know
like I talked about this thing a lot in
in my past videos a lot of math things
known to programmers are like pop things
they are not real math or I mean they
okay yeah well category theory is very
is actually real math in fact it's very
very advanced foundational math okay but
what I'm saying is that you know you
know there's a magazine called pop
mechanics there's also a magazine called
pop science and there's also a magazine
called pop psychology let me show you
you know so there are these magazines
popular science and let me show you
another okay
pop Mechanics magazine now these are you
know you know this this you know the if
you are a programmer I mean if you are
not engineer if you are not a mechanical
engineer you don't have a PhD or
undergraduate in mechanical engineer you
find I mean these are you know layman
oriented very interesting you know over
the years they show for example today's
today's you know this this one is packed
packing what year 1970 so 1938 okay you
know they show this high-tech trend 1938
so today I mean the the magazine I'm not
sure they are still in print but they
have online versions okay Popular
Mechanics you know they will show Oh
quantum I can't content computers okay
they're gonna show you a picture of oh
oh how are we gonna go to Mars you know
some kind of fancy interstellar engine
you know we're going to go to Mars
things like that they are pop you know
popular I'm using that word as a
derogatory sense okay because if you are
a video mechanical engineer you look at
it you look at these they are not I mean
they you know it's like yeah it's you
know it's like you know it's like
scantily you know it's like popcorn
you know you know it's like porn okay
it's like they are not really teaching
you you know the very anything
interesting or the serious stuff I mean
if you study mechanical engineering even
for a mundane thing like make a
skyscraper build a skyscraper be order
bridge what are the concerns you know
what what math you know what what are
the constraint on the bridge like you
don't know I don't know okay we don't
know nothing about it but however we see
these you know pop mechanics oh we we
love it you know we enjoy it like you
know the most powerful so what is sex
with machines you know
so so that is what so so that is what I
mean so similarly there is this science
this pop science you know phone and then
scientist you get your attracted that
you you know you read it avidly oh wow
so interesting mug you know nano nano
machines you know you know all these
interesting things but for a real
scientist
this is you know this this is
it's like a movie you know it's just for
entertainment so in the same way if you
are a programmer the the things you hear
about the any math subject coming out of
programmers day and night they are they
are kind of like these pop things like
you know nothing about a subject okay
for example category theory is one of
the big example coming out from the
programmers mouth all day by the way I
don't mean to you know it's a valid
question okay you know I and and I don't
mean nothing negative about you Peter or
any any person okay but I mean I'm
talking about the phenomenon of the you
know of the of people of the population
you know who don't know a particular
particular subject but you have these
celebrities or whatever you know they do
you know and it's natural to I mean
because for me for example I'm a
programmer okay I know some math okay
I'm an amateur you might you might say
amateur mathematician but I don't know
anything about mechanical engineering or
you know oh much of other sciences so
you know I also find you know the pop
mechanics is very fascinating you know
then I learned oh no no no no you know
jeans or whatever so so yeah so what I'm
saying is that you know category theory
is one of the
subject that came out of the programmers
mouth all the time that annoys me
because I I you know in general I'm very
much I dislike or these pop things I
mean what what I'm thinking is that it
is okay pop I mean they have and then
they are entertaining and they are they
are kind of educational like when you
read you know if you are a kid you read
pop mechanics then in if then you become
a mechanical engineer you know that you
know that pushes you to become a
mechanical engineer like when I was
young young there's also a hominid
magazine okay which talks about science
in UFO and you know things like that
by the way Omni is defunct so you have
this Omni magazine you know I read it
when I was young and you know I I
enjoyed it very much you know about
hacking computing technology you know
but but they are not real serious
science or math or computer programming
you know if you read this you know so if
you so so what I'm saying is that I like
the idea of where hardcore stuff you
know if you want to study math you
really you know you really need to like
study the most boring fundamentals the
abstract algebra analysis basic analysis
okay things like that at least you know
so for example for people who are asking
you know for programmers they talk about
category theory you you ask them do you
know analysis
do you know abstract algebra you know
that like these two are the the ABCs of
mathematicians okay you have to is that
you have to know that otherwise you
don't know math at all you have no idea
what is matter is about so so
programmers most programmers they want
to talk about category theory
especially from the Haskell people okay
they want to talk about the category
theory they want to say Oh category
theory they help you you know I think
functional whatever you know they they
they churn out some math chart chuggins
but these people they don't know what is
a good theory
okay like did they don't they have no
idea what is a good theory it's kind of
absurd so so when they so if you are a
programmer okay you have to be aware of
this situation you have to be aware
don't you know don't fall for the pup
like you you are B you know you are just
falling for some nonsense okay now
category theory is a real thing but but
before you actually find category theory
useful okay as a programmer you know you
might think you probably thinking you
should I be true I should I learn
category theory you know I heard it's
you know it's one of the foundation of
math and it's so powerful you know so
should I learn it my answer is mostly no
well yeah you should but before you
learn that you should take like two
years to study the basics of mathematics
such as basic analysis basically act
algebra that's the two most basic
requirements so what is of abstract
algebra it's you know you have things
like field wings groups you you might
have heard of it now in analysis you
have like you have infinite series you
have infimum you have extremum you have
concept of compact space you know 10/10
subspace continuity things like that and
also topology and also complex analysis
these are a me I mean these are like the
building blocks the fundamental like the
Lego blocks you have to know that before
you have a skyscraper okay category is
somewhere it's somewhere out there okay
it's not it's it's
it's a foundation it's it's it's rather
advanced and it's rather so I don't
think so for programa if you're a
programmer you are asking you know
should you learn category theory my
answer is no absolutely you should study
two years of you you should spend at
least okay let's not exaggerate
okay I mean normally to be an
undergraduate you study four years of
math okay the first years two years is
like basics of calculus the second to
the last two years is actual real math
now that's if you go to a university but
for a programmer I mean I suppose I
assume you're a professional programmer
and you never studied math in college
you know you you know you are not going
to have four years to spend to study
math so a practical answer is you spend
you know I would say one year okay spend
one hour a day for one year to learn
some of the basic topics of math there
are okay first of all you really okay
about what which topic to study that
actually kind of depends but but but
basically you you should know you should
know the basic basics of analysis and
basics of abstract algebra okay once you
actually understand those topics for
example you can do homeworks you know
answer homeworks or questions about that
then you understand the concept of math
jargons and so on then it's up to you to
study category theory okay but most
likely after you learn abstract algebra
you mean you probably won't be
interested in abstract theory anymore I
mean in category theory anymore because
there are other things in math you know
properly the belongs to the logic branch
of math which category theory is part of
it the foundation the foundation of math
okay that you you you may want to go
into
instead of category theory that's my
opinion okay now I don't know my
category theory myself I try to learn it
a few times and I get the gist of the
context of the I don't like it as in
contracts to what I so category theory
is one of the what you may call a branch
of mathematical logic okay or rather a
foundation of math all rather related to
proof systems proof theory okay now in
that in that department in that category
in that branch okay they are kind of
many other things they are type theory
they are homotopy type theory they are
you know logic systems you know proof
theory which I'm trying to learn today I
hope to learn in the next five years
before I die
so anyway so I wouldn't you know
category theory I had it's not on my
plate okay I is it's not one of the
things I plan to learn because you know
I give myself five five more years
before I actually can actually still do
programming because I'm old I'm 50 years
old
so in the next five years I'll be lucky
if I actually understand some of the
other other things and category theory
is not on my plate I would for example
to be concrete I would be interested to
understand type theory and Hamas in
particular homotopy type theory by the
way if you are wondering if you should
learn like that no again you should you
need to know the basic of math first
before you actually really talk about
these kind of things so let me show you
again this Saudi math textbook so I have
a collection of text books I mentioned I
talked about this topic in my past
videos a few times so here is a
collection of math books so if you are a
programmer and if you don't know math or
you know some math depending on where
you are
you want to know here are the things you
want to learn okay you want to learn
calculus you want to learn linear
algebra by the way linear algebra is not
3d graphics okay stupid programmers it's
not like matrix matrices okay the
programmers think linear algebra is 3d
graphics nah not really well not for
professional mathematicians linear
algebra you have linear space you have
fields you have modules in its path
linear algebra is part of abstract
algebra so I have well basically I have
collected a bunch of textbooks that that
are free you can you know download and
read that teach you you know I've
checked out I've checked them out and
I've verified the quality so you can
trust the books I picked so this you got
so these are the things you want to
learn calculus linear algebra real
analysis complex analysis abstract
algebra up to this okay at least that's
the minimum that's a minimum you you
know you need to know okay to actually
say you understand some math before you
can go into category theory or other
things
now now topology is more advanced okay
and also logic you know so this this
book logic you know you can look look at
this book logic okay now if you want to
talk about category theory you cannot
understand this first and this book you
know you say this a prerequisite says
somewhere here basically I forgot where
it says
basically I forgot where maybe it's here
in this book or elsewhere but basically
you have to understand you have to have
four years of math major before you can
read this book anyway so there are these
topics so so I'm suggesting you know if
if any of you programmers who want to
really get into math you must at least
know real analysis and and abstract
algebra these two things these two are
the the most basic the the ABCs of math
okay you understand abstract algebra and
Rio analysis now now if you don't know
have no idea what these topics are just
look up Wikipedia okay that's for
example look up Wikipedia yeah Wikipedia
you can trust Wikipedia to give you a
good introduction of what this topic is
about but if you actually really need
want to learn this subject you should
you you must read a textbook instead of
Wikipedia because Wikipedia has got lots
of things some of them are actually a
graduate level or research level you
know you get confused if you go into
Wikipedia because you know you don't
know which is which so anyway that is my
opinion about category theory
yeah okay so I hope you know I you know
sometimes I give a talk of my of my own
opinions sometimes I have you know I
have the sense you know a lot of people
call me a troll so I have a sense you
know sometimes oh sorry is talking
no it's not
you know you of course always you know a
church for yourself you know you can ask
mathematicians you know kick it out of
the programming programmers community
okay if you really want to know about
these subjects you want to get in touch
with the math community now by that
you know like in programmers we are
programmers right you know you know you
hear about Java JavaScript front-end how
things evolve how complicated is web
frameworks you have opinions about
libraries of versus framework about all
of you vs. functional programming about
different languages you know you because
you are in the community you know don't
who is Donald Knuth you know who is you
know Bill Gates you know you know we
know this because we are in the
community you know this programming
community we know about all these things
and we know we understand what they are
okay
you have different methodologies you
have agile you have functional
programming you have programming
languages you have new languages you
know such as Haskell or camera or you
know then you know because we are in a
in this community we understand all
these things and Emacs versus VI and so
on now you have to imagine the math
community do you know anything about it
can you name let's say three
mathematicians the top three
mathematicians today can you name let
let's say three controversial topics in
mathematics no you don't know nothing
about it that's the point
so you uni if you want to get serious
answers or questions about math you need
to kick it you know get yourself into
the math community which is mostly
mathematicians no programmers okay be
well basically mostly professional
mathematicians mass majority like 99.9
and they are not programmers and they
know nothing about program programming
okay they may be may be hard pressed to
tell you what you say Opie you know and
what is the function you know so society
we have all these different communities
you need to you know it's it's the best
for society if each of us or kind of
know different communities just like you
know HM it's better if we know about
different country we have lived in
different countries for a couple of
years you know then things becomes
better because we have we actually know
stuff we have communication otherwise
you know if you are a programmer you
just hear about this program means
programmers talking about math or
category theory or graph theory Oh
linear algebra or quaternion C's about
computer graphics it's all it's all
you go into the mathematicians
you hear nothing about it I can give you
an example okay I talked about this in
previous videos as well like math
overflow math way math overflow okay
math overflow is like stack overflow
buddy but it's focused for it's used by
professional mathematicians okay
remember it's not just a place questions
answers for math no it's questions in
answers for people who work as
mathematicians
as a profession meaning that they they
their daily lives
they are either professors or they
research mathematicians this website
math overflow is used by professional
mathematicians okay now look at the site
you know take take ten minutes just to
look at it see the website you'll find
that nothing you understand not one
topic you have no have one sense of idea
what they are talking about this is
mathematics now you you know this is not
your from the programming then you go to
the you know
go flow you search for math then you see
a bunch of math as programmers talking
about math it's entirely different you
know there is entirely different so
that's that's what I mean by you want to
get into the community to actually
understand so if you have a question
about category theory you know should we
should we learn category theory go into
the math community you know and get
opinions from them then you start to see
things okay in fact you cannot post that
question to math above a flow because
your question is too stupid you know you
get kicked out right away
so anyway
so hello pace hey good morning bass
happy Friday
so what's up you with you guys I think I
guess that's it for today three person
watching okay so so that's it for today
yeah I guess that's it let's see what
else am I want to talk about Rio
analysis this is a great book I'm still
reading it I got this book like 20 years
ago but yeah I'm still reading it but
you can see you can see the pictures
there the pictures on the cover that's
showing that that is actually Mobius
transformation and you can see the
sphere that is the Riemann sphere the
topics we just mentioned for example the
Mobius transformation oops
let's go down a little bit let's see
some pictures anyway and stereographic
projection yeah but anyway I was going
to talk about the math I mean giving you
a tutorial about this but maybe next day
so thank you guys for watching that's it
for today good bye have a good Friday