hi guys
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
today is 2020 september
6th sunday noon
san francisco time and we are going to
talk random but mostly i'm going to
install this deno
javascript platform and i'm going to
give you my
impression as i install it but first of
all this
first of all this background image today
so let's go to today's talk show and
here is my emacs
and on the right you can see all my
commands and keys
comment this part out showing browser so
today's today's talk show page
the background image is this keyboard
about vfx keyboard
this is just a keyboard from china i
mean you you find it
i find it on uh on one of the chinese uh
selling website chinese uh alibaba or
something
you can see where to buy yeah at
80 uh ali express
okay so this keyboard is designed for
photoshop
and i think it's fantastic you know you
got these
wheels knobs and wheels two knobs one
wheel and another
drum wheel so you know it's
it's designed for photoshop but i don't
use photoshop or image edit editing
that much however i would love this
keyboard you know get two of them
because i talked about this many times
the wheels are
incredibly useful for volume control
or for any activity any kind of action
or command
that has a backward and forward versions
such as left and right arrow up down
arrow
page up and down scroll up and down
previous tab next tab previous window
next tab
next window previous or next workspace
you know those things are uh the wheel
is most
suitable or even move cruiser you know
move uh
move cruiser forward backward for
example
you know so if you have have a wheel it
allows you
instantaneous variable control of
speed and also
instantaneous reversible direction much
more efficient than
keys for example arrow keys
i mean i mean i mean you know two keys
previous and next because for keys for
example you can see your example of this
is
when you you know most modern keyboards
they have
buttons like two buttons for sound
volume up and down
so you if you want to uh increase the
volume you press for example let's see
yeah you know press press press press
press press
that's idiotic okay you have a wheel
that controls
backward back backward and forward
motion
uh so that's a background keyboard you
can actually buy it
i i forgot how much it it is but
so you just go to my website search for
saudi about
vx if uh about vf just search for xrd
keyboard you'll find my pages
okay so today i'm going to install deno
the javascript the new javascript
platform hello hello guys we have so
many people
so uh you guys have questions uh type it
okay
let's see what good morning but uh bart
from germany and
good morning shiko siko from hong kong
good morning
alan from sunny california uh
chrome just scratched for alan
okay so we are going to do javascript
today that that's
uh so there is a new project called deno
okay
d-e-n-o so let me show you you just
search the web demo
uh so deno for example there's wikipedia
okay and uh wait hold on a second
so there's wikipedia and the home page
for demo okay so let's
let's magnify let me show you some of
the interesting things
so you can you know you can read
wikipedia so they have this logo
so you know if you are a javascript
coder
if you are not learn it okay well it's
it's one of the language
uh modern language very highly popular
the most the top
five most popular you know if we
yeah let me talk about damn dental but
let me talk let me tell you about
javascript because i have been working
on javascript for the past two days
non-stop you know
well i've been working on it for years
but for example you can look at my tabs
okay this is all my
javascript tutorials uh
constant declaration global variable
javascript
date.utc method function call
applybind you know we i have like
hundreds of pages javascript so this is
my javascript in depth tutorial i have
and
and also dom find element width
so i've been working on that actually
non-stop today for
six hours uh there are tons of
tons of things to do uh in fact i can
show you what i was doing you know and i
still have tons of uh things to do
so this space page is basic dom methods
you know like you read this page you'll
know
almost 99 of use the need
for the functions i mean the the other
function 99 of the functions you need
to manipulate dom you do not
need you know react or or
angularjs or a bunch of crap like that
you know you follow my tutorial you
follow my
style you'll be most efficient the most
lean and efficient
code you don't need react you don't need
angular
js you you don't need all those crap
uh well i guess in
if you work in a company is you somewhat
sometimes you somewhat need them well
we're getting into that today you know
so there's npm you know library and
there's not js
and we we are going to look at uh deno
today i'm going to tell you what deno is
about
so you can see all my javascript you
know i have tons of tab open
these tabs are pages i already modified
you know i can tell you what you know i
modified them so
i still leave them all open so that i
can read about them
uh like review like oh you know to
review them again because you write a
lot of tutorials over the years
um if you don't review them
you know they will bit rot because
things change or the javascript you know
javascript has a new version
a new standard new features every year
now
since 2015. so for example javascript
iterable
is a new feature since 2015 and a very
extremely useful feature powerful
iterable number constructor you know
some of these are so
rather more esoteric details uh i mean
even if you code in javascript for
living
let's say you're coding you know let's
say you work for google for three years
you may not understand lots of these
because
well part of the reason is that you use
the react and stuff you know and
you know and also javascript is uh
extremely complicated
language rather very extremely
complicated
but however since javascript 2015
you know if you know what you are doing
you avoid those packages you avoid the
bad features so called
the javascript the good parts you use
the good parts
javascript the language today is
uh is equivalent as far as power and
flexibility goes is equivalent to
any of you know python ruby um
yeah but oh oh
oh said with all that said javascript is
still
sucky the entire language is extremely
complex
and hard to understand
tons of baggages that they refuse to
fix they refuse to fix
because they don't want to they don't
want to make a
incompatible version so that's why all
these baggage remains
so you know rejects array object literal
expression
and there are new features in object
literal expression introduced in 2015
you know computed property keys and
method syntax
shorthand and so on and you see so
terms of my uh you know tabs
so you see i'm using so let me show you
one of the
one of the interesting things about my
keyboard setup
you can see the efficiency of my setup
okay so
so here is here is my keyboard using you
can see
and let's switch back to the browser
okay so you can see you you see
it's all uh one
one finger operation so go back here
so this page is about symbols symbol is
introduced in javascript
uh uh 2015 yeah
you know so you can fly through uh
these tabs so this you know single key
press
fantastic uh operation and and again
this is kinesis advantage 2
my main keyboard and this one is um
this one is uh ultimate hacking keyboard
i have reviews on my website you can go
read
so now let's let's put it back in
position
okay so javascript you know you might
want to learn it because
it's quite popular so we are going to
look at deno so what is daniel daniel is
the new platform
it's basically not js you know you know
not js i'm running not js for example
yeah let's do demo okay uh
let's say you know create a javascript a
new template okay so you can see
here's a new template and i press the
button i'm using emacs this is kind of
my custom emacs
huge amount of customers customization
with
powerful features uh powerful
features comparable to oakmod
of of those of you ogmod fans you know
you you have oak babble and all this
that that
you know oakmod people you know they
love it they live in it
but you know so i work in my
site html mod i have similar features so
let's say console.log
you know console.log let's say three
plus two
run it and you can see
five you know you know in the result
panel so that's javascript and how do i
write
well i'm using well the and you see
i'm using uh
many of the things i wrote uh for
example you call uh
star run current file that's how you run
it
so you can see five let's say three plus
seven run it
you can see 10 here so that's that's
all um where is it
starting current file this command
okay but how is that command implemented
let's look you know so
i'm gonna call uh i'm i'm going to call
describe key
and press the key for soldering current
file
then emacs will pop up the documentation
for that
command console run current file right
here so
now you can press tab to jump to the
link
um open it and here is the source code
focus on run current file
so you can see it can run magnify so you
can run php
pearl python python 3 ruby
golan haskell not not js not js is the
you know javascript you know depending
on the
the file file name surface
uh which one to run so this is how it's
implemented so when it sees a dot js
file
it will actually run not js you can see
oops uh not you can see right there that
line
you see you know so that's the emac this
code
so it tells you so you see so this file
is you can see the file name
there uh oops uh
okay you can see the file name there dot
js close it
so it'll run not js so for example let's
go to
let's go to shell okay isha
which nod so you see i have not
installed
right there so now you say
uh now you say not and the file name
that's a temp file name
learnet you can see 10. so that's how
i run javascript okay let's delete that
and that's how i work on my javascript
tutorial as well
for example for example this constant
declaration okay
so copy the url back to emax
open that file this is the file
constant declaration new feature in
javascript
so here is javascript code you can see
the first
block of code sample code
that corresponds to this region and i
press the key
the code is moving you know moved out
there
you see from here so now i can run it
run it uh wait
uh oh yeah type error yeah
so you know i'm trying to show that if
you declare something as constant
you cannot reassign it if you do you got
error which
which is what we get so
okay uh unsplit
delete this undo it you know
so that's how i you know that's how i
work on my javascript code
you know so constant page let's close
this
page uh let's show another example
shall we or shall we not let's not do it
okay so anyway
you see how um you know i need
you know basically i need a
javascript runtime on my system
of course you can also use a browser now
for example
in browser any browser chrome safari or
not or
firefox you can press f12
then you got this panel then you can
type
you know you click on console then you
can type
three plus two you know it says five
let's say magnum file you see
but then but you have to go to the you
see that doesn't
uh work for my workflow because i have
to
you know i'd rather say in emacs i i
don't have to switch to the browser
run it then they maybe copy the result
then
go back to emacs and paste it you know
so that's that
okay close this page so now we're gonna
install
deno so why they know so um not js you
know not js
is invented by ryan dao this guy ryan
dar
hey good morning bass haven't seen you
for a long time
i'm doing well thank you ladies library
of the week
no not you know i i very much trust
denno let me tell you what is dinner
okay so let's go back to daniel
uh deno software you know uh
so about 10 years ago the ryan doll
this guy ryan doll is a great guy i
highly respect him you know those of you
who watch lots of
my videos you see i flame i [ __ ] about
all these programmers for exa
for example the larry war pearl who
invented pearl who is he he's an idiot
uh guido of van rossum who invented
python he's an idiot
uh martin fowler who who you know modern
father a very famous guy for
in a programming community he's he's a
he's a
con man okay in my opinion he's a
comment
he whatever he says it's crap it's
garbage you know he created
agile you know extreme programming and
so on and x
and uh and uml you know the uml
um you you and ml stand for what
uh um
i forgot jesus it's been a while
you know i'm getting old
so anyway so so so you know i complained
you know but
actually some programmers i highly
respect ryan dahl
i highly respect this guy okay
first of all he's a mathematician you
know he's a real mathematician he's
studying phd
i talked about this uh before like half
a year ago
he he's a phd student studying some
esoteric
you know when you when you are in math
when you get to phd
those topics you cannot explain to a
layman you know
it takes a month to expand just to just
to
try to give them an idea what it's about
so he studied you know a phd and one day
well anyway he
invented knot.js 10 years ago
which is you know which is
fantastic but he made a few mistakes
of course everyone does then
what happens is that he kind of
he let other people around you know he
is thinking it's
i'm done he let other people so then
that's when the
mpm began the the leader of the mpm
is a scumbag okay in my opinion he's not
a good human
animal uh the leader of npm
so but anyway he's you know let's let's
let's see
okay that's my opinion
nothing else npm software okay
now npm software is not this guy isaac
z uh shorter something
i i i don't know him too much
but from the few incidents you know
controversial incidents i looked into i
think he's a scumbag
okay so anyway he now he runs not js he
he you know he
leads not js and he als
he's a creator of npm and the npm
becomes a giant
huge corporate thing uh
so anyway so so i'd rather i'd rather
not use not yet you know because i
rather you know i
rather prefer to not use things from
people
i do not like from people i think are
not good person
so anyway so there is now so that's when
so there is deno so not you know the
ryan dog guy the mathematician
he's uh he's incredible because he never
had any coding experience
you know he's a mathematician uh and he
just started to learn coding for a year
or two and he
basically just created uh not in in like
three years
two to two hours you know very short
time he he was a php
coder you know so that's not a trivial
thing to do you
you to create an arcgis you know based
on not js is based on the
javascript engine from chrome web
browser called
v8 so anyway a year two years ago
ryan daw who is working at google now
you know he decided he was trying to he
you know he came up with dana which is
kind of a
a new version of node.js in a sense
so you know trying to fix his mistakes
and you know
start a new so that's what dano is about
and i heard someone told me
that then tenno is the reverse of not
you know
d-e-n-o the reverse of not
you know so i have several of you know
you go watch
several of the ryan dahl's video okay
let me show you okay
uh close that let's go to uh
ryan dao uh sardi okay
actually exactly ryan dal so there are
some videos of him i recommend
i'm going to show you my pages okay
because otherwise today
google and all these corporations make
makes it impossible
for you to find good quality things
because if i tell you to you know watch
some of the video by him
your your search and what will come up
is probably a bunch of clickbaits you
know someone
a second hand or third hand trying to
comment on his video
some things like that not just things
things like that or copy
you know you know so anyways there are
there are a couple you know how to find
good
stuff because you you'll probably see
tons of videos you don't know which one
is good
so i've watched two uh so
here's article ryan daw on software
complexity
you know today's software is just crap
our software the c
especially the c c plus first and the
unix and linux [ __ ]
they they idiots they they create
complexity
also javascript and also the entire web
technology
so anyway ryan dog you know you watch
him he's a
truly a great guy and he wrote the
article this article is written by him
on the complexity of javascript i mean
not just
on the complexity of software
that's the state we are in and here's
another video by him this is this one is
uh less interesting it's just a tutorial
on uh
on not js like 10 years ago uh 2011 yeah
nine years ago so anyway so i recommend
you watch
this one okay so uh you know created you
know
this this one is interesting actually
there's another one
uh this one will be also interesting
ryan daw on history of not so you'll
learn about nigerians
you know why he created it so anyway he
came up with a demo
uh like and and and now it's supposed to
be
uh uh you know ready for industrial use
so they know a secure runtime for
javascript and
typescript you know typescript is also
great
i wouldn't say it's great but because
javascript is pretty bad
javascript is truly a bad language so
typescript help helps significantly
however their type typescript is
actually a superset of javascript
so any plain javascript is also type
type script by definition it's it's a
strict superset so that's one
advantage of typescript because it's
just like javascript
you know you can add more stuff you
don't have to you know so it's
compatible
so typescript is a great help to
javascript
however i mean even you know even
typescript
you know javascript with typescript it's
the language is still pretty lousy
because javascript itself is
tremendous complexity but anyway so
yeah typescript is great okay
so deno actually runs typescript by
itself too so that's
that's great about deno okay so so we're
gonna install it
uh i'm going to install it now okay
let me read the comments bar says i'm
fully
on board with your c plus plus passion
thank you oh yeah uh
dirk bennett says the unified modeling
language
that that uml that crap that crap that
kong man stuff from the modern father
[ __ ]
my they could um
uh you know that's my opinion only okay
okay so we're gonna install it so
actually so there's the install instruct
instruction
i'm going to install it and so there's
blue okay let's just try brew
brew install dental okay so let's go to
a
oops let's go to my terminal
it's magnified so it's huge
okay boo
install denno okay
now brew is one of uh mac os uh
mac os uh package manager there are
quite a few
uh about 20 years ago the first one is
fink
which i used for like over 10 years i
used for for yeah 10 years think
then just somewhat sometimes during that
time they
then came mac ports uh then drew
you know came up it was never clear to
me
exactly what's the reason you know these
people created you know
other than other than think but but i i
can tell you a story about think
you know so there's one guy who thought
you know
he he got idea of creating a package
manager
for the mac based on the based on the
linux
uh debian uh package manager so he
kind of pulled it to the mac so he
created the think project
open source but after year or two he got
tired of it because
it's all take no give you know other
people is asking him questions
oh this doesn't work can you help me you
know things like that
easy got fed up with open source so he
quit
okay brew it says updating proof so okay
so it's this is gonna take a few minutes
i guess
well i have 17 people watching just by
talking about javascript stuff
uh so what's up alan so any
opinions about uh
not or uh deno
so alain says ellen from sweden
says why is he a common
martin fowler okay martin fowler why is
he a comment
first of all that's just my opinion you
know
let me take it back not a comment okay
because if i say he's a common i can get
sued that's a defamation but
so martin fowler in my opinion he's the
idiot
he is some you know he's the type of guy
like kind of like common okay they they
they create let's say a crackpot okay
crackpot is a more fitting word he's a
he's a crackpot
in my opinion he create things you know
he created a code kind of thing
and with a lot of followers you know
because you know you can see today a lot
of followers
love you know they will they will cite
martin fowler constantly
so he's one of the type of guy in
society
you know this happens over you know
constantly in history so he's one the
type who create kind of a code
thing with the file with lots of
followers and the things he creates
you know his ideas is usually like
uh not not science-based it's not
science
uh it's kind of cult like thing you know
modern father uml okay
uh ultimate what is it ultimate modern
language was it ultimate uh
you know he you know one of the hallmark
of crackpot's
unified modern language you know he
created this thing
one of the hallmark of of code is
jargons
you know so martin fowler his things are
full
filled with jargons everything is a
jargon a unified modeling language these
[ __ ]
these [ __ ] will create a modern
language that's unified
but in reality that's just for op okay
that's not
for functional programming it's just
that good and it's not mathematics okay
well i i i take it back because i
i haven't studied uml in depth
you know he created a lot of lots of
things you know a data
object-oriented uh database for example
i despise that
he also created you know something
injection you know some some kind of
programming paradigm
you know jargons you know basically
useless
you you kind of useless jargons like
patterns you know yeah you usually
you know okay so let's go back
let's so deno is installed let's see uh
which
demo there it is
user local uh user local bin deno so i
can run demo now let's go to
uh ishow deno let's uh
which deno fantastic user local bin deno
we got we are going to run it okay
so okay close it let's let's create a
javascript okay
console.log magnify three
plus uh one okay
now this is going to okay so save it
back to go go go to the shell
copy the file name this is the file name
close it
go to the go to the e-shell again
then we are going to run demo okay
denote that file name
let's see oh [ __ ]
arrow now this is a bad sign because
it should just return uh you know four
so error found argument that
which wasn't expected oh okay so okay
so it's because um
you know the options i have to use it
properly
so deno help
let's see what it says so how do you run
the file
a secure javascript and type script
runtime we're going to try typescript
okay
so docs uh modules and books
so so you know i um you know it's
fantastic go use it i get i
i trust it for sure because of the ryan
dollar guy
you know you go to their website you
also read you know the summary of
features it's a i think
it's great it's a uh not
not dot js replay replacement and i hope
it will
uh you know replace not.js
so usage demo options uh how do you run
the file
let's see eval help install linked repo
run run a program given a file name or
url to module
okay use dash as a file name to read
from stats
okay so that's the option so
let's try it again
okay then you need to say run
okay uh
we got what happened oh four there it is
you see somehow the output is um
gray so it's hard to see but you see it
it's magnified you see
yellow yellowish color four
so successful so actually
now shrink shrink shrink okay so
actually successful now
what we are going to do is uh let's
replace my command okay close this we
don't need it
let's replace my emacs command
uh run kernel file to use
deno instead of nod okay
so so go here
make a backup copy so this line
comment out make a new one let's say
deno okay
uh actually they demo run yeah
you know it's interesting you know the
optional design because for some
languages languages you need to say run
you know for example go down you
if you want if you want to run some file
you say go run
but not for php perl python in those
cases you just
type the file name uh that
you know that's a interesting design
choice like which one is better and so
on
anyway anyway so dental run is the one
so eval the buffer let's change the date
the new version number today's date then
eval this command
then go back to my
go back to my html file
wait actually go here uh
run okay so but for some reason
i don't know why it shows the output
colored uh kind of yellow like
i don't quite get what mechanism
you know because usually the output
should not be colored
especially in emacs because what what
right now what what it is doing is that
e-max calls dental and there's output
then e-max will take the output and
display it
in the buffer here but
but i don't see how it gets color
because in order to have color you have
to have
text properties in e-max so i guess
e-max automatically
copy the shells you know the shells
ascii
color coding i guess so anyway it works
so now i want to make sure that
well i know for sure this is from deno
because the output is colored
uh yellow it was not the case from not
js
okay so that works so delete this file
okay we installed deno and we run the
code successfully
uh
now let's see i want to let's try i want
to
say i want to print out
the executable file path how do you do
that
so how do you in dental how do you print
the executable file path any comments
questions
i think that's you know we are basically
um let's see how long have i been
talking
37 minutes yeah i think we did
you know we gave an introduction to uh
denno
a new js runtime to test front-end code
yeah you know so uh you guys work in
companies
you can you know you use deno and not js
for the back
for the server right mostly but me
i haven't been working at corporations
for a long time so
so this this is my use of uh
dental or not.js
oh a feature of dental color in the
console
oh okay that's interesting
uh
okay i think we have 15 uh viewers
so deno is great go install it okay
let's try to run some more complex code
okay let's
yeah so i'm going to go to my javascript
in depth
okay showing browser
so if you like my tutorial uh
buy my javascript in depth okay you know
there's like
200 pages um
you don't need any libraries i teach you
the most simple
simple and elegant way to code using
pure javascript
and the technology building in browser
uh
uh so what oh let me mention you know
with not js you know not js and and vu
dot js and re and you know react no
react.js view.js or angular.js
or amber.js you know this this kind of
javascript
platform you know they are kind of
frameworks
they are useful um they are useful
for sure um
i don't like them myself but i mean it's
it's not true to say i mean they are
useful they are actually
uh lots of coding went into them and
they are useful you know once in
one of the situation they are great very
useful using a corporation
and not not not really because
the features they provide
that too but that's not the main reason
the main reason is rather
they they don't require you to know
the javascript or the language in depth
that's what they do they kind of you
know you just slap
in this framework you just put these
lines you know copy and paste
and your work so in a corporation when
they hire a lot
people um
so those frames frameworks are useful
i mean that's part of the reason they
are hugely popular
on the other hand you know a giant
corporation cannot you know i'm like
my coding style you know use you know if
you want to code
the way i do you know using minimal code
understand the language very well that's
not normal that's not the
normal case i mean that's what we should
do uh
you should aspire to do that
uh you know but you have to spend
tremendous time i spent two years full
time to write this tutorial you know
two years full time nobody have time to
do that right
so well i i do i i i did
so that's a cost you know most people
you don't have that luxury
so that is why those frameworks becomes
very useful
okay so anyway so but but ultimately
because javascript is a very lousy
language
you know if you look at golan golan or
or many other you know modern languages
golan julia julia maybe julia for
example
they have bld library even python you
know python ruby
you know you have a system of libraries
you don't have to use
frameworks you don't have to you know
just use
building libraries but javascript does
not have that that's a problem
you know that's that is why you have all
these frameworks and the most despicable
one is the
mpm [ __ ] npm you know that guy
isaac he made npm so that you know
it's a in my opinion you know the
every choice he make he he he make it so
that
he benefit the most he make choices so
npm becomes the most popular as par as
popular as part
possible and gets the most people
involved
but however it's not a good thing for
the actual coders
you know you you install one library
that installs 10
and each one install 10 more so every
time you install library you actually
install hundreds of libraries
that's what what happens with npm and
some of the libraries are just
five lines of code you know such as
stream stream
you know why does this happen you know
you might say oh well
because javascript then they designed
that way
not really well that's half the reason
the you know
part part of the reason is because they
they made it that way so
so npm will grow and grow and grow
uh you know that's that's you know
that's uh
that's similarly similarly that is how
google all these giant corporations grow
google facebook microsoft you know they
on the surface they tell you oh we are
helping the world
you know we do this way so that we wish
a
word where information is available for
everyone that's what they say
that's which is true too you know from
certain aspect
but on the other hand you know as you
know google today is very evil
that's not you know that's that's not
their pure goal they have something else
in their mind to grow you know to make
them
themselves a massive empire
so anyway so um
so that's about the my you know my
opinions about these frameworks
and also i don't use them not because
well
also in part because i'm getting old and
i just never
actually studied them i wanted to
study uh react.js you know at least one
of them
well so by well i mean to the degree
that i i
would know how to implement them from
scratch
you know not necessarily doing it
because doing it actually will take a
lot of
experience you know you'll take one year
you know but
if if i do it by myself it will take one
year or two
if if that you know to implement nuagex
that's not
my goal i i want what i want is at least
the the the you know the understanding
of how it is done you know what you know
react.js every feature about react.js
you understand
how it is done what is it is purpose
how when you use react.js what's the
major
you know difference what's the major
benefits or
shortcomings but mostly the mechanism
how it is
uh done you know by what means that you
know understand the technology
so that is actually that's that that is
what i want
uh uh to do uh
i'm hoping to do to understand one of
them
so there's ember.jsreact.js
you know vue.js and quite a few there's
you know there's also new ones i don't
remember the names
like a new a new one coming out every
two years
okay similar java and stream framework
so that
alain says then uh how about elm
yeah elm you know so i haven't studied
elm so
m is another m is a language i think
uh i don't know much about l but m is
kind of a functional
language based on based on javascript
right
based on javascript and and
that that parallel programming
language idea right is that maybe i got
confused
anyway so there are quite a few let's go
to um
since since i'm talking random let's go
to
my website
hi sergio we are about done today
i've been talking for an hour for 40
minutes
15 minutes 46 minutes yeah we're about
done
so we installed deno uh so this is my
page
proliferation programming languages i
talked about
quite a few times in my video
so um so you have you know let's see
elm okay scheme
scheme dylan which is a lisp
from apple meta language meta language
is
which is the daddy of ocamo and f-sharp
then you have sharp which is from
microsoft
microsoft's version of our camera a
functional language
then you have erlang right erlang
haskell concurrent
clean mercury q q
q and o z then your ph okay those are
not interesting then javascript
powershell
tcl lua okay
okay so some thought about languages
listing criterion
and popularity why the list okay anyway
so uh let's see elm okay
go rust julia coffee script
copy script is pretty dead now it's
you know back about 10 years ago it's
supposed to
uh it's very highly popular very popular
uh it's supposed to be a javascript
replacement but today
typescript does that now back in 2011
quite a few people corporations and
people too
they try to come up with a java with a
language that replaces javascript
because javascript truly sucks you know
javascript
sucks donkey s so google came out with
dot no good so there's typescript
in this asm.js ometa elm yeah
so m is a functional foreign language
for
declarative uh creating web browser
based on graphical user interface
uh functional reactive programming style
okay
i'm not familiar with that you know it
will be interesting to learn
so i don't know um
you know so you know today so many
languages you don't have time to learn
them you know like
you talk to people some people say oh
you should learn elm then
ask how then you know you know you know
haskell fans right
scout this and that uh
and hacks and hack and swift
and edison pattern matching language and
elixir
elixir is also often mentioned with elm
uh elixir is a functional concurrent
general purpose
programming language that runs on the
airline virtual machine
yeah basically then you have kotlin
uh on based on the java virtual machine
platform
then you have nim name has quite a lot
of followers
from the nerd community um
then you have crystal which is like a
ruby you know a fast version of ruby
then you have pirate from the skin
people
then you have pure script also you know
like pure script along with elm
it's kind of popular and read some ml
okay this i actually i
have some interest reason ml is created
by facebook
it's basically a camel in javascript
syntax so basically this compiles to
javascript
you know it's a it's a language you know
they call it reason
ml uh but
the language is basically ocamo you know
the which is
off stream from the meta language ml
that's why they say ml you know all
these are ml meta language
which is originally originally designed
to do math
proofs like 30 years ago ml so you have
ml you have
camo you have all camel then you have f
sharp
then you have reason ml so it's a camo
in javascript
syntax so i would be interested
in this one uh so
cake ml another email you know so many
languages
okay that's it for today any comments
and questions we shut down in
three minutes five minutes
okay so
yeah so bye guys thank you guys for
watching
uh if you like my tutorial again you
know go buy my javascript in depth
tutorial um and what else you know we
shut down in five minutes
and uh i'm going to show you i guess
some uh some of my working on my website
ryan dahl okay very interesting go watch
his video okay
go watch go watch uh this one
just search the title you'll find it
create a ryan dial on software
complexity
this video okay uh
you know many of his his opinions i
usually agree with i highly respect this
guy
and now he came up with uh daniel
a great guy uh incredible and also
you know a mathematician highly
intelligent but also a very capable
guy you know he just writes software
some sort of uh genius almost yeah
ryan dao so npm you know the
the leader is not a good human
mpm is also crap [ __ ] vm
so you have deno go install dinner okay
so let's see i i want to do some uh let
me show you
you know how i work on some some of my
tutorial page
so recently uh let me show you what i
was doing okay
i was trying to redesign some of the
formatting
things on my website look at this okay
so you see there are two formats for
specification of a function so in one
way it's basically a list
like that and another way you have
indentation
now they are implemented in html in
different ways
okay the list is just a list on the
other hand the second one
you know the list is an ordered at least
an ordered
list ul the indentation is done by use
done by the definition list dt
okay that's html by the way by the way
i have html tutorial too so
if you do not know html at all you can
learn from scratch
a kind of a very simplified tutorial
the whole thing the html and
ncss okay so
what i want to show you is that so you
know
so this is an interesting design issue
uh well not that interesting but you
know so you have these two
formats you know this is related to
technical writing
you know take technical writing you know
it's a skill right and it's kind of also
a specialty
you have to have writing skill but it's
different from novel writing
it's different from creative writing
it's different from
essay writing you know different skills
uh so technical writing you have to
you you can learn that okay i that's you
know i might talk about that as another
topic another day
but in order to write stuff today
so it's not just writing you know
writing you create a content but there's
also the issue of formatting
and the issue the formatting issue is a
big giant implementation
basically think of technical writing
as a uh you know you write the content
but however
formatting and the implement you have
the implementation
issue how do you put it you know you you
it's not like
you write on paper and send it to
publisher they print it it's not like
that
you write it you know in either in html
or xml
or uh or p or uh pdf you know
there are quite a few there are tens of
actually
documentation documentation um
technologies for for example tech la
tech
html org mod uh text info
from emacs from google emacs you know
kind of quite a lot
and and there's also art we do something
ruby uses you know
python you know quite a lot of
technologies
and and there's also open dock i think
it's called
you know so that's a non-trivial issue
what which one you're gonna use
which one is more efficient for you you
know it's not trivial and each one have
different capabilities okay so technical
writing today
besides the writing skill part besides
the writing content you
also have the formatting and
implementation issue
and here so i choose to use html right
because i've been
you know i was born with you know when i
i watched
the birth of html since 1995 i
i began to use i began to write htm html
in 1996.
so so i watched the both of html
css and javascript you know from from
from the from their first day so i'm
very familiar with html so i choose to
use html
but then um so this issue in particular
is you know it's not so it's a kind of
formatting issue
so once you choose a technology you also
have this kind of
formatting issue for example for example
if you go read a technical book you go
out by o'reilly books or whatever book
you know javascript
you know book or haskell books you open
them you know
sometimes they have a tip box you know
maybe with a
you know idea you know a light bulb you
know you have a tip box
then you have sometimes a warning box
you know they
you know those boxes they they have a
visual clue
to indicate their purpose you know aside
from the main content
uh or sometimes in books you also have
footnotes
right so these are issues you know if
you actually write a book even if you
know
publish your book or write online like
me
these are issues you have to deal with
they don't they don't just
come out and you know done so i saw
so this so i have this you know i happen
to have these two
issues you know which one is better so
it seems like so which which one you
guys like better
uh so let me know
okay so for example i think most people
like the indented intended issue okay
i mean the intended version so
once i choose the intended version i
have to change hundreds of pages you
know
throughout my website to the intended
version and that's not a trivial thing
to do
and you know most people think oh oh you
can just write a script you know you can
just write the
python pro ruby or golan you can just
write a script to automate it
not really have you ever tried
have you ever tried for example to
convert a book let's say from html to
pdf
or pdf to tech la tech you know any of
those
if have you ever tried it's not just
untrivia
it's in fact impossible okay you
actually have to do it manually line by
line otherwise
if you do it automatic automatically
it's ink
you come out very ugly garbage
just like lots of automatically
generated html files
you look at them it's crap it's garbage
you know
and even uh it's syntactically invalid
html you know you go to the html
validation website you know just search
for html validation
from the w3c you'll see it's invalid
so anyway it's not trivial and and even
for the simple thing
of the things i wrote with which has
tight very tight control um
um you know my web my html
uh pages are very tight control okay i
control exactly where i should have a
space
where i should break the line you know
every every detail
even that it's not trivial to
to suddenly decide uh to convert those
let me show you an example then okay
so let's go to um okay let's go to
let's see let's say um
array constructor okay let's open that
show this page in browser so here we
have a page this is about the array
constructor the array
uh wait what okay here
yeah so this this page is array
constructor
you see they are using my old format
where it's a
an order list with arrow okay now
now go back to the html here is the html
code
hold on a second so let's magnify
let me show okay okay maybe
maybe this way it's better you can see
this section this section corresponds to
the
to that okay to to this
okay so what
okay so
so i'm going to so i have written a emac
this command that helps me convert
so for example let's uh copy this okay
copy and paste it so we have
two copy of it so now i'm going to
convert the second copy here
so what i do is i put a cursor somewhere
inside the block
here okay then i call the command
ul 2 dl there it is
ul to dl okay then he asked me for a
separator
okay if you know html you know because
if you use definition list there are two
parts there's a diff
the term and the definition you know so
so you need you kind of you have a
separator so separator is an arrow okay
okay then uh keep separated no okay
i'm not going to explain but anyway it's
done
so so this block is kind of it's done so
now
go back to browser magnify
refresh now shrink a little bit you can
see two versions here
here is the first original version and
here's the second version
i just did i just did the conversion
so you know so now i can you know now i
can just um
delete the first version okay back to
browser refresh you see
this is new version so that's what i do
um the end you know so you have to
change
more than 100 pages and usually you want
to do it manually because
why because for example
um because on some pages you know
they are not all together you know here
we are all talking about array but
sometimes they
it's explained in different sections
because
you have examples in between
so you you know i'm talking about some
uh
some esoteric details the interesting
details about
formatting change in in in a technical
uh uh literature
so it's not just change the format that
you know most people think oh just
change the format
you can run a program here work no it
doesn't because
in here it worked but some other page
sometimes they are a part
with with example code in between
but once you change to this you know
indian style
then you want them to be together
because
because the visualization you know
here's an intricacy okay because
visualization how how things are
formatted
has a effect and impact
on how you perceive the content okay so
it's not just
you know a lot of html people like say
like to say oh
you know semantic versus appearance you
know they should be separated
[ __ ] idiots it's not just that okay
how you format has a how things are
formatted how the
appearance the color the position has a
impact to your position
to your perception of the content the
exact
same content no change to the text but
how they are
formatted has a rather
not neglected
impact to your perception
so anyway that's it for today thank you
guys for watching
uh bye guys you should rewrite to uh
react
right um
pen doc right okay so alan has done
so pen dog is another technology for
documentation
uh he doesn't look at the back of his
hands uh
in dutch type he knows html back of his
hands
so i was wrong on the web when was the
last time you worked for someone some
company that's
uh depending on how you count
so if you are talking about you know
working a
company every day you go you know you go
to the company you you know work with
co-workers every day
then the last time is year 2002
but if you can't contract work where you
also work for a company but
at home then then it's
kind of here and there
uh yeah css but
css is not the
it it does not
it does not have the capability to
control the appearance hundred percent
that is some part of appearance are
fundamentally with html
no amount of css can change it for
example
when one primary example is older the
order of elements in your html page
uh it's it's basically impossible just
you know
to to to change order by css you know
and they're they're
intricacy you know they are details
so anyway that's it for today thank you
guys um bye guys have a good day
uh in stream okay so end stream