dr. ha when he's okay
Sonia deg
that's wonderful
I wound up in your shotgun thank you huh
I need EEG Shenzhen what about him you
know how can you million son son Katie
speed towards when seeking Sanyo GE girl
there's a John De Anza turned intruder
she was angel Megan engine Walla poor
sunbong engine has your castle fun son
Susan loses in summary I'm Gretchen she
who maintained alouicious sweet you and
your idiot son - aha
Yuri : banker younger than Wong had
contended and she's a citizen
sorry Leo the Year neo quoi oh do do
the yen Jesse yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
deep at failure yet this TG so the party
had door we also Emacs sorry okay so
Emacs Johnny Emacs Johnny Emacs this
Johnny such a fidget reason Shanda
Sheamus Sheamus take some social though
some start up Syrian song song chicken
down then could what
Emacs that's link the hope is very small
off
no it's good Chris I once sent your
Julius bär bad wisdom essentially was
Bob Anna in way in Kansas young same yet
Kwanzaa
angel even questioned or even worse
leaguer and yet through this game Jana
Jana and or agender young Emacs
kiona okay Johnny man England eurozone
insist on yo sharing when did she wait
you just say occasion Johnny machine
when you shall shout you shall become
fascist
Ayana another YouTube turn filter
good good good
mmm yo yo yo yo gonna do yet your new
yoyo
then the hearty chilled water so anyway
if you are some talking Chinese in his
episode yeah Sheila Sheila Sheila GI
million billion no Joe singlet amudha
Daniel Doheny hi mrs. Marion talking she
wired the window clients and war good
some good yeah
I only hazard war meaning and cousin why
answer since since agenda you can't say
I was a girl we can share okay okay not
okay
you would think Megan justesen toe in
time and we've done she Susie okay so
the other one had Joey she had she
nodded Oh a trade war yo man just Emacs
machine one yeah bad just ate green deck
great to see you two being dick strange
echo okay now that should be good I
think
you see um you see I'm trying to do a
Chinese video for this one so you know
but I guess nobody's watching I guess
only you so I guess you know maybe
you'll revert back to english yeah
because the problem right now I my you
know my schedule is that I don't have I
don't have it announced you know if I
announce it you know a few days before
then
people will be prepared to watch my show
hey Deann how are you guys now green tag
is in California right
Who am I using using diem is in TN is in
somewhere Europe a green tech is in
Russia but which city which city in
Russia because yeah so the Russian is
great you know it's a huge land of it's
the is from UK Wow Yekaterinburg who is
that actor in but okay so I think I
guess yeah let's let's just do English
then because you know Chinese people you
know the thing about YouTube on Chinese
is that China they they don't have
YouTube they you know YouTube is
censored so to speak and so you know
Chinese people do they have like what
you know there are 7 billions people in
a world right and China is basically one
fifth of the world's population
let's see yeah you could mean bug okay
let's see
okay there's IPA let's see if I can
pronounce it
chica tearing chica tearing bug okay I
think that's better
nicotine bug now where is it
oh okay it's right here now is it is it
to the left
it's to the right of Moscow right to the
right of Moscow
hey Israel great to see you guys so yeah
I was saying you know YouTube is
censored in China you should look into
using OBS overlay for the YouTube chat
overlay like what you mean overlay you
know I'm I'm using OBS you know and but
I haven't actually tried to spend time
to learn it you know because right now
I'm just using you know I'm just doing
the basics um I haven't really tried to
read the manual so explore it so it's
great to have you guys you know from
different countries UK well where are
you in UK because you know I I always
enjoyed you know different countries
okay so so the eyes from UK Green Tech
is from Russia well Miss Russia is just
amazing Russia
jika jika terrine bug it's okay let's
maybe we should google it i mean google
map yeah google map okay google map
outer rim of London okay yeah I know
there's a London accent I don't like the
London accent so what you boned around
there over you like in different regions
what is that link okay I suppose it's
safe
okay don't post anything that will you
know Google will Pat me okay don't you
know because Google these days UK you
guys may not know but deal may know
because the eye is in UK and Israel is
that did I pronounce it right Israel
dope you know because these days you
have the it's [ __ ] okay we got a troll
wait don't say that man Finch don't say
that because Google is gonna pen why is
not silent so Israel so that's just like
Israel the country right now I thought
you were true Finch how do you pronounce
that pitch pitch pitch in them
okay no yeah okay well it's how to you
know I think we should do it like a
hangout you know some of us regulars to
hang out so each people can speak
chittering bug pronounced like York but
yech
yeah it's it you know it's difficult to
get pronunciation from words I mean even
if you try to guide me I mean that's why
you know the IPA exists phonetics oh yo
use name is not very polite I don't know
what it means but that's okay
Oh sodium doesn't have a make and
doesn't have a can what what ages is you
don't have a Megan you don't have a can
yo you can get Israel oh okay
now what language is that if I CH what
languages them in them oh okay okay it
stopped having those you know because
Google is gonna ban you know Google is
you know starting to sense lots of
things you know for those of you in
Russia or you know in in Europe you know
in UK and in USA and Australia you know
the so-called white people countries you
know in Canada so these days you have
these social justice thing and you know
they start to ban lots of things you
know so that's no good so let's see
Russia Russia is this big place so
Moscow is here so that place must be
somewhere here
oh here it must be very cold there
broken German so are you from German
okay I'll just call you Finch then
because that's an easy pronunciation
Finch okay guys stop typing that yeah we
should get out of this topic
you know south and I because Google yeah
I don't know if you know you you'll get
you maybe you know because Google is
gonna start to ban they're gonna ban all
accounts who you know if you you know if
I create a video and someone makes a
comment and the comment is bad and
they're gonna ban your account as well
so four degrees Celsius okay so green
deck is from here and so big you know
the word it has like seven billion
people you know population yeah like
seven billion word
and Israel is in Israel would population
here 77 billion so Chinese Scot like
world population let's look you know
I've been looking at this world
population since like ten years ago
okay so here we have China as 18% India
China and India they have babies every
day you know most of the Western
countries they stopped having babies
they are declining actually so in
general you know each woman you know you
have to have like how many people you
have to have like two point two children
to sustain the population you know two
point two because two is to replace
yourself and we pay the dad you know mom
and dad
you know mom and dad you're dying so you
have two children but you have to point
to two to maintain the population you
know steady number people because a lot
you know as your children may you know
children may die or have accent
accidents you know so you have to have
to point to children to maintain a
population but in all basically all the
white countries or the industrial
countries not just white countries
including Japan including China they are
I'm not sure about China but in chalk in
Japan for short Japan Canada USA
Australia Europe you know much of Europe
they have decreasing white population
you know because people are not I think
they are not having you are 2.1 okay
pretty sure India has higher yeah but
India is like keep going
India is still you know making babies
and China is also suffering from you
know young people they don't make you
know they don't they don't get they
don't make babies much you don't want to
have children these days you know China
used to have a rule like one you know
you can only have one one child
I mean you can have more but this heavy
tax penalty but now they reversed that
policy so they they actually encourage
people to have children but you know but
you are not sure it's gonna work because
so it's and also you know they are news
about Edison in u.s. I think and other
countries where the sperm count has also
been decreasing the sperm count in Maine
and also you know then you know 77
billion yeah
do they have TV in the East speaking of
accents I love the Yemeni accents hater
general euro so Finch where are you
located
are you in Germany in yeah yeah and
English and we have people more than in
the West we have people older than
thirty still depending on their parents
yeah as of three years ago our sector
has seven kids per woman oh wow so his
Israel is growing so so in Israel he
speak Hebrew and what's the other
language
so Finch Finch Finch were you from what
country so the answer is the answer is
people rather want to sleep on the
pavement to senior song was movie than
to have deal with responsibilities I
heard that I heard that main strides are
a bit of joke in Israel okay wait wait
wait guys Finch
wait it's not getting into that topic
you know yeah you know I would love to
talk about it you know but I don't think
I'm ready you know I don't want to like
become you know I I really love to talk
about it but yeah it's not doing that
yeah so let's this okay
it stuck for something else so are you
are you guys all Emacs users okay yeah
let's talk about random then today
random yeah cuz the ring bug okay that's
interesting City okay I got a bunch of
Chinese Chinese Chinese let's see who is
for the cannon
Emax always look like too many
restrictions here a note alternate side
yeah we would we would we would love
that you know they you know it's getting
serious and we're actually getting back
to the topic you know but it's getting
really serious because serious yeah
because they are banning they are also
banned in people's bank accounts like
this in USA you know they Bank they bang
your bank account as well you know
patreon and and PayPal so you know yeah
yeah and and the the thing about YouTube
is that this basically this note on an
alternative because Google is like you
know like the alternatives they they are
not comparable I mean you have Vimeo you
have you know a few others but YouTube
is like 1000 more than 1000 times
pika you know I use seven ten thousand
times bigger
okay so let's see what else okay so
close that let's go to talk show it's a
talk show I want to talk a let's talk
about YouTube then Sif's
if Jesus at day 11 okay this guy yeah
okay tweet this you know you know I was
looking into this okay okay let me check
this out okay check this man this this
one is funny now let me turn the sounds
we came here
so I'm gonna play it one more time
so she's saying you know this guy
Casa translated northern Myanmar Miami
north of Miami ethnic militias having
really creative ways to recruiting young
Chinese men to go fight something so
here two girls speaking Mandarin in
Chinese standard Chinese Chinese
brothers you want to marry into Miami
with scissors will plan bananas to feed
you
that's what
so okay so there's that you know um I
don't sing so there's that that's a that
stuff that's kind of funny but the thing
is about okay so he is a story so so I I
saw this video right so it's very funny
so I started to look into so Miami so
what country is it and you know
apparently so this is Miami girls they
look like that
and in Miami is like let me show you in
a bit so if we go to Google map again
it's over here it's like in here it's
this this country so I looked it's
pretty big it's pretty big Obama yeah
Palma is much more familiar name but for
political reasons they change the name
to Miami Burma is much more familiar so
and so I you know so I looked into
Wikipedia you know I looked into the
country it's extremely poor you know
it's they are very extremely poor and
okay let me show you so so so I'm saying
in my American readers this is a
opportunity to learn about Burma read
Wikipedia see maps it's people street
photos girls and yelling crystally
inclined its language and design writing
system so let's see but okay so
apparently Burma is a troubled country
its health its health ranks one 45th in
a world one of the biggest wealth gap by
its people and and is in ethnic civil
war then
oh yeah and you know apparently UK
invent invaded it somehow I'm glad that
okay
and there's also Chinese permit on that
one bunnies war nineteen six 1765 okay
that's long ago okay and and the English
version of Expedia is entirely different
in nature from the Chinese version you
know so that's also interesting that
like for example the sign of Burmese war
77 1765 you know there's an English
article on Wikipedia but also there's a
Chinese version so in in this kind of
articles about what usually you know you
read the Chinese version they are
different you get the different sense
from the English version you know so
that's usually the case in for example
in any war I guess in any war situation
I don't know Burmese ma'am I used to be
called Burma yeah right next to India
yeah where do I sign up
you mean the YouTube okay the
alternative you know so yeah let me
mention I quickly Jordan Pederson and
Dave Rubin they started to create a or
turn
alternative patreon basically so you
know because patreon patreon started to
ban people you know when people they
don't like you know so Jordan Pederson
and Dave Rubin I created they they I
think is still in the process they are
in the process of creating out an
alternative you know patreon you know
donation site site so
you know they Jordan Peterson is making
like 50,000 a month something like that
you know so it's it's like more than
$10,000 a day you know one day you know
just one day mostly just by donations
you know people you know give him money
so he's like you know more than me
immediately you know ten million some
something you know hundred millions Dave
lubing is also not doing bad I'm not
sure exactly how much he makes I mean
you can find out he they talk about it
so they don't hide so but however
because patreon you know did the bad
thing you know they depend people they
don't agree with so debut being and
Jordan Pederson they both quit patreon
like they you know broadcasting on a
video on YouTube you know they just
click you can see they are getting like
you know 50,000 a month but they just
quit you know both of them so they are
very you know that that's very
respectable you know how I heard you how
you call that well they are not that's
true they are not technical because
something if they put resources into
some OSP what do you what does OSP stand
for yeah but that's what I think as well
because they have money I mean they are
not you know engineers but they have
money so they can start you know there
are plenty of programmers willing to
help out and you know
no I don't think open source will walk
you know anything will open sauce you
know you if you're gonna create open so
it's gonna just gonna be a small tiny
group you know you spy you know a few
hackers you know well anyway so Burma so
so I looked you know Obama it's very
poor country and here is their largest
second largest city it looks like that
bloom on and let's see the next picture
and this is this is basically their
highway this is almost the biggest
highway and apparently Burma has a lot
of Nyssa T's but on the northern side
like if you look at Burma like they are
in some kind of Civil War you know
ethnic as a static Civil War but unlike
northern regions like the border with
China many of them are like like Chinese
basically okay let's get back here so so
this is what Burma a Chinese Burma girl
looks like you know that with you know
on a northern side so she's so I spent a
few hours reading about Burma a truly
troubled country the northern and
eastern parts are pretty much Chinese
blood called cocaine people and wah
people and catching people so they are
kind of several different ethnicities
that were originally from China so this
is a catching girl I don't know what
that you know is then okay here's the
interesting thing here here is the
traitor CEO Jack
you know he's like PD and you know BDO
area so you know I thought about you
know how much is it like you know for
example you can imagine yourself making
$100 a day you know most of you make
more than $100 a day if you work you
know as a programmer but then imagine
imagine yourself making $1000 a day
that's a lot you know when you make
$1000 a day in one month you have 30,000
so basically in one month in two months
you can buy a fancy car
you can buy a BMW was you know and you
know that's just in two months you know
so you can make a lot money I mean so
you imagine you know you make $10,000 no
imagine if you make $1000 a day 1,000
USD your day that's a lot now imagine
you make $10,000 a day so in one month
in one month you have $300,000 $300 for
most people that's gonna be like they
have to work for five or six years you
know so people like Jack you know this
jack CEO guy you know so they make a lot
money yeah you know yeah I mean you have
to imagine like how much you're gonna
what you're gonna do with you you know
just imagine if you make $1000 a day
what can you do you know I don't know
about you guys but you have to you know
just imagine for your yourself how you
gonna spend it $1,000 a day you know
because you know if today's you are
tired you know you slept over you sleep
for you know the whole whole day and
tomorrow you have another $1,000 you
know so it comes continuously very fast
you know
so imagine $1000 a day what you're gonna
do so so I thought about it you know
with $1000 a day you know you can die go
anywhere in a world
you live in the most expensive hotel you
know they are less than $1000 day so you
you can live in any any hotel most
expensive ones you want and you can get
any girl you want you almost you know
basically unless they are also you know
very rich you know any girls on the
streets you know because for most people
you know the money talks you know
especially for girls you know they you
have money they follow you they you know
you know people especially you know if
for people in poor countries you know
they'd have to you know they they do
anything for you for a thousand dollars
but you you have like a thousand dollars
a day so you can you know have any girls
you want you know so it doesn't after
where I guess it doesn't is it's nothing
it's not something you think about it so
and you of course with one thousand
dollars a day you can have almost any
cost you want you don't like okay so
basically that's the idea so you know so
anyway so there's this guy Jack let's
see
okay here here is this guy Jack okay
hold on a second yeah so let's look at
his treat treat its opening it up so is
this guy Jack so he says for my birthday
this year I did a ten day silent
Vipassana meditation this time in
Pyongyang
Oh wing mama you know Burma we went into
silence on the night of my birthday the
19th and here's what I know
so he went to burn Burma to do some sort
of meditation you know this this rich
Western white people you know their life
is like too comfortable then then they
start to you know they get interested in
Asian you know meditation and stuff you
know there's a lot Hollywood stars they
are into Tibetan Buddhism you know you
know this is like it's quite city then
so here's traitor CEO Jack he did a
10-day silent
bapak sauna meditation some kind of
special meditation know the super-rich
are always into that which to reach so
rich rich to the ball with pleasure
now you needed a sage of Eastern
meditation a tenday exotic passage you
know these people if they anyway so here
here's you know here's what he did the
jack guy so Jack went to Burma and you
know so he's talking about his
experience you know
meditation is often thought of as coming
relaxing and detox of all the noise in a
world that's not beep out
Vipassana it's extremely painful and
demanding physical and mental work I
wasn't expecting any of that in my first
time last year even tougher this year I
went deeper but anyway so he says I did
meditation and Dhamma something
something something this is my room
basic during the 10 there is no devices
reading no writing physical exercise
physical exercise music intoxicants no
meat no talking or even eye contact with
others it's free everything is given to
meditators by charity you know so I you
know I find you know these people are
sick you know which so rich they have
become sick their life is you know they
become so rich that they they kind of
need somehow they find this attraction
you know to like no devices and you know
no eye contact
what the [ __ ] is this and you know look
at this face he stayed it's like you
know it's a poor you know place right so
yeah so you have this very super rich
guy and you know his birthday he's doing
this for 10 days it's like did you know
this is like to him it's like a vacation
you know because these people are you
know you you eat you know the most
extreme you know it's like a Emperor you
know in you know a few hundred years ago
it would be like Emperor because you you
are basically the most weak riches in
the world you can have anything you want
so they started to fancy you know they
you know like poor people's life they
started to fancy it in some way but
however of course they are not willing
to give up
money it's easy now if you're really
tired of being rich you just you know
like it's extremely easy to give away
all your money and make no money from
from now on but that's not what they
want to do they want to do this 10-day
you know like ten-day exotic secluded
you know some kind of meditation
like connection with Bhutan you know and
also interesting is that it's not like
the Christian the Western thing they'd
specifically want the exotic like Asian
you know they they like the Asian thing
why because it's exotic because they
don't know [ __ ] about Buddhism so anyway
so look I mean it's a story so you look
at so he did this then okay he talked
about okay here's what it looks like you
know outside okay and imagine you know I
I would imagine you know these rich
people like this going to places like
this you know this face is they they are
very happy to have him you know all
polite and welcome you know and and
obviously you know he pays them a lot of
money but okay look at this okay I'm
gonna read the commenting of it then
look at this the second day was my best
I was able to focus entirely on my
breath with no thoughts for over an hour
the most I could do before that was five
minutes
oh so focused entirely on my breath with
our thoughts for open an hour the most I
could do before that was five minutes I
see
so now he can do that for one hour day
six was my worst as I caught a nasty
cold going around the center couldn't
sleep from then on but pushed through it
till the end so okay so he had ten days
of
of some kind of meditation you know then
look at this look at this one on day 11
oh I wanted to do was listen to music
and I again turned to my favorite poet
Kendrick Lamar and his album damn the
greatest effect coming out of silence is
the clarity one has in listening every
note stands alone okay so on tenth day
eleven his meditation you know
meditation is done so he listened to
music and his favorite poet is this guy
and his album damn so I looked I checked
out you know what what is this album so
it turns out so it's a rap you know it's
a rap song and it's like typical rap
it's cancer you know cancer rap you know
the rap songs are filled with violence
can you know cops you know gun kill
girls you know like [ __ ] you know then
that's what they the black people call
them [ __ ]
Oh or shorty so yeah on day 11 he so he
calls this rapper you know this well
literally filthy you know violence
killing people guns and you know girls
he calls at poet and he is listened to
it it's like oh so great so I'm think so
you know so what do you think of this
you know I to me so it's like is this
this Jack guy is a sick rich sick [ __ ]
you know he's you know he's like
becoming too rich to you know to us he
has become a very strange out of touch
with the world and very strange but
however in his head you know he said
he's one of the people who like to pan
you know different you know he's like
one of the social justice people okay
yeah so you know so rich you have to do
meditation like some exotic meditation
then on day 11 you know once you know as
soon as you get get out of this you know
in touch-ups with some kind of Buddha
you know meditation then you listen to
rap you know like violence and blood so
it's like so in this one day you you
kind of unten or the meditation you've
done you know what the [ __ ] you doing
meditation for you know Buddhism you
know his Buddhism is is you know it's
like it's a religion okay well it's it's
different from Western religion but
Buddhism you have deep for example
Buddhism you know there are many
branches of Buddhism but but that's one
thing they share you know basically the
most Oh Buddhism is that you are you
know you are not materialistic and you
do you don't you do not do violence okay
you you've they say you give up or
materialistic things you clean your
thought you make no enemies you you have
no emotions okay you don't even marry
you know like you know a monk you know
you don't you don't have sex you know
you clear out your thoughts like that
that's that's what Buddhism teaches you
know that that's what Buddhism supposed
to be you know meditation so this this
rich [ __ ] he has to go to you know some
exotic poor country to do ten days some
kind of severe meditation on day 11 he's
like listening a rap violent rap song I
went I went to listen to the album you
know some songs you know I'd look at the
lyrics because I have written a few
articles about rap songs and their
lyrics you know it typically is very
violent and demeaning to you know women
in and all that
yeah so so this guy is doing that and
look look at look at his photo
okay he's you know in this one house you
know so so I happened you know I happen
to be looking at Burma in the country
just like few days ago few days before
you know the the Jack you know doing his
thing and you know then you look at the
place you know this imagined the Puma is
such a full country this this face is
not not cheap you know to the Puma
people but the Puma locals probably in
the not in their life they can live in a
house like this in one day and here he
is you know have this you know house all
him or to himself so this is Puma this
these things are called stupa by the way
so boomer yeah Buddha you know if you
ever visit Asia countries Japan or China
or Taiwan or South Asia like Burma you
see lots of Buddhas okay and here is a
video where let's pray that let's pray
that I'm gonna read the comments after I
pray this video so let's
okay
that video is kind of long two minutes
okay I missed all the comments oh my god
someone someone has some anyone like
that I wanna let it end up at the end
the work going on I didn't even know man
I swear yo guys guys an agreement so the
Chinese are asking me where is Chinese
where is my Chinese show so I switched
to the English OH
so so next time I'm going to yeah next
time I'll do a Chinese thing yeah
someone chances chances that someone
okay so so let me check out the comments
so anyway that's the story of Jack you
know I don't I don't like I don't think
he's a good guy you know so he's so you
know so you know he tells the story here
and he's with this guru some kind of
guru you know so you know why why do you
think these people do that this is you
typically white rich white people okay
so from what I see you know from what I
see so they do it it it it kind of like
it kind kind of like helped their mind
you know they makes them make them think
that they are good person you know
because they are they have so much money
they do so much bad things to put to to
prepare their company you know treated
do all sort of nasty you know the most
nasty massive scale things - why for one
one go to make money you know everything
treated us the design even the but color
of the button the size of a button is
specifically designed with with a group
of psychologists to make you you know
Creek or stay on Twitter everything you
know I know because it is and also there
are a lot of articles you know you
I don't know if you guys know that well
so you know these rich people they have
done so many bad things so when they do
this they feel like you know go to this
kind of meditation you know like like if
they are in touch with you know Buddha
you know what some kind of spiritual
spiritual painting so that they they
feel that it makes them feel that that
you know they are good people you know
it helps them to believe that they are
they are the good guys
his [ __ ] you know look at this
picture so he's showing a picture of his
leh lake being bitten by mosquito why
because he has to stay in this cave
you know the whole night or something so
he is bitten by mosquito and he has to
do that because he's you know he's some
kind of part of the meditation so he's
like showing a picture you know oh look
you know I've gotten bitten by
mosquitoes so it's some kind of like
atonement almost like you know these
people they need to do this so that they
can forgive themselves they can forgive
that you know then they come back of
course they come back to America and -
and make money you know do the nasty
things and look yeah so you know look
with his watch monitoring heartbeat and
stuff [ __ ] [ __ ] yeah he's you
know he's got all the technology he
still has to monitor his heartbeat and
stuff then he you know this crap needs
people you know he's you know you you
become something you know when you are
when you are you know when you are rich
okay does even some people are born rich
you know they like like they are
pointing to a rich family you cannot
blame them because you know
they just they were born rich and some
people are not I'm not I think I don't
think Jackie is born rich but anyway
well I talk about a lot of things it's
this quickly scan of comments let's see
what's a that's a lot to read money kill
brain cells exactly that's that's the
exactly good point
can't go hey Krypto my issue with crypto
is based on true for work huh you are
going to get yourself banned from
YouTube where the work is literally
useless since I think so I think how
long have been talking today money cure
brain cells the more money you have the
less of your brain you need then you end
up like a hairy Hollywood actor yeah
exactly
Hollywood actor are extremely bad green
deck says well you can buy happiness
with money
yeah that's what that's not I mean
that's not 100% true though I mean it is
uh-huh you know money doesn't make you
happy but at least you know but but but
being being poor being very poor will
make you unhappy you know that's part of
it as well if you know how to handle it
Danes good kind of like fire yeah I
disagree politely
it may not be directly okay well I mean
about happiness you know nobody can say
the final answer I mean that's complex
thing you know I you know I've been
reading books about happiness like how
to be happy for example I remember
Bertrand Russell
wrote a book about happiness I say the
book Oh a bunch of articles I forgot but
Bertrand Russell did so Dion says I
think Jackie celaya
he went and took a few photos of a dummy
room and posted a bunch of stupid lies
on his account that he knows we will
make the right people have the idea I
don't think those are fake I mean III
don't think he's a good guy but I don't
think this photo I mean it's not fake
right I mean he's I'm pretty sure he's
actually there and he actually seriously
tried to do the meditation George Kogan
II ha Sakuni ha ha ha ha ha ha stealing
hotel eating expensive food
that's on a big channel huh being so
what do you guys doing so what let's see
what time is in UK in UK it's 3 o clock
in the afternoon and in Russia Moscow is
like 6 o clock in afternoon being a good
way
okay we're gonna get banned oh god you
guys gonna get me bad okay I got so many
comments now I cannot follow so you know
I was watching Tim for you know some of
these popular people you know when they
talk about you know when they have a
life you know stream they'll come and
just fly by like they have 10,000
viewers you know they come just fly by
okay what else is interesting
I missed you know it's like yeah I guess
you know if one cannot really I mean if
we only have few people then I can read
comment and while I was talking but in
general when when there's a lot of
people you know I cannot you know keep
reading the comments I mean what I mean
is that it's probably natural you know
because you know for YouTube livestream
it's not natural to read all the
comments because there are so many signs
also on there yeah I'm also master Dan
yeah Master Dan is open source
distributed federated microblog a
so-called micro blogger but there are
not many people there actually you know
sure so let's see how they are other
links I should show the [ __ ] okay okay I
think that's maybe that's it for today
we're joined soon
cheers guys Cheers
for my channel Oh what do you mean we
oh you mean like Tom Esther then one of
you found out there okay yeah so you
know see you guys hey George George
George Sneha George yeah shots a chance
to knowing good and strong wonder what's
one Bay easier shot knowing that some
wonder yeah let me talk yeah let me wrap
it up so see you guys out talks in
Chinese a bit then we'll say goodbye and
someone that it's a Shanda and good
someone and someone does someone I wish
I'd known the pilly pilly pilly para que
tal Fonda even YouTube side our home
video so you should share the want is
YouTube YouTube fun so YouTube know know
how to untie one Shang Gong what does
make what is someone cake
taru doesn't chew chew Peter Hamby a
tensile soup was jobs and non cheat
someone the the entire associate are
would you eat are wasn't war to hide
wallet
so he non someone tena eating no
Shanghai PD PD no that's a pity pity
rouhani watching are young we also see
hama watch enemy Yami Sochi so he went
easy on the Sochi how about you Damon
George Iola shi shi da da da