Good morning.
Good morning. Welcome to another
fantastic day. Today is 2021.
December 20th.
November, December, December is correct.
And uh how are you guys?
So today so topics so where is this
Vi at Vi at something guy who has a
topic today
and uh you know, if you guys haven't
already post a topic, you know, in the
topic notes. Okay, so today I'm going to
talk randomish and uh there is a guy who
wants to talk about Chinese input
system. So I'm going to show you Chinese
input system.
You know, and and you know, I'm going to
explain it so that you can actually type
Chinese, you know, just for fun. So but
you know, so before we can begin, Vi Q
so I'm waiting, you know, for that guy
to say this stuff. Topic tiling windows
managers.
That topic is a uh
beaten horse. It's a dead horse.
So speaking of that, let me tell you
about this thing, okay? When you buy a
keyboard, you know, I got several so
it's going to be random randomish today
and post your comments and questions,
okay? So let's uh pop this out.
Uh pop out chat
so that I can
I can
uh see you guys, okay?
So
dead horse, you know, uh tiling windows
managers it's a dead beaten horse. Uh
what
keyboard, let's go to keyboard and let
me show you key bindings keys, okay?
There are keys on the keyboard. You
know, today it's very common when you
buy a laptop or when you buy a keyboard,
you will see this
FN key. Okay, now I have an article on
that. Let's see where.
Okay, I don't have a dedicated article
on that [ __ ]
You know, that's one of the things to
do. Um
you know, I need to move. It's written
there's an article about the FN key.
Now, if you if you are not familiar with
what's the FN key I'm talking about, let
me show you, okay? So, it's actually not
here.
But, I'm going to
tell you about it.
Okay, so let's let's tell you about it,
okay? So, hello flip. Hello Okay, so
FN key. When you buy a keyboard, let's
see. Let me show you, okay? So,
so today, yesterday, I bought a Mac.
Now, I'm rich. I bought a Mac. This is
Apple's M1 chip MacBook.
MacBook Air. It's fantastic. You can you
know, and macOS, you know, is just 10
times better than Windows. And Linux is
worst, okay? In terms of user interface,
the operating system user interface
design, Mac
Mac is better than Windows
by far, by a magnitude. Now, in in my
past few videos, I have, you know,
recently in this month, I have explained
how sucky is the Microsoft Windows
operating operating system. You know,
you have lots of picture Windows and
lots of things problems. On On the other
hand, the Mac has always been the best
uh user interface design, at least.
And my
the Mac Apple's hardware is usually
actually better quality than Windows as
well. So, the Mac is usually just
better. Better in just about every way,
except except you have to pay almost
twice for
for anything Mac for the same power, for
the same
uh memory, uh you know, RAM. But,
anyway, it's just superior, okay? That's
That's how people That's how they, you
know, Apple makes money. They
They make highest quality stuff. Now,
especially, I want to focus on the user
interface design because hardware it's
easy to see, but the user interface
design
Apple is just supreme. Since 1990 Since
1990s, my first Mac is uh
uh is a Mac 2si. Uh I bought it in 1991
when I was a student. Anyway, so
So, we have a lot of topic to talk
about. So, and you know, you see this
function key here, fn, you see? That is
no good, okay? That function key began
about late 2000s, okay? That function
key that's a
That key that function key, fn
And uh okay, let me show you some of
them.
So, you go to So, let's talk about
function keys. So, let's go to start
talk talk show and uh open that, and
here's today's talk show notes, and uh
let's first topic, first stop, talk
about function keys.
The fn key
uh
dead
holes
squatting
in your front yard.
Okay.
That's what That's what that fn key is,
okay?
Okay, so let's begin to go you know, let
me show you uh talk about function keys.
Then, I'm going to talk about
uh talk about the M1 chip
and uh MacBook.
Air, which which is what I got, okay?
It's fantastic.
Um and then
Where's the guy who wants to talk about
the Chinese stuff, the Chinese input
system?
Come here and post it [ __ ] I hate it
when that happens when
you know, people, you guys want me to
talk about something, but you don't show
up. It's like you don't like nobody
cares. I don't want that, okay? You you
come to seek Sarta Show because you
like it. Otherwise, don't watch it. You
like it, you want to hear my opinions or
you know, it's not necessarily true that
you
agree with what I say, but you come here
to you know, to watch the show. So, when
I do some when I ask you you know, for a
topic, you want to see see something,
you come here and say it.
Okay, so
anyway, comments and questions, post it,
okay? So, uh so
I want to talk about the FN key and the
the Apple's M1 chip. It's just
fantastic, okay? And maybe about Chinese
input system, okay?
So, that's the thing. Um that's the
thing and and and okay, so so first
stop, FN key, okay?
Let me show you some of the FM FN key
that begin to become popular around 2010
or something. So, let's go to normal
keyboard.
I want to show you a massive number of
them, the FN key example. The the the
the keyboard maker that
is found of FN key is Logitech, okay?
Logitech always you know, their keyboard
always have the FN key.
So, here you are looking at the Logitech
keyboard. Okay, this is uh is this
doesn't have FN key. You know, this is
collection of Logitech non-gaming
keyboard. That's important because
gaming keyboard is a different story,
okay? But Logitech non-gaming keyboard,
you see, there is there FN key, and they
color it yellow, okay? I think it I
think maybe Logitech began it, okay?
They began when
2010, okay? Maybe around that. So, there
it is, FN key.
There it is, FN key now in blue, you
know, background color. There it is, FN
key, yellow. There it is, FN key,
Logitech non-gaming keyboard. There it
is, FN key,
blue.
There it is, you see? So, Logitech is
is probably the the one or the one who
made it popular, the FN key. The the FN
key sucks donkey ass. Why? Because
you know, what's the FN key doing? You
know, they are trying to save money. You
know, they they are keyboard makers, so
they save money by having a virtual key,
FN key, another modifier key. You know,
those those of you 40% idiots love that,
you know? So,
so, you know, modifier key. So, Logitech
created the FN key to save the number of
keys they have to
physically make, you know, so reduce
their production cost.
So, they they put this FN key, then if
you want to volume up, you hold down the
FN, then then you press one of these
other keys, usually the
F1, F2, you know, the function the
function keys.
So, you know, they do that.
And also, the FN key, that's not all,
okay? Let me show you a big picture
where we can see the FN key. That's not
all.
You know, so
so now, if If want to volume up or
control sound sound level up or sound
level down, you have to hold another key
to do it.
Like before, you just press one key. Now
you have to hold a key and press another
key. [ __ ] idiot. You know, most most
of the Linux tiling window managers,
that's you guys.
That's That's the same situation.
Um
FN key, okay? So,
that's no good. And they What they do
that they save they save production
cost. You see? Because more keys on the
keyboard they cost them more money. So,
they can Now they you know, they save
money. And then the marketing comes in.
They will say, "Oh, we provide, you
know, the the the all these multimedia
keys." But actually they don't. That's a
virtual thing. That's a virtual thing.
Virtual thing like like the you know,
tiling windows managers, the virtual
desktop, the virtual screen, the virtual
space. Idiocy.
You know, so
you know, like I like like a oh,
virtual. You know, that idiocy. You
know, so virtual means that you spend
you have to actually put more energy.
It's not real. You know, it it doesn't
exist.
So,
so this FN key is not good. You rather
you know, you want a keyboard that has
volume up and down the buttons by
themselves, okay? You don't want this
this modifier. [ __ ]
And also,
once you have that, you know, suppose I
bought this keyboard, you know,
10 years, you know, from 2010 to 2020 I
was
uh I was about to die of hunger in
America, okay? So, I don't have money to
buy keyboard. I have like I bought one
keyboard for 10 years. One mouse.
Uh the the you know, for 10 years, you
know? How did I start to write all these
articles about keyboard and mouse? You
are looking at my keyboard right away.
Kinesis Advantage 2. That's this one. I
got it three. Okay, I don't have money
to buy.
But I do so many so many so many
reviews. They they send me to review it.
So this is
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard. I have
reviews here.
So for 10 years I don't have money to
buy. So but you know, I need a keyboard
because I type more than any anyone in
the world, okay? Almost basically the
top 100
you know, sitting front of computer for
the in the past 10 years. So I started
to read, you know, when I when I'm very
poor, I don't have money like you Huang,
like you Huang.
You know, I want to buy a keyboard. But
before I buy, you know, I read reviews.
You know, you know, I was thinking, oh I
maybe I need this key I need you know,
because my hand hurts right now like
right now.
My hand, I showed this many times before
right now here. You know, every few
years there's a different problem and
and right now it's this problem. So I I
take this ball.
This is this ball soothe this my hand,
okay?
Oh, you cannot see it, okay? So
So I take this ball.
Okay, you can you can you see it, okay?
Right here. Right now it hurts. So I do
this. Knock it. It feels good. RSI,
repetitive strain injury, okay?
Or I
uh hit it with my fist, okay? Right
here. I have an article on my
you know, just search for Ksa Li RSI.
You'll see a entire history of my 30
years history of typing and RSI stories.
Because every time I have a RSI I log
it. I write in detail how you know, when
what's the symptom, which finger is
painful, you know, you know, I write
down the whole detail. I log it. And
eventually, you know,
how do I solve that, you know, how did I
find out what's the problem exactly? Is
it my keyboard I'm using a work I'm
using a good night what what's the
problem? Uh then, you know, so just
search for it. Okay, let me show you.
Sorry RSI, okay? So, RSI uh
there, my typing RSI experience, okay?
Now, this is Now, this part Now, you are
looking at the ball RSI hand exercise
toys. So, you have these
you have these uh
Chinese IM ball, okay? And where is my
Where is my clutch? It's over there.
Okay, should I choose to get it?
There it is.
Now, I haven't done this for a long
time. So, you get these hand exercise
toys.
Okay, so copy that. Go back to Emacs and
look at my efficient
typing system. So, we
You know, there's there's a lot I'm
going to talk about, okay? So, first of
all, copy the links here. Delete that.
Go here. Go here. Go here.
Where's my Logitech keyboard?
Uh
Logitech keyboard. Go back here. We
going to talk about this one and each
one of them. Okay?
So, um
hand exercise toys. So, let me show you.
So, you So, you buy this this good for
your hands, okay? Several So, and
juggling I have my I haven't seen my me
juggling
It's been a long time since I juggle I I
juggle since I was 7 16 in Montreal.
Um
So, these are good things you can buy if
you have RSI to exercise your hands.
This is good, juggling balls and pen
twirling.
Pen spin spinning, okay? So, you can see
There it is.
You can see it on my video and also real
time here.
Comments and questions, okay? So, pen
spinning, copy it.
Then, I'm going to show you
Um so, these are good things you want to
buy if you have RSI. And And this is
article where I
I detail since 1988
about my experiences with keyboard, with
typing, beginning with a electric
typewriter up to up to today. So, one of
the incident, the latest, right now I
suffer from it, and it looks likely I'm
going to be stuck with it, okay?
Be uh that that is permanent, you know,
because I'm getting old. So, I'm going
to have permanent kind of pain
here. And also, unfortunately, I also
damaged my
uh ring finger I talked about in my past
two videos also. So, let me show you the
um
You see? So, I I put a uh Salonpas, you
know, that how you call that thing.
That's You know, this pad, that's
essentially a pain killer. So,
you know, you put that there, you know,
it's a pain killer. You know, I I I
could use one. I don't like to put those
on because I
prefer
some sort of natural healing, you know,
but anyway. So,
this is the incident, okay? This is This
is the instant in incident beginning in
you know, it's fully document documented
here beginning in 2018.
And why does that happen? I have a
detail.
It's because I pressed the three key
here on this keyboard too much. This
three key. Anyway, anyway.
So,
So, let's go back. So, let's go back to
the FN key. So, FN key is no good. Okay,
that's a dead hole.
That's
I explained why it's no good because
it's virtual and it's you know, it save
them cost. So, it's good for them, the
manufacturers, but it's not good for
you, the user. Okay.
So, and most people, the Linux idiots,
you know, they they like telling Windows
managers and the Emacs users and you
know, they talk about one river about
how you should, you know, which keyboard
is better or blah blah blah blah blah
but they they never they never complain
about this. They don't see it. They
don't they don't know. They don't know.
So, this FN key So, when you buy a
keyboard, this is the thing to watch
out. And first of all, you want a
mechanical key, okay? Mechanical key
switch.
So, but it's not all, okay? Besides
being virtual, there's another thing.
So, oh yeah. So, let me tell you the
story why I started to write
keyboard blog.
Why do I have
500 articles about keyboard? Not 500,
about 300, okay?
Why do I have 300 keyboard about
300 articles about keyboard?
First of all, how many articles? Let's
see. So, you are looking at PowerShell
and you are looking at the Microsoft
terminal, the new application.
Fantastic.
So, PowerShell, let's go to uh
web xahlee.info.
That's right.
What?
CD web
xahlee.info.
Then, let's go to keyboard, okay? Duh.
Now, let's find out how many articles I
have. Let's try the Okay. Now,
the
recurse
file
include
Mhm.
include .html
and
s-
private tool
measure object.
Okay? So, I have
847.
Jesus. What?
Do I have actually that many articles
about
keyboards?
Whoa, that's
Wait. That's surprising. Did I do this
right? Uh
Okay, there's a bug about this
uh
terminal. Okay, so, let's
So, I have 800 articles on keyboard.
Wow, I didn't know that.
Clear screen. Let's do it again.
I don't think it's 800.
Well,
anyway, so, let's go to um
Let's go to keyboard and go to the
directory. In Emacs, I can trust you Oh,
I do have 800.
I do have 800 articles on keyboard.
So, why do I have so many articles on
keyboard? Because
beginning in 2010, I was so poor, but I
needed new keyboard. So, but I wasn't
sure and you know, I want to make sure I
buy the right keyboard, the cheapest
possible, the most efficient, you know,
I I want the
the keyboard to be the highest quality
and the most feature rich, you know, the
way I want it with function keys or
whatever criterion. But, I also want it
to be the as cheap as possible. So, I
start to read reviews, you know, as you
know, because I need one keyboard, okay?
I don't have money. $30, that's too
much. $30 is one is 10 days of living
expense expense, okay? $30 because I'm
dying of hunger. You know, I have I you
know, I'm hungry.
Like really hungry.
I don't have 50 cents to buy a banana.
Okay?
Like 50 cents, I don't have it. And I'm
very hungry. I'm about to die.
That is 2010 to 2020, okay? But I
because I also, you know, do computers,
I need a keyboard. I want to buy I don't
have $30. $30 is my like
10 days living expense, okay?
So, I read reviews, you know, one day,
you know, that's enough. I read another
day.
You know, few days becomes a month.
Then I haven't decided yet. I'm still
unsure. Oh, but this one or that one
that you know, I looked at I looked at I
read all reviews on Amazon, you know,
each of these keyboard you can read all
the you know, usually hundreds of
reviews. I read them all.
Okay, that's what I know about keyboard.
So, you Linux telling Windows man, shut
the [ __ ] up, okay?
So, I I you know, I read and I I write.
I write what I have I've read, you know,
a comparison, you know, then then few
months becomes a year.
I have still haven't decided. I don't I
don't have money. I haven't decided
which keyboard I want I need I I can
buy. Why do I have that problem? When
you don't have that money, when you
don't have money, you have that problem.
You know, it's relative to how much how
much you make. Like many of you,
you know, programmers for example, you
know, you might think about, "Oh, should
I buy a Tesla? You know, which model?
What color? Or maybe I should buy
another, you know," then you decide, you
know, maybe you are unsure for a week,
then for a month you are unsure to buy a
car.
You know, that that means, you know,
that's the amount of money relative to
you, you know.
So, for me, that's the keyboard, okay?
For other rich people, maybe it's a
house, or maybe it's an entire building,
or it's an island like the Mark
Zuckerberg, the Facebook [ __ ] You
know, he he maybe he's undecided. Should
I buy this island or should I buy that
island? Oh, I have to compare, you know.
Yeah.
So, I started to read keyboard reviews
and, you know, becomes a month, becomes
a year, becomes 10 years. And pretty,
you know, pretty it becomes 10 years.
So, that's why
I have
800 articles about keyboard, okay?
So, that's that's that's a digression.
So, let's go to keep let's go to talk
show.
Uh show and uh
So, that's about why do I have 300
articles about keyboard. Now, let's
about let let's get back to the function
keys. Why is it not good, okay? Function
keys.
So, eventually, you know, so I bought a
keyboard, you know, so I you know, so
what's my history of keyboard? I can
show you, okay?
Uh let's see.
So, Ergo keyboards, you actually you
have to go to keyboard history, okay?
So,
so actually go to
ergonomic keyboard history.
So,
this one I have, this one I bought
around 2009,
okay? It's like $15, okay? And it broke,
eventually it broke.
It This is one of the best keyboard, but
it has a some sort of static
static electricity problem, so it so
that when you type, the key doesn't
work. You have to whack it, this
keyboard, literally. You take it up and
whack it, smack it. Then it works again.
Uh this is a well-known problem for this
keyboard because a lot people, you know,
you search the web, you'll find a lot of
people talking about it.
And a lot people, you know, contacted me
before. This is pretty old, you know, 10
years ago. So, a lot people contact me
to how to solve this problem. So,
anyway, so this is one of You see? So,
here is my Amazon.
Oh, no, no. Now Now this keyboard become
$100. It was a It was $15, okay?
So, this is one of the first one I have,
then I have
this one. This one is my workhorse,
okay? I bought it in 2005, okay?
Um
then then then I have, let me show you,
okay? So, then I have So, this is you
see all the reviews, my opinions, like
just like you have opinions, 1,000
you know,
100,000 words opinions about each every
aspect of this keyboard, the
arrangements of the home and key cluster
and so on.
I wrote it down.
Uh and uh then
I got this one in 2006. Wait, I
Yeah. No, I didn't buy it, You know, you
see
I write a review in 2006,
but I wrote I actually bought this
keyboard in 2012
or something. You see? Because I need a
keyboard, but I don't have money. So, I
read the reviews. I read all the reviews
sucked them up.
But eventually I got this in 2000 what?
2010 or something. I must you know, I
have the detail here probably somewhere.
And then
you know, and back then I don't have I
don't have a camera to take photos, you
know, so
so I
a lot of photos are from, you know,
other people's website. I spent hours
like not that just hours, days days
after day to search for the photos. For
example, this photo is not mine. This
photo is from a Amazon reviewer.
So, I I took their photo and I give
credit. And so, you know, I traced who
is the guy who posted the photo and it's
this guy, okay? He's a he's actually a
Chinese guy who is into photography.
Let's turn on JavaScript, refresh, and
let's see what is he
You know, anyway, I don't know who he
is, but you know, so
this photo is is from him and so is this
one.
Um
and there it is. Paul Graham, the guy
who began the eat the Common Lisp expert
and Common Lisp hater. You know, he
hates Common Lisp. You know, for you
this is for you Common Lisp fans because
fanaticism, the cult of the languages
and the open source.
So,
Paul Graham is a Common Lisp expert, but
he is the most devout Common Lisp hater,
okay? Now, if you are a Lisp coder,
maybe you don't know. Maybe you
What is he talking about? That's false.
Okay, let me show you
where, okay?
So, you go to my website
Xah Lee code xahlee.info. Then you go to
um
Xah on Lisp, okay? I'm going to
reinventing wheels by using macros.
That's what Lisp people are doing.
So,
so Common Lisp, okay? So, let's see
where is the article where
Paul Graham, the creator of Hacker News,
Y Combinator, he
criticized a lot about Common Lisp,
okay? So, let's see where is it?
Is this syntax readable? What does
symbolic language mean? Can Lisp macro
change Lisp syntax? Okay, all these
topics are the hot things these people
talk about.
Uh okay, there. Famous programmers on
how Common Lisp sucks.
Okay?
Uh yeah, so open that.
So, you see Guy Steele badmouths Common
Lisp. Richard Stallman badmouths Common
Lisp. You can read it for the details.
So, let's copy it. So, let's put it back
to the
to the topics we talk about.
Uh
Rodney Brooks, I don't know who he is.
Richard P. Gabriel is a
another All these are Lisp experts,
okay? All these are Common Lisp the
greatest Common Lisp not just any Common
Lisp expert, okay? All these people on
this page are the I would say the top 10
Common Lisp
programmer Common Lisp expert in the
entire history of human animal history,
okay? These people. And they are saying
Common Lisp sucks, okay? For you Lisp
[ __ ] idiots.
Okay, so Richard Stallman said that
about how Common Lisp he doesn't like he
doesn't like Common Lisp. Richard
Gabriel P Richard P. Gabriel is the guy
who created
Uh he's got a company. What's the
company name? I forgot. But he the
company is most famous for creating
XEmacs, okay? You might not even know
what that is, but
XEmacs is the first schism in open
source. Emacs versus GNU Emacs versus
XEmacs. It's a big schism, okay?
Richard P. Gabriel Uh you know, he's you
know, one of the prominent Common Lisp
you know, he's also you know, you know,
big names, okay? You guys you know, it
Now, it's pretty you know, they are
pretty old. He's maybe 70 or 80
something.
Richard Gabriel and I've exchanged a
email or two with Richard P. Gabriel.
And he's also famous for writing
uh
Worse is better, okay? The concept Worse
is better, okay? That's the That's the C
and Unix. Worse is better. We don't
really care about proper desire. It just
make it run. Just make it fast. That's
That's C and Unix. Just make it simple.
Make it portable. C and Unix. Worse is
better.
That's him, okay?
Richard P. Gabriel. That's from his
article about
about how to spread Lisp or something.
But you can There you know, you can find
you know, you know, follow the links,
okay? Peter Gabriel.
Then there is there is it is Paul
Graham, okay? Historically, Lisp has
been good at letting hackers have their
way. The political correctness of Common
Lisp is a aberration.
Early Lisps let you get your hands on
everything, okay? That's what Paul
Graham says about Common Lisp. And
Daniel Weinreb is the first
person who created Emacs, okay?
Daniel Weinreb, he died about 5 years
ago. He you know, he died um so I have
an article on here. He died in 2012.
This programmer, Daniel Weinreb, died.
And he
he's the first person who created a
uh Emacs, okay? Proper Emacs on what
machine? I forgot.
Okay, but also he challenged, he
corrected, he debunked many of the
things Richard Stallman says about
Emacs. Okay? Richard Stallman, you know,
he has a vision and in in in his passion
for his vision, he
he he bent the truth, you know, he bent
history to the way he like it. You know,
he says, "Oh, those Lisp machine people,
they started a corporation, therefore
they [ __ ] us." You know, so then
then all the Emacs [ __ ] the Emacs
fanatics, that's a typical Emacs, you
know, the
the the the elite Emacs users on the
blog or the websphere, blogosphere, you
see, they all say, "Oh, that's why Emacs
is great."
A [ __ ] lie. A lot of it is, okay?
So, and good and Richard Stallman wrote
an article in one of the Lisp conference
saying that, "Oh, you you know, Lisp
history."
Uh and Richard Daniel Richard Daniel
Weinreb says, "No, you actually that's
false. That's false. What you said is
incorrect history, okay?" So, he
debunked
Richard Stallman's, you know, uh uh
account of this history, MIT, you know,
Lisp machine history. It's a big
history.
You can read about them.
Um
do I have a archive You know, just
follow the links. You you can, you know,
So, he also says
Common Lisp sucks. Okay? Now, this guy,
I don't know who that is actually, and
Jeffrey M. Jacobs, I don't know who that
is. So, I I actually so
I take it back. I don't know who these
two are.
Uh and yeah, I don't know who this guy
is, neither.
So, anyway, so this is the collection of
people, Common Lisp experts, most of
them, who has
who thinks that Common Lisp sucks.
Okay, so
Uh what is that? Leaf photography, okay.
Reopen last one. Reopen last one. Where
did we go?
Yeah, here. Copy that link back to
Emacs. Okay, so we already have it here.
So, that's a digression. That's a
digression about um
about
about the keyboard, this keyboard I'm
talking about, because this Paul Graham
is using it.
Okay. So, this is my, you know, one of
my keyboard. Anyway, so
And after that, after that, it's pretty
much the, you know, I started to use
mechanical keys, you know, I After that,
it's the
truly ergonomic keyboard, okay? So, I
actually it's you go through
you go through Ergo history and you
scroll all the way down. Then after
that, in 2013, I got this one, 2012,
because
he sent it to me.
You know, because by then I already have
lots of keyboard argos. I'm kind of
small, you know, famous on the web. So,
he sent it to me and I love it. It's,
you know, this is a beginning era of
mechanical ergonomic keyboard. The kind
of the beginning craze, you know, then
after this, then ErgoDox came up. That's
a do-it-yourself ErgoDox, then then then
lots of others. Then the whole
mechanical keyboard craze came up.
So, after that
So, in 2012, I got this one. I used it
for like 4 years. Fantastic. This is my
video.
This is me in my poverty. Don't have
nothing.
Uh that's the video, okay? So
So, okay. So, that's that's about my
history of keyboards.
You know, after So, after this, then
after this, you know, then it's Kinesis,
okay?
Then I believe it's this one. Uh in any
case, I have a complete account of it.
Let's see where, okay? Solid keyboard.
So, you can see
you know, of course, some of the
keyboard is not here, but I have a
complete account on what year I started
to use what keyboard. You You see there.
Okay, so it begin with truly ergonomic
in 2012. So, before that
So, this These are programmable
mechanical ergonomic keyboards. So,
before this, you know, then I I was
using the Microsoft I was I talked
about.
Copy that back to Emacs.
Paste it here.
Okay, so what what other topics we want
to talk about?
So, let me digress to these fantastic
regular polyhedra lamps. You know, I
have a fascination of lamps because
lamps
the you know, the device that creates
light
uh is fascinating to me and they and
many of them are beautiful. So, I just
found I took a photo of this one
uh 2 weeks ago or so
when I saw it.
And there are other
math related photos I kind of collect.
Beautiful.
Okay, I'm getting tired uh and do we
have a topic for today yet? I'm going to
read the comments and uh
so today maybe not the Chinese input
system.
This one is funny.
Dodecahedron tits.
So, actually so we have some more
topics. So, I want to talk about the M1
chip and MacBook Air.
Okay, yeah. So, let's
so that's a thing we haven't talked
about.
So, let me read the comments first.
Vim golf
Okay.
So, let me read the comments first.
If you have a question for me, tag me,
okay?
Uh question, have you considered bad
posture for your RSI?
Uh yes, but I don't have bad posture,
okay? Uh that's not one of my problem.
So, Marcos
Marcos says, Marcos Vargas Moran says,
"Do you have any faith into stop using
the computer altogether for a long while
and getting into weightlifting or
whatever else that's physical?"
Uh I cannot stop using computer
altogether because that is my passion,
that is my obsession, that is my life.
As o e essentially, I'm a nerd. I'm you
know, I'm when I was younger, I was
about to merge into the computer.
That's, you know, I'm a bit extreme in
that in that sense.
You know how today you have lots of
nerds, you know, who wear Google Glass
or who have, you know, wear Apple Watch
all the time, you know, technology. And
basically, the idea is cyborg,
cybernetics. You know, you love
technology so much so much that and also
you are kind of a social, you know, you
are a nerd. You don't
interact with other people that much,
you know, you don't you you find it
uncomfortable. You on the other hand,
you just love the machine, the
programming network, you know, you going
to merge into the net.
Like lots of the Japanese science
fiction,
you know, have you
you know, Ghost in the Shell and so on.
So,
I'm kind of like that, okay?
I've I've done that, you know,
since 30 years ago.
And, you know, today you actually have
people, you know, cybernetics. You have
people with kind of digital device, you
know, like devices embedded in the in
their brain. For example, if you look up
you search for it, you know,
cybernetics, you know, the first person,
you know, in UK or something, weird
people.
Uh so, when I was younger, I was very
much into that and I was into the
concept of uploading your soul.
Uploading yourself into the network. So,
you become the network. You become, you
know,
So, I was
kind of very into that. It's not today,
though. You know, as you grow older,
you have
things may change. May or may not. But,
you know, so I today I don't think I
want to be cybernet I don't want
I do not It It It still depends.
But, for example, I do not wish to like
upload my brain into the network. And
also,
as well, I, you know, that is the
whether that is possible at all, nobody
knows. Okay?
In science fiction, we we do that. But,
whether that's actually possible at all,
even in theory, we don't know. Because
we don't know with all the artificial
intelligence, we don't we don't we
cannot define what is a soul.
Yet.
Okay, so so do I have so so do I so do I
ever stop using computer altogether?
No.
Uh
So, like like right now, I cannot
imagine a life without computer. That's
what I do. I wake up, I sit in front of
the computer
till the moment I sleep. And I've been
like that since since about 1991. Okay?
In the '90s, I I go out much more
because when you are a student, you have
to, you know, I take the bus to the
school, go to the library, you sit in
classrooms, which, you know, you
interact with other people, and I was
also on the swimming team. Imagine that.
I'm not a social person, but I was in
the swimming team.
Uh because I thought, you know,
I thought, you know, I'm not good with
people. So, maybe joining the swimming
team, I can somehow it can
I can be more social. It turns out it
doesn't work like that.
But, in anyway, I was in the swimming
team for like two two years.
Uh,
so
So, is it possible I get, you know, that
I don't use computer
you know, there is
I'm not forced to use the computer, but
it's not likely I don't touch a computer
for longer than few days. Okay, because
I First of all, I enjoy it and I don't
see a problem.
You know, and I like some people
idiotic people or psychology, you know,
I don't you know, I you know, even even
even some of the many of the, you know,
so-called experts.
You know, these days, you know, these
experts, they don't know I think they
don't know much. Okay, so they they
might say, you know, like, "Oh, you
should get away from internet or
something."
I can do that. Yeah, sure, I can do
that, but not likely because I enjoy
programming. I enjoy
computers. I enjoy I want to know what's
going on. I want to know the technology.
What is the latest? What's the
programming languages? What do are they
thinking? Who are the designers? And how
they design the things, you know, where
is HTML
system, the CSS system, the JavaScript
system, where is it going socially and
technically? I want to know. I'm That's
my passion. Okay, I and I enjoy it and I
want to talk about it. That is why you
are seeing Tsar Talk Show and you know,
I talk argue with people here often.
So, if you like, you know, if you
haven't already joined SA Discord, okay?
So,
that's about getting away from the
computer and getting into weightlifting,
you know, a lot people are into
weightlifting. I'm not into
weightlifting, okay?
Now, let me digress about that.
Now, when it comes to exercise, there is
weightlifting, you know, bench press,
you know, the probably the most famous
is bench press.
Or well, there's also um
bench press dips,
you know, for example.
These
old man can still do a few dips.
Dips dip on my chair.
And I can put my legs up
to the
to the monitor.
So So, that's gymnastics.
Um
So, when it comes to exercise, you know,
there's the weightlifting,
then there's also on the other hand, you
have the
uh
cardiovascular
system.
You know, the aerobics, that's what they
call, you know, so running or
or maybe you can't climbing.
So, you but usually the weightlifting
people who talk about weightlifting,
they usually they are the big build type
of people. That's what they like.
Because
that's what they uh
do best. You know, those type people,
they don't do well when it comes to
aerobics. But for thin framed, you know,
for small framed people,
this that you know, like typical average
soldiers,
you know, we would like aerobics better.
So, I I
got into weightlifting. I don't find it
fun. I don't I I don't like it too much.
But rather, I do
What do you you know, what's like the
extreme sports, you know, like uh well,
swimming and roller uh
uh rollerblading.
Yeah.
So, I don't do uh much weightlifting.
All I do is at most uh push-ups.
I use VORAC. Okay, so
Also, I've watched some of your videos
and articles since 2012. Fantastic,
Marcos.
You know, if you guys want to uh know me
and you know, get to know each other, so
join Discord, okay? Because
uh on live stream, it's hard.
You know, I can barely remember who you
guys are. So, but if you join uh start
Discord, you know, we kind of uh chat
every day.
Good morning, Alan.
That's about it today. I think we we're
going to shut down. Yeah, 12:10, okay, 1
hour.
So, there's a question.
Give us M1 chip and MacBook Air. Yeah,
okay, so that um
Yeah, so I forgot to talk about that.
So,
well, what to say? Um,
keyboard black, so, you know, I'm going
to create an article on this, you know,
this is my photo. I just took it today,
uh, yesterday. So, Mac is just better
than Windows in in every way, okay? The
only exception is when you get a Mac,
you pay double, almost double, okay? Not
you you know, for for the past 30 years,
it appears to me the situation is the
same.
If you want the best design, the best
user interface without with the least
amount of frustration, then you go with
a Mac, okay? But, then everything you
buy the Mac computer every year, every 2
year, you know, every time you buy Mac,
it's like 1.5 times more expensive. So,
for the like the same machine, if a PC
costs you $1,000, for the Mac, that's
$1,500.
About, you know, for the past 30 years.
Uh, so,
in some sense, nothing changed, you
know, back in 1990s, on the Mac, you
have the mouse, you can draw, Mac Draw,
Mac Paint,
you know, and on Windows, you don't you
have DOS, okay?
You have DOS, like oak, you know, that's
this is that's what you have. That's
that's all you have. You don't have any
graphics, okay? So, Mac invented it.
Essentially, okay? Now, those people who
want to mention Xerox, okay, shut the
[ __ ] up. You don't know what you mention
means.
I talked about this in my past few
videos.
Like, you know, they want to correct me,
"Oh, actually, Steve Jobs didn't invent
it because
Uh, so,
you know, I'm not like against,
you know, that you know, this kind of
technique technically true, but many of
these nerds, what they say basically 90%
of things you see people say on the
internet or even real life,
they didn't you know, they haven't
really spent time to think about things,
you know, so they so most so most of the
time that's why you make you see me
making fun of this and that, okay? That
that's just my character, my
personality.
Uh so
so yeah, Mac, so
so if you want to know my Mac, you know,
so the the whole history
of my Mac and Windows and Unix
experience
at least Mac versus Windows is detailed
in this article, okay? So if you, you
know, go to mis- miscellaneous over
here, miscellaneous stuff, you can see
this is my current computer I bought
this year.
Uh this is my beginning of this is me
coming out of poverty, okay? Due to
personal reasons.
Uh so
this is my gaming machine and you know,
so
um
this year, this is a machine right now
I'm using and uh
oh yeah, so if you want to know about
the history of so
history of my
what I think about Mac versus Windows,
you can read this article. Why am I
switch why I am switching from Mac to
Windows written in 2009.
And this is my Mac in 2005, okay? 2005
to 2009, okay?
So and I also have this one. I had this
one in 1999. 1999, I was working,
you know, in startups. So, I have
actually
more than one of these. I have the G5. I
have the, you know, the the Mac
Pro, you know, the the Mac Pro at the
time. I don't have a photo.
And uh this Mac Mini from 2008.
Are we still on OBS? Reconnection
successful. That's it for today.
So, M1 chip is truly good, okay? So, let
me just, you know, you
um
So, if you want to know about M1 chip,
you go to
here, this article, okay? So, there's
just some videos.
Uh it will of course there's a lot
YouTube videos. So, you don't need,
you know, to watch this in particular.
But, however, these I watched and they
are very good. Actually, I'm I'm about
to delete this page. So, I'm going to
write a, you know, create a new page of
uh just my Mac as a record.
Okay, so, that's it for today. What
else?
Hello Andrew.
Can you give me a source that people
don't think about things before they
post?
Are you kidding?
Uh how long have you been living in the
place you are now? 1 year.
Okay, bye guys.
So about exercise, especially about RSI,
the aerobic exercise is much better than
weightlifting, okay?
Uh yeah, so you should get into
aerobics, do it three times a week,
uh 30 minutes each.
You want to get your heart rate
heartbeat up
about 120, something like that. Of
course, check your doctor before you go
into exercise regime.
You don't want just, you know, if you
haven't exercised before, especially
aerobic, you want to do it slowly. You
don't you you know, you want to
gradually uh
do more and more. Bye guys. If you like
my show, buy me a drink, okay? If you
enjoyed the talk, if you enjoyed, you
know,
buy me a drink.
Okay, yeah. So that's it for today. I'm
just I'm shutting down. I'm going to
I'm just going to shut down. So what is
this?
So I'm going to actually So so now Emacs
workflow.
So
Emacs workflow. So I'm starting to
create a page. Yeah, so let's go to
keyboard. So, this is my keyboard blog.
Now, now let's show the pink window.
Uh
let's see. So, so this is here is my Mac
photo. So, I'm going to create a new
page.
Uh so, Mac
book. Okay.
Air. Okay, put a date. Actually, it's
not put a date. Okay, so
press a key that becomes a link with a
file created. Press enter to open that
file. Showing browser, there it is. Back
here,
close that and uh copy that title.
M1 MacBook Air. Copy that. Open that.
Update the title.
Showing browser, good. Now, copy the
photos
into it. Copy, copy.
And uh back.
Paste. Showing browser, fantastic. You
see, this is how I create uh
new page. Okay. Now, close that.
Now,
open it again. Now, this photo is kind
of two
This photo how what size is it? 1,600
pixels. Okay. So, I want to make an
icon. So, yeah, so let's make an icon.
So, I want to make a icon meaning a
smaller version of this photo.
Okay. So, I have a
Emacs command.
Doom doom doom. 250. Yes, there it is.
It creates a link. Now, if I open the
link, you can see I just created a small
icon of this photo. Cut it. First, this
save.
Now, you can see now I want to put the
Okay, paste the photo here and copy the
full path of this link. So, do it. Now,
move the cursor here. Paste. Now, call
another command. Doom doom doom. And it
becomes that. And move here. Delete this
line. Show in browser.
Fantastic. Now, I have a icon iconified
link. Now, let me talk about this shoe.
This shoe is a flat shoe, okay? It's a
flat shoe.
Uh
There's a whole story of it, okay? If
you search for five fingers toe,
you're you're kind of see the story. It
began about 20 years ago. The story is
that so you go to miscellaneous tech.
So, I have a another pair. So, this this
is a flat shoe, meaning that
you know, a typical
sports shoe, running shoe, they have
very thick sole like this thick, you
know?
So, that
the idea is that
you know, so it cushions your weight.
So, you you're
you know, so so it's supposed to be
supposed to be more comfortable.
But
one of the modern theory is that you
know, one of the thinking is that
actually though this modern shoe, you
know, it didn't begin about 50 or 100
years ago.
So, but this modern shoe, although it
appears you know, you have a thick
cushion so it seems to be good, but
actually they change your natural the
way you walk.
The the way you walk and uh they change,
you know.
So, they have you know you know the
physi- physiology
when you you know when you do going
about your daily business is changed if
you wear, you know, the modern uh
running shoe and so on.
So, and
and it may harm your health.
So, these people the idea is that you
want a shoe without
uh you know, I actually I wrote about
this long ago.
Sali
five finger shoe. Let's see if I can
find it.
Okay, I
I don't think I can.
Yeah, it's it's one of my old article,
but anyway, so
so the idea is that they created this
shoe
so that it's flat. It doesn't have any,
you know, thick cushion and uh
also it has a kind of a glove for each
toe so that your feet is more natural,
you know, so you can feel the ground and
grab it, you know.
So, if you ask people, let's say in
Africa or some people who doesn't have a
shoe, they grew up that way.
They their feet are much more capable
than us because for us, you know, the
modern city dwellers, you know, when we
since we were born, we wear this shoe,
so our feet is accustomed you know, you
don't you don't you don't touch the
ground.
So, you don't have mobility of your feet
and so on. So,
so this flat shoe supposed to improve
it.
Okay, so and this one, you know, for for
example, like a monkey, like a baboon,
like a gorilla, you can actually grab
things with your feet kind of a little
bit.
Uh because we are human animals.
So, that's a that's the idea about this
this shoe, you know, popular in
California among the hippies.
Among the hippies or the or the yuppies
or today's bug men.
Uh
you know, the millennial generation
concept, bug men.
So, the first one who made makes these
commercially in USA or the the the most
popular is this company Vibram. Vibram,
you know, beginning around year 2000,
you know, this during the dot-com days.
I remember it because I was there, you
know, because I was
I was a, you know, in my prime.
Mhm. Now now I'm about to die, you know,
I'm I'm old. But I was in my prime and
and uh you know, I was at the top.
Kind of.
Uh
So, but it's expensive. So,
So So, what I bought is a kind of
alternative, okay? So, let's go to the
page. Where is it?
Okay, click that.
Copy the link. Go back to my Go back to
the keyboard blog and uh
create a new section.
Turn on global highlight mode. Paste the
link. Linkify. Then go here.
Cut that, you know, so you see
So, this is the photo. Delete that. Cut
the block and go back to the barefoot
shoes.
Open it. Show in browser. That is this
page. And go down. We're going to add a
photo here.
So, we're going to add a
section.
Paste the photo here, show in browser.
Scroll down.
There it is. That's my new one.
So, this is my Emacs workflow. So,
anyway, the
you know, I didn't buy this because it's
kind of expensive and it's kind of it's
If you wear this, it's going to be
conspicuous.
Everyone is going to look at you. They
know, you know, you are advertising
yourself. Here comes a big nerd.
And all the pretty girls is going to
disappear. They're going to run far away
from you.
So, this is a big nerd shoe.
So, but but here is a China cheaper.
China cheaper. They are collapsing USA.
China cheaper and pretty good. For 30 40
dollars, I bought this and I wore I I
wore this I still wear it for a year by
now. It and you know, there's a little
tear, but it's fantastic, okay?
Because my ankles because beginning in
when I was 16 years old at Montreal,
you know, I
I talked about I was a juggler and I
ride unicycles unicycle. You know, I can
do
one leg one leg pedaling or walking on
the tire, you know, I do lots of tricks
and going backward, you know,
you know, like I said,
I'm not into weight lifting that kind of
thing, but I'm into daredevil
that sort of sports. You know, what do
you call today extreme sports, like
snowboarding, you know, like
I wear rollerblades and I hold on to
cars, you know, I'm on the streets in
the city, you know, I
So,
I was doing those.
Uh so, when I was younger I I do unis-
unicycle and I injured I sprained my
ankles many times. So, my ankles are
prone to sprain.
Especially, you know, when I wear the
typical Nike running shoe. But with
this, it appears to me
it you know,
reduces reduced the chance. So, I would
I actually recommend this
this kind of flat shoe. Okay, that's it
for today.
Bye.