good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today's 2019
December 12 December 21st 3 o clock p.m.
Saturday San Francisco time and today we
are going to do this Emily clock I'm
going to do live coding plus tutorial
and I'm going to teach you about how
different a time system and how to
convert to different number base I'm
going to explain what is number base
notation like decimal hexadecimal and
octal and sex symbol and 7 based and
lots of others
ok so I'm gonna explain that and we're
gonna do live coding so we are going to
specify the problem and we are going to
live code it ok so let's go to this page
that's almost begin good morning Emily
good morning crash hacker so you are
looking at Emily's watch now ok so so
I'm going to do live coding and the I'm
going to do three possible languages one
is Emma crisp one is JavaScript and the
other possibility is : so type in a chat
which one you prefer me to do okay we
are going to do to live coding so typing
a chat okay read read the description
and type in the chat what which language
emag base Cola and JavaScript and we
don't have time to do more than one
because you know this is gonna be take a
while I hope we can finish in let's say
probably one hour let's say 40 minutes
okay so Emily posted a
reference implementation let's see so
who else did okay so okay here you can
see my calculator optimizer and never
finish the game okay so this is Emily's
okay so Emily's Emily posted reference
implementation okay so actually that's
why I didn't get enough time to see it
but I don't you know I don't think we
can go over it because we don't have
time because I need to go through the
it's explanation what is a problem and
and also you know live coded and
explained number basis stuff so hold on
a second so let me put this Emery's
reference implementation in place and
then we can later on wait then later on
we can check a result if it's to see if
that's correct okay so first of all let
me magnify so this is Emily 3 reference
implementation so so so sauce start
command log mod and I'm going to explain
what is the problem we are going to do
okay so set background color and we
decided last time the Papa we want the
purple color so hold on a second
so hello Daniel hello magpie okay magpie
crash hacker says let's do it in
JavaScript any okay I need a vote which
language JavaScript emag bees or Golan
post post one okay each one of you posts
choose the language and we gonna cook
code that we need to actually I need to
do this fast beast color display because
otherwise I know it's not we are now
going to finish it in one hour so first
of all let me check am I correct
am i all right I'm all right okay so
and Google Google YouTube okay sothey so
let's choose the color the--so okay set
background color feast souls 3 so number
one okay full three yeah that's okay so
you said number one or number two but
anyway that that let that be this is
Emily's favorite color so what is a
problem so you are looking at Emily's
watch she this is fit spits watch and
she programmed it so that it displays
the clock in her own kind of system now
what is this system let's call em clock
okay Emily crock what is this system
this system now in a 24 hour system you
have 24 hours a day is divided by 24
hours each hour is 60 minutes and each
minute is 60 seconds now in Emily clock
the Emily system it's 36 and 6 system so
in this system one day is divided by
divided into 36 hours and each hour is
divided into 36 minutes and each minute
is divided into 36 seconds okay so this
is the clock system this is the Emily
clock system 36 spaced 6 system 36 hours
in a day 36 minutes in an hour 36
seconds in a minute ok this is Emily
clock and then so that's a clock however
there's one more thing
now when you sow so when you have
certain hour and so the minute given
given these Emily crocks you know a
certain number of hours number of
minutes number of seconds the notation
for this clock system is 6 paced number
system in other words you don't say all
right now it's 37 hours and 29 minutes
and and and 30 seconds you don't say
that you have to convert them into a six
based number system okay so that is the
description of the problem well the
problem is that we are going to write a
a function in images or in colon or in
JavaScript which one is it guys
come on pick one okay pick one of the
language okay I cannot do them all I
wanted to but from past experiences I
know that this is not good I cannot do
them oh so so you have to pick a
language okay each one of you who are
watching you know poster language
javascript' emag bees o : so that is
problem write a function that takes a
input take a takes a input string such
as such as what is right now such as
today right now is 15 15 0 9 and 0 0
okay
take a input string then output in this
MD crock notation system okay let's see
: : : i cannot do haskell okay so what
what what is this so let's see
Hayami soap up here top talk show is all
about you Emily is the queen in ink
Saudis corner so we are saying so I'm so
honored and what are we talking about so
the time system yeah so look at this
clock fantastic ofc I forgot what OFC
means okay : question is okay crash
hacker says any is fine magpie says in
his fine Oprah me is just logic syntax
is secondary know that that's not true
okay but I'm not going to digress
I want to see routines okay so s :
okay let's do go Landon well go and okay
go lines gonna take more time because I
haven't been coding : day D okay so we
got a problem and we got the problem
SPECT we got a problem SPECT right here
if you guys just you know you you can
read it here in detail in writing the
problem inspect so so we're gonna write
in : okay so what we gonna do okay
um yeah so live coding is what I'm going
to do oh and okay so I'm going to start
to code and those of you who already
understand what is this is about and who
already know what number format I mean
number base system means how it works
then right now you go ahead and code
code you of every language so you guys
has cow or Earl and you know code it
let's see
you know coded so after 15 minutes show
your code and we can verify we can see
different languages and syntax okay and
actually someone has already written you
know someone we we already you know
someone has given this art out a are W
with a RW n this person is from
California and he has given a C code I'm
not sure I haven't verified its correct
because right now we don't have easy way
to verify it so we got C code the Python
3 code is incorrect because there's the
problem
you know the anyway it's incorrect so
let's go : ok so let's start live coding
goal and let's see how far we can go so
: I've opened a new buffer and magnify
and let's see go okay so we start we
start to have a template every goal and
script you need basically list
so : and we are going to write a
function that takes an input okay
M time okay that's right let's say
that's a function okay function the
function name is same time okay and the
int M time the input will be a string
type time 24 okay so that's a parameter
input it's going to be a string type and
the output the output is also a string
okay and this is the function body and
when we run a program we're gonna call
em time and let's say zero time zero
zero zero zero zero one okay zero one so
that's zero hour this is a 24-hour
system zero hours you a minute and but
one second and let's see you know it
will return the M time okay so and we're
gonna need we need to print this so
print so we're gonna copy that put it
here so there okay so that is our code
and we can't run it now so run it it
says cannot use new as type string in
written argument yes indeed that's true
so let's return some random string so
let's say is three three okay grenade
okay this our template is working now
now the the important thing is we cannot
write this function so to write this
function so what algorithm to use you
have to think about it okay so actually
so this problem again if you don't know
let me paste the enemy copy this URL
okay for those of you are new here this
is a problem description okay so you can
go and code it now in your favor
language and after 15 minutes let's
compare notes problem description coded
in your favorite language okay
Haskell Alan if you up to Emily and and
other languages okay so ten people
watching so let's the clock is ticking
and let's let's get how long have I been
talking Oh
13 13 minutes already G okay so
algorithm so before you do anything you
need to think about how you're gonna do
this
so algorithm our algorithm is gonna be
so first of all a documentation for this
same time so so here we say aim time
returns takes a input of this format
okay so for example 13 o clock 13 o
clock one minute and one second and
return a string that is M time system
okay and so that's the that is the
function documentation so we got that
now algorithm what so first of all so so
so I'm just going to go and code
whatever in my grant like right now
without thinking about efficiency and
all that you know that it's to a
prototype if we finish this in 30
minutes
that will be our code success okay so
algorithm so what I'm going to do is
first find out what is the total number
of seconds okay then
then total number of seconds and find
out okay so and find out what is the
total number of seconds in M clock okay
game system and then I don't know what
next
so first of all what is a total number
of seconds in M system I don't know so
let's let's find it
let's compute total number of seconds
mtoto SEC equals to constant M total
number of seconds equals to 36 seconds
36 times 36 right so 36 seconds times
the number of minutes in our times the
number of hours in a day so 36 times 36
times 36 is mtoto second okay
and let's print that okay let's just
print that to see what that is now mtoto
second is a number we need to convert
that to a string in : and the way you do
that is like that okay if I remember
correctly
okay so wrong you got somewhere wrong
what is wrong God so go for my format
arrow expected that found indent M
seconds okay so
[Music]
what this is not looking good God so
white ways is God okay let's go to Saudi
golden tutorial for those of you for me
who have not been coding : for a while
so constant so let's look at the
variable declaration declaration
constants comments guys comment so so so
we need what's going on I don't know
what's going on so the constant so what
is the goal lines variable declaration
so variable Wow okay so but : also have
a constant so but I don't know why is it
but let's just try this okay what what
is going on okay so
so it says expected that but found
indent
what my said okay okay so apparently
this line is incorrect so how do you
convert a number to a stream I'm I'm
pretty sure it's correct so let's see
stream okay so we have I we have a
string here and backslash escape raw
string literal string a sequence string
is a sequence of bytes in : and string
index string functions run okay so
that's colon string and let's see
comments stream stream functions oh god
I got stuck in these syntactical issues
we're never gonna finish anyway total
number of seconds in M system so what is
wrong that with that let's do it again
so found intent found end of line try it
again
no so anyone of you know what is wrong
of you : expert okay this is walking oh
okay so I think maybe that okay so
apparently this conversion line is
incorrect
so : so sing coding so what what what is
what are we doing variable variable so
variable declare you declare a variable
like that and you that's right oh you
add when you declare a variable you have
to have a type okay but this type is
automatically determined because colon
has type you have type
how they call that type inference so you
do not you do not need to type a type as
long as the value is already of that
type so here's a variable declaration in
:
and default value variable with value
okay
and the parallel assignment okay and
variable scope okay and
je dois from Peru good morning je dois
so do we have : experts here when we do
go format this is tell me is wrong so I
need to think about this what's going on
go format errors found indent but
expected parentheses where when why is
it why is it that
so the problem seems to we are trying to
convert a number to string but I'm
pretty sure that is correct a number to
string
okay I think I know what is going on
string by size and size so let's look at
this string by size and size
oh oh oh I got it wrong I got the syntax
wrong guys because I'm I've I fell into
I am a victim of the C and Java god I'm
a victim of C and Java this is the
correct way guys I forgot so this is
wrong okay so these the second line is
correct so now we go format let's try it
again it's now go format perfect now
let's run the code okay when we run a
code it actually prints out some Korean
now I know the reason because when you
print a stream now this this string is
36 times 36 times 36 and we are trying
to print it and it comes out displayed
as a Korean because because this the
result number is actually interpreted as
a Unicode code point and and that number
happens to be the Unicode code point for
this Korean character apparently so
the way to fix that is you go to go and
you look at print okay so you look at
print there are various ways to print
different formats so in this case we
have a number we want to convert string
okay so the number two string is
actually a big problem in all languages
actually so that's why you got this
print F which is extremely complicated
thing okay so we want this okay we wants
print F we didn't even begin to code and
but we run into so many technical little
problems so strength F is we want to
print okay this thing
okay
and the
okay here here is how you do it okay so
here is your stream and here is your
value okay they are but your stream
needs to be percentage something
percentage is a holder for so we want to
so so this part the second part is a
stream
and okay I know what is it I know what
it is V okay V V means V means in code
and format okay so anyway so what we are
trying to do is we convert this string
into let's just try it okay run it the
problem of not having been coding : for
a while in doing live stream is why is
it come out Korean damn yeah so okay
that's it's it's okay I cannot I really
have to think about this in order to get
it to work so so we have a stream so
this is the string oh okay I see what
it's going on I know what is going on so
this is so stupid
okay so we so this is correct we are
just returning a string but we are
printing it here the the part that is
wrong is over here so we say I think s
okay no
so we really do need to look at print
the D in detail so format print print
okay so use a package format so
percentage V means okay here is the
format details for the percentage V is
any value print in human readable form
so V vennett
no so let's say percentage hash V prints
in Colin's syntax Lynette
okay so okay so the problem is not with
print the problem is we with our
conversion converting this number to
stream is its this is tremendous time
wasting so let's try this let's just say
int okay so let's say this number this
function returns a int then let's just
say that okay and now it returns an int
let's just join it so here is the result
this number this number is a
oh yeah it's a number right yeah oh god
I went to through ok so anyway so that's
a number so we don't need to wait we
want to convert well we want to convert
this number to string we need to solve
that problem because we will be needing
to do that later on
greetings Ultima yeah ok I posted my
ruby solution on this code ok ok I need
to finish this ok I'm hoping to finish
this then we look at all the other
people's solutions so so this is a
number of this function it returns a
number and now we need to change this
number into a stream phone format and
why cannot we do it so for example
print
this is a number okay and let's run it
okay
that's correct but however we want to
turn this into a stream
let's try
it keeps returning the Korean character
so the problem right now we have I have
is to convert a number into a string but
this is so basic but I got so screwed up
here what what am I
let's try this yeah so that is correct
so the problem right now is that I am
unable to convert a number this number
to a stream because when I do this it
returns incorrect result so converting
number to stream okay so I see what go
line is doing so because when you are if
you do this colon is just to convert
this number to a Unicode character yeah
yeah
so convert Golan to number to a string
how do you do that
skiing hot
so let's look at
yes you can append no go line I don't
think that works even if it works that's
kind of a hack that's not how you do it
in Golan because colon is a very
strongly typed language it does not
usually allows you to automatically
convert between types so and so right
now we want to convert this number to a
string I I have worked on this before
but I haven't been coding colon for a
month or two I don't remember
soul and oh let's see random number and
then int I print have B
oh yeah so so so back to the sprints
this is what we need to use I'm pretty
sure yeah that that obviously so here
this is this is the proper way okay so
you so we're going to call sprint F to
format a format a number into a stream
not not used not using the string
conversion so we're gonna format this
into a string so let's try it oh you
need to print it so print print this
okay good finally after some thinking we
got the answer okay that's it for today
so now we cocoa format so here is how
you convert a number to a string okay
you use the Sprint F function so once we
so so once we got a we got a string here
which is a string four six six five six
then we use print print F to print it
okay so now we got that soft now go back
to the our function here we we change it
back to a string type and we we change
it to the okay we change it return
anyway so actually let's just say that
okay we don't we don't need that so M
total second is the total number of
seconds in a day and
and
okay so mtoto ii is a number of a
seconds in a day in m crock the end then
then we then we return a stream version
of it so given a 24 hours so so our
input time 24 is gonna be something like
something like let's say 13 0 do we have
it here yeah so let's say that so that's
the input so first of all we need to
pass the time now there are two ways to
do it one is one way is that we're gonna
do this manually that is we split the
string into three parts then we compute
how many total seconds are there the
other way is use some sort of Theoden
function to pass time which one should
we use I think let's do it manually okay
because either way depending on which
one you are familiar but but I think
doing manually is is it's better for now
so we're gonna do so we're gonna spread
this stream string into a list of three
items so let's go to stream stream
functions ok length substring join
stream stream functions and the split we
already have the code example there so
this we're gonna have a
so time 24 split wait first of all we
you need a sprint function I mean we
need a strange library okay so here is
the strange library we need then we call
strings split okay split in the input by
:
okay and let's call it variable H minute
minute second second least okay is
actually you don't call it least slice
so so this is basically a array of three
items each item is a stream of that of
two digits okay and then we can say
return let's see if it's correct let's
say return 0th okay and let's print it
here
let's let's use that okay
rennet mtoto ii declared and not used
that's one of the colons problem yeah
okay so this just printed here brunette
good so it returns 13 that's correct
because that's the first part of the we
we're never gonna finish by this rate
okay this already what 41 minutes
import strings strange split time 24
yeah so that that yeah that is correct
so once we lets me try to do this
quicker if we see if we can do it let's
see how far we go after 10 more minutes
okay once week
so this is our so let's just be done
okay so our will be equals to that let's
be done minute second to one okay let's
not you know there are so many other
better syntax to do this but let's just
get it done so so we want to compute now
we want to compute total sex sec total
number of seconds so total number of
seconds equals 2 so h h number of hours
times 60
that's a minutes times 60
that's seconds first the number of
minutes
times 60 that's a number of seconds
first seconds okay so we got total
number of seconds okay and now let's
return
let's return total number of seconds
let's see what works okay cannot convert
can cannot convert 60 to type string
okay so we need to do conversion again
so so each one of these is a string
hh:mm:ss is a string we need to convert
it to a number so here so now the
problem is string to number how do you
convert string to number so convert a
string to number a string to number I
believe you need to use a library
because I had this problem before I
believe you you need to use a library so
does anyone know okay the easiest way is
just stack overflow okay
Golan string so what is this string -
number yeah string - number blew through
the length of string yeah you can do
that but that's that's that's not proper
way how to convert string to integer in
: okay so actually yeah there it is you
need this library you know each each
language is a bit funky
I was kind of surprised you need this
library string conversion
and let's go back okay so let's so
because I have looked into this there I
you know I've I've done this before so
here is the package string conversion so
you want to convert a string to a number
so let it let's see what are the
functions we need to use okay
the most common American version are a
two I string to int and I to I into
string string to int that's what we want
so Oh God
: with its aerial stuff or is this
yes you do because colon is a low level
language like C so you know it's it's
not as high high level so I haven't been
coding : in past few months so it's kind
of just - so sorry about that yeah so so
let's see so we have several several
functions that convert string to number
actually this will be quite useful for
our purposes because we are going to
convert to base six near the end so okay
so string to number right so for example
we can use this one string to int okay
so so this is how you convert a string
to int so this the string will be H edge
and and the second part number is passed
int o case the the other arguments are
passed int pace and bit size base and
pitch sighs you know the problem with
low-level languages is that then you
have to worry about this speed sighs
Jesus I don't want no I don't care about
what bit sighs so pass in interpreter
string s in the given base okay you know
in a given base that's the input zero of
binary or 36 and bit size zero to 64 and
return a corresponding I what what is
the bit size mean piece size 32 doesn't
matter
OKC has that in standard pipe so if a
zero in base equals to zero
the base is implied by the strings
prefix okay that's another kind of not
so good design because you see they are
using a trick you know the second
argument is supposed to a base but
however it is allowed to to let the base
be 0 because when the base is 0 it means
you know it is kind of a magical value
and then it means the base is implied by
the stringing in in you know the inputs
prefix anyway that's that's that's just
how things are it's not mathematical the
besides arguments specify the integer
type that the result must fit into okay
what what besides should all be so 32 I
guess 64 let's go to 64 okay let's just
say that okay then you have to do arrow
checking because you see this this
function returns two things one the
first thing is value the second thing is
arrow God
god this is a lot to do means a lot of
code Jesus let's just say that okay
let's be dumb and let's just say that so
we're gonna have
how do you do this function in a
function way I don't want too many lines
that's a problem
so this line returns the let's just
ignore the area okay yeah we can do that
yeah
so yep that is something like that okay
okay so H H numb so this will be H F H
in numerical form this will be m m in
numerical form and SS in numerical form
let's run it please no it's not gonna
work right I know it
so is a single value context : colons
function it can return multiple values
okay so let's just do that so so this
function passed int returns two values
the first value is a real result the
second value is a error kind of error
indicator so when you so when a function
returns two values you need to you the
way you get the values is like that you
use you know you assigned it aside
to like two values but if you but you
need to assign it to two values
otherwise Golan complains so let's do
that
everyone arrow to arrow 3 whatever
declared and not used God an arrow to
arrow 3 declare is not used Jesus if
arrow okay if arrow 1 equals to is not
Neil panic this is what this is what
everyone do you just add this code let's
try it again we declared God so is it
fun guys : this is : guys : okay
: is fantastic because it's most
practical so let's run it again
yay finally so so what's going on now so
we have we have given the number of
let's see let's look at what's going on
our code right now okay so we have we
have the input the input is here okay 13
hours 13 hours 1 minute 1 second and we
have passed that into h h mm and SS then
we can convert them to a numerical form
integers then we multiply them so we got
total number of seconds okay
so the total number of seconds so let's
run a code so this is the total of
number of seconds let's try it again
okay so what if we say zero zero okay
that should return one correct guys
correct look okay let's try to correct
okay so so far so good
so now we got a total number of seconds
this should be easier now okay so this
is me you can almost and so now we got
total number of seconds in a day of a
given time now we want to convert it to
the Emily croc 36 paste system that's
not hard okay that's not hard so what we
do so what we so we take the total
number of seconds and then divided by 36
okay
divided by 36 then take the take the
floor okay then that would be our
our so okay so em our okay something
like that right guys right right right
so we got this em our something like
that but however the flow is not correct
you maybe you need math in Golan you
need a math library to do floor do I
have a tutorial here somewhere okay I
don't know so Golan so you go go you go
to Colin's official documentation you
click on packages by the way Golan has
the best documentation ever in my 20
years 3 30 years of in programming
industry : has the best documentation
ever and the language is very simple
it's a bit tedious okay it's more
tedious than Python than this but it's
510 times faster than Python all this
okay so that is why and colon is
designed to replace designed to replace
C++ basically it's in the same speed as
the prosperous so anyway right now we
are trying to find out how to do how to
do the floor function in : and how do
how to do how to do modular with medics
so we go to Colin's packages and then
look at math so let's see if there is a
flaw there it is indeed floor so you
have okay so here is the floor function
okay so you got a float of floor
function and this package is math so you
need to use the math package so go to
the top add a new package math okay then
in then in the line that says floor we
need say we
need to say math dot flora okay and
let's print em how okay let's print em
how wait now we need to convert that to
a stream because this function returns
the string so convert that to a string
that's how you that's how you convert
and a number to a string now we are so
familiar with it so we can do it right
away so okay so so now we run it it
should return the number of hours I
cannot refer to an exported name math
third floor oh the F must be capitalized
now another goal and tip every function
in a package their name must be
capitalized
okay so we got it wrong and now it
should be good we change it to floor
capital F now run it okay wait so total
seconds divided the batter is 236 and
yeah that's right Janet cannot use 30
total it cannot use total seconds
divided by 36 because typed mismatch
this is problem of typed languages okay
total seconds divided by 32 okay doesn't
work because because float64 in argument
to math okay so yeah God cannot do what
you're gonna do okay we instead of
divide we want to use is there a better
wait let's just say 0 0 okay let's just
say that run it
okay cannot divide total number of
seconds by 30 36 okay then it's
converted to float okay so that's how
you do it in Golan Golan tediousness
wait no there's no type float so let's
go back to Golan types there is no type
float you need to use the appropriate
type Golan basic types so you have float
32 float64 okay float64 Gwinnett Oh
finally God and our answer is correct
it's zero hours so let's summarize again
okay so summarize so we got so our
function right now is printing the total
number of hours in Emily croc so if the
input you know so so it's spinning a
total number of hours the Emily croc we
are getting close so we run into a
problem because when we divide this this
math.floor function the input must be
type float 64 therefore we need to
convert it before we feed it to the
function but anyway now it works now and
once we know we got the number of hours
we need to know what's the remainder
what's that women momenta of total sex
seconds divided by 3 is 36 we are almost
there okay so I guess you can see the
pattern so let me read the comments okay
this how long have I been talking we
cannot finish this today maybe not
so what is
font they are talking about font so so
George has a ruby version so maybe we
should just look at that for the
people's code or should we continue to
finish this :
thing we are almost there so how long
have I been talking one hour already so
okay let me be the comments quickly okay
Emily are you still here
crash hacker is still here so let's read
the comments and maybe we shut down okay
so I don't think he's not a third of our
game right so so the string conversion
from number to string is in : okay it's
a B or D in package it's this one okay
but being able to just say that is so
much better yeah so : does not have that
so thus go have first-class functions
yes : in : function can return a
function and function can be an argument
to another function function is a value
function is a expression so you know you
guys check out my goal and tutorial okay
actually I do cover all the basics so if
you are a golden beginner go check out
my goal and tutorial you follow them one
by one now I don't cover all features of
a goal and go line is pretty basic okay
you can learn actually almost this or
the whole thing in one day but however I
there are some features I'm missing but
don't complain because of the hacker
types they all say oh you're your goal
and lacks co-routine or your goal you're
your tutorial ax some fancy : features
right those are fancy I'm giving you a
basic tutorial so check out my tutorial
so let me just pace it here and so what
are we um let's go back to the code so
there is our code so goal and does have
function as first class function so as
today I had a discussion with a
colleague Freddie says with a colleague
and he told me : takes takes the
readability of Python in the power of C
and optimizes for modern CPUs yes so so
far it seems not so different from C but
I am no Co expert okay check out a talk
code okay so
[Music]
so Dion says Emily says of course Emily
still they are great so Emily is working
on Earl and version you didn't finish it
yet okay we are having a race
okay so you know usually the problem
seems trivial until you actually code it
then lots of these details like this
pain in the ass
number conversion you know number two
string conversion details okay let me do
let me try to finish this okay
in fact George has a ruby version seems
very short let's see if it works okay
now if it is if it doesn't work in the
first time I'm gonna abandon it okay so
because it's a ruby so m time ub m time
george dot RB okay actually okay so hold
on a second
so we have here a version George ruby
version magnify now Lynette
it runs let's try to call it now I don't
know Ruby okay I studied it for a month
but I don't really know it but let's
just try it
1300 zero one zero one okay Lynette oh
you need to print print in Ruby you have
this people print
vennett problem 2m time okay problem
undefined method year what yeah so so
George doesn't walk okay it doesn't walk
other box you know every time I give a
programming problem many people we are
many people you know every time I give a
program how a problem many people will
post their solutions but you need to
make sure your solution actually follow
follow the spec correctly because to you
you know it just walks on your machine
it works on my machine right but it but
wait when you want to show others is
usually doesn't so right now I'm running
into this problem you know you have to
consider other people don't know Ruby
you know for example maybe you are
coding Haskell or LAN or whatever or
eMac this other people do not know
they've never done it so you need to
kind of have it you need to have it like
work and also even even include some
documentation if necessary like how to
compile it like that C code you know how
to compare and things like that anyway
so for example this George solution I
read and it give me is problem so let's
see what is a problem
so use the server up to him undefined
method year so it says undefined method
yeah you know I know a little bit Ruby
so I can actually know a little bit but
you know you have to imagine it's other
people they are running your code and
they have known that they they don't
even have Ruby installed maybe so they
don't know you know so I don't know so I
don't even know what is the problem no
method yeah so there's no year so maybe
you need to load the library on top did
I miss it yeah you need to load the
library is something so anyway so this
Ruby version I consider fail now now
there are other versions like Emily
him/herself has given us a solution now
this this code works this is in eMac
this but however you see we when you run
this okay it let me show you what is a
result okay it doesn't even print the
result because I mean the code works but
it's it's a code she used in her herself
you know for for a long time even though
it works correctly but we cannot use it
in our live stream purposes because we
need to know we needed to print result
and also we need to be able to input
time instead of using a current time so
she needs to modify this for us
for me you know that you know in order
for us to look at this hold on a second
let me close that okay so this so she
has that version and then she has she
has given us another version and this
version has also has a problem see it
turns out it's incorrect because the way
we read in the time we try to read in
the 24-hour time is is not correct code
see so what I'm saying is that even
though this problem seems three
but it's not really trivial when you
actually code it so you have you run
into you run into lots of little details
I mean emily has been coding emag lists
for a couple of years right at least of
few years so then we have this C version
now I don't know C at all
C is by r1 from California in on this
code and this version you know I I try
to compile it so let's let's see why it
does okay so let's go to e she'll go to
okay so let's go to hoedown second so go
to the file which is this file now we
need to compare this file so I go to EC
au and I type GCC compiler optimized now
I don't know I don't know GCC I copied
this command line from crash hacker
crash crash Shaka gave us the the syntax
for that so okay so this so the here is
how we compile it do it done
okay then then it will create a wait I
got a wrong actually did I over
haha
I just over wrote it yeah so this is so
bad I just I just overrode the program
okay I and now I have to go find
somewhere in the discord with our
internal code the C program
Oh George says he doesn't take a stream
okay so so Arwen are you here you know
how when you should be here so we can so
so so I screwed up ONC code
I I compared it and over wrote itself
how idiotic so let's run George's code
again so it doesn't take a it doesn't
take us input but why is there is you
know the I don't think the code is
really hundred percent correct because
there is a parameter there but okay so
let's run this yeah I still have got a
problem so remember next time someone
you know like there's a competition well
you know companies you know competition
then you know you want to be careful
because but anyway okay so let's so at
least I can we can run the are ones code
okay so let's try it
so our ones code let's go to so Owens
codes okay so you need to let's magnify
okay so Owens cold dot slash that's how
you ran it okay you need to give it a
time so let's say zero zero zero zero
zero one one second okay so it doesn't
conform to the spec but let's try that
okay let's try one minute
this seems incorrect this is incorrect
Arwen you guys all you guys code are
incorrect guys wait maybe it's correct
let's try one hour okay one hour and
zero minutes
is that correct
because we don't have reference so one
hour is in Emily time so you have to
remember this is a hexadecimal this is a
sectional notation so that 1 1 : 5 0
that means that's a 6 amount notation
base 6 so this one is space space 6 1
not this amount 1 okay so you need to
convert these space 6 to decimal and
this 50 is also base 6 so it's it's hard
for me to verify because right now we
don't have a reference implementation
okay so George is giving us another shot
so let's go try George's version you'll
be ok it's magnify okay brunette
undefined method pass pass undefined
method method pass George you gotta make
it sure everyone can run it okay
Alliance cards Emily Scott earlier and
version done oh I cannot verify it
because I don't have a line installed
well too bad
and what is that cracker is that a new
version new C version okay so should I
be here today or should we
so Emily got the early inversion then
where is the code okay so it's in here
my island solution it's not pretty it's
not efficient but it works okay let's
copy and look at the code olan olan guys
a line is the massive concurrency
hot-swappable
language it's a language that features
hot-swap ability okay so let's look at
the code so save it as
what'swhat's Islands extension RL Emily
what's Alan's extension let's say yeah
okay
okay so
so there we have early inversion and
open it okay I don't have syntax
coloring so well so that you have a line
version thought ERL okay okay so I think
that's it we you know I so what about
what about our code I mean the goal
inversion we haven't finished it where
is it
how long have I been talking maybe with
one hour and 18 minutes yes I saved it
but so Emily so the early inversion I
already save it you can see but I don't
have you know I don't have a line in
stored so outward and I don't
have the Earl and Maud all I'm are to
syntax correct but okay so let's look at
a code maybe so module export so this is
earl and code earl and syntax for line
is a function of programming language
oh the compiler requires the requires
the file name to match the module name
okay so so Emily says it should be M
time dot ERL
okay so let's rename it M time dot ERL
okay okay so maybe I will install all
and later on maybe yeah maybe not
because I got so many other things to do
so anyway that's all and code about goal
and cold let's let's go back to goal and
code okay let's copy it close it and put
the goal and code here okay so and
rename it goal and saw actually M time
saw
okay
okay so here is the code we can finish
it or M our we almost done okay so M our
then we so we got a number of hours well
the next thing we need to do is to find
out how to do modular with medics so
actually I'll I'll leave that d that
will be a today so for those of you who
watch find : interesting you can go and
write your own you know try to do this
as an exercise and you will learn :
you know so and that will be it today
thank you guys for watching bye guys we
closed down in one minute a line is so
pretty okay so that's really messy so
you guys you know what whatever is your
favorite language or whatever language
you are trying to learn this would be a
good exercise so you go and try to code
it you can code it in bash in Python in
Ruby and so on and Indian and DeYoung
what are you studying
haven't seen you for a while you are
coding Haskell or okay bye guys
oh okay so finally George supplied a new
code that's let's do this one more time
one last time George George is Ruby code
cuz that go to Ruby okay
aim time George Ruby pace it okay okay
run it there we have it
fantastic okay so it says 12 o clock is
aim time you know the aim time is a bit
complex because remember it it is 36
system 36 hours 36 minutes 36 seconds
but however the final notation is 6
based so so when we see the output we
need to convert that 30 from 6 space to
2 decimal to be able to understand what
how many hours is that so it's kind of
hard it's hard to verify unless we have
a reference code but anyway that's it
for today bye guys