foreign
show so today we are going to continue
doing the Advent of code live coding day
five
in wufam language then after that I'm
going to do a uh efficient stack
Implement a efficient stack data
structure in Python in JavaScript and if
we have time we're gonna do it in wufam
language and we're gonna time it so
we're gonna
I'm going to find finally resolve the
issue of whether the Python's smart
array python Ruby JavaScript they all
have a array Or List type that grows as
you add more items so we are going to
test to see if that data structure is a
efficient stack
you know versus our only implementation
using linked list so so that is the what
we're gonna do so yesterday we did uh
two hours you know Advent of code day
five
uh and uh uh wait yeah yesterday we did
two hours at the window of code day five
and uh we I went into attention about
how do you implement a efficient stack
in functional programming languages Okay
so
So today we're gonna just quickly finish
the Advent of code day five then we're
gonna do the stack okay lots of to do so
if you like my stuff pay me okay donate
patreon PayPal on my website you'll see
and uh happy to see your comment okay
so here is my coffee
ready to code begin coffee coffee with
milk coffee powder and honey
this is apple juice
and this is tea I'm ready to code
serious stuff
and the tea
okay I'm gonna blast through the Advent
of code yesterday so okay
so let's begin let's begin
so start a wolfam language
um
code and go to the talk show and that
the pink window shows all my stuff like
his command names and the keystroke I'm
using exposed keyboard
and I'm using some flag keys with
volrack layout this is the Expos I
recommend it okay
so day five
let's show day five I mean day five
yesterday so we got the we need to get
the problem input
uh
yeah okay so let's copy that
let's just quickly do it finish it it
should be in 20 minutes okay
so wait
what are we doing okay copy that
go here today's talk show and post the
link to yesterday so we can easily
access it and then
who fam language we need the code from
yesterday
okay that's not it
okay I think that's it
yeah let's copy that
Okay so
okay so uh paste the code here remove
that and pop it out okay let's begin
from yesterday so yes so the problem to
recap the problem is that you give you
are given this input
uh the first part shows Three Stacks
Stacks like in stack of books it's a
data structure so you
so you are given that input and you want
to move
one item from
stack two to stack one so stack two is
MCD so you move the D to stack one two
over here then the second thing you want
to do is move three from one two three
so stack one is here then you know each
time you can only move the topmost item
so but so you do this three times then
you then you do this one then you do
this one the
problem is to find out at the end what
is the result what's the topmost uh
letter okay so that is the input so
first of all we gonna rewrite this
we did yesterday so you know
uh now after a day you know I have
better much more better way okay so
string input Split That Into You know
first of all we want to split this
string into two parts the first part is
the actual input of this configuration
of the stacks the second part is the
procedure okay so split
then this is lines
lines of Stack which
lines of Stack config okay let's go
elaborate in the naming of things okay
so then you split by the
by the line ending character so you get
you know first of all you split this
string into two parts the first part and
the second part then you get the lines
of Stack config you do it by split
uh with end of line so each line you got
a list of strings each
each string is a line like that that
okay then here string split again
of X1
which is the
um list of lines
uh what
okay
let me do this okay good morning Greg
and dark okay
so strange speed X1 X1 is list of lines
then we string split
X1
the first part so yeah so this becomes
at least of two strings
a list of two string blocks okay so this
is the first part of the string we split
it by
a line character then you we get the
list of lines which is the stack
configuration
then
then the second part of X1 which is the
procedure procedural part in English we
split by the so we got the list of lines
procedure
uh let's see
lines okay least supplies then we want
to get the total count of columns so you
can do that easily by
by get the last item of the lines of
Stack config
the last item which is the last row then
you take the
then you split a string splitted by a
space so you got a list of
strings each string is one two three and
so on
okay so then
you take the last one of that which is
three
then you two expression you turn that
into a number to you know string two
numbers so
so you get the column count okay then
this line is a bit complex let's redo it
so it's much more simpler okay let's say
um
so let me do that
stream partition okay
x two
equals to
so
we
so the x lines is actually
lines of config okay
so
so you want to
let me simplify this okay string
partition
and
this is incorrect
okay let me let me do this
uh lines of Stack config
which is the list of lines here what you
want to do is you want to
pad it
yeah you want to pad it so that
you know you want to pad extra space
like add space so that later on you can
chunk it by
every four characters then you get a
list of rows of the crates then you do a
transpose so columns becomes rows so
each row represents a stack you know
which is the original vertical lines
okay
so you want to uh string pad here is the
let's write this so so right now you
want to pad the string so what you do is
you want to map that's right
Okay so
so that's column count then
then what you want to do uh
okay
you want to Pat it okay so map
forget about that Maps takes two
arguments the first part is a function
the second part is a beast so you want
to map this you Pat it here
so Maps string pad right
arguments and
so here is a function that Ampersand
stand is a shortcut for functions so
this is a function so you want to map
this function
let's do this
you might want to map this function to
this list of lines and this function
will just pad right by how much by to
make sure that there is number of
columns count times four
4 because each of the credit is one two
three four four characters
we want to do that because
so later on you know this empty we have
things to work with
so X2 is pad then
you want to
then then you partition it okay
that is
given a string
you want to separate the string into a
list of items each one is a string how
do you separate them by every four
characters okay so that is the string
partition
this function okay takes two arguments
the first argument is the string the
second argument is how many
you know how many characters you want to
chunk
so
yeah so the first argument is a uh
string partition uses string so X2 right
oh then you you need to map actually so
because you have
again a function
and X2 X2 is a beast
padded list okay so let's rename it
and let's let's just X X2 okay so X2 is
a pattern list then we partition it for
each of this line we partition it by
every four characters okay
then
uh then we
we want to do a trim so let's say X4 we
want to do a trim because you see these
four characters then there's a space at
the end
right so we want to trim it
and we also want to remove the square
brackets Okay so
X4 is Stream So you need a function here
this will be uh
string
trim okay stream trim takes
takes two arguments
uh no string trim
we just need to trim it that's all
so once you trim it
then to every line a list of lines once
you trim it so each
item is like that a string so you want
to replace string replace okay you want
to string replace
um
here a function you map you so we don't
need the trim here so
we'll simplify the code later but now we
want to focus on the clarity of what's
going on so you want to string replace
of the left bracket by nothing right
bracket by nothing
uh and applies to X4
right okay here is should be X3 Okay so
okay so far so good
yeah so in fact let's show it let's show
some Wolfram language code paste it here
okay so that's the code evaluated
okay we got something wrong stream
partition string expected yeah
we can finish this in 30 minutes for
sure so something wrong there so let's
double check
uh what what is the
string partition okay string partition
is wrong where I did here
so
a string pad right
we add we we make sure
there are
each line of the crates string has this
number of characters
then we string partition
oh yeah so this string partition here
this needs this part the first argument
needs to be a function remember so the
function since you are using the
Ampersand Ampersand whatever previous
mix that a function or Lambda function
and the the pound sign is a shortcut to
stand for the argument so
this string partition
uh
is a function okay yeah so now let's
let's do it again
copy it
paste run it
that's what we want you see now we do
have empty elements for example
I'll put 19 show it in input form okay
slash slash is a like the Unix pipe it's
a post fixed notation so you see we got
empty strings so we need to remove that
Okay so
so X six
remove the empty string so uh again you
need to map and what what is the
function you need to use
um
you don't need the parentheses so you
want to
delete cases okay
delete cases take a list okay
uh take a list so that is our argument
for each of the line
then the what do you want to delete
empty string okay that we are deleted
and let's try it so here should be X5
fantastic okay now once we delete so so
so far this represent the stack and we
need to remove that one two three
because you know that that is just a
indicator so
X7 uh
okay so actually so I don't need that so
drop
it takes two arguments the first
argument is the argument I mean is a
list and you want to drop the first item
okay so that's how you do it
now you want to drop the last item so
not first
so let's do it again
fantastic this is this represents the
stack NZ DCM
oh oh we forgot the step we forgot the
yeah so right now they are rows they are
you know so you can see zmp
zmp we forgot to do the transposition so
we need to do the transposition before
we
do the delete cases the empty string so
um
so I think you do the transposition
transpose okay not plot range trends
pose okay
yeah so you just say
let's put it here
so that we don't have to change all the
variable
so transpose takes a square
Matrix which is at least at least then
rows becomes columns okay
so let's try that X3
that's right you see that is what we
want
and now you can remove all the brackets
okay then you delete
you delete cases
uh yeah you remove the empty lines
then you you want to drop the last item
Okay so
in fact we can drop the last item before
we do transpose
so here
so here we want to add a function here
and apply it to that to that so the
function will be this drop okay at the
add Ampersand to make a function and the
pound sign stand for the argument so
this line it works like U map string
trim to X3 then you apply this function
drop
to to drop the row
one two three
then you do transpose okay so let's test
that
that's right you see NZ DCM p n z d c m
p yeah so
and now we remove the brackets okay
remove the brackets and now we
delete the cases empty string okay so
basically we so what is this X4 so X5
and X6
try it
fantastic NZ
dcmp nzdcmp so we got our stack
okay so let's shrink the lines so let's
shrink the lines
okay so that's a bunch of lines we don't
need you know we can make it into one
line like yesterday but let's not
so remove that
so now we need to apply this English
procedure
to our stack
so
what we can do is we first of all we
extract we remove the move from two you
know things like that remove them so
so we just want a list of numbers okay
so one two one three one three two two
one one one two things like that so
first of all
string replace okay takes two arguments
the first argument is the meet the
second argument is how you want it to
replace so we want to replace by
okay let's just type it so we want to
replace move
space
to
empty
empty string okay that's one thing
then second thing third thing the second
thing is gonna be form
space form space okay to empty then
space two space to empty okay so let's
see let's say X7 okay
oh and what is uh yeah so let's try it
fantastic
X7 pivot 2 input form so we can see the
quote there it is
okay
so actually we should leave the space
so that we can string split
yeah let's leave the space okay leave
one space
so move
so we want to remove the move space yeah
then
form
okay then and then let's do that okay
let's try it again
okay that's that's
you know that's uh so for example
any guys watching comments okay so we
got that very nice
one to one yeah very nice now we just do
X8
equals to we want to split string again
okay two arguments the first one is X7
and how do you want to split you just
want to split by space by default that
that is split by space
okay so we got a list of least
so each one of the element the sublist
represents a procedure okay
uh
so for example let's take uh this the
first one one two one you know this one
two one so that means
that means
pop from stack two
pop one item out then add that item to
stack number one
and do this
one times okay
Okay so
so a X8 will be let's name them uh
procedure
uh gist okay
so
so that's just a list of numbers you
know it's a list of three numbers now we
are going to write a function that takes
these These are three numbers as input
then we just apply this function to our
stack
you know to our to to the
to the to this to the stacks we created
there
then we got the result okay let's write
a procedure the procedure is going to be
something like that we did yesterday so
in Python it's very easy
but because Wolfram language do not have
drop and push for at least
so
so let me explain this one okay so
yesterday we did uh let's see python
so for example here is the example in
Python all you have to do for X in range
one to p p is the first
how many times move
you know to do it so for range exiting
A2 1 to P you just stack list and Dot
push then stack list m dot pop so you
know here is the move p number of times
from M to n
so in Python that's what you have to do
so you just write a function that takes
p m n okay so we are doing we are going
to do the same thing
but in Wolfram language
pop you know let me write this out
okay I already returned yesterday so
push and pop in Wolfram language now
there is no direct analog of push and
pop
by the way pop means takes at least
pop that at least means return the first
element of the list but also drop that
element from the list in the variable
and Save in a variable so there's no
direct analog in from language of Pop
however what you do is you do first that
extract the first element then you call
drop that remove the first element in a
list then you call set because we from
language is a functional language so
whenever you do something to a list it
doesn't change nothing
if you want to change the list variable
that that stores the list you have to
reset it back to the list just like lisp
this also works this way except in this
you do have push and pop because this is
based on linked list
so in Wolfram language you don't have
that so you so we know you know the
operation pop is equivalent to these
three operations that's why
yesterday we went into a tangent about
90 minutes on how to implement stack
efficiently
now the way I'm going to do it here now
is not efficient you know meaning that
if you you have 1 million Stacks each
stack has 1 million items
so when when you have that situation in
real life you know process Twitter
input up you know that's not efficient
but for this toy problem even 10 000
input ten thousand eight Stacks that's
not not a problem it's gonna be done in
one second okay but so let's just
quickly finish this then we go on to
about Implement implementing a efficient
stack in Python in JavaScript in Wolfram
language to see there's any actual
difference you know how many
how many stack items let's say one
million does it actually make a
difference you know let's check okay but
first of all let's write this simple
thing
so do so in order to do this in one step
I mean if we're gonna do this so
move p number of items from stack M to
Stack n
okay I don't like the M and N because
they uh
uh they they
let's change should we let's
okay let's use M and
n
mountain and uh
no
so far so good how is going Craig and
Doc where are you from the Greg and dog
report age sex location so I get to know
you like you know roughly you are 10 you
are 20 something you are 30 something
you are probably young people I mean you
are probably a young guy
God
apple juice
and tea okay fantastic
uh
okay
procedure numbers okay let's name that
procedure numbers
um so this is
let's document its document a little bit
so that people watching these
kind of have a sense
okay
and X7
let's say what is X7
X7 is like that okay let's copy that
so people know what's going on here
uh
yeah and X6 let's do X6
okay
copy that
so it's clear okay so that's X6 is
Stacks X7 is the
list of strings then procedure numbers
X8 is this okay
uh then
then we write a function yeah so what
the function do
so you first item is you take the first
item of list of stacks of M
then for the list of stacks of M
stack U
drop it
yeah you drop it
drop the first item then assign it back
and for the nth item you prepend which
is push
okay
you push the first item so the first
item can you don't need a variable there
so
let's let's just write it
you don't you don't need a variable
there so but you need to reverse the
order
you need to do this first
okay so we can be getting
hope you guys see what I'm doing so you
see that's that's kind of simpler
so
so for the stack in
you have to assign it by prepending it
uh an item from M the first item then
for the stack M you drop it drop the
first item okay so that that is what you
have to do
and you have to do these P times okay so
now let's write a function that takes
the argument n m p just to do this okay
so
so how do you call this move
okay let's just say move
okay move f move that's a function
so the function body will basically be
that
okay uh f move
okay something like that so f move takes
three arguments okay
p
m
n
okay
now by the way this is a procedural
programming style which is not
recommended in Wolfram language you know
this these two whenever you you know
typically you never used to
so so I can do it you know I can
I can use a functional style to do this
but let's push on you know we don't want
to end up three hours
so this function
is using pattern matching
so this this definition means whenever
Wolfram language sees something like
that f move square bracket
curly braces then three items then it
will automatically replace that
symbiotic sequence
by
this symbolic sequence and execute that
symbolic sequence this is what timely
writing means or in this
if you are familiar with this this is
um
if you are familiar with this this is a
macro you know this is actually at least
macro
you know these people don't know but
this is this is a
in fact is this macro okay
the very simple one just like this okay
so but
um
okay so when you define your
pattern like that usually you want to
say clear
because you might have defined other
markers or other rules for the f move
so you know when you define this it
doesn't override whatever previous it
just adds another rule so that's why you
is a good always a good idea to
uh do a clear first when you
use a pattern to define a function okay
so let's double check one more time
where is our list of stacks
let's see
yeah so
where uh
so list of stacks
yeah so let's let's name this f x 6 is
as list of stacks okay
so that's all these sub Stacks that's
right
okay then once we Define this function
all we have to do is call it we want to
X
answer
okay equals to
map a function
what you want to map it to you want to
map to this list of procedural procedure
numbers okay that's a list of
numbers like that
oh actually it's a string so let's
change those string into a number so you
have to do is say two expression
okay two expression
then we put this inside okay but you
know but but there's a simpler way to do
that
you can just say add sign remember SI is
a syntactical shortcut so instead of
writing F square bracket something you
can just say F add something
100 it's a syntactical shortcut in
Wolfram language now in classic lisp
McCarthy's lisp he have the idea this
synthetical shortcut he calls it meta
expression or m-e-x-p
that's the original
John McCarthy's this it's called meta
expression look up on Wikipedia you'll
find it okay so who from language is the
actual
the actual list that Implement
implemented that language that this meta
expression the other list didn't do this
they just have reader markers which is
somewhat similar but immature much
smaller scale
so so we can do that okay
so let's evaluate this again so we can
actually see it
okay now let's try X8
uh
okay now input form so you can actually
see there are numbers because you don't
see the double quote Okay so
so now copy that
and copy that and put it here
so it's no longer a string it's actual
numbers okay delete that
okay so procedural numbers
you want to map a function to
these procedural numbers and what this
function the function is f move
okay I think that's it so let's try this
let's just try this part
incorrect
pass specification
list of stacks
did we
um oh yeah we didn't Define it that's
right that's right piece of stacks you
see we change we renamed our X8 so now
we have to do it
so let's do it
copied it
paste here
run it run it
so far so good fantastic and let me show
you a extra trick you see this input
you see this this cell
you know this code we can make it look
prettier you see now notice this right
arrow Dash great and greater than equal
sign we can predify
that it will become an arrow and also
things like this double square bracket
okay so let me do it
Ctrl shift n
there it is
now this is another B format okay too
bad too bad it changed that into you
know it changed this part into that but
however you see
now this this means the first part the
first element of X1 this means the
second element you see and the arrows
becomes arrows
now if you have square roots or Square
or third power or square root nested
square root they become you know
mathematical formula or integration or
you know pretty
uh okay and also uh see the numbers the
number sign the pound sign the hash sign
they become hash one because the hash
is equivalent to Hash one which stands
for the first argument so if you have a
function of two arguments you then you
can say hash one hash two in whatever
order
you see remember this
this Ampersand is a shortcut to
represent a function
the the full form of writing a function
let me show you okay
let's say we want to write function of
adding one okay so first of all one
variable X and return
X plus one okay that's how you write a
function then you can assign it by F
something okay now
there's a shortcut for that
you can just say
uh let's let me do it okay
there that's the shortcut you see the
pound sign stands for the argument
and so this means the argument plus one
and that Ampersand just means whatever
whatever previous is a function
you know so you can put the parent there
but it's not necessary because the
operated precedence the equal has a
lower presidents so so this will become
one thing then you assign that thing to
F okay that's uh
explanation of the shortcut there are
many many more but I'm not going to go
over I have the
okay for those of you interested just go
to
Language tutorial you can find it by
searching
then you can just you can see all
syntax shortcuts or in lisp jargon The
Meta expression of Wolfram language you
can see all of them by
here okay so
Advanced symbol principles syntax there
you click on that I did a full video
talk on that so you can see explanation
of
the you see every possible syntactical
shortcut
also known as meta expression is listed
here
so you can see all of them so for
example the
the percent the percent sign actually
stands for out
out is like a function takes one
argument a number so out negative one
means the last
output
two percentage sign is a shortcut for
out negative two you know very
convenient so
again if you go back you see every input
output is the is is numbered
so this output is not just a display it
is actually assigned
to a function out square bracket 24.
you know that's that's the Wolfram
language okay so you know before we were
talking about function you see the slash
slash is a post-fixed notation so when
you have X slash slash F that stands for
f square bracket X okay so you have the
post-fix notation just like the Unix
pipe you also have a prefix notation
the add sign then you have the slash ad
which is which is equivalent hundred
percent equivalent to the map FX
and before we talked about function so
you also have function composition uh
for example before we talk about
function you see
the ampersand
sign it's magnify
you see prefix postfix you also have
infix then you have the pound sign
standing for the argument so the full
name the full form for the pound sign is
actually slot one
so you can say you can have also a pound
sign your number you know we we did that
okay so you know so this page is a
complete detail about the Wolfram
language syntax or The Meta syntax or
shortcut form you know you move from
language it's called input form
full form you know you can read it and
watch that video
go hit the gym I'm pretty fit
actually
so
so what is the next okay
so so far so good we so so far so good
yes then we just um
need to compute
these
let's try it
we Define the procedure
and uh
okay incorrect no
oh actually that's correct you see
because this procedure f move it doesn't
it doesn't actually return anything
because I put the same icon it doesn't
return anything like I said this is a
procedural programming
while in functional programming every
function always returns something you
need input output input applied to a
function to it return the output and use
the output that's how functional that's
the essence of functional programming
doesn't matter it's lisp Haskell wolfam
language erlan doesn't matter the what
what is the single most fundamental
criteria for functional programming
that would be
every computation
is done by a function call where you
take the input and you take the output
every computation okay if you don't do
that if you use you know if you your
function do things with side effects
such as here
you know you are doing something you
don't care about the return value for
example in JavaScript
often it's a case you take array then
you dot
for each
in Python you also have that or you use
the four you know four
in range something
you know you you don't actually care
about output you just want to do
something in a loop that's not
functional programming okay so in the
more pure a functional programming the
more or less of that so in fact Haskell
you don't have that at all
so anyway so here is a functional
procedure
but now we can check our stack to see if
it changed anything so our stack is here
so we just say the value of M
list of stacks let's see
fantastic
CMZ c m z n d p let's check if that
answer is correct
fantastic so success
okay
solved the problem number
you know day five number one okay so the
answer is
um let's modify these
we we call that function and the answer
is actually just
we don't need actually so it just
modified the list of stacks so that's
not functional programming which is not
good but because of this problem
you know it actually kind of requires
procedural programming because that's
what these instructions are
but can we do it in a functional way yes
by by not setting things so we so we
don't want to do push and we don't want
to do pop
instead instead when you do push or pop
you just want to want the function to
return the new thing and work on that
new thing you never change you never
change your value of a variable that's
functional programming okay but we we
already got lots of things on you know
we need to implement efficient way to do
pushing the
pop of efficient stack data structure so
let's
not worry too much about
these now okay so here is a solution
now we want to solve the real problem
okay so the real input so first of all
paste it here
okay
and
Ctrl shift n to make it pretty
so now we just need to change this part
to the real input okay let's get them
pump this back
and
go to yesterday's talk show
search for input
so a domain of code so this is the input
500 lines copy it
back to roof and paste it okay now press
shift enter you'll get the result
oh we forgot to suppress the output so
it's gonna be long okay so here is a
result
so what does it
uh
so here's the results
um
close that
so but
what does the what does it
it need required results so you just
conjoin you just join in the string so
you need at least two string okay so
this two string is easy so let's do it
cool fan language
okay we want to
um
is at least two string
no
so what is the proper function
what do you what you want is uh you know
a bunch of nested lists to a single
string
so let's go look at string functions
if you are watching say hi okay
tell me how am I doing am I
communicative am I doing good
least to string so Wolfram language very
interesting they have a kind of a
strange
function name
string rifle or stream rifle
as this basically this function is list
to string
uh
so and this function is actually new so
it was it is introduced in 2015.
know I've been coding Wolfram language
since 1993.
so up to 2004 you know I haven't been
using it for like 15 years but
anyway this function is introduced in
2015.
uh kind of strange name like I I don't
know what rifo means before
refill
Iraqi show or Sandbar lying just below
the surface of an Ocean Way a stretch of
choppy water caused by such a Shore or
sandbar
a rapid
a wave or Reaper in such water very
strange why do they call it
um string refill
you see it creates a string by
concoction
concatenating or the you know at least
all the elements in at least
with his spaces insert between them okay
I don't want space
okay let's just do it then
so does anyone know
why is it called string refill
let's see there must be some
digression let's go to dictionary this
is my favorite dictionary I'm very
obsessive and picky about dictionary
because I literally
look up dictionary a few hundred times a
day in the 90s in an 80 1800s and 90s
literally
few hundred times a day by a paper
dictionary of this thick Chinese English
to Chinese so then I switched to all
English dictionary but the Habit
remained for with me for like 30 years
even today I
I look up often so I've looked you know
I've read I literally read lots of
dictionaries like almost cover to cover
so
I have particular taste and judgment on
which one is better and so on
and let me just say the Miriam Miriam
West Webster which is most popular
online today that's the worst okay that
is the worst dictionary because it's a
you know what you see the
Merriam-Webster online dictionary which
is the most popular today that is
actually that came from
Miriam Webster's concise dictionary of
English or in other words Collegiate
also known as Collegiate dictionary so
it's a Abridged dictionary so
when you look up you know with
Merriam-Webster like the definition are
very tough Concepts a brief Abridged you
know you know that's a proper word so
it's
so often oftentimes when you have a word
you don't know
hit
it does it does not properly give you
the the the context the the nuances of
the world anyway I can tell you it's the
worst okay because and also they
then also for political reasons they
tend to be you know they Market that's
why they are the most popular you know
they Market widely aggressively
but it's a worst dictionary okay
Merriam-Webster
but the full unabridged Merriam-Webster
now if you actually buy it you know it's
like this thick big book that's good
okay that that is good not not the
online the concise or Collegiate one is
the worst
so if you have a knack on writing on
literature on English you know uh you
want to
do not read Merriam-Webster you know
it's the worst lousy one what's the best
one American Heritage dictionary okay
that's
okay let me show you an article
so if you just go through
sunny.org
okay then you have this same this
section worthy English
then you have this section dictionary
geeking okay so I have
one two three four more than four I have
also entire vocabulary you know so
anyway there's four articles
that reviews dictionaries so if you read
this page this page is in detail you'll
know
you know you know why uh the
Merriam-Webster is the worst one okay
uh you know
okay so go check them out I give you
lots of definitions comparisons and you
okay and by the way there's also open
source one that's that's even worse
okay I mean the all the Linux people
they get excited about
dick dog dick
.org lots of problems
uh incompetent
okay that's a digression of our
dictionary yeah so but what is refill
uh let's see games to shuffle playing
cards by holding part of a deck in each
hand and raising up the edges before
releasing them to fall alternatively in
one stack
no Shuffle yeah
you call it refo okay
go to thumb through
so yeah so I don't get it you know
usually the Wolfram language function
names
I very much agree on
but I don't get why joining stream from
at least is called rifle
does anyone know
yeah I cannot see why is this called
string riffle
okay but let's let's do it
so okay hold on a second so we have the
input
okay
run it
what is the what is that
yeah okay just add empty lines
why does it add empty lines oh yeah
because you want to say
no separator
oh okay so you actually need to
[Music]
oh so it actually refills
you see when you have a nested list it
actually add the first one followed by
the first element of the second list
then the second element from the first
one then second so they actually refers
okay so that's that's not what we want
so we want let's see
DQ
uh
[Music]
let's just try this okay
empty string empty string
maybe now walk
that's what we want
select it
copy it
are you sure I think I'm pretty sure
it's submit
yo then well it's it's got a string
so actually
copy that
Senegal paste
are you sure yes
the right answer
[Music]
I'm doing this because I have isi so too
much typing for the past
10 or 30 years in particular past 10
years
what is the oh wait you need you
just need the top one
that's obviously
you just you don't need all the stack
you just need the
the yeah the first element of each stack
okay
of course
so let's
put this back
and in fact let's delete that let's copy
that and let's work on our code again
so what you want to do is you
you have a list of stacks you want to
map
okay map
two arguments the second uh you want to
apply a function the first argument a
function to list of stacks and the
function will be just first you know
that takes the first item then
uh then you just
then you just um
do that okay
then you just refill Okay so
yeah okay so
copy all
paste run it
what's CMZ
are you kidding me
oh I forgot the the
full input
not the example input
so
talk show yesterday you want to get the
input so
copy the input
and
put it here
granite
go down go down
okay
hang on
oh god there it is
copy it
close
go here
let's actually the answer
the mid
that is the right answer you are one
gold star okay let's continue to part
two
so we talked for 80 minutes already
70 minutes
okay who now who is watching me are you
still guys there are five people four
say something
five okay
now second problem it should be easy as
you watch the crane operator expertly
rearrange the crates you notice the
process isn't following your prediction
some mud was covering the writing on the
side of the crane some mud
and you quickly wipe it away the crane
isn't a great mover 9000. it's a great
mover 9001.
no what what is that what what's uh is
there a Insider joke
so the crate mover 9001 is notable for
many new and exciting features air
conditioning leather seats
irrelevant
an extra cup holder and the ability to
pick up and move multiple grades at once
okay they are trying to change the the
move you know the
they are they are trying they are
fundamentally changing the way the
stacks are moved okay so again
considering considering the example
above the crates beginning in the same
configuration moving a single crate from
stack two to one behaves the same as
before however the action moving three
crates from stack 1 to stack three
means that those three moved crates stay
in the same order
I guessed I knew it's going to do that
he idiot resulting in this new
config Okay Nexus both crates are moved
from stack 2 to stack 1 they retain
their order as well yeah so now the
Great
can move
more number of the crane can move more
number of items in one shot so they
don't reverse the order
finally a single query is still moved
from stack 1 to stack two but now it's
great to see
that gets moved yeah okay so in this
example the crater mover 9001 has put
the crates in a totally different order
McD
so before the original processing an
updating your simulation so that yeah
that helps this is the center the the
ringing deer this is the the after the
rearrangement procedure completes what
creates ends up on top of each stack
so all we have to do is to change this
part
you know this function okay let's do it
so this this problem one okay
let's go back
copy it paste it
now
let's do this again
change this part copy it paste it okay
let's see so
p is not number of times anymore so p is
something else
okay
pre-paint least of stacks and so so okay
so
so it's not do anymore so let's remove
the two okay
let's not do anymore so
so this p is number of stacks to move in
one shot
oh okay so it's much it's actually
simpler so number of stacks from M to n
so
um
so you move
P of number of them from n m to n Okay
so
so let's do that so you move from m
so first so you have a drop situation
okay
actually so you need to assign it
so you drop but before you drop you want
to actually take the numbers so
so you instead of drop you say take
okay
you take
the
P items from stack m
that means Returns the first P items
wait so you take
from 1 to p
one two P so let's check what is take
let's look at the documentation
install JavaScript
okay take the first n items
so you don't actually you just you can
just say p
take the first P items
so
um
wait so because it's functional
programming so you need to um so you
take the first items then you drop
you take those items P items then you
drop them
yeah you
and you assign them back to him
then those newly taken items you need to
put add to end so you need to prepend
that's right
so this line is to go to go first
so the new in stack in
one in one stack
nanny
the new stack the the new stack nanny is
going to be prepending
the stack Nanny by taking P items from
stack
Mountain okay
so yeah
you take p number of items from stack
Mountain
prepended to
the stack nanny
and that will be the new stack value of
Nanny okay then now you just need to
drop
the first P items in stack
Mountain okay so you don't need this
part anymore
so this
is
that is a function okay now we can put a
module
okay uh let's take a width okay
width is like a
declare constant except there's no
constant basically we just group them
and you can also group them by and we
don't need it
okay so this is the new
function okay
so you don't need this this is original
this is new
now double check one more time we're
gonna run it one shot and it's going to
be correct
right
okay remove that
copyhole
back to Fan language paste
run
Okay so
something wrong
okay
something wrong here
PM in
what
part the expression M cannot be used as
a part specification
I think
I think I may know
okay let's try it again
through this
and now
let's do this
and I think I maybe you need
rain okay let's just copy all and do it
again
okay now we run into this issue when the
stack is empty you know there's no first
item
so let's see McD
is the answer what
MCD is the answer but we got
CM which is
incorrect
okay
Okay so
uh
from stack in
to in
let's see what is uh thing do we
okay
okay let's apply
does the procedure still the same so one
from two to one
one from two to one so we got D and z c
m p
okay
and now
oh
oh that's right you forgot something I
forgot something
oh yeah so because there is the
so that's about
we can easily solve it by just flatten
okay
yeah let's see prepend you know this is
the issue that when you
add
several elements to at least
sometimes it's added as a sub list
sometimes it just ignore the list you
just add elements this happens in Python
in parallel in other languages
in JavaScript so you have to make sure
you know depending on the function or
the methods sometimes they flatten it
sometimes they don't
very annoying problem
so here
yeah so when you prepend
prepend elements okay
you want to pre-pin elements yeah
or you can use pre-pin 2.
see they
okay I'm going to I'm just going to do
this okay let's
just going to say map to arguments
map that
this is gonna be a function
map this function for each one
you know this result is is a list this
is very Innovation by the way so
and in fact you can say prepend two so
let's try this
hold on a second let me clean this up so
you can see better so this is old code
the new code is gonna be here
so the new code is this prepend two okay
so you don't need that so between two
then
then that okay
use a new code
I don't think that will work
because the pre-pin 2 here let's just
say print pin
okay that should work
so here's a new one
and
let's remove the whole one okay
uh wait a second
yeah this doesn't work God when you work
with snacks
you really need a stack data structure
even each one
yeah so actually you need to actually
put this inside
yeah then we'll walk
you do that multiple times
hmm
very inefficient this is not the way to
do with language but it's just
do it
okay
all right we're getting tired and this
is getting into true it's it's incorrect
again
and T3
oh yeah because we got their function
wrong you need a paren
it's getting complex this is not the
right way to do it
but right now I just want the answer CMZ
shut the up
MCD yeah it's wrong again
MCD what
okay we need to think about this
okay let's screen up the code
take those items
oh here you pretend you actually
reversed all the idiotic
yeah you reverse the order when you do
it this way
so you want to so yeah
I don't know if you guys know what I
mean but
no questions I'm just gonna code it
you take this part you want to prepend
now
why you see
this is not really suitable in who fam
language because you can see
this pre pen they don't even take a
they don't even take a argument I mean
they are
the second argument which is
you know usually
usually every function in Wolfram
language when they take a list
they will just apply to every element of
the list but here it's a single element
you know there is no form where this
second element can be released why the
reason is because
um well it's a design issue it's you
know it's basically just because the
Wolfram list is not suitable for this
kind of thing
so what you want to do
basically right now you want to join
yeah join is the proper yeah John is a
proper um
function
so you can see here is the example of
join
yeah you don't want to use prepend you
want to join
so
so let's rewrite this function
that equals to
join
that and the
okay so you take the first M items I
mean the you take the first p number of
items of Stack Mountain then you prepend
it to the stack
then you assign the bat that value to
the stack in okay so that is how
we can do this so let's remove these
things we don't need
no need map anymore then the second part
is just that okay so we can do that
okay so that is our function
Papio
let's do it
McD
[Music]
that's the right answer but let's fix
something else because sometimes when
the stack is empty
you cannot call the first
Okay so
so you want a function that takes the
first element of a list
however when the list is empty you don't
want it to return error okay so how do
you fix that
we can fix that by using pattern
matching
but uh but let's look at the
if there is some
if the Wolfram shows
um
it shows some solution
or if we uh
and we can do a if statement here but
that wouldn't be good
yeah let me show you okay let me show
you a technique something interesting a
technique of pattern matching so now the
problem is that
the problem is that you want to take the
first element of a bunch of beasts
you know list of stacks that's a list of
least each you know that's a list of
least so if there's no first element
don't return error how do you do that
okay we can do it this way
so you start by that and you want to
apply the
this slash dot means replace all
and then you wanna say
at least
first okay whatever
then the second part is anything we
don't care one or more zero or more
three
low lines character okay then replace it
by
uh
replace it by Just A Plus t
so that will
do that yeah
actually I'm not sure you could maybe
turn the empty list let's see
no comments anyone no comments
so here
let's say result stack equals two
these substance
and then it's
we need to
let's modify these
so it doesn't actually change anything
yeah that's not okay let's don't do that
so
you have at least
you want to get the first element
but if the list is empty don't return
any error how do you do that
easy the symphony solution is to use the
if statement okay
if
length
argument
equals to zero then
then what do you do here return an empty
list
otherwise
first
that thing okay this is now a function
so
you can just
do it this way that will return the
result
okay now there are other ways but
um I'm gonna I was going to show you
pattern matching but um
but let's let's get the result let's get
the answer for now
okay that's you know McD
okay let's do this for the real input
okay
let's do this for the real input so
open open open
pump here this is a real input copy
close close okay go back here
select that
paste okay now let's add semicolon to
suppress the long output
suppress long output
okay do it
yeah I forgot to suppress that one
okay so here is answer am I confident
yeah
let's do it I'm pretty confident hello
Sam
okay hey shut up
submit yeah I'm confident and it's just
did we do it
enter
that's the right answer you are one
ghost star closer to collecting enough
stuff here okay we finished the day five
day five problem a and problem B that's
it for
this video
now I'm going to do a next video
okay so what time is it it's it's two
o'clock so this is two hours
so I'm going to start the next video
uh in two hours
so you know I can actually YouTube so
I'm going to start the next video in two
hours okay and that video is going to be
we are going to implement a linked list
in Python in JavaScript and in Wolfram
language all three I'm gonna do it for
sure and I'm going to we are going to
test whether
using the linked list as a stack data
structure is more efficient than just
using Python's default list
okay we are going to push a lot items in
popular item saying and we'll see
um yeah so
in two hours in two hours we're gonna do
that I'm going to create a video and I'm
going to post it on
scored and I'm gonna also announce it on
uh
saw on Twitter okay
okay that's it for today
so
into in about two hours you'll see my
announcement on Twitter and Discord I'm
gonna do another video exploration of
the efficient stack structure
okay in Python JavaScript and the
Wolfram language
so that's it for today by the way
yesterday I did a very interesting I did
a poll
on functional language Haskell versus or
camel okay so you can see we did a poor
and that pole hit jackpot that pole
here's the result
Deadpool has
uh
937 votes close to a thousand votes so
it's rare for me so and I asked people
to post their reason why a camel or
Haskell and a lot
Experts of java of Haskell or camel they
give their reasons very interesting
my own conclusion is I'm I'm always um
I I think maybe a pickup or camo again I
did a camera study some 15 years ago but
I never actually went far so I'm
thinking maybe you know because today
maybe I'll do a camera I also did some
Haskell but never never went far like I
know Haskell in our camera since 1997.
you know so
you know since 1997 back on news groups
and there's there's a lot of others you
know today you guys don't know you know
because for example there's Maran
moranda which at the time Miranda in
1990s is the most popular commercial
version of
pure functional programming Miranda and
clean okay let me let me show you since
I'm talking about this topic
Miranda language okay
back in 1990s Miranda programming
language is the most popular and most
successful
functional programming language
and
and it's commercial okay it's commercial
it's not open source you know this is
1990s and this
this
Miranda language is the main reason
Haskell was created
okay
because it's very popular commercial in
1990s remember 1990 is not like today
because the CPU are not as fast the ram
the maximum RAM you can get is like
256 megabytes in 1991.
256 megabytes
Ram 1991 okay by year 2000 you might
have one gigabyte I forgot but today
it's like six six gigabytes anyway so in
1990s Miranda is very popular then
Haskell is a from a bunch of academics
you know programming language
researchers so they want the version
but Miranda is commercial so you know
they are trying to create a
version of functional language you know
so Miranda is very similar to Haskell
and there's also a
very very successful popular thing okay
a pure functional programming language
and this cleaning programming language
is based on uh term rewriting system
graph rewriting system okay in 1990s and
also it also supports lazy evaluation
just like Haskell okay so these are all
you know these are at this time you know
around year 2000
Miranda
and cream they are far more Superior
than escal okay far more Superior
you know Haskell even in 2010 is still
kind of lousy
you know
but time has changed you know Microsoft
begin in 2003 they started F sharp
so anyway you know that so F sharp
that's the first commercial by a giant
corporation that actually embraced
functional programming and we functional
programmer Fanatics we are like oh my
God thank you finally finally the C and
C plus plus Java idiots they you know
finally they can
see function of the you know functional
programming
anyway that's history so so I want to
say so Miranda
clean
and uh or camo okay or camo also these
three are the superior
functional programming languages in
1990s even back in 1990s now today
Miranda
kind of died you never heard of you know
so you know it like in 2020 a version of
Miranda was released as open source it's
kind of late okay it killed you know
these here's a story another story about
open source Open Source Kill a lot of
superior things open source and free
software Foundation they are a scan
you know when I was back in year 2000 I
was a Fanatics of Richard Stroman and
you know I believe in his
ethical qualities you know in fact
between the war of Open Source and free
software Foundation I'm a fan of free
software Foundation just like Richard
Stroman I'm a fan of Richard Stroman and
I was waiting for his new herd operating
system
after 30 years never came to be okay
gunu heard
and Richard Stoneman became this Guru
you know when I was young I believed in
you know like a lot of you guys you know
um yeah yeah and uh you know now I'm 50
something you know I'm a few more years
I'm done for programming you know um
so that's history so I'm telling you
guys my kind of my experience so back in
90s Miranda is the top quality function
of programming pure okay and clean also
cream is made in Netherlands I think
Netherlands something northern Europe
okay
also commercial
and it also got killed by open source
what else open source killed open source
killed POS
today you might heard of a
Haiku OS okay
POS got killed but got wiped out by open
source and apples apples lots of
networking protocols lots of things okay
anyway boss has got killed by open
source
Miranda got killed by open source clean
got cured by open source you know clean
in 19 in in 1990 in year 2000 they tried
to oh we are going to release a open
source version too late
you know too late
and I got killed by a woman so screen
got killed by open source
uh also back then in 1990s erlan is
another highly successful
superly used in commercial world
in commercial Enterprise
okay
so erlan about maybe five or ten years
ago they also released as open source
but they also luckily Orlando didn't get
killed
hola is your viable language
but you know I'd so Miranda is kind of
dead you know actually I need to read up
what's up you know what what's their
current status
um
clean is kind of dead you know like 20
20 years ago year 2000 I was so much you
know I so wish
and including Haskell you know how they
um I wish they become popular but anyway
so Miranda clean uh and oh come on those
are
highly successful in 19 in in late 1990s
okay
so anyway I was saying I so I did a poll
you know asking people about
uh about Haskell and
and uh where is it
yeah okay it turns out 1 000 votes and
lots of experts they gave their opinion
I I just I don't have much opinion you
know either one of them you know of
course I know them for 20 years but I
actually I wrote hello world you know
just a few but never got into so I'm
thinking maybe I'll start to
between these two I think I much favor
or camo you know I especially I don't
like Haskell okay and I particularly
despise The Fad these idiots they don't
know what they are saying they don't
know you know young people you know they
think Haskell is a pure oh lazy
evaluation
like just like I was 20 years ago when I
see Haskell you know lazy evaluation oh
this this must this is a solution this
is this is the most elegant this is the
answer we must use it this is you know
theoretical you know best thing lazy
evaluation
you know today you asked me I don't
think so I don't think so I don't want I
don't want lazy evaluation
okay so anyways you know I'm just saying
my experiences so
maybe I'll try to pick up my old camo
but
I'm not sure because I'm getting old
there's a lot of things for me to do I
want to actually write a passer passer
compiler for example the Emax with
three-seater I want to dive into that
possibly I'll create my own language or
something like that you know there's a
differential geometry and lots of uh
type proof systems proof Theory I want
to I need to get into homotopy type
Theory
you know that I hope that I become
somewhat an expert in that topic before
I die you know I don't have much time
you know five five years or or and and
Max 10 you know I'm getting old
type Theory and lots of mathematics
differential geometry in particular uh
improved you know type Theory uh
she finished in mathematics geometry and
so as far as programming language goes
well I'm interested but there's a
there's also Julia I'm highly interested
in Julia okay so if you guys young
people you want advice I would recommend
so on camo you can go into it's it's
very
uh it's used in you know by today it's
this photo camera and Haskell are used
in industry
not
not comparable to Golan for example or C
or C sharp sharp C plus first but
however they are fairly popular you can
get a job if you are truly good okay so
you can learn or camo or you can learn
Haskell you'll get a job or you can
learn closure you know you will get a
job if you are really good you know
study okay go study don't around
don't post memes or you know or or just
you know like you read Hacker News you
just pick up you know dreamers then you
post oh Haskell is this way no don't do
that like I did that
for 10 years when I was younger try not
to do that what instead Master one
language right through a project do that
for one year so you actually really
Master you know the language okay not
just oh let's suppose this I know that
that but you actually cannot code a
project okay code a project
for one year okay our camera is good has
Cog is good you can get both a job in
both and closure
if you are really good that's a key
Point okay there are a lot you know if
you are really good okay and then there
is also Julia Julia's language you know
which I I think they are also comparable
but I don't think there are many Julia
jobs yet okay so that's it for today so
in like I you know again in two hours
also a post announcement in two or three
hours I'll do another video on
trying to implement a efficient data
structure of stack in Python in
JavaScript in and in Wolfram language
okay thank you for watching go to my
website pay me okay if you like you know
support
um
you know go to my website you will see
my PayPal in patreon okay thank you guys
bye
okay there's opinion well I disagree
that's a