good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of our talk show today is 2020
Saturday June 6th and 4 o'clock 4:30 in
the afternoon San Francisco time so so
what is the topic today so let's go to
excel talk show and so type a topic ok
you type a topic in the video YouTube
chat else week I'm going to start to
talk random I'm gonna talk about some
keyboard and stuff random stuff going
through my blogs so first of all this
the background image now this is a
fantastic shell c shell now sea shells
are the most amazing thing okay let me
tell you about the sea shell good
morning I'll cook Luis and post good
morning Alan post your questions ok and
let's talk about sea shell you know the
sea shells are amazing I actually
started to collect them back in 2002 you
know that was at the time I was walking
so I you know I went to I went to ebay
or San Francisco you know I bought some
of these sea shells they are spectacular
you know they are the product of nature
and look at this one okay of course for
those of you who study sea shells
biology there are names too you know
there are people collecting seashells
so this one is Venus calm you can you
can imagine why is it imagine why is it
named that Venus come it's they are
extremely delicate actually I have it
here should I should I show it
because I recently I moved out of my
apartment which I lived for 12 years so
there's a box of seashells which I
haven't opened for 10 plus years so I
have to clean them up you know move them
so I found them let me know if you want
to see it okay so i bring you a bunch of
seashells a great seashells actually I
should but I want some reaction okay say
say yes okay am I am I am I going okay I
guess I am so seashells yeah they did
you know so I bought a bunch of them so
look at this you know they are product
nature you know it naturally happens so
look at this one tusk now this this one
is called tusk Chou it's just like an
elephant tusk and let me okay so let me
give you an introduction of seashells
why are they fascinating and this one is
tough shell this is called top shell
because it looks like a top
you know you spin it and look at the
bottom extremely fascinating and and so
you have varieties of spiral shape now
look at this one okay this one is
another beautiful beautiful one this is
pretty small tiny so I thought I got a
bunch of them I collected actually let
me go get them okay
type comments oh hey type here type okay
I only got four people watching so let
me get the seashells and let's see we'll
talk about
so what I have here is one bag what one
box of seashells let's see where's my
video and I'm going to show you this you
see this this so there is my keyboard
I'm going to talk about that this is my
keyboard let's see if I can make it
large
nah yeah okay I need to
actually I need to make it so hold on a
second okay give me a minute let me
adjust the video so you can see a big
one
you
so I was so the OBS crashed because
every time I try to adjust it it crashes
so let me try let me try to add a video
again video capture device
okay what a mess
so I should be back okay so
what a [ __ ] hi Freddie finally I got
someone say something so I'm going to
show you my seashells okay so you look
at the
okay so you look at my desk and there it
is [ __ ] oh god this is so [ __ ] up I
cannot
I'm just going to show you some of them
okay so you see this one this one is
heavy I need I need lighting okay so so
you see this one incredible incredible T
you see this is a scallop kind of shell
but you see it's it's got a needles over
overhead he can open up this is Andrew
from discord hey Andrew
so Andrew you have a question to ask me
ask your questions okay and be specific
and I'll talk about it and this is the
this is the Venus comp on a second you
see the the Venus comp very delicate
shall now the lighting and everything is
screwed up but and there is a tiny one
see there is a tiny one now so seashells
they are amazing they are incredible
they they are natural product and and
look at this one okay let me show you
some of these this one this is a monster
okay
now the camera sucks this is Logitech
hey Bart
good morning Bart to Germany so this
this purple now the camera really lousy
is really lousy so I cannot so it
doesn't show well and then you have this
one heavy you can hit someone with on
the head with this one none now you see
seashells they are all spirals
you know they are all sparrows but you
can see the variations in this in a
spiral for example this one they you
know the spyro spyro spyro and they are
they they got this kind of a cuffs or
how you call their fold you know in
spectacular you know nature produces
this you know if you know it sometimes
you we human animals makes trinkets like
decorative grasses or some dolls on your
you put on your desk and those are
pretty right let me show you the pattern
here of this one can you know the
[ __ ] logitech camera this is largely
tech nice something don't buy logitech
camera it sucks and expensive you know
it cannot focus supposed to be autofocus
but anyone look at the pattern [ __ ] that
doesn't this way okay now it's better
you see now you see this this shout so
they are all Spyros but they are amazing
the this one is heavy this is amazing
variety of the spirals and patterns on
it okay but now let me show you
something different now this this one is
very light this is called Barnett Shale
why is it called bonnet
I suppose it's like the bonnet hat or
something and and now look at this one
spectacular this is also very light and
fragile you know this some of them are
heavy for example this one is thick and
heavy like you cannot you cannot break
it work I guess you can if you throw it
so
but some of them are super fragile like
this one let me see if I can get it to
focus not really okay
factor geometry good collection of
shells okay yeah fractal geometry is you
know fractal geometry you know then you
we have the see stars you know
comparative comparatively they are not
as interesting then you have this one
heavy this one is another heavy one now
the thing is there are all varieties of
spirals and you can end this one you
know it's got patterns and shiny too but
there's one more thing I want to show
you let's see if I can find it then I
have like one bag of small ones like if
you look at the pictures on the web it's
hard to determine the sign and then you
have this variation you know this this
one is long like a school okay so okay
wait there's one most thing I want to
show you then there's one more very good
there a dead delicate one
oh here you see this one this this one
you know amazing this one look at this
one okay
now how do you imagine guess how much it
weights this one weights about one gram
so it's like it's its it weights about
like two pieces of paper like one piece
of paper so super light and fragile in
this one so this one so now that's about
my seashells okay
let me show you let me let me turn the
camera back and let me show you the
pictures
okay for the camera back so there is
this box you are looking at you know
this box this is hewlett-packard I
supposed to be originally was a bunch of
cables or a keyboard or something okay
let's go back to the the the pictures of
seashell and you can see how they are
varieties of spirals you know you have
the super long one and you have the very
flat one then you have this this tusk
one with very little twist
okay they are so we are talking about
the general shape of the spiral then you
have the decorations on the shower I
mean like they for example they quo
spikes like this one and then then this
one you see this kind of fold I showed
you this one before it kind of helps has
this kind of fold and this one by the
way this is a this is a fossil this is
actually a fossil I don't know how many
years old it could be 1,000 years old
some things you know my my aunt my aunt
gave it to me this one is from Taiwan
so the variety of the the general
variety of the shape of the spiral you
have flat you have little tryst you have
you know long spiral or then you have
the decorations on the on the shell like
like spikes spikes and fold spikes and
fold and this one folding and this one
you okay this one crumb but it's like
crumbled you know variation of those
spiral this one is superlight like 1 1
gram like 2 piece of papers then you
have then let's talk about about the
patterns on the shell you see then you
have these patterns now according to
Stefan Wolfram these patterns are
generated by cellular automata now look
at this this one is heavy I also have it
there you see the the patterns are
generated by cellular automata and look
at this one I showed this one before so
now we can look at a mathematical model
of these shells now now there is a
equation that describe this oh this one
is fantastic look at the the spiral the
six they are extremely beautiful and by
the way these are cheap you know if you
go to ebay in there are three dollars or
five dollars but if you actually go to
San Francisco or some you know some
souvenir place it's cheaper you can find
all these are not expensive at all and
also I took this photo back in 2002 a
snail this is an actual photo of a snail
without a Photoshop I you know it's a
snail on a white paper plate you know we
have snails in a garden
so it's you know it's also these
seashells to me it's amazing it's it's
kind of an amazing then you have okay
then you have this the x-ray of the
shells you can see the inside the shells
the trysting they also have trysting
inside the shells okay so that's about
seashells but let me show you some
mathematical models of the shells so
then we're gonna answer the questions
okay so I back then in around 2002 I
actually bought this book this is a big
giant photographic book you know I
bought it like 20 years ago so let me
show you the Mathematica okay so hold on
a second so
yeah and we have this cutting half view
cutting half view of the show you can
see there's twisting inside it and this
is this type of shower is called cow we
show how we shall and you see the
twisting inside and this one spectacular
you see this spiral you see that one you
know one of the most fundamental thing
interesting about them is the shape the
general shape of the spiral so this one
is you know very angular it's almost
like a staircase and yet then you see
this one and you see this one this one
is called angular winter trap I don't
have this one but there are people
collecting seashells
you know they collect them then you can
see this one the technical name for this
is not la Texas Markway something like
that I don't have this one okay so now
let's look at the math models so you see
this one this is strong in Mathematica
and here is the parametric formula you
can actually plot it I did this one you
well it requires some programming so
because you want to show part of it as
transparent so I did this one long time
ago 20 years ago and
yeah so you know it would be interesting
if you can come up come up with a
formula now this is actually would be a
great exercise for for you guys who's
studying calculus not even calculus you
know just try to come yeah it's a good
puzzle try to come up with a formula
that will draw for example draw this one
wait what for example draw this one come
up with a formula a parametric formula
you know X Y Z you plot in 3d X is a
function x equals to a function y equals
to a function Z equals to a function a
function of two variables usually U and
V okay so you plotted you so you want to
create a parametric formula that that
rows this one you know with with stripes
on it and also you can try to come up
come up with a formula that draws this
one so that's the thing that's my point
you know you want to come up with a
formula that that draws varieties of
these spirals that would be a great
exercise okay I haven't done it and and
you know over the years someone has sent
me formulas you know but I didn't got to
talk to them much
okay let me read the comments in this
see where we go now
what's going on with my video stupid
YouTube
okay so hi everyone
connection of shells did you collect
them or yourself yeah back in about 20
years ago 2002 in California yes some
some of them I think most of them like
80% of them I bought on eBay in 2002
I think you can still buy them on eBay
pretty much like my parents collected a
lot of shells okay
more than one shell explodes note how a
hermit crab will only use my shower at a
time Alan says how can you call yourself
a real hermit if you have more than one
show this show should be collected
broken up and distributed to the people
oh yeah okay no comments okay what okay
what's the next topic I'm gonna just
talk about random things in the
seashells okay
let's see okay let's talk about keyboard
let me show you some a keyboard stuff
close close close pc keyboard reviews
reviews so let's go through my keyboard
block let me tell you my recent
experience with some of my keyboards and
actually let me get the Expo Expo
expose
expos I suppose you're supposed to
announce it exposed so they actually
have a USBC us PC you know I mean I've
been studying USB history two days ago
you guys may have seen it if you haven't
already joined this code you know I've
been posting about there's there's
someone who talked about the history of
USB like why why do we have so many
different USB plugs that's really
confusing after you watch the video it
kind of makes sense the reasons why we
have so many you know make sense in some
technical way but but we could also say
it's rather just stupid
actually it's not really stupid is
because you know as time goes on things
change you know you know before when USB
come up there is no smartphone you know
we don't have smartphone before so but
then one days smartphone becomes popular
so us USB started you need to decrease
the size so you have the you start to
have micro USB so you have you have an
evolution of USB plugs and in short USB
C is the best one USB C as far as we
know is supposed to be V the ultimate
the final you know plug USB C so this
this keyboard actually uses USB C so
this expert expose okay so let me plug
in actually let me show you this
you can see my keyboard magnifier is he
okay so expose okay so we have the
Canisius advantage too
now I'm using it as my main now and now
this is this this is the ultimate
hacking keyboard you see comes in two
pieces you know one and two and now I'm
using it as a macro keypad for example
switch to the last application one
single key press you know anything or
you quit press maximize window one
single key press a dozen doesn't work in
OBS because OBS is not obvious does not
conform to the full Mac UI interface
skylines flak and it crashes all the
time will be as open-source slack okay
so let me show you for example let me
show you on Chrome so I press the key
you see on a Mac that is control command
I mean control command F you know Mac so
anyway let me plug in the expose okay so
you can see the light shine
plug a in you see June June June June
June June June June fantastic and you
can adjust the light yeah I don't want
to but anyway let me show you let me
press some keys okay so actually let's
try and you see it fades off so you can
adjust the colors to different kind of
different fashion styles now let's go
back to so there is my keyboards so so
recently because I was moving in so on I
was using the so let's go to my keyboard
block okay so
and crows hide this talk-show Emax back
to the power of Emacs show in browser
and this is my keyboard back and I want
to tell you that I was using ok so let
me show you this ok so I was using
Kinesis of course for the past four
years every day but in about three
months ago two months ago I started to
use this one ultimate hacking keyboard
and here is expose so let me show you so
I started to use ultimate hacking
keyboard for the past two or three
months every day was my main keyboard
because first of all because I'm moving
the Canisius is hot you know I'm moving
on on a go I don't know where I'm going
to live so I lived in a friend's house
because of the Cove igniting you know
there's reasons those so I moved to a
friend house and then I moved to my
mom's house so so I was using this one
very portable I've been using this one
as my daily driver you know my main
keyboard for the past two or three
months you know the the keyboard nerds
the idiots they they they have the term
daily driver tried drive their ass ok
the proper term is just my main keyboard
not driver [ __ ] jog and daily driver my
ass so this is my main keyboard for the
past 2 months then
then about two days ago yesterday I
switched back to to the Kinesis as my
main keyboard so I can tell you my
experience like a lot of people want to
know so which one is better which one is
better well first of all it depends on
what your needs of course if you want if
you wanted to be portable then you want
this right if you know if portability is
not concerned you want this also this
this with the bowl shape you need to
spend some time to learn it and also
this is much more expensive this is $100
more than this one so you make you have
to make a decision there's no like the
best one but I can tell you my
experience on using them which one is
definitely the Kinesis is much more
comfortable
absolutely it's much more comfortable
and I the autumn are hacking I don't
actually don't I didn't like it too much
because it doesn't have too many keys to
fewer keys also it's not a great layout
you see this slanted [ __ ] but it's the
most programmable keyboard okay it's the
most power in programmability like right
now as as I showed you I'm using it as a
keypad so you see I can program the keys
very easy for example this key is if I
press it it's going to call a macro ok I
click on macro and and I choose the mark
or I want which is Mac swing so I say we
map key then I just click Save to
keyboard and it's saved to the keyboards
memory and the same thing for the others
so if you want to add a map macro you go
here you can say add marker then you can
you can either record it or choose what
marker you want to do so what we want
mark what do we want to do
I don't know so we can start to you know
press a key scan code let's say let's
say cut okay let's pick X cut so we want
cuts on a Mac its command X okay so so
and and let's give a name so let's say
dart cut okay when the name start with a
dot that's my convention for it to mean
it's for the Mac so so we're creating a
new mark or dot cut command X save okay
so it's that so we have a new marker
here cut then we go to the keyboard so
we have several key maps let's say Mac
Mac keypad so I can add a key here you
can choose a key press or you can choose
you can make this key switch layer or
you can make this key do the mouse mouse
stuff or you can make this key to some
marker so we want the marker the marker
we just created which is cut
there it is cut okay so we map key so
it's done now you see there now you just
have to save to keyboard so I click on
here I don't know if you can see that so
I can click on here save to keyboard so
now that key is cut
okay so that's that's that's about you
know so so the expose is extremely
programmable but as far as comfort goes
AB definitely the weight so I I did a
video read review of the Ottoman hacking
keyboard so anyway the Kinesis is much
more comfortable for sure now about
expose I didn't use this keyboard too
much the reason is that I got this back
in 2007 the first prototype and back
then they don't have the software to
program the keys yet but then a new app
went by the time they have a software to
program the keys it doesn't work with my
keyboard because they changed though you
know that they change the firmware or
something so I have no way to because
I'm typing of Iraq but this is a quote
by default so I have to use operating
systems way to change to quality for
example I can set to work here but still
that's not good enough for me because
especially for the expo because you see
it got many repeated keys for example
this enter here there's another enter
here let me show you let me show you
actually by video so you can
you see there's the Enter key here then
there is another Enter key here and
there's there is the shift key here but
you also so this is also shift shift
shift and shift so three shift keys then
you have this this control key one of
them that one two three of them control
key also the backspace I mean the whoops
[ __ ] so that key is also duplicated it's
also this one and I want you see so so
you see many keys have more than one key
so in a situation when you use the
operating system to program it you
cannot be specific you know because they
are duplicated so I lost you know it's a
big loss I don't have you know to not be
able to control the keyboard with with
my with you know you lost the
programmability of the keyboard so you
have to I have to use the operating
system and that sucks so that's that's
that is the reason I haven't used this
keyboard much but on location I do use
this keyboard so for comparison for
typing purposes among these three the
Kinesis is the best okay it's the best
I recommend red switches don't get brown
but get red okay I recommend red
switches then the the second most
comfortable is this one it's actually a
joy to use
the only drawback is that it's not split
you know it's one piece fatso it's
portable you can carry it now the autumn
not hacking Kibo you of course it's it's
very good and it's the gut the best
programmability for example you I have
several key maps or you call profiles in
gaming in gaming keyboards they call it
profile so you can Mac profile your
morgue
call Mac for Mac or for Windows you know
you can observer one so you can and you
can it's the most powerful in program
ability but but as far as comfort goes
it's not that great and also you see
it's very highly a high quality keyboard
the highest period quality of of them
all I would say yeah as far as pure
quality it's better it's better than
both of them because you can see I
showed I showed before it is you know
they use magnets to you can see this is
the you know magnets you can you can
connect the two pieces together
so it's really high quality keyboard but
however you know this kind of is rather
turns out you don't need them to be this
way like if you're gonna use this split
you are almost you are never going to
connect them together if you are if you
want them connected you just buy a
single you know you just buy a one-piece
keyboard you don't you don't need them
to be like that so anyway that's my
that's my that's what I want to say
about those keyboards okay anything else
comments guys maybe that's it maybe
otherwise that's it for today
Andrew are you still here so if you want
ask me questions about my life ask it
now
portability
Michael Wagener how do you use arrow
keys on those 60% keyboard switching
pavia you can you know you just hold on
one key and the other key become error
let me show you okay you hold this key
you see the smart key so you hold it
down then the right-hand side let me
show you so you hold the Marquis the
right-hand side i j k l become arrow you
know that's how you press arrow i don't
like that at all
you know because every time you do arrow
for example if you want to play pac-man
you cannot play with one hand every it's
very annoying
this 60% keyboard idiots you know i'd
really despise those 60% keyboard people
you know this they you know they they
like 60% yeah and also so every time you
you need to press arrow keys you have to
hold down this smart key same thing with
a function key so if you want to press
f10 you have to press hoedown mod then
f10 then release eft and then really
smart now in some in some applications
Photoshop [ __ ] second life or even Emacs
when you want to press f10 sometimes you
want shift f10 or meta f1000 to f10 then
on this 60% keyboard then it's gonna be
mad or f10 so it gets very complex it's
idiotic so for my case actually let me
show you so but you see but this one is
very programmable so actually I don't
so I actually programmed for example if
you look at my vorak Mac profile
you can see I have the arrow keys here
now those you see those are physical
arrow keys and I programmed them that
way so I don't have to press smart but
the problem is you know because it's
only it's 60% keys I mean it's only got
60 keys not many keys so once if you
make this arrow then you lost you know
you lost the control code modifier on
the right side and it gets complex you
see you have a shift here so I make this
key dual function that is if you press
if I press it it's going to be up arrow
but if I hold it down then press another
key such as a letter key then it becomes
shift so so this this is one of the one
of the great things about this automat
hacking keyboard it's got the most for
gram ability and it's very extremely
easy to do but however that's not that's
not that does not really you know that
has its own problems because if you make
a key to have dual function what you you
will lose the ability to hold down that
key and let that key be P for example
normally if you press a key like let's
say s it will just repeat you know but
not if if you make it into a dual
function for example right now I press
the uparrow it will not repeat so it's
very annoying so if I need repeating
arrows I have to go back to holding down
mod and press you know the i key so that
that's the issue about the dual
functionality you know the dual
functionality of keys there is the app
there is an application online you go to
my blog and you'll find it on Linux that
allows you to have that but that's no
good if you do it via the software of an
operating system so the autumn of
hacking keyboard is actually better
because it's it's done via the firm
so you don't have glitches on the other
hand if you install Y on those Linux you
know x11 something something I forgot
what's the name but you can find the
name by going to let me show you okay
Casali linux keybinding okay so here is
a linux keep mining tutorial about
everything you need to do on linux and
you know so first of all read this guide
you know linux keyboard software guide
that gives you an overview of how do you
rebind keys on linux so we have the most
basic which which is the GUI building in
most desktop Linux desktop then you have
anyway I want to show you the yeah there
is a software you know there's a bunch
of software as each one just one thing
so there is one called
yes this one space Maz Duur configure
modifier keys to act as another key when
pressed and released on their own ex
escape xscape so that's that's the one
you install so this this utility allows
you to have to make is to have dual
function which is good but it's not as
good as the you know the ultimate
hacking keyboard because it's done in
firmware which means you don't have
glitches when you use this you know xx
escape you know you have glitches all
the time okay I don't know what I'm
doing and maybe that's it for today how
long I've been talking so andrew say so
so so hold on a second you said you did
chuckling yeah chuckling I can show you
some joking
Oh joking so let's see let's see if I
can find my video so did you see yeah I
was a big time Joker you know when I was
a teenager around 16 to 18 and and and
up to when I was 30 so I was because
when I was a team I wanted to be the
greatest juggler so I have a bunch of
articles here best ball juggling a bunch
of videos that are the best jugglers in
the world I have collected some of the
videos they are the best jugglers in the
world okay
juggling is quite a big topic because
there's a lot to go into you there's a
style there's number like to most people
if you haven't been in a juggling
community you you know the immediate
question is like how many balls you can
juggle like oh how many whoa that's
idiotic
okay by the way the world record is like
12 12 or 10 and they count throws how
many throws basically they only make 12
rows or I mean 20 24th or something like
that because once you are you you have
more than tempos it's become it becomes
very difficult so pause then you can
also juggling clubs clubs actually the
record number is higher than powers I
think anyway I collected some of these
are what world record holders so there
is a style and this best jugglers of
course this competition so when I was a
teen I wanted to be you know one of the
greatest juggler so I practiced a lot I
can do five balls anyway
I can again that you know I I could show
it but I haven't been juggling for more
than 10 years for for 15 20 years you I
can still to 5 there's a video of me Joe
Green's
I it's somewhere and also you know so
you go you go to you go to my website
okay juggling performance arts then
you'll see many interesting articles
I've written about juggling so copy so
let me show you okay I mean I'm gonna
show you a keyboard mark war with the
Ottoman hacking keyboard okay so let's
see so you can see let me show you the
keyboard okay so what I want to do now
is I want to go here I want to copy the
URL and go to Emacs
and paste the URL there so what I can do
is you see I press this key that will
put a cruiser to the URL field and copy
it then I press this key that will
switch to the last application now I
want to paste so actually this is not
the place but let me just use this okay
so I want to paste sewing stuff like
he's it's leaky I mean yeah it's a code
TV but however I can also do this you
know so it's all single key press
operation
okay so now I'm backing you max cut
these go through keyboard and wait wait
wait why is my why is this wait let's go
to talk saw talk show today's talk show
paste the juggling here make a link and
the new window saw start command log mod
so in this one closed do I want to save
no wait what I want to close the window
not the buffer so here is the all my
Emacs commands you can see so I have
just pasted juggling performance I did
it right there so show in browser yeah
juggling so first of all you are see
some of the greatest jugglers poor
juggling and there's Club juggling and
ring juggling Thomas das you know he's
he's one of the greatest and you know in
the juggling community they are also
quite a lot different characters this
guy anthony gatto he is the the most he
has the most World Record you know he's
one of the greatest you know actually
one of the good you know let's say top
three greatest juggler in human history
anthony gatto
and you know for Chocola you don't make
much you know he's he was performing at
Las Vegas but I think he quit you know
because you get older you have to retire
you know once you are past 30 something
you have to retire just like every other
sports and and juggling is unfortunate
in that you don't have you know you
don't have prestige such as let's say
figure skating or track and field
running or basketball
or football you know you can make a lot
money but not so with juggling you know
if you are the greatest juggling you go
to the circus you go to Las Vegas two
shows and you know you don't unless you
are one of the best otherwise you don't
make you know you have no future and
these - these are brothers and sisters
they are vulva and ogre cut tkachenko
they are from Russia they are also they
are the greatest crop jugglers so they
are in California because they they
applied for citizenship they trying to
serve anyway they went to computer
science like one of them or both of them
they try to learn programming instead so
anyway so you see some of the great
great jugglers then you also have these
conical surface juggling this is kind of
special juggling juggling is very much
related to math so this sky juggling a
Kong okay
and you can also there's also bounce
juggling there's quite a lot so if you
are you know if you get into juggling
and the math part of juggling that's
very fascinating the the siteswap
notation
you know let's say three balls okay
let's say three balls normally you can
juggle there's a pattern you know
imagine your ball makes a trace so once
you juggle they form a trace now this
this this is a stone ball and this is
metal ball they are heavy if I drop them
I'm going to have trouble so I don't
want to I don't even want to try it here
I have posts you know I have balls there
let me see let me see what you guys are
saying
so imagine if you check out you know
they if you imagine the boss forms a
line between your trail behind it you
can then you can see your shape they
trace out the figure so that's a pattern
so some mathematicians or jugglers they
have they started to create a notation
for different patterns of juggling so
that notation is called size site
siteswap okay size swap notation and
this is very much mathematics there's a
Wikipedia article on that you can you
can you can read about siteswap notation
and also there there is a java applet
that shows juggling you know like you
can just give it a side swap notation
and it will draw people juggling that
particular pattern so this site swap
notation is a notation to show the the
the the pattern of the boss where it
moves for example of three ball juggling
actually it makes speller sense if I
show it so let me get my boss to see if
I can do
so I got now I haven't juggled for for
20 years for for 15 years okay so you
just have to bail me I'm not going to do
a good job
so anyway three balls you saw so you
have this basic pattern you see this
this is called cascade okay so there's a
there's a pattern
okay so you can see the fact
so there's a basic pattern then there is
a so that that's called reverse cascade
okay so they go backwards yeah [ __ ] it
so they go backwards that's called the
reverse cascade and each one they have a
notation and also you can do for example
one hand with three balls you throw them
up high then you throw the second one
then you throw the third one then you
catch them you know one hand three balls
so there are some different patterns and
so that's a side swap notation very
interesting it gets interesting you know
then then you have the obut thing in the
site swap notation OB things means obut
means for example if you juggling four
balls
one way to do it is the left hand you
juggle two balls the right hand you go
to boss knit they never cross okay
that's one that's one of the simple way
but you can cross them so so if you
don't cross them you can see the ball is
always on your left side you know they
never go to the the other side so a ball
forms all orbit you can you know that's
code orbit well I'm not explaining this
correctly but anyway you read you go
read Wikipedia and and read my articles
because they are there are some math
questions about this for example from
from a given notation can you this can
you determine how many orbits are there
anyway so that that's it about your
green
so how long have I been talking it's
pretty [ __ ] up I could do a better job
but I haven't been juggling for 15 years
Oh someone gave me $10 thank you jaqen
chuckles unite you know actually you
know I should if I practice a little bit
I could show you quite a few tricks you
know and I can still do even I haven't
been juggling but I can you can for
example you can do with the claw style
which means you know like normally you
juggle like that you know I have
cross-eyed so normally you juggle like
that but you can also juggle like that
so you know your palm faces down you can
do three you can do five I think five is
a maximum I've seen you know one of the
greatest chocolate ooh and you can also
do it overhead you know like that so so
it's juggling is quite fun especially
for those of you you know you have
repetitive you know using the keyboard
too much like Alan I think Alan you you
go sometimes you take a break in -
chuckling right actually I should get
back to that habit and also let me let
me tell you there are people you can do
it behind your back you know like
cascade three balls but do it like that
like without what looking at the balls
completely you can do that you know I've
seen you know for example that Thomas
Diaz he's done that Thomas tears I have
videos of him on YouTube
wait not here
best Joker the second one so anyway do
you go to my website you search for
Saudi juggling so actually I have a
video of myself juggling let me show you
that that's better
video okay let's see video no that's my
pen spinning that's
yeah
it's um it's my personal blog I know
where to find it
yeah
well anyway let me read the comments
let's see what you guys saying
actually I want to find
now that that is a viral picture of
someone a girl using her feet to shoot
arrows that went viral because it's a
girl and she's showing her ass
anyway I have a me a photo of me
juggling should I should I show it so by
the way I've been using Ultima hacking
keyboard for a month create I love the
mouse smart but convert could be better
okay Andrew says I'm still here I just
mostly wanted to know about your
experience traveling back then I've been
to many countries before but nowadays
it's a lot different because everyone
because everyone phones Google
Translator act while you left to
Paraguay at a pretty young age age did
you speak Spanish Oh Oh karani no I
don't know what is karani no I don't
like well I did I did spend one year to
learn to learn Spanish okay okay what
what am i doing I'm kind of now confused
what is the
so so so yeah so in I'm gonna show
Google Maps okay so okay
okay I'm gonna I'm going to show you
show you the the video of me chilling
you know the the web the website changes
the search engines changes over the
years I have a page that's new that's
named sapphire of Saudi but now it's
hard to find kicad profile you know you
know why it's hard to find because the
web search they focus on what everyone
searches if you know so if you search
profile of Saudi you know the kicad
profile my page on kik a profile that's
the most popular because that is
actually something people as such people
are interested nobody would be
interested about you know Saudi profile
or personal history so so in turn these
days you can add such you know you
cannot find a webpage that you know
exists you it's hard to find
maybe Google will do it go
you know Google about ten years ago yeah
there it is
sorry papa you know they encourage
people you know things change on the web
back then you have blocks you have
blocks fear blogosphere you know jargon
and Google have has Google+ everyone is
talking about how Google is telling you
how you can create a profile you know
and so on and that's forgotten you know
today it's that that is basically
forgotten so this page is basically your
profile of me you can find my contacts
on Twitter or Skype and things like that
and some of them is old you know I have
linking YouTube some of them I almost
never login like Facebook I haven't
haven't logged in since five years ago
livejournal I haven't logged in for like
ten plus years and Flickr and Yahoo and
it's things like that so you can see
some of the oldest website deviantART
Slashdot delicious those are the dates I
I had count on them and stumble upon in
my space in oh good oh good by the way
you guys probably don't know how could
his Google's first social network which
is extremely popular very successful but
then Brazilians took over so eventually
Google killed it like ten years ago
Google simply killed it but it was very
popular
but not as you know popular not not
compared to Facebook head Facebook has
far more people but okay so hold on a
second let me find there so this page is
my oldest page written started in - in
1998 1996 personal info about Saudi so I
give a short biography of myself and you
can find a photo of me juggling I mean a
video somewhere okay so here
so this is me in this precise location
now that that's a living room right
there this is my mom's face so this is
2004 16 years ago and there is the video
of me juggling okay let's see if I can
do this
okay that's that's that's about that
it's stop let's go back to livestream
and it's answer questions
so
okay so let me tell you a little bit
about my my I don't know what am i doing
now okay let's go to what way you wanna
where do I want to go Google Google Maps
let me tell you where being a short
biography very very brief biography so
if you have specific questions you want
to ask me say it okay Andrew I talked
about this like a couple of times in my
past video you know it's long history so
I was born in Taiwan 1968 [ __ ] okay
Taiwan is he okay
you see that's Taiwan
then when I was 14
me and my family moved to in trying to
immigrate to USA you know trying we
tried to do that but instead we moved to
us a way to do that we we moved to
Paraguay as soon showing here so I lived
here when when I was 14
for a year then I learned Spanish here
there for a year so I don't remember
much of it now but you know i don't i
was quite studious trying to learn
spanish so i have some conversation
level spanish in power wise so then we
we moved to guatemala here and salvador
we live in Guatemala for about half a
year Salvador for one week in Salvador I
think there's a war back then this is
1985-86
anyway we lived in Guatemala for half a
year then fly fly fly to Montreal Canada
so I was in Montreal when I was 16 okay
Montreal Canada here then we moved from
Montreal to Vancouver they lived there
me and my family I'm gonna I'm not going
to elaborate but anyway we we live in
Vancouver for half a year then they went
back to Taiwan then I myself I moved
back to Montreal I was 16 took a bus
Greyhound bus that takes five days so
this is 1985 yeah 86 85 or 86 so I lived
in Montreal on my own
illegally basically you know I mean the
process at the time I was in the process
of applying for connect Canadian
citizenship as a refugee or something
like that so anyway I moved to lived in
Montreal on my own when I was 16 to 19
and I wanted to be the greatest juggler
so I was I was working for a company
under the table of course $3 an hour and
also making bagels then we then
eventually in 1989 my mom got me a green
card to USA so I moved from Montreal to
to to Mountain View California basically
right this face I'm doing video from so
that's a brief history of my traveling
in life
so does that answer your question any
more questions
so that I'm I'm to this table on a way
by the ability Chinese people have to
learn languages of countries they they
move to it doesn't matter so I love I
learned English by reading literally by
just memorizing words I talked about
that a few times
why are you not using Linux Mac OS X Mac
OS is floated no it's not I talked about
Mac OS versus windows versus Linux like
to two videos ago you might check that
out you know it's it's kind of a boring
it's a perpetual limb boring topic like
which one to use Mac for Windows or
Linux you know it's a because it's
common you know it has no depth wait
there's something okay
so but it's a common question it's not
you know if people want to know
basically if you want to play games if
you gamma Windows is the only choice if
you have money you have lot money you
like to show off and Mac is your choice
okay it's Eve and it's easier to use the
wind and Linux is the most [ __ ] up
[ __ ] system in a world you know then you
can argue you cannot do anything with it
it's problem except if you are a
developer if if if if the only purpose
you use a computer is to program Python
Perl you know web they have things like
that then Linux is a good choice
not even if you need Java okay Linux is
the worst thing every way but it's free
that's you know if you want free you
want you you use Linux okay because I so
probably figure I think that's it for
today thank you guys for watching
Reaper ceremony Reaper another three
three row epic times before I get to
watch yeah epic times best in extra
chuckling is there no philosophical
tradition sighs not worst in parentheses
chuckling I think the biggest multi
motivator for chuckling for me was that
other people care about stuff like music
more yeah
juggling you always have the stigma
because you know when you think of
juggling it's a bunch of clowns
but juggling can be the great you know
it okay here is a very interesting thing
about juggling in a juggling community
there is a you might call him an [ __ ]
because he's very no he's known as
[ __ ] okay because every time you do
juggling act like to most of you most
normal people when it comes to juggling
they think of cows like juggling a
chainsaw with a bow and an apple and you
take a bite out of that the [ __ ]
[ __ ] scum okay that that's scum
that's I don't want nothing to do with
that
you know it comes a chainsaw enjoy being
that that's not by the way that's easy
that's very easy to do if you know in
Germany sometimes something that's
extremely difficult even just with three
balls extremely difficult but you cannot
perceive it for normal people for most
people you see journey is like crowny
make you happy that's what you like to
see that's what you get paid that's
that's how you get paid if you are Joker
you go to Street you make fun you know
you make a human then people give you
money but on the other hand if you know
you can do that within one year you know
you get you practice you fact
social skills you practice crowd control
you know that's communication you know
you need to be social you know having
Island you know you know you need to be
a brother you know hey brah you know
talk to talk to people control you know
observe people's emotion what they want
you know you make fun you know after a
year you can do that you can go to the
street and to perform performances you
can make few hundred dollars a month if
you are good cheer people that that's
the thing
the primary thing is to like a MC master
of ceremony to lead people you know it's
not about juggling the skill on your
hand you can you can spend 10 years to
master juggling just like the greatest
figure skater you know the most
difficult tricks you spend let's let's
let's say five years to two mastered
some technique of juggling you go to the
street you perform it nobody cares
like they don't understand they don't
they don't you know they don't know
that's the thing
so juggling you have the situation where
you're you know juggling perceived by
most most people it's just clowns
well but that's not how I want to
perceive juggling to be you know that's
not I don't like anything I never don't
want to juggle with chance or Apple [ __ ]
you know or do like there's some tricks
okay there's a larger green tricks you
know for example like I haven't been
jogging for ten years but I can show you
have to you know our practice like some
sometimes they do they for example three
ball juggling that will hold the ball
like the man left hand will juggle two
balls and me while I hold one ball on up
with my right hand I'll just move it so
it has a illusion like you know I'm
juggling you know it's fun you know then
then then the idiotic crowd will
oh my god ha ha ha you know they find it
funny and they give you tips you know
but that's easier that's new elegant I
don't you know you you know you don't
want for certain people like me or many
of you for example if you are you prefer
elegant for
in languages you [ __ ] despise tsipras
first you will never touch it you know
these some people when you do juggling
all these tricks there are so many
varieties in mathematical connections
you don't want to those tricks or
sometimes bounce with your elbow like
juggle and then bounce or sometimes
bounce your head you know that's yeah
that's that's tricks that's fun but
that's not for you you know there's the
difference between different styles but
the thing is if you are a technical
juggler people don't appreciate it
that's the thing unlike for example
compared to figure swimming
I mean figures figure skating for
example there people appreciate the
elegance you know but when it comes to
juggling everyone wants just you know
they perceive it as counting that's what
they you know kind of you can say you
can call ignorant they don't appreciate
extremely elegant technical juggling so
there is a character actually he's a one
of the great juggler but you know one of
the great his name is Jason Caulfield
okay I have a video of him somewhere
here but I don't I don't remember where
gee look up Jason Caulfield okay yes and
Garfield I think he also has a Wikipedia
entry and he also had there it is we
keep here entry okay by the way this
you know the last time I was in the
juggling community that's 15 years ago
you know you get old you you don't you
know you don't do these kind of things
anymore
and also I become you know I become poor
and you know
so anyway Jason coffee oh so this is you
know he's he was born in 1970s 74 you
know when you get old you don't do these
kind of things anymore but he anyway he
is known as an [ __ ] he is a very
technical juggler okay he is an
extremely technical juggler like think
about the in programming community like
someone who is a great programmer but
who is odd who we are like say you go
[ __ ] yourself you know they'll be you to
all the others he's one of that guy he
always criticized just like I you know I
talked before he criticized all these
clowning [ __ ] okay he don't want none of
that he's a great one of the greatest
technical juggler Jason Garfield
okay so so that's that's it about that
juggling let's see what else that's it I
think that's it for today
what the [ __ ] is that room yeah my room
I'm sorry I showed it actually I didn't
want to show it because you know my room
is like I was I was planning to just
show a little bit myself but then I have
to do juggling I have to oh hey Emily
[Music]
okay that's it for today I think
anything else so how long have I been
talking 1 hour and 20 minutes almost
okay thank you Jay thank you Jake and
for the money
wait
my system is [ __ ] so slow wait wait
it
Oh Thank You Alan clear your room and
switch from Emacs to vim
how did Alan's message end up in the end
up in moderation the only said Russian
talking about behind the back juggling
sounds like he's ready to join us I
haven't
the YouTube letters track your message
on duck taco is a classic what do you
mean
you know one time you know this is fun
okay I was you know so I was telling you
you know there's a juggling you can do
it behind so so one time doing around
2005 I was trying to master that so so I
would sit on the floor
and watching TV or the movies okay
whenever I watched some movies Batman or
something so I would just take a bow you
know you can you can actually learn it
so take a bow and just just do it just
just do something like that and just do
that just keep doing that for hours
hours hours and you eventually be able
to juggle behind your back without
looking at it
I wasn't I never actually got to that
point
phenomenal okay what are your current
thoughts on p40 through what's before he
flew
okay so that's it bye guys
it's a great today's video I thought
today's video is one of the most lousy
because sometimes I cannot tell ok bye
guys