Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of sound talk show. We
are going to code wam language today.
Wuam language and uh if you are watching
this offline play at 1.5 speed. If you
are here say hi. So wam language coding
uh this is for beginners. So if you
already know language then you will not
get much out of it. But this is for
beginners. So I'm going to uh work on my
wufam language tutorial from the ground
up for um for programmers. So you can
just search for it, you'll find it.
So this is uh let me see if I can see my
screen. Yes, everything is good. So wam
language uh
uh for programmers. Okay, so this is on
si.info.
No s in http
s no s okay so then you can visit it and
uh you can also download it here it's
free since few years ago uh complete
tutorial and I'm going to work on update
some part of the you know make my
tutorial better so on list operations so
here's an introduction to uh list data
structure in wam language and then list
operations. So there's tons of it like
in a typical programming language in
pearl in JavaScript in Python in Ruby uh
maybe you have let's say 20 operations
on list or methods functions but in
Wufam language you would have you you
have one 100 okay so wuam language is a
magnitude high higher level
uh I I might show some of it so but
anyway I'm going to work on So this is
Wuan language for beginners and also uh
I'm using Emacs the most advanced text
editor and uh I'm going to walk you know
so for those of you Emacs users this is
also a EMAC work session okay so let's
start wuam language okay start
uh I'm also using wuam language in emacs
so there is kasa wuam mode as that
allows me to work in wam language in
Emacs running the code and editing and
everything. So, but right now you are
looking at the wuam language um
notebook. Okay. Now for for interest why
don't I show something fancy here just
to begin with for people to come in.
Okay. So wra language uh download wra uh
let's go to wra language. So I did like
uh hundreds of videos before. So you can
watch language tutorial uh by video.
There's hundreds of them in the past
four years. Uh okay. So let me just go
to uh you know let's run something uh
interesting and fancy. Okay. So this is
always uh
fantastic example to show.
So okay so paste it and uh okay the font
is too large let's just make it 25. Okay
so shift enter to run it.
So there you have it. This is inversion
geometric inversion of
uh 3D cubes in a rectangular array. So
what you get is this fantastic and
beautiful. Okay. So this is just a demo.
Uh but that's we we did this live few
years ago. So if you search for
geometric inversion, in fact I I did
several uh videos about this. We coded
this live. Okay? Including full struggle
session and all. But but you know, so if
you want to do this in C, that's going
to be [laughter]
1,000 lines of code. Probably C with
OpenGL or whatever. If you do this in
Python with whatever libraries they
have, it's going to be few hundred lines
of code. Okay. So anyway, so um so here
is what we're going to do. Okay. So let
me let me let me show this. Uh this is
what I need to um work on. So when I
walk back and forth, you know, take my
notes, I take notes. So these are the
screenshots of the things notes I've
taken that I want I need to improve my
tutorial, you know, you know, create
more examples. Okay, so we're going to
uh based on this. So first of all, let's
do the
uh join. Okay, so let's start to go to
the wam language for programmers. Then
let's go to the list section.
list and uh list operations. So you go
down list op op operations copy the URL
and uh paste it here make a link go to
it list operations. Okay in fact we want
the one we want is join and union. This
one on this page there's no examples. So
let's show examples. So search for join.
Open it. Copy the file path. Close.
Close. And uh link paste link link uh
linkify. Make a list. Go to the page.
Okay. And uh update today's state. So
you can see
there it is. Okay. Then join. Okay. So
join
needs a example. Move friend. Pop it
out. Okay. Join.
And uh let's just say uh one two three
one
two
three anyone here say hi okay seven
people watching and let's say ABC
okay so let's clear clear so run it now
we'll just join two lists Okay. So this
is output and this is comma. Uh okay. So
now syntax showing browser. Fantastic.
We got an example. Now also union
intersection uh complement. Okay. So
union. Let's uh let's see.
Union.
Okay. Union.
Uh one, two, three. Now union is
interesting because um let's just say
because it will remove duplicate.
Let's say one to four.
Okay. Then run it. So you are looking at
woofi mode. If you search for it, you
can see for example, let me uh let me
show.
Okay. So kasawi mode. Okay. Kawufi mode.
And this is about 3,000 lines and you
can get it on GitHub. So show the
website. This is Wuam mode for Emacs and
you can get it on GitHub. Okay. Free
thanks to Wuam Research for supporting
me.
Okay. So that's uh Wu mode. Uh copy
close close. Uh now let's uh let's so
here is union you see 1 2 3 and 1 2 4 it
become becomes 1 2 3 4. So let's just uh
this just a simple example when you are
writing a tutorial the simple example is
the best you want the example to be the
simplest that that showcase what this
function do. Okay. So in this example
you can see you know the same elements
are not included in the result. Okay. So
let's close that. Uh actually so I want
to paste the casawi mode show in
browser. There it is. Uh kasawi mode for
emacs. Okay. So back here. So,
so now back to the to this page we have
example for join union intersection. Uh
actually we need to go faster because
there's quite a lot few things to do.
Okay. So, uh pop it out. So,
intersection
um intersection. Yeah, let's use the
same example. Run it on the pink window.
You can see all my command calls and
their keystroke on the left. So you see
I just called wu evar region and here is
the result the intersection of two
lists. Okay, put it back syntax to go to
the browser. Go to the browser show
refresh. There it is. Complement. Okay,
complement. Now in Python or JavaScript
I believe typically typically they name
this function as
uh difference of two sets but
mathematically you don't say difference
usually you say complement but
difference is actually the easier to
understand you know because one set
minus another but mathematically they
are traditionally called complement.
Okay. Complement
uh completion.
Okay. Complement. Uh so yeah. So let's
run this example.
Can I demonstrate compliment? Yes.
Because three is not in the second list.
Okay.
Syntax color. Fantastic.
So
and uh update the date. The date is
updated. So you got join union
intersection complent. It's okay. We
added examples. That's good enough. Uh,
okay. So, delete. So, this join now this
you see join operation is quite
different from the others union
intersection and complement because the
union intersection complement they are
set operations like in set theory. Join
is simply concatenate concatenate
you know to list. So the join needs to
be separate from them. They need to have
a new section. Okay. So join.
Um so let's see how we going to do this.
Cut cut. Yeah. So
new one,
new section and new definition list and
paste that there. And uh yeah and uh
remove this todo and date showing lists.
Okay. Capitalize
make it H2
showing browser. Fantastic. Join lists.
Then this the set union intersection
complement. Fantastic. Okay. Now that's
good.
Join union intersect. Yeah, that's good.
Okay. Now this screenshot done. Delete.
Next. Okay, this is about auto hotkey.
So we did a video two days ago about
auto hotkey. So that you know so let's
not do this. This is also auto hotkey.
Auto hotkey. Okay. So watch the video
from today's two today's ago. Hello post
1999. Hello ACP junior curious does join
decouple the elements deddup the
elements no they just concatenate
concatenate
uh if you want to ddup the elements
that's the that's called union okay I
hope I answered that that that's what
you meant okay so ne next so this join
union intersection needs to move up
because join is a very comp uh common
operation in all programming languages.
Okay. So search for join. So you go down
in you go down into this um this this I
call this uh
this box. Okay. So go down. So you can
see this box. This is this is what I
call topic box. Okay. Topic box. So the
join operation needs to go up. So search
for join cut. Okay. And where do you
want it? They you want to um see in the
browser it's easier to see. You want to
be before filter. Okay.
So search for filter. Yeah. Put it
there. Now watch the pink window. So
you'll show my the command I call to
update all topic boxes in all pages in
you know in in in the entire website of
10,000 files. So press press press
press. So you see
each page. So let me show you the
output. So each page you know it you
know there's 10,000 pages. So each page
they show you which page has been
updated which page does not have the
topic box before but now it's added. Um
so you know this is output that's a emac
command I wrote which is the name of
that command is
um
uh you see HTML update topic boxes. Can
you see can you guys see is everything
going well?
Yeah.
Okay. So now let's go back. Let's So you
can see in fact you can see here you can
see the join somewhere uh where so it's
at the bottom. You see? Now you click to
you click list operations. Now the join
is right here before filter. You click
create table and go down to the topic
box. And you can see the join operation
is right before filter. So it updates
any page you know it updates essentially
all topic boxes scattered in all pages.
Okay this so this one is done. So let's
see next
delete.
Now remember to play at 1.5 speed if you
are watching this offline. And any more
comments
praine? Yes. Yes. Yes. What? Uh
generating nested list with table. So
let me demonstrate this. Okay. So so you
got this operation list these operations
and one of the most useful is table and
I want to change some wording. Okay.
So generate. So copy the URL back to
Emacs. Close that and uh paste a link
linkify. Make a list. Combine the list.
Combine the list. Okay. Then open the
page showing browser. So that is a
table. Now search for nest.
Uh so this example is about creating
nested table. Uh uh which I can show
you. Okay. So for example,
copy that. Let's now let's do in wra
language.
Uh paste it. Shift enter to run it.
There it is. Now
do it again. Now this time show in tree
form.
You see it makes it easier to see. So
what this table does in this particular
example is it generates a
three-dimensional array kind of. I mean
you can there are many names to call it.
You can call it a 3D matrix or 3D array
or three-dimensional rectangular array
or you can also call it nested list.
Okay, many many uh name to go by. So but
what I want to say here is change the
title. So this is regarding writing. So
I'm saying generated a uh generating uh
nested list. So now I want to change it
to
rectangular
rect re what rectang
don't I have a shortcut rectang
oh I don't have a shortcut let's see uh
let's not worry about it okay
let's just spell it out
so why do I want to rename it
rectangular array array because that's
more specific because when you say
nested list the list may be what's soal
jacked array that is it doesn't it's not
a square rectangle it's not a square
array it may have you know some of the
leaves may just have one leaf some nods
have two leaf some nods may have five
leaf so in that case that's a nested
list still true but that's no longer
rectangular array however Ever the table
function only generates always
rectangular array. Okay. So it doesn't
generate arbitrary tree. So therefore
the naming of this title should be
better if you say rectangular array.
Okay. Also don't say generating. Don't
use the verb. Okay. Generate
just simple noun. Okay. as opposed to
the so-called um
uh it's called uh active voice. You know
active voice idiotic. That's a very
famous writing advice. You must use
active voice which is not true. In fact,
if you are writing mathematics, always
use passive voice. Like you don't want
to put yourself in the center, nor do
you want to tell readers about some
action. Oh, you got to do this or do
that. No. If you want to write any
computer documentation, especially if
you want to write it like a mathematics
code and precise, you want to write it
in a descriptive way. Okay? Describe.
Just describe exactly what happens. No
action at all. Don't don't say oh after
you do this then that then this will
happen you know and this is the result
you know don't do that you know like you
you like specify specification
mathematics it's about description okay
that's the way math works
so generate rectangular array with table
so that's what you say don't say
generating you know generating I I you
know so my writing style back uh 20
years ago I always use generating ing
and it's no good. Okay. So at this rate
we'll never go far. So there's a lot to
do. Okay. So that's uh done.
Okay. Now now there's also minor
details. For example, in this example uh
I can show you quickly. Okay. So
copy this example. What it does is paste
it. It just generates
a flat list from one to three instead of
one over two. So woofam language is
symbolic. So you can you know when you
have a fraction it generates a result in
fraction. You see fantastic.
Now there's a wording problem because
you see here is another technical
writing documentation detail about
formatting. You know there's so many
issues about technical writing or
documentation. There's organization,
there's a writing style, there is a
uh well and style of exposition. There's
a kind you know the kind of words you
use there and there's organization
issues and one of them is s syntactical
formatting issue like programming
languages you have you know function
methods objects variables and uh
arguments in this case these are
arguments some of them are optional. So
how do you indicate to people which part
are variables which part are function
name which part are object or which part
are you know arguments you know so
arguments in a sense is also a variable
or they are also called parameter
so this so there's many formatting
issues now in this case what I want to
change is this you see I I'm saying I
mean IMAX in fact I want to remove the I
okay don't say I mean I IMAX Okay. So,
yeah. So, let's just do that.
uh as to why uh well if if I explain why
it's gonna take a lot more time because
it be well in you know first of all you
need to understand what this does then
you know I so it takes a variable I is a
variable then here I mean means it's a
minimum it's a value that to begin with
for I okay so so this I mean refers to a
minimum value starting value for the
variable I. So that's why I name it I
min and s similarly IAX is the maximum
value and DI is the like D is delta you
know like differential the step okay
each each step you take so I you know I
wrote it um probably influenced from the
wufam language documentation you know
like when you write a doc you can also
look at other people's you know uh
documentation python you know so many
languages Python
uh Ruby so you can see what's their
documentation style Java most of them
are like the worst you know like
the Mozilla JavaScript documentation the
Python documentation the they are the
worst of the worst like they don't know
how to write that is like complete
like and the Unix man pages
like it very popular you know it's like
this epidemic in computing industry the
Unix fan pages, the apach Apache
documentation, the you know, like they
don't know how to write. They just blur
blur,
you know, and they think it's funny,
especially in the uh with the Unix
documentation. Pearl, Python is all
crap, like the worst crap.
Okay, Java,
the language documentation is the superb
professionally written Java. Okay. And
wuam language also superb. They are in
these two are examples of the best
technical writing. Okay. However, they
are in completely different style. Okay.
Anyway, I talk about this because um
it's my one of my obsession uh writing
documentation and tutorials and writing
in general. Okay. Like creative writing.
Uh so I've been obsessing about it for
like 30 years like like most my life so
I know all these details. Anyway, so
this is Wuam language um documentation.
So anyway, let's let me just change this
to uh make a backup show in browser. So
let's update the last updated date. Then
let's make a change. I mean to just mean
okay it's not just it's just not I mean
okay in fact wait hold on a second I
mean so actually I want to change one
shot the I mean and I max them both okay
so change I am with just m do it do it
do it do it do it do it do it do it okay
Now go back to browser. Now when I
refresh all this IMAX aiming will be
changed. Do it. Fantastic. Now this DI
also needs to change. So search for DI.
Yeah. So this DI will be
uh just just say step. Okay.
Okay. This is about technical writing
and especially it's about uh formatting
syntax code formatting issues convention
and so okay so this part is done make
sure delete it okay make sure uh I got
it yeah
okay and what about this uh okay so this
this part is about generating nested
table so let me let me show you guys
just In general, what is the table does?
Okay. What is your opinion on text info?
Okay. Text info that's esoteric topic
that's related to GNU Emacs or the GNU
software foundation their software
documentation. They use a format called
text info. Uh I won't go into it but let
me talk about it for one minute. Okay.
In fact, you just search for si text
info, you'll find the article.
So, Emac should adopt HTML as text info
replacement. For example, that's one
article. Open it. Okay. Wait. Go back.
Opening a new uh page. Wait. So, the AI
started to talk. Kasali is a prominent
figure known for his extensive online
resources on Emacs and programming
including discussion on text info text
info documentation system. He has
expressed
[laughter]
criticism regarding text info advocating
advocating for the adoption of HTML as
replacement for text info in Emacs
documentation. That's correct. Superb
technology unprecedented in human
history with AI today and also extreme
very dangerous is happening. Anyway, Lee
argues that current text info. Anyway,
that's interesting. Okay, let's
screenshot screenshot this. Uh,
okay. So, but let's go just go to my
page. Okay. Blah blah blah blah blah
blah. Okay. So, uh, Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard, that's the one I'm using.
Fantastic. I did a review a week ago,
full in-depth review. Watch that. Okay.
Uh, so now, click that. Press that
button. That's middle click. Press that
button. That's middle click. Oh, this
this guy is a scum. He copied my website
and uh, you know, put on his website.
scum. this guy Westy,
you know, so he is his page he's his
page is not not not now not like not
coming up.
Okay. So he's like
so you know some sometimes people he I
think he bought my tutorial like 10
years ago or more and he put on his
website and forgot about it.
Anyway, so tech you know hacker news
added he seems to have a lot of
interesting and stuff and uh god
I'm about as good as dead that's 2014
okay my hardship in my life
can program a line of lisp on his own
this guy whose name is um he's a German
guy lisp m online he goes by the handle
lisp M [snorts] kind of stand for list
machine lisp machine. Okay. He his name
is um
I shouldn't talk I talked about this
before but anyway he's a he's a hater.
Every time my post got posted somewhere
not by me. I never posted to hacker
news. Okay.
Um maybe one time. Okay. One time they
were talking about me like in the past
in in all my life I posted to hacker
news one time to reply to some some some
some bad about me. So I I never
posted my website to hacker news. Okay
they other people thank you guys they
posted. So but there's this m guy which
I kind of know we kind of talked like
almost 20 years ago. He doesn't like my
stuff. He doesn't like my opinion. So
every time he sees some post about me,
he's going to badmouth it. Okay, I
talked about this.
Yeah, let me mention it because because
this really a scum. Okay, this is vering
on
defamation. Okay, vering on defamation
and what's the other word? You know,
that's legally legal defami defamation.
Okay, you can sue the guy. You know, you
you can say, let me tell you young
people, if you don't know about this
issue, if you don't like someone, you
can say it. You know, I don't like this
guy. I think his opinion is I
think he's stupid. I think he's an
idiot. He's a He's a scumbag.
You can say all that, no problem. But
when you say something that is act
that's concrete but not factual
and and uh damaging then you got to be
careful. Okay. You cannot say oh this
guy he never coded a single line of
leisp
that's verging on defamation because
that's a lie or if you have or whether
or or you have to prove it okay because
that's that's damaging the rep
reputation of another person okay so you
you can say he's a face you can say
he's stupid no problem you know you can
say is a stupid or you can say I don't
agree with his opinion he's no job,
that's all fine. But if you say like he
oh he uh cheated on something or he
didn't do this or he did that something
nasty, you know, then you need to prove
it. Okay? Otherwise that's defam
defamation. What's the other word
uh you know so that's legal uh a legal
problem that's illegal. Okay. So but
there so there's this guy this M. So,
let me just search it so you guys know
cuz I because he he been doing that for
like 10 years, you know, like every few
years.
Okay, this guy who is Lisp M
Reneer Joshwick
a scumbag from Germany. He's a old he's
a old Lisper perhaps 10 years older than
me. So maybe he's 60 something. Okay.
He's a old like list machine guy from
the 1970s 80s.
So he's uh he hates me. So every time he
see some post so here's a collection you
know he just start to you know
bad mouth about me.
Okay. So I you know after he done this
many times I created a page by himself
2023 so people can actually see
my documentation on this scumbag. Okay,
this M
Raina Joshwick Joshwick something. Okay,
a German guy. Okay, so let's copy that.
So let's show that. Let's Sorry for the
digression. We going to go back to what
we doing. Close that. So but but
okay.
Okay. So let's go back. So we were So
you were saying what's your opinion on
tech text info. Okay. So
you can you know I don't like it
basically. I think it's it's not I don't
like it but it's Asian. Okay. It needs
to change. Um,
and by the way, are you are you are you
the
are you the
are you the guy on Discord who was
making trouble
Push or whatever the name I forgot.
Slander. Yeah, that's a word. Slander.
Defamation or slander? I don't know
exactly what's the difference. Um, but
they kind of similar. Okay, that's a le
that's illegal. Okay.
So, ACP Junior, thank you. So, Abraim
say, "Ignore the noise. You are a
resource and personally I have learned
loads of from your video." Thank you.
Thank you guys. Okay, so let's get back
to the coding language. Actually, we've
been going on for 30 minutes. There's a
lot to do actually. So, yeah. So let's
see where are we? Um okay, close that.
We working on list. So let's get back to
work on this. Okay. Yeah. So let me I'm
not on Discord. Oh, okay. Oh, NASA,
right? NASA guy. Okay. Whatever. Did Did
you work for NASA? Why is that NASA
logo?
Yeah, I confused you with someone else.
So anyway, so let's get back to Yeah,
let me just show you guys what table
does. Okay. So
uh so table
table is the most
used function in woof language to
generate a list or rectangular array. So
let me just demo. Okay. So because it's
easier if I just demo it.
Uh of course you can read my tutorial.
Everything is here. But um so
so let's switch to
wam language mode table. Okay. So the
simply simply case is just like that you
want to repeat that item three times.
Okay.
Then so uh let me show you another
example. So let's say for that you know
different expression repeat two three
times. Okay. Now,
now level up. Now you want to um you
want to repeat let's say uh x
i from one uh
one two three. Okay, it you get one two
three. Uh wait um oh yeah so this needs
to be x. Okay
x1 23. Okay. So that three is the
maximum value. Now if you put two
numbers here, let's say four
7, then you get four, five, six, seven.
Okay?
So all these are table this variation.
By the way, if you are a Python coder,
table is just like Python's
um
least comprehension
uh idiotic jargon from the Python idiots
and from their idiotic syntax, least
comprehension. They think they are
mathematicians, [laughter] but they
created the worst syntax
and also the worst name for the syntax.
The the the semantics list
comprehensionhension is the worst
possible and the name for it list
comprehension is the most idiotic. Okay,
the Python idiots, Gido Vanrosum, one of
the lowest IQ programming language
creators. Okay. But he think he's hot
shot, you know, Python like he's got the
he's got the mentality like he think
he's a great great designer
and uh but he's his his result is not as
so great and but he constantly has this
like passive aggressive
attitude to say yeah but I'm the
greatest language you know creating a
language is not just about solving
puzzles you know the way he writes like
G van Rosen the most idiotic guy okay so
table is similar to Python's list
comprehension okay by the way Hascal
also use that term which is idiotic
Hascal
in Wuen language
you if you want to generate any list or
any rectangular array you use a table
function okay uh these are the
variations I'm showing you Okay. Now, so
these are conse consecutive values.
Okay. So, but you can also have let's
say x uh four. So, in in in this example
that x let's let me show you some simple
example. Let's say x pi. Okay. Run it.
You see 4 pi 5 pi 6 pi 7 pi. It can be
any expression. Okay. So let's say x uh
power
second power uh wait where is the power
key there? Let's say x raised to second
power right it
you see 16 15 16 25 36 49 okay now let's
say x second power plus pi plus um
plus where's the plus key uh new
keyboard so that's wrong that's where
where is my plus key
plus key is always problematic. Okay,
let's say plus
uh three. Okay, let's it can also be pi
or whatever you see. Uh oh, there's a
number. Okay, let's not use a number
because when you use a number, it just
compute the whole thing. So, it's hard
to understand. So, let's use a symbol.
Let's say y x² + y x from 4 to 7. There
it is. Okay. Now you see the first part
can be any expression not just you know
simple it can be complicated equation or
whatever. So for example now let's add
another elements let's say x uh let's
say x * y
uh x * y or n plus z or whatever. Okay,
run it.
You see it it gets it's gets big. Let's
say let's format it. Okay,
there we there we have it. Now the all
these are flat lists. Okay, now let's
get into two-dimensional.
Okay. So,
two dimensional case uh example.
Okay. So, same thing start simple. Let's
start with uh just a single x. So, x uh
let's say now let's give a list x and y.
Now x from
one two three and y from
uh one two three okay let's say two okay
because when you have multiple nesting
it becomes the huge very fast okay run
it
so you see
x goes from 1 to 3 so x is 1 x = to 2 x
= to 3. Then y goes from 1 to two. So
for each time x changes the y uh you see
x now in this part x is one, y is one
two. Okay.
Now in the second part so let's format
it. Okay. So, let's format it so it's
easier to see.
Um,
what what
Okay. So, the second part x is 2, y is 1
and two. The third part x is 3, y is one
and three. So, this is a 2D matrix, a
rectangular
[clears throat] matrix. Actually,
actually, it's a bit complicated. Let's
make make this into this form
so that so the braces does not confuse
you. Okay, that's right.
Okay. So now
now it's much more clear. See
it's more it's a bit more complicated
here because you are using a list which
is represented by the braces you know
the curly brackets. So that
kind of gets you confused. So let's
remove that. Okay. So in this example
you can clearly see a two-dimensional
matrix. Okay. Because you have two
iterations X and Y. Okay. Now similarly
you can have any arbitrary complicated
expression. Okay, let's say x + y uh
let's say pi let's say and i the complex
number
okay
then you got that and this can be
three-dimensional okay so uh let's say
if you have the z component let's say -5
to
3 uh z so you want the z component
uh let's say time z okay here so now you
get a three-dimensional matrix and each
element is this expression okay and it
can also again it can contain fraction
okay let's actually try fraction example
because that's fun okay so delete that
and now actually this let's say squared
>> [sighs]
>> x * y^ 2 +
um
+ * y / z. Okay, so it's a
three-dimensional matrix, you know,
complicated
to read, but if you format this in wam
language, you get much better um shift
enter. you see clarity.
Okay. So, let's uh let's copy this.
Okay. Let's copy this uh screenshot so
that
is this interesting guys. Is this
interesting?
Okay. Am I losing watches? Okay. So,
anyway, that's a demonstration of table.
Okay. So, let's see.
Um
okay so let's
cut let's put it back in our example
here. So let's today's talk show
uh wolf frame language paste it syntax
collect show in browser this is today's
talk show here is the code we did okay
am I still going is it good everyone say
hi
uh
check audio check video check
Okay.
So, let's continue. So, let's continue.
Let's see. Uh where are we? So, table.
Okay.
Uh table. Yeah. So, here generate
generating nested list with table. Okay.
So, that's a example here. Um
Okay. So we want to yeah delete this
part. So actually we have already
demonstrated this part that's a
multi-dimensional example. So
let's go to the page and uh
okay so we uh
we want to
yeah so nested. So delete
generate a nested list. Okay,
remove this section basically showing
browser. Okay, there. Okay, we already
demonstrated this. Okay. So,
um, yeah, fantastic. So, let's delete
that.
Delete that. Next.
Duplicate with plus. Okay. So, I want to
show a different example here.
Yeah. So, let's go to search for pre.
Yeah. So, copy that.
Uh,
let's not use Z. Okay. the Z because the
simpler example the better. Okay, let's
just say three. Uh so yeah, so run it.
We demonstrated this before.
Uh okay, so now let's format it so it's
easier to see.
Okay. And
then
we want to say yeah in this example we
just say x + y
uh + y
then you just got numbers in each. Okay.
Okay. Yeah, that's better example.
Syntax collect. Go back here.
Refresh.
Simple example.
Simpler the better. Okay.
Duplicate with plus. Yeah, I wanted to
show a example where the expression gets
simplified.
so that the actual result can be easily
seen as a two-dimensional matrix.
That's what that is about.
Okay. So, delete this screenshot. Now,
what is this? Uh generate a flat list
H2. Okay. So in this table documentation
tutorial I'm writing
uh what I want to do is I want to
separate into uh different sections.
Okay. Because
uh generate a flat list. Okay. Yeah. I
want to yeah separate into sections. So
the first part is generate a flat list.
Then the second part is generate
rectangular array. Okay.
So
yeah. Okay. So go to the top
uh table
cut
new section the power of Emacs. Okay.
And this section
uh move that to here. Okay. So move
actually here and here give it a new
name. Okay. Generate
black uh black
beast. Okay.
Fantastic table. What it does? Then
example generating flat list then
generate rectangular array. Okay.
So that's what this is about.
Delete
uh example move up. So
okay, are you guys bored with this? I'm
alive. That's good.
So if you have any questions, uh just
ask me. Okay, there's not many people
watching now. So you know if you have
questions related to what I'm talking
about.
Uh so so this is about example of
symbolic expressions. So that that is a
flat list
example. So that should move up to um
above. Okay. Um yeah. So cut cut cut one
single key press and make a section
paste it there. delete the time and
to-do and cut the entire section and uh
go to the beginning of that tag.
and
then say nested inside this section and
make it
uh example
symbolic
expression
uh expression. Okay.
So this make this two H3
show in browser.
So you got table
Generate flat list section
subsection nested inside example
symbolic expression any part can be
symbolic. That's right.
Okay.
And then uh and go down. Yeah. So you
got to move remove that HR. Okay.
Now this generate 3D matrix. Um, do I
need it? No, that's a screenshot from
Wuam notebook.
Uh, I think I just Let's just move it.
Remove it. Okay. So,
search for the image file name to make
sure there's no it doesn't appear
anywhere else. No. Okay. So, open it.
Delete it.
delete the image and delete that. Okay,
delete that and back here. Refresh
arbitrary expression. Okay, so
yeah. So let's modify that and move it
to the flat example. Okay, so
run it.
Uh
let's say
divided by Z. Uh wait what?
Divide by Z time
I pi / Z. Okay, run it.
Uh actually divided by let's say X here.
Okay, let's say that run it.
Okay, let's just leave it like that.
Uh,
divided by
three. Wait, where did the x Yeah, x
becomes one, two, three. Yeah. So,
so this is a example
examp
uh example of arbitrary re expression
uh
express
Okay. So,
put it back. Now,
cut. Okay. Wait. Delete the section.
Then cut. Then go to example above.
Um, then
paste it there.
Then cut that. Then paste it that
um
syntax color the whole page. Show it.
Fantastic. Now it's much more clear than
before. You see that's my working on my
tutorial. So this
delete double check one more time.
Yeah.
Any questions? So next.
Okay. So this we already did. Delete.
Okay. Arbitrary expression. Move up.
Delete.
Now. Okay. So now let's talk about
another page.
Close. Back here. Close. Show in
browser. Go to list operations.
Now before we were creating using table
that generates a flat list or
a rectangular array nested. Okay. But
now there's another function that's
dedicated to just flat list. That's this
one range. Okay, stop the YouTube video.
Stop there. Okay, so let's paste linkify
listify merge the list. Open it
and the today's date update.
Okay. And uh then uh pre
so here is the code. That's uh so this
actually
Yeah. So what we want to do is we
actually want to make this um
okay we want to make it separate boxes.
Okay. Um
min
paste it there. Okay. And then here's a
example with steps.
Steps
0 to five
symbolic step next step negative step.
And we want to show one more example
where the last item is dropped.
Um
so that would be for example um
actually here
so this for example if you say 0.7
so that's not even evenly divisible then
the result will not reach three
Okay. So if
step is not evenly divisible
by max.
The result
does not contain max.
Now did I spell divisible correct? So
check
but
correct. Okay. So now
okay
syntax color show in browser. Fantastic.
Okay, that's that.
Okay, that's a formatting issue. Remove
removing the blank line there. Delete.
Okay, so now it's gets more complex. Now
this is about part
A.
Okay, I think most people are bored. You
know, you kind of know what is this
about. And I have to do one, two, three,
4, 5, 6, 7,
8, 9, 10, 11,
12 pages. Uh, 12, 13,
14.
You know, I got quite a few to do on
this list operations with Wuam language.
But I think that's it for today. Thank
you guys for watching.
Uh we talked about that's one hour.
Okay,
bye guys.
Now, if you guys like my stuff, remember
to go to.info
http
no s. Okay, then go up. Go up. Then
programming language tutorials then go
up a code go up codeali.info
info my homepage then go to the bottom
you Patreon me
you Amazon gift card me and you PayPal
me thank you
okay that's it bye guys
we shut down in one minute
so we were working on this page okay
close so here is our talk show today.
After a while, you'll see my website
updated. So,