hello guys good morning good evening
good evening welcome to another episode
of s talk show uh we're going to do
wolam language coding uh I'm just going
to do wolam language coding the most
advanced programming language by far by
a
magnitude uh so how many concurrent
viewers zero okay I'm just by myself so
I'm just going to start code now if you
are here comments if you are not here
here uh play at 1.5 speed and uh skip
around because I Rambo okay so I'm just
going to uh do my work okay wolam
language
coding so if you don't know about wolam
language I did a lot of tutorials just
check my YouTube you you there's over
100 100 videos on wfam language okay so
um yeah
so yeah let's see uh video check audio
check audio check uh that's good let's
move this here and uh let's start coding
okay so we're going to so you can
download wam language for free again che
check my previous videos for uh
introduction about WFAN language
so what I want to do is work on keep
working on this my plan curves project
okay
let's see hyperbola so hyperbola
actually I've done completely finished
hyperbola uh so today we work on either
elisp or
Parabola so one thing we did a few days
ago is this animation creating it in
wolam language okay and here is the code
uh and Optical properties of hyperbola
we explained a lot of things um here's a
pedal of hyperbola okay
so okay let's see let's pick let's pick
um pick a curve I want to work on
Elis okay so I can work on El Le go back
or uh
Parabola okay let's work on Parabola
since because Parabola seems easy it's
just you know kind of random pick Okay
so here's today's talk show and here's
emac I'm using the two windows the pink
window shows all my commands as I call
them you can see and the keystroke on
the left okay if you search for any
commands that's not building in emac
that con command name start with xah
that's my own personal command then you
can search it you'll find the source
code that's for your emac users and uh
most of them are in sofly Keys okay
that's the most efficient key binding
system for
emac so here's a s fly Keys
documentation jump to the source code
about 4,000 lines of code go to the top
so here's a URL open it showing browser
that's sfly Keys the most efficient key
binding system in emac so if you use emx
you might try this the advantage is that
you no longer have to press control and
meta so it's like model system but much
more efficient than be okay so here's a
key binding uh okay so uh so that's s
like ke so copy close close close so
let's just paste it here make a list
that's today's talk show so we're going
to go to yeah we're going to work on
Parabola okay three
viewers have you ever done signal
processing in w language no actually uh
that's a topic I'm not too familiar with
I never done signal processing very
useful and
uh and uh you know very fantastic topic
it's
mostly uh partially pure mathematics but
partially it's mostly application it's
very critical okay that signal
processing is critical
no not not uni signals that's a signal
processing is mathematics so signal
processing is for example today use in
cell phone in radio in radio technology
anything I mean radio like broadcasting
or radio telescopes to space uh or cell
phone you know cell phone network so for
us programmers we know about ethernet we
know about ports um tcpip
but then when the Internet connects
outside outside of your house to the to
to either you know either the the cell
phone um Network and there is the
internet Network they are actually
separate but anyway when it's outside of
your house they have to go either by
wires or under sea or by uh radio um
that is electromagnetic wave so so
basically you just got this signal sine
waves okay so the qu so there's a lot
issues about transmitting you want to
transmit efficiently when you call
someone how do you encode that number
into the wave and and what happens you
want to handle a million concurrent
course so it's a major um topic so if
you are engineer uh almost in any field
you have to know a lot about signal
processing Okay so but basically just
mathematics so it's analysis
basically a lot of analysis of the
basically just the sine wave okay so I
don't know much about this topic and the
related is the forar transforms like
like you can
search uh you know the for forar
transform and there's also a difference
between digital or analog so very and
also for musics like you your headphone
your speakers they also have to do some
signal processing for example
enhancement of the base or things like
that or no or noise
cancelling uh headphones okay I'm having
some drink this is Coke and one shot of
Chinese
BYU Bao Chinese byro which is like vodka
so I don't know anything about signal
processing okay but let's just let me uh
do what I know so let's just work
on um the parabola page okay so close
that close that go back here Parabola so
here's a wolm language um I mean my
website uh so here is a wolam language
notebook you can see here's a file and
uh this is the 30 years old code let's
make a backup and let's open
it so again my job is to
update my visual dictionary of spal plan
curves this is the most famous project I
did I began in
1997 that's linked by over a
thousand universities math department
and uh High School uh education you know
departments so you know that's that was
my most popular
project and uh but it's old
1997 basically after I uh you know I
intern at wam language so there's a lot
of things so I'm updating them so open
the notebook for Parabola uh it says
continue with update styling yes do it
okay so here is a notebook for Parabola
let's magnify
it uh definition okay so you can see
here is here is showing how a parabola
is defined visually
okay let's uh let's remove
this ocean waves and turbulence yeah
signal processing okay so Parabola um
let's see let's go to Parabola so so
this special plan curves they visually
explain all these very interesting uh
curves okay so go to Parabola and I need
to update this for example I need to
update all the images because these
images are created 30 years ago and 30
years ago and today is very different
like 30 years ago just have a one photo
like this is huge photo you know people
have to wait for 1 minute for the
internet to download so you want to you
want to minimize you know all these
images that's why they are kind of small
but today you know the internet is like
100 times faster than you know 30 years
ago so so also you can see many of these
a uh images are kind of not aeast so you
see this these are not alas image okay
so let let me explain some interesting
properties so okay so for example when
you have a parabola Parabola okay so
here is the application of Parabola
which is your uh car's head
lamp uh because of the optical
properties of Parabola so Parabola is a
curve it looks like you know it just
look like that so it's a unique curve
okay so it's not a family of curve many
other curves have different like you
there's a parameter you trick the
parameter they have sled variation like
uh like elisp for
example so if you look at Elis you know
all these are ellip ellipses you know
there's a parameter to the Ellis but for
Parabola it's a single shape so the in
other words the curvature is unique okay
so so you can magnify it you can shrink
it but that's there's only one shape
okay and it it looks like that but why
is that some parabolas for example looks
like more sharp and some of these like
more dual that's just because you are
magnifying into it so you are so the
picture on the right you are just
looking closer that that's why it looks
like dual then the picture on the left
looks like more
sharp but actually they are the same
only because they are zooming in okay so
this property you know the the so the
the uniqueness of a curve is defined by
the curvature okay that's another very
interesting thing curvature so
curvature uh for example konu spiral is
very much related to curvature this this
spiral is a is a spiral such that the
curvature grows in a linear way I
believe um the curvature grows in
linearly or
I forgot the details but you can you can
read it I forgot the details uh the
cloid is is defined as a curve whose
curvature is equal to its length oh yeah
right so you
see suppose you know this is a this is a
this this spiral is called conu spiral
okay it's symmetric so you know it's
symmetric rotational
180° symmetric so you rotate it 180° the
same so you but you look at the curve
just look at one part of it okay so in
the beginning you put your um you know
your point in the middle you start to
move every time you move the point along
the curve there's a length the length
increases so as the you want you want so
at every point on the curve any curve
there is a uh value called the curvature
so
the so the larger the curvature the the
more curved the curve is okay any point
on the curve so you want the you want
the curvature to be equal to the length
of the curve so in other words the
Curve will the
curvature is you know correspond to the
length of curve so that's very special
case and in this case you what you get
is this konu spiral very
interesting okay so you want to learn
about this so all the things I'm talking
about all these PL curves they are they
are uh calculus level so if you are math
student you know it's good to learn very
highly interesting calculus level okay
not not more advanced not topology or
others so for curvature here is a visual
way to understand curvature curvature is
basically
B so curvature for every point on a
curve there's a curvature unless it's a
kink you know like sharp you know but
for every point on a smooth curve
there's a cure at any point on the curve
okay and how is this curvature defined
basically it's a circle that fits that
point in in a tangent way the the most
Okay so
the sharper the curve like when when you
have a sharp turn the curvature is is
very uh small
tight okay so so the actual number is
the um is the inverse of the radius
okay uh inverse of the radius of the
circle so anyway so when you have a
sharp turn the Cure is very small which
me I mean the the circle the fitting
Circle this circle is called osculating
Circle okay uh this circle that kind of
Define the curvature this is called OC
osculating Circle osculate means kiss
kissing Circle so it's a circle that
fits the curve at at a point the most
the most fitting Circle to approximate
the curve so this circle is called is
called kissing Circle and the curvature
at that point is the inverse of the
radius so when the circle is very small
small the radius is very small but then
you have to do inverse which is one
divided by that radius so so the
curvature is actually
large so anyway so when you have a sharp
turn the curvature is large the fitting
circle is very small when you have a not
so sharp turn like just slide curve then
you can see the fitting circle is huge
the radius is huge then the inverse of
the radius is small meaning that the
curvature is small okay so the
curvature is a
critical uh thing when you study curves
and all this is in the field of
differential geometry so you have to do
then you have to do calculus derivatives
integrals to you have to use
um
uh uh you have to use integrals to find
cure okay der der derivatives okay so
this is the how you uh find the
curvature of a curve the formula okay so
anyway so that's curvature uh and we
were talking about konu konu spiral it's
a special because the length correspond
to the curvature very interesting okay
so let me actually copy it to my talk
show so we
get uh so we need to start to code
actually I just want to code
um let's let's not do signal processing
let me okay so you got a curvature then
you got the coverture let's
copy uh
paste showing browser so we got today's
topic okay so let's go back to do the
code of the parabola I haven't finished
explaining the parabola okay so let's go
so Parabola is a curve defined by
you start with a given line and the
given point not on the line so you you
give you know given a line suppose it's
horizontal then give another Point
anywhere so suppose it's above the line
okay then par Parabola is defined is is
the is the set of all points such that
such
that the distance between that point to
the focus and the distance to of that
point to the line is equal so if you
look at this picture you can see uh let
me show you you can see how it is
generated so this is another nice
application in uh called gbra okay you
can you can go and use it g algebra it's
a great
um interactive
geometry so you can see given a line
this line horizontal line and any point
on the plane so this point can be any
anywhere okay so given that you find All
Points such that all points P such that
p2f the fixed point the fix point is
called Focus so p2f and P to the line is
equal so when you draw all such points
what you get is the parabola okay that's
the that's the definition of parabola
there are many other ways to Define it
but this is the very common and easy to
understand
okay so um so what we want to do so we
want to I want to generate regenerate
all these images okay let's do them
Let's uh so here is one this one is
about the
um okay so let me just do them okay
Parabola um
let's let me do that hypera let me go
to so far so good is it interesting is
it
fun so let me copy my
um my packages my code here so I got
some code I can use so I don't have to
type
them uh where where is am I doing good
oh 22 viewer
22 viewers that's
a jackpot hi hi my
[Laughter]
ladies no questions okay feel free to
type questions about programming and
Mathematics uh okay so I want to copy
that
so hyperbola and go to uh go to Parabola
I want to regenerate this Graphics okay
so tracing uh where is it uh Parabola
okay open the parabola go to the top
search for tracing okay so here is
the here's the image of the left side
okay so over here you want to redo it
okay so paste uh so start a wam Lang
language code paste it so pop it up so
here is the um yeah so here is the um
the code okay that that code this code
will do Hy uh hyperbola so let me show
you okay shift enter to run
it so you see that code does
that uh I did the video on this few days
ago so you can you can check out stop
that so but now we want to do this uh um
Parabola okay so yeah so copy that copy
that I'm using S wol and mod in Emax so
I can type wam language code in emac it
allows me to do um I mean it allows me
to use my soft flag keys to uh you know
to to type wam language code and
so what you are looking isaan mod okay
it's free on GitHub just search fora mod
you'll find it for you emac guys okay so
now here is a parabola we need this
package uh this is like this is like
import okay in Python in JavaScript
import or in in emac L it's like
required okay so you need needs that
then you want
um okay let's uh let's remove that those
um it's
not indecisions it's a problem um let's
actually remove it okay so we
got we load the package then here is the
last frame true we don't want because I
remove that parameter okay so delete
that so search
for um search for
last frame
true and uh deleted now why is it
transparent I must have tricked
something now it's transparent I
hate
it okay
replace find
next uh find next uh there's only one
occurrence
okay uh so
I think that's it okay copy the code go
back here close that select all paste
run it
fantastic so it gives gives you a bunch
of images showing this generating a
parabola okay so now you just say list
animate that will turn a bunch of
Graphics into an animation okay so I use
the at at means
add is a prefix notation for the square
bracket so you don't have to you know go
to the end put the ending bracket okay
so this is a code and we don't need that
that that so copy that go here select
all paste
show fantastic is it
beautiful cheers
okay so this is beautiful and I we want
to export this into our animation okay
so stop stop play we can play it forward
and
backward forward and backward okay
beautiful this is the beauty of
visualizing geometry so you don't have
to read anything like like Fe gamma
integral you know like complex sign
cosine you know so you can look at it
and you
understand
um okay so we got a code so put a code
back uh we want to create a uh animation
of this um which we can do
export
um we can just do by export okay let's
do export
okay export then you say ex let's just
give a random name for now okay um so XX
Parabola XX parabola. MP4
okay then uh then what what what is it
you want to export this thing okay
okay now press shift control n to make
it um doesn't make a difference anyway
so let's just run
it processing expression for video
export thank
you okay then now this is exported in
document directory okay so go to
documents
uh you know stupid windows they have
this my music my pictures you cannot
delete them you know it's it's it's kind
of complex to figure out because they
have Junctions then they have you know
like you
know uh this you know this my music my
pictures my videos they are
basically 30 20 years 25 years
bagage because back in year 2000 year
2000s is very popular to name the
default folder to be my something you
know like my windows you know Windows
Millennium my something uh and on the
web too my something my
something so here is the
video so there it is
fantastic okay cancel it close it uh
yeah so here is a video copy the file
path close now we are back here paste
the file path make a link so it
automatically creates this figure video
tag uh with the file okay showing
browser go down there it is
play fantastic so this
this now animation is great beautiful
replaces my you know 30 years old ones
okay so let's
um so let's look at it how large is it
100 kilobytes not too big now we want to
rename it okay I mean uh move it to the
current
directory uh
what what
okay so actually I want to create a
directory
so create a directory just name it I
okay empty that's good now move it to
the I directory do it okay so that there
it is so that this file is not in the
documents because in the documents you
cannot
um you know it's not in a web rout so
rename again remove the XX Parabola
generation
okay and put some uh put put today's
State
okay okay so we got that
now yeah that's good that's good okay
now stop now delete this uh G
yeah let's do
that now this wolam language code we
need to color it so press press press
cify refresh there it is
fantastic okay
now uh
what now the PNG we don't need it
anymore delete delete the GIF we don't
need anymore how large is it 28 K okay
delete
delete okay re refresh okay that's good
uh yeah so we did one
thing okay so we got a code so this old
uh so let's remove
this cartisian
equation
description then you got
formulas
um so but anyway this we don't
need
delete okay I think that's you know we
did something uh that's maybe that's
good enough for
today and uh I'm thinking tomorrow we'll
do emac because it's been a while for
emac um uh you know Parabola is
beautiful let's do another one shall we
maybe maybe we should do another one uh
because it's it's not
hard so let me show
you yeah let me show you this one okay
so this one you see this picture this
means this picture means when you draw
when you have a parabola okay and you
draw a
tangent so tangent means um you know you
do you guys know what tangent
means okay uh I I don't I don't have it
um you know so tangent basically when
you have a curve then at any point there
is a line that is closest to that curve
that that line is called tangent okay so
for example you have when you have this
kind of staircase sine wave then you
draw all the tangent then you color them
in rainbow color you got you know you
got something like that
beautiful and uh so this are for example
if you have a curve like that like some
kind of bridge Ox you draw all the
tangent then it looks like that okay the
second picture so that that is a tangent
now uh now uh that's a the that's one of
the most important critical Concept in
basic analytic geometry and also
topology that's a fundamental concept I
don't have a article on that uh I should
so anyway tangent okay tangent is
another critical
uh fundamental concept more actually
more important than
curvature so tangent so given a parabola
given a
parabola then if you at any point
there's a tangent right tangent exist
for a for any smooth curve okay so any
given point you draw a tangent now
there's a property or Theory any two
tangent they will
intersect in
90° okay that is a theory or property of
the parabola and here is a visual
illustration okay so let's do that
one okay so copy that copy that let's um
so close that close that so this is a
tangent property okay so search for
tangent uh there's uh tangent of a
parabola okay so
now what is is yeah so start a wolam
language code paste it
there there is the code and we need my
package my package is on GitHub PL curve
generator actually this one is actually
you need
um uh sound talk
show Mathematica package for PL curves
you need um PL curve uh plot package
okay plank Cod plot so that's what you
need
so yeah so
needs
okay okay so you got that then
um let's remove this uh tabs you know
okay I think that will
do uh okay and instead of par plot it
should be named planker plot because I
renamed it okay and also you need this
Parabola uh formula okay so so let's go
to
it curve formulas
Parabola this is also on GitHub you can
find it this is a package that defines
all the uh Parabola all the curves
um formulas okay so Parabola is just
that that okay so close that
uh paste so this is a formula this is so
simple Parabola is just um so let's not
um let's just
say
t and
uh T *
1.4 uh wait t squared okay so t one one
over 4 * t^ 2 that's Parabola okay so
put it
there then you don't need that okay so
you don't need that okay copy that go
here select all paste R it make it work
this
[Music]
fantastic can you see how beautiful it
is now let's clean up the code a little
bit
because because 30 years ago you don't
have you know you have Hugh 000000 let
me show you okay Hugh z0000 that's a
Syntax for RGB I mean for the HV
hsl color value okay h00 Z just means
black
wait zero means red then the saturation
wait that is black right and shift enter
yeah that's
black you know so um you know so if you
don't know let's go to um
wait everything youi need to know about
CSS visual CSS okay so CSS you go to
syntax uh V uh CSS color syntax you can
use RGB with this cryptic hexad decimal
Unix
or you can use named colors then uh
all named colors okay then you got RB
color syntax here you can actually use
decimal red blue green r GB model of the
color then you have hsl then you got the
dynamic um so you got Hue which is
Rainbow red yellow orange uh you know
that red red orange yellow and and blue
uh and violet purple violet then then
you got saturation you know no
saturation it just became black and
white okay then you got lightness okay
so that is the hsl value uh
hsl model of color so the in wam
language you have H which I believe is
hsl you know there are several models um
yeah I'm pretty sure it's SS hsl
okay so but why are we using a hue zero
uh I don't get it so anyway this Hue red
H zero that's red
okay when the other two arguments are
emitted it means one it defaults one so
if you evaluate Q zero that shows you a
red square it you know but H zero is
just represent uh the color red but in
wo frame you know after 30 years now
today you can just say red so you got
you know Red by itself you don't have to
go by Hue so to improve the code we can
change this part to Red uh Hue zero just
say red for example and this
Hue 35 1.5 that's some kind of uh green
I think sure yeah that's dark green now
do we have dark
green no we don't have but anyway anyway
so anyway here's a code but um so let's
go back I want to make it pretty like
that so anyway let's let's do this first
okay so copy that that's it for today
thank you guys for watching copy that go
back coast
that put it back and uh put the code
here uh I don't think that's it that's
that's a that's a my lady thing
okay so we need to remove that actually
uh go to okay we need to put it
somewhere else let's put it
um
re move it here okay
okay that's that that's like the recent
you know since two days ago I got a
bunch of this my lady
followers that's interesting thing
um okay and that is probably why I got
like 30 people watching today so anyway
so now so okay so now we do it
again there it is okay so rename it
Parabola
tangents okay
fantastic go back to browser refresh
beautiful now we need to do one more
thing we want to make
this um you know we want to
make we want to draw a lot of tangent so
so it becomes
more beautiful in a artist sense you
know this
picture is better for illustrating the
property of tangents
where
they each tangent any two tangent always
intersect 90 in 90
degrees okay so it's amazing
property but this
picture is kind of more like
pretty uh
so which one to use that kind of depends
on you know your
goal but but I think that's it for today
for you know thank you guys for watching
if you like my stuff if you got money
donate to me
okay go to um go to cali. info my my
website go to you know cali.
info kali.
info uh here's my homepage go all the
way you know lots of programming
tutorials and unic code and all 1,000
articles on keyboard uh you might find
interesting uh go to the bottom patreon
me Amazon gift card PayPal I prefer
Amazon gift card or PayPal okay like pay
me one shot 100
bucks thank you guys uh that's
it uh we shut down in 1
minute so do you do you you announce
before you host talk shows you know I
should but usually it's chaotic so
typically what I do is I announced it I
post it on Twitter and on my Discord
about two or three hours before so just
like today you know you know s talk show
coming in two hours or in three hours
then you can watch it uh yeah so but I'm
kind of chaotic that's the way I've been
all my life so I don't usually I don't
have a schedule you
know uh you know it's it's it's actually
much better if you want like viewers
then you have to if you stick to stick
schedule like every every Wednesday
every Friday uh
noon you know so people are set to you
know you know they they they they are
they have expectation you know on this
day you can watch but I'm I'm kind of
more
random here is
coffee with honey honey and uh coffee
coffee um
powder and milk okay that's it beautiful
exceeding Beauty you know let me tell
tell you why I love them so this is
these are mathematics this see
mathematics and this Parabola property
is so critical you know telescope your
your uh TV cable TV dishes you know
everywhere and
headlamps and uh uh then um then you
know then so many other properties and
the all the satellite path or satellite
or the path of a missile
uh that's all Parabola
okay and then um well satellite is I
mean they are all conic section
satellite is it is then Comics is
hyperbola okay so you got all this you
know fascinating mathematics that's this
you know mathematics then then I love
computers you know technology you see
how do you create the technology that
that allows you to so easily just draw
this so you know you got programming
languages so many different types C
C++ hascal F functional programming wam
language is term rewriting system most
of you wouldn't know you know term
rewriting very Advanced thing uh
computer science ter term rewriting
system uh wam language then then you
know animations you know so it's and
then videos you know of course the video
codc you know how how do you actually
create a video that is very advanced in
fact you know we did one today you know
we did this MP4 hyperbola you know MP4
how do you make create mp4 file format
that is that is very Advanced lots of
signal processing we just mentioned
today you know signal processing sign
cosign and stuff
bye guys