good morning welcome to another episode
of sod talk show
today's topic is I don't know yet so
today's topic is actually you go here
you go to excel programming blog which
is this URL you can just search focus re
programming blog and then there is a
list of topics like this this is my
programming broad list of topics and
just comment in the box here and let me
know what you want me to talk about so
let's pop out this window there is a
popular pop chat that's good okay but
this window it doesn't see it doesn't
show how many people are watching
okay well I'm waiting for people it's
just let me just go to here see list of
topics type one in the chat box
and talk about it actually me let me
begin by let me begin by I got work to
do hey guys say something so let me
begin by I'm going to let's go to my
Python blog my Python tutorial and you
see most of these are Python - you can
see for example stream methods not this
one okay so let's see let's see format
string you can see the code is Python -
because well because the print statement
they don't have parenthesis and this
tutorial tutorial begins 2005 but I have
written also Python 3 but the topic of
not many but basically python 2 and
python 3 are very similar so it's kind
of a redundant redundant to have them
separate and i've been thinking whether
I should separate them or put them
together you know like Jason like one
page covers both and I think now it's a
good time to put them on both one by one
I mean let me merge them together into
one and essentially the plan is I'll
just cover you know the main the main
thing will be Python 3 then with
footnote that discuss you know in this
case okay if you want you if you are
using Python - then you do you know the
the other way so I'm gonna talk about
that and hi guys say something type
something so okay well let's start with
the Python then so this is my HTML this
is my code let me show you an example
what to do what I'm doing so this is I'm
using Saad HTML mod so let's start
so start command log mod and on the left
window here you can see or Emacs
commands I'm calling for example if I
move kusa you'll see the command
everything and so this HTML page showing
browser and we got that that's right on
to code now look let's go to here and I
press a button that's side chemi I'll
get free code make new file kind of a
long name so now we have you know it
just actually pulled a code into a new
buffer and put it in Python mod and
actually I can run this run it so the
result is white out of what what is this
let's try it again yeah I get that
message now and you know I've got this
message before I'm not sure why it's
happening a long crack 14 why is that
anyway so I can run the code run it and
you see here as a result 1 4 9 16 but
this is Python 2 code I need to change
it to Python 3 so in order to do that
let's put it let's move it down let's
put the parentheses then oh and let's
change the file name to py 3 you know
python is stupid
you know they refuse to create an
extension for python 3 and that actually
creates a problem because you know
because python 2 and parents we are not
compatible you know so if you have the
same extension it doesn't really work
you cannot determine you know then you
have to put you know what version it is
you know it's a common something like
that or use the Sheep and which is has
been phased out basically well anyway
you so you put
you put you know what I mean by shabang
shabang is a UNIX philosophy you
know like that like like this use of
being Python you know basically the
first line is special not not not just a
phone actually the first character you
know it the UNIX treat treats the first
character differently so the first line
it's the path to the executable then
you're you start to learn the file
that's that's called sheep and okay
that's called let me show you this is
called she bad yeah you know the UNIX
people have these joggins and back then
it's all very popular everyone is you
know this Jagan joggins cat and so on
tail head anyway so you run this you got
oh you see this is actually this is
Python 3 code because it you know map
doesn't return a list anymore it returns
a blob it returns a abstract blob I hate
that is it's stupid
you know this Python people yeah but
they have a reason of course the reason
is that you know it's inefficient to
actually create at least suppose you
have a billion items you know you want
to create a list of one to a billion and
if you use you know map you're gonna
have a billion items so they arrange you
know they decided you know they wanted
to abstract it so they created this what
what is this code thing where you know
it's kind of like lazy evaluation but
not really basically if you don't access
the elements it's not generated it's
generated only when you access the
element what is it called anyone know
hey no man good morning
where are you at how is it afternoon or
evening or night
so what should I talk about today so you
know go here okay so let me let me put
this stuff here
I don't know if this will work but let's
try it
so today's topic is going to be well
today's state is going to be saw
talk-show 17 okay so wait for a few
seconds it should update and let me know
if if you actually see this in the you
know YouTube below the the you know the
info section iterator yeah no no it's
not East Coast time oh okay so it's a
two o'clock for you 2 p.m. now it's no
it's not iterators it's either they call
it let's see find it so python 2 and
python three differences map returns oh
you are right iterators okay yeah they
you know iterators it iterators yeah you
are right so generator
yeah generator yeah I don't like I don't
like you know those things do you like
those things well apparently a lot
people do especially well especially the
object-oriented programming the cook
those people like that well they like it
because they like it because because the
oo p languages are very limited
you know they cannot express much so
that is essentially that is the only way
for them you know to do that
eat erase iterators and generators yeah
I despise them you know they are they
are now in JavaScript as well Python and
JavaScript you don't find those in
functional languages in general not in
Lisp nodding well in Haskell I don't
know about Haskell yeah I'm not sure but
Haskell has list comprehension which is
another idiocy you know the thing about
the function
programming is at the gym you know
function from I mean is great but but
typically in any field you have you know
when something become popular you have a
fashionable fashionable crowd so this
this crowd because it's very popular so
you have a lot of people and and so in
general the quality the knowledge you
know they don't know things but however
they are enthusiastic about the subject
you know so they try to talk about
things in but they don't actually know
you know stuff you know so which is
today's situation for Haskell you know
you got lots of these Haskell Coda's
they think they tell you about monads
and stuff but they they know like zero
mathematics they know they don't know
what's you know basic math you know
algebra or group theory but every day
they are like Oh category Theory i/o
monad oh you tried you know referential
transparency you know that's a situation
so a Python map to this generator so
anyway so here is here's to a good life
to mathematics are you married
so can you guys see the topics here like
I just posted a list of topics in the I
suppose below your video window
hi Domenico Domingo Domon go don't
mingle
okay should it be Domingo Gomez this is
brandy my my roommates cheap brandy hey
Dee young great to see you so I'm
wondering what should I talk today oh
you can see the topic great so you know
just type something and let me know talk
the topic you know what to talk about
you know I was thinking you know I
should do a non-technical topic because
none technical names it's kind of wide
range of topics you know a wide range
you know like yeah you know that's what
the typical the normal talk show is
about my talk show is is like nerds talk
show you know the programming math and
stuff but the average the general talk
show is like they talk about politics in
Joe Rogan you know Joe Rogan's talk show
is invite guests guests and is drinking
and smoking weed and stuff okay math
good theory and symmetry and wallpaper
groups that's a great topic a Dinesh a
tiny sh oh my god the names are so
difficult to pronounce
well partly because English you know
English there's a term for that that for
linguists in linguistics where when you
have a language where the ranking system
for example if you have a phonetic
alphabet not necessary so I mean even
let's say English you know where the
pronunciation corresponds to the written
you know
the alphabet there's that that property
there's a name for that property I
forgot what it is but anyway Spanish is
very much like that you know it's like
you know there's a spectrum so Spanish
is very much like that you know the
pronunciation corresponds to how it's
written of course in in artificial
languages constructed constructed
languages such as Lois bong and
Esperanto it's 100% regular you know the
pronunciation corresponds to how it's
written when in English it's it's very
bad you know so a the NESH or Danish or
you know I could spell Danish okay I
already forgot what's my first well
anyway so let's okay so let's talk about
then group theory oh my god it's such a
tough subject okay I hope I am NOT drunk
the niche Dinesh okay I think it's
tarnished okay goob oops oops yeah okay
I hope I can pull it off by that I mean
I can I can you know so the topic is
group theory so I'm going to give you
give you guys a introduction to group
theory and I hope that I can express the
way I wanted to meaning that I can teach
you the subject to my own satisfaction
like you know if you know some subjects
such as programming you know you have a
lot opinions and you also have opinions
of how to teach it sometimes you see
other people teaching it you think it's
wrong because they don't they don't
convey the idea or they you know they
they are wrong in some other way they
don't they are misleading you know maybe
that you know so usually when you know
something well you have like your
opinion about teaching you you know so I
do have opinions about teaching math
and group theory so I hope to I'll be
able to convey to you you know teach you
the way I want and also of course also
that you actually understand and grasp
the subject well to such a degree that
from today on you are going to love
mathematics okay here's the question
this group Theory have important
application income side practically
speaking no zero well it's kind of fuzzy
I mean it's kind of hard to say I mean
if you say I mean in one sense every
mathematics has fundamental application
in computer science in fact computer
science is just math okay well you have
you know yeah computer science see the
the if you think into the heart of
computer science it's all just math
involves number theory you know creep
top you know for example computer
science we talk about cryptography
that's actually just number theory
number theory and many other very highly
advanced math such as projective
geometry rational curves and and things
like that those subject you have to
study you know for like five years of
math you have you know you have like
twelve master's degree in math or PhD to
actually begin to understand it you know
and we're not talking about research yet
we're not talking about trying to you
know study you know find out what's new
oh you you you take five years to
actually to to understand what they are
talking about they understand the
subject you know that cryptography
number theory and so on and and also
good theory so what is group theory it
is one of the you can say it is the most
fundamental of all math okay you know
that you know in many math subjects
everyone you know almost like when you
study math almost every subject they
every book the author will say this is
one of the most important after you read
that you know for a while you get
confused so so just exactly which one is
the most important you know but anyway
so in general math you can divide into
like two sub kind of categorization so
you have algebra on my hand and the
other hand the other side is analysis
which is calculus okay analysis in
algebra so analysis studies continuous
functions continuous functions limit you
know basically everything is smooth and
you know in study infinity and infinite
in infinitesimal like infinitely small
so yeah you know if you haven't studied
calculus you might wonder what you know
what do this the how good I mean what
possible possibly things you can study
of infinity but yeah anyway let's
calculus analysis on the other side is
algebra now algebra is about structure
it's it's about structure it's hard it's
hard to explain
until you actually get into the math so
I'm not going to talk about group theory
so so algebra so there's Archer bra then
there's calculus calculus is about as
far as application goes you know you can
measure the speed of a car that's
actually calculus you can measure the
area of some swimming pool
irregular-shaped swimming poor things
like that of course it's far more deeper
than there and fractals in and you know
and too many things so anyway so two
major categories analysis sometimes
called calculus depending on your
country and the other one is algebra
algebra is all about structures it's
about okay yeah yeah you you have to
actually start to I have to start to
talk about it in order to show what it
is so I'm going to talk about group
theory now group theory
okay here's what I can say Group theory
is the most basic the most fundamental
thing you studying algebra so in other
words so-so okay so we have analysis in
way of algebra for every mathematician
doesn't matter which field any
mathematician when you study
undergraduate math major you have to
know the basics basics of both yeah
because I mean you have to know Biff's
basic above both in order to go anywhere
I mean so you have to know basically
both so in further algebra so for the
algebra the the basic of the most basic
of algebra is group theory okay
well some people might say it's linear
algebra but actually group theory is the
algebra proper okay so so that's how
important it is you know and if in fact
every math field every math I really
mean every write country percent all
99.9999% of math in any math field you
have to understand Google theory I mean
Google theory is just that it's like
alphabet in English you have to know it
so that's how important it is but okay
so I'm going to try to show talk about
group theory I need another drink
okay so good theory so let me begin by
saying okay good
you know let me yeah okay so you know
about symmetry the word symmetry now
there are many aspects of group theory
okay there are many approaches you know
it's just like you know like in
philosophies or in economics you know
some books will start by what is
economics or what is philosophy or what
is mathematics there are tons of books
written about those things you know
sometimes in English you know maybe oh
yeah what is programming in programming
in some books you will see you know they
start by you know there's a chapter what
is
programming you know so different author
I always have like different philosophy
you know they try to tell you what is
mathematics but usually they have you
know it's kind of first it's just very
different so I'm going to give you my my
perspective of what is scoop theory so
let me shoot okay so you know about
symmetry the word the English word
symmetry so exam for example if you look
at my face
I'm symmetric it's called bilateral
symmetry you know any human animal if
you are healthy average you know you
have eyes on each side you have hands on
each side you know it's Seema symmetric
so if you can you know you can flip a
person you know left right it's it's the
same you know all for example the
bilateral symmetry so let's say a b c d
e f g h i okay now a is symmetric its
bilateral symmetry because there's a
vertical line you flip it it's still a p
is symmetric it's also pi lateral
bilateral symmetry there is a horizontal
line you can flip it it's the same and
similarly for CDE
h is more interesting it's yes it's
pilot or YZ image image symmetry it has
to bilateral symmetries that's the way
we say it because there's a horizontal
line there's also a vertical line but
however in fact it also has a rotational
symmetry that is you rotate the edge you
know 180 degrees it's h again now that
is not the case for a not the case for B
not a case for C you know unless you do
another flip you know but that's another
thing so anyway we have all these odds
you know symmetry and we have V oh you
know suppose it's perfectly round then
that's a rotation of C
a tree that's infinite rotational
symmetry so let me show some an example
let's say so okay anyway so these are
ideas of symmetry now let me talk about
something else okay let's see this cup
you see this is my mug for my for my
energy drink or tea or coffee
so these things called symmetry again
the symmetry is bilateral symmetry so
you imagine there's a you know plane you
know and you would it's symmetric around
that plane and okay symmetry what else
symmetry I'm trying to give you some
examples of symmetry but I I guess I
suppose you get idea but this is
important because this is all group
theories about the entire group theory
is about symmetry okay this is very
interesting yeah I want to give you some
other examples let's see I mean because
we we are going to be starting to get
deep let's see regular polygons let's do
that all right actually let's go to my
website yeah sorry website it's got
everything encyclopedia of the world
sorry dot info and you go to math then
you go to war paper groups then you go
to hi guys so today I'm talking about
symmetry your math subject good theory
okay so I have written this article but
you know I don't you know the one thing
you know you don't want to do I don't
want to do is to you know when doing a
lecture or a video presentation you
begin to like read off a book because
whenever you
have a page there you know people start
to read it so they they have a tension
bifurcation like on one hand they trying
to read it on one hand you are talking
you know it's trying to listen to you so
they got distracted so I think the best
I mean so there are many styles of
presentation that but for me I want to
avoid it you know you know you know
showing the material of the slides but
basically I'm here but I'm here only to
show you some pictures I want to get
some pictures about well that's that's
not let's go to let's go to regular poly
polygon
what I'm doing is I want to show you
some symmetries let's see google.com I
want to be I want to do things fast
because I don't want to waste your guys
time because I'm a workaholic you know
every time I talk I have to do something
never mind
okay let's look at the cube so we got
many pictures of cube you can see
there's the many symmetries here you see
this cube you have a plan over here you
have like you know three plans
orthogonal pains you know well you have
three planes that's symmetric you know
you flip the cube then it's your cube
that's what symmetry means that means
that means it's it almost means like if
you just have part of it you can
generate the whole picture the whole
thing
that's what symmetry means so cube you
have many symmetries you have you know
you know strains and you also have
rotational symmetry that means you take
this cube you rotate it 90 degrees it's
again the same thing and you can rotate
it again that's the same thing so you
got 90 degree rotational symmetry over
one axis and you also got 180 degree
rotational symmetry
and but that's not all because there's
another axis you know on the side you
know going horizontally that also serves
as a rotational symmetry at axis so you
rotate you know you can rotate the cube
in many ways and and it come back to
itself you know that is symmetry okay
so let's show some others so let's see
cube
okay that's the pyramid you okay you can
also get rotational symmetry in this
case what symmetries are there okay so
your task is to analyze any sub any
object okay in your daily life you know
you look at in your object and analyze
it you want to find all possible
symmetries so what do we have in a
pyramid okay we have a plane you know
you know that gives us a mirror symmetry
we have another thing that gives us
symmetry and also we have a rotational
symmetry over a vertical axis yeah
inyoung symbol has rotational symmetry
okay so these are symmetries so far we
have discovered let's say you know we
have discovered several types of
symmetries we have a you know for
example face bilateral symmetry in math
we call that a we don't copilot robe we
call it a mirror symmetry okay so it's
like a mirror you know you flipped it
so it's called mirror symmetry so we
have mirror symmetry we have rotational
symmetry let me just let me show you
that's it okay let's not get over too
much you know there are other type of
symmetries but let's not cover it now
but so we just have now we have mirror
symmetry mirror symmetries over line in
two dimensions for example a square you
know you have a line in the middle that
you flip the square it's the same thing
so that's a mirror symmetry but in three
dimensional in three dimensional if you
have a cube you have a cup then the
mirror symmetry is obtained you know you
if you you know you you you you flipped
it kind of inside out and it's still the
cup so so you got mirror symmetry in two
dimensions or three dimensions
you got rotational symmetry in
two-dimensional see
or three dimensional or three
dimensional two dimensional symmetries
like neon symbol Z that's right so Z is
a good example Z has it does okay so ask
yourself does it has mirror symmetry
does the letter Z have has have mirror
symmetry the answer is No
however it has rotational symmetry you
rotate you rotate it around the center
180 degrees it becomes itself so X
rotational symmetry
now that's two-dimensional because all
the letters are two-dimensional but in
three dimensions in three dimensions we
in three dimensions what's a good
example let's see god I don't have a
thing for three dimensions rotate we so
we want a example of three-dimensional
rotational symmetry and hopefully not
not anything else you know there's no
mirror symmetry of the subject but
except the only symmetry of the thing is
a rotational symmetry so can you guys
think of a thing a three-dimensional
object that has rotational symmetry now
obviously a cube or a pyramid you know
has it because a pyramid you rotated 90
degrees along a vertical axis then it's
got you know it becomes yourself but
however a pyramid also has a mirror
symmetry so so but we are trying to find
a object that does not have mirror
symmetry that only have rotational
symmetry so anyone
okay I got an example let me show you
wheel okay we got several
wheels but these are not what I am
looking for do you know why because for
example if you look at you know this
wheel yes it has rotational
symmetry you know you rotated a little
bit it becomes itself however it also
has many mirror symmetries you know
around the lines but I'm trying to find
a cop wheel that only has rotational
symmetry and do not have mirror symmetry
okay I'm getting too complicated but
I'll tell you what an example I'll tell
you right away except
let's see
you know you might be wondering why am i
spending all this time about symmetry
and you know just get on with the group
Theory you know but this is this is
fundamental in getting you know warming
up because group Theory it's all about
symmetry group theory is the study of
symmetry period so that is very
interesting so how possibly you know
what possible things can you study about
symmetry I mean it's just okay you know
it's just shapes there it is finally I
found one you see this thing here this
is twisted we all now that this twisted
wheel that has rotational symmetry
you know obviously you rotate it a
little bit it becomes itself however it
does not have mirror symmetry it is
there is no plane where you flip it you
know it becomes itself well it will
become like you know the opposite
orientation you know but that's another
thing so you get what I said what I'm
saying right in two dimensions okay so
this is a three-dimensional example of a
of a object that has rotational symmetry
but do not have any mirror symmetry this
is one example especially this one more
pronounced this one okay but let me show
you a two-dimensional example
two-dimensional example is pretty easy
to find if you look here you'll find it
wait there okay well sad to say but all
these all these are examples of
two-dimensional object that has
rotational symmetry but do not have
mirror symmetry now by the way if you
don't know what these
ah these are these the range arrangin
these symbols are ancient from maybe
3000 years ago the origin of these are
Buddhist symbols and in fact you can see
and I'm not going to go into that but
anyway these are Buddhism symbols okay
in fact in the this character in Chinese
is pronounced 1:1 like waa and that's
the pronunciation of this character it's
not a character you see every day though
I mean it's can't read so it's from the
Buddhist script I mean the arrangement
is from India India is the origin of
Buddhism so anyway so that's an example
of you know symmetry that has rotational
symmetry but no mirror symmetry Oh
actually Z is a good example I forgot Z
right here Z has the Canadian like to
say Z okay what okay we could we talked
about symmetry a lot so we know there
are different types rotational and
mirror symmetry and it can be
two-dimensional or three-dimensional now
let's okay one more one more thing about
symmetry then we'll start the group
theory because once I talk about
symmetry once you know these things then
when I talk about group theory you're
immediately you kind of get at you
because you set it sets up the it wants
you up it sets up the environment okay
so let's look at the most fascinating
object of programmers the most the most
popular subject of math among
programmers which is
holy Hedra there it is let's look at
Wikipedia there are so many symmetries
there okay so you can see this these are
polyhedra you are probably you know
you've probably seen thousands of them
especially among programmers like you
you you might already have written a
program to draw them so let's look at
some examples okay so well let's just
look at these you know these are
polyhedrus
let's just go to these are too
complicated let's simplify let's go to
platonic solids okay here's a good
picture okay these five are called
platonic solids and this is this is a
picture in real life you know one two
three four what those are not you know
why they put it there stupid t-bo
so anyway Lisa Platonic solids
let's talk about symmetry you know so
your job is to let's look at this one
the tadka Heatran your job is to
identify all the symmetries you know
what symmetries are there for example we
we have we know two types right we know
rotational symmetry and we know mirror
symmetry now this thing obviously has
lots of it you know there are so many
planes that that that that it is a
symmetric plane for this for this object
and also there are many rotational
symmetries okay so okay let's get down
to groups I think I've been talking too
much like you know 42 minutes oh my god
okay so so that's it about symmetry okay
so we know we know we
know enough about that so good group
theory is the study of symmetry so now
imagine now you are a programmer right
you are a programmer and you know in
programming we write functions we have
parameters you know like you know in
real world we are learning for a company
or whatever you write programs usually
you you want to capture the different
possibilities by the parameter of a
function
you know the suppose the function does
something and the parameters can capture
different you know possibilities in
other words you encode a problem in real
life into a functions parameters so all
the possibilities are encoded you know
the all the possible variations can be
expressed by the parameters of the
function you know you call a function
with a different parameters you cover
all the situations you need so your job
now is given any any 3d object that has
rotational symmetry and mirror symmetry
you want to codify it so you in other
words let me give you example this cube
has many different symmetries you know
you have you have what three plans three
mirror planes and you have 1 2 3 3
rotational axis each one has a you know
the the axis each one is the rotational
symmetry and the plans mirror symmetry
now the for the tetrahedron you also
have you have like 1 2 3 4 4 rotational
axis and for weight went yeah yeah for
mirror mirror planes so but obviously
cube and tetrahedron are different I
mean the symmetry are different so your
job is to come up with a string you know
as
sequence of code you know you know a
CCPA
or something that captures the symmetry
that that is you know a string of
symbols that that you know when you look
at this sequence of symbols then you
know it's a the symmetry is a cube let's
see you know when you have a symmetry
let's say let's say a cup again you know
this this is a 3d object it has only one
symmetry a mirror symmetry and that's
the only symmetry it has only what now
let's look at another cup in this cup
this curve is a different cup however it
also has one symmetry just you know
mirror plane so these two cups have the
same symmetry even the object is
entirely different in the same way if
you have an object that has the same
symmetry as a cube I mean you can have
many different shapes you know but
however that thing has the same symmetry
as a cube for example you can extend you
know each face of the cube a little bit
make it like a little pyramid however
the whole thing the symmetry is a steel
cube so anyway your job is to come up
with a code so that code codify you know
you might we say codify you know you
know identify codified the symmetry
capture you know so whenever people see
that string they know is this the
symmetry of the cube so anyway each this
object for example they have seen
different set of symmetries and there
there is a code for them there's the it
captures them so let me just say each of
the each there is not a group is a
abstract abstract idea okay
and just like a set a set is an abstract
idea in math in math you can have many
different sets you can have a set of
people a set of numbers set of stones
anything in the same way a group a group
is a set with with a with one operation
and some restrictions we'll get into
that but anyway there are many groups
just like said they are you know there's
many groups so what I'm saying is that
each one of these symmetries remember
not the object not not the cube
octahedron delicate octahedron and so on
the symmetry of the object each one of
them is a group so there is a group
called cube symmetry group actually
that's not the name they use but I don't
I don't I don't remember the name but
but there is a group with a specific
name that is that that is a cube
symmetry group there is another group
that is the octahedron symmetry group
and so on for the same thing for da da
da roca heatran and azekah he drew in
fact in fact all possible set of
symmetries that are finite is a group
and in fact mathematicians has
classified this is a huge task
okay mess magicians about 30 years ago
they have classified they have found and
classified categorized all possible
finite groups okay let's see it's just
such for all possible finite groups
okay fine I group this so he said this
is a big this is another chapter in
mathematics I mean by chapter I mean
it's a huge milestone yeah you know
mathematicians has has classified all
possible finite groups now we are
talking about finite groups because they
are infinite groups as well meaning that
meaning that the group has infinite
number of symmetries what is an example
here is an example can you see there are
infinite number of symmetries of a ball
because first of all it has a mirror
symmetry but on any plane like any way
you cut it it's a mirror symmetry so
there's an infinite number of mirror
symmetry planes and also it has a
infinite number of rotational symmetry
like you rotate the ball in the center
you know from its centre doesn't matter
how much degree or in what direction
it's still the boy it doesn't change so
it so so the the symmetry of a pole is a
infinite group in fact that group is
called cyclic group so you see we are
beginning to see the different groups I
mean even we haven't I haven't I haven't
began to give you the definition or
meaning of it but you already begin to
see the nature of groups you know what
what it is about I mean you you already
understand the fundamental nature of the
group so let's look at the cyclic group
cyc RIC group now cyclic group is one
particular group that is basically the
group of a circle now a circle is also
infinite symmetry you know that's for
two dimensional so there it is cyclic
group so let me read it a little bit
because cyclic group is one of the most
fundamental group
let me read it about it a bit so in
group theory a branch of abstract
algebra a cyclic group or also called
mono channels group now nobody calls
that so a cyclic group is a group that
is generated by a single element that is
it is a set of invertible elements with
a single associative binary operation a
contains an element G such that such
that every other element of the group
may be obtained by repeatedly applying
the group operations to G or its inverse
yeah that's the sacred group okay so I
mean you can read about it I mean so I
mean I hope that gives you the the talk
about symmetry gives you the essential
idea - you know when you read this you
now understand much more now let's get
back to maybe we should talk about the
definition of symmetry of the group
group so a group is a okay from pure
pure mathematical point of view I mean
of course group is a math object subject
so a group is two things
I mean groove is made of two things one
a set a set of things you know anything
a set and operation operation just means
a function okay a binary operation but
you can think of as a function with two
arguments so now what does the function
do the function takes any two elements
in a group and returns any any other
elements in a group that is what the
function do it's called binary operation
by tradition it's called binary
operation so you take any two elements
in a group then you apply the binary
operation usually it's written as it may
be written as the first sign of mod or
multiplication or even amid you know
entirely but based you know
you can't think of it's just like
multiplication so you take any two
elements in a group and it returns
another elements in a group so a group
is a set in the operation of binary
operation however the binary operation
must satisfy some some qualifications
and rules so let's look at what are
those rules a finite group
let's see let's find the definition of a
group okay here is some like
introductory introductory discussion
about group so you can read about it in
Wikipedia so it tries to give you some
illustrations
you know definition okay so Gupta here's
a definition a group is a set G together
with an operation that combines any two
elements a and B to form another
elements denoted a dot B or a B to
qualify as a group the set and
operations the set and the operation
must satisfy four requirements known as
the group axioms so first one closure
for or a B in G the result of operation
8rp is also in G of course an
associative 'ti for a and B and C in G
then a dot B then dot C equals through a
dot P dot C first okay that's just a
rule okay this rule is called
associativity now it may appear to you
that this is odd like why do they give
that definition but I would say just
don't worry about it I mean if you know
already know the topic you can look up
i've article about that sorry
associativity
the nature of associative property of
algebra now if you are curious about the
associativity you can you know read this
article so let's go back to group
definition so you need closure you need
associativity you need identity element
so there exists an element E in G such
that for every element a in G the
equation e dot a equals to a dot e
equals to a code so that means this is a
this you know I mean like the article
said this the the in your group if you
apply the binary operation you know two
elements in a group there must exist an
element such that you know that element
thought any that element add another
element is equal to equals through the
another element itself now meaning that
you have this element in a group you
know we call it identity element such
that when you apply the binary operation
of it and any other ailment the result
is the other element you know is so it's
like you know it's like zero when you do
addition you know five plus zero is
still five ten plus zero is still 10 9
plus zero is your still night you know
or you can think of it as a one the
number one in multiplication so 5 times
1 is still 5 9 times 1 is still night
you know so so one the number one is
called the identity element with respect
to multiplication the number zero is the
identity element with respect to
addition so you get idea so in group
theory it has you know it requires you
to have something similar you know it
requires you to have my elements such
that when you apply that binary
operation it just returned the other you
know the other thing and then there is a
new inverse
okay how long I've been talking one hour
that's about right
we about doing great okay so any
questions am i doing okay I mean wow
mi-mi-mi-mi too verbose you know and
maybe I should cut down on that you know
in my my crock show
am I too verbose like are you guys you
know like going off you know some people
when they listen to a podcast or video
they don't actually watch you know maybe
they are doing some kitchen work or they
you know they are doing something with
their kids or something or maybe driving
so they don't necessarily watch so I try
to you know always you know I learned
from watching other videos and you know
you you want to like read things and
keep talking great thank you
DeYoung so so anyway so you require the
operation requires these four elements
there's also inverse element so it says
for each a in G there exists an element
P in G commonly denoted you know you
know the probable such that a dot B
equals to B dot a equals to e so here is
an important part eight R P so they must
have an element you know so for for any
element in your group you pick any one
there exists another element in your
group such that when you when you taught
them together the result is the identity
element do you see what I mean so this
is interesting but let me explain in in
with numbers you'll get it right away so
for example let's say addition 5 let's
say numbers you know not Google here
even numbers so 5 5 plus minus 5 equals
to 0 what is 0 0 is the identity
identity element of the addition so you
and so what about 6
is there a number such that you added to
six equals to the identity element of
addition yes and that number is negative
negative 6 6 plus negative 6 equals to 0
and so on for any number so there exist
so we call we call the inverse element
so for any element in a group there
exists another element that is the
inverse of that element meaning that
when you apply the operation of them
together the result is the identity
element so it's a similar to with with
regards through arithmetics is similar
to those negative numbers and positive
numbers with respect to addition the
identity element is 0 and if you if with
respect to multiplication then that case
is a fraction the inverse for example
five five multiplied by 1 over 5 equals
to 1 and 1 is the identity element for
multiplication and same thing for 6 6
multiplied by 1 over 6 equals to 1 you
know and and why is the identity element
so same same thing we here with the
groups so if you have an operation that
satisfy these 4 things then what you
have is a group
remember the cube is a set and operation
defined on the binary operation for the
airman in a set now at this point you
might be wondering what is this
operation so you know what where is my
group like what is what is an example I
mean this is you know so and the answer
to that is anything you know you just
start to create a group you know you can
do anything you want you you know think
of this so I have let's say I I'm going
to create a group so I have 3 balls you
know my group is 3 balls and then you
need you need binary operation you know
you need to know you know
they start this equals to what you know
which one you were equal to this one top
this will equal to what this start it
does this week what what you have to
define yourself you know since we got
both you know you just defined yourself
let's say this is ABC so let's say this
is a PC we have abstracted you know so
forget about pause we just have a and B
and C so you just you define it any way
you want you know so so you have so we
let's create group let's say we have the
set is you know and we need to define a
binary operation dot okay
now we need to define a function now
let's use a function of notation so
let's say f a be equals to give us what
it's up to you because you you need to
you know the group definition does not
tell you what your binary operation you
know what it should return he only says
that you know it must satisfy this so
you just anything you want let's say
that you know let's say that a B so a B
you okay a B let's say bi equal straight
let's say BA equals to a let's say a C
equals to B okay let's just say that
let's say C a equals to B okay and let's
say a B EC so we need to do C B so C B
that's faith there it is
so we defined our operation you know it
covers all possible combinations of two
elements in a group and the result can
be anything
I mean you define the function so once
we have that now we need to check if it
if you know if our thing now satisfy the
group definition so we check closure for
a for or a B in G the result of the
operation is also in G is that true
check true because all the result is ABC
you know true associative 'ti a dot B
well you have to check I don't know if
it's true or not so you saw you you know
try to write a Python program or Ruby or
: yeah learn : : is my favorite language
and because I sorry : go to my :
tutorial
and learn a new language : and you try
to see if this is you know satisfy the
associativity property of the group then
you need to check identity you know you
want to know you know and so on so that
is it folks studies group theory but
okay so but what else but I mean we
haven't covered we haven't covered you
know well anyway so I think that's it
fall for me when you're up for me to
talk about this because you know group
Theory it's I mean it's one of my
favorite math subject and by the way
it's also very deep I mean by that I
mean you can specialize in group theory
first of all group theory is the most
fundamental part of math every
mathematician it's like the alphabet for
English every mathematician knows must
know group theory to begin with you know
like you you basically it's taught in
it's part of the first course of algebra
and the first course of algebra is
taught in the third year in universities
for math majors so if you are math major
the third year of university you'll take
the first course on algebra usually it's
called algebra I mean yeah and in
algebra usually the first chapter or the
first you know few chapters will be good
theory okay so every mathematics that's
so basic fundamental every mathematician
must know it but also but also know that
good theory also a deep subject so you
can be specialized you can be a
mathematician you know in PhD or post
PhD specialized studying group theory by
itself that is just just these things
that we just covered I mean it's so
simple and also let me mention if you go
to Saudi math
sorry ok such folks sorry war paper or
paper groups and you can find this
article now and go to the top
introduction you know the this this I
wrote this impact in 1997 and it's
hugely popular it's it's been cited in
you know academia in professors in
slideshows you know they used to write
to me for permission to use some of the
material but anyway this this article
talk talked about the discontinuous the
discontinuous groups of rotation in
translation in the plane so from this
article you can get a concrete idea of
how good Theory works you know the
subject is wallpaper groups there's a
subject called wallpaper groups it's
also in Wikipedia by the way if you just
search for wallpaper groups so anyway
that that's my intro to group theory so
let me read the comments so that's the
inverse rule imply that a group of one
is impossible group of one I know it's
possible I mean because all you have to
do is that elements x that itself equals
to an identity element so you know so
let's say we have a group and the only
element is C let's say let's say ye okay
maybe East yeah so so we define a binary
operation so we define e times e equals
to e okay so does that satisfy the
inverse yes because you know we have a
element for you know the inverse rule
says for every element there exists
another element called inverse such that
when they combine they returns the
identity element so this is true for
every element we only have a one element
so
you know II is he and he is also the
identity because he is he yeah so that
satisfied I think 0:01 of anger diem
that was thank you for the shows Thank
You Allah do you have a RSS notification
not for not for YouTube not for the
talk-show though but if you go through
any of my blogs this RSS link you can
click for example let's go to math you
know any any one of the for example my
home page this RSS you can subscribe
yeah so maybe I should do I don't know
if YouTube provide RSS I think it does
so you have to look yeah I'm not sure
offhand I think I think it does you know
web feed for subscribers you have to yes
if you search I think I think it's there
maybe I should be my I think you I think
you should be able to define a group
using lambda calculus yeah you can they
are simply are kind of unrelated I mean
they don't mesh
he just needs a single function
cool so great thank you guys I had a
great time talking about the subject I
love and it's actually the first time I
I kind of taught I mean our teaching
you know people goob theory you know the
wait god I look at my email so what what
am I was I don't know what I
showed him my email anyway so what yeah
okay 100 in 30 minutes
so thank you guys for coming and see you
next time bye