good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sound our show
today is August 28th 28th and 12 o'clock
p.m. California time Wednesday
good morning bathroom you good morning
Zhi Chong crazy and today okay what is
the topic type a topic guys type type it
I'm thinking let's continue with
yesterday's Python plus Emacs so I'm
going to show Python you know basics
Python and then I'm going to show how to
do that in Emacs Lisp but unlike
yesterday I feel I feel yesterday went
bad you know yesterday then then I start
to learn remember about things and I
don't know anything about Judea number
yeah I don't I don't coach it is
something I like to learn but I got
other things on my plate so I was
thinking you know can you so yesterday I
did video you know Python teaching emag
Lisp via Python constructs but that we
went off on a tangent you know like
every time I feel like you know every
time you know when I'm trying to you
know if I'm trying to do it you know
focus presentation there's pressure and
and usually it's not so fun and I but
I'm getting getting better so maybe we
can continue that today if there are
people like to see that and or other
topics so bathroom you says you are
sorry you know everything programming
language kind of candidate no I don't
it's how to learn programming languages
you know actually yes it's it's hard to
learn
you know you know yeah like people good
morning Pano's you know people like to
say Julia shut up
I don't know anything about Julia oh I
know is that Julia is a language a
programming language that's very fast as
fast as : as fast as in some cases
faster than C faster than : yeah it is
actually faster than : and Julia is
designed for mathematical scientific
programming so in the same class as
Fortran so math you know math languages
Fortran Mathematica Julia APL Matt
MATLAB okay that MATLAB is pretty lousy
and MATLAB and you know these
mathematical languages good morning CMAs
CMAs we don't have a topic yet so type a
topic okay
I don't know Julia so I cannot teach
Julia oh I know is that Julia is a math
language but there is something
interesting let me show you so let's go
to Sally that info and let's go to my
website sorry dot info and let's go to
programming blog let's move the window
here and then check check good and then
we go - oh yeah math languages so we go
to on Lisp no syntax OOP no semantic
noodle yes semantic noodle
math so the search for math this article
class of computer languages math
languages now most programmers they they
code CC pers first Java C sharp Perl
Python Ruby
including Haskell and enclosure and the
least scheme you know racket schemed and
you know rust all those are not math
languages ok so these are industrial
languages and vast majority of
industrial programmers they have no idea
like they've never seen a line a single
line of math oriented programming
languages so every day particularly C
and C first first those type of people C
and C first first you know those those
they like to talk about compilers and
and the UNIX philosophy you know group
they like to talk about that like their
mouth every day is like oh passes passes
compilers int float
you know memory address array references
these people you have no idea they so
whenever when you discuss you know when
often you have debates about programming
languages their brain lives in this well
you know they because in their life even
even even if they have programmed you
know twenty years thirty years
experience people like to brag oh I
programmed for forty years and then this
end output they live in this world they
have never seen they have never turned
in their life scientific programming
they have never seen math oriented
languages why because in programming
industry that's not what you do you know
the math oriented languages scientific
programming well they are part of
industry for example visualization of 3d
objects CAD you know CAD you have you
know those well even CAD you know you
don't program Cadi math oriented
languages but but but we think had
typically they out scripting languages
that's what that's that's when that for
that you do use math oriented languages
ok ok anyway so I was saying you know so
so scientific programming
using math oriented languages who use
them NASA for example you you you know
you do research you should rocket to to
the to Mars you need you need a lot
research I mean it's not just you know
usually when programming talking about
that NASA they're talking about the code
that sends people to the space you know
some it could be see actually Lisp as
being used Common Lisp but but basically
programmers are thinking you know
whatever the console you know the in the
shuttle whatever those are not you know
those are before you do that you have to
do lots of like whole turns ten millions
times more code in researching in
modeling modeling the trajectory
modeling or they're solving differential
serving 1 million thousand differential
equations
you know solving video matrices that how
you do that you do that using math
oriented languages ok so I was saying
Mathematica APL Fortran MATLAB Julia and
the latest one is Julia that's good and
are are for statistics okay so these are
math oriented languages vast majority of
programmers they have never seen you
know never seen never do them in one arm
code never seen never done scientific
programming so they live in this world
this is C C++ Java Perl Ruby
you know Perl Ruby Python these people
including Lisp and Haskell coders you
know Haskell is special because they
think you know Haskell people like to
think oh we are math we are math no
that's the Haskell language they are
designed everything is like is industry
or programming they're not nothing you
know for example one easy way let me let
me let me tell you some easy ways to
tell where the language is industrial is
math oriented language okay guys guys
comment okay so
let me give you two two simple way
litmus test simple way to if you if
there's a language if there's a new
language they are you know a few simple
ways to tell if it's math oriented
language
what what does it does its array or list
okay does it does the index start with
one or zero okay if it start with zero
that's not math language okay that's
crap
that's like C C sharp Java you know this
is Perl Python a bunch of crap
including Lisp and Haskell idiots so if
if the array index starts with one then
it's likely that's a math oriented
language to let me another test okay
first the language has built-in
functions to multiply matrix matrix okay
yes then it's math math language no it's
it's not okay so all these languages
Judea APL Mathematica Fortran yeah well
Fortran is mostly a number cruncher but
yeah I suppose
including Fortran so so yeah so that's
about math oriented languages and
scientific programming so who you know
so who does scientific programming the
NASA researchers the you know a strong
you know the researchers basically sign
typically scientist scientist in
research labs over you know may-maybe
typically have anything heavily related
to physics or engineering around physics
such as nuclear reactor you know nuclear
you know facility hydro dams you know
you know the watered dams you know you
need research you need have the map you
know you need some uh PD and
differential equations that's math
that's scientific programming okay now
it is also true typically these
scientists scientists okay they are you
know they have PhD in physics
engineering math okay but typically they
are not what you might say professional
programmers because they do research
they use this language to research but
they are not they are different from
industrial programmers they so we could
say it's true that they don't really
know you know they don't really know you
know programming that well I mean that
may be that you could put it that way
because they don't study they don't
really study algorithms okay that that's
not what they study they don't know
about our girl whether they know is you
know some aspect but they don't let
unlike programmers they don't study or
ten ways to sort you know they don't
study that they don't study compilers
you know they have no idea what you know
what compared us to oh these math
oriented language you don't compile okay
you type the code you get answers and
and they don't so they don't know so
they don't know operating systems they
just use you know they so so that's why
it's different so these are scientists
scientific programming they do
scientific programming and by the way
it's not like oh he's you know it's like
it's not like using a calculator you
know to solve equations it's involved it
just and some of course some of them
know a lot of both you know and and also
it's true that some some industrial
programmers they have experience with
scientific programming such as myself
you know I do scientific programming
most of what half of my life and II do
the other half is you know Perot in you
know this industrial programming so
that's math oriented languages okay now
we I've given two tests to see what's
the difference of math languages Lamia
is a array index does it start with one
does the language has B or D matrix
multiplication for example matrix and
vector or matrix matrix matrices
multiplication another test another
scene
away characteristics of scientific
scientific method oriented languages is
that typically the language is designed
ok so here there is a word applicative
programming you know that's almost
synonymous with scientific programming
it's an application so you could say
it's like a scripting languages
applicative programming ok so in these
kind of languages you don't you never
ever have the concepts concept of
references ok
references is the is the the number one
crap in programming languages reference
why is there because the C programmers
seek UNIX philosophy these these idiots
they want it to be fast
therefore they created references which
is a which is a side-effect of computer
engineering you don't you know in any
real problem you don't want you don't
actually want references references or
int you know int float this kind of
thing but it almost for in practice it
they are they become reality they are
required because you need to get it to
run fast otherwise it's ten times slower
you know that's why but in this method
languages this all these math languages
they are higher level you don't have the
concept of references ok no no reference
is no inflow thing no you know no such
thing and and you know array starts with
what ok that that's what mathematicians
want you know the programmer idiots they
you ask any programmers you know they
always say oh I prefer zero and and also
the reason they think historically
reason about history is also wrong they
think that oh because memory start with
zero therefore or some reference with
point arithmetic something like that
it's actually incorrect wrong because
for example they people have done
research and I wrote an article about it
you know there's a research like what's
the arrangement
of array you know languages where array
index begin with 0 what is arrangin
because of people this guy have you know
looked into in detail you know and he
contact you know some of the original
designers of the B language which which
comes before C the busy language and you
know so what's the conclusion so why did
race start with 0 because o because some
IBM executed you know he you know he
needs to run he you he needs to use the
mainframe to compute his yatch yacht
races
therefore it ends up you know a race
start with zero something like that you
can read it here and oh my partner and
God Python the Kaido has you know I have
a say on that you know ok so what is
today's topic we what is today's topic
so those are that's about math oriented
languages ok let me tell you so and that
article is about array index so math
oriented language let's see so I was
like this is a Twitter post extravaganza
this is Street opposed it turned into a
US essay so each sent each line is only
140 or to each line is 140 characters
Twitter turned essay so Castle of
computer languages math oriented
languages okay so post comments guys
post comments so : CMOS a skoland how
long we've been talking 17 minutes okay
:
okay um well what to tanka okay so is
close that let's go to some talk show
page and so today's here let's put it
that they're showing browser so here is
today wait what is is yeah today August
28 so comments comments comments so
let's see let me read the comments then
you know math America you are pro okay
actually it's good to mention Julia I'm
working on a project where I need to
accurately calculate pi so I'll give it
a look yeah you can track Julia or you
know in Mathematica let me show you in
math let me tell you something about
Mathematica you want to suppose you want
to compute PI to 1 million places ok
what do you do in Mathematica let me
show you and PI 1 million ok press Enter
then it comes out a result PI to 1
million decimal digits that's
Mathematica okay you know so people say
oh how many lines of Mathematica you
know this one line of Mathematica how
many lines is in C 10,000 lines of in C
and we are not getting into solving
equations like differential equations or
systems of differential equations or
matrices or you know stuff it's all just
like one line you know integral and
stuff integral and derivatives that's
mathematical method entity but
Mathematica is a special case because
Mathematica is also a what's called
computer algebra system now almost
you know computer algebra system can do
what I
just said you know solving equations but
that that does not but not all math
oriented language languages do that for
example APL doesn't that does any of
that full trend I don't think you have
that and also that because Mathematica
does symbolic see you know hey right now
its numerical you know PI to 110
thousand you know 1 million places
that's no mariko computation Mathematica
can do now if you wanna solve a
differential equation let's say let's
say a derivative you can't by the way
you can type this in Mathematica you can
actually just go to buh-bam Wolfram
Alpha you know on the web you type this
your work but this this is too big you
won't do that you can type you know 100
or 10 your work PI to 100 decimal places
for example if you want to do
derivatives you can type you know X X
third power plus B B times X to the
second power let's say that with respect
to X type the type diet in Wolfram Alpha
the in Mathematica will give you he'll
give you symbolic expression now let's
see if my calculus is still member
calculus the answer would be to 2 times
X raise to 2 and plus plus plus X I
think ok I'm i you know i don't remember
calculus let's try let's try Wolfram
Alpha move from alpha
hoopha maava computational intelligence
that's their new marketing lying
computational intelligence let's try the
pie to 1 million places show me assume n
is a math function use as a use unit
instead input PI 1 million digits no
there it is the result ok it cannot show
you know oh of course if you want to
show all you have to click open code
let's say oh let's say open code I think
they're gonna ask you to pay to use
Wolfram crowd or something but anyway
that's that's pi - 1 million places
let's try this ok yeah crowd whooping
crowd they gonna what is it oh oh this
is Mathematica you can actually run
Mathematica oh they have a web version
now let's see if we can actually do
something here oh they yeah they have a
web version Wow experimental let's see 3
plus 2 equals 2 what syntax is
incomplete what this this is wrong
three okay
and I think their web is screwed up is
something 3 into shift-enter ok shift
enter let's see
- first 3 shift enter
okay 5 now let's do let's let's try the
derivative then paste shift enter
okay I got the syntax wrong let's see
derivative this is this is Mathematica
actually this is like wave version of
Mathematica
I haven't coded for like over ten years
so let me read the comments good morning
Nick so next days links topics of jury I
will be prepared to the Main Street okay
as I'm waiting for the stream where you
teach Julia yeah there'll be something
no it's not well this Juke Jupiter
copied Mathematica this you know you see
this Mathematica interface this been
there since 1984 I think that's the year
Mathematica begin
you know 1984 oh yeah today there's a
topic I like to talk about it since you
guys don't have a topic it's just called
random named Wolfram Stefan Wolfram this
guy is truly amazing and I tend to you
know he he and me we see things in same
kind of point of view so a lot of things
he say I agree I mean that's also kind
of my my view of the world my the way I
see things but but of course he's a
genius he's a certified genius and he
just wrote a blog today like almost
every one of his blog you know each one
of his blog is like three to four five
thousand words okay it's not one minute
reading each time he made a blog he
makes a blog every month or two okay
every time he write a blog it's 5,000
10,000 words with pictures instead and
and that's yeah and each time you read
it you know you you can just scan it
quickly you take you you know ten
minutes but or if you actually pay
attention you'll take you 20 mins 30
minutes to read the whole five thousand
words but there's so much detail in
depth like like so many so many you if
you really actually want to understand
you're always you know absorb the thing
it takes several hours to read them
because and and also not just and not
just you know what the content but also
the subject matter is typically like you
know advanced computers you know
programming or computer science or
cosmology you know in quantum mechanics
things like that it's it's you know very
advanced topic so you can you you can
spend hours to dive into and you know
and today
two days ago he just wrote this and I
read it you know after I spent I spent
one hour first reading you know actually
I paid it I pay her attention to details
and it's it's truly deep okay so he's
talking about a book from Alan Turing
and a mysterious piece of paper okay he
you know and unlike you know one thing
interesting is that this alko he posted
on twitter and you know you get hundred
likes maybe you know two actually 30 50
likes you know not not many but you you
you look at what he says you know
compared to hacker news you know though
everyone likes you know 1000 mm you know
three popular but they are so extremely
shallow there's nothing like every any I
get like people of what people talk
about our hacker news oles you know this
piece not lambda calculus actually you
know recency like one week ago you know
the least for phonetics idiots they say
oh this piece not actually not lambda
calculus and whoa everyone is talking
about that you whether is this actually
a lambda calculus or not you know these
idiots you know but you read this
article ok Stefan wolf and he is talking
about Alan tuna chewing and in this
article he you know you can he talked
about he visit he visited you know the
Alan Turing's family because he's trying
to find something out ok he visit Alan
Turing visited several people you know
talk to them and went to some you know
archive Alan Turing and this research
you know this isn't you know nobody can
write this you have to have first of all
you have to have money a lot of money to
here in able to you you to go around
visit people visit you know the Alan to
means teacher or something Alan Turing
student you have to visit them because
they they possess some of the items
books from Alan to me Alan true means
writing you know writing you need to you
need to when you want you know he's
finding our lambda you know in the
this article he talked also talks about
lambda calculus combin Y Combinator
Combinator lambda calculus you know for
more logic you know did you know you can
you can read it it's very interesting
okay and this book is about quantum
mechanics you know by written by this
Paul Dirac you know so it is this
actually so this you know this is this
is even more than Wikipedia this is you
know Wikipedia is you can think of
Wikipedia is like organized information
from the web you know you can kind of
think of it it's like the academic
information on the web then you organize
it that is kind of like Wikipedia this
is this is far beyond because this so
much so much research you don't get you
don't get these books you know you know
these are and you know copy 1930 book
published in German and Alan chewing
chewing on owned it you know and then
gradually he got the book you know then
then they are notes in the inside the
book you know they are you know things
like that notes and you know so he
wanted to find out who wrote the notes
things like that for example this is you
can see you know there's a note in the
book you know so you have to do research
like who wrote a book who owned the book
you know the book passed hands you know
maybe who did add on to him potted or
was it from a youth store you know
things like that when did he read the
book and who you know there are several
notes and there's a bookmark this is
like seven seventy years old bookmark
you know eight years in ninety years of
a bookmark and the more notes then then
there's these notes about this is lambda
calculus and Combinator and also these
these are the heart of theoretical
computer science you know
and when when lease person of lisper
phonetic idiots on how can you so
everywhere when they talk about lambda
calculus the thing is is lease is leased
way lambda calculus Oh Oh Haskell is
based on lambda calculus
you should learn lambda calculus of
idiots okay so I was going to
try the derivative let's see if we can
actually do that let's see there's let's
go - woof M let's this finish yeah let's
finish that Wolfram Alpha Wolfram Alpha
so wait what equations are what go back
Wolfram Alpha
so go through WolframAlpha
oh hi Martha come oh you have to the top
search is on the right side now yeah
that book is principles of quantum
mechanics I suppose if you want to learn
that subject that's actually not the
proper book because it's a it's 90 70 70
80 90 90 years old it's taking a long
time what's going on so anyway so this
article this blog by Wolff and Stefan
Wolfram you can read it's very
interesting and you will also learn
something about lambda calculus and
Combinator's those are kind of the
foundation of theoretical computer
science
remember it's theoretical nothing it's
not nothing practical it's like chewing
machine okay it's not not you cannot use
them yeah let's see they close that new
window paste enter what's going on with
wolf I'm a father maybe because I'm
already using it here so it throttles or
limits limits my access something like
that but anyway I you know if I'm off I
supposed to be this AI engine but every
time you want to search something it's
it's a you you find nothing what
you know so you actually Google whatever
where such is better but if you want to
do math or if you want you know you want
to find how many elements are there
things like that you know very precise
scientific things then whoof MRIs use
so let's let me read the comments so
Julia you know that you know I'm into
computer languages so you know every
week when you guys talk about it that
you know takes my interest but it's
really something I should not do because
it's going to be just you know it's
going to be it's a it's a
procrastination thing for me you know
there I got other things more important
for my for for for me to survive yeah
then those I'll study Julia then that's
gonna just be like yak shaving so easier
a Linux program bathroom uses is there
Linux program code speakers there is
okay there is a Linux program called
spigot which calculates a PI and other
as soon as you keep the program running
oh okay well yeah I mean there is also I
know there's also a program that
calculates Pi in written in C by this C
expert you know the world's number one C
expert what's his name Ballard something
a French guy
anyone remember his name he also wrote
you know the Linux video f FF MPEG you
know the core library for FM FM ffmpeg
you know for processing video anyone
remember the name they said the guy
Ballard something a French guy and he is
also a record ok this Wolfram Alpha is
not going to come up this palette guy is
also the record holder for a period of
time for memorizing PI - you know - some
digits - a Fabrice palette yes thank you
Nick yeah he memorized the PI to some
thousands ten ten thousand or hundred
thousand phrases you know it takes
several hours to recite them
and he also wrote you know he's a Emacs
user but Emacs cannot stop I when when
you're perfect
IMAX crash you know become super slow
and usable so he created his own editor
kind of like you know he created he's
only a data so that he can store huge
amount of digits for his movie Martha
wait I just I just entered derivative go
unlock step by step what Oh computing
okay so yeah the Fabrice palette he say
see that the woods top see expert he
also also he won't one of the
competition force up few stated see code
I remember that because you know you can
go to Wikipedia and you'll find all his
stuff oh and I and recently actually
this this is interesting so let's talk
about that recently he actually so I
this is my web blog web dev blog
JavaScript he he wrote a JavaScript
compiler in you know a new JavaScript
engine JavaScript compiler called quick
Jes so you can this is his website so
he's you know he's a true he is a genius
programmer he's a true master of program
programming you know in a traditional
hacker type sense you know the UNIX
people the UNIX for awesome people you
know those people I've I've flame all
the time now those type of people he's
the master he he is the number one
master who talks about references in
float you know those those things so
every day and he is a master he is a
number one
yeah I consider him kind of like almost
like you know probably true that the
words within top 10 greatest for grandma
alive so you know let's go to his web so
he so he created he wrote his JavaScript
engine you know compiler which and it is
es let's see es 2015 compatible I think
yeah even has it has ES 2020 support so
I mean this is not just a random Joe you
know typically in this hacker types
people random Joe they all say oh I
wrote a JavaScript compiler but that's
just toy you know he's he's compiler is
standard compliant you know it you know
the the spec compliant meaning that you
you have tests to pass you know you have
to pass no 69,000 tests when you do that
you know you you can you know almost
like anyone you can write a compiler for
javascript okay but if you want to be
standard compiled compliant that's like
100 times more difficult literally 100
times more difficult not even mentioning
speed I mean we're not talking about
speed you suppose your compiler can be
10 times slower that's ok
but you want to be compliant with these
you know the suspect this industrial
kind of you know real JavaScript
language that's a hundred times
difficult because you know for example
if you try to compute int you know
arithmetics you know the on the same
machine the dis mode must match i mean
so it's not just you know writing a
compiler in theories you actually
there's a lot of things anyways so
anyway that's my that's my praise for
this guy this Fabrice ballot crisper
fabulous pallid creature
yeah so he's truly a genius but again
like I said he's you know he's in this
hacker you know for lack of was hacker
type of people it's not my you know
that's a community I wallow in but
that's not my type
okay that I don't you know I have no
interest I have no interest whatsoever
in doing what he does I have no interest
so what I am interested I'm interested
in informal logic okay improve systems
yeah
well Haskell kind of you know you ask
God you know that you know language
design that kind of thing but he is just
you know diving in to see and care for
nothing else okay that's that so hey
good morning tenure angles so no
comments no comments today I guess no
comments that's boring boring day okay
so we talked about random chat about you
know the this guy and also about wolfram
Stefan Wolfram this fantastic article
okay go read it strength Stefan wolf I'm
fantastic article and not you see he has
this written this blog but he has
written lots of other blogs in the past
you know you go read them each one you
know you really want to absorb what he
says takes hours okay and also of course
you have to understand the subject
matter for example this one this one you
know half of the content is about to do
you know about lambda calculus about you
know combinator about you know tuning
machines about Scylla automata so if you
never studied that you don't understand
it of course
hey you don't you don't you know have a
V DD you you you would miss big then you
have to study you know then you have to
take one course you know you're gonna
take one course in cellular automata in
you know a theoretical computation
lambda calculus form
logic those kind of thing so this is
just one of his blog he has other blogs
about about you know quantum physics you
know I don't understand about lots of
things programming language design you
know and a new kind of science of course
and you know he sent me the book let me
show you let me show you in my book then
he sent it to me in 2004 but when he
sent it to me I already bought it back
then you know back then I was working I
have money ha
heavy book this is a doorstop and this
is also his book new book few four years
ago for a second
check-check
am i alive
morning the new landlord is how are you
so the new Lango is so bad I have a
apparently I stopped coding my you know
I stopped you know to updating Microsoft
like he's some github I feel bad about
it you know it's my project I have to
I'm gonna get back to that so let me
check the comments real quick then let's
talk about this book this book ok
Wolfram language this is new book this
book teaches you about Wolfram language
you know the Mathematica did he sign it
no I don't think he did ok anyway he
sent me this book like three years ago
away and came out you know I already am
a master I'm at the word stuff maths
master Mathematica back in 1990s I don't
need the book but anyway so this is a
woof a new kind of science published in
I think 2002 very heavy you know this is
this let's see let's see so this is a
pen you know so heavy book and you know
it's it's actually repetitive you know
every every page he says I'm a genius
every page how many page are there let's
see so including index so if we do not
include the 20 pages of index also you
have 1108 1197 pages
you can buy you can buy it you know by
the way you can still buy it but he's
also online on his website just search
for that name I read this book actually
so I read this book when it came out
like in 2002 or so I and then I read it
you know in total I read it almost like
three times and I like you know you know
Wolfe and Stefan Wolfram is a guy a lot
of people do not like because he's a
make love make love maniac you know
because he has to he has to make sure
everyone knows he is the greatest
scientist in the human Kingdom and every
page every page of this book like almost
literally every every page he has to say
he has to he has to let you remember
that he's a greatest great is like it's
like all the others you know the I
instead he doesn't even bother you know
to say I'm greater than any understand
because that's too low whatever is like
in the footnotes in the food and oh by
the way I stunted this so anyway so so
he you know so so this book yeah I read
it and I have a complete well not
complete I have a yeah I can we can talk
about this book you know what is it
about and some of my comments a lot of
people hate them hate him you know he
that doesn't get along with many you
know great great you know scientists
visiting you know mathematicians or
physics
physicists no because he's just too he's
very you know arrogant kind of you know
you know in a way I would say not
necessarily it's not necessarily true
rather you you you know I would say that
because he does not follow he does not
conform you know typically people you
know
is really especially academics in
academia in universities you have this
structure you confirm then you clamp
climbed the ladder okay you wanna you
want to be you have to conform to
the rules the means you know something
you don't want to say don't say it okay
you know then you can't climb the ladder
then you get tenure tenure you know you
are a professor you know cosmology your
professor you know math or things you
know you have to do that but he doesn't
of course he's he's and he's he can do
it he's capable and he started his own
company and stuff so we can talk about
that book so well in order to talk about
that book let's go to my math blog okay
my math blog go through so I can find
the link so here is my blog about this
book notes on new kind of science okay
and I wrote this in 2008 2006 no ago and
so I try to kind of summarize what each
chapter is about because this this book
is you know he Stefan Wolfram he does
have a problem you know this mclubbe
megalomaniac he is that study is
actually true of him he you know so
first of all first of all this book is
about cellular automata which is a
fascinating subject now if you have not
studied that go study yet as you know
just go study there's a game called game
of life okay online everywhere you can
see it you know go first of all go we
caught a wikipedia game of life let me
show you that game of life I play game
of life for ten years in 1990s like was
it for powerful for like two three years
you know almost every day this game of
life it's fascinating okay so first of
all you wanna you go to Wikipedia and
you can read about it
to begin with okay if you if this is new
to you so you go to Wikipedia read about
it then you can try some of the online
implementation of that okay there are
fast ones you you when you once you are
familiar with it you want to use those
fast programs okay so let me show you my
stuff then well yeah so let me show you
a new kind of science let's start to
write what we were talking about today
so hold on second so okay so there's so
many things okay first of all open a new
buffer pace hold on a second
comments okay comments so let's go to my
talk page today's talk page oh yeah here
so so what I want to summarize what I've
talked about today so okay so kind of
weekend so what it is okay we don't need
that we don't need that and what is this
programming blog okay premiering blog oh
there aren't that article this article
we want we talked about that that's a
Stefan wolf friends article blog make a
list okay and then we talk about those
things derivative Mathematica okay copy
it and
mathmatica okay those are mathematical
code and what is this oh the fabric
spattered guy quick Jas okay let's copy
that
crows showing browser okay so some of
the things we talked about and
and then yeah then let's talk about game
of life okay so you should go study game
of life one second
you should go study game of life selalu
cellular automata a uto Mata okay close
that sale Guatemala automata okay
game of life game of life is the most
famous example of cellular automata so
what so so yeah you if you have not seen
this you know this this could be a topic
we can we can show it's truly amazing
it's fascinating and ok so let's see
Conway's Game of Life
ok this is invented by John Houghton
Kong way which is a very famous
mathematicians in particular he's
interest you know the subject matter
that he is interested in appears to me a
lot because you know he's kind of my
type of mathematician you know the
things he study I'm interested you know
because he math they are so many also so
many branches you know some some are
just like programming you know some
interested in programming language
design like you guys interested in Judea
and you know so and other people
interested in Java they just want to you
know write programs so John Horton
Conway he's very interesting he's so
anyway learn you know read game of life
ok that's that's fascinating thing and
automata automata is part of the part of
theory theoretical computer science ok
but not not not not the cool part though
you can have Universal machines in
automata
like chewing machine you know there's
you know you can code there's a tuning
tuning machine in a cellular automata
but anyway so what's so so that's web
dev so what so so let's go back to what
are we talking about
Konya is amazing yeah so yeah so let's
see if how it did okay so Wolfram Alpha
it actually gave the result for the
derivative so did you see equals to what
x times to be first three x squared X
times to be plus three x squared
did I get it right x times to be
to be X first 3x I got it wrong okay to
be X wait that's not right
BX was okay to be X first three x
squared so three x squared
oh yeah that got it wrong yeah three x
squared plus 2 B plus 2 BX yeah okay
that's the answer
so anyway that's that's Wolfram Alpha
you use you use math oriented languages
languages yeah so we were talking about
math oriented languages and because that
close that close that close that close
that index
okay let's copy that we expand index and
math oriented languages okay so that's
what so what so what else what else you
guys have two comments oh you know what
what kind of topics we're gonna talk
about new kind of science so back oh
yeah that's his article so if I'm alpha
okay one hour Wow talk today anything
else if not then that's then I'm just
going to go random then HTML parsing
emag Lisp
I like to write that but so far I
haven't done so I'd really like to do
that but actually I think to do that you
should use : you know there is something
we can show it's okay let's talk about
that let me read the comments a little
bit so Nick says a new kind of science a
new kind of science can keep 10 kilo
grams of raw knowledge it's all about
cell cellular automata so okay let me
explain the book a bit okay you know by
the way so you can read my my website
you know when I'm done go read my
website that's what I'm posting them for
you know because it's my website you
know you stuff up my website and share
share my website ok post to your
discussion Twitter's web in your blog
that that that would be good for me yeah
that's you know helping me oh oh you
know drop drop coins in my pocket you
know my paper in and stuff so anyway
this so so this book I have a you know I
have a kind of a summary of it but I
let's talk over it so this book there
are two parts this book you can divide
it into two parts okay the first they
are like twelve chapters I think let's
see seven seven okay seven eight eight
seven chapters first notes
okay now the two parts of the book the
first seven chapters are about all
related to cellular automata but the
other half of the book the notes part
you know like he's very strange guy you
know he's a one of the kind of very
unusual guy so when he write a book hold
on a second let me find it let me let me
show you what's going on okay so this
book is tremendous
you know I truly really enjoyed it I
recommend you get it but let me warn you
it's truly repetitive so okay so this
here is
here's the two parts to the book so one
third of the book is notes you know this
this third it's all about notes so what
are these notes these notes are
basically a you can think of it as a
overview of the history of math or
computing the his the overview of the
whole human history okay of computing
math or physics that's the you know the
the the the last you know the end part
this section of the book now the the the
the rest you know that the 2/3 of the
book is about cellular automata but
actually so the so that's chapter 1 to
chapter 1 to chapter 1 to 12 okay they
are actually twelve chapters chapter 1
to 12
I only cover seven there's a reason
though okay so chapter 1 to 7 is all
about cellular automata there are so
many different kinds so what what is the
city automaton well we can go explain it
maybe in a moment this this is city
automata okay the things little things
move and also the cover of the picture
you have to see you have to see a
cleared picture of it okay so let me
show you then
cellular automata so yeah let me show
you okay so this there's quite a few
civil very interesting stuff so let's
show them and by the way go the go game
can also be considered as a cellular
automata and which is actually how I
view it now so you can you know yeah you
can say once I learned cellular automata
it changed my view about go yes indeed
so since I learned several Tompa the go
game becomes boring
its of no interest whatsoever but I'm
still interested in it though but but I
changed my view like from theoretical
point of view the go game has no
interest whatsoever is just another
cellular automata as opposed to before I
would think you know Go Go game is like
this unique and very somehow it captures
you know your intelligence you know
because you have to because it's a far
more complex than chess you know compute
you know then then the chess but after I
you know I understand
sailu automata you my view changed so it
you know so what I want to show you
pretty math math books math notes okay
so there is the okay so let's go here
okay this is wolf and language okay let
me show you I wrote this in 2000 in 2000
in 1997 I draw this notebook in 1997
this this is two in tiding studying
theory symmetry good theory so this is
my opportunity to show it that is all
okay so but this but but I want to show
you something else and and all these all
these are math things you know this this
is a part
sine cosine self combination of sine
cosine oh these are done in Mathematica
this kind of plot is this is Co density
plot you know so you have a function of
two variables right so you put two
numbers to a function it comes out a
number comes out a number so you can
plot usually it shows like a 3d surface
but instead of a surface you can think
you know you you you take the output and
you just plot it as a dot you know the
the bigger the value you prodded us
white if it's low the value is low you
plot it black so you you have this kind
of graph now this is called you know
density plot in Mathematica they you
know they call it density plot so all
these are plots of function of two
variables that returns one value okay so
did all these are you know plots of that
I did this in 1990 you know these are
1997 or so I put on the web in I think
maybe I did in 2004 maybe but the core
is probably 1990s anyways then you also
have these kind of things you can do
this this this this is a for example
this picture I don't know if you this
picture is a hexagonal grid okay
hexagonal grid then you rotate it you
rotate the more close it is to the
center you rotate less so the further
away you rotate more then you get these
okay that's that's how you do it so but
how do you code this well you need
matrix multiplication you need a
function you need come you need to
create this function you need to this is
when you need to know math okay you you
need to write a function such that it's
it does rotation but the further away
from a center it does more rotation so
it's kind of it you
so matrix basically is a matrix then you
have this for example this is a it's a
just it's a in a beginning it's a great
of stars arranged in a particular way
then you apply a transformation so it
becomes this wave thing and all these
are matrix all these are basically you
know basically you have to you have to
you have to find the function you know
what what is a function such that you
have such that it maps a point in the
plane such that it comes out like you
have this wave effect and today many of
these you can do in for example in
Photoshop in you know and this fish eye
lens in Photoshop in you know they
you know people have you know study this
and you they probably building you just
pick you know I want fish lens I want
wave effect you know but but at a course
which is a function yeah
so that's this but what I want to do
what I wanted to show is the cellular
automata example okay so anyway all
these are math parts okay I want to show
example of cellular automata
there it is okay it's it's viewing image
okay so that's another that's that's one
example of cellular automata from his
book with new kind of science you know
so so you beginning at the top you just
have one so this is what's so what is
this this these are actually grids so
imagine it's a rectangular grid lots of
rectangular grid now each cell each you
know each rectangle can be colored
either white or black you begin at the
first row okay first row you can color
some of them black or white now on the
second row it generates a new coloring
coloring depends on whether you know you
have rules like if as if a cell whose
neighbors are black then the next then
the next generation it's gonna be become
white let's say for example so you have
several of these rules each cell depends
on your neighbor if your neighbor is
black you know on the Left black on the
right and then it becomes some color so
then you have other rules like if both
are white then what color it becomes so
that's a rule so you beginning at the
first row you can randomly you know make
some sale black then you follow this
rule you get a new row then follow it
again you get a new row then you know
repeat then you get a picture so based
on what rules you begin with you have a
you know this kind of pattern and it
turns out for certain rules the pattern
becomes unpredictable that is random now
random is a very extremely complex idea
because you cannot actually define it
well you can mathematician can defy it
you know like to us you know each one we
think all random is so easy you just
throw a dice but but you need to defy it
how do you define the concept random
mathematically it turns out it's
extremely hard you know so by the time
you
you know it's extremely hard there's no
way you can do by statistics but that's
when random in one way but nodding
although another way you know so by the
time you actually need to an wait by the
time you understand how difficult it is
why all this definition doesn't work
that's equivalent to like you know a PhD
in a mess kind of masters let's say so
so yeah and and by the time you know to
and today they have a definition for
random a mathematical definition I read
it I don't quite understand it but I
know what level it is basically like PhD
in informal logic something like that in
foundation of math or computer science
you could say that yeah the different
the form or mathematical definition of
random anyway so so it turns out
cellular automata forced several certain
rules it is random and you have this
pattern and you can use it to generate
random numbers you know random numbers
is one of the big topic you know people
need you know before I don't understand
what what do you mean why is it so
critical I mean you just fluid ice well
the thing is you can actually throw a
dice but then you so it's rather hard to
generate random numbers and then why
can't you just use electronics you know
something but it you know it's hard
because first of all you know people's
we you know scientists mathematicians
struggled for decades to define random
they cannot defy it you know did so if
you cannot defy it algorithmically I
mean you cannot define then that means
you cannot have a test of something that
is random you know you cannot test
whether you don't know if it's random or
not you know I can throw dice but how do
you know so I I thought eyes I come out
a bunch of numbers let's say Y media but
how do you know my dice is not biased
right so you have to have certain test
then you know okay this is probably not
random
even though
you know I told you look I just bought a
dice I thought it to most people that's
random but then then if you you know
need this number for something you can
tell that the dice is biased because
let's say the number what happens you
know too much so anyway it's so random
numbers so the it turns out that this
can generate random numbers that's
that's an example of cellular automata
okay then let's go back to about the
book so we were talking about a book
what is this book about
so that this book about you know so the
twelve chapters press notes the notes
part the notes section is about is like
a survey or overview over the history of
of math and computation and and and also
aspect of that about physics okay
logic you know logic math you know the
heat a survey so so just for the second
part you know just for this part is what
this is worth it you know you just read
this part notes it's a survey of the you
know history of methane and computing
then the the then the the what comes in
front is twelve chapters now among the
twelve chapters the first chapters is
actually about cellular automata it's
about all these kind of cellular
automata okay they talk there are
several types for example this one is
two-dimensional actually this one is
one-dimensional this one this this
particular one we just showed it's a one
dimensional cellular automata because
you begin with a row okay now the game
of life this one this Conway Conway's
Game of Life this is an example of two
dimensional cellular automata you you
begin with the in a plane okay then you
can have three dimensional cellular
automata okay he talked about the book
you know one of the chapter is about
three dimensional cellular Tom
so chapter one to seven is about several
tomte it's all about civil it's all
about cellular automata okay now chapter
eight - like around Chapter eight to
twelve
it's about applications or consequences
of what he found about cellular automata
how it applies to physics cosmology
biology foundations of math okay in his
point of view okay that that's that's
that's an introduction that's what this
book is about okay that's a that's a
content of this book I would say it's
worth reading I I enjoyed it very much
but let me but but the mean now now this
book is he is a megalomaniac okay he's a
narcissist narcissist
so every Jefferey page you know lit
literally okay every every five pages
every 10 pages he he will remind you in
various ways I'm the greatest scientist
okay greatest genius in the history of
humanity
very annoying you read it you know like
yeah I already know that this is 100
times you say that and also every page
he will repeat he will repeat that
there's a something about you know the
new kind of science you know this
dramatic title he will say simple
programs generates unpredictable
patterns okay he will repeat that that
concept every every five pages
you know sometimes literally literal
repetition every every five pages and
this this is God you know 12,000 pages
so it's extremely painful very you know
you get pissed reading this you know you
have to you know after reading
hundred page pages you get pissed
because every five pages he tells you
again oh by the way
simple programs generates you know
random behavior and then next five page
oh you know random behavior can be
generated by a symbol of MC does that
and of course people in general the
scientists you know the academics
professors they don't like him attack
they attack him you know they they
publish you know this is pure garbage no
content did yeah they are did this is by
the way so those kind of criticism they
are a lot you know there's this guy who
collected all the criticisms of Stefan
Wolfram's book published in you know
physics journal you know math journals
logics journal you know the a lot of
people attack him some will say this
whole book is like nothing there's no
nothing new you know everything he said
he's already studied by someone else he
just you know he just like pretend it's
his invention and you know lots of
things like that most of them are forced
I can I can you know my that's my
opinion
there are criticism a lot of them are
force they do that only because because
they don't like him but but of course
part of it is very solid because he does
you know repeat you know I'm a genius
like implied you know like every every
few pages he's very very extremely
annoying you know I know so much about
this book because I read it you know
like two or three times and you know
from different years I'm you you know
you can call me a Stefan Wolfe I'm fat I
like his stuff you know I usually often
agree with his stuff and you know and
the fact that he's a mega amo
megalomaniac I can understand I also
find it annoying but I kind of I accept
it you know that's you know that's you
know that comes with him you know anyway
so
so yeah you know Amazon you know they
are like thousands reviews when the book
came out in 2002 there are thousands of
reviews I read every single one of them
and I read em every criticism of a book
of this book in journals in physics
journals in you know and I think there's
also one from New York Times in you know
there is a guy who collected all
criticisms let me show you where okay
this mathematician this Edwin okay
Edwin crock whenever there's a new
criticism above the book he collects it
this is old this this began in two
thousand two or three okay so you know
this I read them all anyway so that's
about this book so I like it okay so you
know if you like it you know buy it let
me post my link okay so if you buy it
buy it for my lips website my for my
link so let's go back to the comments oh
my god no comments guys okay I think we
are about done then about parsing HTML
it is I like to do right I like to write
that but I haven't have have not done so
I might do it in : but actually there is
a program I mean let me just read the
comments okay
so panel says I'm a mess you're going 12
people okay yeah okay so hey we are
about to end that's 80 minutes so panel
says panel says how do you source
highlight your code boxes in HTML page
what do you mean sauce highlight your
code boxes oh oh you mean syntax
colouring yeah so so for example let's
go to Python show let's go to Python 3
basics like that you mean this this
coloring right so panel sensor I like
comments guys Emma answered if you are
still there cool graphics great more
magic eye stuff okay Nick say it's the
only thing that's not unpredictable is
that he's the greatest scientist ever
okay Dan says meow maniac is an
understatement he's unbearable extremely
intelligent no question about it but
extremely of pudding yes that's that is
true that is true especially you know
but well mostly in this book but today
you don't see that as much though I mean
this book in particular is like that but
today you read his blogs he's still kind
of you know varies
you know arrogant you know okay you know
but mm not as off-putting though you can
see what you know you can still read it
so yeah so syntax highlighting how do I
do that it's actually very easy actually
I have an article on that with food
detail for example let foot let me show
you an example first of all let's say
building help no okay so let's say this
simple code okay Python print version
it's opening Emacs so you skip around
you can see here's a code okay here and
so let me do this close close so let's
go to let's just do a Python okay it's
all if you use excuse me is if you ask
Sarge tml mod you can do it so I call
command look at the left window you see
my command so I call it then Python 3
enter I got you know I got a template
then I move it to a buffer okay now I
can start to type let's say x equals 2
array 3 4 5 ok oh god I forgot my Python
let's say print X okay run it works ok
yeah that's that's Python books now DVDs
file and copy it paste it here he eats
there so show in browser go down it's
here but it's not colored so I want to
color it now now look at the left window
I call the command now it's color you
see those span tags now in browser
refresh you see it's colored so this
works in emag list too for example let's
create a new email is ok then go to here
tiffen return let's say X X so let's
just say message message hello
ok ok so that's a code copy it to be
that file paste it here color it oops
press the wrong key color it ok save go
to a browser refresh there it is colored
Firefox has a bug every time because
every time you refresh oh it doesn't
happen here but it but sometimes when
you refresh it it Scrolls this began
about half a year ago
so how do you do it actually so I have a
explanation for detailed instruction on
how to do that so if you have to go to
my Emacs Lisp blog practical email is no
command examples yes then search for
syntax right synt okay not their search
for color a color source code there it
is
Curtis ausco so here are a collection of
HTML commands so this this our code it's
very old this began in 2007 because back
then at that time I need to do it so
it's now I've been doing that for 12
years so I show you the detail exactly
how to do it you know how to you how do
you write a code and you know but if you
just want to use it off out of the box
use side chain maille mod you know it's
on github just such so HTML mod ok so
that's it for today's thank you guys for
watching that's that's it for today
anything else
so you so let's see what what one minute
to type your comments ok then they are
click exit so today also so there's
another question about email is writing
a HTML parser I want this that's
something I want to do because I write
HTML all the time
I don't have a validator right now it
used to be on Firefox there is a you
know validator you used to so whenever
it's invalid your CEA is some kind of a
you know red sign but
hey but okay tomorrow HTML and eMac
beasts yeah okay that that's a good
topic so tomorrow I can do a
introduction on excite tml mod you know
because I haven't done that you know I
think that might be interesting people
have been some people I know interesting
in that XHTML mod where is it
general okay so I put it in here haha
because actually I've been using this
for seven four four seven years now but
nobody else use it because well it's
it's pretty good okay so anyways I so
tomorrow we can talk about this like I
can do a introduction down on these
features you know package features yeah
okay so yeah so bad about HTML parser
there's something we can maybe we can
talk about tomorrow
I need a passer so you used to be your
Firefox you have a you know a button you
can install a plug-in then whenever page
is invalid take you know pure you know
strictly invalid like Amanda HTML yeah
the button will become red but I stopped
working several years ago five or seven
years ago what you want actually you
know the important thing is that you
want a local validator you don't want
something that you know you know go to
for example there's HTML validate the
data official website from w3c now it
can anyway you don't want the tool that
goes there because almost most of the
time your file is local usually they
required you the input to be a website
so that's that's one of the issue the
other issue is
you don't want you know you don't want
to go to Kareem oh go to the server you
want just a local validator
so so I've been searching for that for a
long time and still there's no solution
I don't have a solution now
so I've been thinking of writing one
myself the full banner data you know if
you want a validator that's a full
validator meaning that it according to
the HTML spec which is extremely
complicated okay
if you can write that you will be one of
the great top programmers you know
nobody can do that a few people you know
so but what I really want is not that so
what I really want is just a simple way
of firmness check or something like that
you know I need to check is whether you
know all the I have the other ending
brackets you know we don't have missing
missing you know tags things like that
that's all I want
I don't want they you know I don't want
the hundred percent full passer in fact
I don't want that even because the full
posture especially html5 you know you
can omit many tags for example for
example something okay something some
you can omit the closing paragraph tag
for example if such and such that the
next tag is something or you know under
certain conditions then you can also a
mean some others you know things like
that very complex idiotic okay what I
don't want that I want always I want the
text to be always opened and closed and
also for certain tax was for example
image tags
there's no closed tag but you can add a
slash in exa X XML syntax so I want you
to write that maybe right in HD eMac
baseball I've been thinking Golan and
it's not too difficult to do because I
have a program that checks that
validates parentheses like you check
also the parentheses you know
parentheses square brackets curly
brackets braces you can check you know
a thousand a thousand pages to see if
there's mismatched parentheses so once
you know how to write that that is that
is pretty simple then you can write a
you know this way of formed in this form
this check of awake for HTML or XML
because all you're checking is the you
know the matching of the tax anyway
maybe we talked about that tomorrow
softness so thank you guys for watching
bye