good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of shut up shop
today is September 13th Friday oh my god
today's 13 is Friday 2019 California
time simulcram p.m. and I will be back
in three minutes okay in three minutes
okay what is this page so it's great I'd
be back in three minutes okay
another day another talk show and today
we are going to talk about I don't know
nobody is here
so let's see oh three people is are here
so common guys type your comment in a
comment box in a chat box okay so what
is today's topic
now if nobody is gonna say then I'm
gonna just go in to do random okay so
today's topic random okay random then
now I'm I want to show you some of the
something I found okay sorry sorry
keyboard rock oh my god it's hot here
it's hot here it's a keyboard blog and
you go there and so today I was shopping
for a hard disk I don't have a backup so
I need backup you know that's important
you know so I want to get a hard drive
so I've been doing a some research on
hard disk it's hot here so I'm doing
some research on hard disk and first of
all there is a question are you going to
get a flash drive solid-state drive or
hard disk drive spinning hard drive so
the best two choices I found are these
now this is one of the better ones
Samsung t5 you have 500 gigabyte or you
have one terabyte let's click on that
one terabyte okay that's probably
probably what you want or two terabyte
so one 500 gigabyte is $80 one terabyte
is 162 terabyte is to $300 so if they
get expensive quickly but this is a good
one I
from my research so this is a flash
drive or external using USB three and
another one this is supposed to be a
good one is a hard disk spinning hard
disk and it's 2 terabyte is only $80 so
if you are shopping for a hard disk go
to Saudi keyboard blog and buy it from
my website ok
ok let's talk about something about
keyboard now guys comments ok type in
the chat chat box now it's hot here I
need to do something about it the fan is
not a solution because I noticed every
time I do that you have this test you
have this you know window effect that's
why you know microphones they have this
foam that prevents these effect I forgot
what's the name so this keyboard this
wobble board is also pretty good if you
are working on a standing this standing
desk ok so basically you stand on this
thing and you know so that gives you
some movement things like that it gives
you some movement it's sure it
man where is it yeah I was on choice ok
let's pick that this is called wobble
board
it's popular since maybe 10 years ago
and you know so use you use a standing
desk it gives you some movement you know
which is I think it's great
so wobble board let's go back to my
keyboard blog my god it's really hard
here I need to open open the window
somewhere so who is here 5 watching say
something man pick a topic okay pick a
topic for today and otherwise I'm just
going to talk and then pick you know say
hi type something so there is this
keyboard this is from the movie Tomorrow
Never Dies James Bond so this movie is
like 2005 or something like that or even
earlier and they show this you know this
this James Bond features you know China
Chinese stuff so you have this bound
girl who is a Chinese girl and they show
this keyboard and that's City okay
because you will not find a keyboard
like that anywhere in China
first of all in China okay that's an
interesting topic about Chinese input
system in China or the keyboard in China
is the same as American keyboard you
know just quote here there is no Chinese
characters on it you use the input
system such as let me show you some
typing of Chinese okay someone okay so
it song one song one so that means
Chinese song one so that's that
let's type right in Chinese okay
so when okay she had someone okay that
means right Chinese so that's a Chinese
input system you know it's a variable on
the Mac on the windows on you know in on
Linux and in fact in Emacs you can also
do that so you Emacs users let me show
you sir the Emacs Chinese let's just
search for sorry Chinese
Chinese input in emacs meaning that in
emacs you can have Chinese without any
operating system input methods for
example let's let's switch toggle input
method okay so let's call let's open a
new buffer magnify call toggle input
method actually you should what you
should call is set input method okay not
toggle because if you toggle that won't
work for you because I have set my
default input method to Chinese so I can
call toggle input method directly and
I'll be in Chinese but what you do is
you say you call set input method okay
so call meta X let me show you so all my
commands you can see on the left window
so set input method okay now Emacs will
ask you to choose one they are like 40
or 50 input methods in Emacs so you say
Chinese py okay they are they are
several like five or ten Chinese input
methods so you type Chinese py that
stand for Chinese pinging okay now let's
type the same thing we type here
Chinese and write Chinese okay so let's
let's type that let's move this over
here so so first of all you have to pick
the right character too then that then
that okay that's right Chinese you see
same thing is that now this is
simplified character now okay now let's
call meta X let's switch back toggle
input method
okay now I'm back
now I'm back in English English okay so
that's about right in Chinese in emacs
you can do that you know it's it's kind
of fun to try a test - good morning a
test - good morning - Chile how are you
doing today so attached - pick a topic
for us we don't have a topic yet right
now I'm just talking random so we were
talking about Chinese infant method
oh and then let's go back to let's go
back to this keyboard you see in China
you don't have a keyboard like that you
don't have a keyboard label like that
anywhere in China or keyboards are just
the same exactly the same as the English
keyboard American keyboard but in Taiwan
you do have something like that every
keyboard sold in Taiwan you have
something like this but not like this
they they also have English characters
on it for example click here then you
will see they have doing yeah yes indeed
so anyway so here is a this this page
talks about and gives you a overview of
Chinese input method that is how how to
type Chinese in fact you can try it you
can try it yourself on Windows Mac or
Linux you have to install some kind of
input systems and you know some purses
complicated but if if if you are on
Linux you can also try it by going to
Google Gmail like if you use Gmail you
can just go to Gmail I don't want to go
to Gmail because it's going to show my
emails anyway you go to Gmail and
there's a there's a selection that that
lets you choose Chinese input method
they also have you know Japanese input
method and Korean input method or
aerobic input methods so okay so this
page is a kind of over the overview and
to Tokyo
Chinese simple methods like what what is
it what types are there what what how
many are they what kind of are there
what do China use I mean and Taiwan what
do Taiwan use you know things like that
Hong Kong so for example here is the
Apple keyboard Apple keyboard Saudi in
Taiwan looks like this not in China
though remember every keyboard in China
is exactly the same as American keyboard
okay so but in Taiwan they they do have
you know this keyboard with these kind
of labels so anyway this page tells you
how to you know what's it all about
so you can read that and but and you
know it gets complex basically there are
there are many types of Chinese input
systems but mostly they can be
categorized into two categories one is
phonetic based sound sound based that is
when you want to type a character you
type how it sounds
then you have one bunch of choices like
the Emacs we just demonstrated you know
that's a sound base input system then
another input system that require
learning require more learning is
character based system that is when you
want to write Chinese you know the how
the character is written you know like
which stroke begin or you know you know
how it looks
so you basically you take the character
apart so you enter certain keys that
corresponds to the character and this
this is more advanced and typically this
requires require learning require some
memorization and supposed to be it's
more efficient you know less keystrokes
that's character based so attached edge
says like it I like it I am also
learning soo in okay I already installed
chewing in Ibis okay I don't know what
system is chewing I really like it okay
now
suing now okay so attached - are you
Chinese blood like like are you part
Chinese or something contest I should
say so - says what about the explained
JavaScript object in JavaScript Oh be in
depth okay let's do that
okay okay let's do that that's gonna be
a kind of big topic so let's do that
right after we do this after we explain
is okay so Chinese systems a Chinese
simple systems they're they are quite a
few and okay so you mentioned doing that
is different from pinging so what are
they they are a phonetic system they are
a phonetic system for Chinese characters
that means meaning meaning phonetic
system means you basically have
alphabets or some characters that
represents how a character sounds that's
what phonetic system means so for
Chinese they are also quite a few
phonetic systems you know invented over
the past 200 years so the most popular
and used internationally is called ping
in this stand this began around 1950s
ping and it uses English alphabet Latin
alphabet like English alphabet to
represent the sound of Chinese
characters and which is in fact what I
have been using you know when I
demonstrated demonstrated that Emacs
enter in Chinese that's using pinging
and same thing over here I was using P
for example P in Chinese is like written
X tonight like like this okay
so you type P I N and why I n okay
that's a character number one so you
type one that's pinging okay that's a
English alphabet paste phonetic system
to represent Chinese characters sounds
okay that's P phonetic system now to in
doing z hu i ing that's another system
and that system does not use English
alphabet that system uses kind of like
Chinese characters so it's rather more
difficult I mean if you are not Chinese
it's more difficult to learn that that
system is from it's mostly used in
Taiwan okay so for example I have
article on that here you see all these
topics are interesting because they
involve writing systems you know the
things I I am fascinated by they are
about writing systems they're about
languages linguistics they are about
symbology you know all these symbols you
know including Latin alphabets those are
symbols in Unicode writing system so so
I have interest in these kind of things
so I studied a lot of them so this page
explains about doing which is a phonetic
system for Chinese characters but the
alphabet the characters they use to
represent sound are these you see you
know if you are not Chinese see these
are incomprehensible to you but anyway
you know it just represent sound and
also remember IPA IPA stand for
international phonetic alphabet
it is designed in France it's it is
designed to represent sound of all human
languages at least in theory okay to be
possible to represent sound in all human
languages
so in fact we I did a video saw talk
show on IPA you can just go to youtube
and search Saudi IPA I think you'll find
it so IPA is a generalized phonetic
system for any language so on this page
compare suing you know I compare the
three systems pinging system the
phonetic system based on Latin alphabet
suyin system and IPA so I have a table
here you can see on the foot on the Left
column it's doing in the middle column
it's ping it's all English letters and
on okay sue anything and what about IPA
so okay for IPA you have to look at this
chart so the first row is IPA symbols
the second row is pin symbols and the
third row is true in symbols and the
last row is example characters with
those pronunciation so that's about that
you know for those of you you know
interested in languages you know stuff
like that you might be find it useful
help me know it's just it's like it's
like we reading Wikipedia you know it's
not something you really need to know
because if you really need to only these
things you already know it you know you
need to type Chinese you already know it
but as a academic exercise as a
philosopher as a someone you know who is
curious about all the things in the
world you might you know study them so
that's about that that's about Chinese
input methods Chinese and phonetic
systems okay so let's go on to let's
move on to the JavaScript okay so
explain javascript object and opie in
depth okay that's a big topic that's a
big topic I hope I will do well I did
this a few times in the past so first of
all let's go to JavaScript my JavaScript
blog okay
so I did this a few times in the past
and it's kind of rambled rambling but I
hope
today we can do better so here is my
JavaScript in depth it covers everything
in detail so you should read it after my
video JavaScript in depth you know the
difference between the difference
between reading book you know like my
tutorial versus video is that video is
much more friendly you know because you
see so this section Emad in my tutorial
jumba's this section javascript object
and inheritance that's the all these
sections are about the details of
JavaScript are check the technical
details very precise and accurate
technical details about JavaScript
object and its inheritance system you
cannot talk about object without talking
about inheritance because they are it's
part of it it's the same thing so anyway
that's the textbook you know so called
you know that's my tutorial you can read
that very detailed very concise and very
precise you know you you learn
everything accurately you know but it's
less friendly than video presentation
like when you have a lecture someone
teach you you see the facial expressions
you you know explanations or parts or
struggles you get you kind of get you
learning in a different way and a much
more friendly way because when you read
it's you know reading is not a human is
not not a natural human ability reading
and processing the information is kind
of logic it's a trend process you know
you go to school for 10 years high
school after high school then you know
how to read most people if you don't do
that you don't know how to read but but
however you can listen you can watch
people you know that is the traditional
more primitive and more almost more
effective way of communication
so so we so I'm gonna teach you about
JavaScript object okay so I tried this a
few times
pepto good morning have a great weekend
does that mean you are going okay so
yeah so let's let's let's start to talk
about javascript okay it's thirty
minutes
good morning Abdo to Egypt so we are
going to talk about JavaScript objects
so first of all yeah so let me try to do
this first of all the first most
important thing you want to know I'm
going to give you a kind of more
technical explanation about JavaScript
object typically you will not see my
style of presentation in anywhere else I
know because you know I spend huge
amount of time on JavaScript and I read
all the other popular tutorials or books
you know including Microsoft JavaScript
tutorial including you know I I survey I
surveyed them all so typically you don't
see the style I do in those books they
talk about well anyway let's not let's
just begin to let me show you the
JavaScript object when we do that we
also want to write it down because that
way we have a good idea what we are
talking we're more organized so first
first of all understand JavaScript value
types
now javascript is not a typed language
you have but however values has type
variables do not have a type but however
every value has a type for example 3 is
a number it's a it's a number type
string something that's a string type
okay then you have object type then you
have symbol type so they are a few
the one thing you want to begin to
understand well is about all the types
in JavaScript so you go here you go to
JavaScript variables then you see value
types that's the first thing you want to
know so javascript has these types one
two three four five six seven seven no
more and notice it has these seven exact
types okay now remember this okay this
is because every value in JavaScript
belongs to one of these seven types so
this is so so so you know I'm gay I'm
giving you kind of a mathematical style
of understanding JavaScript right now as
opposed to how to or oppose oppose you
know I'm giving you a the structure the
fundamental structure the mathematical
structure of JavaScript so remember any
value you see in JavaScript belongs to
one of these seven types now okay what
are they so there is undefined
they are undefined no pooling stream
number symbol and object okay now
undefined type the only possible value
for the undefined type is this undefined
keyword that is you type the word
undefined that word is the only possible
value for the undefined type okay so
does that make sense in it let's make
let's start to code okay let's let's
create a JavaScript okay so for example
and defined I you see I even have a
brief type u space then you got
undefined that's a keyword that's why
it's screaming okay so now let's let's
say console.log and define oops okay run
it so it trains undefined okay so then
you can also type you can say type up
type of is a operator
that returns a string the string will
contain words that represent what type
of the value is so so type use type of
to find out what what is the value for
example let's run it so it went returns
undefined actually it is a string so we
can check by doing that you see so we
type of undefined equal triple equals
through the string undefined run it it
says true
okay so that's that is how you find out
what type something is okay that's a
code and it's showing browser that's
kind of today's notes okay let's go back
so undefined the only possible value of
that type is is the value is a keyword
undefined now you have a new type the
end is the same thing the only possible
value for the new type is a new keyword
okay so what is undefined undefined is
basically a function that does not have
a return value it returns undefined okay
a variable that is not assigned it
returns undefined
you know the default value is undefined
Easy's the word you know is the keyword
undefined and no no is kind of a mistake
in JavaScript no no does not have much
use and meaning basically it is kind of
like undefined but it's it's you know
JavaScript the language has lots of
historical Watts bad design and in
package because it's designed and
implemented in 10 days literally 10 days
design and implementation so it got lots
of problems so for now just remember
that no no is just the only type of new
thing is the new keyword and it's it's
not it's it's not really have a good
definition things like that it's just no
okay then you have the boolean type
and the there are only two possible
values for the boolean type the keywords
true and false so when I say keyword
here I mean literal like little Awards
for example let's do another JavaScript
so so let's use console.log true okay
that's that's a keyword you know that
you know just the word true it's by
itself so you can say type of type of
true and it says pooling okay so now you
do type of true equals the string
pulling okay it returns true now
remember the types typeof operator
always returns a string okay always to
be turns a string so let's let's copy
that
close that put it here color it showing
browser okay that's true enforce okay
and at this rate we all not go anywhere
it's too slow so anyway let's let me
continue so then you have string type
string type person you know it's just a
string okay let's go faster number type
is any number now JavaScript does not
have float type int type loan turbo
doesn't nothing like that Chavez in
JavaScript a number is just a number
doesn't matter it's got a decimal place
or not is integer float it's just number
there is no technically there is no
differentiation
okay just number number type and number
type now this is important know there's
a peculiarity here number type includes
two to special literal keywords one is
none na n that stand for not a number
the other one is infinity for example
let's try it so let's show the number
type okay we gotta go faster because we
haven't got into object yet so let's see
so yeah when
right now we want to nan okay we can we
can run it nan it's not returns net and
infinity if infinity is just returning
infinity those are key words and these
both of these are number type okay so
for example it's not to type of type of
okay equals to number okay this this is
going to return true okay vennett you
see true and true here here
you see because nan and infant infinity
are just both considered to be numbers
so if you say type of three that is also
true
okay let's remove that so we run it true
true true or true let's say type three
point one two three four five okay
that's also a number type okay that's
number type cut it put it here put there
and color fie okay so number type now in
JavaScript es2015 they introduced a new
type that type is go code symbol now
that's a that's not that much used and
it's more involved to explain so that's
it let's skip that because this is new
in 2015 and it's not really that common
you know it's not that really commonly
used so let's skip that now for now it's
simple type just means it's a symbol
okay it's kind of its kind of like
stream you know you cannot do anything
to I mean it's like inert it doesn't
it's not you know it doesn't do anything
it's just represent something you know
it's that's why it's called a symbol
it's supposed to be unique you know the
symbol type is foldable it's created for
the purpose - for the purpose of
creating unique property names okay that
that is basically the purpose why they
introduce the symbol
but it's kind of advanced so you don't
have to worry about it now
now the last type object type this is
the more the most important of them all
in a sense because because everything
else in JavaScript is a object now
remember I said every value of
JavaScript belongs to one of these types
so when you have you know any value
anything in JavaScript code when you see
you know it has a value right when you
evaluate it evaluate it on the
expression or function or whatever it
has a value it must be one of these
types you know that's what you know
that's the value type so this is
important remember so when you want to
understand JavaScript in depth you know
this is one of the important thing you
know you you go by you know
mathematically what you know there's a
type concept value has types so it must
be one of these okay so undefined nor we
are kind of familiar
that's that happens in other languages
too you know like in Python you also
have you have I forgot what's in Python
undefined I think you know sometimes neo
sometimes no in other languages pooling
is also familiar string number they are
also familiar for media now symbol
Israel now object okay object now
everything in JavaScript now remember a
function what function in function
JavaScript is a value it's a function
expression it has a value it's a lambda
okay so function what is the type it's
object okay object so anything else if
it's not a number if it's not undefined
no type you know is not any of the
pooling or string number it's an object
so in practice object includes array
function state object regular expression
syntax object math object everything
else you know it's all goes by the name
object okay
now so this is
Gordon so object type object value type
the most important type of JavaScript
okay so so function function array date
hash table or object you know jason
jason regular expression they did they
are all technically they are they are in
technically they are not there is no
function type array type you know date
type there is no such thing like like
that technically they are all just one
type object that's important okay this
is critical now okay so that that's
about types okay that's that finishes
one the subject chapter now let me
mention they are also the concept of
primitive values primitive type so a
primitive type now don't worry about
primitive type basically undefined no
true/false any number or stream and
symbol they are called primitive types
so object is not primitive type so
that's just another jargon okay
primitive type and primitive values
refers to any of these any of these
these so accept object everything else
is a primitive type or primitive value
okay so anyway so object now let's let's
get on with object once you understand
types now let's get out well with object
now but before we do that there is
another important and critical thing
find the type of a value okay this is
this is this is critical this is
critical because there are many
JavaScript Watts that's why you have to
know about this thing we are going to
talk about the how do you find what what
are some of the exceptions about types
so let's go back to the types page value
types
these are the seven types right so okay
so I'm kind of hot hold on a sec second
let me read the comments
you
okay so moonshine says have you found
many use of symbols well I explained
symbols are mostly used as a unique ID
for properties okay so if you want to
know about symbols read this page you
know this is an introduction tutorial to
JavaScript symbols okay I explained in
detail but we we need to go on talking
about object today so anyway so these
are the seven types one two three four
five six seven types you know technical
types now there are some crooks that's
important to know the type of operator
now type you know that in order to find
something you know what type is a value
you use the type of up typeof operator
type of operator always returns the
string okay but however there are some
cooks because when you here is awesome
examples when you learned type of
operator many different values for
example type of undefined equals true
undefined the string type of a string
ABC equals through the string string you
know type of true equals to the string
puling and so on but however there are
some exceptions okay let me tell you
what are the exceptions now this is a
quote quote koch of javascript it's a
it's a it's a bug of javascript okay so
that's why you have these problems when
you when you say type of new you know
take you know according to the
javascript suspect you know no it
belongs to the category of type of new
new is the only value of that type so
when you say type normal it should you
know you you would think it returns a
string that says no but that's not a
case when you say type normal
it actually returns the string object
why because it's a bug in JavaScript
you know because JavaScript you know
someone has traced it to the book so if
you look at this page I explained it and
follow this link now this guy dr. Excel
Ramesh Mayo he is a expert in JavaScript
okay he has also written many JavaScript
tutorials online free you know you can
you can you know so so his book is the
one I would say it's a one I respect the
most of all the JavaScript books I know
I've surveyed including Microsoft's
JavaScript documentation including
Mozilla's Firefox JavaScript
documentation online including you know
many oh I've looked at them all his book
Java and JavaScript is the most detailed
and I I respect
you know I recommend of course I mean I
you know if you are reading if you are
watching me I would say you know use my
tutorial you know because I I have a
different you know style you know of
course but he's he's he's is very good
as well okay so I you know I like his
his JavaScript books here several anyway
so anyway he traced you know he the the
reason that type type of no returns
objects object is because in the C
program that implements JavaScript
there's a book you know basically the
program must you know got it something
wrong so that that is why there is no
logical good reason so so it's this is
one of the problem type of type of nor
returns object you should it should not
so whenever you try to you know when you
whenever you use type of to find some
value you want to make sure you also
want to check it with you know it's no
you know because this is a bug and it
just stuck with us
you know it's cannot be changed because
JavaScript people they don't want
because they want backward combated
compatibility so good morning Seema
good morning George do you know any
prototype or language besides JavaScript
the only one I know itself okay let's
focus let's go back to the object
JavaScript object so that's so yeah so
that's today's topic we need to focus on
explaining javascript object system in
depth so okay back to the type of type
of is operator that that determine that
lets you find out what type of a patio
that is now there are some exceptions
books one is no type of no we have
explained already the another exception
is type of a function when you have a
function and when when you say type of
it returns function keyword function
okay why because if you know it's just a
problem it's just a bug in JavaScript
you know like as we have seen before
there is no value type code function it
doesn't exist but however if you use
type of you know operator on a function
it returns the stream function it just
it just the way it is there's no you
know there's no good explanation so that
this these are the JavaScript quacks you
know what's that's you you need to know
when you do JavaScript so for example
let me show you okay so let's define a
function let's say function FF let's say
return X plus 1 okay now that's a
function that's that's okay and let's
console.log type of FF let's see why it
says you see it says function it says
the function you see returns true it it
it's of it returns the function string
okay so this is a JavaScript Koch okay
you just have to memorize it that is all
but however this is actually useful
often times you do want to know if a
function is a function because otherwise
function array anything else they are or
object you know but you but actually for
programmers you really want to know
whether is this is array or function you
know you don't want them both to be just
object even though mathematically that
that is what should be the case so
anyway so type of you use type of to
find out what the value of a type of a
value and remember there are two
exceptions
quacks one is type of new and one is
type of function okay so that's that's
about types that's done we are done with
about types in JavaScript
now let's now we can start to talk about
JavaScript objects the JavaScript object
system in depth okay so you look at this
section object overview okay
instead of a go you know instead of
reading it let me just show you off hand
you know image that way is better
because you can you know you can go back
to read them afterwards so so now let's
talk about objects in JavaScript
what is object in JavaScript so
javascript object is a collection is
okay is a collection of key-value pairs
okay is a base basically unordered so
actually several things let me write it
down so it's a collection of the key
value pairs and each object has a has
has a parent may have a parent
may point to another object called its
parent object also know as its prototype
object okay forget about the word
prototype because that that was kind of
confusing because because there is also
a property a building property named
prototype is so it's kind of confusing
you know just so just remember first of
all what is JavaScript object first of
all it's a type remember this is one of
the type in JavaScript okay but give a
small more description like what exactly
object you know do like a stream you
know string is a sequence of characters
a string is a type in JavaScript but
what is it okay it's a string basically
it's a sequence of characters a number
is a type in JavaScript but what is it
okay it number you know well it's a math
idea it's you have a sensor number right
so object is a type in JavaScript but
what exactly is it is okay now this is
what they are so a object first of all
it's a key value pairs it's a collection
of the key value pairs whenever that
happens you call it an object so every
object now remember this is important
doesn't matter what people say you know
like in other programming tutorials
you'll have oh you know you have oh you
know patterns factory pattern oh ppad
and those are kind of all fuzzy but what
i'm doing here is kind of giving you
kind of a mathematical definition style
of understanding javascript object so
first of all we understand the types you
know the types in javascript values now
so object no so any object when you see
anything that has key value pairs that's
that's object okay
in javascript so first of all javascript
object is a collection of key value
pairs and each object
may point make me may or may not okay it
may be associated with another object
and code and that one is called its
parent okay so one object may have a
parent and this object may have another
parent only one parent okay however not
it may not have any parent so an object
may not have any parent at all so that's
that's the thing so key value pairs an
object may have another another object
as its parent now we are going to
explain what's a mechanism like how does
JavaScript I mean how do you find out
what's a parent or how what's the
mechanism that links one object to
another as parent child you know that
we're going to talk about that later
let me let me type it out so we're gonna
show those how to find a object parent
now by the way objects parents I call it
parent because it's much easier to
understand but in in other books
typically they code prototype so you say
you say object may have a prototype okay
prototype is you know just it's just a
parent okay so so far two things
collection key value pairs and may have
a parent okay another thing okay another
thing a object may have special purpose
or associated with it some spatial data
okay what does I mean for example a
function in JavaScript is a object we
have shown that before right yeah
function you know function okay let me
okay let me finish this thought first so
a object may have a special purpose or
or and/or associated with some special
data for example for example function is
a object but it can also be called like
a function you know you know what
function is so function in JavaScript is
a object but however it's you know it's
also a function you know you can call it
that's what you do come you know that's
how you compute stuff
let's function so function is kind of a
special object so it has a special
purpose you know it has a and it has a
associated data with it because why
because you have a function body a
function body is not is not key value
pairs right but however because function
is also an object therefore it is also a
collection of key value pairs now this
may be counterintuitive but let me show
you okay let me show you and let me also
explain for example array remember array
in JavaScript is also an object because
remember we talked about JavaScript
types remember we talked about
JavaScript types there is no type code
array you know any value type is is
either one of these or object you know
there's no such thing as array type
there's no such thing as function type
so they are just object so array the
array object is a key value pairs but it
has kind of special properties
you know there's it has some special
things with it so that's that's the
thing about JavaScript object so that
that captures the javascript object okay
correct most most first of all it's
collection of key value pairs then each
object may have a parent okay so you
have a pet you it forms a tree you know
kind of a tree
of parents parent-child and you know
then a object may have a special purpose
so associated with some spatial data
sometimes it's internal you cannot see
it I'm going to show you examples later
but for example of a function the
function body
if you define your own function the
function body is a spatial data it's not
part of a key value pairs right so
anyway so let me show you function okay
so back here let's define a function
let's same thing as before let's say
just say return 3 and let's call it f f
it's called
Burnet it returns 3 ok it's a function
now as i as we mentioned before a
function is a object but because every
object is a collection of key-value
pairs therefore a function is also key
value pairs for example we can start it
we can begin to add properties to it for
example a a equals to 4 let's say and
let's say B B equals to 5 ok bring it it
runs fine and let's print FF you see so
here is the printout is first of all it
says function you know with a square
bracket it means its can some kind of a
special object then it says a a is 4p b
is 5
these are its properties so you see a
function is actually just just like
every object it has key value pairs i
mean in in a case of function you can
add key key value pairs if you want to
you if you don't want to you don't have
to you know by default it doesn't have
so does that make sense everyone so the
so far so good
especially your - does that make sense
so I give me give me some feedback edge
ok so if it's good say good ok type like
good you know
get some you know so it's good for me I
get I keep going
so Jordan George says good morning
George press alt f4 that's closing
windows what do you mean okay it's hot
here okay good so let's keep going so
let's continue with this so function oh
yeah we so did here is this example
where we add stuff now let me show you
another example array okay
for example array constant arrow
function so constant let's say a equals
through array now I assume you guys
already know the basics right so I don't
have to explain the array and functions
of course so here we have array and we
we console.log type of áááá okay let's
see what says it says object correct
because arrays object now if you truly
want to find out if if this is a true
array value you can use is array okay I
think okay so I okay so hold on a second
arrays array okay yeah that so that's a
function a a so this function arrays
array that will return true if if the
value is actually a true away-away not
just a object okay so if we run that it
says true you know that that's how you
find evil array so true array now
there's another what you know talked
about javascript is that you could have
a array like object let's not go there
but anyway this function array is array
it returns true if something is true
array okay so that's an example oh wait
hold on so B now remember
array array is just
object meaning that its key value pairs
so in fact in JavaScript array those
indexes of array are actually keys of
the object and the array values are
actually just just values to the key for
example let me show you let me show you
for example let's print all the
properties of a object so how do you do
that let's go here close that let's go
here
let's go to properties section
JavaScript object properties and let's
see list properties so this page shows
you all possible ways to get a list of a
objects property okay all of them all
the possible ways so one of the ways we
want to use include string key include
in memory
reflect on keys let's use reflect on
keys okay
reflect on keys okay that's a function
and let's put a a here and let's say
console.log console.log put it here
print it run it so you see when this
prints all the properties or all the
keys of a of a object so we give the
object a a which is some array and it
prints this you know 0 1 2 links those
are the property the keys you know the
properties of the of this array object
and so you can see here you see those 0
1 and length they are actually you know
they are array indexes and length is a
special property of array it's building
it's a magical property you know it
shows how many elements in the array
it's magical because whenever you change
the array length the length the value of
the key length also changes
automatically so
in that way it's magical so anyway so
you see here that these are the keys of
the way so this is a demonstration
showing that a race actually just just a
object you know is actually just key
value pairs it so happens that in
JavaScript you you know you think of it
as a array but in some technical sense
it's not just array it's actually key
value pairs so this array is actually
for example it's actually like this okay
three four five it's actually like like
this
so you get what I'm saying so already
you know although it the syntax already
looks like that but it's actually a
object is it's more like that you know
it's a object key here's a key he's a
value key value key value and key value
this value is some kind of it's so cold
anyway so just a magical method okay yes
it's kind of syntax sugar but it's not
exactly a syntax sugar because you know
rather let's just say JavaScript is you
know designed and implemented in ten
days so it's got lots of weird problems
so it's not exactly a syntactic sugar
rather it's just it's just the way it is
it's a it's rather it's it's a bad
design it's you know you have a lot bad
designs in JavaScript so anyway so yeah
but you can you can think of it as a
syntax sugar you know yeah so they are
so there's there are many details about
it but I'm skipping it because for
example if you want to understand
JavaScript array then you can go you
know after you understand object and
inheritance then it is a section on
array you know then you started to see
all the you know detail problems and
details but you understand it then you
start to understand it in depth okay so
I'm skipping many of the more many of
the little details so let me read the
comments oh I see so yeah so greetings
to or presence schizoid what
pareo salute okay so we covered function
and we covered array as objects why are
we talking about function in a way
because
we I'm trying to emphasize the idea
about the types of value in JavaScript
as we see you know array is one of the
important type there is no such thing as
a rare type or function type but however
the array in JavaScript and function in
JavaScript they are actually technically
they are supposed to be the object type
and I'm trying to show you what makes a
object you know it's a collection you
know it's a collection of key value
pairs and I you know and each object may
have a parent okay
and some object usually object has some
kind of special purpose of property that
is why I am demonstrating a function in
array I'm trying to show function in a
way they are just object but however you
see I showed that I showed that they are
you know key value pairs I also showed
okay they have parents I haven't showed
that yet I'll show that later okay they
have parents but I also showed that the
in a case of array and function in
JavaScript they can't they are like
object but however they they do have a
special purpose and some kind of magical
internal data such as the length poverty
in the in the in a way you know so
anyway so that's that's almost all about
object now this is about object so now
let's go back to the object let's see I
I there's another thing I should mention
so here's a summary about of JavaScript
object one object is a collection
collection of key value pairs each key
value pair is called property right to
most object have special purpose and
internal data for example function
object is a function array object has a
magical length property regular
expression object
is used to match stream pattern data
objects holds daytime data you know yeah
and the one object that does not have
any special purpose is the data object
key value so so this is the most you
know when people say JavaScript object
they are thinking of these this is the
most common object they don't have they
don't actually have a standard name but
I think the JavaScript suspect refer to
them or sometimes call them data object
you know they don't JavaScript is so bad
a language you know all the terminology
is very confusing it's not well-defined
but anyway when we talk about object
most people think of these you know you
just use curly bracket and you know then
inside it key value pairs that's that's
that's what you use you know that's
represent data data object that's that's
the most common object and this value of
course is the is of type object so okay
most object has special purpose then
three each object has zero or one parent
object code its prototype okay and when
a properties exist JavaScript will go up
the parent object or parent of parent
object to look for the property this is
called inheritance okay
now this is important because this is
the whole this is the whole purpose of
having a parent now let me let me try to
explain this one so object has a parent
usually have a parent okay now the
question is what's the parent for why do
you need a parent I mean okay what why
do you need it
the purpose the sole the only purpose
nothing else okay
the only purpose a object having a
parent is that when javascript looks of
a objects property value it will try to
find the property in the object however
if the object does not have that
property
remember object is a key value pair so
if if the object does not have that key
then JavaScript will try to find the key
in the parent object okay you'll try to
find it if it if it exists then you'll
show that value if it it does not exist
then we it will try to find that
object's parents object to find if the
key exists in that object and so on
until you reach the root parent there's
no more parent you know then if none of
those parent object has the key then it
returns undefined meaning that okay the
object does not have that key now this
is critical this chain this kind of
looking at parents looking for the key
in a parent and in a parent parent this
is called inheritance okay this is the
only meaning of inheritance and this
applies only when you are looking up a
value of a property key not when you are
writing a value or creating a property
key it happens only when you you know
try to find find a value of a key so
does that make sense so if if so say say
yes okay let me let me gonna let me show
you an example so so that's the concept
of inheritance we just actually cover
that that's critically important that's
that's the only purpose of having a
parent so let me repeat this again then
then I'm gonna show an example the only
purpose of object having parent is that
when JavaScript when you type for
example let's let's define let's create
a object okay constant xx okay let's say
object okay let's say K 1 is 1 okay
let's say K 2 is 2
okay let's say object console.log X X
let's say OB
J okay obj okay so console.log join it
you see it returns the object with two
keys so we can we can also now we can
now print all the piece of the object so
we have used reflect on properties
reflect on keys okay so we are going to
print all the keys of this object so
reflect on keys obj let's see okay
it returns array you got two keys k1 and
k2 those are the keys of the object
remember object is key value pairs
that's one of the most important
definition of object and this object is
the most most common object you know we
call a data object user created data
object okay so we have showed the object
and we have showed the keys now let's do
good morning Tony now let's do okay so
so this out so okay so let's do this
okay cut paste make make it let's create
a new one let's do another thing
okay now let's console.log object k1
okay now we want what we do is is that
we are trying to look up the value for K
1 now this is the dot notation for
accessing property keys so the object is
our obj let's rename it xx ok so the
object is xx the property key we want is
k1 and let's see what's the value so it
says what good that's correct
what if we say key k3 that doesn't exist
right let's run it so it returns
undefined now remember and define is one
of the value it
type okay so it returns undefined okay
now now let us create a object whose
parent is X X okay so like now let's
create two object one is parent one is
child
now the parent will have key k3 the
child does not okay so let's do that
okay so let's do that so x1 let's name
it x1 and x2 so x1 okay
x1 is a object of one key k3 and it has
a value of 3 okay now x2 is a object it
has two keys k1 and k2 okay now we want
to make K we want to mix X we want to
make x1 to be the parent of x2 so how do
you do that go to JavaScript in-depth
object an inheritance section get set
parent now this page shows you all
possible ways to to find a objects
parents or set a objects parents okay so
so here is a function we can use to set
a object as parents so we're going to
call that reflect set prototype of so so
the first argument is the object we want
to set and the second argument is the
parents okay we just run that okay now
let's run it okay
once we make the parents well once we
set the parent of X to to be x1 then now
we access the key K 3 K 3 in x2 now
remember x2 does not have the key K 3
right because you see it's not there but
however its parent has it
so let's try to access you know K 3 X 2
dot k 3 let's see what happens let's run
it it returns 3 you see why because you
know it actually look up you know it
goes up the parent and found it for us
good morning test ok so that's that's
about this is about inheritance ihe I
ent inheritance
ok TA and C ok when JavaScript look of a
property value it tries to go up the
parent chain okay that that is what
happens so close that make create our
notes here so this is what we've just
done okay so great thank you attached so
let's continue answered so this is about
inheritance now remember this is oh
there it is about the word inheritance
that's all it means
when JavaScript when you try to access a
when you try to find the value of a key
of some object javascript will try to
find it in the parents now that is the
only meaning of inheritance don't be
confused by any other talk you know like
when like also JavaScript Oh P is
entirely entirely different from the why
in Java in Python so don't be confused
ok if you came from Python or Java they
are 100% completely totally different no
similarity whatsoever
okay in Java you have class in Python
you have class you know Java Python you
have class then you have object okay
javascript is entirely different
in in Python or Java you create a class
okay then you instant instantiate you
know then you create the object out of
some class in JavaScript there's no such
thing this doesn't exist it is 100%
entirely different okay remember that
and in fact we have we have already
completely explained what what object is
in JavaScript you see remember it's key
value pair remember it may have a parent
remember that Y maybe hey've you know
you know may have internal data or
special purpose that's all there it is
about JavaScript object it is not so so
as an example is it is not a some
instantiation from some class it's not
nothing like that
we already 100 percent math Mac
mathematically defined and explained
what javascript object is okay you know
we already covered so so we so let me
repeat the summary here one two three we
covered now the number for each object
has a special info attached code is
extensible internal slot it specifies
whether new properties can be added to
the object okay this is not this is less
info important now remember javascript
object is key value pairs right
correction of key value pairs now you
can prevent you can make an object so
that it is it will not be possible to
add more keys to it you know you can do
that and that is in in the the way the
mechanism for that to work is because
each object has a special info code is
extensible I mean there are functions
you can you you can call some functions
so that you can no longer add properties
to object so anyway that that's that's
not as important as the other three we
talked about and yeah basically we
already talked about the most important
thing that the top three the the other
thing I'm mentioning here is you know
it's useful to distinguish objects by
their or engine for example standard
object hosted object user-defined object
you know we have seen user-defined
object like when we create a function
when we create a array when we create
you know I you know this this data
object let's use a defined object but
standard object came from JavaScript
language itself such as such as this
function this reflect that's that's you
know B or D in JavaScript that's also
object and this set prototype of that's
one of its property you know one of its
key member remember javascript is about
a collection of key value pairs so if
you say reflect its object it must have
key value pairs indeed set prototype of
is one one of its key and the value of
this key is actually a function so
that's why this thing this thing is a
function we can call it and use it you
know so anyway so anyway daddy that is
about object the three most important
thing you know key value pairs may have
a parent and may have special purpose or
internal data that that is all about
javascript object in a technical sense
okay I think we let's take a break let's
see how long I've been talking Oh
nineteen minutes that's almost a good
stop they are they are quite a few
allowed practical things like I haven't
showed much code for example let me let
me go over some of the topics for
example so now you understand your
javascript object in a mathematical
sense now now there are different object
types now remember we talked about value
types
and all these are objects functions
array date regular expression jason math
they are all objects so this page i
discussed you know how do you find out
like which type of object are they now
in practice in real life this is
important because you want to know a
function is you know you want to know
something is a function or array or date
you know you don't want all of them to
be just object you know even though
technically that's what javascript types
ah
you know they are just or just type
object but but in practice in daily
coding you want to be able to find out
so here are some techniques you can you
know I show you some techniques about
that object type find objects type okay
here you know and about the prototype
chain we actually just explained you
know the parent why why you need a
parent things like that prototype chain
what's the purpose of parent and as we
know the the the entire sole purpose is
about when you look up a keys value it
goes up at the parent and the whole
thing is called inheritance okay then we
have okay some practical things this
page is all possible ways to create a
object you can do by literal expression
you can use the function object create
you can use the keyword new you know
those are different ways to create
object the end result is the same you
know you just create a new object okay
but you have different ways an object
literal expression here you know when we
do that that's that's that syntax is
called object literal expression it's
the most common way to create a object
okay and then you have how do you create
an object with a particular parent
you know I show you how here for example
you can use object.create or you can use
new something you know it's more complex
but I show here or you can use a new
keyword called class now in JavaScript
2015 you have a new keyword called class
now don't be confused with this class
you know with the Java or Python scrat's
like I said before they are entirely
different things but people try to make
them similar but don't think don't don't
think of it that way because that way
you got more confused confusion but
anyway this page explains how do you
create object with a parent with a
specific parent but you can also you can
also just create an object first then
set a parent you know so this page shows
you all the ways and also how do you
find out a parent of some object you
know and show prototype chain or show
parent chain prevent adding property
chrome object test object equality those
are some of the technical some other
practical details you can read but the
main thing the the you know the the
mathematical like under you know the
mathematical structure we already
covered that is what is object you know
key value pairs parents and so so on and
I hope you know this I hope that gives
you a different and deep understanding
of JavaScript that's that's my hope so
attach says so if you modify a children
of a parent value if you modify in a
children a parent value you actually are
modifying the value in a parent know
depending on what you mean so all the
children of their parent will get the
same change well
you see if you modifying a chore in a
child of a parent value I'm not sure
what you mean though attached so for
example let me show show you an example
I don't know if that's what you mean
good morning good morning wet dog
so so attached so we have this example
right X 1 is K 3 I mean X X 1 is a
object it has one key K 3 X 2 is another
object it has two keys k1 and k2 ok then
we make X 1 to be the parent of X 2 then
we showed the property k3 in X 2 you
know K X 2 doesn't have K 3 so it came
from X 1 so the result is 3 ok now if
you modify X 1 K 3 now remember we are
modifying the parent X 1 K 3 equals to 4
okay then you do this then you do the
console.log again X 2 dot K 3 he will
say 4 so is that what you mean you know
B so what we demonstrated here is that
we change the parents key we change the
parents value of a key we changed one of
the parents keys value but we are trying
to get a key from X 2 now X 2 does not
have G 3 so key 3 came from the parent
so you know that that's how it works so
I don't know if that answer your
question
now remember this this looking up the
the keys from the parent only happens
when you are trying to look up the keys
value it does not happen when you try to
assign now this is important
okay so for example if you say for
example if you say X 2 dot K 3 equals to
5 okay what will happen is that
JavaScript will you know right so when
you do this JavaScript will check if K 3
is in x2 now it's not so it will just
create a new kiiiing x2 okay let's try
it
so we run it it runs okay now now let's
let's do this again
k 2 dot X X 2 dot K 3 okay let's run it
you see the result is 5 now because you
know because and also you can show the
properties let's see
reflect key reflect on keys that show
all the keys label object let's say X 2
okay okay o console.log okay console.log
that you see now the X 2 object has
three keys k1 k2 k3 it no longer use the
parents k3 value because it has k3
itself okay that's I think that's it for
today and so we got a TRO here that's
good okay so I think that's it for today
so we're gonna shut down in two minutes
also thank you thank you for coming by
to my show any questions guys we've dog
house going now I think Webb dog is a
expert in JavaScript Oh a web dog knows
a lot I want to hear your opinion on the
simulation argument oh that's a
philosophy
I think today is too late for that
because it's you know it's 100 minutes
hold on a second I'm pretty hot any fan
a little bit Oh
so wave dog says wave dog says hold on
so so let me put this here
and
[Music]
you
so about the simulation question that's
that's kind of philosophy and pretty
involved but let's not do it today
because I'm kind of tired and so yeah
let's talk about that you know maybe
tomorrow next time you come by wave dog
so post that and let's talk about that
that's you know that's interesting yeah
I'm yeah let's talk about that
so Tony says thanks for shoka saw your
website has helped me great thank you
and with Emacs thank you Tony
yep see you guys thanks bye