hmm good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of saw talk show today
is for the record of humanity today's
April trough 2020 the day of the bad
death
am i alive check
so guys say something so let me begin by
I guess I'm alive so let me begin by
starting the mod and here we have Emery
colors in this window you will see all
my Emacs commands for your use
so what were you going to talk about
today we're gonna talk about tons of
topics we have we haven't been talking
about we haven't been doing stuff like
talk show for two or three months so
today I have several topics prepared
this is gonna be a long one a long one
so mostly I'm gonna tell you about my
website updates what I have been doing
to my websites and we're gonna talk
about the bat death the bat death that's
the pandemic pandemic as they say
thousands of dead dead
okay so let me check so do you guys have
questions the bad death yeah the day of
the bad days and Emily and we're gonna
show I'm gonna tell you guys about
Emily's novel keyboard layout she's got
she you know Amanda discord sorry
discord if you haven't been already
joined sorry discord this is my Saudi
fan club so to speak and and you go
there and you meet all sort of people
all different opinions great diversity
and we have Alan Captain Alan the artist
the in-house artist and I'm gonna show
you some of his drawings and he is also
doing 3d modeling and stuff so Emily
Scott she's got this she's the most
technical person in our group and she
has done lots of things we have done
talk shows about her stuff and she has a
new keyboard layout design now there are
turns of keyboard layouts you know out
there you know these geeks and nerds
they all want to design the ultimate
layout but oh they are all the same all
the [ __ ] same they claim to be better
than Warrick so you have Commack then
you have walkman then you have normal
layout then you have a bunch of others
so you go to you know just go such Saudi
keyboard layout and you'll see a bunch
of them and the pros and cons of them
one of the earliest of course you have
corty then you have Warrick layout then
you have one of the earliest other than
that is the more Tron layout
which is quite different they then quote
he and vorak but then you have you know
Commack and Norman and workman and a
bunch of others like tons of these nerds
this ineffectual nerds they just they
are obsessed about the ultimate layout
but however they are the same way
there's no novelty no no no creativity
these these idiots these Linux fanatics
you know these nerds no creativity but
this one by emily has creativity it's
different from the others so let me
start talking about her layout ok let me
show you so you got you join discord the
discord invitation link is just such 4
sorry discord okay my name is Adi and
you'll find it now I'm and let me show
you okay so why why is a keyboard layout
novel different how is it different let
me tell you so she is the most technical
person here and she has God why is he so
slow
she has okay wait hold on a second let
me check am I like doing okay Oh long
live Thank You Allen for the super chat
this go goes things super chat that
makes me money and makes Google money so
let me pop this out or actually let's
not pop this out so Thank You Allen for
that so Allen you got a spot for
question of the century and I'm gonna
answer that okay
and and and okay so let me see what else
is going on lots of things I cannot read
you know you get old my eyes cannot be
so I have to read slowly and magnify but
let me show you let me get back to
Emily's layout look look there so she
has you know she's she's also a
programmer she has written you know
she's doing Earl and these days you know
the function of her me language Earl and
with massive parallel parallelism and
practical too
unlike for example the closure closure
[ __ ] in Haskell [ __ ] Olin is used since
like 20 years ago in telecom
communication you know in Ericsson or
something you know for massive parallel
computation and they have novel ideas
Olin I never learned it myself but
anyway
Emily is coding Olin house so she has
this she has a program that's returning
Olin that that confused
I think it's generate generic algorithm
or is it not Emily
so Emily you have to Emily you have to
answer questions online so what is the
methodology you use in your program so
anyway her program she wrote this
program to find out what is the most
efficient keyboard layout now a lot of
people have has written these these sort
of programs there's quite a few
but Emma that you know Emily's is a bit
different from theirs because there's
the you know there are people returning
pearl you see evolutionary algorithms
doing that so anyway the goal is to find
the optimal arrangement of the keys but
hers is different in that you see
normally when you have a keyboard you
have home road right you you assume that
your home rose as your home row fingers
you know focus on the left
asdf asdf for Cody and and JKL semicolon
the idiotic Corti layout that's Alan's
favorite favorite favorite
it's QWERTY theory sophistries okay so
anyway so you have home rose that's a
concept because these home row keys are
the most you know your your finger sits
there
wait let me check if I'm still talking
good okay I am so anyway so so back to
Emily's layout so that's a home row but
however her Emily is layout she does not
use the concept of normal home row keys
if you look at this image let's see if
you can see it you can see it right you
guys can see it right so if you look at
this image it's let's magnify let's see
a glorious version
well that's not too glorious okay so
anyway so if you look at Emily's
keyboard layout you see that her home
row is not the normal role rather it's
like how shall I explain her diagram is
confusing nevertheless yeah yeah I want
to come faint Emily her diagram is
confusing you look at the color it
doesn't mean anything
what's this blob of yellow and green
doesn't make sense okay but anyway her
brought home row is like two keys two
keys here on top row and two keys here
on second row something like that took
he's here on the third row and and two
keys on the bottom row so the thump the
thump are actually on the home row so
it's kind of so you know you look at
these three fingers you know the ego
claw so that's kind of her home so it's
not it's not just row it's like that so
so she write a program to optimize the
layout you know with that particular
home row so this is you know this is
quite novel this is different I have
seen opinions who you know this I don't
believe it you know they are people who
says that the home row should not be you
know on a row because they say you know
when they dressed their fingers on the
keyboard on a normal PC keyboard the
middle finger is typically resting on
the top row not not a meter so some
people say therefore anyway that yeah
they have some people say that but
typically they are not this idea is not
detailed out but Emily however you know
when in deep depth and you know she is
creating these layout so she's her
program is still working still creating
the most efficient layout for her but
that's not something I would do you know
I want to make a complaint you know this
but you see this like you know it's it's
it's a good idea you know it's a great
alternative layout idea okay so let me
so so if you have questions to me put my
name it so I can see okay so let's see
what Emily say so Emily says saw each
color represents the keys that each
finger presses Oh
oh okay okay okay so the thumb
I think the thumb is overused you know
you're gonna wreck your thumb and oh my
god look at the middle fingers middle
finger is underused
only two keys and the index finger is
four keys yeah the thumb I think the
thumb B is overused so yeah so Alan says
you need to recognize people of color
like myself I recognize myself how do I
follow this code you just go through my
website
sorry that info there's a link just such
just such folks sorry dis code you'll
find a link and click and you follow so
anyway so emily has so this is great
idea and she created but however you
know the I don't think it's practical
because if you are really concerned
about efficiency of fingering or layout
first of all what you should do is you
should teach
the PC keyboards you know throw them
away this is crap garbage so let me show
you the keyboard you know Emily loves
them Emily her favorite keyboard is the
happy hacking keyboard every nerds
favorite keyboard the happy hacking
keyboard you know so we have this
typical PC at the MPC formation the
layout form factor so this is a typical
you know keyboard design and that's not
good it came from typewriters and it is
not it's not economic okay so if you are
truly if you went to this degree of
concern about ergonomics and efficiency
I think you know first of all the the
the first thing you should do is throw
these keys you know this PC idiotic
keyboard away you you want you want
things like these Kinesis okay let me
show you now I have to show off my keys
so how long have I been talking a oh
clock and 4750 15 minutes okay so I've
been talking out of 18 minutes so turn
on the light let there be light and
there is like god I'm so powerful
something like that yeah
anyway lousy camera so so this you see
this Kinesis layout you go to my website
and buy it right away
let's see if I can make it big
woofs it doesn't work I have to adjust
it now and it's not do it so anyway so
you this Kinesis of hay
now Kinesis and you want that turn that
off and you gotta I gotta turn off that
light
okay so so I was saying you know the PC
keyboards are no good you want you want
things like this you know that actually
redesign the keyboard you know such as
this and that in that in that one in
this one in that one in oka docks okay
and and you know truly ergonomic Creve
keyboard this is coming out and they
have novel key switch designs optical
key switch and an analog key switch and
mantra so anyway so you have so that's
what I'm saying so if you so the PC
keyboard is no good I mean so that is my
opinion it does not you know that that
is assuming you really want to push
efficiency to the utmost degree I think
you should throw away this PC keyboard
layout but you know but you know sheshe
that's not each person has different
cause I guess that's not her cause she
said she just won this for herself
okay that's about Emily's keyboard
layout oh my god we spent 15-20 minutes
talking about that let's go to the next
topic shall we let's see let me check
the comments anything else
and what's wrong with typewriters yeah
they're soo de su what do you think
about coded keyboards code Ichiro is
great but not what do you think okay
coded keyboard okay we talked about
these a few times
coded keyboard let me show you the coded
keyboards okay so the one of the best
coded key bow is the steno type machine
that's this thing you press multiple
keys at the same time now this is a true
true coded keyboard meaning that the
order of which the keys you press
suppose you press two keys at the four
keys at the same time okay you press
that now a true color keyboard you have
to you know it does not matter which key
you hit first as long as they are all
hit you know that's one code this is
different from the chords on the idiotic
PC keyboard
you know like ctrl alt shift then key
then you release T then you release that
you know modifier that's idiotic
extreme idea idiocy of the shift
mechanism of the from the mechanical
typewriters that's the way they are
because it's from my mechanical
typewriters you have the key named shift
key why is it named shift key because it
shift the gears so you hope you press
and hold the shift key they shift the
mechanisms underneath the hammers and
elaborate things and then then they
strike different letters that's why it's
shift then they become then when the
computer keyboard came they started to
invent to emulate the shift key that's
what happens habit you know habit don't
doesn't go away habit is the killer of
innovation habit will go away when you
die and your children will not follow
your steps they we hope innovate so so
innovation in general goes by
generations
except the millennial generation the
most idiotic with regressive generation
that's the Millennials
[Laughter]
okay coded keyboard so so this is a true
quarry keyboard now there are many
people you know this this this ten old I
mean let me tell you about it okay I'm
gonna rant non-stop this this idiot
stand with PC keyboard is this this this
what's the name
well what's the name clover clover the
idiotic prover nuts
this is this unthinking people there you
know there are many keyboard enthusiast
sticks you know Kibo phonetic same day
they buy they buy this PC keyboard this
you know they buy this one code what's
that what's that one codes you know the
the one typically used with stay no I am
I'm not going to go into it it's on my
website you go to my website so anyway
okay let me get focused okay so code
keyboard is great and another code
keyboard is the piano key the piano is a
true coded keyboard okay and there is
this girl not her but there's this girl
who did research for her PhD or maths
master's degree who created the piano
text system that allows you to use a
piano keyboard to type text and you
actually have a system you know the end
it's pretty efficient okay so these are
examples of coded keyboard okay and and
also this one but this one is idiotic
okay so let me show you some other so
this one is also fantastic mission our
coded key whoa fantastic coded keyboard
okay
you want to talk about coding coded
keyboard this these are coded true real
chorded keyboards not the control ode
meta super [ __ ] factory Linux [ __ ]
and Emacs idiots these are so what's the
difference what's why are they different
first of all you see a PC keyboard you
know that control meta odd you have to
the order matters you have to hold the
mid modifier then press the keys name
released and release the modifier that's
not good
that's that's not that's not like piano
or saying okay that's entirely different
thing it's it's not the same thing okay
these these idiots the keyboard nerds
idiots
let me show you what what's the other
one okay that that that probe over and
this thing the bank
is this the most idiotic keyboard on
earth is and you have turns of phonetics
loving this plank keyboard turns at one
one one one thousands of them and when
one jjigae bites of people loving this
plank idiocy and they say oh I'm gonna
use this for over oh it's there no
snelfus stand on my ass these people
don't know what they they don't have a
brain so you want you want a real Cody
keyboard okay so stand on stand on
machine this could efficient yes much
faster than what you can do on a PC
keyboard piano system okay piano text
and others that's good okay oh this
mixture coded keyboard then you have
some abominations such as they let me
show you okay this bad keyboard and this
[ __ ] pad and this data hand and this Gog
and this skinny okay I'm not going to
flame Choji and Guinea because this guy
is very nice he sent me one let me show
you but I because the core because of
the coronavirus The Cove igniting bad
death crisis so I haven't had time to
look into
you see so there it is this is my GOG
keyboard two of them you see so I
haven't had time to program them you
need to program them you need to program
them via this open source
qmk software which is very complex
you're gonna spend I have to spend hours
to read about how do I do this
programming I want to I wanted to become
a programmable keypad to type key
markers many ways so back to the code it
keyboard so you have these these kind of
abominations why so why are they no good
where are they no good let me tell you
okay why okay now you look look at these
okay so so let me show you several so
you have this pad pad coding keyboard
okay this is pretty old 1986 then you
have a [ __ ] pad this came out in around
1919 year 2000 or something I have have
the date here somewhere 2008 okay so the
Frog pad came out in 2008 this is a
coded keyboard pretty small and then you
have data hand now this is an entirely
different one okay but anyway you have
the data and then you have Georgie okay
so these are suppose the coding
keyboards well not really
okay they are not they are not coding is
[ __ ] and they're they are not coding
well they are coding but what so why why
look at these video coding keyboards you
see each of these key is three four
times bigger than a normal PC keyboard
keys why because that's how it suits
your hands that's how that's the way
your hands are that's how they are
invented coding you know
and and the same for piano same for the
missional codis system-- okay it's
different it matters okay it matters for
example a car okay so you have a car
right you have tires now you don't
change your car into the bicycle
bicycles Tire bicycles for your sorrows
or tires you don't you don't use that
because this doesn't work okay it's
different yeah they are all tires they
are we always different
same thing with you know keyboards you
don't use you know you don't emulate a
coding machine by some you know idiotic
keyboard keys but anyway so for example
you know some of them you cannot blame
it because we are doing ritual analysis
you know this history so this pad coding
keyboard when it began when this began
at 1986 there's not you know it's
reasonable that you know they have the
idea of coding and they have these
little keys but this this one you know
the [ __ ] pad you could say it's
reasonable because the you know the goal
of it is so that you have this tiny
thing you that allows you to type you
know it you know that's the reason of
the existence but in general so so what
my point is that if you are starting to
get into keyboards ok and you want to
get deep into details you don't want to
say oh look now look look at that prank
you know this no more PC keyboard or
look I can make this into a coded
keyboard oh now it's fantastic you know
it's not ok and in fact if you use this
you know the plank keyboard for steno
you're gonna you're gonna have is I
you're gonna have RSI you have you're
gonna have hand pain faster than they
otherwise okay that's
that concludes my rant about coding
keyboards okay how long have I been
talking now I haven't done I have quite
a lot other topics but I guess we had to
have not so I talked for for 30 minutes
so let me look at the comments
so what else guys
[ __ ] am I still alive
what about data hand okay let's talk
about data hand hi guys so today our
hand I don't have it it's a novel design
it's a good you know it's a novel
designs a new design new novel design is
good in that they explore possibilities
and the the way you use this is that you
and by the way okay there's a
do-it-yourself version look at this
thing there's a do-it-yourself version
okay now the way this works is that you
let me show you okay you see you see
this data you see those horse is it is
for horse you dip your fingers into
those horse okay and then you you nudge
you move your fingers up and down to
press the walls of the hole and or left
right so that's how you do it you use
this you know combinatorial combinations
to type and of course you have to learn
it you have to you know your your your
your pointing finger like you have to
push up your middle finger maybe you
have to push left and your ring finger
have to push right so it's like up left
right it's like you know it's gonna [ __ ]
up your hands that's that's what it's
that it does that is my opinion that is
my analysis of this data hand I don't I
don't I don't think I like it and I
don't think you know it's you know if I
actually have this and I learn it it
might change my mind but I don't think
so you know just by my you know just why
I feel I don't think this is a good
design
maybe I'm wrong but yeah so okay so I
know but what your thoughts okay that's
my thoughts so Emily says oh my god I
don't to get a dinner hand yeah Emily
does I know she's never been able to
find one very expensive when they are
when when they were on sale it's like
$4,000 $4,000 I think okay Papa moon now
papa moon you are lunar oh yes right are
you right if I remember correctly okay
so maybe that's it for today how long
have been talking let's see how long so
okay
it stunk for twenty more minutes
let's see what comments you guys have
and maybe I can answer them comments
okay type comments now my computer is
kind of slow stop that
okay comments and questions
okay so let me check the comments a bit
then let's move on to the next topic
maybe we talk about coronavirus you know
the bad death that's so serious you know
actually so so every time I started to
do a live stream I have so many things
and to talk about and we end up for each
topic it ends up like 20 minutes so we
didn't even cover much
okay so originally let's see today's
talk show so we didn't even do Emacs
yeah
so we're gonna have okay let me start to
cover what I want to say you know so I
have a new Emacs tutorial guys you know
you know past four months I haven't been
doing a video for like three months
because I had a family crisis my mom
died in January okay my mom dad died and
in this problem okay so that I had I had
tremendous stress but then the
coronavirus
you know the kovat 19 the bad death the
Wu Han virus happened you know and
that's another you know a big problem so
so that's why I haven't been doing
videos live streams for three months now
but about a month ago I started to work
on my website again so let me show you
what I have done so yeah let me just so
you go to my Emacs tutorial you know
just search for Saudi Emacs if you are
watching me you probably know about my
websites so I don't need to tell you the
links so over over you can find it for
my youtube you know you find one link
and that we link to all the others so my
Emacs tutorial now they have a
streamlined navigation bar on the left
you can see so you go to the home page
sorry max website you can start on any
one of these Emacs tutorial and or Emacs
in it tutorials all about in it you need
fire what they are what's made you mad
what is the concept of minor mod and
what is the customize command the the
graphical user interface customize
command that how to use that how do you
organize in it files how do you bite
compiled in it files and what does it
mean
what's a hook things like that so so you
have Emacs tutorial that teaches you
everything you need to know about Emacs
fantastic you know
endless scrolling on my image tutorial
they are a total about I think 400 or
500 pages so it's actually more
extensive than any Emacs books on earth
okay any of them historically or even
online it doesn't matter it's printed on
paper or like my Emacs your tutorial is
the most comprehensive tutorial out
there except the GNU Emacs manual and
the GNU Emacs list
manual the manuals are of course the
official but the manuals are hard to
read and incomprehensible anyway so so
you have Emacs tutorial section Emacs in
its section Emacs Keys section in Emacs
everything is about keys okay so Emacs
keys everything you need to know
keyboard how do you define keys what's
how do you what's the syntax of Emacs
keys how do you change keys in major mod
how do you change keys in minor mode and
so on and so many of them super what's
super what's hyper how do you define
them how do you define key sequences how
do you define the Menu key you know
there's this Menu key in this Menu key
by the way is invented by Microsoft in
1993 from the Microsoft natural economic
keyboard the Menu key okay so you have
the key max keys section you have eMac
list section this is a great and
fantastic introduction to eMac this
essentially my eMac this tutorial is the
only one out there basically the only
one that is you know comprehensive then
you have eMac base examples you know you
have tons of eMac B's code examples for
example let me show you
upper cut upper case sentences this this
does quite a lot of things title case
you know many then you have a section on
how to write a major mod so you can you
read this and in ten minutes you will
have your own eMac based major mod for
your own purposes so if you like it pi
it okay put money in my pocket
that would be good okay so that is my
Emacs tutorial so the navigation bar on
the left now it's like easy to the
structure is easily is more intuitive
the structure the navigation panels and
in the same way I've done for my
JavaScript in-depth tutorial so you have
so you have JavaScript in-depth so you
can see one page down to page down three
four five you know so many things on the
Left you know so that's JavaScript
in-depth and even if you are a
JavaScript beginner you can learn from
this section JavaScript basics
okay so basics operators true and false
and so on then you have JavaScript
object reference section okay so this is
a pretty much complete JavaScript
reference better than better than the
Mozilla empty end okay in many ways it's
better but actually I cannot compete
with them because they you know they
there are so many resources
okay so yes so you have the reference
section in tome section so and anyway so
I did this new navigation panel so it's
all awning or they are like 2,200 maybe
a hundred to two hundred pages and also
you know then I have HTML tutorials then
I have CSS tutorials so anyway if you
like them buy it okay
buy it link links right there so let me
go back to so let me see if I am going
what else to talk about math cube so
what do you think is very tech
Tech or ex-spouse expose that question
okay so let me answer that question so
okay I fail to sorry for the small smell
guys I thought it Stella have you ever
have you ever have you ever used your
Georgie steno for all keyboard no I
haven't I haven't had time to to look
into that yet
brought to you by we're wolf video
gaming hikes ah hi guys hi I thought no
I uses the Menu key
oh the Menu key you should read about
the Menu key on my website I have cried
have at least two pages about the Menu
key that that key is actually very
useful make use of it just such folks re
Menu key okay you'll find my webpage
okay so there's a question what do I
think of tech vs. let's talk about that
tech truly you know let me tell you what
they are so tech keyboard is code is a
keyboard called truly organ ami keyboard
okay so that is here and maybe that's it
for today so because it seems like I'm
unless you guys comment ok comment or
and we have more stuff to talk about so
ok so so this is the truly organ ami
keyboard now this is a newer version ok
I'm not sure they are already on sale or
not but anyway probably yeah I think
they are on sale already so this is a
truly ergonomic keyboard I don't have
this version but I have the older
version now the older version looks like
that it's no longer available so if you
want to buy you have to buy the new
version now the older version I've used
of course I've used this older version
for like 4 years
it's very good ok except it's flat it's
not tainted now tenting is important if
you actually sit in front of a computer
for like five hours a day then then you
want to attend it so so so you don't
want you know you want your hands like
that instead of that because I used the
truly organ ami for for five years and I
started to feel pain I forgot where but
anyway what happens is that if you put
your hands like that on the desk every
day for you know even if you are not
typing just put your hands like that for
five hours a day after a several month
after year you're gonna have problems
okay so how do I know because it
happened to me what how do I know
because when I twist my hands like that
it feels comfort you know it feels
comfort by the way like even even right
now so that's what happens when you are
like like
you know your hands are pronated for too
long so but of course not everyone sit
in front of computer literally for five
hours a day another thing is that you
actually have to measure like
statistically not oh you know oh I'm a
programmer I sitting in front of a
computer eight hours a day and that's
not true if you actually you go to lunch
you go to meetings you drive to work you
go to the bathroom then you chat to you
know people on the union company the
actual time you sit down in front of a
computer is only one [ __ ] hours okay
you idiot like people okay so measure it
okay so but for me I actually you know
because I don't go out I don't I don't
work is actually sit before in front of
a computer for like for like was it 13
hours a day literally for like 10 years
so I had RSI problems so that's so
that's when you know you know whether
you you this finite ones are okay for
you or not okay so but I haven't used
the truly economic the new version the
new version is definitely better than
the old version because you got more
keys and you got more thumb keys it's
definitely better it's also better
because it's it got a optical switch new
technology so that's about truly you
know organ ami Creve keyboard now the
expose keyboard again they have a new
version okay this is their new version
now I have the old version this is the
old version I don't have it with me it's
in my old apartment otherwise I can show
you so this this I have it's very good
very very good actually I like it very
much I don't use it because I you know
when they send it they sent it to me
it was not the final product and at that
time they don't have the the
programmable software the drivers to go
with it so I cannot be mapped keys you
know because I type ammo rack and for
this keyboard remapping keys is
important because they have several
duplicated keys for example enter is
here and also here actually you need to
see a bigger picture so let me show you
okay so you can see enter is here and
also here control is here and also on
the left and also on the right so three
control keys to enter keys and the two
old keys and you know so you have you
know you have kind of lots of wasted
keys so you want to remap them but when
I have this keyboard I don't have those
you know the software is not ready by
the time they have a software is the
firmware is different for my so I cannot
use it so I didn't use this I only use
this keyboard for like for a month but
it's very good okay I can you know I
trust me it's I like it very much so
which one is better between this one or
the truly organ ami and by the way they
have a new version expose expose night
ok so
obviously the night version is is even
lots of improvements but the layout
didn't change the layout is basic
basically the same
so anyway which one is very is this one
better or the the new truly ergonomic
Creve I'm not sure because you really
have to have this keyboard in order to
tell ya I from just by pure analysis
yeah I wouldn't I
I wouldn't give a opinion I couldn't say
which one is definitely better unless I
actually have this keyboard okay so
maybe that's it for today so what else
any anything else so so so coronavirus
yeah let's talk about karana good
morning George okay so this may go back
to the
let's go back to okay so
let's go back to the let's go back to
the San talk show talk talk and I think
we're gonna shut down okay so I've been
talking basically for clothes for now
let's see okay so this is a new setup
for me so you can see my face so what's
the topic
Oh coronavirus yeah the you know the
corona virus is quite interesting
because because all of a sudden over
sudden in a ward
you know we have you know in a short
span of one month or three months we
have these giant crisis around the world
and with right now 20,000 people dead
the wuhan virus and this quite a lot to
talk about that because this is there's
a lot political issues because these
right-wing white Americans [ __ ] they
started to you know they want to call
this Chinese virus that's the that's
okay but they they basically they they
have a hatred they started to hate
Chinese or China you know that's a
different concept but however it's a bit
complicated because it's raided maybe
we'll get into that but anyway so look
at the current status so we have
worldwide we have 101 million 1 million
and and 800,000 people who have the
virus and worldwide we have hundred
fourteen thousand people dead 114
thousand people dead and in USA USA is
incredible it's growing and growing you
know right now it's five hundred fifty
nine thousand cases in USA the second
country Spain is only 166 so USA is like
two times three times
[ __ ] USA more severe than the other
countries and when when this happened in
China back in January February you know
the u.s. Americans then the the part you
know the Americans the left-wing and
right-wing party fighting every day they
are making fun of it oh look at China
all this oh it's not important Oh flu is
more important you know all the major
media the corporations New York [ __ ]
times they are you know saying clickbait
you know that they doing creepy prick
paid every day so but then on YouTube
you have you know you have then you have
fake news like people dropping dead
China in China
look look Chinese you know the yeah you
know then you have you have videos of
people sitting doors you know the police
windows and things like that then now it
happens in USA is far more serious you
know the Chinese China is only look
eighty eighty two thousand back then
back you know just like two months ago
it was it was you know a crisis look
eighty thousand people but now in USA
USA alone you have five hundred fifty
nine thousand
and it's not going away he's not going
away
okay it's like in the past few days I
look every day it's like 10,000 20,000
people every day more so so USA is 559
thousand and Spain the second most
country right now is 166 then you have
Italy 156,000 Germany hundred
twenty-seven thousand you know that's so
basically all the Europe you know Spain
Italy Germany France and United Kingdom
Kingdom or not doesn't help helpless
eighty-four thousand people and United
Kingdom have ten thousand people dead so
it's um so over sudden you know this in
three months despite you know we are
kind of helpless or the people you know
world order Sciences or the technology
artificial intelligence
you know cryptocurrency concurrency
cryptocurrency doesn't help other visual
intelligence doesn't help google
satellite Google this and that doesn't
help so it's quite amazing you know so
this means you know so bio you know one
interesting observation about this is
that you can see that bio weapon is very
real
okay it's it's very you know it's very
real someone some country you can easily
create a bio bio weapon that wipe out
the entire human human animals on the
earth on a planet
you know it's you know here we can see
that it's kind of you know it's very
real so that's one thing the other thing
is that we I observed he said you know
the future is rad it's rather
unpredictable
okay the future what will happen in
future like nobody we don't know this
would happen nobody knows and it just
happens so before i we you know we were
thinking about artificial intelligence
robotics cryptocurrency
you know how society will change how
they will change society what's the
future will be like in 10 years you know
maybe we will reach singularity you know
things like that but now over sudden in
3 months we have these drivers out of
control and we don't really know what
will happen so what this means is that
the future is truly not predictable you
know alike there is this guy this
academic fox this steve pink steve pinky
something like that you know there's
famous linguistics
I think he's a linguist like you know in
quizzes or psychologist in business I
think so he kept saying he you know what
he's found of saying that oh look
actually the world is better according
you know if you look at statistics the
world the crime rates are down the you
know democracy is more democracy around
the world the wealth of people is you
know more wealthy less pool and things
like that he's found of saying that if
because you know right now the American
politics the the left-wing right-wing
the social justice [ __ ]
versus the guard believers they fight
every day then then comes out as Steve's
you know Steve pink pink guy say you
know actually don't worry you know you
worry too much
only because you read Twitter too much
because statistically actually the world
is a better place look at the statistics
the crime rate is now and so on he is
found of saying that
yes well that's kind of true but that
doesn't that does not mean you know the
wood is gonna be good
you know it is you know we don't it
doesn't mean some you know we don't have
to worry okay
this coronavirus is a good example why
does it happen because future is not
predict predictable you know you have
chaos theory you know you have you know
in dynamic dynamical systems in
mathematics you have these situations
you know you you don't know what will
happen and in the corona virus is an
example so so that's what I want to say
about that this is quite a lot to talk
about that about this virus of course
from you know there is political issues
then there is conspiracy issues then you
know too many things okay let's go back
and maybe that's it for today let's go
back to my youtube okay and maybe that's
it for today we have actually quite a
few other topics I wanted to show
Allan's artwork which which I didn't
let's show that quickly okay because
it's fun
sorry Scott artwork okay so let me go
back to life UK again so math cube says
I heard for the x-files keyboard that
you over reach for six seven keys on the
number row since the columns have space
between them yeah it is true you know on
exposed keyboard the keys six and five
not six seven five five and six you I
kinda have to reach but you get to use
it you get used to it quickly so it's
not a thing to worry
I am from UK even our Prime Minister
caught it by following your own advice
the Johnson right he's naming what what
was his name Johnson right he's an
extremely ugly guy
hey good morning good evening great
break the loop okay I think I'm about to
end unless you guys have questions so
ask questions yeah we'd so we did a talk
for one hour now any questions any
comments questions that's it for today
so coronavirus it's good time to do
livestream because you know even I get
bored you know with you know with this
shelter in shelter in stayed at home
order from the government that we are as
good think I'm happy with it
UK again what what do you happy with
Emily are you going to spend your $1200
on your keyboard
well yeah that's you know that's a
government money I'm not even sure I'm
going to get it because I haven't I have
not been paying taxes for for over ten
years so I'm not sure I'm going to get
that money things might change though
you know because now there's some change
happened so so yeah I don't know what
happened had I'm not sure I'll get that
money
so Dale carnage is that your real name
Te'o carnage because there is the there
is a extremely popular marketing book by
the guy named Dale carnage
Thank You George George thank you George
from Australia for $1 okay so any other
questions sir George George Hanson
alysus came up with a number around
8,000 bits of information stored in the
Janome for sass of 19 not terribly hard
to make or modify an existing virus for
a nation state level entry I don't know
you know when you know during these
crises whenever a crisis happens you
have quite a few number of people who
who are crazy you know who panic and who
do you know then he they create rumors
and all sort of craft information they
spread information or sort of fake
information
you know because people get nervous you
know they want to do that sometimes they
think the government is lying to you for
example zombie like zombies situation
you've seen a lot Sambi situation in
movies you know zombie situation in
movies so then the government is trying
to hide information then or the
government what don't want to know about
things you know so so you are a citizen
you try to survive so you try to you
know you tell other people what do you
think is true this kind of thing but in
general I think okay let me tell you
what I think
when situation when a zombie situation
happens like a giant crisis epidemic or
pandemic when when this kind of thing
happens your you know your conspiracy
theory usually are typically useless
like no use whatsoever what's so [ __ ]
ever okay for example right now there
are so many people claim even that even
three months ago people like to claim oh
this is a China made by a weapon
released by accident you know some
people like to claim that and now
Chinese you know there's a spoke person
of China Chinese they say you know they
spread he spread the rumor spread the
rumor actually he never actually said it
he just implied it you know that's these
people propaganda was he implied okay he
never actually claimed but however he
implied that this this is bioweapon
made in USA you know somehow released
released by accident accident you know
so so this crisis actually there are a
lot things going on the government they
are fighting each other and they are all
doing propaganda Wars if they have you
know they have huge amount of money they
billions they throw billions dollars
into it because this is propaganda war
is one of the most critical warfare
today okay not the actual you know
nuclear bomb or weapons that those are
still important but you know you don't
you can't readily use them you have you
know so propaganda war is actually the
most important warfare today so the
government they are you know doing also
the propaganda you don't know you know
the thing about propaganda is that you
don't even know you believe it that's
that's the point about propaganda you
know if you know I believe this because
it's a propaganda with my government
told me that's not Papa ganda you
believe something but you don't think
you know you just naturally believe
that's that's when propaganda works okay
so the government you United States and
China all the big powers they spend you
know they spend obedience you know
research you know you know it's
psychology they know how to do
propagandist and also propaganda the
point of propaganda is that you want to
control the massive population not
individuals okay remember propaganda
usually does not work for thinkers for
example propaganda comes to me it does
nothing it stops because because I think
I think too much so when you have force
information in general general generally
speaking if you think you know you you
are not likely to believe in
superstitions or force information
because you can decide what is actually
true or false but that's not the purpose
of propaganda they did propaganda you
know is not going to target you you you
are smart okay you guys are smart it's
not going to target you guys because
it's gonna be you know effectual its but
what what it is actually affect you is
the 90% of the population the rest not
not even ninety percent let's just say
fifty percent the rest of the population
it works on them that's what how
propaganda works so you know and so USA
has been doing propaganda I don't want
to talk about too much about you know
USA propaganda because well I'm American
okay citizen wise but my blood is
Chinese so it's a bit complicated
complicated but anyway so but you know
it's back to propaganda you know use the
most you know
majority of white Americans they just
believe USA a whole team across here
things like that but if you are not if
you you know if you didn't if you are
not pointing USA you will have different
opinions about it in and in China today
is also very powerful so they are
actually I would say fairly successful
in propaganda okay they have fairly
successful you know and so anyway anyway
so you have these crisis the big powers
you know US government in China they are
fighting propaganda Wars
that's one thing the other thing is that
you know I was saying that there are a
lot of people who just believe
conspiracy they are prone to cut believe
conspiracy theories and my my opinion is
usually is useless when a crisis happens
when when some big giant zombie crisis
or epidemic or pandemic happens crisis
situation usually your conspiracy
theories are useless okay even if they
are true okay even if it is true that
government lied okay this this is
actually a bio weapon from China or from
or maybe it's something else okay even
if that's true your information is
usually useless useless in the sense
that it does not do anything to help you
to survive okay it might help you you
know for a month and also a lot of
people they try to trap you know the you
know the meme called peppers they try to
buy stuff you know that doesn't you know
and also people try to buy guns you know
especially Americans you know the white
Americans you know the what
winger's they like to buy guns you know
it doesn't usually it doesn't help okay
if it's a big crisis people are going to
die you are going to die - okay you have
guns maybe you'll survive for one more
month typically yeah so I died so I
don't you know in general I don't
believe in propaganda stuff or having
conspiracy theory stuff okay that's it
for today thank you guys so thank you
Alan again how in-house oh wait al-azhar
work artist so well we have this one is
by job of serenity so this as me and
this one is by Alan captain Alan and a
captain Alan my request has strong a
bunch of facial expressions so he'd you
know I think drawing one of the most
difficult thing about drawing is facial
expressions because human emotions the
facial expressions they are Manute you
know they say human face has thousands
of muscles you can detect that's that's
how you can detect smile you know like
when you you know you take a photo you
say smile in your passport photo driver
sizes those are fake smiles fake smiles
is different from genuine smiles you can
tell the reason you can tell because
those two facial expressions are
actually different okay because some
summers are not moving some muscles are
moving fixed smile and genuine smile you
can tell the difference every normal
person can tell the reason you can tell
because they are actually different so
facial expression is very intricate and
I think it's a difficult thing to to
master to draw them so that's why I ask
Alan to joy and alle Juden
you know you're also physically that's
very interesting I wanted I was going to
talk about another thing that's not then
you have these funny comics you know cat
then we have I mean let's wait so I'm
going to stop only anyway for five more
minutes okay so let me show you then we
have this are si Pepe repetitive strain
injury Pepe this one is straw drew by
Alan what okay is I Pepe I love this one
because you can you can see the
expression in the hand
oh god [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] posting too much
then you have this okay this this is an
insider joke okay this this is an
insider joke we have this alien guy who
who does not take up to 20 hours a day
now if you are not in our discord then
you wouldn't understand so and this is
alien again you know he's in the area
next mask all these are drew drawn by
Alan then we have this we have this
Ripper guy from the institution but from
the establishment Reaper
and another insider joke and here is
Emily Alan's impression of emily alyn so
have you actually ever seen Emily's face
I forgot to ask you that
so so then we have this every ran guy
who is Indian who is posting link dumped
every day in discord he just dumped
links okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching bye bye
so let me add so that's it for today so
let me just go over the chat see what
happens see what we have here so I don't
think there's any evidence that this is
a man-made virus I think it's much more
likely it was natural yeah I think it's
natural to I'm just saying that I'm just
saying the people saying it's being
proven that he wasn't man-made are
idiots
okay sure
look guys I need a new Mac look at my
CPU it's all maxed out and when I scroll
it doesn't move [ __ ] I need equipment
okay thank you guys I'll see you when is
the next one I don't know you know maybe
I can start to do it regularly now
possibly so maybe possibly tomorrow okay
so thank you guys Thank You Alan
Thank You Jorge see you next time