good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of excel talk
show
today is today is today is
march 2nd 2021
noon san francisco time good morning all
we have nine people watching
and today's topic is going to be random
so
questions and answer session okay you
ask
i answer and otherwise i'm just going to
go random
and i'm gonna talk about you know i'm
going to go through my emacs
uh blog my keyboard blog my programming
blog my math blog
and see whatever is interesting i've
done in the past month or two
so first of all it is there is this
interesting artwork the background of
today's video
uh before am i alive yes
check check check everything check
okay the background of today's video is
this one splinter
art this is the splinters art this is a
fantastic
artwork uh you know
some artwork they have meaning and this
is one such example
um this one in particular i just found
it
randomly a year or two ago you know
uh and apparently it's a illustration
to uh to horror stories
okay so it's an illustration to horror
stories so so you can see
kind of uh you know
and it's kind of uh abstract and
it does you know it does illustrate you
know illustration to horror stories but
it's
it's a bit more than that okay so
very interesting uh that's today's
artwork now who is the artist
i do not know and okay so there is a
research
job now now look now now you guys go
and look you know to find out who is the
artist for this one that that would be
interesting i think
i love this one it's a fantastic
illustration
the power of communicative art
good morning guys mark good morning mark
orlanek
good morning pedro pedro morales
morales hi can you please talk about
emac setup on windows
mingw okay so let me tell you something
about that
again i have a bit cross eye that's why
i put this patch on
uh when since i was young it's minor you
may not notice it but
but basically because my glasses are bad
i need to get new glasses this
one is for near-sightedness one is one
is for
uh old age
[Laughter]
for looking at things close
uh good morning so again ask questions
okay post questions i'm gonna talk about
that otherwise i'm going to go random so
the first question is about emacs set up
on windows okay
now first of all so on on so you can see
on the pink window is all my emacs
command codes i'm using stuff like keys
and i'm using html mod everything is
kind of custom
and i can magnify the you see every time
i call
command or key stroke you can see the
keystroke and you can
also see the command name on the pink
window okay
and that command is uh
exhaust dot command log okay you can
find it on my init
let's magnify so source.commandlog
that's a command
that's a wrapper too so here is my own
command it's a wrapper to this
uh this package command log mod.el
which is on melpa uh on mailpower or
maybe alpha i forgot but anyway you can
you can you can find it easily and the
thing about but that package is written
you know it's got some pro you know it's
not perfect
okay let's just say it's not perfect so
i
in order to start this mod you have to
run a command to start the buffer a
special buffer then you have to run
another command things like that a bit
not intuitive so therefore i you know
therefore i wrote this wrapper just to
start everything you know
like the pink window you see okay and
you can find this on on get my github
sorry github uh
emacs in it was uh the file name for
this one is this one
emacs miscellaneous okay so here we are
in diode i want to delete those backups
press a key
uh press the key gun okay back close
that close that
so the question is how do you set up
emacs init on windows
now emacs init files are basically
operating system agnostic okay so it
doesn't matter on windows or on linux
or on uh let me show you okay so here is
my
okay here is my okay i don't wanna okay
uh
wait uh
hide uh tired hide
or what ah let's show again
i want to hide the
i want to hide the what's the
diet height details mod okay diet
height diet height details mod so here
is our here are my emacs in it so emacs
in it doesn't depend on operating
systems basically on
windows on mac on linux it's all the
same
and for me as well now of course there
are uh
some things you need to specialize such
as font for example
so let's go to my settings okay settings
now this file settings
contains the most basic uh emacs in it
that does not require any packages
it's just plain glue emacs okay oops
so this file let's open it so here you
are looking at my settings file so you
can see
settings first of all i set up the you
know the toolbars
remove the toolbar so you see
if it's on windows on my one of my
windows
machine then remove the toolbar remove
the you know say the background color
then within width and height of the
window for example i can open a new
window you know there's a default width
and height
height okay so but if i'm on another
machine this xpc which is another
windows
which has a kind of laptop screen
is my um surface
tablet you know microsoft surface so so
the width
width and height is smaller
because otherwise you're gonna go over
your screen so
so that's a little bit differences for
you know different
machines but in general it's the same
okay so so i'm talking about in general
it's the same
doesn't matter which operating system
but there are few things you want to set
such as the default width and height
height of the
frame the window or end font
okay so here is the settings for font
because
on mac and windows and linux they each
have different
uh fonts set come with a system so for
example if i'm on windows
then i want the default font to be
consolers okay consoles is the default
basically the best mono space font
that comes with microsoft windows
consoles so you are looking at consoles
right now
and on the mac the best one default that
come with the mac
is menlo six uh and also you need to set
the size
because depends on your screen you know
you know the monitors the display
differs a lot these days
some has very high density some has
uh you know smaller or larger different
so you need to
specify the font size otherwise it's too
small too big
and on windows i mean and on linux the
most
uh general purpose greatest font
that contains the most unicode
characters such as math
symbols i'm not talking about emoji but
also including emoji
for example if you are a scientist or
engineer you use a lot of math
symbols or stuff you want
uh deja vus okay so online it also comes
with
linux so so you see
font is one of the things you might want
to set if you are on you know different
operating system
uh and and here is the settings for
emoji that's also
and you know depending on whether you
use our emoji or not
uh and basically this and also a
set set fund for chinese if you are
typing chinese for example let's see
chinese blog let's see my chinese blog
okay
so i have a chinese blog so i do type
chinese for example i can open for
example
you are looking at my emacs chinese blog
okay so you can type chinese
uh so if you do use chinese then you
might want to set up that
okay so font is one thing you want to
set depending on
operating system or the machine or the
monitor size
font font size and
windows height and width okay that's
that's the primary thing and basically
everything else is the same but however
if you are on wind there are more things
to set if you are on windows let me look
at the comments okay keep the comments
coming okay whatever questions
you have type it and i'll get to it so
one of the thing on windows is that you
know emacs
depends on uh
about five also unix commands
and what they depend on i can tell you
okay so
uh emacs depends on few unix commands so
let's go to talk show okay so
go to talk show magnify open this page
so the first question is uh
talk about emacs in it
for windows okay and
the thing you want to do uh
usually it's not
dependent on os but
you want to set up font
and default window
width and the height that's the two
things you want
and on windows and
on windows emacs depends on a few unix
commands i'm
not going to type okay so the commands
are
now this is actually a flaw of emacs now
the the command c max
depends on depends on r find
graph that's the two most used uh
command
and if uh let's see what else
uh that's it okay now these three
let's let me do this so you can see how
fancy i get
okay so you see
and you see my the power of html mod now
show in browser magnify
okay now hold on get back to emacs or
one single key operation comment that
out
show in browser so you can see uh
you know we have typed what uh what i
was talking so emacs
on windows emacs depends on this unix
command
the and it's a design flaw because
find and grab for example graph means
search file for example i want to search
my current directory start talk show
directory of
all the words that contain let's say
haskell okay because i love to make fun
of haskell
so i can call command pascal
and type this directory or html files
and you can see
here are the results let's magnify okay
so i can press arrow keys to go to it
and you know talk show and i can press
up down arrow to go among the files
you see and i i put the cursor on one of
these arrow key
type enter then it opens that file and
you can see
haskell is mentioned there so this is
by the way i'm using this uh this module
okay i mean i'm
my the package i'm i used scifi text
dot yeah you can you can you can you can
um
scifi dot er you can it's on mailpad
okay so
i'm using my own command but in general
when you want to search
find and replace and grab you emacs
requires you to have the unix command
grep
installed and and sometimes in direct
you also
some direct operations requires you to
have the unix find
command so on windows you don't have
that
so what do you do so there are several
solutions you can install them
today you can install them by a chalk
okay so let me tell you the story okay i
want to finish this topic quickly
because
we have lots of other things correct am
i correct are there other
questions
okay hold on a second let me read the
questions tell us please about your
math self-study okay uh routine okay
okay i'll answer that are you the are
you the
jimmy guy or mark
olenek are you the jimmy guy weenie
hi winnie are you using the official
emacs
binary uh yes uh yes i'm using the
official e-max binary actually i better
put it
this song because i see better
yes i'm using a visual emacs binary glue
emacs
on windows um so i'm using plain emacs
with my own packages basically i don't
use you know
much others i'm getting sick of windows
almost switching to linux you have
experience with linux of course
you haven't watched my videos i have
i have linux experience since 1999.
uh what do you have paper on the eye so
that's
my cross eye i talked about in my last
two videos
uh so i see better this way because the
mild cosine yes
ignoring cortez uh your video on this
kind of logistics on emacs are really
really
good okay thank you alfonso
but jean says source code pro is also a
good font for me
okay yeah you know when it comes to font
lots of nerds programmers they all have
opinions
i don't mean to attack you but i talked
about
what on one episode i talked about font
actually i despise
the fonts uh obsession you know that's
one of the obsession among nerds you
know
of programmers they'll talk about you
know and they
you know they're obsessed about fund and
uh
kerning and oh you know and and every
five years there are new fonts coming up
you know they say why is this the best
and so on but anyway i talked about that
in one of my uh
video just search for font in one of my
video you'll find it
uh do i have linum global of course
uh just for a set of files no i have
them globally
uh and not linum okay linum is the old
one
right you know that uh you know
you know lots of these questions um if
you just search
my website you'll find it for example
ergo emacs
linden okay uh
show line number mod okay so in this
page is
full detailed explanation so this one
command is global display line number
mod
this is new uh written in c uh
and this is new around 2018
emacs 26 okay now linear mod is the old
hack
uh hack that created in 2009
that tries to have the number lines on
the column but it's a hack so it's
extremely slow when you have a file if
you open a file with let's say uh
5000 lines then it slows the whole the
emax buffer to a quote
so you you don't want lin linda ma linda
mod
is uh deprecated okay
you want to use the uh display line
number mod or
you know so look watch so look at this
page i explain in detail okay so let me
copy that
uh so make a link okay
so i want to go back to so so the
question now is
how on on windows how do you deal with
the linux commands
okay so why the okay
long story the last time i used windows
for
four years
is around 2009 to 2012 okay
so i haven't been using windows for nine
years
now i'm back to windows i talked up i
talked about
which os i used uh you know uh several
times in my past videos but anyway
i haven't used windows for for about
eight years
so i'm back now in the beginning i was
thinking oh i need to
install how do i solve the problem of
installing
uh unix commands because i need them
find grab diff
basically these three okay i have an
article essay that explains what you
need what
you know what the things you need
exactly uh
you know it's so it's all on the
my website okay there's a lot of things
to read
so when i come back to windows this year
you know two uh
uh two months ago i was thinking okay
should i use uh
sig wing i have a few articles on
tutorials on sequin sequins the classic
okay
the classic unix kind of emulator or
something like that that's what i used
for since year
1999. uh okay sequin is one solution
then after 20 years there are so many
new solutions then there's
ms uh there is this one you
uh you just mentioned uh what i i forgot
the name
you know what's the name
am i getting boring so ask questions
okay whatever questions
uh uh or any other thing
so i'll i'll try to finish this topic
quickly
are you using a feature okay where is
the question
oh m mean gw yeah so sigwin is the
classic
then you have mgm
means uh mi and gw okay which is
supposed to be lighter
uh you know so i use that for for three
years around 2008
uh uh win gw okay let me quick
just i have tons of articles okay
so sigwin essential install list this
is written in 2011 uh and not just that
okay so let's let's see let's open that
let's open that
uh almost on any topic just search for
saudi
then whatever the words you'll find my
articles on that
so here's the sequin essential install
list why do i write this list why do i
write this down because
why am i new machine window windows for
example yeah
i want to so i don't forget you know i
need to go through this
install these things you know zip first
of all
install zip because
well actually you don't need zip because
window actually can unzip but however
you know zip is uh the command line zip
is uh useful
so you know then you have to install
bzip because lots of unix
uh you know or xz needs those then you
open ssh for ssh but
things have changed so yeah so i'm
getting ahead of myself you know
so this is backing i wrote this in 2011
but today
you have not seek wing you have uh win
gw
then you have the you have choc choco
which is uh which i recommend which i
i'm using right now
so for example i can uh let's see
powershell run us admin okay so
uh can i magnify the font uh how do
i
how do i magnify the font size
of
okay a little bit yeah okay so for
example let's say
choco choco info find
okay choco is a package management
system
for windows and it it was created maybe
five years ago or ten
so over the 20 years lots of technology
so today you don't even
you don't need to install sigwin you
don't need to install
mg i mean gw i don't okay i don't
so this time i don't install them and
then so you can install choco
and uh actually find is not the name
okay uh let's say grep okay
you see so you found grapes so if you
want to install grab
choco install grab enter it will install
that okay so
all the unix commands you need or ssh or
whatever
you can use choco to install it uh it's
very
uh easy to do painless okay
so i don't use sigwing i don't think you
should neither because
it's kind of too old okay it's gonna be
you know as we progress you know oh
technology they are going
away and mean gw
i don't even use i don't i think i don't
use neither so i think it's also going
away
so choco is the thing you want okay now
even with choco
you see i want to find uh you know for
example i can install grep
uh i but i also emacs often often needs
fine too so the name for find package is
find uto i think
so let's start to try again choco info
find uto
zero package uh found so i forgot
uh maybe it's granule find
okay find you tears okay uh
find you tears
yeah there it is so you you just run
choco and still find your tears then
you'll get the find
the unix find command
so i recommend choco okay now
even if you know we are progressing okay
no more sick win
no more mg you know mean gw
then you have choco which is unique but
however i don't even install
find and grab anymore because i realized
today
uh powershell you know powershell began
like 15 years ago today is so powerful
so
when i need unix find ut and your to
grip you know powershell is actually
much better i talked about this in my
last two videos okay
yeah last video i think i talked
for 20 minutes or something about
powershell powershell is far more
powerful
than all the unix utils so get to use
powershell
if you uh you know try to use powershell
learn powershell and i have a tutorial
for powershell just search for it okay
so let's go back
uh so sigwin so well where is my uh
sigwin okay so uh too many articles okay
so sigwin
so for example i have installed sequin
tutorial let's open them all
install sequin tutorial unix tools
on windows sequin versus virtualbox you
know then you have choice you can also
run emacs within virtualbox
uh how to install linux on virtualbox
okay then linux setup so let's copy that
uh i'm pedaling my web pages okay don't
forget to donate
that's why i'm doing it doing youtube so
install sequin tutorial
let's copy and paste it here so you can
read
uh all these are written like like 10
years ago so
you know they they're getting old so
this you know
uh virtualbox i you know 2011 virtualbox
then how to install linux on virtualbox
uh
you know all these are this is 2012.
then linux setup okay this is this page
is what i need to do when i'm
on linux it kind of remind myself what
uh all the settings i need to do okay
so my linux setup
uh then okay and this page how fast is
running perl in sequin or using nt
file nt file system on linux so i the
the price you pay for layers and
emulations
so one day in 2013 you know i was
i had an issue i want to know just how
fast you know just like
for example if you need to run pearl or
python okay is it faster if you run the
pearl you know python is sequin
or is it faster if you run perl on linux
but
but via ntfs so why do you have a
question you have the question because
uh because suppose you have a dual boot
you know which
which was very common you can boot to
linux or you can move to windows
and let's say perl or python is your
main language so you want to know
should you you know do dev on windows
you know you know questions like that so
that's why you have questions so i
measured the time
and stuff so let's post that
and press one key look at the pink
window okay so let's
uh let's look at the pink window
so now i want to make them into a list
okay so
uh sigwin let's mention
chalk okay choco okay
uh win gm
not gw gw or gm gw
i think uh siguin okay
then doom boom show in browser
there it is here's a list okay close
that close that
close that show line numbers do i have
did i
uh okay let's put that there show line
numbers
close that okay chinese block copy that
put it here close that
artwork i already have that okay so back
to emacs
showing browser all one single key press
you see what i'm doing is all one single
finger okay no
no code no control oh
and no 30 40 keyboards those
those are repetitive strain injury uh
things okay so okay i'm going to talk
about math
okay i'm going to talk about math uh
let's
uh you know let me migrate to math
because i want to
i guess you know because there's a
question about math
uh so so choco is great thing you want
to install choco
there are alternatives you know new
people they say oh just something
something else is better i'm sure
it's better but i haven't spent time the
thing is you have to spend time
to invest you know there are better ones
than choco
you know some my nurse friends you guys
told me
but i haven't take the time to study
choco just work fine for me
so choco you want but so you can use
choco to
install grab find you know or diff you
know what what uh
emacs needs but these days i don't even
need them because first of all
i try to use powershell okay you can
install a powershell mod
so you can run powershell on within
emacs
i don't have it right now uh i i haven't
i i do have the mod
but um wait
uh not the direct buffer okay what did i
just run
uh powershell let's see
so okay so you have you do have a power
shell so let's see if that works
okay duh now uh it works
okay there is a uh let me show you okay
so maybe
you are not familiar with powershell you
know there is an alias to
the command okay let's see help um
you can see edius there is the edius to
the command get children
and get children is also gcm okay so you
can type
uh alias
yeah i need to be on anyway so install
powershell mod
so you can run powershell within emacs
okay
now i'm going to you know and i have a
powershell tutorial okay let's let's go
to it
powershell tutorial i talked about this
in last video at length okay so you can
study powershell it's uh ten times
better than
um than unix stuff kill it
yes okay so
powershell okay so so you can
install chalk on windows for emacs but
uh
use powershell powershell can replace
most of it
and also what about find and replace for
example if
in emacs often you want to do grep or
many emacs command they will actually
implicitly call grab to work
if you don't have graph it doesn't work
so what do you do
so in my case use the scifi command okay
cause i find dot el so just search for
it
and you'll see there it is github
sapphire this is a find replace package
or graph
returned entirely in emaclis so with
this
you don't need any commands in emacs for
find find or find and replace anymore
that's what i use i i just did the demo
uh you know a few minutes ago and here i
there's also explanation of why
you know some people will say oh my god
why are you usually
using this you know you should use grape
you should use
silver you should use you know there are
quite a few replacements over the past
10 years
uh each one is supposed to be faster
than the one before
i have a i have an article on those
uh okay so anyway so grab
what's the names uh i think one is named
silva i think one you know
every about every five years there's a
new one coming up
you know it's supposed to be faster than
grip
but why do i you know why do i uh so so
why do you
write a pure emac list version for it
you know why don't you just hook up to
8g
right one of them i think the latest one
is called ag
and i i you know i even filed a bug
report
to the guy because he didn't have
problems on the mac
a few years ago when it first came up
so anyway so why why do i write you know
what do you do it in emac this okay emac
list is much
more smaller smaller uh slower
but however there are quite a few
advantages for example it's e-mag this
so it's 100 more integrated with emacs
than any of the
any of the other you know when you call
the grab command you know outside of
emacs
external command this is more integrated
than any of them
also it uses the same regular expression
syntax
as emac list okay or c max
so you don't suddenly you have to use
the unix you know the pearl grip
you know grab synax is another story
very complex
i have like 20 uh 20 articles on grep
including tutorials for emac this for
for python for perl for javascript
just search for exactly javascript uh
regular expression
rejects sorry emac this rejects sorry
python rejects
i have a complete documentation
of regular expression uh in all these
languages also a regular expression
tutorials for
all these languages and also go like so
what so the point of using
star find uh dot er which is a pure emac
this
uh frank grab or find or
find replace um is that it's fully
integrated with emacs and it's also uh
consistent with e-max the regular
expression syntax
now the last flaw you know but it's slow
it's slow
you know the other ones are you know
that's written in c or c
plus plus or rust they are much faster
than
like five five or ten times faster so
why should you use
uh find replay scrap in emac these
written images well the reason
is most of the time you know i run this
about every two or three days for the
past 20 years
on 6 000 files 10
000 html files because my website is
static so i have to do find replays
all the time every two three days i do
that
that on a thousands or so files so i
have a version in
python in perl in golan 2 which i do use
when i need
speed but most of the time
you know for 10 000 files it's instant
you know the result is instant
you know for example let's do let's do
around one right now okay so
let's say i want to find the word
haskell okay
i want to find a word haskell in let me
show you okay
i want to find the word haskell in or
sally dot info now exactly.info is got
you know it's got 10 000 files okay i'm
not going to show it
but okay so let's just do so let's let
me show you okay let's do that
so type pascal here type haskell
okay in this direct wait uh
query uh wait okay
haskell and in what directory exit info
okay enter then all html files right
yeah enter then you wait you know 10
seconds
because when you run you know for the
first time it's
loading the files loading the files
actually is the
bottleneck it's not the speed of the
grip loading the file is the bottleneck
once i do this once if i do it again
it's going to be within one second
so right now it's going to about 6000
html files
also it has to filter out you know it's
only looking for html files
otherwise there are you know 30 000
files look
there is a result magnify i can
you know i can jump around you you can
see the
you know the the scroll bar there's lots
of results
so let's uh shrink shrink shrink
so you can see
you know that's uh so it's a it's fast
you know so let's close that okay let's
try
let's do it again but this time i want
to find all the words containing pearl
okay so this is what i do okay
let me show you so look at the mini
buffer okay magnify
so you can i can just modify the word
pearl here instead of
answer each question you see find the
word pearl
in this directory user website info okay
or html files enter
let's see how fast look instantaneous
one second
so do you do you really do you really
really need a graph that's written in
rust
no you don't unless maybe you work for
google where
you have to find replace 10 million file
files okay
so that is why you should use
fine.el okay okay i talked to
uh i talked for too long without looking
at the questions
uh let me go back to look at the
questions okay
so where's my page so the official page
is this one
uh okay so let's paste that
okay delete and show in browser there is
my
talk show page okay okay so let's go
back to the i
so so i think that uh answer the
question about what you should do
about when you about any files on
windows
okay sigwin i don't recommend
mean gw i don't recommend chalk
i recommend you should get chalk then
for integration of emacs you know when
you need find and grab
yeah you can so you can install find and
grab in
chalk and diff or try to use powershell
and use client so so you don't have
those problems anymore
so which is this is what i do i have you
know because i was going to install i
was thinking oh i need
you know i was thinking you know since i
am on windows
uh you know actually i was thinking
there's another
solution that is windows linux you know
windows
subsystem for linux okay
that's another new tech you know i was
thinking i'm gonna i'm going to install
that but it turns out
it seems like today i don't i don't need
to i don't have a need for unix commands
anymore
you know powershell basically solves all
the problems
uh you know microsoft is gonna take over
the world
take over linux is such a sad story with
open source
such a sad story okay i
talked about uh okay now maybe i should
i can talk
about math now i've been talking for
jesus
i i already talked for 40 minutes that's
like almost the end of today
my god
okay so that's just about emacs in it
okay so let's see what
what other questions uh
okay let me answer about math okay so
okay that's
actually i can talk about math for
another
half an hour so there's a math question
tell us please about your
math self-study routine and what your
favorite topics okay
okay let me read break let me read
so does that answer the question about
emacs init on windows
who who asked that
oh yeah mark okay mark
break the loop break the loop good
morning
i have a theory out of my ass that
uh the common emax control key
combinations contributes so to uh
contributes to carpal tunnel users like
emily have chosen to use
emacs with vim controls yes
yes of course
uh what do you think of my theory that
emax control key contributes
to risk yes of course that's that's
also that's also my claim you know
emacs is the worst of all
software emacs is the one the most
responsible of history of human history
all software in human history e-max is
got the keybinding default key mining
contributed to repetitive strain injury
the most
uh okay break the loop so of course i
don't use emac control i use
soft light keys haven't you watched
my videos enough i use stuff like keys
i showed that uh too often okay
hi windows 10 i think you can install
ubuntu
mind via ms store okay i don't know
what's that another nice solution is
m632 which is
mgw-based yeah but also wraps up in a
nice package okay
uh why are you why are you
pirate huh uh what do you think about
this
uh the happy hacking oh yeah okay
i'm curious to hear about your
self-study math okay let's talk about
math
break the loop the math capstock uh
don't you
three finger salutes you have two hands
on the keyboard and once you type modify
with your hand we need
well the thing about modifier i mean i
talked about this too many times
so you guys go watch my videos okay
watch my videos studiously i thought
you know this i talked about this too
many times you know key code should be
ideally ban them completely
not us you know try not to avoid any
key code at all no control c no control
v
no old meta nothing no key codes at all
that's the ideal situation ideal
solution however
because of tradition because of
convention you know because of
you know keyboard you cannot avoid you
know you cannot completely get rid of
the key codes
therefore but you you can do a you can
try to avoid them so
my recommendation is to get rid of key
code at all
buy a keyboard macro okay go go buy my
stuff
okay donate
donate and go buy my stuff okay my
keyboard blog uh it
has all the information you need you
know they are
there are 500 articles on keyboard
keybinding and all the stuff okay
and this by the way this is the latest
do it yourself this is fantastic
it's got a uh ink screen you know ink
technology uh this so this is a
programmable marker keypad
so buy one of that it only has four
eight keys not enough okay so you what
you want is
uh keypads okay so i have some
recommendations on key programmable
keypads programmable is the important
word
i have you know as i showed this too
many times you can see
do you see my keyboard that's my system
man that's
so ultimate hacking keyboard ultimate
hacking keyboard i'm
using as a keypad kinesis advantage
2 and lf linear so
this is new i bought two months ago
red switches okay so you go by you can
see reviews and video reviews
on my website okay do i look good
okay get rid of the cyclops
okay so for example keyboard that's why
it's important so
why why do you need this because get rid
of you know try to get rid of uh
any key chords okay now some people i
know a lot of people they are
they are a fan of the
30 keyboards for example
this section okay can i magnify yeah
so these are so where's where are they
so you see
they're there you see irish
54 keyboards this strange one 52
uh google 50 keys silver bullet 44 keys
46 keys 42 keys google plex 36 keys
you know some people like that so what
do you do when you use one of these
keyboard let's see let's see the most
popular the most famous
is the atrias look at these atrias 42
keys
you know so a lot of nerds of you guys
love this one
so this one doesn't even have number
keys no number
and no symbol key so what do you want
what what do you what to do if you want
to uh
say press the dollar sign let's say
three dollars okay
you have to control shift old you
know up your fingers but
but many notes like this okay i don't
like that you know
and get rid of you know many of these uh
keyboards they'll claim
oh we have 10 layers oh we have one
thousand layers
to press you know this symbol you just
old layer two
and they did the up your
fingers okay i don't like that
so buy one so you know so my
recommendation buy a programmable
keyboard with building memory
uh so meaning that many some of the
popular gaming
keyboards uh does not apply because they
you know they require you to have a
software and cloud and stuff
so okay so anyway i talked about this
too many times
uh so you want programmable keyboard
then then get a programmable keypad okay
so
completely get rid of the key chords
whenever
you can so in emacs for example i use
class stuff like keys
as you can see in the pink window
there's almost no
you know you did do you see your control
key there
do you see a meta key there no they
don't see
there's no everything is one single key
press well you see
you see this for example um you see this
some control key control w
but actually that's uh that's because
i'm using the programmable the
ultimate hacking programmable keypad
i press one single key that single key
sends
control w so that that is why you are
seeing this control w
in fact i don't press any you know combo
you know
you know keys so that's enough about
emacs
let me go and talk about emacs i mean
math and that's it for
today uh yeah
because i've been already talking for uh
talking fast for 49 minutes
okay i think we let's talk about math
uh
okay so let me read the questions then
we're gonna talk about math
okay if you have questions type my name
okay so i can see it i'm
i'm probably gonna stop reading
questions now that's it yeah because
that's about it for today
so math so the question is uh what how
do i
learn math okay well the
basic so how do i how do i learn math
what motivates you how do you get
motivated motivation
question like that i suppose and also
what kind of math
topics interest me okay
uh so basically
the thing about math is that if you know
it's just like programming so
for example you know let me let me
explain okay by way of
explaining by way of telling the story
then you'll know how i go about
and maybe you can you know maybe if you
are young you can you want to be a
mathematician or something
you can try that too but actually if you
really if you already decided you want
to be a mathematician you love math you
don't have that question anymore
because actually this is a part of the
fundamental answer
to the question because you know for
example like programming
you know many of you are programmers
many of you are emax
users a fan uh obsessed with emacs
why you know maybe some people we ask
you
none programmers will ask you oh how do
you get motivated into emacs how do you
you know keep learning all these
algorithms programming languages
seems so complex how do you you know how
do you get the interest
you know what what makes you to study
your protocols you know http or
encryption you know it's so
complex how do you get
how do you do it well the answer is you
just love it
you just want to know you need to know
you have a need you have the need to
know what's the latest in emacs
how do you set up oh what is this guy
saying what is
saying about setting up you know this
strange and you know
you you look you know you are into it
so then the question is why are you into
it
then that's a bit more complex okay that
maybe have to do with your family
with how you grew up and also it has to
do with your dna your biology you know
so about math let me tell you why i'm
interested in math because
you know so i'm kind of you know
so why so you know it's it's kind of
hard to explain
you know when you ask a person why is
x why are you interested in x you know
it's just natural okay some people some
people become lawyers
some people become politicians
businessmen because they
maybe probably you know part of the
reason is because they
are good at it so for me i like math
because
i guess i'm good at it you know i'm
somewhat you know
good better in math then you know i'm
not good
at social interactions for example i'm
not good at
you know so if you are not good at
social interactions
then maybe you are not fit for becoming
a leader
because first of all you don't have
interest in that because
to be a leader you often have to talk
to uh talk to people and you also
to be a leader you know you know there
are books uh
seminars which are usually scams you
know they teach you about how to be a
businessman
salesman or leadership but anyway one of
the
qualities to be a leadership is that you
tends to
be convinced you know that you know
better than other people that's one of
the most important
uh requirements and characteristics to
be a leadership to be a leader type of
person you know we are not talking about
we are not talking about bad
leaders i'm talking about in general
okay even good
people great leaders such as uh
what's what are some examples you know
i'm trying to avoid politicians because
usually they
they are not good but anyway you know i
mean i mean even your small team you
know you have a manager you know even
among your friends
one guy tends to be you know tell others
you know and others listen to him so to
be a leader what you know i'm digressing
but anyway to be a leader one of the
most
fundamental characteristics is that the
guy
believes in himself have in other words
have high confidence okay
and he believe doesn't matter what issue
doesn't even doesn't even matter if he
doesn't know nothing he has no
knowledge about this issue but he has
you know he is firm in
believing that what he knows or what he
uh his uh t you know tell others
what to do it will be the better
solution so if you believe in that you
tend to be
a great leader okay you have to be you
know
at all the time confident even if you
don't know even
on the other hand this is in opposition
to philosophers
philosophers the one thing you must not
have
is to have great confidence okay to be a
great philosopher
because you think oh you already know
you know this should the answer is just
that let's do it
you are not you are not going to be a
you're gonna be a
worst philosophers okay
so different personalities have
different you know ways to go
so i'm interested in math because well i
guess i'm
good in math when i was small and also
okay
the reason is that because mathematics
you know among all sciences
among all human subjects matter doesn't
matter what subject
of everything math is the only one
that is we can say is the most well
defined
and every question has only one right
answer
okay this is this is this is the
almost the this is the defining
characteristics of
mathematics the subject okay math is the
thing
among all human subject doesn't matter
writing literature law
business whatever humanity you know
social sociology or whatever
math is the the most okay or the only
subject that
every question you know mathematician
you know in
in math there's only one correct answer
that is absolutely you know that that is
that that
is a difference between math and all
others including physics
okay so that is uh so that
is a reason i'm interested in math
because uh
and this question and often the question
can be very simple
however to come up with the answer is
extremely difficult
also math requires high iq okay
intelligence you know
today uh that becomes you know that's
the concept ifq is not something people
want to mention but
because you're going to get cancelled
but actually
that is actually you know i come to
realize that is
actually a fundamental very important
critical
uh concept in in in human society
among people iq okay
yeah you know i you know the they you
know and and
and and uh half of the have you know iq
doesn't mean you will be great
you know look at me i'm pretty smart
okay there are
there are lots of people who are far
more smarter than me okay
especially when you do math if you do
math you'll realize
you know you think you are smart i think
you know i'm smart oh god i got that you
know as
and and and also it requires
you know a lot of study smart by itself
doesn't do nothing
but if so i i'm also studious you know
since i was you know anyway i study but
when you are in math then you will find
out you know they are 10
000 far more smarter than you in math
you know far more math than you then
they are all
they are mobile mobbing toilets and
mcdonald's
that is true okay that's what you do
that's what you get when you get into
math you know
math has a certain attraction eternal
attraction in human history okay math
doesn't get
you know don't be you know if you know
don't be
don't think oh i'll study math and
you'll get your money no
math is you know the one thing you do
well if you want money
don't go into math okay there's no money
in math
do do programming okay you can be a
dummy
but you do you know you study
programming a lot you know uh
two years after two years you're joining
google make a lot of money more than
professors
more than professors who spend 20 years
together you know
all the uh math degrees then to become a
professor
they make less money than you spend two
years
you know learning programming and go
work for google okay so math don't think
of oh math
you know it doesn't do nothing it
doesn't do
you know it's not a good financial
reward okay math
but however math is such as because you
know the
properties i mentioned about math it's
such an eternal subject you know people
are not the mathematicians they are
studying math not because money you know
they
include including me okay so
you study math because this is just you
know it's like the you
the question about the universe for
example uh
you know common question among us am i
still alive
guys comment okay i guess we're gonna
shut down
soon soon let's see uh live
one hour so i've been talking for one
hour so
so okay math back to math so you know
first
you know i talked about iq okay iq
doesn't do you much okay
a lot i uh you know uh um
so you also need to study uh but
but so i want to summarize so iq does
not
you know give you uh that much of thing
uh and but also you need to study but
but however you cannot just wipe out the
concept of iq
because it actually has a significant
impact
of human uh uh animals okay i'm alive
good
so so why am i into math because you
know like i mentioned you know certain
you know it's it's a thing that
every question has only what uh the
correct answer
okay so let me let me tell you another
thing that's attractive about math
you know math is the eternal thing even
has it even
even when it has almost almost zero
reward you know financial wise or
otherwise
but but you find people you know the
most
intelligent people they just study math
look at that russian you know that
russian mathematician who
won the millennial price one million
dollars he declined
you know he's living with his mom in his
mom's basement mom
can we go buy some eggs you know he's
poor
but he solved the millennial price one
million dollars u.s dollars and he said
no
no i don't want to you are not
qualified to give me a word
that russian guy okay look up i talked
about that
in one of my videos i have a article on
that
where's my articles okay math blog okay
so here is my math blog
you can find uh go back to math
you know so i have you know lots of
articles on math so this median okay
so this guy gregory you know pyramid so
he you know he's a russian mathematician
he declined one million dollars
because you know in math there are a lot
quite a lot
strange people quite a lot not just him
okay
there's also you know quite a lot very
strange and they don't want money they
don't want your money
and and so so there's eternal attraction
you know you attract
math so what so for example let me tell
you
so for example one of the questions we
often ask about you know the mystery of
the universe how big
how big is the universe why are we here
you know what's the ultimate question
you know does god exist is there a god
you know
these questions you know uh although
usually it's answered
in you know in in the in the area of
philosophy
or uh sciences you know a lot of
sciences neuroscience what what is mind
what is consciousness what is the
relationship you know
does a soul exist you know what is the
soul
so these questions you know some are
answered even you know gradually
answered by physics or neuroscience you
study the brain
but all these questions you know how big
the universe you know
you come back to you know when you dig
dig
you can you know one of one way of
asking
these questions is mathematics because
when you when you answer
when you try to answer these questions
inevitably you have to use logic
you know but by the way what is logic
because without logic you don't have
reasoning anymore
without reasoning you don't you know why
are you listening to me where are you
talking what do you know why are you
drinking a cup of water
you know you go to the kitchen you
thirsty you drink what what
how does that work what what's where's
the logic you know
maybe you are thirsty you go to the
kitchen and you drink
and you are still thirsty like without
logic nothing works
but what is logic so what is logic
that that that is the that that is a
the the deepest question in
in in in the universe okay you in one
way to put that
what is logic that is the deepest
question in the in the universe
that question even beyond the size of
the universe the shape of the universe
the age of the universe the where the
god is is that that question is beyond
those questions
what is logic what is the you know so
who studied that question
mathematicians okay or or more
specialized logicians
because you know you know today you know
about haskell they're talking about
proof theory you know the
homo homotopy type theory you know the
haskell people
they mentioned that now and then what is
that that's
study of logic you know when you dive
deep into logic so what
why is logic how does it work you know
that's that's math
so so i get i hope that illustrate
uh the one you know the attraction of
mathematics
uh at least to me okay so
that's the attraction of math
okay so i think that's it for today i
guess that's it for
today so i've been talking for one hour
and five minutes
so let's wrap up five more minutes i
think
okay luis says please uh at least few
minutes of your thoughts about this and
communism
okay luis you are late you asked that on
this code right
yeah so comment so so the question is
please
uh your thoughts about lisp and comment
this as a general programming language
was learning
what's to gain so actually i talked
about that
you know let me show you where to look
for that uh that
because i talked quite a lot you know
few of my videos is dedicated to that
question hold on a second
okay let me copy the url here back to
emacs close
uh keyboard blog close and put that here
shows today's talk show
so common okay common list so you go to
my just go to my website
go to programming go to tutorials are
actually not tutorials you see this one
programming my list console on lisp so
here is the
index of articles i have related to lisp
the programming language
and there are two videos i've done after
more than two
you know the whole entire hour is
talking about this
and programming languages okay so you
probably want to watch these two
uh but i can answer your question okay
so
uh so basic you know this uh
hold on a second let me copy that go
back here paste
uh that that that that okay
so there it is on list okay so basically
least okay the i would recommend
so if you are you know whether you know
your question is whether
is at least still worth learning and
generally my answer is no that's
probably a disappointment because you
i know you probably want to study lists
you have a lot of books on common list
especially common lists you know so if
you are asking me
i would say no it's not worth learning
at all okay
okay if you want to learn this i would
say closure okay
learn closure and you also have might
have a chance for a job
okay now if you are uh trying to learn
this
for maybe intellectual reasons or hobby
then i would say learn racket okay
racket
or skim this okay racket is fun you know
skim this
is part of racket you know
yeah learn racket okay if you are into
programming language design
programming language research that kind
of thing uh
for you know for learning about
programming languages
yeah so racket for intel for hobby
closure if you are into you know maybe
looking for a job
uh and maybe email at least if you are
using emacs
well you know otherwise other than that
emac this
is not useful at all but if you are a
fan of emacs
you know if if emacs is your editor for
life
then it will benefit hugely if you learn
emaclis okay i have a tutorial on that
so otherwise um but in general do i
recommend this
no because today there are so many so
many so many
languages you know if you are studying a
language
for uh as a hobby as a way to learn a
new concept in programming there's quite
a lot
more a lot more uh you know haskell
is common you know popular example
haskell erlang
i'm not even going to mention because
because i talked about this too many
times you know a list of new languages i
have article on that
uh okay proliferation
uh programming languages okay just
search for that
and your this is my article okay
proliferation of programming languages
first of all go back here
and make a link go back to browser
magnify
and here first of all you have this
family throughout history then you have
um
you have mathematica you have a new list
which is another
you know this scripting language you
have oculus you know then you have chi
this long story chili's i designed the
logo by the way
uh which chi this became shen okay you
probably heard of
then you know closure then skim this the
old grand daddy
then you have you know racket then you
have detona and you have uh you know
ml erlang has got concurrent clean
mercury q
oz pearl php uh pearl six
scala group you know so on so on and on
so
so many languages so you you know and
many of them are new
uh which also means they are pretty good
design
okay so if you are into new learning new
concept you know
there are a lot of newer ones then this
it's not it's not like 20 years ago
where uh this is language to learn okay
that's that's my answer about that
oh thank you thank you guys for the
money
and that's it for today i guess
uh tech shivoni keyboard i don't know
what's that keyboard uh i i gotta
okay i think that's it for today one
hour and ten minutes
okay thank you guys for watching
bye guys see you next time