good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today is June
15th 2019 and today we are going to do a
light coating demo first tutorial I'm
going to code goal and I'm going to
write a script that kind of does well
it's a text processing script and the
purpose of the script would be similar
to grab and set or find and replace a
bunch of text files in a directory and
I'm going to do that using Emacs and so
nobody is here yet let me type it out so
people know so today live coding in goal
and doing a find/replace kind of hex
processing script writing okay and using
Emacs and sawfly keys okay that's what
we're gonna do and let me paste it here
okay so we got one guy watching say hi
and let's get started so what we gonna
do what we gonna do is we have this okay
talk-show we have these let me show you
this page let's see if you go to Google
sorry
Monkey King I'm hi guys I'm describing
what we're gonna do so if you go to
Google not Google but if you search for
journey of the West
so search for Journey to the West
there that's the first item here so I
have this web page this web page is a
novel it's a it's a classic Chinese
novel one it's said to be one of the
four greatest Chinese novel and so I
have it here you can see this is bad so
you can see you know it has about 100
chapters and you can see each page you
know is the text and let me show you the
directory so this is the let me go to
the my my home directory here so so this
file if we show in browser you can see
that's a file and here is a directory so
it could you know it's about 200 files
now there's a problem there's a issue I
want to change that is for each chapter
you can see this is chapter 1 and this
is chapter 1 part 2 and this is chapter
chapter 2 you can see the two here means
the chapter number chapter 2 part 1 page
ok then chapter 2 page 2 so for each
chapter let's go to number 5 for each
chapter you have two pages this is first
page then you click here you go to the
second page then if you click Next then
then that's going to be the next chapter
but this is a problem because I don't
want you know I don't want two pages I
want to combine them into one pages it
was two pages because back then 10 years
ago you know the browser is not as
powerful as today so you know short
content is more preferable but so what
we're gonna do is today we're gonna
combine you know go to every page that
is the page two and combine the content
in to pay
one so let me show you it's a mr. since
I'm using Emacs let me start this sawed
command log mod so so that so that you
can see all the commands I'm coding in
Emacs
so let's call star start command log mod
okay now if I move kusa you can see it's
cause this command tired next line in
fact for any command I call it it's
gonna show up on the Left panel so if
you are using Emacs that's a good tip
good thing to know
so anyway we are going to create a :
script that perhaps every page you know
a bunch of files we want to open each
file and the grab part of the content in
that file then put that file to another
corresponding file that that is the what
we are going to do in fact I started to
write this code today you know about
half an hour ago but let's start from
scratch okay so let's go to open a new
file close this and let's say let's name
it save the file as go find replace
let's say go monkey okay don't go so we
have a new buffer new file let me add a
golden template in : every program
basically we will start like these will
have these lines and files
so let's see gay people watching so say
hi let me see so let's do what we're
gonna do so first of all start a comment
ok comment goes go through a least the
you know I'm gonna type out what we're
gonna do
please some files for each file open it
grab part of the content then put that
content into a corresponding file so
first of all let's get the files we want
so now in Emacs we can call this command
tired mark file rejects so we want - -
dot HTML so that lists all the files we
actually want to process in green I mean
in orange here like this so I'm going to
call command
this command is a copy file path so what
we got is all the files we need for
example let's paste it here you see
that's the list of files we want to
process now so first of all we have to
make a file list a variable so this
variable will contain this bunch of file
names but I haven't been coding go line
for a while so let's go up to goal and
this is my goal and tutorial you can
find it by searching sorry :
tutorial and while I code it I also use
it to you know when I code goal and this
is my tutorial it is also
uses my own reference there's a mistake
here yeah okay so so yeah so so golden
reference so right now I want to a I
want a variable that is a array so that
would be slice we want a slice of
strings so let's see string okay this is
a slice so let's go back to the code
our file list file list is going to be a
slice and it's a string and what is the
syntax for the slice I believe it is
that so let's put it here and I have a
command that is code you don't need that
let's add some code lines so quote by
double quote yes each line ends with a
coma
yes so we got that this command is
called Saad if you are using Emacs if
you are a Mac user it's code
some cool lines here and you can find
the source code at this URL if you like
to see it I mean you can you can copy it
for your own use so okay so we got a
bunch of strings and let's move the
directory name part out oops
it's wrong let's move the directory part
part so far
oops
so we just want actually oops
import format and the stream so this is
the directory part
then we have a bunch of files let's now
let's just print them you know to make
sure how code is actually running so
print line and print file list and run
it
syntax error line 15 so let's go to line
15 error because he says done expected
that expecting expression okay so now we
have a problem with a slice data type he
says now what is the problem sighs you
dr. Dillon types literal expression for
slice okay
file list it's a slice type then it's a
stream each element is a string then we
say I don't see anything wrong okay
maybe
this way let's run it
correct so now we fix that so we got a
list here of file names then let's print
here then we got a bunch of lists we got
another directory so let's start do a
for loop we want to go through the list
of files for each one we want to open it
so prints nice what we want to do is we
want to loop through size yes
so you use this syntax for range file
list okay for range this for so this
file list is a slice a slicing colon is
just like a ray except that the length
can be changed so it's similar to
pythons array or Ruby's array so we have
file this is a slice now we need to go
through it and this is the name then the
first part is the index we don't want
let's just say print line file name okay
let's see what happens so we go through
the file list print each file name yes
run it that's good that's what we want
and we can in goal and it comes with a
formatting tool called GOF empty go
format okay so let's let's format our
code because you can see it's not
aligned so go format let's call it good
so now we print the file name now let's
get a directory let's get
full path full path we are equals 2/3 +
filename okay then let's print that run
a code that's correct so now for each
file now we got a full path for each
file full path we want to open the file
so how do you open a file so I go
through my tutorial I forgot read fire
we that's what we want so there so we
need this IO uto copy it
we need the IO utility then library then
this is how you open a file great
everything is what we want so here's the
code formatted read whole file yes and
the the file name the the path will be
that ok we did then my text is the files
content that's good let's try now let's
try to print it let's see can we print
it yes let's try to print let's print
the file so my text okay hold on a
second my text let's say the first 20
bytes the first 10 bytes so 1 to 10
let's say that see let's see if that
works
now each my text is of type type string
the way so we want this substring of the
first 10 points now what is the syntax
for substring so let's see
string functions yeah so we need a : is
: instead of coma so let's try that
donate okay
aro panic no such file or directory okay
why is that oh because we are missing we
are missing the slash for loot pass
route pass so let's run it again okay it
seems to be walking because it is
printing the first ten bytes let's see
one two three four five six seven eight
nine well yeah night the first night
bytes of the each fire and the first
night bytes are always the same because
because if we if we go to monkey you
know if we go to the if we look at the
file each file is a HTML file and we go
to the top each you know the first 10
lines you know the first line is you
know always that so that is correct then
we go into let's see so we we
we are going to so we got yeah so then
we're going to open the file so let's
see how we open the file
yep so let's go back to Golan we want to
open a file yeah we already that's right
we already
oh here now we already open the file
okay so now the next thing we want to do
grab the main content of the file for
example header for example we do not
care for header and footer okay so let's
go through the file and look at point-o
of the file as an example and see you
know which part we want so basically now
we have a string that represents the
file content and it's a huge stream we
only want part of the string for example
this is the chapter so the so we ignore
the beginning until we reached until we
reached let's say men okay and then to
the bottom that men again so we want to
search given a text file you know a big
string we want to search two strings one
of them will be the beginning position
one of them will be the end position and
remove the rest of it that's right so
that is the main content we want so
let's let's try to do that go back to :
the main content will be delivered
native by men and that okay now we want
to grab this pot so keep on a text file
we want to grab part of the string how
do we do that
I don't know so let's look at go line
functions go lines string functions
that's what what we want substring we
want a substring but not by index we
want you know to find the beginning
string and industry join string no embed
expression no stream functions okay
so we need to use the library go string
functions so so here is several examples
of you using the function okay what we
want is not here contains no so we want
to go to the goal golden string function
library so let's go to it search for :
go to the go website and click on
documents oh sorry
should be quickly click on the packages
the packages is basically the
documentation for all the standard
libraries so the way the one we want is
the stream section path and see stream
so all the stream functions is here
you know : the language core itself does
not have much stream function so you
have is like substring string index join
string string length and that's it you
know so for any text processing even
trivial ones you have to use the string
package package strings so first of all
let's go to top add the package import
strings okay so I think I've got I got
for people-watching so if you have a
questions comments opinions write it in
the comment box okay I love to see that
I need anything this is you know I'm
this is a informal this is a talk show
you know I talk talk about random things
usually programmer related nerd stuff
and it's pretty informal so today you
know we are just doing this light
coating of : so we got a giant string
that represents the file and we want to
search certain you know part of the file
and grab it as the that's the main
content we want so so what function
should we use magnify magnify
so string contains okay maybe the
contains last index sub strange
substring bass index any less index page
okay so let's see so the answer should
be
let's see contains and let's see index
you see basically we want the position
the index for the beginning part we want
and we want you know we want to do this
for another string that indicates the
end then we then we want to get the
substring you know grab that part so the
candidate functions are contains
function contains returns a boolean no
that's not we want we need the position
so function index index returns the
index of the first instance of substring
in s that's what we want you know or
negative Y if doesn't exist
okay what about the index any index any
written index the first instance of of
any Unicode code point okay so it so
index any is just like index except you
are only searching a Unicode character
you are not searching a stream and in
the X part is pretty much the same thing
except you give it a bite to such so
what we want is this index function so
let's use that let's see variable main
content a good moenay's cat 44 Catherine
from Australia hi I don't think I have a
female audience before so good morning
so main content will be the main content
so what we're gonna do so we're gonna
get that we're gonna try to get that so
so carefully for our Katherine are you a
programmer are you learning
are you learning or you are experienced
programmer or Emacs user
so let me call the function so how do we
call the function let's see I think it's
like this strange start index we call
the function and the first argument we
is our text so the first argument is my
text it says is a string you want to
search from you know the the file
thus then the second argument is a
string we want to search so we want to
search this string mean okay and it
returns a int so we say start index okay
let's see if that works
print printed start index okay okay so
there is something we are doing wrong
here that is this one so we do not allow
that okay now let's see if it works we
we grab we search the string and when we
find it we you know that's a start index
and we try to print it run it okay
error cannot use my text type bite as
type straining argument okay so colon
has this issue in : a string is as you
know it is technically a sequence of
bytes
you know like different languages they
deal with strings differently you know
in JavaScript as string is a sequence of
two a sequence of pair of bytes two
bytes you know that those are Unicode
sixteen characters anyway so in
JavaScript that's one thing string is
one thing in : a string is a sequence of
bytes you know they are not characters
this is important you know we when you
actually start to code golem you know I
have a detailed explanation here because
so anyway income you know you can read
if you rate up but basically colon in
colon string is a sequence of bytes and
then there are functions to convert the
bytes into a Unicode because for a
Unicode character you know like like an
emoji or or right right arrow you know
oh math math symbols so a Unicode a
character is you know is maybe
represented by two bytes two or more you
know what one to four bytes so in : a
stream string is a sequence of bytes
what happens when you have a Unicode
such as smiley so you know it is
represented by you know three or four
bytes and so there are there are methods
to convert a string to you know as you
know a string sequence of bytes to a
sequence of Unicode characters in Cola
and a Unicode character is coded run you
know that's that's just the term Cola
and invented so there are methods to
convert sequence of bytes to Unicode
characters or into a slice of bytes you
see so so this is interesting so in
colon a string is a sequence of bytes
but also string is not mutable mutable
that mutable that means you know you
cannot every time you change your string
like you take a substring colon will
have to make a entire new string and and
so other way the old one if you don't
use it anymore so every time you create
a string it you know it's a major cost
you know it's Cola has to do lots of
things especially when the string is
very big such as a you know file content
so a colon string is a sequence of bytes
and they are not mutable so because they
are not mutable mutable every time you
change your string go long will have to
create a new string that is slow process
so therefore you know when you want to
change when you want to change the
string frequency such as you know doing
fine and replace so like what we are
doing you better to use a slice of bytes
instead of a string you know slice of
bytes slice is just at least
okay so slice of iced bytes is just a
list of bytes so what's the difference
to a string the only difference is that
when you have a slice abouts you can
change you know you can replace you know
take a substring or you know or cut out
some part of the string things like that
or to finally replace so when you want
to change us
you want to work with a slice of bytes
so there's a there's a way to convert a
string to size of bytes then there's
another representation for string is
that run size run is just a Unicode
character so you know before when we
have a string which is a sequence of
bytes or if we have a slice of bytes you
know each index is actually just a bite
they are not a character you know so
sometimes if you are really working with
file textual content you you know you
want to work with characters instead of
bytes so so in that case you want a run
slice one slice is just a list of nohrin
strange it run is just a unicode
character that's the how : cost cause it
so that is why when you walk in : you
have this three kind of data structure
representation for for a string for text
you know for human text and each one has
advantages and disadvantages and you
know so a string is a sequence of bytes
but they are not mutable every time you
make some changes
you know it's slow then you have slice
by slice which is like a string but you
can change it you know very efficient
then you have run slice which is when
you want to actually deal with each
characters you know for example you want
to find the 99th character you know you
know text file you then the run slice is
most effective so but why do you have
these rivers you know this different one
so why can't you just have one you know
that you know that does demo well
because colon is kind you know it's kind
of low-level language when you want to
program games for example or networking
you want to send networking packets
you're dealing with or video processing
you know video you know you have
sequence of bytes stream you know of
bytes you want to you know you don't
want it to be
you know characters those are not
characters you want the bytes so so this
is one way : solves the problem between
bytes and Unicode characters and it is
very good it is actually a very good
approach on the other hand in Python you
know in Python 3 string is a sequence of
unicode characters but in Python 2
strange the sequence of bytes kind of
like : : so you know it's it's
problematic
you know because many people do not like
the way Python went and ruby has its own
ways so that so this is you know this is
actually critical when you when you
learn :
you know after you learn the syntax this
this part is a very important part you
want to know it very well because string
and bytes they are you know essential
they are essential in any program you
either deal with you know characters you
know text processing or you deal with
the sequence of bytes so let me look at
the content I mean a comment right at
your site some months ago searching info
on algorithmic art oh great fantastic
have found your talk shows has sparked
an interest in programming so cool thank
you thank you for that so yeah let's get
back to the goal goal and so so yeah :
Quran is a good language to learn and
you know it may not be the first
language to learn I mean you know if you
have never programmed before if you
never programmed before : is still a
possibility but but some other
alternatives is Python let's go to
yeah Python Python is pretty good you
know popular choice : is also pretty
good yeah so let's go back to this code
goal and code so I mean how many people
are watching 3 okay so we got so we're
gonna we should speed this up because
because how long we been talking 30 or
40 minutes okay we are not done yet okay
so we try to run the program we got an
error it says cannot use my text byte
type as a string type okay yeah so we
are dealing with this problem this is a
important critical problem in : so
basically we are running into a problem
where when we read the fire when we open
the file in this slide it actually the
result is a byte slice you see when we
let's let's see I run the program you
see it says what I have here is a type
you know bracket byte that means byte
slice at least of you know bite so
sequence of bytes meanwhile this
function string dot index requires a
string type not bytes so okay so this is
kind of an issue in : so that's that's
why it's important to understand it well
and I think so : string I know there it
is index bytes you see so in the :
string library they have a set of
functions almost like each function has
two variations one one takes a yeah one
takes a bite one takes a run and one
takes a string as input so okay so every
function string function has almost like
every one of them has three variations
one of them takes a string as you know
the argument 2nd argument and one of
them takes a bite as a second argument
and one of them takes a run a unicode
character is a second argument all these
are trying to search your string and we
return the index so but our problem is
that we have sequence of bytes but this
function requires a string so we are
using index we are using this function
it requires us
okay so the first argument needs to be a
stream so what we need to do here is
convert convert bytes to stream okay so
let's go back to here string two bytes
slice by slice two strings so that's how
you do it so let's just do that string
that okay let's run it great fantastic
so we got a you know for each file we
got a number this number is the position
where the character the stream main
appears that's what we want then the
second then this is great so it's
working now let's do let's get the end
index
start index and index an extranet great
it's working now we want to take the
substring of these so let's say so this
is when this variable is useful so the
main content equals to equals to my text
my text substring start index and index
okay let's try to print that main
content let's print the first 20 the
first 10 bytes okay vennett fantastic
now it seems to be working but however
we don't know these printing bytes you
know it's a pretty sequence of bytes
these numbers are I think these numbers
are the code point for each byte no they
just represent the byte so our job is
actually to turn this see turn this size
of bytes into a string so let's do that
string then run it great so we just
printed so you know each one shows me
that's a good thing and but actually
let's just print the whole thing and
let's see what happens
yeah print the main content okay it's
all printing out Speights
that's not what we want we wanted to we
wanted to print us strings so again we
are back to the string and bytes issue
so let's go to print string section so
we have a sequence of bytes we want to
print them as strings we don't want to
bring them as you know this small a
bunch of numbers so print one by the in
string print whole string you can so you
can print string as is print with ASCII
so we want to print them as
okay so we need to convert the sequence
of bytes to stream I think
let's run it great this is walking this
is printing all the contents we want
there are a hundred files there
okay it's close it cure it so we got the
main content what's the next thing to do
we want to find now remember in a
directory for each file each file has
two pages you know one and two we want
to put you know we have opened the file
of this second page we want to put it
insert it into the first the files first
page so what we need to do now is we
need to find out the file name for the
corresponding file for page two so here
let's change file name okay let's run it
main content declare and not used
okay let's print the file name oh if you
don't use it then it's you know one of
the issues in Cola is that if you do not
use a variable it will refuse to run it
will refuse to compile they do it this
way so that you know the code will
remain clean if you don't use some
variables if they are not used you know
you have to remove the declaration so
right now here I have been I have
created the start index and end index
for that I'm not using it anywhere so
that is why goal and refuse you know to
compile my code is making a complaint so
we have to use those start index so
let's make that then so we have to use
the index to create the main content but
however we are not using main content
but we have to use it so forth but okay
in that case that's common this lines
out so we are not using the and comment
this line up it's just really now its
face now it says because I'm not using
the library strings so it refuses to
compile so this this is a major
complaint of : a lot people complained
about these because every time you are
when you are doing a prototype you know
experiment then you know you you load a
bunch of libraries but it complains if
you do not use them like right now it's
happening to me
so okay comment out let's run the
program again
my texts declared and not use Oh God so
now I have to comment out the opening
file even so that's not good let's let's
revert it let's let's uncomment them so
we start index and main content let's
say we just print the first one
character of main content okay we don't
care about that really so now we run the
program great the first character of
each file is that correct then this is
the part we want but however the actual
part we want is this one you see yeah
it's the chapter name the first part
before the dash is the chapter number so
for each name we want to get the chapter
number so basically we want to take a
substring so let's do that so this is an
example of a string a substring would be
0 1 2 3 4 0 to 4
okay so substring is 0 to 4 okay
joined it that's correct
that is correct so the next thing we
want to do is
chapter filename chapter filename will
equals to the found in press press that
let's see if that works
okay let's run it
great this is fantastic we we got that
file this is the file we want to open
then insert our main content okay so now
now let's see there's a no now we want
to open the file again so Open File is
that code so we want to open my text -
my hero - and this we want to open this
file and once we opened it we print that
the first ten characters let's do that
my arrow - declared and not used
okay let's use it try it again okay it
works
hi Emmett now we are going to comment
the whole file now we're going to
comment the whole file what do you mean
coming the whole file okay this is
taking long and let's see how many
people are watching this is like getting
lonely and getting boring I think you
know is it like kind of boring to you
guys it would be better you know if if
you know I'm hot you know that there's a
issue with doing live-streaming demo
programming you know like coding because
when you do you know when you do a live
coding if you do not explain like like
when you are at work you know you don't
explain you just do it then then that is
no value to people watching it because
they don't know what you're doing
because it's impossible impossible for
anyone just should look at you your
swing and know what you're doing you
have to kind of explain along the way
but when you explain along the way you
are not actually really doing like
coding because you have to actually
explain lots of things well yeah kind of
you know so
so anyway I think the issue is okay so
anyway so let's keep doing this almost
complete so we got a code I hope in 15
more minutes we're gonna be done okay
we're gonna get get it done
so we have successfully got the file now
we want to add basically all we want to
do now is to insert the main content
into the fire we just opened okay that
is great so we want to insert the text
the main content into the fire we just
opened question where are you going to
insert it okay let's go to so let's go
to let's go through the file let's see
where do we want to insert it we want to
insert so this is a file you can see in
browser we want to insert it at the
bottom because you know remember we are
inserting grabbing the page - you know
append it to the page 1 content so the
bottom will be above this line above
this ads bottom line that's where we
want to insert ok so now now let's go
back to let's go back to the goal and so
we want to grab these strings so again
we have to do some search there so let's
clean up the code a little bit so main
index main decks print main contents we
don't need to print it anymore print
print now it's you know make the whole
thing cream
so Emmet says I mean when we comments
single vas and then their depth in lips
oh now we're going to come in the hole
oh yeah I see what you mean yeah that's
a problem with the goal and you know a
lot of people complain about that
because of because this strictness issue
every time you extract you know you do
prototypes it's a pen so Russ ed I'm ed
says rust has a way to avoid this issue
Oh interesting
you know I don't and I'm not much of a
fan of rust you know even I don't know
rust because well because rust is like
Lola low-level language you know they
they they require you to manage in the
memory like Oh garbage collection you
know they require you to do it manually
I don't like I you know those kind of
languages that those are you know low
level languages so Kathleen says a
appreciate the time thank you
she says I appreciate the time you take
the time to explain the workflow so no
we're gonna do yeah so we are kind of
repeating what we did before so now we
have this file we want to find the
location where this string exists
yes that's what we want so we you know
just like before we almost can just copy
this thing so just like before we copy
it paste it here and my text to so this
is
main content we don't care about main
content actually instead position inside
position is going to be oh now we have a
string which contains the double quote
now that is not allowed so we need to
escape the double quote how do you do
that let's go - oh okay so we just do we
have we can use this tactic so let me
show you what I mean so instead of that
we say back kick like that yeah so now
we don't have to you know add escapes to
the string so anyway so we the inside
position will be this okay
now let's print and see if we got it
right
comment this out Lynnette main content
declared are not used let's let's the
pain again main content let's just say
print
plaintiff first you know don't rain
print the zeroth character yeah so let's
run it again great so we you see it
shows this fire which is the fire we
want to insert and it shows this number
this number is the index where we want
to insert actually actually it is the I
believe it is so let's see so now what
we want to do is that we have my text to
basically we want to insert a stream
into the middle of another stream that's
right we want to insert a string
now insert main content into my text to
add position oops
add position insert that's what we want
to do so how do we do that
so now main content is a sequence of
bytes byte size and inst and my text to
is also a page size so we got a batch
size we want to insert another page size
oh that's easy
okay so in so we go back to the tutorial
and we look at we look at slice so
literal expression print slice create
create slice with make length of slice
take us the slice out of a size a pen -
sighs clear size nested size do through
size so there is no is there is there a
function or method or operation that
inserts a size into another size well
obviously I'm pretty sure
but how do you do that why is it
so any any suggestions any any NGO
programmers so so we got a slice which
is you know like a ray or least we got a
slice of bytes and we have another slice
we want to insert it into the first
slice at a particular position okay so
normally in many languages you call a
function or a method which is usually
you know called the slice you know you
know all the names are similar and
confusing but anyway typically you call
a method yes you call a method you know
function that you know we will insert
size into another size
but we want greater size with make no
length of sighs take a slice of size
that's not you know what we really want
okay we do not see the function so crea
size nested slice okay I don't see the
function here so so that probably means
there is no piolin function because :
because otherwise I would have written a
adhere likely maybe not but because I
know : is rather a low-level language so
sometimes it does not have you know
convenient functions you have to add it
your own in this case you know it's
trivial to write you know a function
that instead size into another part so I
ran out I believe we we don't have that
function building you know we can look
for it you know Stack Overflow but to
save time it's actually easier if we
just write it you know just let's just
do it so okay so the first my text to is
the slice we want to take a slice of it
you know like a sub strange okay
a slice of the size we want to say from
from the beginning to the from the
beginning to the insert position okay so
that's the first part the second part
will be the will be the you know the new
content we want to insert so main
content okay then the last part will be
again we take a slice from insert
position to
to the end position so what is the end
position that would be the length of the
my text that's right so how do you get
the length of a size you use the length
function wait how do you how l en you
know each languages they have their own
thing so okay basically this is the the
new content we want these these three
things these three slices and we need to
join them combine them so there is a how
do you join us rice append
so here's the new content new content
new content equals to append okay append
append a bunch of sizes now can append
the second argument be a slice well in
that case we have to go look at goal and
documentation so you go to packages and
the building functions are documented in
in this weird place but let me show you
Theoden you see this is a funny thing
and a good thing to know if you are
learning all that you know in there this
page is there documentation for all the
packages you know you can find the
package you need and you click it you
know there's a documentation for that
package however there is one thing
special here in this page you'll find
this building
now this build in thing is not actually
a package it's actually just a
convenient place where they document or
the building things in : for example all
these functions are building they are
not packages but however you find this
documentation in the packages you know
section so that's interesting so wait so
in practice so practically what it means
whenever you are you know looking up :
documentation for some building things
such as bar or such as you know for
example if you want to know what you
know why is for in : you can look at is
it here
no advice actually too low-level but you
know for example length is documented
here but anyway so the thing we want to
look for is append here so a pent takes
two arguments
you know like actually infinite number
of arguments so the first thing is a
size the second you know the rest of
arguments are of any type as long as
they are the same type you know it says
here so so that's good so that's that
you know we got what we want to know we
found what we want to know so we got we
want to append three things the first
thing is a slice the second thing is
also slice the last thing is also a
slice that's what we want
let's go format and go format says you
got a problem
it says expected that but found coma so
this is line 165 so here
oh okay so wait
you say oh yeah so you need a call and
instead
so go format again another error the
arrow is lying 165 and it's missing home
missing coma before noon line argument
list okay I think that that's good
you know : here's another thing about :
: technically you require the semicolon
in most of the in most phrases in the
most end of line but however however
colon has a feature that you do not need
to add that because when you have a
newline character : will almost
automatically assume that you have a
semicolon at the end you know it's a
part of the feature of : because so you
don't have to type you know the
semicolon all the time you know tedious
you can just use a new line you know
whatever something something something
and new line you know no no need to
manually type the semicolon but
technically you actually need them you
see I I you know for example I'm adding
semicolon over here adding a semicolon
you know and your men
it will run you know as usual but
however when you Coco format you know
the command the building commando format
which formats your code for you it
removes the semicolon for example you
see nah now let me Coco format okay I
call you see it remove so Mike
semicolons because even though
technically you need the semicolon big
but the convention of go :
you know the convention is that people
who don't
type the semicolon you know so so that's
you know it's you know even easier to
read
you know without all the quarters of
semicolon so that is why when you KOCO
format it it just removes the semicolons
you know for you but however sometimes
it it got confused for example if I have
this thing you know in three lines then
go format got confused it says you know
I need a comma here but actually that's
not the case because this whole thing is
should be considered one line for
example let's see if I can do that
let's try go format again let's see what
happens oh it runs so if you actually
intended then they actually now
understand this is you know but anyway
let's make it one line so new content
will equals to a pen now okay now let's
print let's print out the first file
that let's print out the new content
okay but we don't want to print it here
because then it's gonna print for every
file then it's a huge number of files
but let's print it here so that before
let's do it here like this variable X is
a temp temporary variable let's just say
something okay okay then at the bottom
we say x equals to new content okay
then at the end out of the loop we print
X okay that that works so in this way we
will only print one of the file new
content because otherwise he'll just
keep printing a lot so run it undefined
my text - okay that's because I miss I
need a capitalization my text - okay
where is it oh here
and one more okay run it okay it says
cannot use main content page slice as
type bite in append okay so
so our problem now is to combine several
bite sizes it says we cannot let's try
it try it again what's the error
so he says cannot use bite slice as type
bite in append so that tells us that the
append will only take bite as as its
arguments that's it's not good
oh it should walk because you see this
one
oh if so if you appending slice then you
should walk
so what is saying
so main content what is the main content
main content is a Oh main content is a
stream yeah because wait my text my text
is a pipe slice and main content should
also be is also a by size okay let's get
over this and so we can be done with
this donut you cannot use main content
type bite slice first type bite as type
bite in append so somewhere here it is
assuming
I tie plates to these let's just remove
the last one
and let's run it see what happens
same thing so what is the type of main
content so we want to see what is the
type of main content how do you find out
what type something is in Golan you can
go to print and percentage sign T is the
type
yeah so this how you this is how you do
it
learn it now
which let's comment on how to come and
comment now
okay Lynette okay it's printing this
whole thing this is wrong because I want
to train the tight butt
oh because
let's try this again maybe because i'm
using print lie instead of print
okay let's try this that's correct so
you see this line square bracket uint8
that means it's a bite slice because in
:
the uint8 means a bite it's a it's on
areas to abide so if you go to here and
you see basic types so we have int 8
here then you have uint8 here so
basically that just means a bite so the
type of main content is a base slice
because you know so the type of main
content is a bite size then why is is
not working append
cannot use main contents cannot use main
content type by size as type bite in a
pen so the paint function assumed how
the second argument has bite type but
why is that
does anyone know
we whoops where did it go
append packages strains building
the OD'ing obtained
I don't know why why it's not working
but let's just try to make this into a
string maybe that helps you know let's
see what happens donate so nowadays
cannot use string main contents can I
use stream main content as type string
well can I use stream main content of
type string as type fight in your paint
yeah so the paint function this the
second argument
it keeps assuming that we are using bite
but we are not using bite man hey
Gabriel how are you I'm doing great
thank you yeah I found out I noticed who
you are on Twitter the other day sir so
do you know Golan are you new too : oh
so we are coding this problem and right
now we have a problem of with the append
function you know basically what we want
to do is to we basically we want to join
three three slice of bites you know just
join three slices and we try to use the
append function so how do you do this so
so we keep running into problems so ra6
says i'm new to go only know about the
basics okay
same here
so KS cannot use main content type
string as type biting a pen okay so how
do you join how do you join a slice we
want to join a bunch of sizes print size
line by line
grace eyes with make okay length of size
takes slice of slice append to size so
building function of hand okay
Korea's rice create nested size with
make loop through size so definitely the
answer lies in append that's the
function we want to use
oh ok so we need three thoughts that's
right I know these these three thoughts
are actually an operator if I recall
correctly I might be mistaken but I'm
pretty sure so let's try it again okay
let's you know let's try this comment
this out and instead of that we don't
need or we have to do is give it three
thoughts you know because the append the
second argument to append really must be
bite it doesn't want slices he wants a
bite you know you can have many
arguments they all must be bite so now
you so our main content is a slice it's
not a bite it's a slice of bites so we
want to pass this into the paint but we
need these three dots to make it into a
you know a bunch of arguments so let's
run it that's successful it says new
content declare they're not used that's
good finally so so that's good now we go
back to our original here we want to you
know we are want to make all these three
dots dot dot and
and here too dot dot dot okay vennett
unexpected but this is confusing
oh can you do that okay I know what's
going on
so actually what we need to do it can
append when you use this it can only be
done once yeah so so new content new
content this probably something like
that
so comment this out so new content
equals to that then we want to append
new content again by that let's see that
is correct I think that's it correct
it's running ooh
it seems good it sounds good
now let's print the content shall we
it's let's get back to the printed run
it
okay cannot use new content because type
spice spice as types training or
assignment okay that's easy to fix
so X is a string so now we just turn it
into a string great fantastic it seems
like it's working now let is let us
double check let us double check and
when maybe when this is correct
we shall shall call it a day so let me
read the comments Michael and why go
line is great but what does three
thoughts me is they like convert type
too tight no it's not convert type 2
type 3 thoughts means you want to for
example if you have is let's say any
language let's say bar equals to bar
list equals to something 3 4 5 ok now
let's say you have a function f okay and
it takes three arguments X Y Z okay
equals to something okay now this
function takes three arguments X Y Z
now you want to code a function with the
content of the least three four five but
however you don't have you know that the
problem now is is that you want to pass
this you know away this list kind of
thing
into the function but the function
doesn't take a list the function needs
the arguments by itself so how do you do
that this is a common problem so in some
languages you can say in : for example
that's what you say you know you give a
variable name then you put three dots
that kind of put you know that it
sometimes it said slice or surprise you
know the the list into the arguments and
in JavaScript in JavaScript you have to
put the three dots before you know and
each one works differently you know
JavaScript in a case of JavaScript the
list is considered an iterable anyway so
that is what the three dots is is for so
now we seems to be successful and what
we did is that we have printed out the
new content now all we have to do is to
double check if this is new content is
correct so how do we do that you know
you go to here you can see this is
correct because you know I know you see
these two lines are repeated at bottom
why they are repeated because I know one
of them came from the second file while
the other one is already you know
originally in the first file remember in
the first file we we searched for this
position we say we want to add it before
these so that's why you know so from
here and the perb is from the second
file so if we go up and look at
so yeah so we are sure this is correct
this is correct now the last step this
the last step is to write out this new
content into the into our file you know
original file so let's just do that and
you know it should be done yeah so so
let's do that
and it will be done for today maybe 17
minutes so far we have talked about or
ninety minutes
yeah this takes a long time you know if
if I've been working with Golan a lot
then you know todavía will be much
smoother you know but I'm they're just
doing this for fun you know that
exploration and all these frustrations
is part of part of the ship so yeah we
know we want to write to fire so how do
you do that so I go to my my tutorial
which we function as a notes for myself
so here is how you write to file content
okay you want to create a file first
then that's how you write to fire okay
so let's copy that
okay here's another example
so basically they are there is this
library OS and you can use write stream
so you have to do OS create then OS
create it returns a file object and this
file object has a method named write
string so you use always start create to
create a path it returns a file object
then the file object has a right to
string method then that's how you write
to a file that's one way now let's
totally look at the other way so in this
case in a in this example we need to use
IO IO uto so in this way you write to
file by by this way okay let's use this
method because I prefer this seems to be
a simpler method so we need this library
go to the top of the file then we need
the library here
okay then we need to use this function
to write to file go has lots of error
checking you must have that otherwise
you won't compile so that is also a
common complaint about : so here we have
the right to file code so I owe you t or
right file and this is the path we want
to write it to we want to write it to
plus let's just say xx test okay let's
let's just say for now okay so every
time we just write to that file
repeatedly you know just for now we're
gonna fix it later
so the TT will be the pipe slice you
want to write to in this case it will be
new content and the write the create
file mod the UNIX file permission mod is
zero six four four okay come on in
George okay let's see if that runs go
format run it okay I owe you - we
declared as imported okay that's another
pane okay all right yeah we already
declared that okay
run it again yay looks like it's working
fantastic now all we have to do is just
to go to the directory then look at the
file there look at the file is this the
one
yep so instead of this we're gonna do
one more thing two more minutes so
instead so the file name will be
directory plus we have a file name here
somewhere the current file name let's
search for name okay here yeah
so chapter file name let's do this okay
so let's do this
huh now second it's
so directory X underscore there in
Chapter file name then HTML dot HTML
okay that's what we want this we should
create one new file for each of these
let's see if it works
run it please free space it's spinning
this we don't need
let's see oh it looks like we failed all
the files a week we've succeeded you see
all these new files are the new files
you see yeah that that is correct all
these files let's try to open one of
them chapter four yep
this is chapter four Chinese chapter
four so in this chapter four okay
actually it's correct you can see this
is the second page content you know have
added to the first page content now it
appears like that because we had we have
because you can see if I can show you
here you see because we remember we
added from starting of the main tag we
actually should have not included that
and also we shouldn't have included that
but you know we have you know that's
essentially it's it's what we wanted you
know these these are just minor things
we have to tweak the code so actually
that so I think that's covers it you
know we you know basically that's what
we set out to do and we have finished it
you know it's not very refined but we
spent ninety minutes you know the you
know I'm just gonna clean the code and
that would be you know for myself so you
know
so thank you guys for watching have a
good day I hope you liked : : is now my
favorite language you know it's Cola is
a great language it's my favorite
because you know I have you know quite a
few my favorite would be Mathematica but
in general :
I like : a lot is because it's extremely
simple very simple I mean among all the
languages among Python JavaScript C C++
C sharp you know among all of them : is
one of the simplest one okay so if you
are a beginner : is a good choice Python
Ruby PHP they are actually your good
choices okay I like : okay : is but : is
almost the simplest among them that's
one thing that's one reason the other
reason is I : is industrial it's you
know hugely popular it's created by
Google of course and it's it's
industrial language so if you you know
want to work for some company you know
doing : you can easily find a job you
know if you know provided you actually
you know you have to learn : of course
you have to be you know good you know
spent you know you know to to study : so
: is industrial language now this is
different from some other languages
where it's a niche for example this you
know has cow even it's kind of a bit
niche so : is very popular widely used
and it's and also the third reason is
that : is a very powerful modern
language you know it's created like only
10 years ago all the other languages are
you know 20 years ago you know Python is
like 30 years old almost Python Perl
Ruby I'm almost 30 years old
yeah thirty actually 31 it's something
you know and CC press first those are
even older so golden is a modern it's
only like ten years old you know as far
as foreign languages goes in general as
far as technology goes anything related
to technology such as your cell phone or
computer laptop the late later the
better okay so yeah so I like goal and
and I hope you like it and you know you
know try to check out my goal and
tutorial just go to Saudi :
thank you for watching see you next time