welcome welcome
okay sorry about that good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh first of all we are going to do a
demonstration of live coding JavaScript
okay I'm like I'm alive like alive is
good not alive he's no good
okay is that true yes well not
necessarily because if you are dead then
you are dead there is no good and bad
anymore so so today's our talk show yeah
I'm going to do this I'm going to do
this i j k l okay let's go to this page
and let's copy the URL and i'm going to
so yes yesterday two days ago we did
this live code in javascript of web
application like these this application
is for interactive vim hjkl versus ijkl
efficiency calculator so you know we are
trying to find out which key binding
either the vim or inverted T is more
efficient for example I can change in
the number here and you can see a number
updated here
but now let's enhance it what I want to
do is like I put the mouse here and I
can scroll up or scroll down and that
number will change you know so this way
it's easier for people to change you
know one of the input parameter and see
the update in real time so that's what
we are going to do first and as usual if
you are here if you are watching let's
see if you are watching please
type any comment in opinions in the box
here okay and also let's see also copy
this file path okay hold on let's start
command log mod ok copy these file path
split the buffer new buffer paste so
that's the local file path and change it
to a URL you see and I say post pick a
topic and the type in comment box okay
copy that back to Chrome browser and
let's put it here so you can see you can
go to that link and type any comments
any opinions of what I whatever I'm
talking about and oh just go to that
page and pick any topic you find
interesting and we will talk about that
but so first of all it's code let's code
this javascript thing okay now if you
don't know JavaScript if you are curious
about how web application are done you
can check out my previous video but
today we're going we are going to
enhance it the code so let's go to the
page let's begin let's see him so so
this is the page okay I mean well this
is the page okay
and here is my local copy of the page
and you can see let's search for da GS
so here is the JavaScript code let's
open it let me put this window up here
so so this window shows all the Emacs
command I call so if you are Emacs user
it's a useful thing to learn you can see
whenever you don't know what I'm doing
like you are wondering how did I do it
you can look at the command you show the
command
my keys the keys are used and you can
search the web and you'll find the code
so ok so here is the JavaScript code you
can see and also so it's only 60 line
lines okay it's so it's very simple and
in fact this code is is kind of the
fundamental the the the core of how you
code web applications
it contains basically all the essential
things for example first of all you
select the element then okay so this
this Potter you select elements you know
the elements are the HTML stuff such as
the input box okay
then over here is the body you know the
kind of the code body okay what you want
to do and then you add event like this
you add event so adding event means that
whenever this is changed for example
let's change it to 10 and notice here
okay your change let's say change it to
99 so if I key is you know value 99 and
you can see the update score so yeah so
this is the fundamental it contains kind
of the fundamental elements of how do
you write the web application without
any framework okay I'm coding my my
style of JavaScript is without any
framework or library of course I mean
when you write a huge application then
it's kind of necessary but for simple
ones you don't need you don't need
jQuery you don't need react you don't
need view you don't need any of those
okay and in fact you you must learn this
because if you really want to master
JavaScript and web application
programming because you know what do you
think all those jQuery libraries or
react what do you think you know how
they do their stuff they they they you
know you
you locate the code of course they do
like you know what I'm doing here and if
you are interested in learning
JavaScript sorry
so search for JavaScript in depth so I
have written this tutorial I have spent
two years to write it so here's a my
JavaScript in-depth tutorial and the and
this page is basically teach you the
JavaScript the language ok the language
in detail in depth pure JavaScript then
you go to here that's when you start to
learn how to write web applications so
yeah so to write to you know to code web
applications they are to basically you
can say there are two essential parts
one is the mastery or you know
understand JavaScript the language okay
then you need to understand a so-called
Dom okay
it stands for document object model
anyway it's just web scraping scripting
so this is how you create web
applications basically all including
actually including games that's how you
do it of course if you write a web game
you know that you use lots of libraries
you know other stuff but but what I'm
teaching you here on this page for
example is the core technology
fundamentally how they work according to
the spec you know so you know for
example you know for example let's say
change CSS how do you for example I can
click here and the text become red I
click here it becomes blue how do you do
that here's a code you know it covers
the fundamental things you need to know
you can change you know the color the
style you know that's all CSS and there
are other things you know change the not
content for example this one I click
here
it changes the text you know question
answer you know so did you know so here
are some basic examples and then you can
learn it if you are new to JavaScript
with web scripting so but today we are
going to cover so that's my tutorial you
can but okay you if you like my stuff
you can buy it you know I sell this
tutorial for for like thirty thirty
dollars $29 it's available online as
well but you know if you like my work
you know give me some money
and also it's it function as a
commitment you know if you really want
to learn the stuff yeah so let me so
today we are going to modify this code
we have written so that when the mouse
is here you I can just go up and down
you know use the mouse button and the
value will change that's very convenient
okay so let's do it okay so what we want
to do so first okay so move mouse up
down so that means I need to add an
event to to these boxes
so basically okay for example here okay
let's go here first of all first of all
make a backup copy and paste it here
then we need to so this is box I box I
is this box we're gonna work on this box
first and we want to add an event
basically mouse scroll event so that
mouse squirrels will change the value so
what is the event name for mouth
squirrel we can find it out by let's go
to my JavaScript tutorial
so let's open a new tab dumb scripting
tutorial and it's search for event add
remove event handler okay then I have a
link to all the possible events
now that's such mouse okay so here's a
bunch of Mouse events we want to wheel
okay wheel button a very pointing device
is rotated in any direction so that
looks like the event name we want to use
okay select that I mean go there and
let's see the wheel event fires when the
user rotates a wheel button only
pointing device that's good okay so the
event name will be real okay so when
that happens we want to when that
happens so this is a function to call so
if we call print it which is this
function here this function
okay there's one more thing we need to
check because if if we go here if we you
know we want we want the event had to
happen only when these input box is in
focus you see the you see it's
highlighted because otherwise people you
know squirrel you know you you still
want through a lot of people to scroll a
page it's only when this input box is in
focus we want to do that so actually so
the function we want to call is let's
say update input let's just say that
okay and we need to write a function
let's see where we want it so constant
arrow okay it's hold on show the window
constant arrow function okay update
input so we are creating a new function
and the the function will not take any
arguments and the function will okay
so the function will check which one is
the current input box in focus then get
that input box value then increment it
by 1
you know if the mouse is scrolling up
then update the the value then printed
printed is actually you know update the
score over here so that's what we want
to do so let's see
check current input box in focus then
[Music]
but is increment by 1 0 1 or 1 depending
on which box it is ok so for these boxes
increment by one okay so anyway so
increment by 1 or 0 1 then change the
value then we might want to call printed
actually
yeah so this way your walk but but I'm
wondering if it's change occur an input
box in focus if we do it this way then
that means whenever there is no focus
when people squirrel because whenever
people scope squirrel it's going to call
this function repeatedly you know and
I'm kind of thinking it may not be
efficient because when the input box is
not in focus people scroll all the time
so you you are going to you are calling
that compunction all the time so if so
this may not be efficient it may be is
there a way to to only check when the
input box is in focus
yeah we can do that but it's getting
more is that would be more code more
complicated but for now you know since
we are this is pretty simple we are just
doing a prototype so let's just go with
this so check update input okay so now
the question is how do you find how do
you find which input box is in focus
okay I have to think I have to think
about that let's see one guy watching
okay so input box so let's see mouse
wheel
so how do you find out which input box
is in currently in focus now these are
events now there is a focus event so we
can add a event such that when a input
box is in focus then we set a variable
that tells us whether something is in
focus you know when it's out of focus we
we said another we set up two events one
is in focus when it's out of focus so
when something is in focus so we always
know when one of these input boxes is in
focus we can you know set set a state
you know to a variable so we know when
when you a box is in focus
then when the mouse events go happens
then we check the variable to see if
it's in focus if it's not then do
nothing if it is in focus then we
increment the value so that's one way to
do it the other way is to you know so so
that way so the way we just talked about
is first of all we we create events to
to check whenever something is in focus
or out of focus okay that's one way you
you you need some kind of you know you
so you have to do this check but I'm
thinking so another way is to when you
when mouse wheel squirrels you you Auto
you you try to find out which if any one
of these input boxes is in focus
so yeah so we have these two two ways
yeah I so actually I'm not sure which
way to go so box is in focus okay I have
written some to talk I mean I have
written some other applications before
so let's check if sorry
programming languages and it's machine
what house map okay so let me try to
find out
so I'm not sure which page is it so
let's go to let's try to find out SVG is
a web dev tutorials web design
validation history okay I know where so
you to go to sorry dot info go to
programming there on the side box you
have tech review and this page is all
topics related to technology they are
essays about technology you know
commentaries
so this is these pages about how fast
the internet speed grow
okay so I don't know where is that code
so another way to find out is simply go
to my home directory go go to CD comp
okay then just find all files that
contains JavaScript okay and 24 hours
watch binary converter computer language
char distribution unicode such okay so
let's go back to web I think maybe it's
there okay go back to JavaScript
directory then we try to find it out
okay so lots of JavaScript code here
basically basically I'm trying to find
find a web page kind of a web
application I have created before that
shows a word son Matt and showing and
wherever there is a internet usage it
shows a dot and around the clock in 24
hours so so you know as time time ticks
you know does the Sun moves around you
you have you you might have seen a Sun
crock and you can see all the it's a
world map and you see a bunch of lights
lights up in that area that means
there's an internet usage so from this
world map you can see when is internet
you know most active in which region in
a world but right now I'm trying to find
where is that page I forgot what's the
name their internet usage they cycle
okay so it's in the W directory so let's
go to the directory Internet you there
it is so this is a page now copy the URL
back to Chrome browser paste it let's go
there there it is
so let's magnify so you can see this is
the map I can click the you know each
start represent Internet usage and red
means heavy usage blue means no you see
usage and you can click or you can press
the arrow key and you can see how they
shipped you know so so this is stay
light this is night so you can see when
USA for example New York is around noon
it's the has the most users internet is
the most like active there as we shift
you know to meet
for example it's least it became blue
basically around four or five o'clock
New York time it becomes you know this
usage they start to increase because of
the morning so from this application you
can see you can observe you know when is
internet the most busy for local time in
the local area
in fact it's different for example in
USA in general the internet is most busy
around noon ok actually is the most busy
around but however in China for example
the for example let's look at over here
near Shanghai or Beijing you can see
Internet is actually most active around
like you know it's already here it's
around like five was around six six okay
five o'clock local time after noon so
depending on the region you know they
are internet usage pattern is different
in USA is around noon it's the most busy
but in China it's around five o'clock
p.m. evening so anyway so you have I
have this web application you can also
use the mouse like I'm use I'm pressing
the I'm scrolling the mouse wheel so
this way gives me you know interactive
animation almost you know it's an
animation so how did I do it I forgot so
let's see so I mean obviously there's a
mouse wheel event but this mouse wheel
event only works when when my mouse is
in the region of the image map of the
image but not outside so that that is
actually kind of similar to what we want
to do so let's look at you know what
I've done before and so here's a code
let's open it let's go to a directory
okay so originally it's
in typescript so this is typescript by
the way typescript is a hundred percent
compatible to JavaScript so any
JavaScript is a typescript but here but
but then typescript adds type
declarations so you know but even if so
so so in this page I'm not using any of
that it's actually just plain types
plain JavaScript but however I'm using
typescript is so because I can convert
the JavaScript 2015 features back to the
you know plain JavaScript so this this
fire is a typescript but if you go if
you look at the directory you see this
file is JavaScript this is actually
compiled you can see it's using bars
here now Val vaz is kind of deprecated
JavaScript it's got lots of problems and
it's using the good old function keyword
to create a function but starting with
JavaScript 2015 you have a bunch of new
features such as arrow function like
this one you know you know F psycho
image you have you know the parameters
and you have the function body you know
which is which is similar to the you
know the in JavaScript es5 that's the
way you do it so anyway you see so
typescript compiles to this JavaScript
and this is like the last time I did
this is 2007 when JavaScript es 2015 is
not widely used yet and but today let's
convert it actually let's just converted
to years 2015 so I have to do is I just
run a code
so I just run cassava and current file
and you see it actually update it be
compiled and updated this page you see
now it's actually using javascript 2015
and now if we go back to here and see if
it still works reload the button still
works okay and arrow keys also still
works and the mouse wheel still works
that's good so anyway so we are here
because we want to find out how do we do
the mouse square-mile also search for
wheel you can see you can see this is
the event wheel the image tag Oh obvious
that's right oh yeah so you add the
wheel event to to the image so this
image is an element HTML element you
simply add event to that element that's
how you do it
yeah the obviously I didn't think of
that so here so we back to back here we
all we want to do is yeah we are doing
that actually we are doing a right thing
at a wheel you event then call the
function update input then the update
input will
okay but how do you check if the wheel
is moving upward or downward so that's
such the function there it is so this is
how you do it
so let's copy the code we are doing like
copy and paste which is the most
efficient way of coding actually so copy
that code and then let's put it here
let's remove that put it here
search for that we need to change the
function name but actually let's just
use this name so change that okay so
when the mask wheel turns we call this
function and this function will check
current in input box so okay so when
when it's rolling up it's when scrolling
up Delta y greater than zero when
scrolling up we want to increment by 0.1
okay so okay so we want to increment so
prevent default so default is the
scrolling page behavior we want to
prevent that when we want then we want
to increment
okay so let's increment the value here
so let's see let's go down let's go down
box i sub box i
box I value equals to actually we can do
prospers
I think prospers is a JavaScript now we
want to so okay
equal plus I think we can use equal plus
now let's look at my JavaScript tutorial
we want to check if JavaScript has the
operator of equal plus or plus equal so
assignment operators plus equal okay so
we can do that first equal zero point
one okay and same thing here will be
minus equal okay so that will update the
value but
let's change the function name
okay so this is for the box
kiai
okay so I think that's it let's go to
the page and see if that works
refresh oh it worked but not so well
refresh incoming okay so it is not
working so well because box I value
press equals two
so what happens here is two guys
watching so what happens here is okay so
when the mouse we are squirrels then
this event fires so the mouse wheel
squirrels then these event fires then if
it's scrolling up then box I dot value
is updated let's let's just do this okay
let's not be fancy I don't like those
fancy stuff so same thing here okay
so bucks I value equals two bucks I
value so it changed now when it changed
we have another event here input when it
changed it also starts to call the
printed command which which start to
compute the whole thing so why is this
let's scroll down
refresh
what is the value there
okay so wait so it's changing the box
value but when the box value changes it
also tries to print it
okay so let's check let's open up the
console and see what happens in a
console
hey good morning Frank
first - one cup first minor and scare it
down by ten what do you mean scale it so
why not press all - one good evening so
so why do you want to scare that I mean
why can't I mean what's the advantage of
that I mean we can just add zero point
one directly why you need to you know
use one and scale down so anyway so
there is something wrong here it says
you know we are getting none is it
because it's a stream that we okay yeah
I think it's because it's a stream it's
yeah that's what I'm yeah so box I dot
value is actually a stream so we need to
turn this to a number actually I think
that's that's what what's happening how
do I know because you know when you code
any programming language or any
programming tasks
you just have to gain experiences
because I mean how could how could I
possibly know you know that's the case I
guess it's you know it is just from
experience so let's look for we want to
now we want to convert a number to a
string and I have a tutorial here number
random number string - number let's see
string - number a number two stream we
want to string two number yeah so string
two integer string two decimal number so
that is number dot pass float
you know javascript is pretty bad anyway
number parsefloat okay so that's a
function
and that's the function and we want to
convert so we convert let's see let's
correct syntax pass float stream yeah
yep so we converted the string to a
number then we add yes so let's try that
okay not back to the web page and
refresh refresh now let's see if this
works okay now focus it screw the mouse
yeah it's working so but however now
scrolling up scrolling up is is actually
decreasing so actually we got this
reversed so we once go up you know the
thing about scrolling up and down is
that there is a lot of inconsistency
today yes because Apple especially
because Apple started to reverse the
mouse direction well this is actually a
very old problem and I remember back in
night 1990s because when you scroll up
if you are thinking of a coozer
you want the cruiser to move up but if
you are thinking of the page when you
scroll up you are actually moving the
page down
so depending on how you think you know
scope scrolling up may mean you know
different directions because I remember
back then in 1991 for example different
applications disagree so so well back
then you don't have mouse but but you
still have page up and page down for
example the page up and page down key so
some application when you press page up
it's actually moving the page
you know today when you press page up
it's actually moving the page down you
know so so and you can see the same
Emacs for example if I call the function
if I press the page up key it's actually
calling the command scroll down command
so you see because you are actually
scrolling the page you know down when
you press page up you you want to see
things above it but you are so you are
actually scrolling page down so they are
you know this is confusing confusing
different concept of up and down and
also Apple made it more confusing about
10 years ago when they reversed the
mouse wheel direction so that it's in
sync with touchpad you know like when
touch with a touchpad or iPhone you know
when you when you push down you know
touch push down it actually you know is
you are pushing the page not your kusa
physician so so you know that makes more
sense
so anyway so let's go back so actually
now this is working let's see yep
let's see but however it's not updating
the it's not updating the score but why
is that
okay yeah because this is just a real
event so we actually need to call print
it here
so print it now let's refresh try it
again
yeah it's working so so you see if we
yeah so it's working great now we just
repeat we just need to repeat this for
all the other boxes so so let's see how
many people watching three people three
three is the second prime number
okay so let's repeat these boxes so box
i j k l what are other boxes hi j k l h
i j k l h and mouse okay we're going to
write five more functions so are we
going to just use this function okay so
you know the simplest is actually just
write five more functions but actually
you know then we refactor to combine
them into one function but you know four
brainless nests it's actually just
easier if I just create oh we all we can
pass the parameter actually the
parameter is not used here so but it but
you know it's faster if we just do five
more for now
one two three four five so hi Jay Jay
Jay okay Jay Jay okay
hi JKL okay then I'd say KL edge okay we
got five functions and hi j KL edge good
Moni Isaac so Isaac we are doing
JavaScript oops we got got a hero so
basically we are enhancing this page to
add scope wheel interactivity so I want
to scroll the wheel on this box and have
the value change and update this number
and right now I got a problem
he says f maaske i is not defined so
okay why is it not defined hi box a box
J Box Camus key
so it says because he said because we
didn't refresh F mouse key I our
reference X is not defined yeah
oh you need the X okay so let's do that
X yes no no no okay so let's replace
that by X yes yes yes yes okay
yes it worked and see yes yes superb now
we don't want the you know you see it
becomes sometimes it becomes zero point
three zero zero you know extra extra
digits there so what we can do is
actually we can trim out the the numbers
because it's ugly you know to show you
know to have it become like that so we
can trim it out by using number pass
floats so this is a number prototype we
go to a number prototype there is a
function called two fixed okay and we
want one digit okay two fixed so let's
at that pass float okay okay so this is
getting long to fixed okay to fixed one
digit okay that's
okay we we definitely need to refactor
these now because now the code is
becoming too long to fix one digit okay
but let's try that first let's try with
this box so let's magnify so you can see
it now is Jia hum
bauxite value so box I value so to fixed
actually what we need to do is actually
to convert you see this part is a number
and when you assign your number the box
I dot value is actually a string so we
are actually we need to convert a number
to a stream and it is in this process
that these zero zero crops are you see
those crops up so if we want to
eliminate those extra zeros we have to
do the conversion ourselves because
javascript is actually doing a number
two string conversion automatically so
so we want to convert it ourselves
the the to fix function is actually
converting numbers you know so so you
know the string and number conversion is
usually very fairly complex complicated
in any language so okay so what we want
to do format number and see format
number show only show only n significant
digits so all these are so these are
number two number this is also number
two number oh wait this is number two
string oh yeah that's what we want to
precision so okay to precision
okay one two two
- precision - let's see if that works
No
so to precision to precision returns a
string representation of number with n
significant digits
so let's see compute skull okay here
actually we want to precision as well to
precision three
good morning Daniel so okay so we are
still having a problem of these two
precision so why is that
so number Pass floats so box.i
value is a box I dot value is a string
yes because it's an input box this is
actually returns a string then pass
float becomes a number wait so so box I
dot value is a stream then we turn it
into a number here because we are
calling a number pass float so it
becomes a number then we minus 0.1 okay
and so far it's your number then we do
to precision oh wait is that because of
that yes obviously
refresh
okay we have failed so anyway so so but
I mean I'll go it's actually working but
however we are trying to make it look
nice without you know the extra digits
we only want to we only want one decimal
place and in that regard we it is not
working but why is it not working
working I don't know so but I think it's
because of the number two string
conversion that's going on that's why
it's not working so this is a float so
this is the float
so this is a number then to precision
makes it a string we sure to precision
returns a string representation of a
number
yeah returns a string representation of
a number but and and a string
representation so so this so this part
becomes a string so we assign box I
value to a string but oh okay we got a
mistake here yeah that's a mistake that
is why refresh
okay so happens refresh
to position one let's say to peach
precision one
let's see printed printed really printed
this this is Emacs 26 bug you see how
the buffer suddenly part of it becomes
blank
that's a Emacs 26 bug
yeah I don't know what's going on so
maybe we it's yeah I'd so I don't know
what's going on and you know but you
know you get idea what we are trying to
do we actually it's successful but you
just these appearances you know
aesthetics we want to fix and we have to
figure out I'm pretty sure it's
something has to do with the string and
number data type conversion issue that's
going on way yeah we try to fix it here
but it's not successful
yeah so but anyway so how long we've
been talking so one hour in one minute I
think that's it for for this one I guess
so yeah so what's up you guys that's it
for this one today we're gonna you know
I think maybe in six hours or maybe
eight hours we're gonna do another one
because recently I've been trying you
know first of all yeah so let's just
chat you know a little bit so first of
all so as far as today's topic you know
that that's kind of done but so it's
this just chat so you know first of all
I want to do a video every day it's like
the spice must flow you know have you
guys watched that the the movie the or
the novelty oh sorry
Dhoom series okay doom is an epic it's
truly an epic novel it's an epic story
you know epics means during TV series
you know epic is a whenever you have a
novel epic is is Frank Herbert's dune
yeah you know it means it spans several
generations or centuries a story that
turning turning a history you know you
have thousands of characters you know
you cover a spam a period of time you
know hundred years or thousands of years
that's epic when you have something like
that so doing the novel doing is novel
is it's a grand fantastic novel I
haven't read the novel myself but
actually I have watched these dune
miniseries they are a lot you know
movies out of it but I want to show you
this one
I have written about actually excites I
cannot find it
but but anyway this this is the one this
is the cover is right so it's it's now
that not that video gallery so there's a
movie doom
directed by David something David Ben
Lynch I think and that is no good
okay but there is a TV series around
2000 around year 2000 and that is very
good you want to watch that one
amazon.com
so this one do
sometimes you can find it on YouTube
three you know people yeah it's actually
on YouTube the whole thing because a lot
of people you know copy and just put it
there and it's a mini TV series so it's
it's like few hours three or six hours
but doom but anyway so I watched this
and I studied I read up about this story
it's just fantastic it's great I mean so
it's so deep and you know you can be you
can it's actually it's like a game of
throne epic in the same epic senses so
it's got vast history you know families
map and details the difference is that
game of throne is about you know you
have dragons you have you know in that
period of time dragons and knights but
doing is about it's a sci-fi you know
future so this is fantastic a wreck I
highly recommended not the movie but in
this TV series so have you guys seen it
so during TV series so why am i
mentioning because I was talking about
yeah the spice must flow so that's one
of the phrase into so
so you guys still there okay two people
watching most people are already gun
Frank Rowland
so where are you wait no no second where
are you where are you from Frank what
what location
so okay that's that's it for today and
you're we gonna we may be probably out
do another possibly likely another one
in about 600 eight hours okay thank you
guys for watching I'll see you