it's wrong there I don't know what is
the problem the points are too big so
let's shrink the radio size and let's
define radius let's say that radius
equals to 0.1 and say so okay okay so
this is incorrect something is wrong
with it
okay I think I got a YouTube poppin chat
disconnected live stream health good
your viewers are happy okay viewers may
be experiencing minor issues and
got a problem
so regards so that's so dot radios okay
let's continue it's just trying to
finish this
Todd radius now why are they creating
this kind of weird thing that doesn't
look right
so where is our math function what is
our math function the math function the
math math function is T squared that's
right T squared oh oh yeah because in
JavaScript that is the syntax is wrong
you you won the power should be to
asterisk not not the Hat side the Hat
sign is some kind of integer with bit
shifting so let's try okay now it looks
great fantastic finally my the fruit of
our work so now let's try to fix
something else okay so so now if we say
T times two it should all work well
great now it now let's see let's try
sign okay math dot sign
okay let's see what happens
fantastic so you see now because we
fixed this coordinate problems to
automate automatically find the xmin
xmax and why me why max of the data
then create the SVG canvas with the
coordinates such that the end points are
that you know xmin xmax ymin ymax so our
graph shows nicely here so that is a
good thing now so this this is
significant because now we can change
our function to arbitrary things let's
say let's say x squared okay so let's
change it to x squared minus x first 10
okay arbitrary function it's a
polynomial x squared minus X plus 10
refresh okay so what oh we didn't save
save it
refresh reference arrow egg X is not
defined what oh it needs to be T naught
X T okay refresh okay that's kind of
good now let's go to the negative part
as well so let's see
wait- Y the canvas does not start from
here
I mean there is no data to the left side
of it so there is something wrong with
our function let's see let's see teeming
is let's say Tim is X minus 5 let's see
what happens okay so for some reason
it's not let's not worry about that
okay so but actually we need to worry
about that because because our goal is
to plot this function now this this is a
power function it's it's a bit more
complicated let's just try it so let's
try to try this function and see what
happened what what what it shows
so copy it and so what is a function
okay so the function is this function
the function is just that one point two
times one point five raised to the power
of T okay copy that and put it here okay
let's see what happens
shown okay get close so so I'll you know
the our boundary algorithm actually
works but there is something not clear
to me I mean why do we have a blank
space on the right because this is x max
x max so let's look at our coordinate Y
with Y with is y max - y mean xmin xmax
ymin ymax y max Y - y min so I don't
understand so let's change to a simple
function and let's see
you see this this plank should not be
there
so now let's console.log print the value
and see what is the problem
console.log x max x mean why mean Y max
okay
refresh x mean negative 5y mean why max
X X mean negative five x max 5y mean
negative 10y max 10 that seems correct
let's change the function to again let's
change the function to just simple T
itself identity function yeah so it's
all correct but why is it why do we have
the blanks on the side I don't know Chad
is disabled for this five stream why is
that oh it's here again Chad
disconnected I'm able to connect to
child face try again
okay I think there is a problem with my
livestream because the alas alas time is
incorrect probably because I have a
disconnect I have an internet
disconnection very annoying okay I'm
going to stop now
so that is hopefully next time I'll do
you know when I do again next time it
will be far more improved so let's call
today thank you guys for watching bye