good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of XR talk show today is 2019
December 9th Monday noon san francisco
time and we have this beautiful pink
craft so guys hi Matt and today the plan
is good morning tank Moni Allen and bot
and all you people
so today's plan is the first 20 minutes
or possibly 30 minutes we will do a eMac
based session and after that it's going
to be random and I'm thinking Japanese
keyboard and Japanese input system and
japanese keyboard layouts those are
fantastic topics okay so we're gonna do
good morning Kathy and we're gonna do
the Japanese keyboards you know I'm
going to explain to you how the Japanese
input system works how what type are
there and the history of the keyboards
layout they are quite a few so that's
another topic so but the first 20 or 30
minutes is going to be technique
technical eMac B's okay and so shall we
begin
are you guys ready so I think we will
begin and I have a description in the
youtube description section and we are
going to I'm wondering should we start
from scratch or should we start from a
existing code I think I'll start from
squid scratch okay I was going to ask
you guys to vote but every time I ask
you guys no answered readily so that you
know it it's faster if I just make a
choice and do it and you just watch what
I do okay so so eMac please let me begin
that
okay so let's check this caca myself so
I don't so we gonna do this quickly this
is gonna be a technical live coding and
tutorial of eMac B's okay so what are we
going to do I'm going to show you the
command that that is what we are going
to do is okay okay so let me prepare
first okay so let me get into a let me
get into let's get some images okay so
okay so Genesis okay okay so we need to
get a image okay so I need to choose a
image let's see some fantastic ones
okay so choosing the images hard
well right let's just do doot doot -
lets do the trunk okay so strong okay
and you can look at this is one of the
Japanese keyboards wrong jpg okay copy
the file path okay so we go to
accounting show show the window and
today's today's page and go back and we
want to copy let's go to the directory I
okay go to the directory I and open this
file image file go to diet
okay and so this is file and we are
going to make a copy so it's over here
in this directory and I'm going to
rename it xx strong okay so we're gonna
rename this file xx strong so now here
is an image close it and we are going to
okay actually so okay so here I just
renamed space to underscore so here is a
file and close this directory close and
copy the copy the file path of the image
close it close it okay now we are
backing saw talk show page
okay and paste the image link you see
there and make it a image link of ice so
now we have the image now I'm going very
fast you see all these custom commands
are calling flying through now if you
don't know what they are just just look
them up search them you'll find it most
likely on my website okay so open this
image first of all I want to convert it
to JPEG okay open it go to diet and you
see this is a image file and convert to
JPEG so that command is going to be
these three key presses so convert to
grayscale no max number of colors
actually drawn that's a wrong command so
let's see I forgot what's a key so let's
look at what's the key okay so such four
so there it is tired to P&G so on
varrock keyboard it's it's basically f10
comma n okay so let's call it on this
file convert to PNG so if a coma what
what is n okay so n it's done so the
here is a fire you see PNG files are
usually 10 times larger than JPEG so you
see this is a PNG and here is a jpg
usually usually about nine times bigger
well anyway open the PNG copy the file
path close it close diet and paste it
the file path there and link a file
showing browser so we have a PNG version
now we don't need a JPEG version anymore
open it go open it and delete it okay
it's done showing browser you see it's
gone
remove that and now we're going to open
that again go to tired go to tire you
see this is PNG and this is the jpg we
are going to rename the PNG to be just
xxxx trunk okay do you name it
successful open it copy file path close
close
and paste the file path Minka fight we
remove that block showing browser there
we have it this is a PNG file now all
these are preparation what I want to do
is I want to convert this to JPEG so
normally what I do is open the file
hold on second so no Morea I do is so
here is a task ok here is a
specification for what we need to do so
I I want to open I want to convert this
PNG image into JPEG then I want to link
over it so you know reduce this file
size by 10 times because usually here's
a tip okay usually when you have an
image file JPEG version is ten times
smaller and you do not lose visual
quality usually okay so so normally the
way I do it is I open a file go to tired
then call the command to convert it to
jpg wait and the command to jpg is this
okay so you see it creates a JPEG image
open it I copy the file path close close
close then I paste the file path here
and I can link of I okay now cut it and
we'll move it here so you see we have
two image files here so here's a new jpg
so showing browser you can see two
images but the process is tedious
because it requires me to go to you know
open a file go to tired coda command
copy the jpg file path close the diet
close the image then paste the link then
link of I to many steps I wanted one
shot okay so I want to do it one shot so
that is the command we are going to
write today okay yeah that is a
specification but before we do that
before we continue let me delete this
jpg okay so we are back to one PNG image
now now I have another command let me
show you okay so another command that
does similar thing but it's not is is
not exactly what whoa
want actually let's just start to write
a command okay so so let's write down
respect the spec for our command okay
convert the image fire under coozer
from jpg to PNG then link by link Oh
fire it in HTML
okay that is a command we want to do and
so convert the image file under kusa in
a HTML file okay from jpg to PNG then
link a file so in other words when I
have kusa on this on this line I
just press a button and that PNG becomes
jpg okay that's what we want to do so
showing browser so here is aspect let me
magnify okay so here is a spec and we
are going to code it now so how long
have i okay we have ten minutes let's
see how fast we can do it
okay so before so we're going to create
eMac this okay so actually call the
command eMac please okay create a
template opening a new buffer define
function okay and define function the
function name will be exact invert PNG
to jpg in line okay make it - ate it
okay because in emag is the name by
convention is hyphenated okay doc string
talks doc string is talk string is
actually this one okay convert the image
file on the coding HTML file from jpg to
T and G then Dinko fire okay then
version day to the tre state okay then
we start to code okay but before white
code let me read take a minute to read
the comments okay
so Aaron says do you ever write bash
scripts no or basically never have to
because you do eMac B's okay the answer
to that question is I do not code any
patch at all because spackling 20 years
ago I learned Perl you know I code for
for four years so everything you can do
in bash you can do in Perl and it's
going to be C me possibly faster faster
more powerful shorter code shorter code
so so that's that's the reason I don't
use bash in fact I think bass should
should should be replaced by Perl but
anyway that never happened so that is a
reason I never coded bash I always just
called PO and but in all case that is
not the reason I don't code bash in eMac
B's because well you eMac this view
basically you don't want to code you
it's best if you do not call external
program so for example in this task I
could I could make writer Emacs command
that cause a shell command you know the
image magic magic convert then then grab
the output actually we are kind of doing
that anyway let's let's go on with this
code okay so bar says recently I read
that pearl is very slow except for
stream and information which is the
thing I made which is a thing is made
for not no pearl is actually parolees
pearl is about the same same speed as
Ruby and Python in fact it's probably a
bit faster a little a little bit okay
depending on what you do but the chain
in general Perl Python Ruby they are the
same exact same speed so anyway so let's
read the comments let's see and we're
gonna start to code that okay so
subpolar says good morning Paolo we're
gonna continue this okay we're gonna
stay focused on these in ten minutes
we'll be done actually probably more
than ten minutes
Duke's video installing those packages
from
not being a super what do you guys are
talking about God too many too many too
many chat okay so if you have a question
for me put a you know put put my name
there okay I'm gonna escape the chat no
don't listen to the what you hear okay
did it well anyway so let's let's keep
going on with this so what about bash
well let's I'm not going to talk about
that today
so basically try not to code bash okay
unless you really have to the only
reason you have to is when you work for
a company and that company is need to
install programs then that it that is
when you use bash because Bash is is by
convention okay technically you don't
need you don't want to use smash but
because of convention you have to follow
it kind of so if you work in a company
and the company is writing you know
programs installation programs then use
bash otherwise do not use bash use
Python Ruby pearl okay and you don't use
pearl either because Pro is kind of dead
so use Python and Ruby and I don't like
Python okay so you can just use Ruby so
anyway that's my reason about bash or
not bash and and and and don't use any
of the fancy - or whatever fish or
whatever well you could use them but
they are insignificant okay
inconsequential so it's okay so let's
begin with this okay so first of all the
task first of all so Dan says how do you
control the web browser from Emacs what
do you mean control like there is a
command I press a key and it shows in
web browser I press another key back to
Emacs so that command is called excite
camera browse URL or buffer okay you can
you can find on my website and and there
is also be Odin command
code browse URL but anyway I did a video
about that how do you control so so okay
so if you have have address if you have
questions put my name to it okay so I
can see it so let's continue with this
code so we want to so first of all we
need to we need to do this fast okay
because otherwise it's gonna be too long
here phille so first of all we need to
get the file path under kusa okay so let
let fire input path okay so let input
path and input file path will be okay we
need to get that path into a string okay
so let's do this okay so so input path
is a variable set okay set input path
okay and we want to set it to thing at
point thing at point now I'm going to
code this fast if you have questions put
my name into it okay then I'll see it in
answer and I'm still going okay so so
thing at point I want a file name okay
file name so delete though that D do
that okay so yeah so so input path is an
input file path then so now we get the
file path we can actually print it
okay so actually this code will walk
vennett and copy the file name and we
put the cursor here we put the cursor
here and call the command
metarex shall convert P&G to jpg and
it's called and you see in a mini buffer
it prints the path so that is great
success now we continue now we got the
file path so now the next step is to
convert it to jpg we can do that by we
are going to do that by calling the
image magic for command line okay and
that command line is going to be let me
try it okay that command is ok it's not
that actually so this is my shortcut to
so actually here is a command convert
something p.m. convert something okay so
okay we are doing this from scratch okay
so actually I already have code if I
just copy it here might be much faster
but since we promised to code this from
scratch so let's do it from scratch okay
so the the image magic command we want
to use is something like that okay so
it's going to be it's going to be for
example cat cat yeah my cat okay my cat
jpg - actually not jpg so the this is a
command for for image magic so that's
the command we want to call
okay so copy that so command string okay
this is gonna be shell command stream so
we're gonna set command stream then the
command string will be format
okay so format basically something like
that oops
go back here format and okay so that and
that okay and here will be input path
okay
so let's create it so the command string
is a shell command we want to call so
we're gonna we call convert which is
from image magic and the PNG file name
okay so yeah but we need to fix
something else so input path so we got
we got an input path then we need to we
need the file name part without the
suffix without the PNG you know the
extension PNG and JPEG so how do you do
that go to go to sorry Mac this tutorial
practical emag B's you can such that
you'll find the link URL so you go to it
and this is so this is about file name
so you want to go to read file file path
so that section so functions on
directory function file path functions
so file name directory file name none
directory file name extension file name
sense the extension that's what we want
so close that so file name sends
extension that is the command we want
yay
so we put input pass input path here and
we set a file name okay file call name
okay so set cue file call name and the
value will be that that's right okay so
file call name so now we go here
that is correct okay save it close it
reopen it now he's a far too small here
I think it's is it too small or not so
Dan says do you know next browser from
atlas engineer no I don't know what that
what is that let's talk about that later
okay focus focus on the eMac beast guys
you guys here to learn you Mack baseball
not you know as pertinent questions like
related to what we are doing because
otherwise I feel like I'm wasting it
this is gonna be I mean we are not this
is not random chat right so if you wanna
be funny is okay for you great so okay
so we have we are trying to create a
command string here and this is seems
right so let's print it okay so message
that's this print message command string
cool avow the buffer go back to the HTML
code a command press enter correct
can you see its you can you see the
messages so let me show you let's go to
open the messages buffer so you can see
the message buffer we you can see that
we are being correct here correct
correctness is our concern so you see it
prints out it printed that meaning that
we are we are doing good we are making
progress so go back to the disk code and
let's let's set background color
what color should it be pink
we don't want pink so let's pick a color
that's light Alex blue whatever that is
okay so so we can tell this is the
messages the output so now we are back
to the list so we need to okay so we
have a command string that's what we
want and it works and now we're just
going to call the shell command okay
call the shell command
couette so how do you cause y'all
command shell command so shell command
obviously so you just put the command
string there and we don't need output
buffer we don't need arrow but we don't
need so that is it not yet but the
almost we are almost done okay so let's
shrink shrink shrink the shrink shrink
shrink this thing
Avada buffer we are done so go back to
the here go back to so you see here we
have the PNG file remember now we go to
tired we drop into diet and let's before
we do anything let's remove all those
backup remove all those backup files so
we are we start clean okay delete okay
so you can see the xxxx strong is the
file name now if we call the command it
should create a PNG version so let's
call it now convert PNG to jpg JPEG in
line co-ed it says share command
succeeded without without output so
let's look let's look at the directory
okay there we have it you see this here
is our file JPEG file fantastic now of
course we are not done yet because we
want to we
want to automatically convert this line
into that and there is a question
whether our command should delete a PNG
file
we don't know let's you know let's do
and see okay so now it created the JPEG
file
but now let's delete a JPEG file okay
because we're gonna do it again okay so
back back now let's go back to our code
so now we call shell command now that's
success now what's the next state next
step the next step is ask the user
whether we should delete a PNG okay so
ask the user so how do you ask user yes
or no okay so yes or no no okay so how
do you ask user in eMac this a question
you go to some practical Lisp oh the
answer you need is here so you need to
be familiar with this tutorial structure
so this is about asking user so get user
input right there okay so you have
several different kind of questions you
know get a stream from user get for a
file name get a directory name get
regular expression prompt for file name
or pump for directory from 4th string
and in case what we need is this one
query user for yes/no so there it is so
yes or no P so in eMac this there is a
convention whenever a command ends with
- P that P stand for predicate predicate
which means which means this function
returns yes or no true or false usually
ok so yes or no P and you want to ask
user okay you want to ask user delete
the PNG ok so if if user type yes that
means you know
you got the you got you got the answer
from user so if so if user says yes then
you delete the PNG then okay how do you
do PNG you can you want to delete the
file okay delete file there it is
then you give a file path I believe so
our file path input path okay so that is
that so otherwise to nothing so we don't
need that part so change if to win okay
make it pretty so when yes or no
question
delete the PNG file and if user says yes
then you you call the delete command
okay okay that's about that then the
next thing we need to do is we need to
let's go to the back to HTML remember we
need to replace this line so what we
want to do is we want to go back to the
beginning of the tag then inserted okay
it's a bit tedious okay but we can do it
okay bar say sporks off like he's 2 vs
code but but pay me $50 I'll do it okay
then we gonna seriously someone okay
someone you are there if you want me to
port stuff like his to vs code I would
ask a hundred dollars you know a hundred
dollars this is not too much okay and
I'll do it because you know oh you wait
for me to do it but I don't know when I
need to I need bread and butter so
anyway let's let's get back to this so
what what we need to do yeah so we need
to let me just code it okay such
backward okay hold on a second let me
show the command window such back would
okay it's such backward okay
such backward will move the cursor to
through something use such so we want to
search for the less than you could less
than sign okay okay that will move
cursor to the beginning of the less than
equal sign less than sign then then we
gonna say newline okay now what does new
line that the function new line will
just add a return okay actually I don't
want to say you know let's just say
insert okay insert a return why why do I
prefer insert a new line instead of
calling the newline function because in
this is a tip about eMac list coding
okay because when you when you call some
function such as the newline function
they are designed for interactive use
for users to you know press keys so
usually they have lots of other features
like you know options you know whether
they you want to automatically indent
things when we for example when you
press return in many mods Emacs we also
automatically intend the line so this
kind of commands some commands they are
designed for user interactive use but in
eMac this code usually you want to avoid
those because because if you use those
you it might do something else you know
you don't want that you want tight
control so we want we just want to
insert a new line use with that use with
this okay so you call insert so we
insert the new line and for now let's
just say okay let's just say insert a
file name okay so let's do it let's do
it okay so we insert a file path okay so
Avada buffer go back to the HTML and
we're gonna try this on this again so
call the command Co it
he asked me delete the PNG file yes or
no no okay
here is our result you see it's it's
good it's already it's pretty good okay
but there is something we want to fix so
let's do let's fix it okay so hold on a
second go back to the beast code we want
to insert the new line afterwards not
before right so you've out the buffer
back to the code
try it again move the cursor to the
image file path coda command
go ahead delete a PNG file no there it
is and I can cook a command wait
that's PNG wait we won the JPEG so
that's the ROM file path okay so let's
do it again back to the code we want to
insert the input file path no we want to
we want to insert a call name then
insert a string dot jpg okay eval the
buffer go back to the HTML file code a
command couette DV PNG file no there it
is that's what we want now I can
manually link of I it there we have it
so actually we are almost done okay
showing browser you see we have one JPEG
version one PNG version almost almost
done
so three that go back to the disco so
what else we need to do so the last
thing we need to do is actually we need
we need to turn this line into okay so
we need to turn so we need to turn this
line into a line like that okay so we
need to turn that into that now I
already have a command to do that oh we
can do it from scratch I think I'll just
use the command I already have
okay so what some questions no questions
right so how long have I been going 34
minutes okay three more minutes then
we'll be done with this so we need a
command that do this okay let me show
you we begin we begin with this now now
look at look look at me and I press
three keys okay two keys okay one two
and it becomes that that's that's what
we need to do and what's the command
what's the command that does that that
is saw HTML image link of I okay let's
go to the code because I already have
the code here so this command is in this
file size H TMAO mod dot G dot year so
open it so here is the function it's
kind of big okay so that's why I don't
want to go into square I don't want to
rewrite this whole thing from scratch
but but anyway let's copy it close it
close that back to the list code and go
down and paste the whole thing so we can
have a look okay the the code is about
hundred lines why is it that long
because it is actually trying to do
quite a few things now how do we okay we
are not too going to code that from
scratch let's just code let's just call
this code let's just call this function
okay let's just call the function there
so once we after we insert a new line we
want to go back move the cursor back
because this function needs the cursor
back needs the cursor on the image file
path so let's show that so we back watch
ah okay backward charge and let's say -
okay as long as the the cursor is on the
image file path your walk
so anyway I think that's it that's done
okay so eval the buffer hold on a second
before we learn it let's double check on
this function
okay this function does not require any
argument okay that's good
it just works on whatever is under kusa
okay that's good so eval above a go back
to the HTML where is it here so we're
gonna call it okay so call the command
yes
do I want to delete the PNG no yes
fantastic look we got it show in browser
so that is success and that is actually
that is the end of that the completion
so we have the code this is the code
okay that's that finish our topic now we
want to clean up we don't okay so we
don't need this messages thing
so actually you know I'm doing this life
you know pot possibly as a tutorial and
you know but but in real life I actually
I want that you know like you know in in
real life I probably want something else
you know I mean I need to add more
features for example for example one of
the feature I want is you know I don't
like every time I call this command
let's try it again okay
every time I call the command I don't
want it to ask me like by the way this
is a user interface design issue on
Windows or Linux the idiotic
Linux people like when you call command
you don't want it to ask you questions
like when you would try to run a command
it's try to install it asks you
questions oh do you want this oh yeah
but this one over the make a choice
freeze and they give you a bunch of
creep
cryptic things you don't understand so
for user interface you you want to avoid
that
kokom and and just go ahead do it okay
whatever questions just do it for
example if the file already exists what
do you want to do you know one way is
you ask the question oh oh there's
already a jpg file do you want to delete
it that's no good okay rather you just
just just create a new file with a new
name like - jpg - you know - point jpg
or three point jpg then in the end maybe
you tell the user okay you know there's
already a file so you created new ones
that's a better that's a better user
interface so you so you don't want I
don't want it to ask me you know whether
I want to delete the PNG or not just
just do it you know don't delete it you
do it
but however sometimes I do want to
delete it then you can modify your
command so that so that it will take a
universal you know Emacs is called
Universal command meaning that you press
control you first before you call the
command so you press control you then
you call the command then it will just
delete a PNG beforehand you know they or
you can ask questions you can ask user
questions you know that that's so that
that's something more we can add to this
command you know features and also we
can start to worry about efficiency you
know for example shell command can be
replaced by call process because for
example when you call shell command they
actually start a show you actually start
a bash and that's less efficient and
also we can start to worry about you
know code code elegance things like that
for example you know instead of set a
set Q on each one of these we can put
them inside the let things like that
anyway that's it for that for today so
so Aaron say is
the living web framework what do you
mean you mean my eMac setup stuff so
Alan says in real life is your normal
workflow more copy pasting from older
code yes absolutely
less stuff from scratch yeah how would
you compare yeah of course obviously
because if I were to do this from
scratch I mean if I would do this
offline I mean the reason I'm doing it
online because that's the talk show
because I need some you know some people
can you know you guys can learn eMac
this or you can see my workflow how I
work in this you know maybe you see how
I operate you know it's good to see
things so that's why I'm doing it live
but if I'm doing you know in the past 20
years I just call them as you know
without going on YouTube and I would not
do it from scratch because I already
have a code let me show you okay I
already have a code that does similar
for example now I want to make a icon of
this I so I call the command let me show
you okay I call the command
he asked me your width let's say 500
okay there it is you see it creates a
new file with the new dimension 614 by 4
407 you know it and it puts into the
path there so I press a key it becomes a
and now I can show in browser
magnify you see I have three versions
you see this one is scaled down version
so I already have that command that does
almost almost identical to the one we
are doing today the difference is that
that command is designed to scale the
image well originally it's designed to
create a icon let me show you okay you
see it's designed to create icons so
that
so that if you go into you go you go to
my you know Kibo you see all these icons
you know that's that's the that's a
that's a fruit of that command so but it
does almost exactly what we want today
but except what we want today is to
convert from JPEG to PNG and and you
know PNG to JPEG and not ask for scaling
I don't want it to be scared that's why
so if I if I were coding it myself I
just do this okay so look so look at so
let me show you okay so I code describe
key then press the key so this is a
command so create some nail image okay
go to the go to the source code here
this this this file open it and here's a
code copy it new buffer pace it eighty
lines of code and make it eMac this okay
so here it is so if I were to do it from
scratch I just modify this these got
lots of features like you know it
already has lots of features and it will
be faster so I don't have to yeah so
that that's about that so okay so now we
can do I feel like you know every time
when I do a video I feel like you know I
have a purpose now now that purpose is
complete a a accomplished mission
accomplished now we can do random chat
let's do that for 10 minutes and and
what have you guys been talking about
let's see okay no more people in our
jokes so what do you guys talking about
so actually let's start the JIRA okay
it's so you guys come on okay come on
and top talk to me and talk to people so
let me let me get that up okay but
before we do that let me clean up my
buffers so I don't get confused what you
know my habit is always to shut down the
buffers I don't want anymore and also I
need to okay so open this we don't I
don't want that cause it should it open
this I don't want it delete it open this
delete it okay
and open that go to the diet so we can
see we have several deleted files okay
dd them yes okay in fact open this PNG I
don't need it anymore
delete it okay so delete that and now we
go back to the list code delete it and
paste it here show in browser that's our
code and we need to color fie it show in
browser that's beautiful so now next we
are going to talk about Japanese input
systems oh we gonna have a chat with you
guys so Aaron says does your ideal
workflow have no open terminals enter in
text commands yeah I rarely use
terminals okay so this is my terminal
you know the Emacs spit out these
garbage
arrow messages so let's just clean it
command K Oh control K okay control K
wait what wait why am i okay yeah there
it is
wait why is it such a long delay and
something is wrong here
Oh s wait something is wrong here why is
this it's not even taking my input
because I just type you know it takes
ten seconds to show us what is going on
go back to terminal wait go back to
terminal there is some problem with the
terminal I'm not sure what what is going
on with the terminal terminal she seems
my terminal seems to be not responsive
now so yeah normally I don't use
terminal anymore I mean if I want to
usually I guess go to Asia okay so here
is a Shou now let me show you okay so
here is my talk show for today my talk
show page you can go to my talk show
sorry talk show wait
so you go through sorry dot info the
first link talk show and you see all the
indexes of my talk show and you see
today I just added that you see but it's
not on my website so if you go to sorry
dot info go to talk show scroll down go
to today's talk show you see it's empty
and now we go to Isha go to Isha Ayesha
is kind of a shell written in eMac based
entirely so I press a key this is
interactive a brief so I make I pick the
first choice that's a sync and now it's
syncing to my server now you go you go
back to the browser refresh you can see
you know everything is synced to my
server that's today's fruit so I don't
you know so and also when you want to
copy files copy create the directory
create a new file you do all that in
entired
okay so here is a diet that's you can
copy it copy file TV file create fire
move file rename file or in Emacs tired
it's far more efficient then
then doing it in terminal the only
reason I would use terminal today is
when you want to when you are doing
something new such as a new command in
some installation script for Ruby or
some new language things like that then
you go to terminal because in Emacs
sometimes they don't work well so when
you are doing something new new new
shell command you go to terminal that's
well anyway my terminal is for some
reason frozen okay I don't know why so I
think that's it for today explain your
machines hostname o my machines hostname
is from my a professor who gave me the
Mac and I just didn't change it that's
all you know Richard Perle a
mathematician so okay so let's see what
happens so we are going to I was going
to start aid JIRA so weekend so you guys
can join and talk with me maybe not
maybe that's it for today you know I'm
I'm still kind of pissed why my terminal
is not responding and I have no clue why
is that because this shouldn't have
so Alan says does your idea work flow
okay we answer that no oven terminals I
typically always have a open terminal
though you know because you need that as
well yeah because you know I I quit
Emacs often you know some people some
Emacs users do you create your Emacs
like many Emacs users they keep your
their Emacs
open for weeks and but me for me I need
to close it like usually once a day at
least because when you go to eMac B's
there is no way to clean things out okay
clean this well that you can try but I
can tell you for sure these languages
including images and Mathematica they
create symbols like you know they have a
single table for all the variable names
you know they are that's why they are
called symbolic languages but there is a
issue in these languages they the
symbols they just accumulate you could
clear them but it's never as good as you
just restart them so in these languages
you do want actually want to just quit
we start you know from fresh so so let's
just do that okay so I mean let me do
anyway close that create Emacs it's good
okay now go back to terminal oh did I
just close the terminal window wait okay
the terminal window is dead you know I'm
okay so let's this force quit terminal I
don't know what's this this annoys me I
don't know what's going on with the
terminal
okay I say quit it's not quitting I have
to say force quit okay I just forced
quit terminal now I usually keep a
terminal open because this is how I
start Emacs
I just press the up arrow key then
that's the command add to that's the
command to launch Emacs that's how I
don't my Emacs so I create Emacs like at
least once a day
to cream you know to start from fresh
there there we have it now you see my
old setup you know it's not you know now
we have to enlarge found again you know
that the great clear that okay so okay
so this Allen you would be interested
this is my exploring web pack thing you
know it's still here I really need to
continue I haven't been coding you know
the doing live video is kind of sucking
the life out of me I think that is true
for the YouTube us too I mean even it's
not much like just one hour day and I
try to not do much preparation I don't
you know I try just to do like it life
but actually for some reason it does
suck sucks the life out of you you know
because most you do it is it sucks the
energy by anyway so let's see it and
that we are about done maybe five more
minutes so we shut down let's see eight
people so so Alice's hostname stuff
works so what's my host name yeah big
dick machine you know Richard Richard
you know the nickname the english name
richard has a nickname dick by
convention now i try to look up that's
that's a hard question okay why is
richard why is why is dick the nickname
for richard I did look up before but I
forgot you know some of the there's a
real weird
etymology we
so oh it's magically so nice coding okay
so terminal working supports meta point
what does what do you mean
anti terminal physician so sorry can you
show us doing some heavy processing with
Emacs what do you mean heavy processing
so you need you mean like I need to wait
where's my Emacs okay go back to Emacs
like typically I put this window you
know my workflow okay let me let me show
you my workflow so open a new buffer so
typically I have a Emacs now notice the
bottom of the window it must touch the
screen okay it must touch your screen
okay and let me close this window okay
so why why must it touch the screen
because I move my mouse now my mouse has
auto click I just move down I don't have
to click then I'm backing Emacs now the
other option is to have function keys
okay let's show let's show you my
keyboard okay normally I would have the
function keys like I press f9 it just
switched me to Emacs f8 will be terminal
okay
f7 will be browser things like that
that's what I usually do I've been doing
that for 10 years Oprah or more but now
because of the Kinesis keyboard they
don't have you know their function keys
is tiny so I don't want to you know it's
it's not as good it's like tiny function
keys so I do not have that option and I
also have a keypad in the middle but all
the keys are already used up for browser
Marco's I showed that a few times in my
video so I'm out of keys so I need to
get a another programmable keypad anyway
so I'm out of key so I cannot just press
a key to switch to Emacs but I do have
this also extremely useful auto click I
just move my mouse I don't
creak I showed that many times I'm not
clicking okay when I click you're here
and actually listen actually I don't
think you can hear it but anyway I don't
click so I just nudge my mouse and we
can look at Alan's food today
the P Rocky
so what is silence food real life so
heavy processing with Emacs so this is
Alan's food ok so it looks like
dumplings but I'm not sure why what
what's about the pure rocky we'll have
to see but heavy process oh so what do
you mean by heavy processing processing
a large file inside Emacs oh well if you
mean writing a email is function that
process files ok you mean you mean
writing or text processing programming
eMac this so if if so now it depends on
what you mean by heavy
okay so eMac is actually not good for
really heavy text processing okay for
light text processing Emacs is better
than Perl Ruby Python because Emacs has
perfect
buffer data type has lots of features
you know that's geared for text
processing so but however Emacs is not
fast okay in my business is not fast
it's about six times slower than Python
Ruby or Perl so so if you are talking
about heavy text processing like like
you process more than 10,000 files you
know I I do regularly process more than
10,000 files a day
every day because I for example let's go
through my programming blog you know so
let's go through Kesari info CD up
magnify okay let me let me show you okay
okay so let's show the command saw start
command log mod okay so now you can see
my commands again the commands I call in
Emacs citrus okay so now I for example
iOS this is Mike solid info directory
now I can do find dot name let's say
anything edge tml and it's gonna put
five thousand files two thousand in
Saudi info okay this is a full maybe
five thousand files okay that's one of
my website and you see so so you can see
the line number four thousand four
hundred HTML files okay now i go to i go
to the index file so you can see this is
my exact lead info now i can call a max
command it's such let's search for all
places that contains the word Haskell
okay let's say Haskell okay enter
searching solid info yes
Oh HTML files yes okay you wait for five
seconds you will show the results so
this is written in eMac this and that
command is Safa in text is a package on
my Appa you can get it okay
so right now it's in the here it is
here's a result it's searching you know
five thousand HTML files and here's a
result so this is this is text
processing and you can you can scroll to
any part open it for example here is one
with article that contains what has
language purity code in this
this is a big riot rent scheme dis so
anyway that's a example of text see text
processing program retaining emag B's on
a second okay so what do you mean by
large you know heavy processing is this
heavy now this is you know this works
fine but if you are talking about like
Google Facebook you are processing you
need to process 10,000 files every
second
then Emacs is no good okay you rather
call this in Cola
well in Ruby Ruby Python Perl okay now
if you want even faster you need to code
in : in fact let me show you the same
I showed this many times okay first of
all let me show you the package I just
used so describe key that so that
command is Safa in text and it's in this
fire ox a find on al open it here is the
source code code so the fire is 800
lines you go to the top magnify and here
is the URL open it
showing browser here's a package you can
get it from mapa okay now i have the
exact i have the same program written in
:
that is when i need speed okay so let me
show you the : actually i showed this in
previous video before so goal and so go
to bookmark : actually go to bookmark
fine go here is the code : script 186
lines of code so we are going to find in
this directory and find all files
contains what Haskell Haskell okay here
so we run it and it's going to run in
background you know it's very easy you
see it's faster it's much faster than
the Emacs version about five five five
or ten times faster so it's done so now
we go to the output directory
magnify
I'll find out put mod so now it's
colored it's just like before so we can
you can we can go to open that showing
browser so this this article is about
programming problem construct a tree
given its edges this is a question I got
asked at Google from a idiotic Indian
programmer okay so the problem the
problem is given a bunch of edges edges
of a tree you want you need to construct
the tree so I wrote my solution
so that's it for today so I didn't say
so so yeah so if you want heavy text
processing you need to go to Ruby Python
or goal and now also large files Emacs
is not good for large files okay so yeah
you need to go to Ruby or you know go
let so can i program our sofa same three
what do you mean I don't know what you
mean so pierogi is like Central East
European dumpling
oh okay okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching and bye ok so if
you like my stuff go by my Emacs
tutorial okay so you just go to my
website there is the tutorial link
you can somewhere somewhere here where
is it you know anyway so so you can you
can find a link at bottom I think yeah
bikes are Emacs judo yo okay so you are
committed to learn eMac miss the most
powerful fantastic language and patron
of me okay bye guys