good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of top show as usual go to this
page on this information panel here and
here over here at the bottom of the
YouTube video and let me know and take a
topic you know pick the pick a topic and
we will talk about that meanwhile some
talk show let me fix the title here okay
so so what are we gonna talk about today
well you know today the Notre Dame
Cathedral burned it down
basically that's a sad story
so that keyboard I'm gonna talk about
that keyboard that's the what's the name
but anyway yeah there's a few things
happenings happenings in the world you
know and we might talk about that one of
that is the biggest news today is
probably the notre-dame Cathedral you
see if you have a youth Twitter account
just go to Twitter and such you know in
a search box type Notre Dame you see
your our videos this Cathedral is about
800 years old so and you know it went
down
and this Cathedral took 200 years about
200 years to build so you can see from
this video the spire fail that's pretty
bad
you know I feel it's pretty bad for
Europe
it's like France is falling apart
because of the yellowjacket protests
it's been going on for you know for
almost a year it's still going on as far
as I know you know lots of violence and
and UK United Kingdom you know you have
the brexit going on and lots of violence
with thee you know lots of violence and
upheaval you know it's a chaos it's a
political stability problem you know
that's the problem it's in political
instant kind of you know it's in stable
chaos to mode and you know that's going
on you Europe yeah and you know for my
perspective I blame much of it on social
justice scan you know basically they
that you have this left you know it's
not clear how to code you know maybe the
proper term is extreme left okay
basically there are topics their subject
is about immigration Islam for Islam
like Islam this or that every day and
feminism LGBTQ you know trans stuff and
race you know racism yeah so they that's
a you know the topics they talk about
everyday you know they've been frying
you know like when you when you eat
fried rice you know you fry fry these
topics every day since since you know
since 2016 election
you know the Trump got elected and it
got bad
hi guys so say hi we got four people
watching and I'm drinking tea and this
is along tea computer tea Earl Grey Earl
Grey tea is from from from England from
you know as something like that but I
think you know I think chai tea is
invented in China I think but anyway we
don't drink a great tea we don't have a
great key which we drink cool auntie the
thing about tea is funny so in America
UK you've drink tea with milk and
sometimes you put sugar and but to
Chinese that's like what the [ __ ] you
know he never ever put sugar or milk in
in tea you drink tea it's just tea
anyway that's and also do you know you
know in in America you know it's like
sometimes you co t like chai you know
this stupid American you know you see
what the reason that happens is because
you know the the cooperations you know
American is a capitalistic country you
know the corporation's name they make
money they want to make money like
Starbucks especially especially
Starbucks so if you sell if you're gonna
have a tea you know item you know you
say tea people get bored you know they
know what T is
you know they so you want to create new
jargons like chai you know something
something chai then then people say oh
what is that oh I never tried that you
know let's try chai come on Isaac
what about milk tea the boba milk tea
that well milk tea we don't we don't
drink milk tea any what
I'm not actually offhand I'm not sure
what what is milk tea you know basically
but basically in China or Taiwan I
suppose in Japan as well
tea is just T you have green tea but you
have alone tea green tea you know they
but they are basically all they okay
okay they are like oh great tea okay
kind of you know this is so it's like
you're just tea there's no milk no sugar
tea is just T in fact this actually you
know in America for example you have
lemon tea or you have other fruit tea
like healthy herbal I gotta how about
you don't know what the [ __ ] never heard
of that herbal tea and you know then
they have you have citrus tea like you
put lemon flavor or sometimes orange and
I never heard I mean okay but anyway in
addition in Taiwan or China okay it's
like a foreign concept you never hear of
that you know but in America you have I
mean it's kind of understandable because
corporations they created these things
to sell you know to sell stuff it's like
it's like latte you know okay it's it's
similar to coffee okay so something
coffee is the American thing oh I don't
know maybe I don't know whatsoever
engine buy anyway coffee is very popular
in America right a lot of people are
crazy about coffee like programmers like
coffee every day coffee these in that
then you have Java you know where the
Java programming language is named after
Java some kind of coffee then latte so
and and also other food items like pizza
and spaghetti but basically in USA when
you sell them often you create jargons
and you create the food or drinks that
that is totally different from from
where they came came from you know from
the foreign country in Italy or China or
whatever but however you put on a exotic
name to sell
and you know it's like oh this is
something something child
this is Lotte is from Italy Oh from
China it's like exotic is farming and
you have these foreign names but when
you are when you actually buy it drink
it or whatever you know the food is
actually not it is you know so-called
Americanized it's you know not not even
it's like you know fast food fast food
iced nights huh yeah tonight's hot yeah
milk tea okay we don't know
well the boba milk tea okay there's
something interesting about that okay
okay first of all about the boba milk
tea that's that's not really teed I mean
that's like a dead desert desert desert
you know it's a sweet drink and they put
tap high card thing you know I looked up
what is the tapioca exactly one day but
anyway they put this you know like you
know both in America you caught boba
milk tea I I think I think that that
originated from Taiwan you know Taiwan
Taiwan is very famous very popular for
for this old kind of small eatery items
like special drinks special dishes you
know so anyway that's from Taiwan and it
began from you know from young people
drinking that you know it's like it's a
it's a dessert you know it's a sweet
thing but when you drink that okay you
don't it's not tea I mean we Chinese
people we don't think of it it's like
you know it's tea it's not tea it's just
a sweet drink but by the way also
another thing interesting is that oh you
know why is it called boba boba means
basically okay
literally okay exactly
you are American Chinese right I mean
Chinese American so let me type the name
of that tea here so that Oh bah that's
it
so that's a name papa nights are the
first two I think that name came from
Hong Kong that name originates from Hong
Kong so that the first two characters
you know in America you call it boba
milk tea okay let's see boba milk tea
okay let's see if we can get some like
pictures you know there's a there's a
problem with the DuckDuckGo because you
know when you when you have JavaScript
off and and if you want to image search
you cannot do it because for example I
just tried it you know I I have
JavaScript off then I type the item
there's no way for you to click to get
two images there's no way even then you
know now I have turned on the JavaScript
but still there's no wait for you to get
to it so what do you do they both are
empty so what you do is you you go all
the way down wait not all the way don't
you you click the logo then you click
the logo again then you go to all the
way down you click on the logo what
again
now you type now you type yeah you have
to type again it's very extremely Cydia
see of the duck taco you know the
company so now they don't see it you
know I got problems with these open
source and this groups still stupid like
that like when it comes to user
interface they cannot
function they cannot think this Linux
people okay including e-max people they
are somehow incapable of thinking so
anyway the problem I'm illustrating is
that you see now I have images basically
I want to image such you know go to you
know DuckDuckGo but there is no way but
now I have JavaScript on let's see oppa
milk tea okay now you have when you have
JavaScript on then you can go to okay
the problem let me recap let me
summarize the issue okay the issue with
my issue that this problem with the
DuckDuckGo search engine is that when
you have JavaScript off which happens
often for people who like to use doctor
go right because doctor goal is you know
doesn't track you and stuff so a lot of
us nerds have the you know JavaScript
off so when you have JavaScript off you
go to doctor goal and you want to search
images you cannot do it okay I mean you
you cannot do it
okay that's one problem because when you
you know it's like you cannot there's no
link there's no link to it it just
because when you have it JavaScript off
DuckDuckGo
sends you to a HTML version of the earth
search okay very stupid okay but notice
the big deal is that it's not as you
know the big deal what I'm trying to
illustrate you know what I'm trying to
convey convince you is that these people
there's a idiocy they are incapable of
thinking about user interface design
because for in contrast can't
in contrast okay when you when I have
JavaScript off I can go to google search
open I can search images no problem this
happens just with doctor go there's a
stupid people okay [ __ ] and there's
no way when I talk to them I mean almost
most of you and most of my followers are
Linux you know kind of
people right that's that's the feel what
I mean but when you talk to them with
discussion I mean between friends even I
mean I'm not talking about some someone
who doesn't like me okay between people
my followers okay or acquaintances wait
on them they cannot get it they don't
see they don't see the user interface
they don't see the or they say they
disagree or this or that or whatever you
know they don't they don't get it
this is part of the reason Linux you
know and open source and Emacs the
[ __ ] Emacs dev people okay they they
get nowhere they cannot call nowhere
they forever they stay in this niche
groove you know like geeks you know a
bunch of nerds every day talking about
talking about you know you know privacy
stuff but but but they have no influence
to anywhere outside of the their little
world big and ended they don't see it
okay that's a little bit digression
about about about the user interface
issue okay first of all dr. Koh first of
all you should allow people to search
images even when they have JavaScript
off okay Google Google for example
allows that you know okay again such
google images we know without having
javascript up first of all dr. code
should do that secondly if for some
implementation you know issue so you
maybe you don't have resources you have
to like separate this javascript version
and no JavaScript version that's stupid
anyway but if you have to do that you
must allow people to who whose browser
has JavaScript off then they'd have to
search term then you you know you go to
you send them to this no image version
you must have a link to image to a then
then I turn on JavaScript okay I see it
oh I don't have JavaScript then I turn
it on then you should have a link you
know to let people go to you know just
by clicking not having to retype
everything again you know let people go
to the image such links so you know you
suck it so the image shows so that's a
problem with a duck duck oh that's just
one problem the other problem is an EM
they really dr. ko it's one of the most
idiotic stupid name you know you you
cannot fly if you cannot grow you know
with that name you know you first of all
you need to shorten it duck go okay just
stop go
I'm intercom okay or something oh oh
duck go calm okay but they kind of
refused I mean sometimes you see they
have reasons because although many or
they did is that but in general yeah
this Linux it open-source stupid idiots
they always have reasons but the end
result is I did ago they go nowhere
because their user face interface is
just idiotic now this applies to a
master than to maths Masterton is again
one of the extreme idiocy that's that's
going nowhere in fact there's no people
there you know I mean the the the the
the the great thing is that it's you
know it's it's anti this cooperation you
know control so there's no algorithm
that controls my post for example when I
post something you know usually I post
our master done and Twitter at the same
time like I have efficient keys and I
just press a key and it's posted to both
phrases without you know without using
scripts of Bart's I'm now using scripts
of what parts okay so when I post some
ideas for example about a cathedral fire
or some ideas about firefighting I mean
you know like nuts interest I mean
easier you know then our master then
often I get reply immediately like some
other nuts will see my question and they
have you know opinions sometimes you
know good you know I get into action not
Rita it's almost not because of the for
multiple reasons but on Twitter I have
look I have two thousand you know
2,400 followers a master then I have
only you know on this
I have 365 followers there will be maybe
more because I'm a student there's
another issue okay it's this Federation
which is a problem actually so but so I
mastered and I don't have that many
followers but however I get you know
there's a exchange of information this
is a conversation it is a you know
interaction because you know that the
reason is because Twitter is controlling
information they are controlling you
know information flow they are doing
censorship and all that so I mean so
that's a great thing about master then
but however you know if it's a students
got so many problems that's typical of
the open source Linux or you know these
nuts idiots they cannot go out anywhere
they you know part yes there are so many
reasons okay but one of the reason is
they have this okay they they have open
source ideology vision that's one
problem but but I'm not focusing on that
today I mean right now I'm talking about
they these nerds they have problems they
have problems you know understanding
user interface understanding people
basically the point I want to get back
to is that the name master Dan okay name
acid that it's Dean's not one of the
most idiotic name it's not going
anywhere okay so anyway so the other
thing I was saying semester then you
know it was he was like hugely popular
by all the Nerds
oh we're gonna master the master then
you know Federation no K no corporate
control you know distributed but then
today I knew from the day one I have you
know I've argued with people you know
it's not going anywhere today it's
lesson these people it's like nobody but
again the advantage is that you know
because he's without corporate control
we
algorithm you know controlling
information you know that therefore even
I don't have you know that many photos I
get some discussion ok is it's trending
and drinking the people is less than
this anyway so the name is very bad you
know and you know like mastered and like
what the [ __ ] is it and also you cannot
type it like this is like multitudes of
ways to spell it you know you might
think you know you might think it's um
master done you know let me magnify okay
you know that's wrong they mastered then
that's wrong master done you know that's
wrong mastered then that's wrong made
master done that's wrong you know so you
have this this stupid word they want to
use then you have this region it's
impossible now of course you talk to you
know my followers you talk to these
geeks they they say oh they don't see it
basically they don't need they they
don't see this and like like today a
brain they don't see these issues they
don't see oh it's just name then then
then bla bla bla bla bla you know this
is this Linux FIFO Emacs people
basically the UNIX people basically this
type of people they they cannot yeah and
they are unable to see to get
perspective or user interface or how
society works okay now as to why that
happens that's not another topic but
anyway let me get back to the topic here
okay so so that's Mastan that's so
that's about Macedon and this open
source people's problems their problems
be you know you don't want to stay
forever in this niche I mean it's been
you know open source it's been 20 years
30 years okay you have Linux for for 30
years today you know basically oh if we
count the day when lean Linux became
popular you know we have 20 years
ready it's going nowhere then okay then
the stupid open source people say oh
look at Google they are using server so
Linux yeah you always do that because
it's free
you know Linux is such a free operating
system you know you download it for free
it's supposed you know such a free thing
it's great yeah it is it is where it's
supposed to already wiped out windows
already it's it it's not happening
because you're doing excellent because
you have you guys you people's behaviors
and thinking pattern does not reflect
reality because that's why Linux is so
bad you know it's you know it's such a
free system you're supposed to wipe out
windows already I hope I really hoped
you would but it's not I've you know
I've used it the Linux see I've used it
you know I've used for four years you
know two years ago it's it's one of the
worst compared to Mac Linux Windows
Linux is by far you know by like two
times three times the worst [ __ ] on the
planet okay offering system anyway
that's a hello guys I'll get to the
comment so but anyway let me backtrack
so we talking about Linux and mastered
and bad naming okay and before that it
was because Duck Duck Go okay duck duck
goes the patna me okay and also they got
the user interface problems of searching
images you know you when you don't have
JavaScript oh okay that's that's a
sidetrack so that so I kind of that's
that's that part is finished let me get
back to the baba ki boba tea okay boba
milk tea so you see this these are very
popular these days like well I don't
know about at least is popular in let's
say Silicon Valley you know in the San
Francisco Bay Area you know you go to
almost any downtown where there's
Chinese restaurants you have this coffee
shop they sell these okay now this
originated from Thai
as I said but this is something
interesting about this tea which reflect
the different reflects the differences
of American thinking so that the name is
PO bad you know you might wonder where
does name what does Baba me
so Baba that the Chinese character is
that over there here Baba okay and what
does I mean that that is literally it
means huge waves like ocean wave you
know huge waves but actually that is a
slant for big kids okay for women's
breasts like you know some woman's got
huge you know big breasts that's a slant
for big breasts so that's why it's boba
you know yeah that's a I believe that
name originated from Hong Kong oh the
milk tea the boba milk tea I think is
originated from Taiwan but the boba the
boba turn you know the slant is from I
think it's from Hong Kong but anyway
that that's why it's named that okay so
what way is a big breasts oh yeah
because it's milk you know that's why
you know giant its milk you know is it
like among young people you know is this
drink is mostly enjoyed by you know the
young people teenagers in generations so
it's like huge tits milk tea okay but
anyway yep a Time in America you can't
how not I've that oh my god big big tits
milk drink no no no we can that's that's
that's me solids misogyny or what
whatever you know so so okay that's one
topic about the boba milk tea and back
then to tea we don't drink Chinese well
this this this is dessert okay we don't
I mean this is not tea I mean we don't
think of this as T Chinese you know
Taiwan ode this Taiwan okay in China and
I suppose in Japan as well okay
and much of South Asia we drink tea
every day there's never milk in tea
there's never sugar in tea tea is just
tea you drink you see people drink it
every day especially like in kung-fu
movies you know it's like in America as
well not just American but in Chinese
kung-fu movies so it's like you have to
drink tea you fight or whatever so I'm
actually drinking from a tea bag kind of
so yeah it's so key but but what's the
deal with milk or sugar I mean there's
nothing wrong with it you know it's just
a different culture I suppose I suppose
in England they drink tea with a me milk
with tea I mean yeah so it's just
different that's that's that is all
about that so also some milk tea yeah so
back to the you know so in America you
don't cover these you know well the name
Papa milk tea is from big tits you know
the giant tits milk tea that's a slant
okay
but in America you cannot you know you
it would be hard to actually explained
our engine you know people like you know
don't talk about it basically yeah
especially the white leftist White's
comes ok the social social justice can
because they because you know on one
hand every day they are like oh we need
multi culture multi-culture but this
this this way up Tok giant it's milk tea
that's a random and Chinese you know the
day Eunice Natan suddeniy America oh no
no we cannot do that so that the the
multi culture of the left ok it's
actually just the white men white men
what means ideas with with different
hats with different sinker you you know
when they want what they want to
consider Chinese when they want to
support you know you know like Chinese
easy amor whatever community in the
American you know the left social
justice scan is that you know you just
put you know you just make your eyes
land oh yeah we accept you but you
believe me now ideally then for black
people
okay black people they are that's that's
a different story because blacks they
were they were from Africa but they were
you know they were bowing America for
like two hundred years now
anyway did the other cultures like Islam
okay yeah yeah you know anyway so that's
getting into another topic so yeah so
what I'm saying is that the the multi
culture you know that that's spread by
this social justice can is that they
it's it's it's it's it's just it's just
you know just white people's thinking
the left the leftist you know the
extreme leftist white people's brain
with colorful you know they want you to
put a colorful hat or different skin
then they consider that as my culture
you know because if you look around what
Japan Chinese you see Japanese anime you
know these little girls you know the
anime stuff and the Chinese you know
that they have you know they have women
tits you know statue in towns like in in
Thailand you know you cannot have that
in America so what is your multi culture
about I mean that the culture when we
talk about culture it's about true
culture not not oh you have slanted high
or whatever you have you know it's funny
hat or you wear a turban or or whatever
but but you're Indians you know with
feathers we're gonna you know whatever
the I mean the American Indians a Native
Americans what they call so so the left
left multi culture is just it's just
that I mean they they're multi culture
is just like people with funny hats and
different things they accept that
anything actually different beliefs in
thought
they don't follow they don't they don't
they don't support so it's the social
justice kind it's really skin' okay now
if so happens if you know I have
programmers watching my video you know
we have to have the you know after the
real time I hope to you know I hope to
you know convince and well not
necessarily come inside but I hope you
know I'm giving you some information so
if you can think twice if you are kind
of if you are in kind of in believing
this social justice that you know left
is kind kind of thing you know the
pronounced [ __ ] okay this today okay
back in 2016 you know I have treatise
right so I treated you know whenever you
know I have a crane I never followed
politics before that basically you know
none none of my father was up I'm I'm
I'm not following any political accounts
like I don't know much about it you know
and but but I see the news in and really
now and then you know every month
sometimes I treat I post something you
know that's my old you know about some
opinions about you know feminism is
stuff then you know I can see some you
know so all my followers and what I
follow are mostly almost all programmers
or you know or into math you know nuts
stuff so sometimes I put some opinion
you know really you know then III
noticed you know I do know some people
and followed me you know because at that
time okay - this is back in 2016 late
okay then I feel very bad you know when
I see that happens I feel very terrible
okay I feel I feel sad you know I'm just
you know feel you know I maybe I should
you know the but not today
you know today if you are one of those
people you know who is like posting
social justice stuff
every day pronounce feminism you know
whatever you know
go [ __ ] yourself okay you you are a Nazi
okay you are extremes it's not nasty you
you are about to kill you know a
thousand people million people is going
to die okay so I'm so if you still
believe that I hope like you know you
might consider but otherwise if you are
already strongly believing that okay go
away you know that that's what happened
today because there's so many stories in
the social media are lying every day
actually there is an example we are not
talk about today because I'm gonna
answer the comments in a minute okay so
today so there's another incidence okay
every day this is like if you actually
look into the issue every day on the
news okay
today the social you know the the
political situation is that yes you know
you know is heavily divided you know you
have the you know left you know like
their topic their subject every day is
immigration
you know the racism you know feminism
case trends you know kind of every day
it has become it's it's just basically
it's just became it's not really about
you know solving humanity's problems or
whatever it has become just the train
you know this is their ticket you know
this is the a flashcard you know I think
trans racism stuff you know they do
nothing just to they don't I don't
it's like they don't really care okay
this especially these people are very
rich okay it's not like being in
Hollywood you know the big you know they
have like they are all media areas okay
so these teachers or professors you know
right like you know the the you know
human equity Department whatever they
they they you know like universities
today these people this at the mean
strattice for the human what they called
equity and diversity I add diversity
Department they they make more money
than then the math professors the
engineering physics professors because
you know I've checked well I haven't
really looked in detail to verify but
but it's for you know one hundred
percent certain they make a lot of money
equal or more does the stat I've read
it's like a lot of them or at least at
some universities they make more than
math professors for example or physics
your chemistry professors and they are
the administrators I mean they are like
the the diversity Department you know
the head of diversity and equity
department that's why that's why this
happens because money because the more
of that you know the racism the the the
LGBT gay you know trans the more of
these kind of things the more they
thrive once you have actually truth as
how to solve some problems okay then
they don't have a job anymore
okay and many of these people a lot of
them are female okay women okay this is
sad to say but they are but that's a
fact the majority of them are women and
they why because why don't they go to
stem you know like science and
engineering like this social justice can
[ __ ] heads they want to women and want
to they want to force women to stem so
why don't you why don't they go to stem
because women in general and they are
not interested it's not the topic they
are interested so anyway this this these
people would mean people they makes so
much money and you know how college is
getting so expensive today and anyway so
like every day there's so many you know
issues controversies you look into it's
all lies like it's fake news you know
like like you know fake news by the way
do you know how fake news the word
do you know how the where dust came from
where does the term fake news came from
you know it's like almost like two or
three years ago suddenly everyone is
using it for his fake news and
especially Trump I guess I guess Trump
but whip but where does it come from I
found out you know there's a video for
my for my journalists okay a female
women reporter I'm following her okay
and she she did a video actually maybe
we should can search it she had I think
Ted X talked and she explained the
origin of the phrase fake news let's see
if we can find a video so you can look
otherwise arrangin of fake news there
okay go check out this video that's her
that's a journalist okay so I'm going
I'm not going to play it but you can go
check it out so basically the range and
the fake news is that it's actually some
kind of like Obama associated
organization okay they you know powerful
with lots of money they created this
organization and their intention is to
spread you know the term fake news the
concept to the population so that so
that actually actually they can control
you know information you know these so
they can you know say you know that
whatever they don't like this is fake
news and it turned out it backfired you
know it backfired by Trump know you are
fake news so yeah yeah so I found this
or engine
it's interesting because when I first
heard the word fake news like all the
media is using what everyday I mean
that's even before Trump start to use it
okay so you know I'm interested in in in
in linguistics you know the energy
strand and if for example Papa Mark T
where the word came from why is it Baba
okay so fake news while all of a sudden
where does that face came from and she I
I ran into her video I I don't remember
how but then as I then I started to know
how she say you know I'm following her
so you can very much she's a journalist
so she researched she had [ __ ] she had
the same curiosities she researched you
know the arrangement of the fake news
phrase so and the other thing I want to
talk about today is actually this
incidence by this Jim Jeffrey guy was
come back okay anyway let me read the
comments thing because I'm probably like
on a train of my own okay only for
people watching that's all of you I
guess so break the loop good evening oh
good night so bring the booze break the
loop says what makes you prefer browsing
with JavaScript off because because all
the virus is in tracking they all came
from JavaScript
once you have JavaScript off basically
you filter out 99.999 you know percent
of all possible viruses or you know
tracking or whatever and you know if you
code JavaScript then you know you know
you
it's from JavaScript that they can know
everything about you about your location
about your history about your what other
sites you check you know it's all
JavaScript without JavaScript
if you have JavaScript turned off
basically this is this almost nothing
they can do they did like all the
viruses you don't have to worry about it
almost it's like like like that unless
you clicked you know some download
something you know so I a disable
JavaScript but also once you have
JavaScript off everything is fast okay
and all the website like like I use
brave in general for my general purpose
browsing so whenever I see your link I
can I can it's like I can almost feel
free just click on it you know I think I
don't have to double check the link I
can click on it you know show you know
the site because I have JavaScript off
so that and and also it makes page
faster but but however note that today a
lot web site does not work with our
javascript twitter is a example a lot of
web site does not you know if you have
javascript orbiters off it doesn't work
okay do you find this there is enough
interesting content to read mastered and
AD no no if you are no if you are if
your intention is to actually find the
content or interesting content none of
the social media works not traitor now
master than none
basically yeah but you know twitter and
master then they are more like you know
so you know social network meaning that
you talk to some people you know your or
your friends your kindnesses so in that
aspect that's that that's how you know
useful that's how i find useful in
social networks so but but on twitter
you know basically on social networks
the more people you have the more
valuable useful it is mastered on you
don't really have that much people
but the people they attends to all be
notes so you know you can you know that
in that way it's good
meanwhile the traitor though you know
you have a lot of people you know but
they control because they use algorithms
to control information flow and they
have heavy censorship you know like I'm
a student I don't really worry about
talking about all the controversial
scene things like the social justice can
the you know the whatever the topics
they talk about every day I can I can
say it on Macedon without much worry
okay the does the that's a short story
the long you know the longer story is
more complicated because they are these
social justice can people okay they are
actually they have like I mean what they
do is they every day they they are kind
of like a code a militant code it's not
it's not just like okay the certain
people you know you know some percentage
of population have these opinions you
know which is different from yours okay
it's not like that but it's like they
are militant code they they aggressively
and actively spread their ideas but
meanwhile also I mean attack you know
wipe out anyone who disagree wipe out
actively seeking to wipe out anyone who
disagree that that's their goal I mean
understand this okay because I have
studied I have a obsession about coat
about brainwashing about marketing about
propaganda okay you know for like twenty
years
since since since since I was a team you
know the idea is that you know there are
some codes leaders okay I can say and
people like you know I have like
millions of followers and they all give
me money yeah you know like they all
give me their money and if I say okay
today's a day you should all die curious
and they'd cure themselves you know
their their coats like that so the idea
I mean so the idea is that how do you
how does the brain washing works you
know the marketing how do you influence
people and there are many books on that
you know not just you know it's it's so
important idea you know Google Facebook
they all have like professional
psychologist you know and in marketing
is you know billion-dollar industry so
basically that the the goal is how do
you sell things to people you know I
want to tell you guys by my Emacs yeah
you know Sammy this is send me money by
my Emacs tutorial you want to you want
you know as I say something you want to
get people to do it you know believe it
how do you how do you do that so if I
can say that you know but just you know
primarily Mike's tutorial and then
medium people do it you know that's
power so this is this is you know
together its marketing propaganda you
know brainwashing is kind of all related
chunk of thing you know influence people
you know how to how to do that and also
of high interest in militaries you know
so I have an interest in that and and of
course if you look if you look into
codes you know there are a lot even
today and is also ties to religion
because cause and religion kind of
similar entity they they differ in some
some minor did did you know differences
anyway so so so it's a big topic you
know and it's also a big academic
subject so how do you do that so anyway
I study that so so back to the social
justice scan so so one of the you know
the code things you know what might have
a good example is Scientology okay you
go study Scientology stuff they they are
a giant huge code very code very
powerful okay they have like
encyclopedias their own okay they have
their own set of encyclopedias about
everything of the world they have their
own dictionaries okay I mean they I mean
not own did like they have written
their own like encyclopedias and
dictionaries it's like everything about
everything about every behavior about
what rules or what you should do and so
on
so I study Scientology quite a lot and
you know they have jargons they have
like collection of joggins how you talk
you know basically it's almost like a
little language okay they they use them
on themselves okay so when I see anyway
so when I see social just just it's can
these these you know these people they
are things it's very extremely similar
the tactics are similar so today the
social justice can is okay so I'm what
I'm saying is that it's not simply you
know just a good people who whose idea
are different from mine you know and we
may argue sometimes we may agree
sometimes it's not like that
the they have tactics you know the best
way to consider is like a coat very a
coat whatever they do okay for all the
things you do you observe other what
they are like follow a certain rule
behavior okay which is taught by you
know in their group post-modernism you
know it's part of it so that so that
basically okay so so they are go they
did they have one goal okay is to call
their coat and wipe out any anyone who
disagree if you look at you know if you
studied code if you observe the behavior
of the social justice people you know
that's you can see that's their that's
that's what they do like the it's not
that they have these opinions about you
know feminism or maybe it's good or bad
or debatable you know it's not like that
it's actually more more realistic or
more a proper more more fitting more
correct to think of them as a code whose
the goal is to expand themselves and
wipe out you know eliminate who or any
who does a to who disagree using using
the the most you know the the kind of
perfected you know tried and true
strategies about behavior about what you
should do about what happens when
there's a conflict what what should your
reaction be you know it fits into that
very well the social justice can so
basically for example one of the things
they do is that they say if you know
first of all they dragged into they drag
race and sex into their to net you know
like for example you know they talk
about feminism trans and gays in a surf
okay baby it's basically sex okay why
sex because if you are a code if you if
your goal is to expand to maximum
possible you know you want to get the
whole population to get to get them
involved you know you have to have
something that everyone can relate to
and everyone can associate and one of
such a thing is sex
you know because either you are men or
you are women or these days you know you
also have trans or whatever like you
know forty different things okay so yeah
so you have that so everyone becomes
involved you know like normally in
politics when you have some issue most
people are not interested you know oh
it's politics you know it's about you
know economics or policy you know most
people are not you know he interested
but now it's about sex you know it's
about like male female and you know
stuff everyone is you know part of it
like you have to have a girlfriend or
wife you're gonna have daughters so
sense okay oh you have husbands you know
you know then it is so so so they use
this topic so they so they are ten eight
they they make this part of you know so
if you are caught you want to grow one
of the things that you want to get your
issue you want to raise the issue such
that everyone we are
has a part in it you know because this
this topic because it's you know the the
female of male stuff you know the sex
stuff is is is part of human you know
core part of humanity and then is and
its stony you know nobody you know
nobody can solve the problem because
there's always tension between male and
female not not just in human animals in
oak animals you can see you know males
fight to get a mate and the females you
know the compete and all that or that
you know fight to the death
to get mate often that's the time that's
often that's okay so you know so so one
of the thing you do is you know to get
into the subject as part of your Tonetta
or you know your your your codes rule
stuff so that everyone will get involved
and because insects is such a
complicated issue that you know this
there is no you know it's not it's not
it's not something like math or was
something that you can simply like solve
it I mean it's it's you know you cannot
even past you know it's not you know
it's not like there is a solution you
cannot even think of it as a problem you
know it's always issues between you know
male and female because we we are
different you know because you know the
the we what the needs are different you
know
so you see you see so that's that's why
you know sexy is the issue that and and
also the the other thing they do is you
know race you know because your skin
color your eyes and whatever it's always
every everyone relates to that so that's
also part of their thing so they give
these things to go their coat and also
notice one thing they do that they have
they have a mantra okay so like for
example they say if you are not white if
you if you are wider and and you do
nothing okay
then you are part of the problem like
you are complicit
okay Miwa so what does it mean so so you
can see from this perspective you know
this this idea this idea about if you
are white men and if you don't do
anything about it you know if you don't
participate about the discussion then
you are a bad person that's what they
say why do they say that because if you
you view these as you know the code
perspective I'm talking about because
that's one of their tactic that's that's
the way you know they want to prepare
these as one of their rules their belief
that you know if you are not if you are
white and if you don't participate in
this discussion then you are part of the
problem okay that's they want to sell
that as one of their belief okay for the
good of humanity but actually you can
see that this is this is their
aggressive way to get all people to
become part of them that's that's what
they do
so let me and get back to the comments
so I've been talking to for like um for
how long Oh one hour okay that's good
so right now here it's 11:30 p.m. near
midnight so I have to kind of lower my
voice so let me read the comments um
actually there's another topic I want to
talk about but I have kind of already
rambled quite a bit about this this
incidence happened you know like this
week anyway
so master done you know if you want to
join
I don't think actually I'm not sure it's
worth it I mean if you really I mean
yeah if you want to study you know stuff
computer science or stuff yeah anyway I
don't think social network is worth it
today okay any next and saying I know
we're bad also
well it's yeah so mobile yeah
Mobile is becoming more popular than
desktop this happened about few years
ago
yeah because is that that is true
because you know because for vast
majority of people they are not you know
nerds like you know only 0.01 less less
even less than that when one in in one
hundred thousand are nerds programmers
or engineers kind of that most people
you know they they are they don't know
technology stuff they don't know you
know so mobile you know like I have my
roommates you know they were working
restaurants they have no idea about what
what is a browser like you know it's
actually impossible even if you try to
explain to them for let's say one hour
it is you can see that you you know it's
impossible for them to understand even
if you try to explain to them you know
for one hour patiently what is a browser
they don't get it they don't know okay
so most people are actually like that
okay vast majority so for them but they
do have iPhones you know iPhones you
know they buy Apple's iPhones but they
use iPhone all the time you know they'd
need to talk to people and chat and
video chat - you know people in China
they do it every day so you see that's
the situation you know so why do I use
DuckDuckGo and not Google if I have
contains about dr. Koh because Google
Google is the evil and evil empire it's
far worse I mean my complain about the
taco is just one tech technique karate
you know some user interface stuff in
comparison to Google you know Google
thus far was you know because it's a you
know they it's far worse yeah so I
really do hope you know dr. Koh
improve but it's kind of hopeless with
you usually okay let's not be too
pessimistic pest pessimistic okay
usually this open source all kind of
this usually these typical nerds you
know my group of people they go [ __ ]
know where they don't understand you
know the society is fly make and fly
check no I never used them I never used
needle so zero zero ever could have
occurred Dora's Oh Erica Dora's we
should talk about algorithmic
mathematical art but it's too late today
talk about that Nick you know tomorrow
next day so let's see I'm thinking about
showing it to my grandma tonight I want
him to see how big it is I forgot what
that is about
zero zero Y zero zero avocado Rose you
should watch Siravo savage Z's X you
should watch siravo's Isaac's
explanation of fake news okay I don't
know who is that
Savo Z Zak okay he's got a Wikipedia is
a let's see so he says Slovenian
continental philosophy oh he's a senior
researcher and Institute of sociology
and philosophy at the University of
Ljubljana global something-something
okay
hanck Asahi hey break the loop
okay that's a link
Ted Kaczynski Ted Kaczynski is that the
Unabomber guy says social justice types
are over socialized yeah I should talk
about that no no don't show that link
let me show you my link okay on Obama
manna-fest oh okay do they show my
website yeah [ __ ] okay cuz I didn't hear
the Unabomber manifesto now I have
actually around 2005 I have read the
whole thing and I have actually
annotated it so for example a notation
for example let's see so this is on my
website sorry dog
una pan una bomba manifesto now if you
don't know what he is basically this is
Theodore Kaczynski okay he he was known
as Unabomber because around 1990s he
he's a serial killer
he killed you know maybe five or ten
people you know he basically he sent
bombs to people typically the leftist
professors but eventually he got caught
because of his brother you know gave
Cruz to FBI and the by the way he
happens to be a mathematician okay he is
one of the genius you know one of the
you know one of the top mathematicians
did you know very sharp guy so anyway so
he so anyway so back then he got before
he got caught he wrote this una bad you
know Bomberman affair
okay and he want the media to publish it
he says that if you publish it you know
I'll stop and nobody nobody did but you
accept the penthouse
you know Penthouse magazine whose pass
was you know Gucci something but anyway
Penn House published it and eventually
other people like where I was something
where Todd SF Dulce aired on us you know
anyway so he probably should published
it then his brother
read it and so you know found you know
this looks like my brother's book you
know so that's how he got caught so
anyway I read it I read the whole thing
and annotated in 2005 for example this
this chapter industrial so the manifesto
is is officially titled titled
industrial society and it's its future
this chapter the nature of freedom so
you know for example all the names
political you know all the historical
whatever names in books he mentioned I
have annotated you know I you know I you
know annotate you know telling you who
they are in stuff for example limit on
JavaScript
yes so you know you can its interactive
kind of and and also some of them are my
comments let's see
surrogate surrogate activities so that's
the Japanese Emperor over socialization
yeah that's the part you're talking
about okay so there is something I want
to okay the feelings of inferiority but
anyway so so back to the so this
actually I found many typographical
errors in his manuscript
I mean he's you know so these are all
the errors I collected you know for
example paragraph 27 parentheses is used
to mark footnote three and four
why our square brackets are used
elsewhere it's you know typographical
errors he made and paragraph 28
mismatched parentheses and so on you
know I have corrected them in my you
know in my Edition huh so anyway so what
is this manifesto about basically the
first half is criticizing the left the
left ISM basically the US leftism make
today's social social justice scan okay
they he criticized them severely like
you know the political correctness
things like that okay then the the the
the later half of the manifesto is where
he can nuts
he he he so his solution to the left his
problem is anti technology so in his
beliefs he believes that we should
eliminate all technology okay so he
he he's kind of he believed that we
should go back to you know something
like before industrialization okay
without you know tech and he's kind of
going nuts
he's very extremely in that I mean first
of all he describes some symptoms of the
you know the leftist you know the
American leftist political correctness
basically correct political correct
correctness captures the phenom
phenomenal man he is talking about okay
he made criticisms of the American
leftist then on the second part he is
trying to say his ideas about some
solutions and in this part he is so the
first part you know about criticizing
the left I pretty much agree and by the
way this is back in 1990s
you know I read it it in 2005 he's very
accurate his criticisms of the political
left okay
back in 2005 but the the the other part
of the article where he he's kind of
become nuts he is so he he proposed a
solution to basically he don't want
technology in society like eliminate or
technology yeah that that's that's
essentially what he says in this
manifesto now when I read this you know
what you know this is published in what
in nineteen in first published in I
forgot when in year 2000 around there I
read it in 2005 okay
oh no no no wait this is published in
1995 or before yes I remember because I
was at you know Illinois yeah the the so
the Unabomber manifesto is published
around 1994 or something but I read it
in 2005 anyway I read it I find his
criticism of the American left very
accurate but however at the time you
know I'm thinking wait a minute you know
back then you know in 2005 the US
society's mostly still controlled by
conservatives you know there was a still
very strong idea of God in religion you
know a Christianity you know in USA and
you know did you cannot fathom one day
we gonna you know there are people is
gonna you know the anti God in USA I
cannot imagine possibly imagine that
back then so when I read his criticism
on the left I was thinking hold on a
second okay it's very accurate but
however you never take you know even one
sentence to create criticize the
American right the Conservatives
conservative for example the the George
Bush okay george george w bush the
scumbag who bombed the wagon you know
like so what do you mean conservatives
so they you know they they do you know
the US you know they control or other
countries they control the world by you
know just just just just so that it
benefits them that's what they you know
to you know they they influence also
away the other countries politics in the
name of democracy okay usually it's fake
okay it's just just you know in the name
of democracy they control other
countries made up with other countries
of affairs you know today you know the
let's say russia gate russia get you
know yeah but the american is doing that
over the world for the past 50 years
like not just topple but percent
militaries or send huge billions dollars
to create faction groups to you know or
techniques or tactics possible you know
is so that's why we have all sessions
you know military stations over the
world you know like so
so I was wondering so why didn't you you
know you don't even have one sentence
one paragraph to criticize the
Conservatives so that part's alright
that's that you know I find that part so
that's my criticism you know about about
his criticism of the left okay
then the other part where he says we
should get rid of technology I think
he's just got nuts so I think he's just
you know this is like I don't see it
that way I mean even though I agree with
his criticism of the left but I don't
see you know reading technology is is
even necessary or you know I don't see
it that way so I don't so what I'm
saying is that I don't I don't find it
convincing I don't follow his logic you
know he to him he's probably like okay
so therefore therefore therefore and
therefore we should read of all
technology but I'm not you know seeing I
don't agree I don't follow
he's magic so he wasn't you know I don't
think we should throw away technology at
all so this is back in 2005 but today
it's amazing you know today what he said
has come true has actually become true
no I I don't know about the read of
Technology part but at least the first
part about criticism of left it has so
become so true you know they've like
reflected in a social justice scan it's
it's the word or I mean not just in u.s.
in UK in Canada in Australia basically
all the white people the white people
nations okay
it's becomes a chaos right by that like
political tomo to more
it's like meaning that you know people
don't really follow laws anymore so it's
not rule of law anymore it's not it's
it's rather just power struggle you know
if I have power I do whatever I want I
kill you I I screw you I get you fire I
do whatever because I
can because I got money you know society
has become that you know the then the
media is like lying you know everyone is
lying all days I think he's so fake news
yeah so I I was quite taken aback you
know actually you know many of these is
becoming true and you know a few years
ago to you know two years ago last year
people are citing my website on reddit
you know which is good you know if you
want to spread this straight my website
instead of others Indian guru okay so
I'm gonna check that
yeah Indian goo I mean that's old news
to me you know so you know you got this
Indian gurus in whatever yeah and some
of them you know they also say like you
know the in affluent places in USA like
like the Silicon Valley and lots of the
programmers you know they are into like
yoga and whatever [ __ ] and they follow
this guru is like you know like their
life is too good you know they get tired
of nice food rich food then they seek
then they also tired of you know
Christian arity they want something new
so they seek the you know the some East
and you know Buddhism or yoga or stuff
and mixed with New Age stuff like
pyramid or healing you know that this
Oh evoke Edoras seis I watched your
other livestream but thought you would
talk more about heart just briefly
mention mention architecture so you
would like to see more talk about
architecture now I was thinking I'm
going to talk about this subject
algorithmic but algorithmic mathematical
art okay I have this article I think
this is a great idea that I hope to talk
about it in one of the you know saw talk
show so I was thinking you know well I
was thinking you were asking about these
because this is one focus one topic that
I can you know talk about it in a
focused way because there's a subject
there
okay yeah lit yeah so we're gonna let's
talk about that tomorrow or something
yeah because I because I still you know
okay so I you know I'm pretty bad at
these but I really should have a
schedule and what topic you know but I
don't have it now so maybe tomorrow or
next you know next few days
make the loop yet today is actually my
first episode where I just simply talked
about the politics so zero zero says do
you know my dick see rekt know what is
that
let's see Urban Dictionary oh right how
is the major [ __ ] Center
oh so worst yet passed yet first yet
says just joined curious on what the
cheapest programmable keyboard is I have
been your I have seen you show of some
from China you haven't been able to find
them but haven't been able to find them
what do you mean cheapest for
programmable keyboard okay so I would
say okay just this one sorry
he warned I'm gonna make evil reviews so
if you go you know here and this one
yeah if your goal is the is a cheap and
programmable keyboard okay programmable
meaning it has memory and you can you
can program the firmware meaning that
you can plug this keyboard in any
computer or you know at work at home and
your work as you programmed it you know
building memory as opposed to cloud and
stuff whole software anyway so so smart
yeah I would recommend if you are
looking for you know not too expensive
ones but other than that okay smart
Yahoo Kinesis freestyle or expose okay
now actually mister perot code is also
apply so that that okay yeah so that's
the few I would recommend you know if
you go is programmable in in you know
not too expensive they are cheaper ones
though I think but I haven't really
looked into anyway
so I hope that answer the question if
you if that does not answer question if
you want to elaborate just type in the
comment oh you know just typing in my
video comments you go to youtube just I
like to see comments yeah so here you
know any question or comment or opinion
just type it I see all of them and we
see it okay by the way
ibaka Dora says by the way I think you
would be intrigued by this communist
Italian philosopher before okay
future ability okay yeah I haven't I
don't know much about him okay I might
look up you know the thing is you know
like there are so many philosophers in
books you know one can you know your
friends suggest you a book oh you know
but you don't really have time you know
especially especially if you're out
anyway so future rapidity let's see
what's his name before
okay Oh check it out so philosopher okay
yeah so so bossy at first yet so if you
want programmable keyboard I recommend
those I said but however if you don't
care if it's ergonomic then you have
cheaper ones for example I would
recommend you know actually a lot of
these gaming keyboard will do this
Logitech oh this one G and C a master
keys you know yeah so CMS the keys I can
recommend and these Logitech I can
recommend if you know if if you don't
care for economic ones but I actually I
highly recommend Okinawan okay this this
vortex vortex is also very good it's
also programmable and it's travel is
programmable yeah so these are I can
recommend they are like hundred dollars
this actually I can also recommend not
to take my you know but you may not like
the funky look if you don't like the
funky look there's this one also
programmable now programmable to me is
critical you know I would never use a
keyboard that's not you know firmware
programmable so yeah so these are the
choices if you don't care about
ergonomics you know but actually
economics you know being split and and
so on it's also critical for me so I
think that's about it today so I kind of
today's my my first talk show episode
that's actually completely politics
because you know the social justice it's
it's so getting so bad I feel you know
you know the world is crumbling you know
the USA they say you know Civil War see
Civil War is coming you know in in some
kind of shape and form and we are
already seeing
you know violence is you know for for
example the Chris Chris Church you know
whatever you know what what you know in
New Zealand you know from the social
just it's just the scan what they say is
that oh look they are you know we are
right all the time you know all this
time because look the violence from
these you know people that's not what I
see you know what I see is that you have
this social justice scan okay you you do
violence you know antifa you know you
you suppress all the normal people you
do bad things to all the normal people
the the Christian also the traditional
the Conservatives okay you do because by
power you do all these bad things to
other people you keep doing it you know
year after year after year until there's
a point people cannot take things
anymore
okay then you have this you know
whatever Church that that things
happened okay so that's what I that's
what I think and even back then back to
the other incident okay but in fact if
you take actually violence this far more
from the left okay
the difference is that anyway that
that's another topic okay so anyway
thank you thank you break the loop and
thank you guys for watching today hope
to see you next time bye