hello guys it is a very sad
disappointment because I've been
streaming in the
past 15 minutes in fact I finished
coding
it but I forgot to turn on the go live
button so all all is
wasted anyway we just coded this you
know and the explanation of the whole
thing in the past 15 minutes it works
okay let me Demo okay the code is
already done it's here so call S insert
do type enter there you have it now if
you want to insert different doc type
you press control U that's
emac uh tradition control U then meta X
HTML insert do type do it then you go
but you can pick a choice let's say I
want frame set okay then it insert that
doc type okay so that's what we're going
to do and I just actually coded but I
forgot to turn on you know go
live but am I Live Now okay I'm live now
so you know so okay so but uh maybe I
explain the code a little bit okay so um
insert doc type if un Universal argument
is called first prompt to
uh prompt to
uh to
select a do type from choices okay so
okay so how do you do it well you have
the if statement so if the current
prefix AR is true that is a building
local variable you can say describe
variable then read the documentation you
see that's a buildin local variable so
if this variable is true that means user
has pressed control U for the universal
argument before calling your command so
if that is true then you do this let
local variable
block if that is not true then just
insert the the HTML 5 doc type for you
example let's do it call the command do
it you see it just inserted now but
however the user if there's a universal
argument then you declare local
variables dock type and menu the menu is
is this five choices different doc type
choices okay and in fact we can put the
menu because you know so the
menu we can just move it here okay that
makes it kind of
um you know like set local variable to
this string uh I mean a list of strings
okay
so so then you call completing read then
a prompt pick one then a menu a list of
choices okay completing read will prompt
the user like which one to pick a choice
the result save the result as a doc type
then just insert it okay so that's how
the code works okay then now put it back
syntax CCT showing
browser there it is okay we we coded
this in 15 minutes so let today be
short so in fact it's only four minutes
now okay so should we do something else
or should it be this one um
um yeah let's try a short one so today
it's only five minutes we already have
the code now um so so you can go to Kar
emac tutorial just search for Kar emx
tutorial and you'll find my tutorial and
you'll find you know I explained how to
get user
input you know there you can get read
file name you can ask for directory or
file name you can ask for arbitrary
string or you can ask for a regular
expression or ask for a number or ask
user to pick a choice from a given list
this is what we used today or you can
ask us yes no question so you know so
that's one you know helpful uh for emac
this coding okay let's copy that go back
here showing browser and in fact paste
that link file okay and so there it's
helpful now so if you like my stuff go
all the way to
s.in then go to the bottom PayPal me
patreon me Amazon gift card click it and
paste my email address then type the
amount you want to send me okay credit
card whatever and PayPal okay thank you
for
that if you like my stuff and and
uh uh that's it for
today super short hello
F okay so yeah so so today right now
it's only six minutes okay let's try I
never done a six minutes before so
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching