Good morning, good evening everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Kasan Talk
Show. We are going to code Emac Lisp
today. Emacs lisp for programmers. This
is for computer scientist, for coders,
for programmers, and for those of you
young people because usually older
people, they already know what they
doing. So, let me introduce my
keyboards. Ultimate hacking keyboard 80
UHK.
I have a YouTube review. Look for it.
You'll find it. This is NIA track ball
na. [snorts]
Okay? And I have reviews uh I think I
have a YouTube review but also on my
website. Search for Kasali keyboard
um blog.
And this is my iPad with fantastic pink
uh protective
cover. Okay. Now let's switch. So let's
do let's go to Emacs. Let's uh go to
Emacs. So let's look at my screen.
So let's stop that. So can you see my
screen, my browser, my Emacs section, my
pink window of all my command course.
Yes. Okay. So let's do it casually.
Hello uh and
Andrew
Andre Rian.
Andre Rian. Hello. Okay. So yeah, so
we're going to focus on just Emacs Emac
Lisp coding in fact. So this is for you
actually those people who do emacs or
like mo mostly emac lisp coders. Okay,
you know, so for lisp coders, you might
be interested as well because emac lisp
is a lisp. Uh but um anyway, so let's
begin. Uh let me show you what uh we're
going to code. Okay, so first of all, so
again, if you don't know, this is Emacs.
I'm using this most powerful editor. We
don't want that showing browser. Okay,
and we don't want the to-do. Go there,
remove it. And the pink window shows all
my command course the name of the
commands and the keystroke on the left.
So as I move the cursor or or whatever
delete you know so you can see that
smart delete undo. You can see that's
undo and the key on the left. I'm using
a Vora keyboard layout and I'm using
softly keys. So if you do not know what
they are let me take 20 seconds to show
you. So this is source code of softly
keys 4,000 lines of code and go to the
top and here is the URL my homepage for
softly keys. It's the most efficient key
binding system for Emacs. It will makes
emacs more efficient than vi or vim by
scientific measurements like count
keystrokes of doing the same thing or
you can go play golf uh vim golf
[snorts] it will beat vim in in less
number of keystrokes okay that's
slightly keys it's modal just like vi or
vim or neo vim and so you can see so I
have like lots of videos about it like
tutorials how to install and there is
also a diagram of the major like what
what is like the uh key map. Okay,
that's five keys and the Vorac keyboard
layout. If you don't know already, Vorak
is like a letter arrangement like
normally you have corti which is q wer t
y and as sdf
you are familiar with most people but
there is vorac letter arrangement that
is more efficient. You got a o eiu.
Okay. Then of course there's also
comarmac. There's comarmac dh. There's
workman. There's quite a few other
ergonomic keyboard layouts. Okay. Soal.
So I'm using a Vora keyboard layout. So
when I type uh let's say this key on
quartD that's actually E. Okay. Anyway,
I'm using VA keyboard layout and I'm
using keys. Okay, that's introduction.
So fly keys is free of course. Go and
grab it.
Okay. So let's begin coding today's like
main topic. Okay. Close that. Close that
talk show. So I wanted to uh fix
YouTube. Okay. So let me tell you about
that one. So yesterday we did a talk
show about
yesterday. Okay. Uh Kasan music blog. So
yesterday we did did a talk show. We
talked about this music video of the new
generation breathing Ellens Musk a new
music video and I was talking about when
you want to blog a video from YouTube
for example so you go to the YouTube
website okay like you go to it you copy
the URL of course and but usually you
also want to copy the the title of the
video like that. Um [ __ ] it's not
annoying. Title of the video, the person
who uploaded it and also the date
typically. So copy, go back here. So why
do you want to so open new buffer paste
it? So you can see this is what you get.
Okay.
So you know by by the way there's uh
there is a very interesting fact about
this when you copy this this YouTube
title
poster and the date you know I know
because I do this you know I do this as
a blog you know I do blog all the time
or by now since 1996 so by now 30 years
you see but I've been doing the YouTube
you know blogging about some YouTube
videos in the past let's say 10 years 20
years basically since you YouTube began
now but but I noticed in the past like
five year uh let's say past 3 years this
every time you copy this the result is
different like every every month you
know very interesting because this this
gets into deep nasty details of the
corporations and deep state okay
every time every about every month. You
copy this title, you know, poster uh and
up to the date. The format is different
like yesterday. Actually, in fact, this
is different from yesterday we just did
like sometimes you you you will also
copy, you know, part of this view share,
you know, like 45K or subscribe like
appear here. Sometimes not. It changes
like it changes every month at least.
Okay.
And why do they do that? Because if like
if you can look at the source code,
okay, like actually you have to, you
know, these days the source code uh is
incomprehensible. So you need to like go
to the control control shift I go to the
console and to you know to use this kind
of like the ID for JavaScript to de to
debug and to look into like what's going
on with these uh tags. Anyway, the
reason they change is that they they
want to prevent other um they want to
prevent
bots
from passing from automatically grabbing
their you uh their videos or or passing
their titles, things like that. That's
why they change every month. So, it it
it can get very uh severe, you know,
like uh for example, can we see what's
going on here? So for example let you
know [clears throat] we actually we
should be doing uh eag this coding but
we digressed. Should I go back to emac
this coding? Okay. Nobody's watching
like nobody give a [ __ ] Okay. So
[laughter]
okay. So
so if you guys care if you guys like my
video okay say so. You know comment on
video comment comment on my YouTube uh
you know thumb up. I don't like those
things because those are nasty. Those
are like the corporation's way to
basically [ __ ] up all
actual
the communication for quality of the
content because of all these thumb up
actually they do negative things. So
anyway, so but but there's nothing you
can do you you know so if you guys like
it you know show my videos to your
friends blog about it things like that
okay and or comment okay anyway so let's
go back to this so I was saying that
when you whenever you copy this it
changes every I notice you know it
changes like every month because I have
a command to process this you know for
example I call the command kasa YouTube
uh description
HTML fix YouTube description. Press
enter. It will compact those lines into
this nice you know title, poster and
date. You see undo. You see before you
have like how many number of views you
have like subscribers.
So but now I call my command it'll
compact it nicely. So then I can like
make this into a list and I can you know
post this list in my uh blog about that
video YouTube video you see. But however
my command I noticed because I you know
because my command has to pass this it
changes like every [ __ ] month like
every month I noticed something you know
my my command doesn't work anymore. it
let you know it leaves you know the view
count or some other words like like
please subscribe or thumb up
you know it changes every every month
fascinating so let me show you the
command okay
uh kasan YouTube fix YouTube description
okay so that's a command you know that's
how I noticed it because I use this
command you know almost every other day
you know every time I blog a YouTube
video which is about almost every week
or two. So I noticed so you see for
example this example uh for example here
now this is a example when you copy some
uh YouTube video that's what you get
this is like uh three years ago okay I I
think this yeah this example must be
five years ago you see it used to be
like when you copy you get like um you
know the title the first one is title
then like number of views then you got
date, then you got like 1K, 17 share,
save, then this is a poster, okay? Then
subscriber of subscribers, but it
changes like it changes every month. I
noticed because I you see my my command
has to pass them like whenever you see
sign in, you know, you like for a period
of time, it will also show sign in. So,
you have to remove that. Then for a
period of of time you you know you have
subscribed like like please subscribe
like this subscribe button like where
did it go or this button you see but it
changes you see so anyway
so what I want to do today is that you
see so I do have this command so let's
um so let's copy the command why don't
we copy it close it okay now close that
we don't actually uh reopen Let's um
[snorts] leave that for now. So I wanted
to right let's go back to talk show and
showing browser. Let's talk show today
and go down. Go down. Go uh go to the
section uh go to the section and
make a new section. Okay. Make a new uh
eag this code block. Paste the code.
There it is. And uh press a button to
pop it out. So we're going to modify
this command. Okay. Why why do I want to
modify it? It's only 73 lines, not long.
Uh most of the lines is actually this
comment. So in fact, it's like just 50
lines, 40 lines. Okay. Why? So why do I
want to change it? You know because
right now this command is dependent on
this this command this command is an
external command replace regular
expression pairs region. What this
command do is we replace so so you want
to replace the low line by a space. You
want to replace tab by a space. You want
to replace amp% by a and d. You want to
replace this sign in something by empty
remove it. So this command replace
regular expression pairs region is a
very convenient command. So you can have
a list of pairs of find replacement
pairs and it will do it in one shot.
Okay. So very convenient. But however
there's a problem now. MSC are going you
guys watching. So say hi. Okay. Say hi.
Uh uh can you actually see me? Uh video
check, audio check. Yeah, I think so. So
so this command is very convenient. So
copy. So let's uh describe function and
let's look at it. Okay. So replace
regular expression pairs region is a
function in this package and this is
usage example. So you give a region
beginning, specify the region beginning
and end and list of pairs and it will do
find replace. Okay, super compact code.
But the problem is that it it is an
dependency.
That means every time people want to use
your code, they need to uh they need you
know they need to get this package which
they need to get this package. Okay,
which is replace
pairsel
which so so this is the definition of
the function here. Okay, which is not
too long. Okay, we it's like 30 lines of
code. Okay,
third 20 lines of code even. So, but
okay. So, this command this package and
it's available. You can grab it if you
want. So you go to this URL kasali.info
or you can just search for it. Search
the web emacs replace
pairs.el
you will find the command. So it it
shows an example how convenient it is.
But the problem is dependency which
becomes very annoying as I realized as
people realize in general in the
software industry dependency is really
nasty on one hand as a software engineer
it's really necessary because then you
know you have libraries you have modules
you you don't want to repeat the code
you know everywhere hundred of times you
know you have libraries and modules and
Right.
But um so you you basically build a
structure you know you build like a
cathedral or whatever using components.
U but but when you distri distribute the
software when you have dependencies
depend on on some other library it
become very annoying because the code
becomes
like it's not one unit anymore. Like
every time you want to pass it around,
you need to tell people, oh, you need by
the way, you need to you need that thing
and how do you get that thing? Oh, you
get it by this this or that way you know
become complicated and software becomes
fragile because the dependencies even
though you think it's you know people
can get it but you often you know some
sometimes not
you you are you know you have the
missing piece problem
so anyway so what I want to do is close
close that so I want to do is we want to
remove this dependency we we just going
to write this manually so that so that
this function
is no longer is is is a unit by itself
you know I can just show it you know for
for example you look at my son talk show
go back to talk show
in browser you know you can just look at
my talk show and grab the code it will
work but not right now with the
dependency okay so that's what we going
to
We just going to remove this uh this
this uh this by
by without dependency. Okay.
Okay. That's what I'm doing. Okay. Uh
now have let's have some coffee. Coffee.
This is coffee and milk.
How how many people are interested? Two.
Okay. Emac bisp.
It took me 20 minutes to explain the
situation. Okay. Okay. But that's okay.
So, okay. So, that's the one we don't
want. So, let's start to do this.
Um, so what do you want? So, this is
easy. Okay. So, if you guys don't know,
for the for you, those of you eag
coders or beginners, you go to my
website kasali em eagisp
basics. You you can you can just search
for
Emacs tutorial.
Okay. Then go to Emac this basics. Uh in
fact you want to do find and replace
then that's the EMAC list section. Okay.
Because it's not about variables,
functions, conditionals, if then else
data structure. Those are the lisp
basics.
you know uh string what is a string what
is uh what is a number what is a boolean
what is a numerical operation how do you
compare numbers how do you define a
variable that's basics
that's basic lisp okay but we want to go
to emac lisp because this is lisp but
specialized for emacs which is about
find and replace okay so if So just go
to find and replace text processing.
That's right that section. And
there it is. So this this find replace
text in buffer. How do you do it
programmatically?
Go there. That's that's a function.
Okay. And if you want to do multiple um
you know so I explained the general like
the idom. How do you do if you want to
do multiple pairs basically like this?
Okay. So, you can just copy the code,
copy it. In fact, we're going to do
that, you know. So, this is uh my EMAC
this tutorial on how do you find
replace? So, let's just start to do it.
Okay. So, let's paste the code. So, here
it is. Save restriction. So, EDM for
multiple string replacement within a
region. Okay. A region is a beginning
and end position. So beginning position
that would be so let's um
that would be that.
Okay. So
now to region. So yeah uh begin and
position and we actually we just want so
let's just delete that whole thing.
Okay.
Region actually
wait. Okay.
Uh okay. So
this about this thing we let's just copy
it.
Okay. So, close that. And what we want
to do is we can actually so go back
here.
Delete that.
Okay. So, yeah. So, we don't need that.
So that okay so now you just need a list
of pairs. So can can we go back here? Go
back here. So the list of pairs we are
interested in is co.
So the list of pairs are these and um
okay so for each line like that we want
to turn it into this.
Can we do it? Yes. So, let's um
So, do we want plain text or regular
expression? We want well uh the first
two is plain text. The first three is
plain text. The rest is regular
expression. Okay. Uh but but they are
similar. Okay. So, let's see.
Okay. plain text find replace the
difference is just uh one is search for
word the other one is rearch for word re
for regular expression okay so delete
that delete that delete that delete that
delete that okay so let's see if we can
write a marquo so we want to write a
marquo so that each line of this becomes
a line like that
can we do that Yes.
Okay. So, first of all, let's transform
this by removing the square brackets.
Okay. I have a command which is
that which is change bracket pairs.
Okay. So call that and you want to
change square bracket by none. Fantastic
and complete. You see? Now the next
thing I want to do is um
you just want to replace. Okay. So what
do you want to replace?
Find and replace. Okay. So,
so the first part is the fine string.
The second part is as we play string.
Okay. So, the first part is the fine
string.
Uh anyway, so wait. So, the second part
is a replace string.
Okay. So, what you're going to do is
so the middle part is is this. Okay. So,
first of all, let's change the middle
part.
Change that by
that.
Do it. Do it. Okay. Then
then you just need to change the
beginning and end. Okay. So the end
would be
the end would be that and the beginning
would be that I think so. Okay. Uh
Okay. So
change
a return
do it replace by that.
Let's just do it. Okay. Uh
uh would that be would this does this
look correct? Now move that one to the
beginning actually.
So we did new one
Okay. So, search for word. Let's read.
Let's compact that.
Okay.
And let's
let's uh
make that into two lines.
Okay. So, looks like we did it.
Does that look correct? I think so. You
see, we have um
transformed.
Let me show you the other code. Okay,
we have
we have transformed
this block of code
to
to this. Okay, let's see if we can.
Okay, so we began with this block of
code. Now we turn that into that. Now
you actually need to um
prefy the code. I think that's it.
So, make a backup.
Uh, wait.
Make a backup.
Wait.
Okay. Go to the directory by compile.
Let's see if compiles. No.
Uh, file has no lexical binding
directive. Okay. So we can add it.
Usually it asks you for lexical binding.
So X UTF. Okay. Now there's a lexical
binding.
Now B for compile. So let's do it again.
By compile. Okay. Uh warning. Unused
lexical variable XPT. Okay.
So,
oh, I didn't use the XPT. That's right.
Because I made some change. Uh,
actually, I should use XPTt. Uh,
and let's go to char XPTt. Okay.
Now, save it. Back up. Back compile.
Fantastic. No error. Okay. Delete the
back compile.
um code.
So we here here is the code we made a
change and now this version is
this version does not have any
dependencies.
Uh but it's quite a lot more worthy. You
see you got this version versus that.
This one, this is so compact, you know.
Okay. So, I mean, so right now I'm
thinking, do I should um like do I want
to go with this? Now let's evaluate it.
Put it back. Syntax color it show in
browser.
So we got a code here.
So you got a code here. Um okay.
And uh let's modify the description so
that
um
so that um
let's copy that. Okay,
talk show. So, let's modify the
description. Um,
actually this also this is also changed.
Okay. So, actually it becomes that
You see?
So let me tell you what's going on. So
originally you would have that. Okay.
And now it becomes
now it becomes
that. Okay.
So yeah. So this part we can make
delete.
And uh the and uh
delete
and put today's date. Fantastic.
Delete unwanted YouTube description
under cursor. Okay. If region is active
use that else act on the text between
between the
greater than and less than sign for
example start with that
and uh then it becomes that okay and
here's the code and uh evaluate the code
okay quite wordy okay
quite wordy D.
So
yeah. So it's quite worthy
but but however it
it doesn't have the dependency problem.
You see
it's not as compact as this.
Okay. So what you want to do? So let's
have a look at them. Okay. So let's have
a look at them
actually.
Actually
evaluate it. put it back and uh create
another emac this block.
Go back to this code and cut. Okay,
you want to see which one is kind of
better. Okay, so
hello
Uh, I saw your last stream and hope that
you make a dedicated video about Unix
and why do you think it's a disease? I
only hear Unix philosophy praise and I
like to hear a different take. [snorts]
Uh, I have done about 10 videos on that.
Okay. So, you have to just search for my
YouTube. Okay. on why Unix sucks. In
fact, last one is about
two weeks ago or maybe last week. Okay,
so
for that question, you can go to
um go to sorry blog. Hold on a second.
Okay, let me clean clean this music
block. So this is my command. Uh
third undo close. Okay. Paste it there.
Syntax color everything.
And uh actually in fact uh there is some
so showing browser. So we got two
versions of the code. Original version
here
with the compact find replace pairs and
the new version
not compact. However, it is it doesn't
have dependency problem.
I think I'll use the this new one. Okay.
But the old version needs also update
because uh remember we changed the
documentation. You see the documentation
should be updated to the new um like
here.
Copy back paste it there. So for example
that becomes that. Okay. So put it back
again syntax color everything show in
browser.
Okay.
So we got two versions. So the question
is which one do I want to keep? I think
I want I'm going to keep the new one
because
dependency is really nasty. Okay.
Although this looks so short and neat,
you know, Emacs, Emacs
uh really should have a function built
in that does multiple pair sequential
find replace. So you can have this
instead of you know like
find bind you know something then
replace then go to chart to the
beginning then do it again you know.
Okay. So regarding the your question
about Unix, why Unix sucks, I have done
hundreds of videos on that. Okay. So
like go just go to Sound Talk Show,
search for Unix. Okay. So, the last one
I did a week ago, 2026, February 8th,
episode 759
on Wuan language coding session, plain
curves, geometry, and why tech sucks and
Unix code. So in the last 10 minutes or
so or maybe was it 20 minutes I ranted
about in relation to the this topic
about the Unix code
this Unix people you know I despise I
truly hate the Unix people
and that is why I have done hundreds of
videos not actually not 100 but but more
like 10 hours worth 20 hours worth
talking about why I hate Unix in every
way in in in in technical detail in
examples of code in you know their
documentation man pages. So anyway, so
one of the you know, so one of the video
you can watch it probably start with
this one because this this is just last
week. Okay, check the time stamp you
know American let's see where is it
critique you know so this is around um
time 48 minutes in a video critique of
Unix and related tools he strongly
criticizes Unix C Vim and tech
as disease or code phenomenon okay
arguing that they promote outdated and
brainless practice practices. He
references the Unix haters handbook and
views his work as a lifelong fight
against the Unix code. Okay. Now, is
that the one you have watched or not?
And uh
maybe you have watched this one. In that
case, you know, go earlier, search for
Unix again. So, not this year. So let's
go to year 2025.
Search for Unix. So there it is. Episode
681. Why is Unix operating system named
so? Okay, that's like one that's one of
them. Is there a AI summary? No. You see
at that time we don't have like we don't
have AI summary yet. This is 2025
July. Okay. So search again. Search
again. Okay. Python history episode 625
Python history
and crimes of Unix C line truncation.
Okay. So, so there is timestamp which I
manually created. So, you can watch that
one and then uh you can go then you can
search again search my YouTube on Unix.
you'll find 10 more at least 10 more um
videos. Each one is about one hour long.
My rant against Unix, Linux and
associated you know open source
fanaticism
uh basically basically they all they
they all came from this kind of the Unix
uh code. Okay. So they all kind of came
originated together
about 40 years ago with a Unix operating
system which then you have Unix
philosophy which later on it became you
know you got this Unix philosophy which
is a code jargon you know and uh the C
the C programming language part of the
Unix and and you know bunch of things
then then the fanaticism the hacking
mentality like the programming style,
the view of programming, software
engineering as kind as some kind of
trick, you know, with bits.
So the whole thing you know about the
Unix and later on it became Linux. Okay.
So I talked about that. So um have you
seen them? I will search and watch these
videos. Yeah. Okay. So you know check it
out.
Yeah. So and in fact you know so you
know I can tell you you know one of them
so if you just search YouTube there's
one that's more popular but then few
years ago you know it's funny YouTube
like viewer popularity is not
uh relational is is not proportional to
how good the video is. Like some of my
videos they became popular like you know
10,000 views or something like you can
you can just search why Unix sucks on
YouTube. Okay, YouTube s let's say uh
let's say uh actually just search for
Unix sucks
you'll find you'll find a few. Okay so
Unix code Linux surplus a crime of
computing industry the damages it has
done. Okay, so this is 3 years ago and
this one 2022 why Unix web sucks history
of regular expression wam language
string expression okay so that's another
one related to Unix uh then another one
2020 5 years ago Jesus golan backup Unix
shells and why Unix sucks donkey ass so
this is like my
like almost my earliest one five years
ago. Okay, that was that was you know
when I was um anyway so you can see my
old videos. Okay. Then there's another
um Okay. So anyway,
then you know, so anyway, so if you
wanna like
check out my rants against against Unix,
there's quite a lot quite a lot. And and
in some of them, I get very angry like
[ __ ] the Unix. [ __ ] the Unix people.
Okay. Like you you don't you don't
understand. Okay.
So anyway, so that's this is like my
life like my lifelong obsession okay of
the basically
to put it blunty Unix's hatred it is my
lifelong obsession or you can say my
lifelong work okay as a uh let's say as
a um
uh t you know take uh programming
language computer uh tutorial writer and
observer you know kind of
yeah
okay so that's about that so anyway yeah
so I did a lot of video so you know so
they they you know some of them I try to
be like like sometime when I say someone
who does videos or lectures like
sometimes you want you you think about
can you create one coherent like the
best summary for example why I think you
know Unix sucks
uh but the fact is that I've done that I
have done that in some of these videos
you know I consider at that time that's
the best like you know summary of why
Unix sucks I've done that but the the
the problem with the you know the
problem with kind of the YouTube and in
general not just me but
other people is that Um
I mean including professors you know
like like like the you got millions of
new videos every day. So even if you
have the best lecture on a topic it it
just goes go away. It just like get
buried. So so so
you know so I have made a page if you
you know like if you check my um s talk
show index there's a s talk show best of
index. Okay. So, if you wanted to see
like my Unix hatred, did I archive some
of them here? Uh, okay. So, there's
episode 530
2024 January. Uh, this is Unix uh move
versus rename. Okay. So, let's search
again. So, what is this about? This is
about um the cryp sign.
Okay, that's about the crypto sign.
That's about not. So let's see there.
Okay, hack. So there's a section
dedicated to the to to the thing you are
interested hacker culture Unix Linux the
crimes of open source in free software
foundation. Okay, check out that one. is
actually a time stamp so you directly
jump to the point.
The crime episode 711
the crimes of open source and free
software foundation [ __ ] Okay,
they they do damage to society to
humanity
to uh to to our uh community programmers
in my opinion my opinion.
So that's one uh I mean so that one
there the episode 711
the crimes of open source and free
software foundation which is very much
related to Unix. Okay. Now the free
software foundation their name is GNU
which stand for GNU is not Unix.
Very interesting history. Let me talk
about that. Okay. I don't know. I don't
think I have talked about this before.
GNU is not Unix, you know, the Unix
[ __ ]
They, you know, like they they think,
you know, they they they like people
don't know, you know, since like they uh
Oh my god, the hacker culture. I heard
heard that like are you like I I suppose
you you guys are pretty young. Like how
how old are you? Like [laughter]
anyway, that means I'm I'm too old. uh
you know so the GNU is not Unix you know
like
do you know why is it named like that
GNU is not Unix I mean so this is like
several levels of the
like people don't know you know so
Richard Sman named oh you are 32 okay
you are not too old but but [ __ ] it um
oh you are 39 so you guys you guys are
not code. So, what do you mean you
haven't heard of hacker culture?
Okay, but well, you you probably have,
but uh it's hard to understand, you
know, actual what you know what people
are saying via the text. Anyway,
so the GNU, you know, you have the free
software foundation with their um
project called GNU GNU, which the hacker
idiots that [ __ ] despise them, you
know, but the they are proud of the fact
that, you know, when you ask them what
does GNU stand for, they say, you know,
here's this is what they say. Oh, this
is this is a a recursive acronym. [ __ ]
them. Okay, this this is like one of the
trivial like aspect of why I despise
these hacker idiots, you know. So,
especially the Unix people, you see,
they like to play on these little trick
words, you know, you know, like
recursive
acronym. Okay. So, but if you if you if
you are in linguistics, is there actual
such a thing recursive acronym? No, it's
just the hacker created it out of the
blue, you know, because they, you know,
in computer science you have the
recursion. So they created the word
AC R O N Y M. Okay, recursive acronym,
right? So you got that, you know,
recursive acronym. A recursive acronym
is an acronym that refers to itself and
appears almost frequently in computer
programming. Okay. The term was first
used in print in 1979
in Douglas Hofstatter's book. Oh well.
Well, I didn't know. It's actually this
guy I highly respect. Okay. Douglas
Hovat Statter. Uh he's uh he he's like a
kind of a mathematician type of like
intellectual. Okay.
Uh so uh what his most famous work he's
known for this book having written this
book Godell Asher and Bach all these
topics people I love okay like um like
two days ago I talk about my favorite
uh piece of music that's spark and I
have a whole collection of you know I
bought Asia's book you know like the
huge topic and Godell like yesterday I
uh yesterday YouTube I talked about live
stream about
uh problems of set theory and proof
theory and type theory and you know
those kind of topics. So all these so I
very much you know this this is Douglas
Hofstatter is my type of guy but
actually so I bought this book in 1993
you know very early on I actually never
read it I like I read one chapter and
apparently that's very common a lot of
people you know bought the book think
it's great but actually never read it
that's that happened to me that's the
case in fact I I do I have the book
somewhere Yeah, like you must be
somewhere
uh you know so so this is a great guy.
Okay. So anyway, so the the the so
apparently the the jargon recursive
acronym is um is created
in 1979 by this guy. Wow, I didn't know
that. That's interesting. Okay. So,
wait.
So, what uh
Okay. And that's you know, by the way,
this video is interesting. This chick is
hot. This chick
emu. Okay. And then this guy is also uh
becoming famous. Asmo Gold. Okay. I
didn't know about him until like a year
ago. And I didn't know about you know
this Emiru. I I guess you guys might
know uh if you are young, you know,
maybe
you know this like young you know this
new generation of like stream streamers.
Anyway, so recursive acronym. Okay, so
apparently this guy first used it. But
my point is that these hacker types like
the Richard Stoman
well most you know I despise the C and
Unix but I like the lisp camp anyway but
the the hackers okay actually I'm very
much uh have a lot in common with the
hacker group that's me actually you know
but I don't like but I don't you know I
don't like hack I don't like hack
anything you know I'm a like if you you
know I'm a computer scientist. I'm a
mathematician. I'm a great, you know,
programmer. I'm a software engineer. I
don't hack. [ __ ] Go hack your mom's
ass. You know, these hackers, I despise
them. But what they love is is hacking.
The the the very aspect, you know, they
can do little tricks, you know, so to
make it work, you know, this the very
nature of hacking. That's what they
love. That's the what how they identify
themselves, you know, a great hacker.
which I despise
although although we are like in kind of
you know have the similar interest so
anyway so about this recursive acronym
you see I'm also interested in
linguistics and vocabulary right so they
too you know so but they but they they
started to like in other words abuse you
know they they start to coing words like
gnu gnu is not gnu is not unix oh look
We we created a fun acronym, recursive
acronym. By by the way, this is called
recursive acronym. Your ass. Okay, this
this this hacker [ __ ]
So they created that word and they they
pretend. So all of a sudden like they
they are the you know this is the valid
valid you know according to linguistics
you know this recursive acronym which
actually doesn't exist. Then it got
abused so much you know like for for
example PHP
pretty homepage my pretty homepage
then when then PHP be PHP became most
popular you know then the PHP Wikipedia
page they they started to lie these open
source [ __ ] they lie they say PHP
stand for um something something um fix
processor you
>> [laughter]
>> you know what what what what is it? What
was it? PHP um hypertext processor. PHP
is not hyper you know like like they
they also started to to to have some
recursive acronym so called um let's see
if I can remember it correctly. PHP.
Uh, let's see if I have a PHP.
Okay, it stand for PHP is hypertext
processor. Something like that. Okay,
let's look up PHP.
They lie about this on Wikipedia for
like 10 years. Okay, do you guys
understand? Do you guys understand my
hatred of these people? The PHP in
computing industry. They lied
on Wikipedia homepage. You can you can
you by the by the way if you don't
believe me you can go back view history.
Okay. Go go go to the view history
section. So what did they lie about for
10 years minimum on the PHP page article
on Wikipedia?
They say they never mentioned that PHP
stand for uh personal homepage. The
origin
of what PHP means historically.
They never mentioned it for 10 years.
Instead, they say, "Oh, by the way, PHP
stand for recursive backon, PHP
hypertext preprocessor.
[snorts] [ __ ] liars. [ __ ] them. Do
you guys see my hatred? You know, you
know, like sometimes you like I get
that, you know, I get I know, you know,
I'm regard being, you know, I'm I'm
being regarded as like weird guy
sometimes or crazy, you know, jobs, but
do do you guys see like my hatred of
this situation,
the Wikipedia article, which is of
course very popular like almost as a
reference for more than 10 years. For
more than 10 years, the Wikipedia
article on the most popular programming
language PHP contains a lie that it
never mentioned that PHP originally
stand for personal homepage. It just
says PHP stand for the recursive backon
PHP hypertext prep-processor.
Okay, do you guys get it?
this [ __ ] you know [ __ ] you know
offends me but but what's more every
time I mention this to other programmers
especially to these Unix people or the
hacker types you know they they ignore
they ignore it like they you know in
this case you know this this is a bad uh
aspect of PHP usually they agree you
know they they like they attack PHP all
the time. This Unix and C [ __ ] and
this [ __ ] they these people this
Unix C
they attack PHP programming language all
the time because PHP is considered like
a bad language because for it's for
beginners it's too easy this C and Unix
[ __ ] scumbags they like you know
real men's language that's complicated
difficult to understand C and C++. So
they attack PHP all the time for more
than 10 years. Do you guys know do you
guys remember that history? You know
like like most of the 2000s. Okay. But
meanwhile the PHP does the marketing
marketing lie you know they they try to
erase you know oh what what do you mean
personal homepage? No, we are no we are
hypertext preprocessor and we are
actually recursive back on them. It's
related to linguistics very advanced.
[ __ ] them.
Okay, but this but again this is like
trivial matter. Why why are you like so
get angry? You know actually I'm not
angry this I'm just expressing you know
like but why am I like focused on these
little things? Because I'm a nerd. I'm a
hacker. Okay, I cons I'm concerned about
this little factual details. You don't
you know you should not lie. Okay, now
back to the recursive acronym. Okay,
back to the recursive acronym I haven't
done yet. Okay, there's a lot. Okay,
beginning the first the most famous
recursive acronym is GNU GNU by Richard
Stoman. Okay,
then there's a lot in the list
community. Why? Because for example the
the you know then then you got let's see
uh in I is not emac that's the first
lisp based that's first emac written in
lisp okay I then zy which stand for z y
was i initially you know like you know
they just created out of a blue oh so
they they actually they came first
before gnu okay so actually those two h
interesting I didn't know so Those two
came before GNU. [clears throat]
Okay. GNU is not Unix. Okay. So why do
they do that? Because this actually the
reason is these are lisp people. Lisp
programmers you know they are into
recursion you know. So they they are
very fond of this recursion concept.
Okay. But but okay that's one thing. So
the other thing I want to say is that
the you see the least people are the
enemies of the Unix people. Okay, the
Unix and C [ __ ] Now today you guys
don't know and also back even in the
1990s people don't know. People think
that you know Emacs and GNU they are
just like Unix. They all love Unix but
that actually they are actually enemies.
Okay, the Richard Stoman, the Emacs
people and Lisp machine, Lisp, you know,
list machine and list uh Lisp coders,
they hate Unix just like me. I'm I'm on
the list side. Okay, we we despise Unix.
I we think Unix is the worst [ __ ]
possible.
But people don't know people people, you
know, they don't they don't know about
it since like 1990s.
They think oh Richard Sman they you know
you you should use Emacs or VI because
both of them are you know for Unix
[ __ ] idiots. So so so by now by now
which is like 30 years after we have
like layers of ignorance you know like
layers of
you know misleading facts and ignorance.
It's it's like you know history is like
you know like there's a comic there's a
comic when you look at you know there's
a movie in year 3000
you know people coming you know humans
coming out of a movie theater in the
year of our lord 3000
okay and the movies the movie's title is
world war I okay then you got then you
got uh propeller airplanes fighting with
jet fighters and there's a laser
shooting up you something like that.
So, um anyway,
anyway, that's a that's a big rant about
So, there there you go. You have some of
my rant about Unix and uh why I hate
them. Uh and again, this is not a big
deal. I mean so so far like what we
talked about in the past 20 minutes
about this this use of phrase recursive
acronym it's it's no big deal and PHP
well yeah they lied they lied a little
bit about you know marketing they
pretend they are you know they they try
to
uh it's marketing you know it's just
marketing they they they obliterate you
know the history of the word the phrase
PHP for personal homepage instead of
they say hypertext prep-processor and
they add the the academic you know mumbo
jumbo recursive backon right so that
that's my comp complaint okay about this
this um well this is not related to Unix
but the GNU is the GNU you know the
recursive acronym so that's so this is
like just a one small aspect of my
dislike why I dislike this kind of the
hacker types and the Unix people. Okay,
this this is a small part um and this is
not a technical part but so I was saying
in the past I've done a lot videos
talking about many other aspects.
Okay, that's about that.
Uh so
am I Christian? No, I'm not. Is that not
obvious?
So let's see what you guys are saying.
And uh did we finish what we want to do?
Actually, no. actually because I got
lots of other things to do. Uh should I
continue? Yes, because you know because
um so we talked for
oh only 50 minutes. So we got like 10
more minutes at least to one hour but
actually I got few other things to do.
So let's do them because
why? Because recently I got influenced
by these by these uh streamers, you
know, like today you have quite a few
streamers, right? He's he's one of the
famous guy, the Asmo Gold.
And then for for the girls, of course,
there's lots of these pretty girls. Emer
[laughter]
like what the [ __ ] they do every on on
stream? Anyway, I don't know. So, I I
looked up a little bit, you know. So,
like I asked a question.
I asked um
I I I I I posted about it on Twitter
about streaming like what like what do
also on my discord?
Let's see where do uh where did I talk
about that AI art? So we were talking
about things you know people on discord
like what does this like what does these
um
you know streamers like there's quite a
few very popular you know like they got
few million followers like what do they
do every day like so do they just like
chat like random chat every day for a
few hours
what else do they do so I you know so I
got so turns out. Yes. Actually, a lot
of them is they just chat just like like
like what I'm doing now, you know, they
just chat for hours a day [laughter]
and you know, they tell you their
reactions about about news, their
opinions about whatever is going on. Uh
so
no but that but you see but that's kind
of nasty because you see for example
this one this one I've watched only two
minutes. Oh wait is it only two minutes
anyway I I think I've seen because
YouTube you know showed it to me. So
this you see three months ago people
have found the clip uh you know so this
one so so basically what they doing this
one in particular is that they basically
just fry drama
like that that's what this this Zuma
[ __ ] do fry drama because what he's
talking about here is like he's he's
saying that oh there's this girl this
Emmeru which is very popular one of the
most popular, you know, uh, live
streamer for girls,
you know, they got like millions and
millions followers.
And someone apparently someone asked
Emmeru about what do you think of the
ICE, you know, the the the
immigration, you know, the [ __ ] up, you
know, that Trump is doing. And Emu says
like, oh, you know, I don't talk about
politics, you know, like if you don't
know yet, you know, you should know. I
don't talk about politics. That's what
she said. And then people started, you
know, people, you know, according to the
video, people got angry at her. You
know, you know, people attack her like
on Twitter, you know, like, oh, you
should, you know, you should, you know,
something something, you know, nasty.
Lots of nasty. And some of them from
girls, of course.
So that's drama, you know. That's the
drama you see every day on Twitter. You
know this this by these [ __ ] zoomers
by these [ __ ] zoomers scums.
That's what the that's what you guys do.
The younger generation, the zoomers, the
[ __ ] scums like team uh Tim among
others among others. [ __ ] the [ __ ]
scums. Zoomers. They just go talk drama.
Oh, this girl, oh that guy did
something. Oh, and you know this
shouldn't, you know, you should
something something the [ __ ] scums
and that and most of these this is, by
the way, I must mention this is white
men. This this is what white men do.
This is white men culture. They don't
seem to get it that, you know, they
don't get it. They they are like
obsessed about like justice or rape rape
culture or whatever. You know, we we
we're going to talk about it. you know
that that that you you know uh you know
they like these white men have lots of
jarens about [laughter]
toxic you know something something toxic
or something something uh you know
rights or whatever [ __ ] them
so so I was looking at you know this
asmo gold from what I heard he's he's a
good person okay like he just like I
think you know a friend told me he was
very poor. He just, you know, live
streamed games and and uh and he became
very popular and now he's pretty rich.
So, I think he's good person. But, you
know, but this video, you know, like
YouTube showed me I watched. What are
they talking about? This is just [ __ ]
drama, you know. So, so the girl, you
know, someone asked girl the question
like on live stream, you know, and girl
says, "Oh, I don't talk about politics."
and that become a drama and he
is like you know [laughter]
trying to make it add fuel to it then he
is going to talk about the oh look at
that go and this and you people are
idiots you're talking about drama
actually that's what I'm doing now
so this is kind of so that's you know so
oh so so this is how you get popular is
that right so that's what you you know
the the deep state the YouTube you know
the Twitter That's what they want us to
do.
So let's, you know, let's start a fight,
right? Do I mean, okay, for example,
this, do you get what I'm saying? Uh,
beheat
Juaka.
I'm not saying he's right or wrong.
Okay. Yeah, I'm I agree with him, you
know. Uh but but but but
you know don't you see that we are we
have been in this situation of the drama
frying for more than 10 years.
So are we going to just talk about this
drama? You don't you know the the what
you should do is don't talk about it
then will die die out. I'm pretty sure
the Emiru does not talk about it. You
know people like attack her. She just
let it go and it just dies
instead of like, you know, repeat this
like don't we have enough of that?
So anyway, so you know, so this is
disappointing to notice like like he's
like just talking about drama. That's
how Tim became very popular, super rich,
you know, since like five years ago.
Tim, you know, because I've been
watching Tim every almost every day. uh
in 20 let's say 2018 2019
that's how Tim Pu became popular and he
became a scum he became like very
ugly scum okay in in the past few years
um yeah that's so well that's you know
that's my you know reaction about this
you know the influencers and like how to
become popular.
Yeah, sure. I I like to be popular
because well, so I can have more money,
but I don't but but but I don't want to
like
write drama, you know, like like there's
plenty I can talk about. I can tell you
my opinions. I can rant about
there's a profit motivation in all this.
It's ad sponsored business model. That's
right. Yeah, that's that's what that's
correct. That's why that's why I'm
saying that's what deep state want you
to to do. That's what promoted. That's
it's you see the whole thing is shaped,
guided, designed by so-called deep
state. That's what YouTube want you guys
to do. And how how why is YouTube want
it that way? Because YouTube has deep
state want YouTube to do certain things.
you know the you know so anyway
okay I think that's it C++
versus Russ people okay I think C++
should die
uh and zuma [ __ ] like rust and zig
>> [laughter]
>> I feel old as [ __ ] [ __ ] Yeah. 32 39.
Well, 3239 kind of
uh compared to the younger generation,
you see. Anyway,
um so what do you Oh, yeah. So, we got
lots of to-do actually.
But so actually I I got lots of things
to do. So let's just do them. Okay.
Let's do like the
the like the Zoomer live streamers.
Okay. Let's just talk [ __ ]
So but actually I got lisp things to do.
Okay. So let's just code more lisp.
So today we finished that coding that
thing. So I got more things to do. Can
you guys see me?
You cannot see my iPad. But I got notes
here. Okay. So notes about things I want
to do.
So actually maybe I should stop.
You can only delete one. C, C++ or Rust.
Uh,
that's a hard choice. You know, the the
thing is about C or C++.
So, if I can only delete one, that would
be probably C++. Okay. C++.
[laughter]
[ __ ] the C++. [ __ ] that guy. You know
the pajamas stro
he he's he's like a crackpot. Okay, that
guy.
So I got few things to do.
Uh well
so should I continue or should I stop?
So what is this uh text
that we did that?
Okay. So
okay.
So go to my e-ac lisp tutorial.
There is a section.
Go to the lisp basics. Then go to the
for each with brake. So let's go to um
okay so you need to go to the sequence
section sequence type okay sequence type
which includes list and vector and
string those are called sequence
okay then you go to the sequence
functions uh iteration guide so and you
go to every
okay
there. So copy that. So close that. Go
to Emacs blog showing browser. So this
is my Emacs blog. And uh create a new
section. Paste the link. Linkify. Make a
list showing browser. There is the page
and uh go to it. Open it. Update the
date. And I want to make some
modifications.
Uh this is about English writing. So
this sentence I want to change it. So
this is about the function sum. Okay.
Tip. This is useful as functional form
of loop with break especially if you
want the return value of the predicate.
Okay. So I want to rephrase it
uh by
this is useful as a functional uh form
of loop
with break
when
when you need to know
which element
returns True.
Okay. So that that so show in browser.
So you can compare the two different um
versions of these phrasing
compare their clarity for the purpose of
tutorial. So this is useful as
functional form of loop with break when
you need to know which element returns
true. uh
let's say
especially
especially when you need to know
uh which element
returns true. Okay. So
okay I like to use the second version.
Okay,
this is a functional form of blue with
mic. Okay.
Okay. Yeah. This the second one is
better because it emphasize on
it emphasize about which element it
stops. You see this is a form of loop
functional programming style of loop.
But you but you use this form when you
want to stop when when some condition is
satisfied.
So what I want to say here is that this
is useful as a loop functional style
loop with break.
But especially if you want to know if
you need to know when you know which
element cause the condition to to uh to
to change that you want to stop. Okay.
On the other hand the you know the the
the previous statement just say when you
want to know the return value of the
predicate which is less um
less clear. Okay. So
okay delete that this is useful
functional style let's say
functional programming style of loop
of ring a loop with break especially
when you need to know which element
return true. Okay. Now there's another
part. Now here
there's another
function which is for every we have
similar things we want to change. This
is useful as a functional form of loop
with break. And you do not and uh Okay.
And you do not
when you do not need to know which
element
stops something like that. Okay. Um,
and you do not need to know which
element
Let's just say which element breaks.
Okay, something like that.
Okay, does that make sense?
Okay.
Did we change the updated date? Yes.
This is February 17th.
Um, okay. So, that one is done.
Delete it.
Delete is done. Fantastic.
Now add the tip.
Okay. Now I want to talk about
so go back copy the URL the file path.
So this is Emacs blog we made change
there. Then go back to talk show and we
also add a link here because it's
something we talked about.
So here. So go to the top. Search for
fix there.
There. There. Showing browser there.
Okay. Then the next thing.
So let's see. Add a tip. Don't use new.
Okay. So the next thing is very
interesting which is about hash tables.
Okay. So you go to there Emacs blog. You
go to uh EMAC listp, you go to hash
tables.
So you got data structures, list
structure, vector sequence um
which they are all part of this list
data structures. List special lists
list structure vector sequence.
Then you got hash hasht. Okay. Go to
hasht.
Copy that. Go to emac blog and paste the
link
linkify make a list. Okay. So showing
browser so that we can later on people
know in my in my emac blog I have
updated those articles. So open that
update it update the update last update
page then what I want to say is that so
here's a tip about hasht in emacisp
the tip is that hasht values can be any
type however
you should not use neo as a value in the
hasht
value Okay. Why? Because
there's no way to know if a key does not
exist or if a key returns Neil. The
key's value is Neil. So there's no way
to distinguish
the two facts. Okay. One is the key does
not exist or the key has a value. It
exist
and has the value of Neo. There's no way
to dis distinguish these two. So that is
so that is why you should not
when you use create a hash table you
should not use um value of neo. So let
me add that tip somewhere. So uh so
the reason is because there's no way to
distinguish
key don't exist versus uh versus keys
value is near. Okay. So let's add here
tip don't use neo as value.
Okay. So
because
there's no way to distinguish
uh is that spelled correctly? Check.
Correct. Okay. There's no way to
distinguish
either key
does not exist or exist but has value of
neo. Okay.
Okay.
Mark it up. Make it one line. Make a
paragraph show in browser
and scroll down. Scroll down. There it
is. A new tip. Don't use Neo as value in
hash table because there is no way to
distinguish either key does not exist or
exist but has value of Neo. Okay. Why is
that? Because in EMAC list there is no
function that
returns
that tells you whether a key exist.
Okay. The only closest one is uh you
know if you want to check if a key
exists is you use get hash. Get hash if
the key does not exist it will return
neo or you can supply a default value it
will return that default value. So you
can you know you can use get hash to
check a key of a hash table and uh if it
does not exist you can say you know you
you can you can tell it to return let's
say one
but
that's a problem because some key may
have a value of one then you are not
able to distinguish whether it's because
you got a one because the key exist or
because which has a value of one or
because it doesn't exist and you return
the value of one.
So what you can do is you try to make
the default return you know if the key
doesn't exist return a value that's like
a random number you know let's say a
random number however you cannot
guarantee that random number does not
exist as a value in your hash table
value you see there's no way to know so
you this you know whatever you change
this default value to be can be a random
you know long string or even universal
like UU ID you know like a 32 bits long
string um but the but but the the like
there's technically this you know you
just not able to tell because that value
may happen in your hasht value okay so
that is a uh kind of that's a actually
so this is a flaw of emacisp okay so for
you uh emac like this coders some you
know sometimes you wonder if you know
some criticism of Emacs this is one of
them a minor one okay there are lots of
major ones such as such as lacking a
names uh lacking a named parameter
lacking
um a named parameter in in defining a
function okay usually it's useful to
have a named parameter also it lacks a
um default uh value.
Okay, that's related. Also, Emac this
lacks a name space which is arguably uh
kind of problem lacks lacks a name space
and also it lacks a organized library
system like library hier hierarchy.
Okay, those are my main complaints. Now
some other people they will complain
[clears throat]
about things like this doesn't have
threads. Now this is like the typical
hacker types like the C and Unix. That's
what that that's their complaint. They
would say this you know emac this lack
lacks threats or concurrency.
Um
so but yes that's a issue but that that
is actually that's not my main concern
you know because I'm I'm more of a like
functional programmer I'm more high
level but but that's a actual practical
issue because when you don't have
threads so-called threads
you have a problem of you know every
time you do something in Emacs Emacs
rows until that thing finish then your
you know key becomes responsive You know
that's a major problem. So
but thread is like a very bad idea from
the C idiots from these C type of
idiots. What you really want is
concurrency support and parallel
computation.
You don't want never you should never in
your programming langu language have
like threads. Oh, let's create a
threads. Oh, there's a green threads.
Oh, let's uh, you know, let's have
flags, you know, [ __ ] idiots. That's
a from C. Okay, you want a parallel
programming language. That's what you
want. Not threads, you know, with this
incomprehensive like floats, bits, you
know, floats, uh, int, double, let's
have a double, let's have a pointer,
this idiots
thing.
So um
so we talked about hasht we added a tip
which is what I want to do there. Okay
now there's one more thing okay so you
know so I'm working on my Emacs tutorial
so this update hasht so copy that copy
the URL back here and showing browser
talk show. So let's uh paste the hash
table here. So that because we talked
about it showing browser. So we did
that. We did that. And next I want to do
is so there's a code. Okay. Sash table
equal. So let me show you that. Uh
oh actually I already have some of that
here.
What?
Yeah, I already I already have the links
here. So okay so let's let me so let me
demonstrate one command press press.
So that will show all duplicate links.
So now I know in a glance that this link
is duplicated
but not that. Okay. So this is exit loop
function. Okay. So
we don't like combine them and uh test
hasht equality.
Uh wait showing browser
hasht test hasht equality. Yeah, that's
a that's my personal function that
compares given two hash tables determine
if they are equal meaning that it has
same number of keys and all the keys
match and all the keys values match.
Okay, so this is my personal function. I
need to make a change modification.
Okay, and uh so what is that? Uh so what
is uh exit loop or function? So
this uh there is something I need to do
or two there. Okay. Anyway, so let's
let's make the modification about this
one. Okay. Test hasht equality. So let's
see uh what you guys are saying.
Next, uh, you probably can create a
unique closure value as a default value
to reliably check if they are guaranteed
to compare an an equal. Okay, that's
interesting. Let me see. Hold on a
second.
Oh my god. So, I'm getting tired a
little bit. So, by now it's like two
hours.
This shirt my wife gave me.
She doesn't know what it says. Oh, it's
Mickey Mouse. That's good. That's right.
That's good.
Okay, let's see.
Very technical technical
advice here from
Hello GCS.
So he says
let's see it's uh
you can create a unique closure value as
a default value to rei re reliably check
if they are guaranteed to compare an
equal
Really? How do you do that? What do you
mean unique closure value? Oh, so what?
But that would be inefficient. Okay, so
but how do you like how do you do that?
Show code aluma show code or post post
code to discord or to Twitter. Okay. To
my Twitter like show me what you're
talking about.
Create a uh unique closure.
What do you mean like
unique closure like a function? You mean
like a you know function?
So you mean a value that is a function
and uh then
oh okay so what so right so well
so if so the hash table's value
will
not likely to be a function. So you are
saying that basically you know have it
have it return if the if the key is not
found have it return like a closure
function function closure
it returns a function. So but normally
hashts value are never almost never
functions. So that's what you're saying
but plus also you are saying that this
function since since it's a function and
it's a closure function so uh therefore
it's a kind of unique
it can never be recreated so because
function is some sort of reference I
think that's what
uh you're saying okay yeah post code
so but yeah but even if that works
works.
You know that you know even if that
works that's get kind of like
complicated. You know all you wanted to
check is if it's a value exist but in
trying to do so you you you create a
like like advanced you know function
trying to work around um you know it's
not practical I think
so anyway.
So we we so yeah so so now there's this
function you see it's tricky so because
this function hash table equal compares
if two hash table are equal
now what I wanted to do was that um
you see I I I I was going to you know
there are two versions actually so one
is older version the other one is I just
modified today and uh the so the older
version uses uh you know like this
random
symbol
as a you know if a key does not exist it
returns this random
random symbol but it will fail if your
hash table actually contains a value of
this random symbol key right
meanwhile the new version
the new version here is basically the
same except you know the the default
value if a key is not found is just a
random number
uh you know it's this we have the same
problem
uh I use a number because there's
another complication because when you
use a key you see let me show you let me
talk about this okay interesting for you
this is for advanced eac this coders you
see this value. This is a symbol and
this symbol it start with a colon. So in
EMAC listp that has special meaning when
a symbol
you know begin with a colon that means
that symbol is so-al self- evvaluating
basically means that symbol
cannot have a value I mean it's its
value is is itself
the essence of this symbol means that
this symbol is purely used as a symbol
like a label okay it not it's not
supposed to like have a value like
typically a symbol means either a
function or a value or you know like the
catch let interactive those are all
functions or maros you know or a value
like neo is a value a variable you know
can have a value like one two three but
this symbol if a symbol begin with a
colon
that symbol is meant to be used just
like a symbol like a string
not cannot have a value itself. It its
value is is is itself. Okay. So that is
called um that is called um just key um
I think it's called keyword symbol.
Search for you know search for my Emacs
blog you'll find it. In fact I can tell
you where it is. So this basics you go
to the symbol section
boolean variable conditional loop list
this this data structure then you go to
uh then you go to functions then symbols
okay then you have this keyword symbol
keyword [snorts] symbol colon prefix
keyword symbol so when a symbol start
with a colon that's called keyword
symbol
And when that's the case that means it's
constant. Okay, evaluate to itself and
uh so you cannot set a value to it. The
meaning is that this kind of symbol is
just used as a label. Okay, that's
keyword symbol.
Okay, now now back to the about the so
we were talking about uh test hasht
equality. So we got these two functions.
So, so anyway, we got you see I'm using
a keyword symbol. So, if this hash table
when we compare the hash table keys, if
the key does not exist, you know, return
this random symbol.
But the problem is if the hash value
contains a value of this exactly you
know random symbol just then the my
function is broken you know
it it will behave incorrectly
so but I change that to a number same
thing you know same situation but the
the difference is that you see what's
the difference if you replace this
keyword symbol by a number
the number is you know
you see when you when you use a symbol
there's a nasty problem whenever you use
a symbol in eac lisp also true in common
lisp and I believe also true in scheme
lisp and racket lisp okay whenever you
use a symbol
the symbol gets added to the so-called
symbol table so-called Um,
you know what's the symbol table name?
Uh, ops. Um, so you need to go back to
the symbol section. The symbol table.
Okay. The symbol table symbol sales
the
anyway. So to to it's not important
right now, but I'm uh I'm talking about
the symbol table. Okay. Convert symbol
to uh string. Convert symbol to string.
Convert string to symbol. Uh what wait
what is the table that contains all the
symbols?
Um
something called ops array. Okay. So did
did I mention it OB? Yeah. OB array.
Kind of funky funky name. OB array. OB
array is a variable building variable
whose value is a table of all existing
symbols you ever used. You ever you know
whenever there's a new symbol it get
added to the AB array. Okay. Table
which is kind of low-level stuff. Okay.
So this up array. So whenever you have a
new symbol such as I'll use such as when
we you know use this keyboard symbol it
creates a new symbol and adds to the op
array table. Okay. So that means every
time you create a symbol you use a new
symbol it gets added to it to there. So
that is a pollution. Okay. That is a
pollution.
You
you see because normally you never
remove symbols from the op array like
you like basically it's not recommended
nobody does it ever so of so this is one
major problem of lisp programming
languages the op the op array will grow
and grow grow and grow so if you run
lisp system for 10 years you for for one
year it will crash okay because the top
array it does not clean itself
and normally but you but you could you
could remove the symbol manually
yourself but that's like I don't think
people ever do that
in fact I remember like
in year 2000 like 25 years ago I asked
when I first learned about scheme lisp I
asked people you know how do I remove a
symbol because you can create a symbol
you know like create a variable or
whatever but how do I remove it and
basically people say why do you want to
remove it
I want to remove it because I you know
because I want clean program you create
something you remove it right when you
are done
that's people just don't do that so in
these programming languages you got this
problem the symbol table just
accumulates
okay and this this This this problem is
especially bad in wuam language in
Mathematica
because every time you use a let like
the lect let in wuam language it's
called module does the same thing as let
okay so every time you in wan language
you have module it creates lots of
symbols like uh like internal random
symbols so pretty soon you know they I
mean they don't add much memory
especially not today but they grow that
I mean the the point is that they keep
growing
um they don't self clean so that's uh
like a generic problem of lisp I don't
know how
this solve this problem uh because I've
asked guac AI it told me this this exist
this problem exists because I was
curious I've been thinking about this
like in my mind for 10 years I asked Gro
and Gro confirmed it. Uh in fact I have
like
uh documentation about it. I wrote it
somewhere but let's not find it. Anyway
uh so that's about the symbol table.
Okay. So uh so what I want to do here is
um
so this problem. So yeah. So I want to
make a change. Okay. Let me tell you
what I'm going to change and that will
be it today.
Uh okay. So uh so
why did you change some stuff like key
default key bind?
Why not? I mean are you talking about
the um the this key like quartT
because someone complained did you read
the comments you know the commit
message?
Uh I think uh anyway yes you got me
right equal lambda lambda is neo you
understood me right okay so
uh equal lambda right so the function
right that does not um
you know two functions they
if you use e eq on them they return neo
so have you ever used vim
yes I F that's back in 1997. Okay. I
mean
I'm old guys you know so you guys
question kind of funny. Have I used V?
Yeah I have 1997 you know I used for
I wrote an article emergency VI. Okay
just search for it you will find it but
um you'll find it you know funny
emergency vim. Okay. Like sometimes like
V vi is one of Unix's [ __ ]
Sometimes in a emergency situation like
in servers like you have root key uh
passwords to like 10 you know server
accounts you know live servers emergency
situation like some some some customer
custom you know Verizon is complaining
their account doesn't work something
major happened you know earthquake or
whatever check it out you are you know
in some emergency situation you are
forced to deal with VI I and the [ __ ]
Unix admins refused to install Emacs.
Okay, that happened in back in 1998.
Okay, because we have the colloccated
servers and the Unix mean idiots. They
they don't they they didn't install
Emacs. They don't, you know, they like
they don't want to because Emacs is like
big, you know, can like can see the
bloated. You don't like usually you
don't want it on a server.
I would say you know but back then but
anyway so you know so so when you SS s
um to the server you need to use vi
which is actually required skill if
you're going to be anything dealing with
Unix okay so vi is like required if
you're going to be any dealing with Unix
or in any capacity as cis admin
Okay. Or maintaining or security
whatever. Okay. VI is like required.
So have I used VI? Yeah, sure. 1997
also. Um
uh defend hashkey table
def
table. Maybe like this. Okay.
Um okay. So, there's some code I can
check out or
Okay, let's check out the code. But I
think I got to go. I got to stop.
Uh, let's see.
Let's today's talk show. So, let's go to
the bottom.
Uh, yeah, this. So, check out. So, so
this is Aruma code. So they got some
unic code stuff here. [ __ ] the unic code
invisible characters. Okay. So let's
check.
Okay. So let's see if we can
uh
so wait.
So is this wait this is not valid code.
Uh so is this code valid?
Okay. So, hold on a second. So,
so pretty.
So, let unique equals to lambda. Oh,
okay.
It's interesting usage. That's okay. But
anyway, this returns this is a this is a
value of a function
and uh
yeah. Okay. Yeah. Yeah, I guess that
works. I think you know I'm pretty sure
that works. So, let's delete that.
One trick to
check if a key exist
in hash table. Okay, that's one trick to
check if a key exist.
So you know actually you know we can
test we can test this make this code
robust. So let's do that. Why don't we
since we already since we working on
this anyway? So, okay. So, let's go to
hasht.
Uh, let's go to hasht. Okay, I got some
test here. So, let's copy the code. Uh,
copy there and
okay, then there there here's the test
code.
So, um,
let's let's compact this. Okay. So
actually
what what
uh okay so you see there's a invisible
character there very nasty like started
you know this happens since 10 years ago
every time you copy from YouTube or
Twitter you got you started to have
these invisible characters for for
example this one is
this one is uh zero width space okay
very annoying okay so I delete it you
see because if I don't delete it I
didn't know you know then I want to make
this two lines into one line if I do it
it becomes that incorrect so but that's
because there is a invisible character
because my command and
relies on the fact that there's a empty
line separate.
So if you delete this invisible
character then you do it then it works.
See?
Uh so anyway,
so we want to see uh
well, in order to test this, we have to
Well, let's just um
Okay, let's let's finish this and let's
be it and that'll be it today. Okay, I
got to go. I'm tired. Okay, test hasht
equality. Okay, let's work on that.
Okay, so let's create a new um
Okay, let's create a new version.
Paste it there. Okay, let's say
two. Okay,
and for now, let's just remove all the
documentation. Okay, let's just
this is like version two. Okay, now in
this version, we're going to use this
trick by um this trick by um by Aluma.
Okay, so basically that.
Okay, so
just actually just that just put that
there. Okay.
Do that. Okay. So, so if we do that, uh,
hold on a second. So, hold on a sec.
Let's make a new one.
Okay. Paste it there. Okay. So,
so if we do that, um,
not found. So, let's actually, that's a
good name, unique. So, actually, so
let's change that to not found.
unique. Okay.
Um, so will that work? Well, it I think
so, but let's copy that. So, let's
do it. Okay. Paste it here. Okay. Uh,
copy that. Go here.
There. Evaluate the whole thing.
Okay. Then, okay. So let's evaluate it.
It returns true. You can see there. Now
if we change this to
that okay evaluate and evaluate now it
returns Neo. So it
works.
Now if but if uh let's say for now let's
say what if we return this thing
let's say a aa is this thing
very tricky nobody does that value is a
function that happens in javascript but
does not happen in eac this uh it well
it could but I haven't seen it happen
not I don't think it's moment. So,
evaluate that, evaluate that and run
this. It should return.
Okay, we got into a tricky situation
because these two hash table you see one
of them the key aa has a value of
lambda. Now, this hash table is exactly
the same thing. The key is a function
lambda. But the question now is should
these two
hash table be considered equal or not?
Now depending on
point of view because if you go by
reference they should be not the same
but if you go by like the more intuitive
concept of function they should be the
same because they are
well actually they yeah they they you
know their function does the same thing
you know these two lambdas does the same
thing which what does it do actually
those two lambdas they they return Uh,
do they just return Neo?
Anyway, let's try to run this. Okay, so
what happened? They I think they return
Neil. You see
it? Oh, they return true. What?
Uh
what?
Wait. So what? So if you what if you add
a lambda like three uh
can you do that? Yes.
Okay. Evaluate that. Evaluate that then
evaluate that. It returns Neil. So now
it's different. But if you delete that,
evaluate that. Evaluated that. Now it
returns true. So interesting. So these
two is considered the same
but then
so then I don't fully understand. Now
you see here aluma.
Yeah. So
I mean it works. So but then how is that
anyway?
Anyway, I so anyway, so this um this is
great, but I mean it's kind of tricky.
So in real life, you know, we not we are
not going to use this. You know, in real
life code,
this is probably not what you want to
do.
But anyway, right now
we um
right now we have still some issue like
we we want to fully understand
why is these two return this and this
considered equal. So evaluate the whole
thing and try again reevaluate it
returns true. So emac this consider
these two as equal.
Um
so
emac this consider this two as equal. So
what? So we don't understand. So but
what does this return?
Uh that returns that
hard to understand. I don't understand.
So anyway,
yeah. So this is getting you know this
is fairly advanced.
I don't I don't know what's going on. Um
yeah. Anyway, so this very interesting.
So let's you know but probably we don't
want to use this uh in real life because
it's like
getting complicated.
Okay. But meanwhile another thing we can
do is that we just cheat and change the
spec. Okay. So like for example let's
copy this one.
Copy.
Okay. So instead of saying you know
return true if two hash table are same
else same means
same means all key
um
you know you you you change the meaning
so that if a key value is new is
considered the same as the key does not
exist.
Okay. So you you change meaning to that
then you don't need you don't even need
this you know. So let's modify the code
first. So you see not found delete that
not found
delete that. So you like uh
so this uh this is new. So if when
so basically you just say that so get
hash if it returns neo
so wait does what does uh neo
neo evol neo neo true okay so You say
yeah. So you see you say if it equals to
neo
then you just throw and return neo
saying uh saying that um wait it should
be nilo um
right so that means whenever you have a
key whose value is
you just throw it.
Okay. No, you can't do that because then
you have you also have to make sure that
the key in table A also has a value of
Neo. Anyway, God, this is getting
complicated. So, but do you guys see
what I'm saying? you know I'm trying to
change the meaning so that
anyway
that okay so
I think that's it for today
bye guys
so that's today is like 2 hours
4:30
I think it's two hours um
okay that's it.
Bye guys.