hello guys so I'm going to read this
passage about received pronunciation BBC
pronunciation you know I'm I was born in
Taiwan and I'm Chinese but I lived in
USA for like thirty years now and so but
I didn't grew up in USA I was born in
Taiwan I lived I grew up in Taiwan until
I was fourteen years old so you know I
have a Chinese accent so I'm just going
to read this passage out you know so you
can hear
maybe someone are they are interested in
Chinese accent okay received
pronunciation also known as PBC
pronunciation now this is just how I
talk normally so there's no I'm not
trying to be pretentious or trying to
pretend to be another accent so anyway
received pronunciation RP is regarded as
the standard accent of standard English
in the United Kingdom with a
relationship to regional accents similar
to the relationship in other European
languages between their standard
varieties and their regional forms RP is
defined in the concise Oxford English
Dictionary as the standard accent of
English as spoken in the South of
England although it can be heard from
native speakers throughout England and
Wales Peter Krogh Gil estimated in 1974
that three percent of people in Britain
were our piece because though only three
percent although nothing intrinsic about
our p-box it a superior to any other
variety social linguistic factors have
given up he particular prestige in parts
of Britain
it has thus Bheem Singh as
the accent of those with power money and
influence though it has in recent times
been perceived negatively as associated
with undeserved privilege since the
1960s a greater permissiveness towards
allowing regional English varieties has
taken hold in education and the media in
Britain some linguistic some linguists
have used the term RP but expressed
reservations about its suitability the
Cambridge published English
pronunciation dick near the Cambridge
published English pronunciation
dictionary aimed at those learning
English as a foreign language uses the
term BBC pronunciation on the basis that
the name received pronunciation is
archaic and that BBC news presenters no
longer suggest high social class and
privilege to their listeners the name
BBC pronunciation has been used by other
writers that's it