welcome okay now here I am welcome to
another episode of exotic show impromptu
talk-show extempore today we're gonna
talk about a specific topic which is the
scourge of HTML XML entities now this is
very interesting topic it's related to
writing systems
human-animal writing systems and human
more reading systems and and HTML XML
technology and Unicode in symbols
symbology you know the meaning of
symbols so here are the entities let me
explain what is entities entities is
okay let me explain so you have these
characters right these are you know
asking ABCD efg all these symbols now
before you know in the 1990s you know
you you cannot type these symbols
directly because you know Unicode is not
popular yet so instead you have these
so-called entities so in order to type
this character for example the inverted
exclamation mark you can you know eight
you know XHTML file for example this is
my HTML file so you let's say you type
this okay so I II xcl so you type a
ampersand let me magnify I am percent
ten percent then that okay like this
okay and you show in browser you can see
here you see this line that's the
exclamation inverted exclamation okay so
yes I'm explaining entities so entities
allows you to type a character without
actually typing the character you type a
kind of a coded string to represent a
character so so in the night you know
you know HTML entities you have these
bunch of entities and today I saw this
post by this guy very interesting guy
you should follow him okay this guy
Frederic Brennan
he is the his story is amazing okay
looking at look looking up you know
looking at Wikipedia your CEO article
about him and also look up a photo of
him he's got brittle bone disease so he
sits on we were he was born like that so
he he sits on a wheelchair you know he's
a disabled person but this guy is
incredible you know because he's
disabled so he focus on programming and
computer stuff and he became a great
programmer and he started the 8chan chat
and you know that became you know on the
news this month last last month you know
but he he stopped he quit agent in 2016
so anyway look up this guy Frederic
Brennan on we keep Wikipedia and
elsewhere look up his photo okay so this
guy says says this you know the fact
that there is not a named html5
character entity for every character is
a tragedy wouldn't you agree
sorry no I don't agree okay but anyway
then he says here's an interesting
example he gave me
like seriously this contour integral you
have you know the math single contour
integral
it has a named entity but the
right-pointing index finger hand logo a
common type of graphical symbol at least
before widespread use of word processors
does not have a entity so this that is
true okay that hint that pointing let me
show you since we are doing XR talk show
and unicode so sorry unicode so go to my
you Nicole page and I'm going to show
you these hand symbols so go to Unicode
characters and go to hands okay
so you can see all these many of them
hands emoji many of them are emoji but
some of them are not
you see so this right pointing index
finger and there are several versions
you know in a beginning there are only
like four of them I forgot which one you
know II different operating systems Mac
OS or Windows the hand shows differently
but anyway one of them is extremely
popular before computer age you know
that that is this one either that one or
that one
so basically a right pointing or left
left all right point in index finger
that is used to refer to like see you
know like a reference mark mark like see
then a footnote to something see this
article you know with a finger pointing
to that so anyway that that symbol is
why it was very popular because for for
time being I was planning to use a
Unicode in place
see something-something a link you know
in place of see something because the
see because in my articles for example
JavaScript reference lots of places you
have see this link see that think you
know some technical stuff of JavaScript
like objects what is object what is
property what is you know the type of
property key so I have lots of see see
see link link link so I was hoping you
know to find a Unicode replacement in
his instead of the word see so I was
using this character so actually let me
show you about that article sorry
Unicode eg so I have a few articles of
that nature about how to use Unicode for
example let's see this one symbol
semantics design Unicode for eg dot so
this article discuss at one time I was
trying to find a Unicode symbol to
represent the Latin eat dot G dot which
is for example which means for example
and you know so that Arco discuss about
that but then yeah this basically this
is the article where I try to find a
replacement either for the eat out G dot
or see something you know so this you
know I searched all the Unicode symbols
and you know he's and I also must check
the history of their usage because when
you are doing something like this you
know replacing all common you know not
English what you know some kind you know
cut the common word or phrase by a
symbol that's addresses such as that you
wanted to be you know compatible with
history I mean
in a sense it's a new invention but you
you you want to have good reasons for it
you know if you choose a symbol but why
do I want to replace it Archie dot you
know because that is Latin for exempli
gratia i don't know how to pronounce it
but basically ichi means for example or
to wit so it is not a intuitive word
it's it's a word that's used in academia
often by the way there is also another
similar abbreviation i thought e dot IE
now IE means i means that is you know if
you want to translate to english IE
means that is EG means for example so
they are slightly different and these
abbreviations this EG and IE
are used in academia often at least you
know in the 1990s so before they are
very popular in academia publications
writings but they are not really good
because they are you know first of all
they are not english words the it's it's
it's a more advanced acquired learning
so rather you you can simply say
whenever there's ichi you can just say
for example when there is IE you can
just say that is you know and there's a
lot alternative way to express the same
idea so so but why do I want to replace
it out G by único why can I just say for
example well because for example that's
kind of a long word the word is like too
long and then when I write write
technical articles you have lots of eg
so lots of places you have for example
for example for example you know it's
written it's kind of too long and
it Curtis the page crota's writing so I
want to use the symbol instead when you
have a symbol such as for example this
arrow key or for example the you know at
one point I was using the pointing
finger I don't know I don't remember if
I if it's this article I have written
another article yeah at one point I was
using the pointing finger symbol but but
I don't remember if I mentioned here or
if it is another article symbol syntax
semantics design use of único ellipsis
symbol versus dot dot ok probable
congestion semantic symbols examples
Unicode simple usage okay let's look at
that so all these articles are all
related about the usage of symbols in
the problems of not using them properly
for example when when in unity in you
know you have for example you have the
backs backslash escape characters that's
very annoying and error-prone oh yeah ok
so here is the page where I talk about
the use of the index finger there okay
it's this one so so you see these are
about you know symbol usage so if I
replace eg by some symbols such as arrow
then arrow is kind of universal I mean
people do not you don't really actually
need to know to read the word you know
for example people understand you know
it's an example you know with the arrow
you know arrow
kind of a universal so that is why I
decided to you know do that but
eventually after several years of
experiment at night I went back just to
say sometimes eg sometimes for example
instead of a symbol because symbol when
you use symbol in a contrary manner
meaning in a fashion that is not widely
used you introduce lots of other
problems for example such engine will
get confused about your use use of
symbol even though it's obvious to
humans but you know that's one of the
problem with AI because AI on one hand
they are very efficient you they you
know Google search for example they
press process massive amount of info but
however the AI at least today they don't
really actually understand text so you
know so in in my example here if I you
know if my pages use the arrow humor may
understand that better than adult eg you
know it are G dot but machines don't
know what a heck because that's not a
popular usage they machine then wheel
you see there's a difference this is an
illustration of AI technology massive
use of AI in today's society
it influences what otherwise the
decisions and behaviors of humans
because if without AI then I would have
gone ahead and use one of the you know
obvious symbols for my page but then
search engine will get confused
therefore I cannot use it because you
know if search engine to not find my
website like you know I get this is hot
you know less less readers and that's no
good so it it changes in influences my
decision so I decided I have after a few
you know few years of experiment I
decided not to use
you know the Unicode fancy Unicode
symbols for to replace what eg but this
decision is influenced by you know the
stupid search engine technology and not
that's just not it's not just me it's
influencing it's influencing massive
amount of people you know so that is a
problem so humans you know we human
animals our behavior becomes you know in
a sense we become slaves of technology
you know this is one example one small
example but they are a lot they are
there they are tons of examples I can
talk about for example file name you
know he used to be in the 1990s file
name space is represented by an
underscore low-lying character you know
file name that's the most popular but
because of Google search engine kind of
by a mistake then the dash becomes more
popular you know because every one every
one one wanted to follow Google's search
engine suggestions so everyone started
to use the - instead of underscore so
that's another example of this AI you
know machine that's changing human
behavior for not for the better
for WASC for kind of wars you know this
these are just two small examples but
you know there's to illustrate there
there's actually big problems but anyway
I digress a lot so I was talking about
my use of Unicode symbols so I was
talking about so there are several
topics we have we talked about either
you know the use of the you know the
symbol index finger it was very popular
and in my use of it to replace eg and ie
words and Google search engine knows AI
and as an example that influences human
behavior for the worse so that's so far
we've talked about but I digress
let's get back to the topic of of this
guy so this guy Frederic Twain and so he
mentioned you know so you have this
contour integral sign as an entity but
you don't have the index finger sign or
the entity that's kind of strange and I
learned two things from these then
there's a lot more I'm going to talk
about the whole HTML XML entity scourge
you know crap so I learned two things
from this his post so he's very
interesting guy you know the interesting
guys so one example is that when he put
when interesting person post something
you learn something new not the old
hacker news
you know every every programmer
whitey programmers you know they're
telling you what to do so anyway he
posts this and you know so the first
thing I learned is that oh there is a
contour integral named entity I did not
know that because I wrote this page
which is a complete list of H HTML XML
entities based on the w3c standard
organization they published article so I
did not know that now there is a named
entity for contour integral so I
searched you know it's made such for
HTML entities you know so you go to
Wikipedia you know I check this every
you know pages like this every few years
so I didn't notice so you know you look
at Wikipedia
and indeed you have all these new
entities I wasn't aware of before for
example we scroll down they are like
thousands of them let's go down yeah all
these are new this is from as from you
know and all these are new entities so I
didn't know that so I looked about and
you can actually so I read it you can
see that they say in html5 html5 adopted
the XML entities named character
references however it restates them with
now references the html5 specification
additionally provides mappings from the
names to Unicode
so anyway the the the gist is that I
think that ok I don't know who created
this the first time for anyway the Jesus
is same thing html5 we have turned more
entities so here is a list you know like
there are probably over a thousand
entities new entities including lots of
math symbols so let's go to math symbols
math so let's search for integral int eg
ha you see so in Unicode you have all
these integral signs so this is ok with
one circle integral sign with one
circles contour integral two circles a
surface integral ok 3/3 integral sign is
a volume integral
that's for multivariable calculus now I
cannot define I cannot tell you what
they are I've forgot but anyway so so I
learned yeah so there's now there's a
bunch of new named entities I also
learned apparently you have this tool
called utf-8 to ent so so basically I
suppose that allows you to type any
Unicode character and it will tell you
the named entity code for it or the the
hexadecimal for the code point in the
HTML syntax you can use either one of
these so entities you know edged
entities HTML entities so is such that
ok let me explain so ok first of all let
me summarize so I learned two things now
we have a bunch of new entities and also
there's this utf-8 to ent command-line
so let me see if it's in on a Mac utf-8
to int okay there's not no such command
but however let's let's search it maybe
we'll find it utf-8 to ent
okay so so it looks like it might be a
tool he created himself of this guy
Frederic Brennan yeah so it possibly
it's a tool he create he wrote himself
because otherwise usually if you search
it you know if it's a commonly used to
tour it should show up but it's not here
yeah so maybe he created himself very
interesting so okay so two things new
entities okay now there's a lot of
interesting things going on I'm gonna
talk about them one by one
but let me finish here so so so first of
all I so I told him you know I didn't
know that that's interesting there's a
new entities named entities so as far as
his question you know he asked me your
question you know the fact that there is
not a named html5 characters entity for
every character is a tragedy
wouldn't you agree so he asked me do I
agree I don't agree because I think my
opinion on this is that entities should
be banned altogether you should have not
have that in the first place in the
1990s before the Unicode you know yeah
you can have you know you you created
entities that's a good because back then
there's no way it would be you know with
our entities will be hard entities is
quite useful back then but not today I
don't think it's it creates confusion
and and and but particularly when you
have entities that function as a escape
such as you know ampersand a.m. P
semicolon you know for the that's the
named entity for the ampersand
sigh okay and emphasis and alt semicolon
that's the entity for the less than sign
and you have also the entity GT for the
greater than sign now these three
entities they function as a sort of
escape character because in your HTML if
you need to type these characters you
know these characters are used by HTML
itself so when you want to use these
characters you have to escape them so
that's so that is the purpose you know
they function as escape characters but
that's not a good solution because a
good solution is that you shouldn't you
should have you should have a infinitely
variable delimiters instead instead of
us escape artists it creates a huge
amount problems I talked about in here
in this article you can see at the
bottom let me show you some example here
problems of symbol congestion in
computer languages ASCII Jam versus you
know Unicode so here's another here's an
article that talks about this in detail
you know this is actually this is a
related article the article the the
point I'm talking about how escape
characters are harmful is another
article so let me find it actually so so
you can read it offline
so just go to just search the stream
syntax okay this article computer
language design stream syntax now you
know how in programming languages you
have you have strings but sometimes you
need to escape them like if you use
double quote for a string but if your
texts contain double quote then you need
like you need to have a backslash double
quote to like escape it then you also
have you know so eight HTML entities is
also a form of escape but then in
different computer languages you have
alternative string delimiters for
example in Python you can use triple
quote that way you don't have to escape
you know stuff in your text and this is
extremely convenient and it's in a
similar way you have that in perl and in
PHP you also have that in a restrict
restricted form in :
but you don't have that in eMac eMac
sleaze so if I think this is pretty bad
here so anyway this is a problem about
string syntax that's why you need escape
escape characters are often paying the
ass to deal with because because
normally without escape all you have to
do when you try to pass the text is to
you just search the delimiters when you
say when you find the end
delimiters and the beginning delimiter
then whatever in between is the text but
if you have escape characters that
complicated the whole thing by a lot
because
then you then in the text you have to
search you know which one characters are
escaped you have to process the text and
this becomes more complex very
pronounced when you have for example for
example if you are coding a programming
language you have to call shell command
you have to translate the escape into
the shells escape then the shell command
you know uses a regular expression you
see you see you probably have experience
with this this is extremely headache in
fact it's it's a problem that is not
practically solvable for example you
know if if I if if I'm programming
Python and I'm using a rejects I'm using
a regular expression to find another
regular expression but however I need to
call this I need to pass this this code
into into let's say shell bash so so
when you have rejects to such another
rich extreme the escape becomes
extremely impossible to read then you
have to translate it to patch because
smash has its own escape code stuff you
know so in practice this is a real
problem you know we see it every day
it cannot be done I learned a great
technique from this David guy you know
one solution to solve this problem is
that you encode the host
howtechs into let's say into some hex
hex string format hex string
you know like pure ascii hex string then
at bash at the destination bash or
something you
decoded you know back to the stream so
you don't have any of these escapes
anymore it's just you know without
there's no backslash of stuff so
basically to capture this whole problem
the problem with the string syntax with
escapes is that when you have escaped
you know nested stream especially from
different languages spatch to Python to
shout to you know to HTML you know when
you especially when they are nested it
becomes practically impossible to
convert or pass them so that is the
problem with the escape now if so what
is the solution well one way is to use
delimiters you know variable that like
different derivatives like triple quad
because from Python is an example now
but what what if your string contains
triple quote well in that case you use
triple single quote or triple double
quote now what if your string contains
triples in single quote or triple double
quote then you could use some other you
know delimiter that the point is the
solution is basically you want infinite
possibilities of the devii meters so so
you want to make the delimiters
consistent in some regular way that's
easy to identify once you have that you
have you know all sort of delimiters
which is by probability it's not likely
ever to appear in stream you know the
chances of findings
such as delimiter inner stream would be
less than you know you got strike by a
lighting so one such example is here dog
let's say sorry your dog now this is the
tradition jargon for this thing for
example
here doc so so this is PHP here doc here
doc is basically a way to quote long
text so here's an example I have a long
text and you can use triple less than
sign then followed by a random stream
that random stream will be your
delimiter so this way this is one
example this way is a solution to quote
any long text without having to deal
with escape sequences so in so if you
have this so I call so here talk is one
of the implementation of the idea of
infinite variable stream delimiters okay
that's not the only idea by the way
so once you have the infinite variable
delimiters then you don't have this
problem of translating you know of
sending text from one programming
language to another programming language
because you know whatever his text is
just text you just pass it through
different programming languages or
protocols or network you know no problem
no problem you don't have to deal with
escapes so yeah escape is a very bad
thing improving languages usually you
should avoid that now okay it's actually
more complex than that some escape is
actually maybe good you know for example
the new line escaped that's a different
unit you see and we are getting into
details here the new line escape like
backslash
in there stand for new line that is not
the the functionality of that escape
is is it's like a entity it's not you
see it has nothing to do you see that
new line character is not a core
delimiter so you see it has a different
purpose so in other words if we look at
all the escape seek characters or
sequences some of them serve the purpose
of replacing some characters by code and
why do we want to do that because for
example the newline character is
invisible character sometimes you don't
want invisible characters you want to
represent invisible characters by a
visible one such as tab or control
control sequences you know in ascii so
that's one purpose but another purpose
of escape characters is to is when you
have a character that is the same
characters your string delimiter so we
are talking about this case in this case
we don't want these escapes characters
we want infinitely variable DV meters so
anyway that is a case about that yeah we
actually talked a lot about this okay so
let me get back to the the these guys so
so that so that's my answer to this
guy's question you know he's asking me a
question not really you know he's just
this is just a common way of introducing
a topic you know he so my opinion is
that no you know I don't think I think
entities should be banned at least the
the entities that function as escape for
the string delimiters those type should
be banned at the
we should not use those so anyway that
that finishes that topic about why I
think it should be banned now now let's
talk about the entities itself which is
why I'm doing a talk show today the
entities let me look at check if I was
still talking correctly and let's check
who how many people are watching one
people that's strange for the past few
days it's always one people I'm
wondering if it Google is you know not
showing me my stuff so anyway so let's
go back to entities yeah so entities so
there is this you know I'm telling you I
found a mistake in this spec so we go to
the html5 spec of entities so you see
this long list okay
you see this long list then ok scroll
all the way down then he says the
data is also available as JSON file so I
look up open the JSON file so you see
this big file so let's copy it copy go
to Emacs create a new file paste okay
save xx entity Jace let's put today's
date okay hold on a second it's name is
JavaScript okay
so you know so they are how many how
many are there they are two thousand two
hundred thirty of them and let's search
for LT semicolon you see so you can see
they are several of them however you do
not find one that just says oh you find
it here
no T no wait
there's a there's a problem here you see
so LT this should be less less than sy
but you see this one LT doesn't have a
semicolon that's all so that's I think
that's a error right
because entities must always ending a
semicolon so so this one is odd and then
they have the capital letter case which
is I'm not sure what what is a deal with
a capital letter case and then then you
have the mixed lowercase and capital
case this so this is strange
so if you look at these five lines let's
copy it go over here and paste you can
see that they let's magnify so the first
four is all the code point is 60 okay
but the last one is 880 110 now what
character is that you know with the mist
case capital L and lowercase T so this
is all very strange it's it's strange in
two possible ways one you know one is
that maybe the spec
is incorrect you know they got an error
typographical error and some sort of
error here
the second way it's strange is because
we have this mix you know you see we
have the capital case LT then we have
the capital k ZL and lowercase T what
you know what what does that mean and it
points to this character 8 8 1 10 so
let's find out which unicode character
is this 881 10 so 8 you know I got UNIX
code you know called search here 8 8 1 8
1 0
yeah so 8 8 0 is this character this one
turbo let's equal sign oh it's a ok the
único name is much less than okay so
that is very strange actually much less
than so let's try let's try create HTML
file save xx dot HTML okay then okay
then let's say title h1 okay
showing browser oh holy cow okay so this
is very interesting so this means that
later case matters wait this really case
matters always okay I don't remember I
looked into that issue whether later
case matters in entity in HTML entities
but I've apparently it's showing in
Safari and let's see if it's the same
behavior okay so looks like it's so late
later case matters
okay now let's do another thing let's go
back to the Jason okay now let's look at
the source code
command-u
let's look at the source code copy
everything copy back to Emacs open the
new buffer paste search for our T
semicolon
okay nevermind because you know what I'm
trying to show you his knees let me see
if I can reproduce it so let's copy the
URL for the SPECT of entities so let's
go to Chrome paste it and her this is
Rea this is a Chrome browser
okay so HTML and it's a huge document
still loading
yeah it's still loading
now this is this is taking too long so
so basically the problem I had is that
when I clicked that Jason link you know
as a JSON file I open it and the file
name you know ends in not Jason so it's
not HTML but however when I copy and
paste to Emacs I noticed that some of
the LT some of them becomes less inside
you know instead of the entities so I so
you know so I think that's a that's a
bug in browser because these days brows
that when you open a file sometimes they
try to you know it tries to pretend it's
a HTML file actually actually
technically it has to do with how the
server is set up because when you have a
file that Jason or Dargis or not
whatever
technically what what format that file
supposed to be is not does not depends
on the file name suffix you know does
not depends on the file name extension
but rather depends on the servers so as
the media code you know the the main you
know the media code so so when a server
you know it may say that Jason is
supposed to HTML which is wrong though
it's it would be incorrect set up so
anyway here we have the entities so you
go all the way down to to the end to the
JSON pod
see okay there is a JSON file let's open
that income
now copy that copy go to Emacs open a
new buffer paste search for all lines
containing LT semicolon okay so he so
somehow I got the arrow before that must
be my mistake
anyways still this this interesting part
you know so so in summary something
interesting we found today is that there
are a lot more HTML entities in html5
this must happen in the past 5 years I
guess or became popular so yeah new
entities then the letter-case matters
that's another interesting thing and
also another interesting thing is that
apparently this is a mistake
you know LT with our semicolon it's a
mistake by you know w3c or something
the and yeah that that's about it for
for that okay so that that is it for
today
oh the privacy it's private that's a
mistake that is why
privacy private that's a mistake that's
why all my talk shows are in the past
two days it's like oh it's all hidden
one person watching okay that's it for
today bye