Good morning, good evening, good night.
Uh you are watching talk show. Uh we are
going to code
eag and python.
So if you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed
necessarily. So if you are watching this
live, say hi here. Okay, say hi right
now. Concurrent viewers one that's
myself.
So okay uh EMAC this so video check
audio check video check audio check. So
Emac this coding. Okay now uh two days
ago we did a
episode
of San talk show episode 715
JavaScript markdown to HTML code
algorithm of text processing. So we
explored that uh fantastic that's 1 hour
go watch it. So and uh since about few
month ago we got video artificial
intelligence summary from Google.
Fantastic.
So it summarize what I'm talking about.
So you can read it you know just in 30
seconds you can see what's going on in
my video. The video itself is 1 hour and
if you watch at 1.5 speed which is
optimal then it's going to be uh let's
see that that's going to be divided by
so that you know this is a test 1.5.
So what you want to compute is 1 over
1.5. So the question is 60 minute video.
If you play at 1.5 speed, what's the
duration of the video? So the factor to
multiply would be 1 over 1.5. So that
would be equivalent to 10 over 15.
Multiply both top and bottom by 10. 10
over 15. Then you divide it by three uh
wait by five. So that's two over three.
So the mo the factor the scaling factor
is 2 over 3. So that's 2 of a3.
So so 60 minutes
uh divided by 3 * 2 divided by 3 is 20
minutes * 2 is 40 minutes. So 60 minutes
video become 40 minutes if you play at
1.5 speed.
Is that fantastic? You get that? Okay.
So now let's proceed to today's talk
show. So that's two today two days ago
we talked about the algorithm of text
processing. How do they do it of diverse
language designs Python Goland F. We
haven't got into it. JavaScript we
haven't. But anyway so today let's just
write a eaglist command emacs which is
what I'm using right now. It's more
efficient than VS code. You Microsoft
you unlearned Microsoft people you know
most popular VS code.
So uh what what is VS code for example
open in VS code this command I wrote in
eac list this. So eac list starting VS
code. Now every time I start VS code I
want to show you this. So VS code just
one single file you know open this file
in VS code you see right there and uh
you know compared let's go to the top
you see doc type html s talk show 2025
1123 episode 716
and here is vs code same thing okay now
how do I magnify let's see control
scroll doesn't work old scroll ah stupid
vs code doesn't follow the Windows
tradition. Control score doesn't work.
So now control +
even control plus doesn't work. What the
VS Code. Oh, okay. Control plus
works.
So you can see VS Code is opening one
single file.
Actually two files because it got the
release notes whatever.
So, two files and the Emacs. Let's see.
I got a, you know, I got three files. In
fact, I can open 10 of them. So, uh
let's see.
Uh those are those are thumbnails. Those
are um you know, right now I'm actually
using a lot of memory because I'm
opening uh image files. Anyway, so let's
look at the memory usage. Every time I
open VS Code, I have to show you guys
this. So there it is. Emacs 105
mgabytes.
By the way, normally it's 60 megabytes
because I opened a few image files. It
it goes up, but after a while it go
down. Okay. 105 megabytes. Several image
files.
Now VS Code you can see one gigabyte
Jesus wait that's Google
that's Google Chrome so there it is VS
code 480 megabytes
you know if you start to do something
it's going to be G one gigabyte you so
that's a problem of VS code besides it's
less efficient than EMAC okay close it
shut it shut it
vs code it situation why is that Okay.
Well, let's not talk about it today. So,
anyway, let's let's So, today we're
going to do is uh let's close that uh
showing browser. We're going to do our
talk show. Uh yeah, let's get a Python.
So, we're going to download a Python
program that does markdown to HTML.
Convert markdown to HTML. Then we're
going to write emac this code to call
that Python program so that so that we
can have you know convert uh markdown to
HTML right here. So actually let me just
show you okay so uh make sure today yeah
so markdown tutorial if you don't know
what that is copy this uh uh this
markdown tutorial is kalei.info
info, then search for markdown.
Okay, so you search it, you'll find it.
And there it is. Kasali.info
markdown tutorial. No HTTPS
in the URL. It's just HTTP, no s. Okay,
don't be fooled by browser telling you
security problem. This site is insecure
because something my website is not
telling you to send me credit card so
you don't need https
the coding uh populace has been fooled
anyway markdown tutorial so you find it
and okay close it so here we already
copied it so that's markdown so you
select all then you press a key look at
the pink window on the left. You can see
the command I call press a key. You see
the command is HTML markdown to HTML
right here and tab S is my key. I'm
using softly keys and I'm using War
keyboard layout. Softly keys is the most
efficient keybinding system for Emacs. I
talked about it in almost every video of
my 700 videos. Okay. So, you can see it
converted to markdown. So undo. So this
is marked down. Now redo. Go to the top.
This is converted to um
to HTML. So you can see but so this is
this command I showed you guys two days
ago. This emac this. So copy it. New
buffer paste it 130 lines. So there it
is. So show in eax this mode. So you see
pretty short text processing. Okay,
close that. Close that. But so this is
the result. But it's not it's not there
are some errors. So I talked about uh
two days ago the major issues is that
you have when you have nested list and
when you have table table
in markdown or when you have a code
block of code that contains markdown
text itself. Okay, that's that's a
issue. So let's see if all these other
programs you know written in Python in
Golang in JavaScript let's see if you
they actually
deal with those situations okay like
especially when you have code
of Python for example that process so if
you you have a code Python code that
process is markdown itself so you have
so that's so you want to turn that into
uh to HTML it's going to create a
problem. Let's see if they uh do that.
Okay. So, close that. So, showing
browser again. So, so the first job, the
first job is we want to ask artificial
intelligence guiological
intelligence
um
let's say uh Python
markdown to HTML. It'll tell me which
one to get. Okay, here are the most
common and effective ways to convert
markdown to HTML in Python using
markdown. Most popular recommended. So,
pip install markdown. Okay, there it is.
So, now let's uh hold on. Wait, wait for
it to finish. Let's magnify.
Magnify so you can see the glorious
text.
Okay. So, uh let's do it again.
Okay, this is this is not turning into
this. I want to magnify the window.
Stupid. You know the the cruiser doesn't
change. Okay.
Okay. This is kind of idiotic.
Okay. So anyway, so um so you do you got
to do pip install markdown. Okay. So
that's too big. Shrink, shrink, shrink,
shrink, shrink.
Okay. PIP install markdown. Now, should
do I should I do it? Yeah. Okay, let's
Why not? So, I can do it in ESL or I can
go to PowerShell.
Let's uh let's do it in PowerShell.
So, magnify
paste. Okay, let's do it.
Downloading markdown. Same thing. Same
thing. Up to date pit upgrade. A new
release of pip pip is available. Okay.
Python m pip install upgrade pip to
update run.
Okay. Downloading markdown 3.10 Python 3
none any something something something
something installing collected packages
markdown. Okay. Successful installed. So
that's good enough for me.
Uh let's so
let's
track the AI answer so we get so close
that show browser. So, are you guys here
with me?
Okay. Say something. Oh, fantastic.
We're gonna check your comments
in a minute. Okay.
Fantastic.
Okay. Showing browser. Uh yeah. So, we
got Yeah. So, we got first of all, we
got the question. Uh
let's see.
Okay. So we got Python markdown to HTML.
So copy the URL.
Copy the link. So this is AI bot answer
showing browser there. Okay. Click it.
It's public.
So you guys can look at
okay. Python markdown to HTML. Then uh
then it says this is how you do it.
Let's let's let's do it. Okay. So,
Python,
paste the code. Pop it out. Let's look
at how it's going.
Okay. Hello world from Python mode. Uh,
now this code is incorrect. You see the
bracket
I mean the triple quote is not closed.
The AI idiot.
Hi AI. You are an idiot. Oh, you see
this is a mistake. It dropped there. So,
let's see. So, supposedly
No, that's not right. So, let's see. So,
it's a string and here's markdown
uh and uh and uh then
yeah, markdown text. So,
and uh when what is that?
Uh
markdown text. And wait, this is this is
all up. Where's the function?
Where's the function called to convert
it?
Oh, here.
Stupid. You see? You see the guac got
syntax like uh rendering issues when you
have code involving this back tick and
quote that typically happens. Okay. So
let's see. So here is uh so here is the
code. So you don't need the triple back
tick. Does it mean anything in
Python? Um
no.
So this is a variable markdown. So that
that that should be hello. Uh
what why are they printing these
idiots?
It should print HTML. Okay. So let's
name it XHTML.
Copy and just print that value. Okay. So
now press a key to format pretty format
the code. Let's see if there's a syntax
error. Wait,
press this key
Python format buffer. That's right. So
So let's say that do it. Okay. No, you
cannot have that. Wait, you cannot do
that. Do that. Okay. and say do that.
Okay, it's formatted now. Let's run a
code. Run.
Oh,
beautiful. Let's see. Compare both
italics. So, it seems to work.
Beautiful. Okay.
So, uh let's
let's change the v variable name because
I like them to start with x. So let me
read the comments, okay, before it's too
long. I enjoy agent coding now. No more
need to learn linear algebra data
structure and algorithm. What is agent
coding? I don't understand.
One Jesus by electron my friend eat my
ram. That's right. So do you recommend
to kill buffers that are not in use to
save memory? Okay, so let me answer that
question. So hold on a second. Okay, so
let's put the code back. Syntax color in
HTML show in browser. So this is today's
talk show. Fantastic. That's progress.
We downloaded a Python package markdown
and we run it, test it, it works.
Okay. And uh so hold on. So let me
answer the question about Emacs.
Question from ACP Junior. Do you
recommend to kill buffers that are not
in use to save memory? Okay.
So, Emacs you tend so here you know
Emacs you have lots of buffers like uh
you know I just compile something you
have compile lot list buffer go back to
list buffer you have validate HTML close
it it's empty because every time I open
something in browser there's a hook it
it will automatically validate the pages
HTML
so show in browser so you can see at the
bottom
HTML XML valid. Okay. So if I for
example delete that. Okay. Let's say
delete that section. You see it becomes
colored because
I'm using
HTML mode you know. So so here's my
source code. HTML mode is in fact
several files about 2,000 lines of code
act you know maybe 2,000 lines of code
so HTML so let's see
highlight them yellow so you see all
these are HTML part so HTML mode there
is a function that close close that will
validate the HTML buffer
So we wrote that about two or three
years ago live. Okay, just go to
YouTube, search validate HTML. We wrote
it live. So it's putting to great use.
So if you have this page like that, you
can call the command directly. Now watch
the pink window. You'll show my command
there. Okay. So let's press the key to
that that.
So you see error buffer todo.h HTML
closing tag SE at position 1 190 does
not does not match last open tag section
at position 1701. So let's go to 1 190.
So press press there it is it jumped to
the location of the arrow. You see?
So close that. We don't let's say we
don't we we let's say we didn't know. So
we simply wrote something. something uh
you know and we show in browser and boom
you see it automatically do a check and
tell me this error. Okay. So now undo
undo undo undo undo. So we back to the
section. Okay. Now
now let's close this. Okay. You expand
the window. Showing browser. You see it
says HTML XML valid.
That's the power of Emacisp
and I can show you the source code.
Okay, so the source code. So describe
key press
and here is the documentation HTML
validate XML buffer found in Kasa HTML
mode map which is an interactive byte
code function in HTML engine.el.
It is bound to the key tap uh on Vora
keyboard layout.
Okay. So go to the source code. There it
is. So we wrote this live. Okay. So you
guys can check it out. So date 2023.
That's two years ago.
Fantastic and beautiful. So close that.
So that's a digression. Okay. So close
that. Close that. Close that. So the
question is in EMAC you got all these
buffers.
Personally I close buffers I don't use
because I'm a functional programmer. You
know a functional programmer is a clean
programmer unlike the C and C++
bit dedas.
You know when you are done you close it
as as opposed to a lot EMAC users you
tends to accumulate buffers. So like
normally you don't shut down emacs. So
after a week you have few hundred
buffers open. Okay
I used to be like that. The reason Emacs
tends to accumulate buffer. You don't
close it. Like if you for example let's
okay refresh. Okay that's gone. So let's
say let's open this. Okay. So this is
the talk show index page.
Okay. So
so let's say I want to go to today's
talk show. So I you know today's talk
show is right here. So I just press
enter. Open it. Showing browser. That's
today's talk show.
Now what? So but you but if you list all
the buffer you can see the previous the
index page is still open. So you can see
there you see this index page is still
open.
So you tend so for I believe for most
EMAC user you just leave leave buffers
open. You just open what you want. You
don't bother to close them until one day
you find out oh my god I got you know
500. It's very common 300 buffers. You
know, I used to have like 300 buffers.
Then you start to close them. So you can
you can for example, there's a command Q
buffer um Q buffer
kill some buffers. Okay, that command
will go through each one and ask you.
Okay. Or you you know or you can just
quit the entire Emacs and start restart.
So personally my habit is always kill
the buffers I don't want I don't need.
I'm done you know using for so example
this talk show index page close it you
know I have fantastic one key press. You
see I just did that. Undo
reopen it you know. So one key then this
page this buffer validate HTML output. I
don't need it. That's close close.
Okay. So that's what I typically do. I
close buffers I don't need. So my buffer
are usually just like 10 10 20.
Sometimes I do batch. So you know 50
buffer then I close them all.
That's my habit. Now the reason
people tend to accumulate buffers in
EMAC
you know you have a few hundred is
because the EMAC command to kill buffer
is this.
Okay that's a EMAC command when you call
it it's very annoying.
Are you sure? Are you sure this is the
one you want to kill? Kill means close
by the way. That's a traditional hacker
word for close or Q process, you know,
like like close. Okay. Are you sure?
Very annoying. So you have to say yes or
no, you know, like yes, then you kill
that. So that's annoying. So why you
want to you know so that's why buffers
tend to accumulate because you got this
the default command Q buffer
affirms you know asking a question to
affirm you annoying
and uh and go to Emacs blog search
search for kio buffer you'll find I have
an article on that emac Next flaw kill
buffer command induces buffer
accumulation.
That is my research finding. That's the
reason people have so many like hundreds
buffers and they tend to brag about it.
Look, look at my Emacs. I got 500
buffers. That means I'm powerful.
No, because your user interface design
is So that induces this garbage.
That's the real reason. Okay. So this
article is 2012
and there is a collection of articles on
Emacs flow. Most of them written about
10 or uh years ago 10 or 20. Okay. So to
this day most you know many of these are
not fixed like most of these are not
fixed you know that's you know that's
Emacs that's open source.
So that answers your question about do I
close my buffer. However, I don't close
them because of memory to save memory.
Well, that's
I mean that's not you know that's not
not my primary reason especially today
in the past 10 years you got like few
gigabytes you know 16 gigabytes of
memory. So so Emacs doesn't
uh the memory doesn't grow.
Okay. So, no certificate.
Uh, yeah. Ching New Zealand 8.99. Thank
you, Johnny. Walk 9KS 9,000 miles.
Thank you. Do you have a question,
New Zealand?
Okay, that's a digression about Emacs.
Okay, so let's let's let's actually um
so let's go back to talk show. Wait,
this is already so uh let's not talk
about Emacs. Let's get this. So, we got
this done marked down Python code. I
want to look at the code. Okay, so but
actually we got it done. Well, wait. We
need to write a EMAC command to call
this. So,
okay. So, that's okay. Let's focus on
that. Let hope that we can do that
finish that in 30 minutes. Okay. So we
need to write a emac command to call to
to send whatever in current buffer you
know text to this Python program and uh
the Python will create a output then the
Emacs will grab the output and replace
the text in your screen. Okay, that's
what we're going to do. So let's let's
focus on that. Let's not digress too
much. Okay, so far so good. So far so
good. Say good guys. Applause. Please
make this lively. Okay. So, let's so
let's let's begin. Okay. So, that's a
command. So, um
uh Okay. So, now
emac lisp. Okay. So, let's quickly let
let me get some you know the template
things out of the way. So ka html
uh markdown
no hyphen markdown to html I think I
already have that function okay so yeah
so let's add python python variation
because my function is written in eacisp
okay okay now this is python variation
okay uh call the external command
to
um convert
the
current
X block
or selection
of markdown to HTML. Okay, that's a
documentation. All important.
Typical industrial programmers, they
they don't care, you know, they don't
write this, you know, they because they
can't type, they can't touch type, you
know, oh my god, oh my god, this too
much, you know, so and they are the
typical coders in the industry. Most
people C, C++, they are trial and error
coders most of them because they don't
know mathematics. They don't have
mathematical training. I I am a mathemat
mathematical type of coder. So I always
write the documentation first, you know,
spec first.
But the but but but the vast majority
from my experience in the industry vast
majority of coders they are kind of like
in intuition trial and error you know so
if they want to write this they just
start code right away. Oh you know they
can they can do it fast okay faster than
me but they they just start trial and oh
error oh got to fix that then error oh
but how you know trial and error. So my
style is opposite of that.
I write the documentation first and when
I code typically one shot coding I think
about the problem taking me an hour or
something something then when I start to
type type it once perfect typically then
I mean well this some exaggeration okay
but that's typically the case in
contrast to these most you know uh
industrial coders trial and error and
also I know the language down to you
know down to the last bone of the
language, the last feather of the
language may be emacis or Python. Well,
not to not any anyway. Most languages
emac this, Python or whatever.
Golan language I study, I study the
language in depth first,
not necessarily Python though. Python I
haven't
uh so anyway. So,
so you need to Okay. So uh so what what
you need to do is
call Python
select region of interest
then
send it
call the Python
markdown to HTML
uh script. It may be a script or it may
be not. Then then um send
the
region to it
get its output.
Okay. Now replace buffer text with that.
Okay. That's basically V steps algorithm
also known as okay so let's check the
comment no certificate yeah I talked
about that many times https
okay the triple back tick is part of the
markdown to mark up a code block of
course did did not close the triple uh
back ticks okay so
No. Well, it's besides, you know, trip,
you know, actually, you know, the the
book
render is pretty You know, it's
basically
No question. Just here for the rents.
Thank you, Johnny. Okay, so let's keep
going. Okay, keep your comments. Okay,
so we got so far so good. Now, the one
of the issue, okay, so here. So put it
back. Syntax correct showing browser. So
here is a Python code. So you want to Oh
god. So this is getting a bit involved.
You want to um
so it's is you see the Python markdown
is a library. It's not a standalone
command. So you kind of you you you you
can't
so you effectively you have to create
this script on the fly.
Oh god.
Yeah. You create this script on the fly
you know or um
Okay. This
Okay. We need to get faster. We need to
go faster. Okay. We we can't we can't
think too much. Uh so you let's let's
just save it as script for now. Okay,
let's just save the script for now. Then
then we worry about then we write the
eac list code to create this script on
the fly then the as a file then call
Python to code the file you know.
So is it interesting? Are you guys
following me? Interesting. Okay. So, so,
so let's open. So, here save uh let's
say markdown
markdown to html py. Okay. So, uh go to
the directory uh and change the space to
underscore. So, we got the file and put
some date. So we got we can track. So
and here is the input. Now before we do
anything, let's make sure it actually
works on more complicated markdown.
Okay. So
So you want to go to a markdown.
Copy that. So now markdown is this. Can
you do that?
Okay. It's not your simple example. It's
my example. Can you actually do this?
Run it. Oh, very fast. Okay, let's see.
Okay, now copy that new buffer. Paste
it. Make it
emac this mod. Okay, so go to the top.
So, and we want to format it. Let's see.
Uh, wait. So, wait, not eaglass
HTML mode. Okay, now that looks better
now. Tap F to format it. Okay, looks
so
Looks good. Looks good. Now let's see.
Let's validate the file to see if it's
valid HTML. So press press. It's valid.
Oh Jesus.
the Python people I mean well
they have to work correctly because
otherwise it's going to be a disaster
because this is used very frequently. So
whatever error they have to fix fix fix
so so looks like it's working.
Uh so let's let's try save this xx uh
today's state then html.
Okay, now showing browser
looks good. Does it looks good to you?
Yes. Italic and important and bold and
stuff. And unorder list
and dash order list. Order list.
Correct.
Nested list. That's one of the tricky
part. They did it correctly. Fantastic.
Okay. Copy. Copy the path. Close it. So,
let's go down. Hold on a second. Okay.
So, close it. Close it.
Paste. Reopen. Copy the file path. Close
it. So, we got
um let's link that. Link that. Okay. So,
we got uh this is the output
showing browser.
So this is the code the Python code.
That's right. And uh this is the um
I mean this is the uh the output. Okay.
Fantastic.
Now there's something we can try here
the Python code. Now let's try if you
have a nested code. Okay. So let's let
me do it. Okay. So let's just say
so we got the nestedic code. Okay. So
close close.
Okay. So you see now let's try this is
JavaScript
console block and the back tick tricky.
I'm going to try to trick you. I have
dollar sign this cats you know you
should say I have four cats so this is
code and this code is in JavaScript
let's put it there that's standard
markdown you know so so when you convert
this you see if you do this naively if
you're going to write markdown to HTML
naively this part is going to up
because that's you know that is the name
of the programming language which is not
part of the code. So it the first line
needs to be treated specially depending
on whether it's you know programming
language name. So that's a you could say
it's a flaw design flaw of the markdown
because this
this represent code but that JavaScript
that's that's that's not code. Okay.
Then inside it you have markdown. So,
so if you have JavaScript
uh wait so this wait so this should be
uh that you know uh wait so uh god
okay so this is a JavaScript uh
string syntax okay so if you convert
this so let's run it let's just see if
it works
it works correctly can you
It didn't convert this back tick to
code. So this work correct correctly. So
okay. So we can so so far it's very
good. Okay. So we you know okay so so
far this is good. Good. Now now now
let's copy the full file path of this.
And now let's go to emac this. So this
is the script you want to call.
So sh let's just do it quickly. Okay.
shell command.
Uh what
I believe it's uh which one?
This one. Okay. So do it. Shell command.
Yeah.
Okay. So um
well
so let me do that. Okay.
And wait.
Okay. So this is uh
script path.
Okay. Define that to be that script
path. Okay. Now
uh shell command script path and you
need the input.
Okay. So you need um
Okay. So markdown text you need to uh
set it. Okay. So how do you set it? Let
for now let's just um do trivial. Okay.
Let's just say um if region active P if
there's a selection then
you do
okay uh
begin end okay that's beginning end so
that's beginning and end those are
integers for the beginning position in a
buffer and end position Okay. So if
region is active then
set qx begin to be region beginning.
Okay. Then set x end to be region
end. Okay. Region beginning returns the
position of the beginning of a selection
like like this. Okay. And end is the end
position. Okay. The set them then. So if
region active said that okay if region
is not active then what you do is you oh
god
you need to go to beginning of the oh
let me do this quickly okay saving
search and search backward okay search
backward for two uh to
set X begin
search backward
search backward two empty lines then
match end then you set the beginning of
the so if there is no region what you
want to do is you want to do a text
block like this this is a text block.
This is a text block or if your cursor
is here, this is the text block. So text
block is separated by blank lines. Okay?
So if region is not active, then you
search for two blank blank lines and you
set it to the end of the blank line.
Then you search forward again. Two blank
lines. Uh that's the that that that that
that.
Okay. And two of it then. Okay. So we
don't care. Then uh search for that.
Then um
then then set
X end to be
match beginning beginning of those blank
lines. Okay.
So So is it is that clear? So okay. So
but let me check bound. Is that clear?
Does does you guys
understand? Do you need explicit
handling of end of file? Yes, you do.
So, yeah. So, actually that's what I'm
doing now. So, you know, so um so
optional bound no error true. If you
cannot find it, there's error. So, but
you just say no error true. That means
don't don't tell me about it. Don't
ignore the error. Okay? Come. We don't
care. So you need neo and n here. Okay,
delete that. You need the neo and t.
Same thing here. Okay. Uh pify the code.
So there. Okay. So like if you are at
the beginning, what's a block? This is a
block. But there is no two blank lines
above it, you know. So so you want to
deal with that situation. You know,
ignore the arrow. If you cannot find two
blank lines. Okay. So if there is no
selection then you uh say set okay
that's that's let's that's that's let's
that's let's that's let's that's let's
that's let's set up the beginning and
end okay
then markdown text okay set markdown
text
uh buffer
uh so you want to grab the text between
the beginning and end uh buffer
substring no properties okay that's very
common I I did this 1,000 times in my in
my 100 emac this writing uh live
streams. Okay. So, just search for my uh
YouTube Emac list coding is like 100
videos. So, okay. So, we got that set.
We got So, we got beginning and end.
Let's put that in the in in here. Then
we got markdown text. That's a variable
local variable. Then script path. Okay.
We got the beginning and end set there.
We got mount contact and the script.
Okay. Now the script needs to take a um
okay the shell command needs to be uh
something like python location then okay
so you need contact the string python
then script path then
then x markdown text you know this so
it's a bit tricky how do you pass so on
the command line when you want to call
some Python script you know uh
you know convert this py uh wait
what oh god so that's the question
python
convert mark
down to HTML py right then you need kind
of the
so it's a bit tricky so you can the
typically your python script can take
input from the standard in from the Unix
idiots you know std in
do you guys know what I'm talking about
that's like you know if you code then
you must know stdin that's a standard
input
or you can take like you know text
equals to uh you know like this way this
way is no good because then you got the
back tick back slash hell. It's
impossible to escape them.
Uh so you so so let's let's make it take
from standard
input
and let's make it output to standard
output. Okay, you guys are following me?
Do you guys understand? Could you use
mark paragraph?
Uh
yes in Emacs. So in Emacs you have a
command called mark paragraph. For
example I call it mark paragraph. I
never use it.
Why? Because the mark paragraph
what what is what is its definition of
paragraph that depends on something
called syntax table for the current
buffer. So in EMAC buffer you have this
thing called syntax table and that is
each buffer has one okay they may be
different.
So when you turn on a major mode like
Python mode, HTML mode HTML mode or SE
mode or El mode from you know from other
people when you turn on a major mode the
major mode typically set or modify the
syntax table. So the current buffer it
has a syntax table um
you know local to the buffer and that's
so that's when the markdown command
what what is the paragraph it it checks
it checks it depends on the syntax
table. Okay so we can look at the code
please. So basically what that means the
behavior
is dependent
on what is the current major mode. So
when you are coding that command here it
does this you know without blank lines
but somewhere in when you are tomorrow
when you are on a different machine
doing uh JavaScript it may be something
else that's a problem that's so I don't
like it. So let's look up
uh mock I never use this command. Okay,
so look, let's look up the
documentation. Mark paragraph is a
interactive native compiled function in
paragraph. EAL mark paragraph syntax is
this optional arg allow extended
something inferred type. This is new you
know in the past few years Emacs this
added this type thing. So put point at
beginning of this paragraph mark at end.
Okay, the paragraph marked is the one
that contains point or follows point.
You know the Emacs idiots jargon like
what the is a point? Just say C
position the the Emacs dev. Okay,
they refuse you know because oh we
invented the concept C position before
any text editor that's why we call it
point you know point.
So, so after 40 years like today's
generation then when they want to you
use Emacs what the is the point
like what the is the point you know
so that's why they go to VS code
so you know Emacs people we refuse you
know we don't going to change this so
stupid Emacs people that's why nobody
use Emacs it's die dying it's dying like
dinosaur
Emacs dev
You guys, okay, I'm too old, you know.
They know I'm a troll. They think I'm a
troll. I've been fighting with them for
10 for 20 years. Okay, so now it relies
on you guys new generation. So you guys,
you know, talk to the death in some way
politely or whatever. Get them to uh
change this point in documentation say C
position. Okay, the point my ass.
Okay, anyway, back to the mark
paragraph. Okay, so put point at the
beginning of this paragraph, mark at the
end, and the mark means, you know,
that's another concept. But but
basically, it just means selection.
Okay, so with arc something something
okay, let's just look at the source code
because I'm a hard coder. I want just
see the code there. Okay, so here defend
mark, you know, mark paragraph. Let's so
let's look carefully how they define
paragraph
uh so transient mark you know
complicated go to j forward there there
it is so it depends so it reli so what
is the meaning of paragraph in mark
paragraph it relies on this command
forward paragraph so now let's look up
that command that function forward
paragraph is defined so let's go to that
documentation
uh and expand the window. So for forward
paragraph move forward to end a
paragraph with argument arc do it arc
times and okay a line with a line which
paragraph start matches either separate
paragraphs if paragraph separate matches
it also or is the first line of a
paragraph
confusing I know what what is saying a
paragraph a paragraph end is the
beginning of a line which is not part of
the paragraph have. Oh god. So let's
look at the code. Field prefix rejects.
Oh god. Field prefix not equal field
prefix. What the is field prefix?
You know complicated code. That's why I
don't use you know I don't use this
start if and not equal empty string or
paragraph start.
So highlight paragraph start. Let's see
where did you what the is paragraph
start. Okay. So it's actually a
variable.
So you need to look at.
So then you know the code go on and on
and on field prefix you know I just want
to select a paragraph like what the
are you doing?
You know complicated. This is
fundamental code in Emacs. You know,
this is this is written like uh this
this this code mark paragraph is like at
least for uh 40 years old. I'm pretty
sure 30 at least
you know because well you know in part
they also have to do to deal with right
to left languages such as Islamic.
Okay. So then they also have to deal
with like a region of text that you are
not supposed to move cursor into. They
have to deal with that. So that's why
it's kind of
you know complicated. So that's why I
don't use this you know I don't like but
but my question our question is like
uh what so what is paragraph start? So
look at the documentation.
Uh wait
documentation paragraph start is a
variable defined in paragraphs. Its
value is
okay. So this is how they define
paragraph.
Okay. So that thing means
line break. Okay. That's forward uh
you know that's one of the asy
characters called uh line feed okay form
feed you know it's you know older
practice you guys may not know anyway
that's that character is called point 12
in as keyi okay called form feed
so let's uh wait let's go back so
describe paragraph paragraph start okay
so it's defined as a string of regular
expression
form feed character which is a line
break is which like page break. Okay,
which in EMAC this code it means page
break or it means it just means like
something like that. Okay, like you put
a a break, you know, line something, you
know, code something that's so but in
EMAC they use this
control Q
L that what EMAC people use it's
invisible character form feed to mean
just like you know just like just like
that okay
I you know again I have an article on
that I have several articles search for
foam feed you'll find it. Okay.
So, so back. So, we digressed far enough
yet. So, paragraph start. Let's describe
variable. Let's see. So, it's a regular
expression. So, it's a phone feed or uh
or god. Then, let's So, it's bunch bunch
of blanks, you know, bunch of white
space. So, let's turn on show white
space. Press press press. So, it's a
space, then a tab. space or tab.
Okay. Then zero or more and end. So a
paragraph is defined. So if you have a
phone feed, that's a beginning of
paragraph. Okay. Or it's a space or tab
one or more. So
rejects for beginning of the line that's
that starts or separates paragraph.
Okay.
Yeah. Anyway, that's so that's a deal.
Okay. So,
I you know I don't like it. So, uh so
anyway, that's that's so let's go back.
Okay. Now, we got confu we we digressed
into several levels. So, let's keep
track what of what we doing. So, so that
other people have some idea what we
talked about. Okay.
So uh so originally we were talking
about mark paragraph. Okay. So copy
that.
Okay. Add corner brackets. Add corner
brackets
and make it HTML and and make it that
and show in browser. So we talked about
these things.
Okay. A digression. Now
go back to So close that. Go back to So
go back to Yeah. code. Okay.
Could you use more? So is that a bad
thing? It seems like a do what I mean
command which is more EDI edomatic to
Emacs. Yeah, that's up to you. Okay. So
for me, no, I want universal.
It depends depends on the situation, you
know. So depends on the situation.
for some situation you want a command
that's universal. let's say common
command you know so so in EMAC this the
common syntax is that so you you always
call the same command doesn't matter
it's in Python or whatever language you
know the command will depends on the
language and do the comment right so
maybe so that's fitting but for the
paragraph
you know so so here's the thing what
does a paragraph mean in a programming
language
okay It it kind of depends. For example,
you know, I can tell you what's the
wrong with the mark paragraph because in
HTML, if you call mark paragraph, it's
unpredictable.
Okay, for example, copy the whole file,
new buffer, paste. This is our talk show
today. Save it. XX uh random number.
Okay.
Uh
okay. So, HTML. So there it is. Save it.
Uh wait, we named it wrong. So rename
it. So this is uh
okay. So here is a HTML file, a copy of
today's talk show. Now let's make it
HTML
mode. Okay, that's a bod emac mode for
HTML.
Do it. Okay, that's the default. Now
when you call mark paragraph let's see
what happens okay
mark paragraph do it okay it goes one
line above you see there's a extra blank
line at top okay so what if you call it
here so
you see what the is that you know
what what what is the meaning of
paragraph can you see
so can you see Franc's this holder.
You see okay my cruiser is here call
mark paragraph it does that now if my
cruiser is here what does it do it does
it it goes up to meta so does that mean
it's somehow dependent on
so what is it depend on so if my cruiser
is here call mark paragraph it it went
down so if if my cruiser is here co par
Mark paragraph it went down again. So
what the is your meaning of
paragraph?
So if my cruer is here in the body
called mark paragraph it oh it okay so
it always go downwards.
So if my cruer is here before the body
tag call it still go down. So you I
don't know what the is going on. I
don't want to spend one hour to find
out. You see that's a problem.
So for code you don't have you know you
the general concept of paragraph should
be a block of code
separated by blank lines or you could go
semantic. You know a paragraph just
means like the the the element you know
whatever nested complete element you
could do that but in the default HTML
mod I don't know what the it is. So
anyway that's an example. Okay. Delete
this file. Okay.
Okay. So delete that file. Make let's
make sure we are not confused. Okay. So
close that. Close that. Okay. So that's
a digression about the mark paragraph.
Now
we digress so much. Now we need to get
back to get get this to work. Okay.
Let's let's let's get on to that. Close
that. Let's see.
Okay. is well. So, okay. So, let's make
a
uh
uh screenshot so we have a record of
that. Okay. Wait. Yeah. So, we don't
care about that. Okay. So, now
uh now we will coding this. Yes. Okay.
Now, remember we are coding this command
begin end.
Okay. and uh markdown text. Okay. Script
path. Okay. This is a argo outline.
Okay. Argo outline. Perfect
documentation. Okay. Then set uh and
this part is set X begin. Set begin
point positions. Okay. No, not point my
ass. Okay. Then set markdown text. So
now we got to call shell command. So we
need to modify the Python script so that
it takes input from standard in. Okay.
So now let's put um
need to feed
weight okay to standing to the script.
Okay. That's what we need to do. Pedify
the code. Put it back. Syntax color
showing browser. Now we have um
we know what we are doing. Okay. Here is
the emac this code. Now we need to
modify the Python code. Okay. The Python
code needs to take input from standard
input. Okay. So how do I how to do that?
Python. I don't know Python.
Let's read my tutorial.
So I forgot where.
St I N. Oh. Oh. Oh. Python says stand
out but there is no stand in.
Oh god.
So what is how do you um
so in Python how do you get the stand
in? That's the question. Do I know?
Uh do you guys know? Probably some of
you know.
So what what what you guys saying is
that a bad thing it seems. Okay. Can you
create a entire program like example
Windows word using Python code only?
Can you create a entire program
like example
Windows word using Python code only?
What do you mean? Seems like it went
back to the last unclosed tag. Okay. Use
subprocess.
So what do you So I don't know how. So,
so right now our job is to make the
Python script
to take standard input. I don't know how
to do that. So, let's and my tutorial
doesn't cover it. So, let's ask Gork
in Python. How to get std?
I've done this before. Oh, yeah. CIS
stand in obvious obviously
okay so now let's go to um the Python
code Python code here so you need to uh
take stand in import sys read okay so
let's write
okay so we do we care about that no no
okay markdown Text is just that that
that that
that
competitive competitive programming. My
ass
don't like competitive programming
because those competi competitive
programmers they are like they are
useless you know they they you know they
they they are just good for like fast
coding but for real you know creating a
huge project they are like not very
good. Okay read all input at once. Yeah
shut up. Okay. So that's simple. As
simple as that.
Is that the magical? Yes.
Okay. So let's save it.
Okay. Can we test it? Yes, we can. Yeah,
but it's uh involved. Okay. So
yeah, we can test test it. Okay.
Markdown to HTML. Okay. So here. So, so
that's so you want to create another
file.
Okay, let's open this one. Make a
backup. Go to the directory. Rename this
markdown. Okay.
Uh let's say
sample markdown. Okay. This not let's
make it sample markdown.
Okay. And this is called sample HTML.
Okay. Uh
HTML output.
Okay. Let's X X it. So they are in the
same location. And now let's add
underscore to them. Okay. Then then mark
these two file. Copy their file path.
Close it. Close it. And uh and there
there there link them.
And uh
so markdown to HTML.
This one no longer exists. Okay. So here
is our code. So here is the markdown to
HTML and here is okay. Output. So sample
markdown input. So there so in this file
we need to put a sample markdown input.
So how do you do that? You go to
markdown link.
Where is my markdown tutorial? So
I just showing browser. Okay. So some
markdown tutorial. So copy that.
So
sample paste it. Okay. So we got sample.
Now let's not make it too complicated.
Let's just say
easy. Okay.
There it is. Okay. Sample markdown. Save
it. Close it. Okay. Now we want to test
this
script. feeding it the standard in.
Okay. Open this directory in shell in
PowerShell magnify.
Okay. Then
call this command. So copy the command
name.
Close it. Okay. So we need to write a
shell command. Okay. So we are multi-
language coding. So you need PowerShell.
Now
PowerShell you need to call this command
with uh standard input. How do you feed
it standard input? You can. So in
PowerShell, how do you
pass the standard input?
God. Okay.
So are you guys following me? Say yes.
Okay. If you are still here,
make this you know active. Make my video
active. So let me know if you are still
watching. Do I make sense? Am I going
too slow? Okay. So PowerShell
search I don't have I don't think I
cover standard in oh PowerShell run
PowerShell from command. Oh no no that's
different thing. Okay.
Yeah. So I my tutorial don't have the
Okay. So let's ask Gro. Okay. So
So first of all, let's put that into our
um
Okay. So
wait
okay so put it back. So let's ask in
Python how to get stand in copy.
So that's the guac answer
and uh then we want to know in
powershell how to get standing. Okay,
new question.
Paste.
Oh, we don't we don't want to get
standing. We want to pass
we want to pass the stand in to the
Python program. Okay.
Um
well in that case it's just get content
okay yeah there get content that I know
okay so get console here's what we do
okay so powershell
get content
get content what what file so
the file would be sample markdown. Okay,
so that is the file. Okay,
so
this file copy file path close. Okay, so
and now go back to PowerShell
get content
this file. Okay. Oh, yeah. Path. Okay.
Oh. Oh, right. The dot.
Oh, the Python can just say dash. That's
right. Okay, we skipped. Do Do you guys
know what I'm talking about?
Do you guys know what I'm talking about?
So, one way to do it is like this. Okay.
Then the Python uh file name. So, what
is the Python file name?
Uh
uh HTML markdown to HTML Python
but
what oh god showing browser so
oh yeah okay so py search for py Y.
Okay. So, here is the Python code. Copy
the file path.
Okay. So, you just So, this is one way
to do it. Okay. So, you say
Python.
Okay. One line. So, it's one way.
Another way which we learned is just
forget about get content. You just do it
like that. Okay. I think so.
So there are two ways. Okay. So yeah.
Yeah. Okay. So
pass
into the Python script
method
one.
Okay, we are commenting
it so that other people watching this
can know what I'm be doing. So
this is the way. Okay. I think
yeah let's try. Okay.
Uh wait. So wait. So
Oh actually you need to do this way.
Uh you need to do them both I think. Do
you guys know?
Okay. ACP. Hello ACP Junior.
So we want to we have a file this file
we want to pass it the content to the
python
script a standard in so is this the way
to do it let's try so put this back show
in browser I mean syntax color so we did
this is uh asking guac so let me comment
and okay So
work answer.
Okay, we ask guen
here is a simple example
and here is our act the script we script
and here is a sample output html and in
python how to get stand in. Okay, that's
a GU answer and uh um
yeah, Gork answer which is actually
pretty simple and we can show the code
you know it's just that okay and then um
then we need to test that. So copy that.
So let's test that. Okay,
can this work?
Try it. Yes. You see one shot coding.
Perfect. Perfection.
You know in video games when you did
something right, you know, they they
they will say something perfect or
sometimes it's girls, you know, sexual
orgasmic voice like when you did
something correct, you'll go
Perfect.
Okay. So, so, so where are we? So, we
got the um So, this works. We don't need
that. So, let's let's clean it. Method
two.
Okay. So, we don't need let's not Okay,
let's just that. Okay. Okay.
It should refresh. Fantastic. Okay.
So now
the final step emac bisp
there. Okay. Now we know the syntax. So
here you
so copy copy this. So what you do here
is you call
uh wait you need to call powershell
Jesus.
Because in Emacs by default when you
call shell command it calls the
command.exe.
idiots.
Okay. I know. So in EMAC right now the
problem is
here is a problem. Okay.
Beat X down text to stand in of the
script. Okay, how do you do that?
S E Emac this tutorial will tell you.
Okay, so this is EMACB shell command. So
there's a section co shell command.
Okay, co shell command on region.
Okay, let's try that shell command on
region. It calls a shell command
region. Are we calling a shell command?
Yes. And uh so call a shell command feed
the emac region to stand in. That's what
we want. And take the stand out
optionally replacing the region. That's
what we want. Okay. In fact, I got the
Python code standing read stuff. Okay.
And and we got a code here. Okay. Show
command on region. It's just copy copy
paste coding. Fantastic. We don't even
have to work anymore.
Delete whatever. Delete whatever. So
shell command on region basically just
this. Okay. Shell command on region.
Begin end. Oh, okay. X begin X end.
That's our region. Then command string.
Yeah, command string. So let's define
our command string.
Uh then we don't need this anymore.
Command string is going to be now where
does this come from?
Yeah. command string is
is here. Okay,
let's see. Wait, call shell command on
region. Wait a minute. It's still
calling the command.exe.
So,
yeah, but I think that that'll work
because the command.exe exe will simply
call Python. There's no complicated
stuff. Okay, let's try it. So, command
on region.
Okay, then command string. You need to
set command string. So, the command
string is a script path. What's my
script path there?
and uh and you don't need this then but
you need
hyphen. Okay, so
let's go back. Yeah, so you need a
hyphen at the end. Python markdown
Python script name hyphen that takes
that in. So Python
script path then hyphen. Okay. So that
is a command string and the command
string is a variable. So local variable.
So let's you know
so you need to define it a local
variable. Don't forget
and let's rename it
to be uh the more
uh let's just leave it. Okay. Clean the
code.
Highlight it. Wait,
highlight the command string.
Okay, so set command string
equals to that. Then
then feed x markdown text. Okay. So,
so actually we don't even need to define
this.
Okay.
So, sh command on region begin and
command string
uh and what's neo neot. Okay. The is
that
okay show command on region.
So
okay so it's a complicated start and
command
optional oh output buffer okay you need
to write
so what is the out okay so let's so you
need the output of
describe function
Am I doing good? The Python package come
with a command line tool. Oh, you don't
need it. Yeah. Okay. So, but you don't
need it. Okay. So, how many people are
watching? Three.
Please guard four.
Okay.
YouTube. Okay. So, you so so sh
command on region. That's the right
command. Start and position and the
command. Okay. Then optional. Then
output buffer.
Um so describe function. Let's see
what does the
output buffer.
Oh god. Very complicated. Can you see?
You know the documentation is a few
pages. Now let's look at my tutorial.
because my tutorial might explain
better.
Uh, no.
Okay.
Uh,
optional fourth argument output buffer.
Specify where to put the commands
output. If the value is a buffer or
buffer name, erase the buffer and insert
it. Uh, a neo a
new neo value of shell command. Don't
erase buffer prevent erasing. Okay. Any
other than neo value means insert the
buffer insert the output in the current
buffer after start. Okay.
Neo. Okay. So it's just neo.
Okay. So this you see emac doesn't have
named parameters. That's why you got neo
t neo t. You don't know what it mean. So
output for neo t means replace t replace
true true error buffer neo uh replace
okay so that so that's it
yeah so that neot neo t okay so I think
I think that's it double check one more
time
let's compact Okay.
Select region.
Send it to
Python
script
stand in via shell.
command.exe.
Okay.
Get the output. Replace buffer text with
that. Okay. That's that's what right.
Okay.
So, let's um
Okay. So, that's you know, here's a
whole code. Okay. Uh go to the beginning
xf make this uh declare a lexical
binding make a backup go to the
directory b4 by compile okay you got
some issues warning unused lexical
variable markdown okay so yeah we can
fix it because we are actually not using
it
and unused variable okay in fact it's dd
the Oh,
do you guys know what I'm doing? See
this text? We don't need the text. We
just need the beginning and position.
Uh,
okay. And uh, let's see.
Predefine the code. Okay. Looks like
that. Okay.
Make a backup. I compile. No error.
Fantastic.
Run the code.
Okay. I think this code is ready to run.
When we call this meta x in emac on a
region of markdown, it will do the job.
And uh that'll be it for the day.
Just you know example
you know but in real code you you you
have to like
um do a few other things. For example,
you don't want this script, you know,
this magical script. For example, you're
going to, you know, put this on website
so other people can use it, right? But
before they use it, they need to create
a magical script. You know, this Python,
which is not necessary because in Emacs,
you can create this script on the fly,
right? So, you need to fix that. But for
now, let's just try this if this work.
Okay. So now let's open a new buffer.
Let's go to a markdown. Let's get some
markdown.
Copy markdown. Paste the markdown. So
here is a bunch of markdown. Let's uh
let's delete the rest. Okay, just that.
So let's put the cursor here.
Uh wait, let's copy. So what's the
command name?
Okay, copy. Let's go here now.
Oh, the command size mark on markdown to
HTML Python. Oh,
okay. Wrong.
Okay. So, wait. Undo. Let's do it. Let's
Let's call it again.
Let's see what it can open file use ex.
Okay. No, no such file directory. So it
cannot
use a EMAC temp
info talk show markdown. So
okay so let's it cannot find the file
script. Oh okay script path. Okay, you
needs you you can't you you cannot use
this shortcut
because the command.exe don't understand
this tilda.
Okay, so you need that
and see
yeah
okay evaluate the buffer. Let's try it
again. Now, maybe I need backslash. I
don't Okay, go back here. Did that. Move
the cursor here.
Or do it.
Did Did it work? No.
Okay, let's try something else.
Call it.
Do it. It It worked.
It works guys.
Select all met
HTML markdown to HTML Python. Do it.
Fantastic. And beautiful.
They must also pip install. Yeah, that's
required. Yeah, we just So that's
required. So we need to put that into
documentation. Um you know because
that's a design of this command to call
the Python.
Um
yeah so you need to say you need to have
the Python mark. Yeah that's so that's
annoying thing. So this script this
command. So let let's let me clean up
first. Okay. So it's working. So you can
see but now we need to clean up. So
you need to say you need to have Python
installed
and you need to have Python
um markdown lib installed and annoying.
So this okay so that's you know for this
live stream that's what it is. Okay. So
put the code back and uh syntax show in
browser.
Okay. So
so that's it today. I hope you guys like
it. I think everything is clear. If you
have questions, ask me. Okay. Uh
so we got this code to work
but it requires Python installed. That's
obviously requirement. But then a nasty
issue is that you need the user to
install Python markdown li
it's not present because you know
you can assume people have Python
installed because we are coders what
you're doing with markdown to HTML right
but then you do not want to assume
people know Python how to code Python.
So when you say you need Python markdown
library installed, they they are like
what what what does that mean? What
library? Which one? How do I install it?
You know like like ask guac guac will
tell you you know you need to do python
pip you know pip
something. So any anyway so this works
and uh
yeah so th this part I don't really like
you know I you know I wish Python has it
built in or easier language has it built
in so far as I know not in JavaScript
you know in JavaScript you need to
download the common mock or some other
you know we talked about two days ago
common mock.js JS you need to install it
install it it's npm it has 10
dependencies you know the dev dependency
then you need to build it then it ch out
the script then you can use it complex
and python apparently it turns out it's
not building you need to install this
pip markdown so it's not not
satisfactory
uh and for Golan. I believe I asked
guac, you also have to install a
external library. So that's
and you know markdown to HTML. Is there
not like one
programming language that has it as a
build library?
you know, probably not because it's it's
not core to a programming language.
So, alternatively,
if you want to write a EMAC command that
do that, so you can
you can have the user install a markdown
to HTML command line script,
you know,
and it's another step, you know. So,
The best is actually just
Elisp code.
Okay. So like the e-magisp code I have
here.
So I need to spend few hours like
actually 20 hours to make this robust.
So so I think that's it for today. But
another so what we need to do what I
want to do is to look at the markdown
code.
How does Python do it? Let let's do
that. Okay, let's do that. So now
given a Python library, how do you find
where is the source code? I don't
remember but I have looked into so
Python tutorial
print version building help. Let's see
print version. Uh then this related
Python path and module file path
functions print version get script path
import module show show module doc okay
list module functions list module list
loaded modules okay module search path
there
okay so let's run that code
let's see where where where is it Where
the can they put it on my um
computer when you pip something?
Okay, Python paste run it. Run the code.
Okay, here is the output and paste the
output and make it one line per line.
Okay. So it's in
oh app data.
Okay. So it's in app data
local programs Python.
I mean where where where did I put when
did I put in data? So
where is the command python
do it use app data local program. Okay.
So it's in app data.
Okay. So it's in app data. So open that
li
down. Wait. Search for
search for markdown. Wait, that's not
there.
Side packages. Okay. So, app data local
programs Python Python 312
lib side packages. Now, search for
markdown. There it is.
So, let's look the code.
Now, this is going to be okay. This is
going to be next live stream. Maybe not
next one because next one I probably
going to do wuam language. So this is
going to be you know in in in a few
days. Okay.
Where I'm going to look at the code. So
this is another topic about
the the question of algorithm of text
processing.
Do you grab text? Do you turn them into
a ch charact character array or bite
array? Or do you pro, you know, deal
them a string? Like what do you do?
Okay, so this is text processing
question. So let's look at oh god HTML
parser.
They actually have a HTML passer.
What?
So another So this is getting
interesting because you know there's
different approaches. Do you actually
use a parser or do you just do like a
regular expression?
Uh and but why do you need a HTML
passer? Because you are just you need a
markdown passer because this is turning
to HTML. Why do you need a HTML passer?
I don't know. But um
okay so that's next one. So thank you
guys for watching. Bye guys.
Actually how much preparation do you do
before live stream? Uh the short answer
is basically zero.
Okay. Uh the long answer is you know I I
work on computer all day. So I have some
thoughts and uh I have a list of todos.
So so it's in a sense even I have zero
preparation is kind of already prepared
because I've been working on this. For
example, the thought about
creating emac this code to do markdown
to HTML is a long time. Then I wrote it
live in live stream. then
I run into problems because you know
nested list or uh you know issues I know
it's there I already know because I have
experience
so so I already know I wanted to look at
you know Python Goland you know
different languages and the other
question is how they do it because in
EMAC this you turn it into a buffer so
you know you got a buffer then you can
move the cursor you can insert here
remove there but in other languages ages
all of them you cannot do that you got
one giant string fixed immutable
so but how do they do it of of course
they can do it but then it's maybe
turning it into
you know bite array those are dynamic
array you know in different languages
depends in Goland it might be
what they call a slice
of run you know run is bas basically the
character type for golan of UTF8
characters unic code characters so you
you turn it into a like slice of run and
slice means
slice means like basically just means
dynamic array okay it's array is a data
type in golan so depends on the language
that's another interesting to thing to
look into okay bye guys.
Hi guys.
Shut down. Shut down. End stream. Pay
me. Okay. Don't forget if you guys enjoy
like my stuff, go to kasar talk show.
kasali.info.
Okay. kasali.info. http no s. Then go to
the bottom. Patreon me, Amazon gift card
me, PayPal me.