hello guys welcome to another episode
ofan talk show we are going to code emac
lisp I'm going to explore the emac lisp
P case which is pattern matching D
structure that topic okay I'm I don't
know that yet so I'm just going to
explore and study and maybe explain part
of it so this is not a coherent lecture
about emac lisp the programming language
but you can enjoy the ride if you are
watching this offline skip skip skip and
play at 1.5 speed because I ramble if
you are here say hi love to see your
messages okay now drink coffee and uh
coffee and uh tea you see my elaborates
setup okay remember skip skip skip okay
uh so glove 80 keyboard fantastic
ultimate hacking keyboard fantastic
nulia track boo fantastic and this fancy
device most advanced SW board s v a l b
o a r
d okay you should um get
it expensive though so I have a video
review for each one of them I will be
using uh Spar board you know window is
very annoying every time you jigle the
USB it disconnect and reconnect and you
know that's why you
hear okay emac this P case okay let me
relax and go slowly remember skip around
play at 1.5 speed
USA army be or you can
be nice coffee that's coffee with honey
Elite honey from Costco
the American middle class Elite
Costco okay P case Okay so P case is a
lisp Library introduced about maybe 10
years
ago so P case okay let's look up the
documentation
uh no not search Twitter I press the
wrong key so P case describe function P
case there it is is so it is in this
package okay so the list library is
pk. in the standard lisp bundled Library
okay so this is a source code about
1,000 lines of code okay and it is
written by this guy I respect Stefan
Monier he is a professor researching
functional programming languages and and
he has been a g emac leader for about
five or more years starting about
2008 okay Stefan monia a professor
researcher in functional programming
languages so that's today we we're going
to look into this package because this
is very useful and uh I'm just going to
learn how to use it okay and talk about
stuff that's what we doing okay so
um so recently I changed my key binding
what is the key binding
for um oh
H wait tap hm I just changed my key
binding today Forks HTML mod so I
forgot what is
the uh preag Edge okay so Edge new preag
what is
it insert preag oh
th okay em mag
lisp uh okay God the key binding is
wrong
again
T I want to pop it
out what is it God
uh V tarle HTML
insert oh I forgot what's the command to
pop it
out okay
so tap Edge then search for
pre
uh insert
God frustration okay let's look at the
um tab HED let's look at the HTML mod
source code this is my HTML mod source
code
uh oh pop out source code there oh oh
that's why it got repeated over readen
that's why
that's bad so this pop out I wanted
to okay so insert let's say insert this
side so evaluate this okay then
um
then go to S emac key binding customize
evaluated close close okay
now close reopen so that reloads the HTM
mod now tap
HED HED tap HH okay PKS um now PKS yeah
so let's look look
um hello Arrow hello simple hello
do hello simple you have switched from
Firefox to
Brave uh what Ed question is that
trolling because I answered that a
thousand
times Firefox Brave okay uh if you are
trolling I don't know if you are or not
or if you are new here probably new but
because I talked about that like well uh
why do you use multiple browsers which
browser do you use there's a
dedicated talk show like a few month ago
and before that and before that okay P
case so
study so I'm just going to do my job
okay which this is what I need to
do study of P case okay let's let's
focus on
that so this is p case
so ml style pattern matching that means
ml means meta language one of the
first uh functional programming language
ML stand for meta language back in
1970s I think so to do okay you got a
bunch of too I don't care I want to know
how to
use
uh well the first version was written
before I knew about rackets match
construct the second version was
significantly influenced by
it okay so a good presentation of the
underlying ideas can be found at
extensible pattern matching in an
extensible language oh this is actually
a academic paper 2010 by Sam
toin extensible pattern matching in an
extensible language okay pattern
matching is why to use technique in
functional programming languages
especially in those meta language and
hascal conditions where it is at core of
the semantics true and wolam language of
course wolam language is the granddaddy
well I wouldn't say granddaddy but it's
a it's the most powerful than them than
hascal Meta Meta language because wam
language is symbolic patter magine th
hascal and metha language ml P magine or
F or or Cam their pagin
is structural but not symbolic okay so
wolam language pattern matching is like
wolf is like list maros but 100 times
more powerful
elaborate uh so the language in Lis
tradition in contrast patter matching it
typically provides by libraries build
with maros okay we present match a
sophisticated pattern match for racket
implemented as language extension using
maral Okay Mar this Mar really sucks the
syntax the system supports novel and
widely used paring forms and is itself
extensible the extensibility of match is
implemented via a general technique for
creating extensible language
extensions okay I'm not quite sure what
it means technically about extension you
know what do you mean by language
extension because you just add a
function via Marco or whatever means so
but what exactly you mean extension how
is it different just
uh unless you you mean
syntactical you know adding syntaxes
which which most language cannot do even
this maros you know let me dispel one
myth about this maros the list Fanatics
they will say list maros allow you to
change
syntax actually no not at all list
Markus you know with whatever list
Markus your syntax is still Ned parent
always
okay then some lisp phonetics they will
say especially common lisp they will say
oh Lis reader Mar allows you to change
syntax not really
you you still basically stuck with the
nested par except maybe you can add this
you know back tick a little bit you know
like a little trick but you cannot
create like 1+ one * three syntax like
that infix syntax so this this maros or
this reader
maros they are kind of
a uh historical quo okay they don't
actually change anything syntax however
they do the nested parent transformation
that's what they do they
transform you know for example this you
know parent something something parent
you can transform it to call other
functions or you know that's what it
does Mar and stuff you know you can hold
evaluation you know then check what's
the argument then depends on what's the
argument then you do something such as
in a if
expression or while loop you know you
need to check you know you need to hold
evaluation first then in while loop you
change variable in each iteration things
like that but your syntax is still
nested parent okay you know this people
Fanatics these idiots they insist this
is a giant huge myth for 30 years you
know still today they insist this marro
can change syntax no not really it's
still n it par you stuck with
it
okay so so okay so we uh so we got this
paper let's save
it conell University okay let's make a
let's make a um I want to make a
screenshot
and uh then read it later okay I will be
reading it let's download okay view
PDF okay let's see how many pages is is
this academic paper which I read like
eating
bread you know and uh I find the
academics very annoying
usually okay this paper is pretty short
okay they are BAS basically you know
it's um focus on the scheme disp
language also known as racket well I
mean one version of it
so so it's writing a racket extension
now is this match part of Racket already
I suppose this is
2010 the uh extending pattern matching
the following racket program finds the
magnitude of a complex number okay
represented in either cartisian or Polar
form as a three element list using the
first elements as a type type tag
okay so let's save this so I'm going to
read it
later okay
close uh but uh wait reopen back copy
the
URL uh back to talk show
let's paste the URL
here ah I changed my key so now it's all
new
copy let me show you this
fantastic command Okay so submit it I
don't care let's put the date date here
buy this guy title URL
title author
press a key it becomes citation
biography academic citation make a list
the is this part showing Bowser
fantastic beautiful extensible pattern
iming okay let's focus let's get back to
so okay there's that paper then
what um then what else okay so it's
somewhat based on this paper Okay so now
notice there is no documentation what
the
you know impl
implementation is your problem how to
use this library is my
problem documentation of how to use this
library is your problem but you didn't
do
it that's what annoys me so let's
check control h
I to go to the info documentation index
let's see search for p case list
matching lines
none okay
so okay so let's search
for let's call
um emac L index search okay let's call
that P case search there it is the P
case Mark okay so it is in emac list
manual so this is what you need to read
okay now press a key to show this page
in browser this is
fantasticar extension Kar view emac
manual in
browser okay so now you
see makes a giant difference a lot emac
Fanatics they just like to read this
text plain text version but but the
browser is much more beautiful and
easier to read because you got all this
formatting and bold and you know
coloring okay so so you got a marro PK
case expression this is what I need to
do okay so any comments none
so PK's
expression PK's expression rest classes
so PK each cross in crosses has the form
pattern body form okay so evaluate
expression to determine its
value
um eval expand eval find the first cross
in
crosses okay whose pattern matches
expand evolve and pass control to that
Clause okay so P case is like a
conditional Case Case
statement okay if there is the match the
value of P case is the value of the last
body of body
forms in the successful Clause that's
right otherwise P case evaluates to Neil
okay I understand do do you understand
that yes already so close that uh go
back to talk show close this and uh
showing browser and let's start to um
this this is a
marro okay I mean this is a manual there
it is link to the Manu and let's start
to I know how to use it already Okay so
I need you see right now I'm using SAR
emx mod so everything I do is like SAR
mod
okay okay HTML mod but here is
so emac this mod go to the source code
go to the directory delete the backup
delete yes so you see this all my
basically all the packages I use today
uh is all just my packages because I've
been coding emac lisp for 15 years 20
years
almost
so so this isar emac this mod so first
thing to do is I want I want a template
I want you know for example d space
become different space become the full
template I want a template for p case
right now this got nothing so let's do
it let's create it so let so template
you you go here so so search for first
of all search for p
case there it is okay PKS so PKS in PK
def Mar okay PK is there that's part of
the keyword but we don't have Mar so
let's add a mar
okay uh okay so go down go where is it
here okay so PS s o PQ so let's see
p
uh push and quote okay so let's do a p
case P case
abbreviation uh
wait wait
what now what is the documentation for
PK that okay so actually so we just um
P
case expression then rest cases
okay now rest is
um split the window search for comma
rest is done as a comma so okay let's
just add a comma
instead so PKS so now let's alphabetize
it so
okay there search for p case Okay o n p
right
there evaluate the buffer you can see
run current file or Evol buffer go to
directory buy compile it is there an
error no okay open it delete it close
now back here now close it and uh reopen
it okay now P case
enter
fantastic okay expression let's say
three now cases okay so we need to
modify because PKS you always
need it's always going to need cases so
let's you know even though it's optional
but you you're going to always need
cases
pattern and uh so classes so what how
does it
work uh classes
pattern each class is pattern in body
forms so in
[Music]
fact so for example let's say four then
four okay okay three then three let's
see if that works evaluated seems to
work you see it returns three because
three matches three here then run this
okay so we can do we can actually make
this
um uh not messages okay got
three and and
here got
four
okay
evaluated got three perfect so this is
how you use P case
now now let's make let's fix the
template okay let's so this case is
going to be it's always gonna be
um okay let's fix the template so I'm
doing
multitasking I'm doing
um you know learning about PKS meanwhile
creating a template for it in emac this
mod okay so that's that okay so this x
is um
not
date crer okay
so and uh new line any new line encoded
by slash n do it do it do it okay and uh
then we got this uh space space okay
leave
it okay
so this is our new P
case template evalate go back here close
it save it close reopen so that the emac
this mod is reloaded saw emx mod so now
let's try again PK space
beautiful okay so we got
that okay so now I know how to use PKS
case
you you know you got several Arguments
for different patterns
now now but we haven't got two patterns
because right now it's literal you know
it's like matching literal
expression um there's no pattern
involved so then it's just like
conditional you know nothing special so
but so we need to figure so we need to
to learn about what is this pattern for
example we got some X and we want you
know some of them is like a
string uh let's say uh T
then then you return string so for
example right so you want to um you know
if this x is a string you want to be
able to match a string so how do you do
that not just you know not just match T
exactly but you want
to uh match if that's a string so each
pattern has to be a p case pattern okay
which can
either which can use either one of the
core patterns defined below or one of
the patterns defined via PK Define Mark
okay so you can you can extend your
patterns
syntax that by using PK def Mark I see
so that's what it is so there's a
documentation extending P case okay go
back go back okay so let's check of the
patterns the rest of this section
describe different forms of core
patterns presents some examples and
concludes with important caveats
warnings I'm using the lead binding
facility provided by some pattern
forms okay so PKS can be used in lead
binding okay a Coe pattern can have the
following forms
okay am I doing
good it's like one person watching is
that right four four people
okay okay continue with the p case Okay
so let's remove that
yeah so P
case so pattern okay so now I need to
write a tutorial for
this okay this page is
um example advantage over over CL case
common this here's an example that
highlights some advantages of P case has
overse our
case common
this okay so this documentation is you
know it's a few pages okay so let's make
it larger a bit so I am going to read
this
offline because I'm meticulous reader
technical documentation geeking that's
what I do been doing that for all my
life uh I've read more documentation
than all of you
combined including the thisis
phonetics okay so let's see
so uh so you got some patterns so let's
look at the pattern underscore matches
any expression okay
okay underscore is like don't care while
out card this is like the
last you know condition like nothing
matches then just use
this uh quote vow mat uh equals to
Val comparison is done by EV equality
okay
so quote W does that usually mean s both
usually
matches equals
v wait but if it's a number you don't
need to quote it so what what so you
know there's a question here because
usually when you quote you quote
symbols so does this mean this quote
this vow can also be a
list you know we can actually we can
test it so for example let's Okay so cut
let's
see uh let's say it's
a you know
let so this this expression can be a
Leist okay three four then let's say one
of the condition is
quote
34 then message
got list
okay uh say
message got
four okay so let's eval this let's see
there it is I was correct so you can
like you know you can you can you can uh
yeah so but I still don't fully
understand okay anyway let's move on so
there is
underscore so if if underscore means
nothing matches
okay
uh okay so
underscore H interesting so you see this
is the this underscore is beginning to
be a real pattern because that's not a
valid
lisp
syntax because underscore is
undefined so now um
okay let's see what
uh okay got this okay so but now if we
try let's say
nine there it
is because nothing matches now let's see
now let's see if the order matters okay
so copy and let's say
um let's say four but you put the
underscore at the
top okay will it just match this one
like do they go by order I suppose okay
so let's try
it there it is okay so yeah so this
shows
okay pattern match in
order okay so
next so we got keyword integer
string uh what does it mean keyword
integer string match if EV equals to the
literal object
okay special case of W
okay self quoting okay now what does
this what is this
keyword control
h uh well we need going to search
um what
P
case okay so what is
that okay so keyword integer
string they
basically this is a bad formatting from
G emac this
manual well okay because it's
semantically logically
kind of inconsistent
anyway um
so keyword integer string so all these
are literal
values okay so keyword does that mean
it's a
symbol I don't know okay so let's see
symbol match any value and additionally
let bind symbol
to expand evolve
such that this binding is available to
body forms
okay if symbol is part of sequence
sequence pattern God this okay so this
this all these patterns they can get
complex so you got a mini pattern ma
language here oh then you can you have
and patterns where a pattern must match
all these patterns a expression must
match all these patterns then you have
all patterns which means a expression
match any of these pattern and you are
you have
RX okay so matx string again is the
rejects RX expression using RX notation
okay so this is this pattern is
for
matching this pattern is basically
regular expression for matching
string however using the lisp regular
expression syntax in the RX package okay
called structured rejects notation okay
but anyhow it's still just matching
strings okay so you got end or you got
let
uh so this lead is a
pattern evaluate expression to get uh an
Matrix got evaluate expression to get
that and matx if expression
V matches pattern
okay what does this mean evaluate
expression it is called let because
pattern combine symbols okay I don't
understand now this card is basically a
condition God matches if buing
expression Eva evaluates to
true
so so this
pattern basically
here is a
function so basically this allows you to
use a function that returns true and
false to
determine whether the it match or not so
instead of using a pattern you use a
function that's what it is okay so this
app function pattern matches a function
code on the expression Returns the value
okay okay so yeah
so okay so this gets a bit complex to
um actually test out each one yeah it
can get complex so so what we do now
am I doing good night people watching
Rudolph and uh Rudolph and
nbj okay
so so what we do today I mean what do
what do I do to make it useful for you
guys because this P case you'll
need few
hours and I'm going to write a
um tutorial for it in fact I can start
to write a tutorial yeah so you see we
have we got some examples of P case
patter iming I will be writing a
tutorial of a complete
tutorial and uh with lots of examples
uh
but the question is what do I do now so
let's let's let's have a overall look at
this page okay so here it covers
different patterns now what is qad a
back quod style pattern
okay okay so you got back quod style
pattern you know so it's it is a bit
complicated okay so you got patterns
patterns so symbol backward style
pattern CL type okay Matrix if eval
expression is expression eval is of type
type okay which is a type descriptor is
accepted by CL type P type predic in
common disp
extensions uh common
disp uh okay so it's got you know type
CR
prut yeah I I really don't like the
common this
thing
uh and predicate function Matrix
predicate function return new okay so
you got these
patterns okay a function code with n
arguments okay so all these are patterns
patterns patterns patterns okay it will
take few days actually to write a full
tutorial now example
advantage over CR case
Okay uh example using end okay so
combining patterns example reformulation
with PK case what does that mean here is
an example that shows how to be
formulate a simple matching task from
its traditional
implementation to one using ke case okay
now what is a
gr uh the dark string oh so there is uh
oh okay so G is something it defines
here so if object is string okay
so yeah so
basically this example is saying
that you know if you are not using p
case and if you want to do string match
then this is what you write so he's
showing you
how if you are using p case then you can
make
it um
something you can make it simpler I
suppose you see fairly
complicated okay yeah so this is going
to be fairly
complicated side affecting code
referencing symbol is
undefined avoid for example here are two
similar functions both use end symbol
and God okay okay so what is this
section this section is cavat so warning
okay it's on and on okay so that's a
that's a overview of this page now let's
go so what is this
um the PK marro let's go
up chapter section 11.4 pattern matching
conditional okay so aside from our basic
conditional forms EAC L also has a
pattern matching conditional form PK
smro a hybrid of conditional and cl case
see conditionals in common this
extensions you
know okay so it goes to you know Common
this has its own
documentation outside of emac this
manual okay I don't want it okay go
back go back okay so you got PKS in CL
case that overcomes their
um that over comes their limitations and
introduces the pattern matching
programming style okay the limitations
that PKS overcomes
are okay something something something
something conceptually the PK marle
borrows the first Arc focus of Cl case
and the Clause processing flow of
condition
okay replacing condition with a
generalization of the equality test
that's right which is a variant of
pattern
matching okay yeah because equality test
is basically a pattern matching of
testing literal Expressions okay that is
pattern matching with no patterns at all
then that is equality test typical you
know equal or
something and adding facilities so that
you can concisely express a cross prut
okay and arrange to share Le bindings
between uh okay the con the concise
expression of a predicate is known as a
pattern when the predicate C on the
value of the first Arc returns n NE we
say that the pattern match
matches the value okay so when it you
know when it matches we say it
matches okay so the P case mod we looked
at extending P case which is extending
the pattern syntax we don't
care uh back back quot style patterns
that's more complicated you know this is
very fairly complicated part
of emac disp and common dis
uh then destructuring with PK patterns
okay okay so now I'm I have a overview
we have had an overview of
this
PKS documentation okay now the last part
is in in interesting destructuring with
PKS so it adds the
function you know it add PK
slet PK slet and PK SL star PK St list
PK set Q PK Lambda
okay okay so I have a good overview now
I know what this Library
do and
um you know my my my
my initial feeling is that right now is
don't use it I'm not going to use it
never going to use it
why
because this is pattern matching okay
pattern maging is very fairly
Advanced uh feature in functional
programming
languages
okay so for functional programming
typically they are built in such as meta
language wolam
language hascal or camo
FP those are derivatives of ml meta
language they are
building that that is they are not a
extra Library they are designed as part
of the programming language okay part of
the programming language in fact they
are the core part of the programming
language so when you are talking about F
or Cam hascal ml the patter matching is
part of the core foundation of the
programming language okay they are not
something like let's write the library
and add it okay so for that's important
that's critical because this pattern
matching is
fairly you know if you're going to
implement it it's it's not trivial okay
and there's a lot cases you know
theoretical
issues just like regular expression okay
so like regular expression is for stream
matching for majority of languages is
build in like core
Library well I mean anyway so so so when
you want when you add a pattern matching
like in the emac this case as
a language extension you know as a
library like like right now we have you
know this P case
Library 1,000 lines of
code that makes
it you know I you know that makes it
slow and I mean relatively slow and
makes it kind of
FAL and a bit
complicated um
so my right now my feeling is that I'm
not going to use
it because you are you are essentially
learning you know if you want to use
this P case you are learning a like a
mini language for the
patterns that's not native to emac
disp no common
disp okay so and I'm presuming the
implementation is you know fairly
involved uh I mean even just learning
how to use it is fairly involved you
know you got
this so the implementation would be
fairly involved let's
see okay let's see what def they
have okay so you got this dash dash
means it's intern function if the
function name contain dash dash it's
like internal okay so you got this oh so
it's like almost all of them are
internal functions
def okay so you can see they are relying
on these internal functions to work now
let's
see Define maral
okay so these are the
exported functions these markers P case
PKS exhaustive PKS Lambda PK
lead yeah okay so you know I guess we
know I know you know we know what this
this package is for
um
yeah do we want to use it uh I don't
know
you know you know I don't know I'm not
sure and I'm not even sure I want to
write a tutorial for this because to
write a tutorial for this will take
several days three or a week full
time and for that time I rather be
writing a tutorial for f shop language
or link okay so I think that's it for
today
hello Big Fan Joy where is the Tequila
No tequila today today is
coffee okay I think I'm done
today we learned what does PKS do
and uh what is the use
well I mean there's some use for example
I can you know pattern match and find
out which is a
string but in general in emac
disp the use is not very
common
um
yeah so and uh the code is fairly
complicated
um okay bye
guys if you like my stuff pay me okay go
to go to go to go to go to. info all the
way down pay me 100 bucks Amazon PayPal
by okay let's let's put it
back
uh showing browser that's what we did
okay bye guys