hello everyone
so yesterday someone asked me well I
mentioned that Python Ruby is a better
language than Python and someone you
know asked for comments and someone said
that might be an interesting topic to
talk about so today let's talk about
programming languages you know which
language to choose what you know what
the language to learn so okay let's talk
about that well first of all if you're
gonna ask that question unless you are a
beginner like you've never programmed
before then that's a good question
basically okay but for those people you
are not not probably not watching my
chant channel for for those of you
wondering about you know which language
to learn which which is the better
language and that probably means if you
are asking that and you find this
today's topic interesting that probably
means you are not a very practical
person because well so which language to
learn so let's talk about which language
to learn okay so there are many aspect
you know which is the best language
programming language and which language
to learn and maybe which language is
most popular okay you know when we ask
questions like that we have to be very
specific in order to have answers
because otherwise that's like asking you
know which is the best car you know
which is the best airplane you know
there's so the depends on what you mean
if you want you know if you ask which is
the fastest airplane then there is one
answer and probably you know 102 you
know answer if you ask which is the
fastest fastest airplane but
you know not not very expensive you know
within reasonable price then there's a
different answer so it really depends on
lots of you know the specifics and then
there's also the question of which is
the best general purpose language so
anyway so first of all you know which
language to learn really depends on what
do you want to do you know if you plan
to be a programmer like a professional
programmer meaning that you want to find
a job you know it's going to be your
bread earning skill then of course then
then your choices of languages you you
filter out parts of languages for
example the most popular what are the
most popular languages you know there's
not parole today okay so so right now
it's 12:45 a.m. so let's talk about that
for 15 minutes let's talk about so this
this is my programming blog and I have
lots of tutorials on programming
languages oh you know programming
languages is one of my most favorite
topic topic you know I can go on you
know and I yeah I have like literally
hundreds of articles on programming
languages so each one of these is a
tutorial then you have syntax soup where
I talk about their many aspects of
programming language syntax then is a
semantic noodle and that's about you
know various issues related to the
meaning of foreign languages so yeah on
a second let's put this in perspective
so let's talk about okay which language
to learn which to learned you know okay
the general topics okay which language
yeah so you know if so if you want so
okay which are the most popular which
are the most popular okay to answer that
you actually just go to the you just
actually just go to a web site that's
such popular programming languages there
are a few websites that's okay you see
these these ones are general generally
carbage websites these you know because
everyone tries to make a page that
because you know which language is the
most popular that's a sensitive well not
sensitive but controversial kind of you
know dramatic subject so everyone you
know want to know which one is the most
popular because the more popular meaning
more survivability more jobs and you
know it's like a language war but anyway
so the language popularity ranking so
let's instead of such that let's say
programming languages banking
okay there there are a few websites that
focus on this question that that's
really really good
this is reasonably good Redmont that's
reasonably good you know I checked this
you know I checked this website about
every year since since like 20 years ago
you know so but today the landscape has
changed because today there are so many
languages you know so many it's you know
it's fascinating so anyway so yeah for
example it's you know this this this is
a reasonable website you know all these
website try to rank a popularity of
programming languages but there are so
many ways to measure it you know there's
usually there's no again it depends on
what are you measuring exactly you want
to know which one is the most popular on
github which one is the most popular on
Stack Overflow or which which one is
most have the most demand in job listing
or which one is actually the most used
by company and by that you know there's
also different measures like you know do
you can't Google as one company or do
you count the number of programmers you
know cuz you know compare the number of
programmers of each language so there's
so there's many different ways but in
general you know we can say roughly the
top ten most popular and languages are
this is probably a good summary of
Python C + C C sharp PHP ha Java Script
go assembly
I'm not sure about assembly but okay
this is spectrum you know website they
try to make this every year say like you
know the top the 2018 top for any
languages because people tends to want
to know the answer but basically there
is no correct ranking you know even if
you go for popularity because first of
all it's hard to measure and also
because you know there's if the
specifics you know how do you define
popular exactly so this one TI o P this
one has been around for like ten years
so they they update every month or so so
according to their list Chavez a Python
C++ Visual Basic JavaScript so anyway so
let's stop here so okay so how is is not
very used today so basically everything
and I would say okay everything on the
Objective C you can ignore well yeah I
mean as far as you you know wait wait
so go is here swift and Ruby those you
cannot pick no those are those are very
popular and visual basic so this ranking
is again you know it's questionable
MATLAB for example MATLAB Madhavi is a
math language used mostly in academia
and you know and and by scientists in in
you know scientific program is is
extremely is very different from
industrial programming in you know
industrial programming for example you
can count web programming as industrial
web programming is actually one of the
biggest field then there's game
programming there's networking this yeah
network programming there's
for example robotics then there's also
research AI programming is so this I
mean even in games there's lots of
different programming and but web is the
most popular and also depends on you
know web there's also a phone smartphone
programming so basically that's part
well it's it's part of the way of kind
of because programming for the phone you
use Swift or Objective C or Java oh oh
yeah and there's also server programming
so there's very different and also
there's hardware you know firmware
programming like it's used everywhere in
your TV in microwave in your car so very
different for me well my personal
experience is mostly in a web
programming or system in UNIX systems
since I started programming around 1992
in Mathematica so the first 10 years you
know it's basically scientific
programming math math oriented so anyway
mad MATLAB is a basically for to in math
visualization of math so and programming
there is very different from most the
others so Java C so okay so anyway so
we're talking about language popularity
so if you want a job you can you know
you can go through these sites you know
look for the top 10 most programming
most popular ones a walk but for example
this one is what this one is from
then Frederick's and I'm not sure which
one is this one so anyway so for example
in this one Cheryl programming no that's
not you know that's not something get
your job not really well I mean you can
of course I mean you can you can choose
any programming language and if you are
very good at it and you have a job you
know but we're talking about a
CoffeeScript that's kind of you know so
can pose dead goobies still used Haskell
if you land has go you never find a job
well actually you can't find a job but
you know I mean you have to put the
whole picture in you know you have to
look at the whole picture for every one
haskell job they are like 1,000 jobs for
JavaScript or Python or Java or C++ in
any way of it so yeah so it's like that
so anyway so if you want to find a
programming language that's most popular
for a job then you pretty much want to
look at the top ten you know pick any of
any one of these ranking site top ten
popularity and then study them you know
but but of course that's that's not a
good way because because learning is
something like especially programming
you have to be very interested in it
otherwise you wouldn't be good but you
know just like every we say you know
mostly it's true you know if you want to
be a good it's a job you must have
interesting it you know you find it
interesting and you find you know the
because you are but you you love it you
know there's deep motivation within you
you know not not because you know
other things so so yeah so so so what
I'm saying is okay so the top ten
popular languages you can you know it so
in general it doesn't really make sense
to ask ask the question you know which
one which language is the most pop most
popular for a job that doesn't really
make sense you know I wouldn't say but
rather which one but on I mean on the
other hand you you cannot you cannot say
you know just you know it doesn't matter
what language just pick one you really
love and focus on that and you'll find a
job that's not true either
you know because there's this effort in
you know relate related paper for
example this for example Haskell is one
of the code kind of you know less
popular language Common Lisp is one of
the less popular language Common Lisp
has cow Oh camel and scheme and
Mathematica for example Mathematica is
actually my favorite it's the most
powerful language of them all by by far
bilobed by like ten times you cut me and
you know however it's slow it's much
slower but in terms of power it's it's
it's it's more powerful than any and
then then all languages I can convert
competently say I program Mathematica
you know through our 1990s for ten years
like intent intensively Mathematica is
like is basically it's I would I would
put it in Lisp family but the Steve
Stephan Wolfram he probably don't want
to associate with Lisp because you know
he he would probably say no it's not
this you know my language is
yeah please get the hell out of it all
of you on the other hand you know these
people you know Mathematica is a
proprietary language and so usually
open-source people they don't you know
it's you know it's it's not in their
view you know they like they live in
this well of open-source things wherever
there is something not open-source they
don't want even to look at it so in
general these programmers are pretty
ignorant of Mathematica so they don't
you know out of every 10,000 these
programmers maybe one maybe one of them
have ever tried to use Mathematica and
maybe one other 10,000 have actually
known something technical about
mathematical language but anyway so we
let's get back to the topic and so I was
saying you know you can't just pick a
language and say you know you love it
then just do it and your friend job you
know not every one of us is you know
very you know have that's so much
interest and dive into it and sacrifice
everything because you have other things
to do so so I mean for example let's say
if you pick a language Ruby for example
or Python you can easily you know
trivially find a job let's say you spend
one year study Python or Ruby or
JavaScript then you know you study it
for one year and after that you can
easily find a job but if you study one
year in Haskell suppose you know let's
let's even say you put twice as much
time in Haskell let's say you so you
studied Haskell for two years and you
know know it very well it's you know
it's still hard to find you know we
compared to the to the Python okay
it's hard to find a job so that so
that's the that's about that question
you know and also this question of which
language is most general and so yeah so
it's a there's a lot of question to talk
you know to talk about languages you
know what makes a language popular
what's the best syntax for language what
what are the characteristics of
different languages so for example
usually there's a concept of
general-purpose language you know you
suppose this one language that's general
purpose you know general purpose yeah
it's true in some sense there's for
example for example Python PHP well
Python Ruby let's say Python Ruby
c-sharp Java you could say they are
general-purpose
you know as opposed to Haskell really
MATLAB again that's for mathematic
mostly for scientific computing so it's
not regional purpose
Visual Basic not really it's I don't
think so for example Mathematica is not
really
yeah it's not really general-purpose I
mean again it depends on what do you
mean by general-purpose
of course almost every programs can can
be solved by most of these languages but
I mean you can even use bash or Perl you
know to to to program anything you know
after all they are programming
programming languages
so anyway so I've been rambling a lot so
now it's so I was going to talk about
Python versus Ruby well I've been
program programming Python for in and
out on and off for 10 years I don't
really like Python language and but for
Ruby I actually never have actual
experience except I only studied it for
like half a year well not even that
three let's say three months so I
studied Ruby for three months and to me
I find rubies a much better language in
Python so for example you know one way
to yeah you know well basically you can
you know you of course you can Church
for yourself
you know there's basically programming
languages you know
many of them are in the same category of
power let's say the same you know they
are like in the same class you know same
type of field they are useful they are
designed for and the same same level of
power and you know or density or you
know how powerful is the syntax or
semantics so Python Ruby Perl PHP they
are pretty much in the same class and so
yeah but you know on the other hand for
example C C++ C sharp Java yeah maybe
Java and colon is kind of like colon
colon is my favorite favorite
general-purpose language now so so yeah
so those C C C++ C sharp : they are kind
of in the same you know category you
know for comparison you know and stuff
so but between Python Ruby PHP I think
Ruby is a better language for example
you can okay so so if you don't know
these two languages what you can do is
you know just start to read the read my
tutorial so you read there's a basics
you know not too long is just 10 pages
20 20 pages you can spend 30 minutes
each then you can you can you know then
you get a sense what the language is
like and you know do the same for Python
then you can have opinion Python is okay
the history of Python is that you know
python is popular because google made it
so basically in in around 2000 year 2000
google choose python because back then
the other choice is pearl and pearl is
known for lots of crazy syntax
unreadable syntax you know for your food
for example well anyway yeah so so
Google you know the guide they they
picked Python and back then Python is
not very popular and and because Google
is using it then you became very popular
because everyone follows you know what
big big company wants to do I mean he's
doing so Python becomes extremely well
it became popular because of Google that
that's the starting to rise in
popularity and Ruby start to rise in
popularity because Ruby on Rails around
year 2007 Ruby on Rails so it's
basically popular for the for the web
because Ruby on Rails is his is a web
framework and so that made it back back
then it was the extremely extremely
popular all the other languages tries to
try to make a similar library and you
know copying Ruby by web framework so
okay so that's the story of that but
since around 2000 since around the same
time no no since around a few years ago
let's say let's say 2012 you know the
machine learning starts to become
popular you know machine learning became
a thing you know everyone wants to know
big companies is talking or talking
about machine learning especially Google
so and what happens and and and again
Google picked Python you know it's there
as as the interface as the language for
machine learning of course the the heart
of the machine learning engine usually
is not written in Python but the
interface you know to the machine
learning library or engine is written in
Python so Google kind of again made
Python popular so Python today is all
popular in math or machine learning AI
visualization there's a Jupiter notebook
you know it's a copy of Mathematica
notebook interface so anyway so so from
what I see you know that's my impression
that's how that's my view of history
Python became popular for two reasons
one what both been here are due to
Google one is the Google choose Python
that's the beginning of Python
popularity around 2001 or so and and two
because we go
choose Python was the machine learning
language you know kind of was the
interface to machine learning because
python is using Google so what about
Ruby well Ruby is still more popular
than Python for web for websites you
know if you look back in 2004 I looked
at a lot started
market like job offerings you know you
know job market you know if you go
through job market you know look you
look what startup is looking for there's
huge amount of blue be much more than
Python you know you look at all these
stops startup websites like I so you
look through job listings they are all
you know all the startups you look at
their website they are actually they all
look similar anyway so they are all
using most a lot of them using Ruby and
Ruby on Rails so anyway I've been
remembering too long so focus so yeah so
I mean if you want to compare you know
Ruby and Python you know all you have to
do is just you you you kind of really
have to learn it yourself to make a
decision which you like better but as
far as Ruby and Python course both are
very popular you can find a job easily
for sure
okay what things okay yeah so no I don't
I don't like Python
the problem with Python okay anyway I've
been traveling too much
so by example you can so I'll talk to
you again next time
yeah I I have a collection of articles
about why Python suck read it okay
anyway so thank you for watching if you
have comments comment questions question
if you like it like like my videos talk
to you later bye