hello guys hello guys good morning good
evening welcome to another episode of
talk
showan talk show we are going to code
JavaScript today
leisurely hello Unholy and
hello Park Rob Park Rob dust
P proc dust
okay JavaScript we are going to go
JavaScript add a button so that you can
click to Copy Source Code uh here's my
keyboard glub at Fantastic ultimate
hacking keyboard
fantastic nulia track boo fantastic
logic Tech Mouse with spin wheel
fantastic okay and and let me tell you
guys I promote this thing SVA l b o a r
d SW board this is the most fancy device
about $800 or something I will be
showing
it you can search for it I have done
reviews before okay let's begin our talk
show today love your content thank
you uh JavaScript coding okay if you got
a questions for me ask okay I'm just
going to go leisurely because when I do
you know I'm not you know whatever
anyway so JavaScript what we doing today
JavaScript of course so first of all
let's search for
FSH not dictionary close Okay search for
it FSH software Foundation actually I
don't care about fop software Foundation
I just want a document you know usually
you don't want any of these
beneficent or organizations like
nonprofit you know those are very very
corrupt today since about
2010 you know all these organizations
like G
Foundation extremely
corrupt uh Interlink with USA government
deep State okay including Firefox you
know the Firefox Mozilla Foundation or
this so whenever you hear a name you
know that's for peace Foundation or
Center some Center for democracy you
know that's very very
corrupt okay so what uh what we doing so
you see so simple mod use get started
okay let's click on get started and uh
fop one of the best functional
programming language one of the best
language industrial language I recommend
okay download create your app okay so
you can see they have this copy button
so you just press that oh you need to
turn on JavaScript turn on JavaScript
script to let Google know what you're
doing what pages you are looking so now
you click on
copy and uh you can paste it fantastic
that's a feature I need okay so that is
what we going to code today so show show
my code let's say go to emac lisp okay
so emac Lis tutorial go to emac lisp
search forar emac lisp tutorial and
andar packages and Kar emac
command and uh let's see new previous
empty buffer you see this code I have
10,000 codes on my website so but if you
need to copy it you need to go here and
here and you know then press contrl C
then back to your editor then copy paste
okay so that's
tedious so I want to add this copy
feature so that's JavaScript and doome
stand for document object model which is
EDC you know 30 years
ago okay
so you know this copy feature it wasn't
available until about 10 years ago you
know about 10 years ago about 15 years
ago about
2010 the people the web TB led by Google
especially because Google is making
making money via the web not via
operating system such as Microsoft or
apple Google makes money via the web so
they want they really pushed for a lot
Technologies to the web so for example
you can watch YouTube you know videos
and and a lots of things so since about
15 years so actually Google has been
pushing the web technology but you know
you know since like 2 five but anyway
starting about 2010 it's really getting
more serious so anyway so that's when
the HTML 5
organization called uh what the [ __ ]
group they create they kind of created
this copy okay so this feature was not
available before because it was
considered security risk because you
never want the the web to be able to
erase your
clipboard something like that okay so
anyway I want this feature so how do I
do it so you know there are many ways
you can search the web which we will do
but another way is just look at the
source code let's see what are they
doing okay so uh yeah so let me write
that out so what is this emx blog so and
also let me mention jav
JavaScript uh JavaScript in depth okay
so you go to cali. info then you go
to scroll down there it is Javascript in
depth this is the most easy to
understand and most correct technically
correct accurate and most
comprehensive JavaScript tutorial you do
not any need any Frameworks you can do
this Al all this with just just
JavaScript okay so it took me three
years to write so you have you know the
tutorial and you also have the reference
section for example all the methods of
array and if you like my stuff you can
buy basically you support me you give me
money you support me and I send you the
zip file the zip file allows you to
quickly uh use it as a reference or if
you use it on the train but it's a zip
file of HTML files so that means it
requires you to have a laptop okay but
it won't work on your phone because the
phone uh because of the nasty reasons
phone they don't you know it's they
don't they don't let you you know
manipulate HTML or read you know HTML
Pages local
HTML that's another story but you know
they just developed that way so so that
you know phone you cannot you cannot
control nothing so anyway if you like my
stuff you can buy it and you can get it
this um you know in a zip file
JavaScript in depth okay which is what
we're going to do so what is uh so let's
close yeah so we want uh this is emac
close and this is a talk show yeah so
there's there's add a copy paste button
to source code okay let's begin to code
that yeah so first of all we look at the
web you know the source code here let's
see what what does the Microsoft website
do okay you need to magnify this
um this page this this panel so you guys
can
see the full Glory of
it okay
anyway uh so yeah actually you guys
cannot see much of it but
let's so I want
um so I want to look at that inspect so
that's this
line let's make some
room okay that's this
button okay so let's have a drink red
wine let's I mean let me tell you what
what is the overview what does the code
involves okay let me give you the
overview for example we are going to add
a panel here for
example uh not here okay add JavaScript
code JavaScript so we add a pre- tag on
the pink window you can see all my
command CES and the keystrokes
keystrokes on left using a the VAC
layout and command name on the right as
I you know type for example I press one
key that will delete that HTML element
paste you see and press another key that
we select that element press again
select the element above it the entire
element so you can see that command is
calleda HTML select element tab M okay
and I'm usinga flag keys if you don't
know already that Sly Keys search it you
can you can find the website and it's a
the most efficient key binding system
for emac more efficient than Vim or Neo
Vim or EVO mod so it's a keybinding
system so you never have to press
control like I never you can look at my
key strokes on on in the pink window
there's no control key in uh
no meta basically so it's a model mod
okay so something like is close close uh
yeah so now we add a JavaScript so let's
open let's pop this out let's say
console log three run
it print three correct this isar
JavaScript mod okay now let's put it
back put it
back press a key to syntax cor showing
browser there it is Javascript code so
you see this thing is a pre-blog with
the class javascri JavaScript name okay
so what does it involve to add this you
know like this this copy
button well basically so first of all
you need to use a JavaScript to add a
add this copy widget or button so the
Javas when the when the website you know
when the web page loads it will it will
run the JavaScript and JavaScript will
add a copy button okay basically a
button it can look you know like
anything but anyway it's functionally a
button so it adds a copy button then the
JavaScript will also so make that button
do something so that when you click on
that button it will um
copy the you know whatever the code
inside inside this
pre block I mean the pre- element okay
so technically what is doing is that
when you click it you in order in order
to make this work what you need to do is
that you need to add a event handler to
that button so when user click on it
it's a it's called event you know so the
event fires know the event happen then
you have a event handler attached to
that button to this click event so the
event handler will call a function and
the function
will you know grab the text and and put
it on clipboard clipboard you know so
people can paste it so that's all uh
that's overall what you have to do okay
uh and if you don't know if you're
watching this offline you can go to
JavaScript tutorial JavaScript in depth
ons.info
JavaScript reference Doom so this Doom
scripting tutorial will introduce you
this whole thing uh for example you can
how to get element how to change CSS
says let's
say uh let's say you know so we have
Color Me Red it becomes red color me
blue that's a button and here's a HTML
code and here's a JavaScript code so you
know this are this this is how you do it
and you have how how to insert a HTML
element click me hello click me hello
click click click it just add hello very
simple the basic fundamental ideas is in
this Doom scripting
tutorial okay so that is the um overview
of what this thing involves so this is
for I mean for total beginners if you
are web dev you prob you already know of
course so steps let me
see let's just write it out okay uh
use JavaScript to add
a copy button okay that's one thing then
use um use JavaScript to add a event
handler to the copy
button okay
then the event handler will attach a
function the function
will will
copy the text
inside the
preag to
systems to operating
systems opting
systems
clipboard okay
steps
overview showing browser
fantastic okay now I don't know how to
do it so we have to look at what what
they doing so let's see question let's
see
question I'm new to coding first video
actually since I
am let's see what is this saying
since I'm trying to learn I'm a little
confused on what I can do with coding
could you tell me Well coding coding
opens a a a new world whole world to
you but whether it's for you you have to
find out yourself so once you know
coding coding is very extremely
important and it is the
future because because of as you know
everything is computers today your cell
phone the web page you buying something
on Amazon or anything Bank transactions
all is computer without computers
Humanity will collapse
instantaneously okay so computers well
how can computer do things code okay so
you got people working at Google
Facebook Microsoft Amazon you got Google
working for the internet in
infrastructure n network engineer
security engineer you know also game
gaming you guys you know young people
play games how does it work coding okay
so
coding is if you are a programmer you
know coder it's a you you got a bright
future because it's essential you know
unlike any other you know any other you
know for example if you study history if
you study
Arts you know if you study sociology if
you study Linguistics you are jobless
essentially effectively okay so
code you know what what is the use of
coding well it effectively guarantee a
livelihood for your
life now but whether you like it that's
a different thing okay it's like being a
doctor okay the alternative is being a
doctor
a doctor is a permanent
permanently hired okay maybe a dentist
maybe a doctor you know eye doctor your
head doctor your heart doctor whatever
everyone needs to see a doctor so you
can become doctor then every day you
just deal with you know with
people Doctor coding is the most
extremely practical and makes you a lot
money okay now let me and also by the
way another thing is lawyers lawyers
Jesus they make a lot money and and also
businessmen but the difference is that
for businessman it's not a technical
profession okay among all these
professions businessmen people they make
the most money 10 times 100 times than
you lawyers then you coders than your
doctors because
businessman the essence of businessman
is to make money Merchant okay so but of
course whether you can succeed or not
that's a different question a lot in
fact most will fail okay but however
businessman's got the most potential
than all you you know technical
professions so businessman is different
from you know this professional Fields
programmer lawyer
doctor okay so businessman uh you can be
a business businessman any well I mean
you know you can try so I'm not because
I'm not you know I'm not you know I'm
not that type okay so it doesn't shoot
me I don't I don't do good there so
anyway so you have you know so among so
you know we talking about programming
field and uh doctors and uh lawyers now
lawyers are different from the other two
be because lawyers is not a technical
profession while being a doctor medical
doctor or being a programmer is a very
technical profession because everything
has got the answer how do you call this
there's a very precise answer how do you
fix someone's
brain how do you help someone with heart
attack very technical answer to that but
not lawyers so lawyer is this kind of
different from these two okay now
lawyers is kind of
questionable because why does lawyer
lawyer make a lot money depending
on I mean it depends on the person of
course ultimately it always depends on
the person but lawyers in general they
can make a lot more because why because
lawyers they basically play with power
okay power in society especially USA USA
become so corrupt in the past 10 years
the number of lawyers increased like 10
times you know like a sharp
increase uh more than programmers I
think you have to look up I forgot you
know so lawyers you know lawyers is such
that you can make a criminal who killed
someone you can make him free just by
talking you know so they have to pay you
100 million you know millions of dollars
to do that that's what lawyers
do so lawyers you know why are they
powerful they are not just rich and they
are also powerful because the essence of
the job of the lawyer is to play with
power is to well technically play with
law you know they can explain the law
they can say you are right you are wrong
okay you should go to jail you are free
to go okay that's what loyers do they
play with the
law and law is important you know
because Law and Order you know you don't
you want a you know generally speaking
you want the society to be based on law
not based on you know some
King uh so that is important so you have
lawyers but
however you you know you could have a
situation where it's all
corrupt you know yeah you have law but
then you have have like powerful lawyers
they can like go around the law you know
like they can say a murderer to be free
you know they can you know they can do
things so that is what what's happening
in
USA okay that's a digression about these
different
professions so about
coding uh if you are a nerd like me you
know you are not a social light you know
you are not you don't enjoy like
socializing talking with people you know
finding out you know little chat how are
you today how is your family oh you know
let's go have a drink in a bar if you do
not enjoy that maybe coding is for you
generally and on the other hand if you
enjoy socializing talking with people
then maybe coding is not for you because
for those people usually they find it
very boring like who's going to you know
sit in on front of compter you know
figure out all
these algorithms and stuff
okay okay that's about
that you know what how useful is coding
but oh let me mention one more thing
today you might have heard the AI
technology you know the AI you know the
chat GPT it's all the fat and 80% of it
is
misinformation is basically grifters
trying to make money they will say oh AI
is going to do this or that you know uh
of course and cause Panic AI is going to
rob all the jobs and things things like
that you know that you know this kind of
thing been going on for for for
decades so how do you know what is true
and what is not true well basically you
cannot know unless you are a coder like
a like me a pro a programmer and you are
really into it then you know how AI
works I know how AI works then you can
kind of tell what is true what is not
true which AI expert you can trust which
AI you know online you know on on
Twitter on Reddit they think they are
expert they talk big ethics of AI oh USA
you know we need to create the ethical
committee on you know govern to govern
how AI should you know the Govern the
Google's AI or whatever AI you know how
make rules you know those are mostly
[ __ ] those are kind of the lower
they are just like scums okay they are
scum
scumbags so anyway back to AI so you
might have heard that AI is going to uh
take away the job of
programmers you will hear that very
common even including many
programmers now let me tell you they are
idiots patently Force AI is never going
to take over the job of programmers if
you are good one I mean of course if you
don't know how to you know if you just
like the like the low level you know you
don't really know how to program you
just you know you went to school college
you study programming but you really
have no interest you just go to stack
Overflow you have some idea you know
like you can just copy and paste and
make things
work if you are that type of programmer
you know the lowest
level yeah then you'll die your job will
be taken away by AI okay but if you are
anything normal you are you know you are
interested in programming in computer
science in algorithms in bit ding like
the many of the C
gentics AI is never going to take your
job away in fact the more AI the more
you are valuable because AI are written
by programmers okay of course people
will say yeah but AI is so Advanced it
it it knows how to program itself no
that's false
okay until AI really
becomes a sentient being then that's a
different story if AI become a sentient
being so smart it became sentient then
that's basically the end of
humanity and whether that will happen we
don't know okay you can you know there's
a lot of AI experts you know they they
they got the title like AI whatever uh
half of the time they don't know what
they're talking about I know what I'm
talking about and I'm telling you about
that okay so when you hear someone say
oh AI is going to take job of the
programmers away that's
[ __ ] what is g code it's very simple
for most part for CNC what is
CNC what is CNC and what is gcode
hello Viper now let's
continue on this on our project to
create a copy button to Copy Source Code
okay now right now we are looking at the
Microsoft website to see how they do it
because they got
this in fact this exist I believe it's
also on stack over overflow where you
have a you know code you can just click
to copy anyway let's
see
so so button so here is a button so they
have a button here event and flex style
okay class listing actions okay and
they they use an SVG inside the button
C uh why do they use SVG because because
they want this little icon you uh you
can see okay let me show
you you see they want this icon so
that's why they are using SVG SVG stand
for scalable vector
graphics and I have a tutorial for it
too uh so you can you know write a code
to have a clock basically Graphics okay
line basically line illustrations that's
what s SVG is about so here you know
they have little SVG here okay we don't
we don't really
care okay then they have span copy
that's this text okay then button okay
let's copy this um copy this source
code right click copy alter HTML okay
now let's go back back to our thing here
let's paste
HTML paste there it is now pop it
out and uh that's the code now let's s
HTML format okay let me let me call this
command
HTML do I have like a pretty
print that's what I want to
do the HTML
precode
uh there it is tab u m HTML format to
multi lines tab u
m
okay let's expand it it
doesn't oh it doesn't expand that much
but anyway so anyway so here is the
code okay so here is basically their
code so you got the button that's a
whole thing then you got the span there
then you got the SVG here so SVG this
part is just the graphics for that
little you know two
squares okay so you got a button then
you got a image then you got copy okay
that's so simple so basically that's
just that so that's a button okay when
you show this in HTML let's let me show
you uh and I don't need the class
listing options okay so let me show you
this
um in fact remove the pre-ex so you see
we got the copy button it looks like
that okay you can click it it does
nothing
because right now there's no action no
event Handler okay so you yeah so you
want to attach um so let me show you
guys how to do it okay so you want to
add a event handle let's add an ID
here okay uh x copy okay so you got a
button you got the ID then you okay so
actually um then you want the event
handler okay how do you do that well
let's go to my JavaScript tutorial
because
I have a JavaScript tutorial there but
let's copy the link here so we know we
have a record of what we talked about
okay go to dome copy that back to emac
paste the link
here and uh we want to know how to do a
button how to get a event handler for
button so here Basics examples HTML
input there it is button there it is
copy the URL back to emac paste it make
a link make a um list and uh delete that
let's move it here showing browser
fantastic now click on the button this
is how you do a button okay so actually
let's so you can see click me you see it
insert click click click click that's
how you do a button now let's copy the
whole code okay let's just copy
code okay and paste here so we don't
need this anymore so we got a button
here type
button uh and this is the uh span
element show area actually we don't
need okay so then we need a JavaScript
code that's this part okay let's copy it
let's create a new buffer paste it let's
save
x uh
copy
button.js okay so let's rename it so
it's got a underscore so there it is the
file copy button. a uh oh you got a name
wrong let's rename spelled it wrong b t
t o n
yeah uh is that right bu yeah B again
okay so here's the file copy the file
path close it close it paste the file
path here make a link so you got the
script it will run this
script so showing browser so we got
click me click click click and it just
the current action is just insert the
word clicked okay now all we have to do
is change that action so let's go to the
file open
it change you see so let me explain this
code so first of all you have a constant
variable name button something and uh
that button is the document get element
by ID you get you know you basically
grab
the uh let me show you okay so you got
the button element here and the button
has an ID so here you
basically get the element and assign to
this variable and here same thing you
got this span element you get it save it
as a variable then here's then here's a
function Let's ignore it for now now
this part is the add event handler this
is important part so this part says this
button
thing called the method add a event
listener to it and the event name is
click and so when that event happens run
this function called update okay and and
the other argument you can ignore so you
run this function which is update and
this is what this function do so this
function let's make it prettier okay so
let's prettify the code okay so this
function update
will use the show element which is that
which is the show which is the span so
get the show element
then text
content uh variable then you just say
text content plus click you know join
the string add a click so that's how
this works
okay so that's when you say click click
click you just add a click okay now all
we have to do is to change this function
so instead of just um this one
insert
add text clicked to it that's what this
line do instead of that we want to copy
the text in the pre
element into
clipboard that's what we want to do we I
don't know how to do that but that's
what we want to do
okay okay now uh save it uh save wait
save it close it okay sh browser again
okay now let's look at the FSH I mean
the Microsoft page let's see how they do
it so you got SVG that's for graphics
you got spans so it button it doesn't
um it doesn't really do
anything uh okay lots of comments hold
on a second I'll answer
that so you got this code this code
doesn't we need to find out where's the
event handler okay so this is just a
button code for that
yeah but how do you find the event
handler okay um let's let's put
this do to the right okay let's put it
this way so you can
see this is a FSH tutorial we are trying
to find out how they do this copy code
and here here is the copy section but
where is the event handler that's what
we are look uh looking
for let's see what this okay this part
we don't
care this part is the actual code you
know actual
code
uh right so we need to know the event
handler for this
button now I'm not a professional web
dev meaning that I'm not working a
company doing Dev web dev so I'm not too
familiar
um so you know if you work in a web
there professionally you would know
right away right now we need to find the
event handler for this button okay how
do you do that let's
see so here's a CSS Styles we don't care
layout computed changes compatibility
font we don't care we need to know the
event handler for this
okay
uh event handler for listing action oh
oh there's a button click click to show
event listeners for this element
fantastic
you know the power of the web dev the
browser becomes an IDE you see just
click on that just click on that okay
jQuery [ __ ] you know this this is
idiocy so right now this part tells you
that the microsoft.net
website is using jQuery what is jQuery
jQuery is a JavaScript library or
framework somebody else Road and it's
bloated okay it's for people who don't
know what they doing that's when they
use jQuery very popular super popular
since about 2008 or so so very popular
almost 20 years ago the jQuery idiot
microsoft.net website is using jQuery
but anyway let's
well you see so they have a click event
oh okay it's still simple let's see so
here is a function when you click this
function is called very simple okay
maybe we'll just use
this let's see Cur target. closes.
listening okay so it's trying to find
the
listening uh
listing uh class okay then. find code
okay then. text so it's getting the text
so this e here is the source
code is this basically this source code
okay uh let's
see Okay click event then it says
I uh
what so what is this I jesus this you
know this this compressed
framework
Fox you see when you have a library
JavaScript library typically they
compress the code so they rename all
functions to be one single letter so
this I is a function but you you have no
idea what that function is
doing via the name you know so you just
know there's a function I
called with the um e is the text
okay and uh yeah you just and t. current
Target is the is this pre-code
element so the function I is
called and so the key is here you know
because we want to copy to TCH click boo
that must be probably somewhere in this
I so how do we find out what's this I
so this function actually there are two
event um attached to it okay one is
bubbling oh God
complicated so what does this bubbling
do bubbling is kind of like event
hierarchy okay so you have one event
nested inside another so when the nested
event
happens the outer event may also fire
depending on your set your config for
the bubbling that's what this bubbling
means nested event okay very complex
[ __ ] so anyway this button has two
events one is just copy the source code
of the preag then call the function I
now how do I find out what is function I
is
doing you can I see it no [ __ ] [ __ ] the
jQuery
and uh then this event what does this
event do return void bubbling C event.
triggered not equals to two. type c
event dispatch apply e arguments void
okay that we probably don't care so the
main thing is this event function and
the main thing is the I
function now where is what does the I
function do here okay so maybe
here
Jesus oh God this
this oh God this is you know this is in
encrypted you know this is like Minima
you know this one [ __ ] single line
one [ __ ] single line of 10 million
characters
okay at this point this is not you know
for example let's copy that copy copy
back to emac the
powerful Power Station the battle
station paste it okay so you got this
one single
line
36,000
characters yeah so you got one single
line of 36 kilobytes
okay now you know this this is this is
so this is part of the jQuery and
whatever a bunch of
[ __ ] you know this is what happens to
corporate
site a bunch of crap so let me let me
try to make it um let's try to make
sense of this and also emac has problem
with long so let's see
search for
all right cly
Braes replace it by that with a new line
okay and do it for all oh okay
so we made it somewhat more readable
okay so still so what is this I function
so list matching lines function we need
need to find a function whose name is
the single letter
I you know this this [ __ ] minimal
minimalize the [ __ ] the JavaScript
coders in
scum this web dev environment this
design gurus this
JavaScript
gurus in general they are scum because
they are the Zuma generator they are the
late M gen Zuma generation and they
created basically they create the
situation where you don't know how to
code you just look up stack Overflow
just copy and paste they create created
you know the not JS that scum the what's
his name Isaac I think the leader of of
the the the the Nots not not the creator
of NS Ryan Ryan da is a fantastic great
guy of a great coder of great programmer
and also a great person but the however
the the guy who took over njs I think
his name is Isaac something who created
the not you know the
the you know the the njs library thing
he is a major scun
hello
George so there's quite a few questions
I haven't gone through so anyway so you
know we are trying to find out find a
function whose name is I I
think can we
even uh I don't think you know I don't
think this is the right way to solve
this problem there there it is
wait function fun function I let's have
a look okay let's go
there wait are we already we are there
so so uh wait this is not it yeah so we
go there so here is a function I let's
see if it happens one more than one time
just just to make sure function
I okay it happens in two places we got
to be sure to check them out okay this
in this minimalized
[ __ ] by this JavaScript M malen and Zuma
idiots so what is this so so
this okay so what uh okay now this time
to callar JavaScript mod to color it
okay press press press fantastic saw
JavaScript mod and now let let's save
the file
XX uh let's just
say ms. JS okay random name okay so we
found one instance a function named I
let's see you know this is just too
cryptic okay return something type of
symbol symbol equals to type of symbol
do it
iterator then you call function god type
of
[ __ ] what a scum you see typically this
is a situation you don't want to get to
if you are a professional programmer
because this is the worst part of
programming to look at this
crap uh but if you are uh Security in a
security field especially web then this
is what you have to do do all
day to to find out what's you know what
this thing is doing when you know to
trace out you know viruses or one way or
whatever okay let's so we are you know
so we are still trying to code this
let's
see let's see the next instance of
function I okay is here so
okay it's also
short four h this is this is not right
this is a four Loop then what is the
four Loop doing the
arguments uh four I in N then t i equals
to N I return T yeah some
tic okay we we are not finding the copy
to he George do you know what is the
function the Doom function to copy a
text to click boo that's what we are
doing today George George is expert in
JavaScript okay so anyway let's give up
in looking at this source
code yeah you are right but I'm going
through the process you know so of of
course the alternative way you know in
fact the better way it just stack
Overflow
JavaScript copy to clipboard
okay so let's search for
it so what is the okay W3 schools the
most for idiots yeah I'm an idiot please
I want to you you know that's the
advantage of
W3
schools tutorial it's for idiot okay so
let's copy so let's copy their
Cod oh add JavaScript oh okay so they
actually you know they showed the whole
thing so here is suppose this
HTML and here is
Javascript let's see how they do it okay
uh yeah let's create a new JavaScript
code JavaScript and paste it and also
let's see what's there HTML input text
okay the button used to copy the text
okay now let's look at their code
JavaScript okay my function document
something okay so copy text is the
element then all you have to do is just
say
select and say select set selection
region wait set selection range for
mobile devices oh okay then just
this Navigator do clipboard. WR text so
simple okay let's let's copy let's steal
their code this W3 School
scum
copy
back uh wait where is my back uh yeah
this key okay basically they you know so
now let's go to our
code so you know our code and uh let's
paste the part
here uh let's see what we want to do so
you need
to uh
wait yeah so first of all you need to
get you need to get the element you want
to copy to okay let's see what you guys
are saying navate cre right text George
is expert yeah I know so anyway let's
see what are the questions above
um so I've been talking for one hour
already okay I need more wi I need more
100 ml of red
wine okay nobody is saying
anything so now let me tell you what we
need to do the first thing we need to do
what wait I close that by mistake let's
pop this
out the first thing we need to do let me
let's go over okay so
what oh what close it okay okay so let's
see let's clean up okay so what is Hello
word I don't care about the hello word
[ __ ] okay I don't want you know the W3
screw is is not very good okay it's for
it's you know it's it's it's not really
good okay so what we want to do is first
of all we have a button then you we
don't need this show okay then you need
to have
a uh kind of a Target like what what do
you want to
copy uh we have to think about okay so
we have a copy text so instead of Click
me let's say copy me okay so it needs to
say copy the button okay
so and so when you click it uh what part
you want to copy
uh let's say let's say we don't care
okay I mean
let's let's just hard code so you know
let's just hard code it okay
so so do we have a description of what
we're doing yes we do that's
here okay then okay so then the
JavaScript part uh what is it
so this is this is the W3 schools code
which we don't need I
mean
uh okay so let's copy it okay let's put
it
there and uh yeah so we got yeah so
let's this links
go there so we clean up so people know
what we are doing clearly okay so we
need the copy me let's move the copy me
button delete it and uh move
to let's say move here okay so when you
click copy me it should let's say copy
the next preag okay something like
that okay and the JavaScript code let's
copy it I mean let's move it here here's
a JavaScript code okay now let's open
the JavaScript code now hold on a second
yeah okay let's open the JavaScript code
so you got the button you this show you
don't need anymore we we we deleted it
okay so this function named update will
rename it let's rename it let's name it
f
uh copy text
okay there it is we so now so what is
the purpose of this function this
function will copy let's
see copy the
next pre
elements text okay now let's
see uh then what we do yeah so then you
need to select the next pre-
element now I know George can probably
finish this in one minute okay but I'm
not George George I'm a slow coder okay
but I'm
analytical okay probably nobody's
watching this right now now so
anyway so what we doing so we need
to uh wait what is is let copy the next
pre- elements text okay let's do
that so the next pre-
element actually that's hard to get so
let's just say copy the ID tdt okay
let's give this element an ID so showing
browser you can see this is the element
with the ID TTT okay and you know let's
for now let's just do that so V uh V TTT
for example document get element by ID
that's right TTT so we get that element
then once we get the element we need to
get the text of that
element okay uh Jesus this is going to
be involved because
in the case of my my website you know
it's not plain text because you got all
these
HTML tags inside it that you need to
strip so you need in other words the
JavaScript will need to
process this you know this text by
removing all the HTML tag inside and
then convert um convert things like amp
percent for example m% GT means greater
than you know things like that so you
need to yeah so okay anyway but let's
just do this step by step so we make
progress okay slowly but
shortly so first of all you get element
by ID uh what okay element by ID which
is uh is the ID the TTT just for test
purposes okay
then according to that
w3c W3 school it
says uh copy text okay so wait copy text
replac by
TGT okay so that is element the element
you do select not sure what that do
exactly then select selection range then
Navigator keboard WR select what do you
need to do select
George but anyway so it seems the
key method is really just this Navigator
do clipboard. WR text okay td. td. value
okay so let's say we don't even need
this
I don't know what those do let's just
common them out okay so this is our
element
and and this
is this is put that
elements value to the clipboard okay and
uh let's
see okay copy
the okay let's just say that okay okay
now cing up the code pre formatt it
fantastic very simple this is our
function copy text then we add a event
handler here so when the button is
clicked it will copy text okay sounds
good sounds
good close it showing
browser now would it work let's try
are you guys seeing me yeah my code okay
so let's try copy
me back to
emx actually go back to let's open uh
let's open the
notepad paste
undefined
okay it seems to be working but
something is wrong for example copy
class paste class okay now you go here
click click copy
me and now paste undefined so it
actually did something it just copied
undefined so we need to fix the
undefined uh okay vah you know never use
raah in JavaScript because since
JavaScript 2015 I believe uh you have
let or constant Okay so
uh don't use
V and uh you know I let me show you go
to JavaScript in depth then go to Value
types you know you have JavaScript basic
syntax then you have value types you
have variables you have let constant F
okay so always use let or constant now
because I'm into functional programming
so
I do not even use let I use always
constant very
strict okay constant tdt is document get
element by ID so we get the element by
ID uh so search for tdt yeah there's
that
ID so we got that
ID yes and
uh then why is
that oh not value you need the inner
text okay so let me show Inner
text
uh there it is
okay save it close it showing
browser copy me
click back to
notepad paste
oh beautiful
success okay so that's you know so so
that's the heart of what we need to do
it's so simple you know of course most
people you know most YouTubers they will
just show you show you this in 3 minutes
but for me it took one
hour now of course there's more to do
yeah like I'm very detailed so I need to
know for example what does this actually
select do and set selection range okay
and uh and also I need to look up the
documentation for this Navigator clip.
WR text so for example let's search for
it and let's go to mdn web doc which is
MOA which is from Firefox the
browser uh this this feature is
available only in Secure context https
in some or all supported browser
what that doesn't seems to be true
because I was not on https and it
worked you know so you know you run into
these little issues um
writing to clipboard can only be done in
a secure context additional security
requirements are covered in the security
consideration section of the API
overview topic
okay uh okay what is uh you
know
so are they kidding
me so if you know my website is not
running on https
so are they saying that this code won't
work if I actually upload it to my to my
website if that's the case that then
then that that [ __ ] [ __ ] these people
this Google Facebook they are scums okay
you guys don't know what I'm talking
about but they you know many of the
reason why is called this way or that
because there are there's there's Heavy
Deep mechanis mechanization ations you
know that is not designed for the good
of the community for the programmers for
the users for the you know security
purposes but rather they are designed
for something else like you know for
them to scam and uh you know for them to
you know for devious reasons that is why
today you know web dev is very
complex and you have so many scum
players you know they doing for their
little things including the entire
agile you know the agile Community
you the the scums
anyway
so it's okay so so so in any case the
code right now
works I need to so it's I already been
talking for 70 minutes so I should stop
yeah but what I need to do is that I
need to have a JavaScript to generate
this copy
button you know not
manually having a copy button myself why
because I already have one I already
have like few thousand pages with this
pre- tag so I need for example I need to
add a JavaScript that will generate this
copy button for any page that have
this this pre you know source code tag
so what I do is I go to the bottom you
can see there's a highlight link
JavaScript code open
it this JavaScript is run by every page
10,000 pages so in this page I need to
add a function I need to add code that
will add this copy me button to any page
with to to every each and every pre- tag
okay that's what I need to
do okay
so so in other words this code this code
we added today needs to go to that
JavaScript and also add a code uh you
know create a
button uh
yeah anyway that's what I need to do and
there's also a little other things I
need to figure out but anyway that's it
for today I
think lots of to do lots of things to
do okay anything else we shut down in
two minutes
am I still running let's make sure yes
10 people
watching yeah I'm still running okay bye
guys don't forget to donate to me okay
bye my JavaScript in depth tutorial and
emac tutorial or donate me
via
patreon and uh
PayPal okay go to.
info uh. info in the bottom you'll find
Amazon gift card and patreon me and
PayPal
me okay bye
guys uh let me prepare to shut down so
what else we did today so HTML button
do we already have that code link yes
that's how you add a
button uh what is this emx okay emex BL
s Keys important copy
it uh we talked about SVG Sly Keys F
shop tutorial
okay uh HTML button close that Java copy
to clipboard
okay by