hello guys welcome to another episode of
startup show we are going to code emac
Beast today
Advent of code day 5 continue from
yesterday so let's show today's talk
show
December 30th the second to last the
penultimate day
of the year 2022.
so Advent of code day five b continue
from yesterday okay
yesterday we stuck with writing a
transposition of Matrix function and uh
I'm happy to tell you that it has been
completed
offline yesterday
the code is pretty short just that okay
and there's uh extra
um
function so create Matrix
okay so that creates a two by two Matrix
in Vector in lisp Vector data type
so it's a vector and its elements are
also vectors two by two Matrix you can
specify three by two three hundred by
four thousand you know in value initial
value then you have the transpose
function let's demonstrate because this
this transpose position function is the
key to the event of code problem
five
okay interesting problem
so yeah so let's demonstrate the
transposition okay so let's see so yeah
and uh let me give you some news about
my emacs uh tutorial you can find it
just go to xali emacs tutorial you can
find emacs tutorial initialization uh
setup emacs Keys everything you want to
know about customizing keys
emac this Basics the disk programming
language hello secondary account and
practical emac this this is all you want
to know about
writing emac this to manipulate text
refactor you know and supreme okay
and then you can learn about emac you
know a bunch of tens of emac this actual
examples let's say you want to remove
the accent characters
you know uh and you know each one is
independent you can copy and paste to
your init file and you will have it
so uh you know and then you there's how
to write a major mod okay so this is my
emacs tutorial if you like it if you
like my work patreon me okay this is
critical
this is my effort you know money money
is talking
so or Amazon gift card me and or PayPal
me
okay and let me I want to mention one
thing okay because I got the biggest
Christmas gift
of my life
from Andrew okay so thank you very much
500 thank you thank you so much
um
you know so yeah so uh and many other
you guys
so let's go back to emacs the emac this
tutorial and then I have a Blog so uh
you know I've been writing this blog for
since 2006 so for 15 years you know and
I continuously update enhance it just
like software you know new version you
know so
yeah so I want to say if you like it you
know you can go to the page and you'll
find the buy emacs tutorial
so what does it give you well
everything is free
you know just like free beer
um
but you know it's already it's online
you can access it but you like my work
pay it okay pay it you get you get the
zip file of the entire emacs tutorial
which is about 1 000 Pages plus 2 000
pages of the emacs menu well formatted
that's what you get okay so uh so you
can instantaneously use it as a
reference or as a commitment you know a
lot of people wants to you know they use
emacs using emacs is one thing you know
but learning emacs is a different thing
most emacs users they've been using for
10 years for 20 years but many but at
least half of them they actually never
write any emac bisp
so this is a very powerful you know you
don't have to you know you don't that's
the thing you don't have to but if when
if you want to it's very powerful emac
this I would say
is the most
uh is the most feature reach and
efficient programming language for text
processing okay that's a key text
processing normally emac this is only
useful within emacs you know as a editor
so you can create lots of features you
know refactor your code key macro or
whatever so you can write emac beasts
you know shell for example shell
duh you don't have a the issue is
written entirely in um
in emac this you know you you can go to
um
you know the source code and jump to the
source code you can see here's the
e-shell and uh this
400 lines here but there's more okay so
um
anyway that's the source code so is Xiao
is a bash like shell but it's not it's
not exactly bash okay but it's a batch
like shell
with e for with emac based features in
emacs and it's written entirely
in emac this it's written by this uh
Zhang weekly guy okay he he is currently
the maintainer the leader of emacs gnu
emacs for the past five years or so so
here are these you know
so it's fantastic so I've been using it
for five seven years before I was using
the Shell you know in emacs you have
multiple shells you have you know let's
see so you have Isha um you know you
have multiple anyway
so so yeah I was talking about emac lisp
so emac this is a programming language
embedded in emacs or you can you can
think of it the other way around
emacs is actually just the environment
supporting emac bisp so emac this is
kind of like the list machine of the
1980s and you know mostly 1980s the
artificial intelligence list machine
yeah very good okay fantastic so emac
Beast is a language in emacs but however
and and generally it's not useful
outside of emacs so if you want to want
to do web development if you want to do
you know
writing or extension for Linux kernel or
for Microsoft whatever drivers or Mac OS
or you want to write a graphical user
interface in on desktop on Linux on
Microsoft Windows or on Mac
you cannot use emac this you know you
have to use Java JavaScript
Swift depending on which operating
system you know python Ruby you know
then you have you need a GUI Library so
in general or if you want to write write
a web server or any server of any kind
you know a website or on a phone
you know you have to use other languages
because emac this is only for emacs use
within emacs
you know you have to use Java C or if
you want to write a game usually it's C
plus plus because it's a dominant
language
you know C C plus plus
Java C sharp
d That's one category of languages then
you also have of course commonly schemes
all these are general purpose or closure
lisp or
racket lisp or you know Ruby python
Pearl bash you know it's not not
counting bash because bash is just a
shell but anyway so these are general
purpose programming languages and also
gold land oh I cannot forget Golan and
rust right
so so many languages and then you have
functional academic kind of uh languages
such as Haskell erlen
uh and rust some what an old camo and F
sharp F sharp for Microsoft or camel or
standard ml ml stands for meta language
standard ml then you have o camo which
is derived from ml then you have F sharp
for Microsoft which is derived from or
camo or ml you know that's one family
and and this ml is kind of similar in a
category like Haskell
so these are functional very kind of
pure
so lots of languages all these are
general purpose languages
okay
and e-maglis is not general purpose you
only use it it's only basically useful
in emacs however
if your programming task is text
processing that is you want to you have
tons of text you know you want to
manipulate you want to move things
around you want to remove this you know
any occurrence of say a link
only if they appear within some other
text before or after
I'm sorry excuse me too much cigarette
the coffee so if you
so if you want to to do text processing
okay that's a major task
in
one of the major tasks tasks of
programming reports you know basically
you want to process text okay lots of
text then
if that's your that's the thing you need
to do then emac this is the best
language of them all
okay text processing
including processing HTML XML
and and lots of others
you know the Wikipedia doesn't say much
but you know
about it okay so that's the point I want
to make in summary emac this is
basically only useful for emacs it's not
a general purpose language however for
the task of text processing
then emacs that he beats them all
doesn't matter it's Pearl python Ruby or
JavaScript whatever
emac this
for
task of text processing bits demo
okay that's the point I want to make
that is the point why I mean so why is
it better than demo because emac bits
has this special data type buffer and
point and and lots of things to support
this text processing where you will not
find it in any other language in
parallel in Python in Ruby in JavaScript
okay
text processing
however not not a scale I mean if you
want to process a billion you know files
where each one is one gigabyte then you
make this is not good okay in that case
you have to go down you know C plus plus
or Golan
in Haskell
but for the kind of small scale text
processing emacs speed demo
okay hello Jr have you heard of the full
heart shutdown due to Windows 11 always
on State
no I haven't heard of it heard of it
what is that I don't know is there
something I can search no I haven't
heard of it okay so
so let me Demo demonstrate the
transposition function we wrote
yesterday okay transposition so let's go
to a brief
so this is my um my emacs init okay so
search for transpose uh actually I
I named it Matrix okay so you have two
functions this one you know wrote
yesterday and this one okay fantastic
evaluate them show the pink window the
pink window shows all my command course
you know as I move closer you can see
all the command cores
and the keystrokes on the left side that
I'm using a vorac layout physical vorac
keyboard and this keyboard is
expose I talked about many times if you
search exactly keyboard blog you'll find
it okay many of these I recommended I
talked about it often in my video
and good news possibly I'll be getting
the glove 80.
you know then I'll tell you guys how it
goes this I I think it's very good okay
so expose okay
okay and you if you like my stuff you
like my talk my tutorials pay me okay
yeah support me do that and for you
watch my video those of you watching my
video offline uh you know comments you
know or paste a link you know stem stamp
you know
uh tell your friends you know some parts
interesting show it to your friends
spread it thank you okay so let's demo
create Matrix okay let's let's just show
you
uh new buffer so I'm gonna do that and
let's go to Kasai Max mod so Matrix
let's say three by two and with the
value of uh let's say a
let's say a okay
uh run it okay now go to the go to the
messages buffer you can see that is a
result you have a three by two Matrix
three rows and two columns let's let's
say um
four by two okay at this times let's say
B do it you see fantastic that is now
let's write transposition okay
uh
transpose okay so we want the Matrix
let's say
let's manually put it one two three okay
four five six a matrix
okay we want to transverse that now
evaluate it you can see the answer there
is one four two five three six The
Columns you see
one four
two five three six transposition
fantastic
okay so here is a code from yesterday
pretty pretty simple okay you can read
the code and shouldn't be you know
understand each of the function call
look up the documentation and you will
understand it okay
fantastic now close that
close that don't save okay okay delete
that okay now
go back to
yeah so let's go back now what we want
we want to continue yesterday okay
yesterday we got this problem
so the problem is that given a text
input like that
you know like that and uh actually this
is wrong
let me fix it
hmm
you know there is some reason not like
that okay refresh so you got the this is
your input a text input there are two
parts the first part is a visualization
of bunch of boxes stacked on top of each
other you know column one a stack column
two you know several Columns of boxes
okay now the second part is a
instruction a procedure so you move one
box from column two to one then you move
three times from column one to three
then you move n times from you know M to
nth column and so on so you want to
follow those steps and uh know move you
the way you move out the box is only one
at a time the topmost Sparks you know
one move one box to the other and move
another box to the other so after you
follow this procedure
what is the resulting
stacks that is the problem day five
advent of code and it won't it asks you
to list the topmost box of each column
okay so your function will return a
string a string of letters
okay that is a problem
so yesterday's code let's copy it and uh
let's start to do it
today copy okay
so close that so here is today so let's
start a emac this paste it there
pop it out okay so here is the input
okay
so we did you know I'm not going to we
did this yesterday so
okay so split the boxes then
Okay so
build Xbox Matrix so we got the Matrix
uh then yeah we got the Matrix then
convert The Matrix to a nested vector
so what we are doing is that we
we already passed this part to this and
now we got a matrix
where you have each row
you know you have like one two three
four five six seven eight eight by nine
Matrix
each row is corresponding to the row so
but we want to represent the vertical
column
as a row so we need to transpose it
because we are going to you know we want
to operate on the
moving boxes on the columns so we want
to transpose The Matrix
Okay so yesterday we got the Matrix
okay and we want to transpose but we
failed in defining this function you
know we spent half an hour and didn't
succeed but now we have so we just
delete that
and for example let's evaluate this you
can see
the answer at the bottom one four two
five three six that's that works okay so
now you just
um
you want to transpose our Matrix okay
our Matrix currently look like that
okay so let's run it okay you need to
evaluate you know okay let's do
so that's the input let's let's just
evaluate the whole buffer okay
do it okay you can see I'm calling this
command runcon file okay it's done go to
the message it's buffer
and you can see
the result is
what is the result let's do it again
the result is here
okay let's copy it
let's make it uh
is that so does it represent the
vertical columns yes
NZ
check
DCM check
mtmtp
check
so
so now we got the correct answer so this
will be called stacks
okay
so set Stacks equals to that okay and uh
basically the output is like that okay
now we want to
turn this into a
you see each one is a vector we want to
turn them into a list okay so we want to
turn each stack
from Vector to list okay
so
let's set Q stack again so
how do you turn a vector to list let's
check
Emax e Mac list
okay I have worked on a lot yesterday if
you go to my blog yesterday I worked out
a lot enhancing my tutorial about the
data structure data type Vector list
sequence you know so now it's much
better I'm still working on them to
improve
okay so Stacks you want to turn a list
you know you want to turn a vector into
a list okay so Vector let's see
oh
join Vector convert this to Vector
convert Vector to this append is what
you want to do okay so append
uh you want to
so the Sequence gonna be Vector okay
something like that
so you know the stacks is uh a vector of
vectors so you want to map you want to
map each row to turn them into a list so
let's map
okay
so actually you need map
C
okay map C actually you want to map
car map Car returns the
list actually we don't care about the
result so let's use map C map C is like
JavaScript for each okay when you don't
care about the result okay so the
the sequence is gonna be stacks and
and the body this is what we want to do
body which is this append
X
okay a pen takes a bunch of sequence
sequence means either list or vector for
string
in emac Beast okay so a pen basically
they return at least okay
morning if you wanted to return a proper
list the last item must be released on
Neo okay that's the cork in emac list
and in common these two you have to put
a new
uh I'm not going into the detail but
basically
you you can you know if you want to know
the detail read about conspire okay
that's why you need to understand the
Neo okay
so anyway we are turning a vector into a
list okay so
that
okay so map C okay well map C doesn't
return anything
and
let's let's say car here we'll just
change the whole thing into a list
[Music]
I don't want to change the whole thing
to at least
so
yeah append returns at least you know
list is very annoying
yeah it returns at least
okay
you saw that this year
yeah
okay okay let's do this then
so map car that into the stacks so we
got a
this will turn the hole nested Vector
into a nested list okay let's let's do
it
oh wait uh
wait a minute uh let's see
so we are mapping this function to the
stack so we turn them each one of them
into a list
so that means each row is now at least
okay
and we
yeah then we set the result back to
stack so now Stacks is gonna be your
list okay let's run it
run it
oh avoid variable Stacks what
what wait
what's going on
okay let's run this run it okay
now run it okay now it works
let's see
yeah you see
that's a result
you see they become parentheses which
means at least
you know
um
but now
you want to remove the empty
you know the empty list
so
you want to map again okay so let's
secure and stack
okay then you map
call okay
map con sequence okay and the sequence
is gonna be stacks
okay
and this time what you're gonna do you
want to
kind of filter so if the list start with
a empty stream remove it okay because
because empty string is like you know
the you know but okay
so okay so now
emac this again so we are working on
list
uh so what
to do
okay I know what to do uh
you know we can use a filter function
but we don't want to do that because the
filter function will go all the way
you see in our case
we drop the first item if it's empty
string
you know but however the empty string as
long as you know when the when this item
that's not empty stream the rest will
not be empty Stream So the empty string
only happens in front Okay so if you use
a generic filter function you know test
if element is an empty string that will
go through the hole we don't want to go
through the hole you know because once
we found an an empty string we are stop
okay but this but the
you know so that's that's more efficient
but however if you use a generic filter
function there's one here you know
sequence filter
that will just you know apply to if you
have a million items you just keep
checking keep checking we don't want
that so anyway
so okay so our function
will
do
if
car x x x is a list okay if car is a
um
if car
string equal if the first item is empty
actually it's let's let's use a length
okay
if length car X is equals to zero okay
e
q-u-a-l
say zero
let's use the screen string equal
because it's more clear Clarity because
it tells you it's a string and it's
empty string this will work too but it's
you know what if you have an empty list
or something that won't happen but
anyway this is more clear using okay so
string equal if it's empty then
then then you want to set
x equals to cut the of X that means drop
the first one
you can just do put a pop okay
drop the first element
otherwise do nothing
so you need to put this into a while
loop so
wow
that is true
then
pop
okay
okay so let's put this into so we don't
need that
so the function will take on X which is
a one of the row so y on string equals
to
yeah pop X
yeah
I think that's it
okay
okay let's see let's
hope it's not infinite Loop okay make
sure we back up you know
run it
Neo Neo Neo that's incorrect
let's see what these are stack
okay that's incorrect hmm
uh okay so we need to get our stack back
then this
okay
that's our stacks
yeah that's like that yeah
and now
go through stacks
map it
append
which turns it turn it
okay convert from Vector to list
hello condemned had condemned did you
send me your email about your emacs
tutorial
I don't think I see any email you know
check your spam folder maybe you it's in
your spam folder of emacs tutorial
okay am I still going good am I doing
good guys
uh
okay convert it from Vector to list okay
let's run this
run it
correct
at the bottom now
so now you have a list of
least
and now
you want to
oh you don't want to map car
wait uh God this you know this this
so where are you pop that's right
that's right but you want to return
the X that's why okay you know you pop
you drop you drop the first item then
you when it's no longer true you want to
return the rest of it okay so that
fantastic
go to the message buffer copy and paste
it here so that is our stack okay the
state so we got the stack
okay now let's move on to the next part
of the problem
which is to turn this procedure in
English into code in other words we are
writing a transpyler
we are compiling English source code
into emac this source code okay so let's
read the comments
uh Pinoy boy I got the Xbox keyboard
okay thanks I just discovered your site
and for sure our support thank you very
much thank you you inspire me to buy the
Expos yeah very good uh Deep dive in
learning programming
thank you
what do you think about springboard
framework
I don't know what is that
spring boots he said is that Java thing
I don't I don't work with Java okay
spring boot introduction spring boot is
an open source Java base yeah and I
don't call Java okay
okay you know yeah I don't know anything
about it
okay so now we want to turn this into a
you know English into
into code you know so first of all
you know you know I'm so big actually
this part is already here so
actually it's copy it
[Music]
uh this this procedure let's see
describe variable
and what
[Music]
what procedure you see it's already a
list okay so the value of that is that
okay
and see procedure text okay let's change
the name
okay
so that is the procedure text now
let's go to the bottom now we want to do
something with that okay let's read
let's create a variable let's say
input numbers
let's say
procedure
Hawks okay that is this English we want
to extract just the numbers okay because
the move from two it's not important we
just want to get the numbers then we
write a function that deal with these
numbers you know a function that takes
these arguments
so procedure arcs
okay now let me show you guys something
interesting okay
because typically you know in other
programming languages you manipulate
strings you know every any text is a
string so you have you you call stream
functions like you know stream trim or
stream you know get index from n to m
you know
but in emacs let me show you the text
processing okay so let's do that
you know very different from any
language because the only emac this has
that uniquely like we talked about
before text processing so
this procedure text you can let me show
you okay
with temp of a
okay we create a temporary buffer
then insert
insert this procedure text you know
this this thing okay
then
uh then we
then we insert it into the buffer then
then delete we want to delete all the
move all the words move form okay and
two okay so we can do
wow okay first of all go to chart
go to uh point mean which is the
beginning of the buffer one position
okay move the buffer to the beginning of
the buffer you know with temp buffer
create an empty buffer like that
okay then you insert it just insert you
know it just insert whatever you know
that string procedure text then you go
to the beginning of the buffer then you
do a wire Loop so while search for a
word let me show you okay so why I'll
search forward
move okay
and bound
uh
but we don't care Neo
no Arrow true okay can't we don't care
so you you search forward for the move
character if it exists deleted
I mean if this function founded
then you will return true okay so this
while loop works so if it's found then
you want to say
uh replace match okay replace match by
empty string you know so fixed case and
know that we don't care okay so uh yeah
TV that okay
so so so this part
let me show you okay
let's do it this way okay
so these two lines will re delete all
the
world move okay now we need to repeat
this
okay now change the word to
form
and change it to two Okay or actually
you know we can combine these three
lines using a regular expression
okay but let's just stick with this
simple
okay
so remove the move from two words then
okay then
return the string okay so we want to
so let me show you how this is done okay
so set we want to set this
uh yeah let's do it and
okay so let me show you some okay let's
do it here
okay let's say
X1 okay
copy that
okay
so that we can see what it actually
returns okay
okay so let's do it
oh yeah so at the end we want to
um
you know this with temp buffer it will
return whatever the last expression
returns so we need to get put the text
here
so it will you know return
the stream then set it to X1 okay so
with 10 buffer the last expression will
be
um
the first substream no properties okay
position point mean
to
Point Max okay that will return it now
let's do something else I mean once you
get that so you remove all the words
then you also
yeah let's just do that okay so let's
evaluate this part evaluate it can you
see beautiful that's the result so you
could you know
then all you have to do is split
split string
by
empty
by a new line okay wait wait okay wait
three string X1
by empty
by a new line character
okay
and amid news that's true we don't want
anything okay so yeah
okay so let's do it
you see
it becomes a
Orange
three string X1
oh my God I
coding takes a lot of time and now I
feel like I need to get up and walk
okay and we also need to trim string
okay so my God
let's let's combine this okay let's try
to combine these
into one expression
Okay so
research forward okay
so the rejects is going to be
several
uh in emac basis you need the
you need a lot of that yeah very
annoying
[Music]
Okay so
move
from
two okay that's how you do them in one
shot
okay so optional
bound
new no error true account we don't care
okay
yeah so these three lines
is now just this one single line okay
regular expression the power of regular
expression
and
you know we can run it and so you can
see
you see and then
um
or two so we want extra the space there
so let's run it again run it
fantastic okay so now let's remove this
redundant one okay
and now let's let's shorten okay
and now we split the string let's run it
again okay now run it
oh the I got the slash wrong it should
be backslash not slash okay
yeah that's that's right
okay so you can see
fantastic okay now so we can put the
split string
combine these two yeah let's do that so
this whole x one
let's just put it here okay
and uh okay let's put X1 here okay
okay so if you run that you get that
okay
that's x one
okay at least of strings
okay
uh
okay string Ox okay let's uh let's
rename them
okay
okay let's just rename them so it's
easier to understand okay now okay now
we don't want that okay now we want to
write a function so such that when the
function
takes a stream
of numbers then it will manipulate our
stacks
by following this procedure move it you
know okay let's write move let's let's
define that function
if I
say move Stacks okay
okay
stream
so actually
should be XYZ three arguments
okay x y z
okay
so it's gonna be x y z three arguments
okay uh
move
y
one box from y to Z
x times that's what it means
documentation okay we don't need the
interactive okay
then okay so then that's the body so
what we're gonna do so x y z
so
from stack y
to stack Z okay
okay and do it x times okay
okay so oh God
how are you guys
six people watching say something
so we already coded almost one hour you
know coding takes a hard time this
Advent of code
okay so move Stacks okay yeah there's
some kind of boring okay so here is our
stacks and our Stacks is a list of
so
stack number one would correspond to
you know stack column one would
correspond to our stack index zero you
know NZ you know like over here
you know so that's our Stacks so okay so
so the data structure we want to
manipulate is this
okay
Okay
so
let's see move y to Z so that means
this means
oh God
move
stack y to Z one time okay so Stacks so
so it's a list right so you wanna so you
can what you can do is you first of all
what column
yeah well column y to column Z
so you want pop so you want to do so pop
uh
dad
is
so pop
and
foreign
let's fix this
you know so here our Stacks is a list
of this
right
a list in this this his efficient
representation of Stack
okay
but however so I mean efficient
represents notation of Stack which means
you can push or pop the first item
but however
when you access nth item is slow so
the whole thing should be your vector
or in other words array
so you can access any column very fast
but for each of the column is a list you
can push and pop very fast
but the whole thing should be a vector
okay
why am I concerned about this because if
it's not a vector
then you know then our problem right now
is we want to pop the wife stack
so how do you do that you know
the why the white stack would be it
would be something like
um
something like that
you know it's it's a it's a bit fishy
because when you have at least
it takes nth time to get to that column
and also you have to worry about do they
update the variable or not or do they
just return if they just return you need
to
set it back to the variable and also
because
of each column our stack is a you know
it's
there's only one variable represent all
the stacks so when you change any one of
the stack you have to reset the whole
thing back to stacks
so
so me meaning that you have to do
something like this okay set queue
um
set Q stack
uh
by
you cannot do just do this because this
will just return the topmost item of the
column y
so you need to get the whole stack you
know that's why it's cumbersome
with the list because when you have the
whole thing if it's a vector
at least then you change you then you
can just say
uh
yeah then you can say a ref okay
let me show you how it's done okay
okay so you can just say
white stack
to Z stack and here erase your Matrix
okay
you know then you can you can update by
uh something like this okay
set
a ref okay
what's a vector form
so vector
you want to change one element of a
vector a set okay yeah so what do you
what you do is a set
okay your array is your Matrix
a set
push and pop so you want to pop y
push Z
okay
so there are two change pop y push Z
okay so let me
um
comments questions okay
very annoying
[Music]
Okay so
you want to so first of all you push
next to push pop okay
pop
push okay now
set box equals to pop
y
th stack so if it's a vector then would
be a ref
and uh hooray
y okay
so that is the
one box
you pop it up
and uh
and then you want to see
then then you want to push
Xbox into
into a ref
ER Z okay that's how you push and pop
you take one item from
stack y then you
um saying stack
then you
put that item to
the Z column
okay
after you do that you need to
you need to
reset your whole stack
to the new thing so
pop and push
you pop and you push
yeah you pop and you push then
then you changed your Stacks variable
the value
it you know it doesn't change actually
it doesn't change
so therefore you need to
set them
yeah so
okay I don't like you I don't like using
this actually it changes the vector
this bar oh how are you at least it does
I mean but you see we have a vector of
Beast
assuming assuming we have a vector of
least
so when so we are doing pushing and pop
of the
of the list inside the vector
oh it does so so you are saying it does
change the the okay
I I think you are right I think
um
okay you maybe uh yeah maybe you are
right let's try it
but first of all do we want to turn this
into a vector of this I mean turn this
into a vector
at least or not
maybe not
okay let's get let's get it to work
first and let's worry about whatever
later okay let's assume it's just the
least
of least okay
so
so stack is a list of list so now we
need to write this in terms of
least
so nth let's see nth okay and
return the nth element okay
oh and the zero indexed
but
but the number here is one indexed so
you need to minus one
idiotic
uh
yeah you have two minus one so
so okay let's do it
decrement okay
so nth
the nth
you pop it
uh yeah but you cannot sit okay so so
you don't need to set let's assume that
yeah
so you pop the ends
and then you push
yeah you're saying then you push okay so
this
you just
push
this thing that's a new item here you
push it to the
to the Z
list right
and assuming
it does the setting of the variable okay
so let's remove this yeah
let's hope that's maybe that's it
then you have to do this y times let's
let's ignore it for now okay
let's say
so now
we just evaluate this function and let's
test on this function
okay
you know last time I did Wolfram
language and I realized this
when you modify things it's not good for
functional programming let me explain
quickly I want to move on but this is
important because now we want to test if
this function works
however if we run it then call it you
know
with Stacks okay if we call it
with some number uh then it's actually
going to modify this
so when we want to test again we have to
Freshly
set our stack
can we do that yeah
so after each test we have to
reset the stack
uh wait so where does it take value from
Stacks Stacks okay so these two needs to
be combined into one
you know we are writing a lot
inefficient code these two needs to be
combined into one but anyway
so where does the stack okay starting
from here
yeah so yeah
okay so so we will
so okay let's do let's push on so let's
move stack or alternatively you know
what I'm thinking is that you you put
these Stacks as an argument there that
way
you know then you stop using the pop it
you know and stop using push you know
functional programming the whole thing
just returned a whole new
nested list of stacks
then then when you want to repeat you
know the move three you know then you
just reset you know then you can do
choir or do times that way
you know that way it's functional
programming
okay but anyway let's push on with this
okay let's try let's evaluate these
okay move Stacks is there then let's say
uh let's say one two one the input one
two one which moves
D to the first carbon so the First
Column will be D and z
so run it
real number of arguments yeah okay so we
yeah so that's why so because
and okay
copy I mean evaluate run it
D and Z fantastic
fantastic
but that's only column one why does it
just return column one
oh yeah when you do push
so you see this function we don't care
about the return value we just
in you know State manipulation
procedural programming
okay but it works but it works okay
so does that mean we kind of already
solved the problem
yeah then we just need to map
okay let's get
um
uh map map car map C we don't care about
the
you see we want to map to the arc string
for each Arc string we want to split
by wayspace
okay I mean won't snow
okay so this will be the argument then
we just call
move stack
uh then we're gonna splice it
idiotic
let's turn this into at least then
he had this yeah so
the problem here the function takes
three arguments
uh well you can you can but now we have
a list instead so you want to turn a
list into three arguments into here
yeah you can do that but um
it's not
you have to you have to use the reader
markers
like
like this okay
tick
something like that okay splice and very
annoying
you supply oh thank you
this Spa is a this expert I can tell
that's right you supply
uh apply function yes arguments
fantastic
so
um
yeah okay so let's read let's use a pie
okay let's remove that apply
now apply a function yeah the function
is move stacks
okay and uh uh rest arguments
co-function without remaining arguing
with us I guess
using our last August list of box okay
yeah that's right and walk
okay so put that here
now that should work now this this needs
to be a symbol or whatnot
the emac this you have that
pound sign idiocy
I don't like that you know usually I
don't want to add that anyway
ah
so yeah so that yeah so apply
so we don't need that so we
apply oh and we we are still not doing
the
do it n times
it should be here okay so let's add it
here
do it in times okay
this episode
yeah so two times should work two times
count y result we don't care and what
we're gonna do is this okay
and since we are not using that we don't
need the whole lead thing
just now simple
move one box from stack y to stack Z do
it X do it x times Okay so
yeah do it next time so so yeah
so we don't even care about I
can just do this yeah extension okay so
now you don't care about that
that's our function evaluated good now
let's see if this works
Lambda
should work
okay but first of all let's see what
these are you know when we run this if
it's correct then it would be the answer
for the
for the you know for the question so the
answer should be cmy for the sample
input like that CMZ okay
so if we do that
let's see
double check one more time xox string is
that yeah
yeah okay Bennett
run type argument number marker p
oh
so did is two times incorrect
long type of arguments
your own type of arguments
oh we got a string oh yeah
so
so we need to turn string to numbers
yeah we didn't do that
yeah
so okay
okay map
car
why
sequence
uh what wait
it's pretty strange yeah so
map
car
that's a sequence
and let's say y we want to
string two number
string two number y
okay
and it kind of works that kind of okay
like that
okay so let's try again
evaluate evaluate
okay then
then we need to look at our stacks
looks like it's incorrect
m
well okay it's incorrect
CMZ the result should be CMZ
okay
okay so
uh but basically it should work
so let's evaluate the whole thing let's
see what happens okay
and we need a lot clean up you know this
can be combined into one and uh you know
um let's okay
so if we evaluate the whole thing
string two number okay then call move
stack okay
yeah let's evaluate the whole thing okay
and now let's see what is stacks
CMZ
no let's write another function let's
just to get the top boxes okay
so
X
get top
box okay
okay so so yeah okay
so that so that okay given the stack
yeah this time you know
um
yeah so you for each
what is the structure a list of
Beast okay
car so you want to map yeah so you just
map car
and
sequence is stacks
and what you're gonna do well we're just
gonna
call the thing
this this coding car and cutter there it
is
Interactive
okay that's it evaluated then call it
okay then
do that
there it is yeah but then you need to
join string okay
join so at least two strings
I believe the function is just join
these two strings and this this empty
list
length get the element had to release
modify these two string
map contact
there it is
but
number two string
uh yeah nothing we don't need any
function identity now the identity
function is very interesting it exists
in functional programming languages but
not in C C plus plus Java
the identity function is a function that
does nothing you know given arguments it
just return arguments unchanged
so why is it useful it's useful because
when you do functional programming
you need this kind of thing like right
now we are doing you know we want to map
contact
it takes a function name basically
you know apply that function to each
element of the list
so that you know maybe you want to turn
into a string or you want to do some
transformation but in our case our
elements are already a string so we
don't want to do anything
well so that's why you say identity okay
uh then separator empty string okay
so let's run that
oh that oh God then we have that
oh
you know that those things we could you
know those square brackets we could have
removed it earlier
you know when we
when we uh you know
yeah but
no let's just write another function to
remove it
yeah
okay so this actually let's uh put it
here so
let me show you okay so let
something not here
map car
okay uh
oh wait uh
so you get that so what what we have
here so
map car get the top elements then
then you can join as a string
okay
then you join us the string then you can
do stream replace in Rejects
I don't know what is the name
string rejects replace
use it instead a map car
what do you mean it
Oh you mean apply
what
uh
so in yeah so so now we uh
we need to I think you could just
replace map car with map contact
oh I see that's right you are right
so
um
let's see
that's right
fantastic thank you
so map car
map contact that's right the then we do
we get the first element
then we can also inquire yeah let's you
know let's just remove the bracket here
so car
okay then then you do a substring
substring
I think I'm doing what you are saying
right I think so
uh
so the string is that so
the string is for example something like
that so 0 1
two so from
for example let's try it okay
foam
one two two run it m that's correct okay
so that's what we want
Okay so
yeah yeah yeah yeah that's what we want
so just that
return the string okay
okay evaluate it now let's call it
it's
real number of arguments oh
something we forgot
uh what is my contact okay separator
function sequence separator function
sequence separator okay then run it
run it
fantastic
okay then some of the problem number
available code day five number one
the you know the sample problem now
let's try the real input
uh okay so you know so pop this back
clean it you know show in browser so
here is our code Advent of day five at
the event of code day five number one
and now we need to check the real input
check the real input okay so the real
input where is it day five
day five there it is okay
so let's open uh let's open a new one
open that
you know so here is the
the real input 500 lines okay
now copy it you know and we can pop this
out again
let's run the whole thing
just to double check go to the bottom
let's run this yeah CMZ correct so now
we just replace the whole input by the
giant thing all we can do
uh no it's not let's copy the file path
let's do something so let's read
let's read this file okay
then set it to our inputs okay
set
X input
by reading a file of this path okay
and it's showtime like that
so so read the file
so
how do you do um
you can use the temperature and insert
to insert from file there's a function
okay insert from file so let's go back
to emac this reference so you want to
read a file
so there is a um
you go to
practical emac disp
because reading a file is not core of a
functionality of this so there it is oh
that's that's right file so you read a
file
okay insert file contents that's what we
want insert file contents okay yeah so
set input with temp of create a
temporary buffer then insert file
contents okay then the file path will be
that
that okay optional visit no no no no no
no no no
okay
then after we insert the file content we
grab the whole text
because it needs to return okay so
uh buffer string
perfect substring that will work you
know actually there is a
this way or two okay this function
purpose string will return the whole
thing
return the contents of current buffer
string okay so the
Okay so
that will set the input let's try it
run it fantastic now we can you know
describe variable
you can see that variable you know we
got it so close this now just run the
whole file
that should do
okay then the whole file
problem
outside of range
string trim all right let's come from
stream trim okay
copy
I'm gonna see uh
string trim this matching line is okay
stream only happened one time
so
what the is this
build Matrix
okay stop saying boxes just say Matrix
okay
a list of lists
okay so what is the error message
stream hog out of range string stream
so it's trying to trim
substring what do you say
stream pad
substring
[Music]
we take
wait what is odd uh strain trim hog out
of range
so
stream trim
so this substring is giving us arrows I
think
I have very annoying you got this
problem you know
um
this substring is out of range
and
so we printed something there
what happens
so what is what is this doing so build
the Xbox Matrix
so build the Xbox matrix it's building
this Matrix
so do you
um
oh God this is gonna be boring parts so
debug
you know what we should do
is actually clean up the code right now
you know that's a good step to do bring
up the code make things proper rename
variables so we don't have these
you know um
so this is Spill The Matrix so we are
trying to build this
thing
and first of all stream pad
32 is a space here that's idiot extreme
pad
we want to pad it just in case you know
because we are splitting them by every
four characters
we don't want to run out of characters
then X this is near and do you do do we
have like leaked variables or something
what is this X
okay so let's
change that to y y y y y y y
that should be the only occurrence there
yeah
so Lambda y so string pad
number of columns let's see what is the
value of number of columns
what
Waits
number of columns
that's a problem
our number of columns is wrong now what
is the okay let's now let's run them one
by one then okay
first of all input is correct
now the input parts
what is this
uh this is this input no no second copy
that
yeah this is today let's put the input
here okay
now input parts
okay let's go to messages buffer
what
because that
so that's a list of two things okay now
box text that's right that's that
procedure or text okay that's not God
procedure or text that's right yeah
close
now box box is line beast and see what
that is
okay
a list of
um
of the boxes that's correct
okay and number of columns
zero this is incorrect
number of columns okay so number of
columns the way we do it is we take the
last
item
uh
let's see run it yeah so that's the last
line wait
okay we got a problem here let's
the last line
is dropped you know we should get this
one two three four
five two nine so
let's try again
instead we have this NG thing it should
be that
so here is the problem
why is that
do we
now let's look up the input the input
should contain it right
yeah it's there
so let's see
input pods
text yeah it's there box text
box line this okay it's missing here so
that's the problem
so box text
we have the last line
but box lines list
it's gone
okay that's not
oh it's gone because it's dropped here
so again this is a problem a procedural
programming
you know things happen you know they
change state
because here
you know because you drop the line here
but before you drop you need it to get
the columns
so we maybe we um
so let's rerun everything again in order
so when that
the net
uh then what
remember that
procedural text
then box lines list okay so you see you
do have that
then
that
the column is still wrong
so you do have the number
but the column is your room okay so our
code is wrong
box line is least
how
so let's see what are we doing car
last
then speed string
then last in card then stream to number
okay let's evaluate this part
empty string okay let's evaluate that
part empty string let's evaluate that
oh empty string oh yeah idiotic
you need to drop when you split you need
to drop no okay
okay so you need to Omit no or true
yeah
okay there are better ways to do this
but you know
you know we should actually just use a
regular expression
uh actually is it faster no not
necessarily anyway so
if we evaluate these uh loan type of
argument what
oh we got T in the wrong place should be
here
there
okay
there nice now it's good
now this part we don't want and this is
super inefficient
and we don't want it here so this should
be
drop the last item let's forget about
efficiency but but this line is moving
here so
let's do a trick so that e-max highlight
all that
this command is you can see
highlight symbol a point okay
uh and uh okay but we don't we don't
want to drop here okay so here we don't
want to modify it okay
yeah so we
hmm
yeah okay leave it
foreign
so we got the columns
okay now let's just run the whole thing
okay
and the whole thing and please
let's face it works let's run that ah
there is the answer let's check I think
it's correct
d h b j q j c c w
dhbjq jccw we
are good to go we finished
God finally finished
close to two hours okay
Happy New Year
okay uh
now we want to exercise our emac this
muscle
now we want to make this
short concise elegant and the fastest of
all possible it's possible to do that
it doesn't matter if it's a million you
know this input a median Stacks obedient
lines
you know we want to make sure
in fact possibly emacs yeah well
actually
it's possible that emacs can do this
problem
uh faster than any language
is it possible
um
no I'm actually I don't I I don't think
so not not because you know
in some problems it will be possible
because we exploit the emacs ability to
manipulate texting above so when you
have yeah but I'm not sure in this case
congratulations hey thank you thank you
for your help
so what we do now I think that's it you
know so we can
yeah that's it we can yeah we can cling
up and explain
things
uh but perhaps that time would be better
spent you know doing a new advent of
code
you know it will be wider audience uh
easier problems you know so right now we
have turned the Advent of code in wufam
language up to day seven we we didn't
finish day seven we stuck
I know how to solve it but you know but
we we didn't finish in a video
so and there are quite a lot more
calendar
you know so there are 25 problems we
have like more than 10 to go
uh so we can do Wolfram language and
then
we should you know we it would be good
to do emac business so I'm going to do
it every day yeah so
you know it's maybe advantage of a code
maybe some other problem no there's no
hurry you know no hurry yeah so thank
you guys for watching
uh bye guys if you like my stuff buy my
stuff okay go to
saudi.com.org there's no come
and pay me and donate me okay
and uh
condemned 77 if you haven't sent me
email if you haven't got your emacs
tutorial do it okay send me you know
send me your email so I know your email
so I can send it to you okay thank you
guys
bye