check
morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's show today's 2019 on
November 14th 3 o clock in the afternoon
it's time thank you guys for coming and
look at YouTube YouTube got this new
interface you know this is a YouTube
beta I wasn't using this before and it
shows all this junk is streaming URL you
know I don't want this screen to show
but let's pop out the ok that is also
changed and let's stop the video here
can we actually stop it okay stop this
morning bots come on e Alan are you in
night Mart
well I I guess I you know I don't do
much with that I don't know if it's
automatic or is it because my YouTube
said to dark mud I don't think I always
said to talk much so Kathy good morning
long time no see good morning Emily and
what you guys up to so high okay I need
to get on the show you know because I
need to stop like being chatty and stuff
this because this is not this code and
so I need to do something you know show
other people interesting things so what
you guys have a topic good morning is
e-tron do you know about Greg repairmen
yes yes indeed of course everyone knows
that and anyone has any inkling about
math knows that guy because he solved
one of the most most difficult problem
in mathematics that's unsolved for a few
hundred years and he proved it and then
so he got $1,000,000 prize and he turned
it down he said no thank you
this guy actually I talked about that
this guy before a little bit on my
livestream
YouTube you know the video is good now
some of the video is gone so that's how
he looks like so we cannot we talk about
that a bit this is him in groceries so
he lives with his mom
like mom can you go buy some eggs this
is a Russian guy you know he solved one
of the most difficult problems in math
and they are you know they want to give
him the 1 1 million dollars we would
know thank you no I don't want it go
yourself
that's what he says basically to the
mass to the math as establishment you
know the stashed establishment like
Google and Facebook and Twitter modern
establish establishment in other
universities so morningbut
and papa moon papa moon good morning
where you from I forgot so Z Tron crazy
haven't seen you for a while do you see
my link no I don't see your link you
know the light the you know just forget
about posting links you know this
youTube Live Chat is annoying so what
sort of keyboard stole stuff I don't
know any anything but no idea so let's
see so Emily Post keyboard stuff you
know if you find you know if you have
something interesting posted and maybe
your comment on it because you know you
got a lot keyboard stuff so good morning
so in incarnated are you Night Man okay
so morning woken broken good morning to
to to UK United Kingdom
so Aaron says I've been trying to switch
in text mode and oaked Ola tech to see
which a small efficient way to write
I've been trading trying to switch in
text tech mod and o'clock' no use Oh Kai
I pretty much I'm pretty sure Auggie's
better I don't know for sure because I
don't do tech these days anything I
haven't written about yeah of course a
lot you know if you look at at at the
world whatever you know even if you
spend all your day just reading you know
encyclopedias you know it's like you
only know 0.01% of of the things common
artists about or common are turned off
the language for this the language
forest changed a YouTube stream from
common are disabled to comments or
turned off
okay yeah I'm well again I guess that in
this case comments are turned off makes
better sense because you know it means
the author the whoever created YouTube
turned off the comments so you cannot
comment on the other hand if you say
comments are disabled that could mean
because maybe because you know because
whoever is watching a video maybe there
is they said something I turned off the
comments oh well actually you can you
know either
either case either wording could be
ambiguous anyway arrow key stuff okay
let's do that our icky stuff you like to
hand arrows or something no I don't like
to hand an arrow I think I think in
theory should be better but I just don't
like it so I'm using this Kinesis
keyboard so you can see where to a
seedless YouTube the
new YouTube interface disorienting you
know that's why we love our habits we
don't want to change nothing so this
this arrow key this stupid camera okay
so on the Kinesis you have ever left
right on the left hand right left arrows
and also on here you have I need to turn
on my light okay so this is Uptown on
the right hand so you you need both
hands to press the arrows I much prefer
the can inverted T let me turn on the
lights so maybe your baby better so we
already got some random topics going so
okay let's just not talking about the
arrow keys so arrow keys ice I studied
arrow keys for you know for the issue
about arrow keys arrangement now let's
go to where let's go to keyboard okay go
to keyboard keyboard way where is that a
block okay let's go to well there are
several new things to talk about
keyboard very interesting so let's okay
let's get on one by one interesting
keyboard stuff okay arrow keys let's
talk about arrow keys first
so arrow keys you go to design the
design of keyboards everything about
keyboard design the physical layout the
physical the mechanism how it works the
firmware what's its purpose
what kind of firmware are there what
kind of features are there how you
program the keys the interface and so on
so arrow keys let's go to arrow keys
arrow keys now this is a unfinished
article it's kind of unfinished but
anyway but there is great information
there let me show you okay so this
article is fantastic so I have two
articles to show you one of them is this
one it says history of the inverted T
arrow
arrangement on keyboard 1998 by Jim
Burroughs I read this his article before
but I don't remembered not but anyway he
researched all the arrow key
configurations like sometimes you have a
cross like he's got this tiny tiny
graphics he should make it larger so
anyway he researched into arrow key
configurations for example these are the
ones you that occurred in the past
keyboards and also this all the arrows
on one row which is also the case for
vim now let's see which is wyms
let me try to is this is this the same
as whim yeah I think so right
JH I don't I don't remember I have to
because I'm using wrong let's see JK is
JK is uptown so JK is over here
JK's
well yeah I don't remember so that's
that seems to be him is left down up
right okay
so left down up right okay so this so
this is not the same as V so this is V T
100 weight but let's go to the V key
binding so I mean let's go through the
to look at the keyboard where the V key
binding came from
so that means history so we got actually
several things to talk about
hold on a second so let's get that this
this is the computer that V key binding
came from so 1976 at ADM 3a terminal so
now you can see so it's JKL hjkl and
that's left down up right okay so this
is where beams key binding came from you
know because this guy pho pho he one of
the founder of Unix
he later on founded is a co-founder of
Sun Microsystems in some Microsystems
died in 2007 yeah around that year so -
Oracle so Bo joy and he so we you know
so there's history of vim key bindings
so basically the key bindings came from
this keyboard because the the guy Bo
Joey created him on this terminal and he
just you know since there's already our
printed on it just use it and and it
turns out it's pretty good it's very
efficient in arrangement but there's
another question if you want to trace
the history of hims key binding that is
okay so Vince key binding came from this
keyboard but why does this keyboard have
this specific arrow key configuration
now that is explained that is because
okay then you you need to go to this
article the history of Emacs and VI keys
okay
the reason this computer uses this arrow
key arrangement is because it's half of
the reason is it's a it's a hack okay
it's a hack it's not because okay first
of all let me say why how it is not it
is not because someone some some
engineers sit down and and thought about
what's the most efficient then they
decided oh it should be hjkl and it
should be left down up right and that's
not the case okay that's not the case
for most vast majority of things we get
we are used to today but how did that
happen is it so happen is that it
happened so happens that the the ascii
key code there's some kind of synergy or
Cowen's coincidence with the asking key
key code bits you know so you have to
read the article in detail it's how to
explain because i haven't read this this
for a while you have to because it has
to do with a key the binary number you
just drop one bit and and also because
of the ascii key code and somehow that
that is just come in convenient to
convert one to the other so so that is
what hjkl okay if you guys know better
ways to expand if you know history just
type it okay yeah okay so Kathy asked
about kima kima's let's talk about that
okay so because there is someone you see
here hello beautiful people are you here
so he's got that keyboard and another
guy also got that keyboard so we can
look at that later but anyway so we
let's go back to the the arrow key
configuration so so here is the history
of themes key binding okay that's one
thing
history of in ski binding and okay so
that's one thing then now let's go back
to the question of which arrangement is
the most efficient okay so I have two
it's also popular history of so so about
the arrow key configuration one is this
Jim Burroughs article he talked about he
studied the arrow key configurations and
he has found that the inverted T is the
most efficient basically basically what
happens you want to compute the finger
movements you know how frequent you have
to move your fingers and you can see the
cross shape is obviously no good because
you when you want to press left right
left right
there's okay that that works but if you
want to press up down up down your
middle finger kinda have to make a don't
jump and that's a big punishment you
know in school you know how efficient it
is so that's no good
so the cross shape is not good then you
have kind of that way anyway he studied
it the reason is mostly because arrow
key sequences like when you study arrow
key efficiency for the arrangement you
want to so you let's say you begin with
a bunch of random arrow key sequences up
down left left left right of left left
up down left left right you know things
like that like when you play pac-man and
you compute you know finger movement
distance between the various
configurations and it turns out the
inverted arrow is the best so anyway you
can you can go read his article now what
about now in this article he didn't
study the beams
piece and I did that somewhat so on this
article this alcove so I was
specifically trying to determine before
I before I know about his article the
Jimbo Asarco I'm trying to specifically
determine whether inverted T is better
or Vince hjkl so how do you measure it
first of all you need to know the
frequency of the arrow key occurrences
like you lock your keystrokes and after
a month or a year you you know how many
times you press up arrow how many times
you press down arrow and so on for left
and right and you also do this let
assume you do this for everyone you know
so they are let's say when you know what
medium programmers they all have key
dogs so you got a good statistics so you
know the frequency for each arrow key
and okay that's one thing you so I did I
did that I have a frequency in Emacs
basically the previous the up arrow is
used the down down arrow is used most
frequency about seventeen seventeen
percent okay of or Emacs command so
these are yeah so anyway down arrow is
most frequently used then up arrow then
then right arrow then left arrow
basically this is like a ballpark figure
okay so in particular you can see that
the up and down arrows are much more
like three times or four times more
frequently used then left and right
arrows and this this is a ballpark
figure so if you do your own statistics
I think you will find something similar
so first of all you find a frequency
of the arrow keys usage then another
important thing is you want to find if
you have a particular arrangement let's
say let's say V okay hjkl so you want to
find out you want to give a score to how
much it does it cost when you use your
finger to press that specific key for
example you know typically we know that
home row keys are good so they should
score the best and for any key you have
to move your finger that shouldn't go
too high so you give each key score like
either press cool so that's what I did
here so you can see hjkl now K is right
under your middle finger so K should has
a highest score 1 and J J and L J index
index finger so score 0.9 and now is you
know your ring finger that's not so good
so 0.7 and H is a key you have to move
your fingers you know move so that's no
no score and is on top by your index
finger again so you go for each key for
a specific arrangement now you can
assign scores yourself a me of this up
to you to assign a score so once you
have the score information for the ISA
press key information and the command
frequency then you can calculate a score
for this this arrow key arrangement the
higher is better so for example if if
the key youth if the for example the
town arrow is the most frequently used
and if you put down arrow to the key K
then that's the best because K is the
most easy to press so you have Kate you
know multiplied by the number of times
you need to press that so that so that's
kind of how you compute the key score
for arrow key
management efficiency so that sell ice
so once you have you know these numbers
you can come out with a score so I did a
little JavaScript interactive JavaScript
you can you can compute yourself let's
type it here so let's go
let's open in Chrome because I don't
have JavaScript in my in my Firefox so
here is okay so it's here Araki's
efficiency so you go go down so assume
you know you can change these numbers
kiss code to whatever you prefer so if
we assume this is a press call and this
much frequency let's say they are all
press equally frequent then the VI ska
is 31 the inverted T is 34 so it's it's
kind of slightly better so you can
change the score and find find find for
yourself if you agree my logic in
computer computing is the score is good
then you can you know find out okay
that's one thing that's how you measure
that's one of the way to measure the
score for aro qrh arrangement okay
that's just that's just beginning this
this way of measuring the score is kind
of like a heat map you know you want to
find out which key you press the most
often and find out which finger it is
under so this is like the most basic
heat map based then you have to consider
pie graphs diagrams is like for example
if you have inverted arrow if you have
inverted arrow then you have to move
your middle finger a lot up and down so
if if up down up down up down that
happens a lot let's say 90% of the time
you use arrow keys then then your score
will be very low because you are moving
your index finger up down all the time
you know so so the bigram that so that
is for consideration of bigram so so you
know like combination of two keys
present at the same time so when you
consider that then it will track down
Wims arrow key configuration you'll get
much lowest score that's what I found I
don't have a calculator you know to
calculation to do the diagram but you
know you guys can try it so what do you
think Emily what do you think about this
methodology to you know to figure out
which one is better okay so that that is
about the arrow key that's so that's
what I think about you know these so I
have decided this for myself you know
well I I'm pretty sure you know I've
decided that inverted T is just better
than being period okay now this
alternative solution you might think
okay let's move themes hjk out to one
key to the right so you don't have to
move your pointing finger to the to the
left but then the problem is now you
have a pinkie you know why your pinkie
needs to press the right arrow key so
that Y your pinkie is not as you know
powerful as the other three fingers you
know so that is I don't I think you may
even you might get lower score or
something you know similar it's not
going to improve if you move the whole
thing to the right so that's what I
thought about how you compute arrow keys
configuration of efficiency arrow key
layout efficiency now what about what
about the Kinesis for example on the
Kinesis you have like I showed before
you have you have left right on the left
hand and up down on the right hand we
have a we have a you can see
I have a there it is ok so you can see
this this this diagram so I think you
know in this case now you use both your
hands and this you don't need to move
your middle finger like the inverted T
so I think this is this should be
actually more efficient ok because now
the the two most of your strongest
fingers are using you know on the arrows
but but another aspect comes into play
that is intuitiveness you know this is
not so intuitive you know because you
know up-down typically you want it you
know on top and bottom now its side by
side so it's less intuitive and so
anyway in theory I think this should be
more efficient but I just never you know
I still prefer inverted tea you know
I've been using the Kinesis for like 3
years now so I've been using the Kinesis
for 3 years I'm pretty used to it but
you know I would think that the moment I
play pac-man I want to switch back to
the inverted T you know possibly because
habit you know I
because for example because I've never
tried to use this keyboard to play
pac-man but let's say if I do it for
half an hour a day for one week then
perhaps you know I are like this kind of
to two hands approach better
so it's habit is the thing that's that's
a thing killing killing progress in lots
of cases so that's my opinion about this
you know separate arrows on for each
hand
so that one-handed keyboard layout so
Amy says okay so similar things for
designing keyboard layout yeah say so as
many things we normal computer users
adopt inverted T yeah so of course the
university is also adopted by gamers
another interesting thing is that the
gamers they use WASD it's on the right
it's on the left-hand Y on the left-hand
because you know they want the right
hand to use the mouse for most people
they are right-handed so you need more
dexterity that's you know dexterity to
move the mouse so they use right hand to
move the mouse so arrow keys becomes on
the left hand so that's that's the
convention you know so mass majority of
people are used to it you know so but
there are many many interesting issues
about gemma's approach because why WASD
why not say es D F because es D F would
be on the standard typing typing
position touch type position you don't
have to move your left hand left hand
one key to the left Y ASD well because
it's all due to history in my you know
in my observation it's just due to
history why because for gamers they owe
the tip they usually they also need the
caps lock the shift key so let's show a
keyboard that's that show the gameís
keys where is it so let's show this this
one for example
so cameras they also typically they also
needs the caps lock tab shift and the z
x c keys mostly because of the shift and
cap lock because they want to you know
in brain games you want to you want to
have shield you have you want to space
for shooting fire you want to you know
like
lower your body you want to run so so
many of those other keys on left are
useful that is why chemists
you know use WASD instead of ESD F yeah
so I you know I was going to say because
you might have argument about well ESD F
also works because you have the qwa and
other keys around it
no no because the chemists they want the
shift key really I think that's the
that's a key reason actually I have a
key I have a Arco about that so let's go
to a history again let's go to a history
and see history ok not history let's go
through layout oh yeah so one of the
article about history of Emacs and VI
keys ok the history of Emacs keys is a
big history I'm not going to talk about
but basically both Emacs and VI they're
key bindings just came from evolution
from history
not because of design no not design at
all almost no design at all they just
happens it so happens at a time they are
using this list peek keyboard so I have
a huge number of list keyboards you can
see yeah for much things in life they
just happen by history due to evolution
so you can see this bunch of whole bunch
of list keyboards and you know at the
time when Emacs was invented you know
they have this control meta super and
they are using this keyboard keyboard
and they are of a particular shape or
arrangement
and it just it was convenient at the
time so they just pick whatever key was
convenient on this keyboard that is why
so history so and of course this
keyboard I doubt since 1990 so you know
we are stuck with many of the relic
habits stuff
same thing with VI then you have
terminal keys you know in terminal
there's also many interesting things
going on for example right now I'm in a
terminal now as you know if you are a
Linux user you can press what is fresh
start
CFG so anyway in terminal as you know if
you are Linux user you can press ctrl D
to exit so let's try it okay ctrl D you
see I exit my terminal now let's open
another new terminal control D logout ok
new terminal
however control D is not actually a
shortcut you know for example if I type
something yes now I thought you know
suppose I am a new video okay I think
okay I'm done with someone oh you know I
want to exit so ctrl D oops doesn't work
okay our Mac terminal it doesn't do
nothing but I I think on Windows you
might get something like that
okay so let's try it again control the
you know nothing doesn't work so you see
when you press control D it meat needs
to be the beginning of the thing it you
see the reason of that is because
control T is not actually a shortcut
because thirty years ago when you use a
terminal it's actually used to
communicate with some other machines
like I don't know back then you know you
beginning with teletype and something
you know the the point about terminal is
to communicate you type something you
send it across across continent or ocean
so control
is not a shortcut back then you don't
have the concept of shortcut at all
there's no such thing but rather you
have control D which is which is
actually you know a ski one of the ASCII
characters invisible characters that's
control D so that's why so what I'm
saying here my point here is that this
control D thing is actually kind of a
relic you know it's like for new people
you might think oh that's a shortcut but
no it's not actually your shortcut it's
you know it's that's the point I'm
trying to say as you know lots of
history so let's close terminal so let's
get back to my get back a terminal now
okay so that's that's the interesting
interesting things about control D in
terminal and control D is not the only
one you have quite a few others for
example control H control H typically
means delete the previous character you
have control L control C and control Z
okay those are actually or sending or
signals across you know history gets
very complicated but now after 30 years
some of these keys no longer walk you
know actually in fact some of these
signals some of them has become
shortcuts proper shortcuts let me let's
see if I can show an example so if I do
LS right LS shows my screen now let's
say I want to clear the screen okay
so typically you can do that by
traditionally you can do by control L
okay let's press it control L it creates
a swing but actually not really because
you see you you you can scroll back your
old things are there this is how to
explain but basically you know 30 years
ago
when you have terminal you don't have
this you don't have these go back you
know it's you cannot likes go back like
that you just have one fixed bitmap
terminal like you know like the old you
know this VI terminal kind of thing you
just have you cannot scroll back there's
no such thing so that that is like 30 or
40 years ago 40 years ago by now but
today since about 1999 let's say we
don't actually when we use terminal we
still you know it's not actually a
terminal anymore because terminal refers
to a physical device it's a hardware you
see this is actual terminal or sometimes
they call co-ed console okay so let's go
back to history so so these things you
see are actual terminals terminal so
console you know I remember back in 1998
by 1998 the concept of terminal and
console is already gone by 1998 you
don't see your terminal anymore like
these physical terminals so you see by
1998 when it started to do UNIX you
don't have physical you well you see
exists but it's not what you're seeing
in companies you know you don't have
that anymore instead of you have
terminal emulator so this the proper
term for this thing in Mac OS it should
be terminal emulator but that time again
is already face out because people just
go 8 terminals so what I'm saying here
you see that terminal concept has
changed in the past 40 years it change
and change and changed anyway so in
general these these kind of things are
terminals physical device and and in
1998 I remember I spent days or weeks or
month you know trying to figure out what
is the difference between console and
the terminal ok I was you know working
on the so Microsystems hardware back
forty thousand hundred thousand dollars
you know server and so I I want to find
in the official manual like what what's
the exact what what is three or the
debris or difference between a console
and terminal so I spent days at that
time you don't have Wikipedia okay
remember you don't have Wikipedia we so
let's see so today you can actually read
about it in Wikipedia III remember I
read about you know after 20 years I see
oh so this is kind of the difference
between console in terminal
I don't remember what's a detail right
now but basically back then I think
console console refers to this kind of
hardware you know physical hardware with
a screen and monitor that is physically
attached to the computer like part of
the computer that you call console okay
but there's only one terminal is like a
physical device like one of these that
is connected to the computer so you so
you know across buildings or across
offices you know remotely I think that
is the that is the difference you know
in 1970s let's say or 1980s so by 1998
you already don't see that you don't see
physical terminals anymore and of course
you don't have consoles anymore in
general so by 1998 it's already it's by
that time every every time you use you
only use terminal emulators you know on
Linux on UNIX you just use terminal
emulators you so you still don't cover
terminal you call it terminal emulators
nobody calls it terminal you know the
common standard term is terminal
emulators and now it's 20 years after we
just call it terminal you know and and
people have no idea what
what what what it was what it means
people so that is a point I'm trying to
make history changes you know meaning
changes and keyboard shortcut changes
and okay that's that's about that so we
spend actually so we talked about
terminals and stuff a lot today so let's
see Emily so what okay oh that's this
seems to be a good article the history
the fascinating history of WASD okay
let's see let's see Phi the fascinating
history of WASD I think I've seen this
article
I don't know for sure you know because
sometimes you read this article
especially by Camus you cannot be sure
of their accuracy because these schemas
they I mean the modern websites they
just want quick bait you know you you
want to get you want to read an article
from the Greybeards okay they they tell
you the real history of the wasd anyway
so that that would be interesting to
read you know to check you read first
and check their how trust trustworthy is
the article so we talked about terminals
we talked about arrow keys we talked
about history of VI and Emacs keys let's
see what how long have I been talking
captured top moments what the is is
capture top moments so does it say okay
42 three minutes so guys type comments
let's see what we do not have cut talk
next and oh we might just shut down
that's it for today so type your
questions I'm gonna go over the
questions and let me read let me show
you let me show you this polyhedron
thing key mouse track okay let's let's
talk about team key Mouse okay so I
don't have that key Mouse thing but
apparently two people watching my video
they have it okay and one of them one of
the guy hello beautiful people he is
active on this code so Kathy if you
haven't joined this code yet please join
so this is kind of my my my forum so and
there's a lot post and of you guys
interesting people in topics so let's
copy the link and paste it face it
okay
joining us are discord
oh I think Cathy you already here
because I remember I see I seen your
name so anyway so she Mouse yeah so one
of the guy in Germany he has it and he
has shown many photos it's few days ago
this a lot you know you have you you
scroll way back so let me show you what
is the key mouse I mean I guess many of
you don't know what that is
it's where did it go okay
Chema's okay so it's like you know it's
like this keyboard and mouse combined
into one so each of these you can move
around each one actually function as a
mouse plus some models as a trackball so
you so you can move the whole thing as a
mouse either left hand or right hand and
some models you even have a trackball on
top so G so you it's like you have three
Mouse's so he has used it and I got
several videos if you go to my website
you can see the videos it don't show it
doesn't show here because I have
JavaScript off so for me I don't I don't
find this idea interesting because it to
me it's too bulky you know I don't want
pokey things but so to him I so I asked
their opinion you know the guy who has
this that both of them the opinion their
opinion seems to be it's pretty good
okay now if but it's very expensive it's
like 500 dollars plus if you are in
Europe you have to pay taxes or import
fee or whatever so it's gonna be 500 or
more so I wouldn't buy it because you
know if it's very expensive and the idea
of using two giant Kibo is not very
appealing to me but
so he's his opinion I think is it's like
mixed okay he doesn't regret it but if
he's gonna do it again he may not choose
it may or may not that's the that's
that's what I got I think that's that's
his opinion so for me I wouldn't you
know I wouldn't I would rather for
example you buy you buy any one of these
ergonomic keyboard and then you buy a
mouse you know there are many fancy
Mouse today let's show many diverse
designs for example these are typical
okay these are typical gaming mouse many
buttons some of them I have this one it
has like 20 buttons you know or you can
use one of these fancy organ Amma class
if you have mouse problems so that's
that's what I would do I wouldn't you
know do the key mouse thing farces
versus Kinesis is the one of the most
pokey what not actually not you you you
have seen the pictures you have seen my
pictures right but you should know okay
so compared to a normal standard PC
keyboard they are the same size in fact
Kinesis is a bit smaller I mean compared
to the Microsoft Peugeot Kinesis is
significantly smaller you see you see
their size but compared to a normal
standard PC keyboard it's about the same
width but the good thing about Canisius
is that your right hand is right here so
look at my for example you look at my
let's see yeah you look at my right hand
it's it's it's right okay it's right
beside the key key keyboard so as
opposed to as opposed to a standard key
with the arrow keys and number pad so
for a standard keyboard you would you
would you would like move the over here
for the mouse because you have number
pad and arrow keys you know that's the
thing
so the Kinesis is you have a empty space
in the middle so I put my key back there
so it's not it's not pokey actually but
in fact and also Kinesis is super light
but of course if you don't like Nessus
you have you have tons of other
alternative choices you know so but
you're gonna build a somebody is going
to build a this one I crashed my quest
so have you done that yet sure you know
if you have done that show us okay any
other comments or questions well it's
not super big my quest yeah imagine
putting that into backpack yeah that
yeah you don't want to do that yeah
Kinesis is not really portable so if you
want pulled about you know many choices
you know some of these are very portable
and but you but then of course then you
don't have the power shape so and and
emily is going to get this monster this
motor on emily is going to buy this
monster this in fact this this one has
the same size physical size as the
Kinesis you can see a picture
so that's Kinesis and that's Kinesis and
there's more more size comparison so
Kinesis actually smaller than the
Microsoft ago then you have Kinesis and
motrin they have the exact same width
although I mean even though the motor on
looks okay here's another different one
The looks much bokya you know just
by an impression but actually they are
the same size
the motor on is higher of course so
let's seek nice is so Kathy yeah pokey
indeed yes I have been every times okay
my question okay imagine putting that
okay so let's see what else other
comments
fresh dot CFG is deep for quake players
config file that became the basis of
modern 3d can control on PC
ok so Allen says one more thing related
to arrow keys sometimes I press the
arrow keys with modifiers like Control
Alt + Shift with the other hand ok yeah
yeah arrow keys you know in browser
especially in browser it's useful like
like for switching tabs like it depends
on whether you are on Windows or Mac and
also depends on which browser you use
they have this is very annoying super
annoying they have different key
keyboard shortcuts to to switch tabs now
let me actually so let me show you my
fantastic key caps
I mean the the the I programmed this
numerical keypad so so actually can we
show this
okay that is empty I need to fix it so
give me a few seconds
check audio no audio is back now let me
fix the video check video check check
video no good this is okay let me fix it
hold on a second add a new video
remove the old video capture device okay
and this camera this much pixels okay
okay so now you got big picture so OH
but actually I need to show you my
screen so what I'm going to show you is
my how I so this is left tap switch to
the lat the the switch tap forward
backward okay left right left right then
this is magnify okay shrink magnify
shrink then this is going back and forth
so for example I click here then I can
go backward forward backward then this
is select all copy paste this is then
this this this is refresh refresh cross
window open last closed this is new tab
so that's how i program my food keypad
that is not a programmable keypad but I
programmed it via OS so what I was
saying so I was talking about the
keyboard shortcuts to switch tabs in
browser okay so we good here okay so you
can you see I can make my browser you
know
fly and also I have done the same on my
mouse you see these two buttons so left
tab left a black left half light up
light up like that
so very convenient I don't have to move
my hand from mass to keyboard all the
time so it looks like the video got
shrunk this annoying this OSP software
anyway so what I was saying is that the
keyboard shortcut to switch tabs they
are different depending on browser and
also depend depends on OS so for example
you can press ctrl page down to switch
to next step control page up to switch
to previous tab okay
so control up and down or you can press
control tab to switch to next time or
control shift tab to switch back okay so
depends on the browser they use
different chokers and on a Mac it's more
complex so some some browser supports I
think it's also control tab I think let
me try and control tab no it doesn't
work control tab yeah control tab or
control shift tab but some of them use
like like command shift right arrow
command shift left arrow things like
that it's very confusing so and this is
particularly bad if you want to program
a keypad that just do that you know
because then you have to find out which
browser you are in and that feature is
usually not available in any
programmable devices programmable
keyboard or programmable keypad and that
is also typically not available in any
of the
for any operating system based key
mapping software yeah so when when it
comes to you know programming the
keyboard that's a issue because this for
this to work you need to find out find
out what is your current application you
know so and so usually that feature is
not available so instead what you have
instead typically a gaming keyboard or
programmable mouse or keypad you have
profiles so like you have one profile
for Mac it's all your Mac shortcuts if
you're on Windows you switch to a
Windows profile or on Linux you know a
Linux profile things like that so this
is very annoying and this is this is
also has to do with related to Emacs
because you see I programmed my mouse
and keyboard such that it works in in
Emacs too so for example if I mean
browser this too is the left tab left
tab left half okay right up right up
right up left tab laptop right type
MyType okay but now if I'm in Emacs they
should do the same thing they will
switch to previous buffer you know
previous buffer previous buffer next
buffer next next buffer and I can also
do just like browser okay close the
current buffer oops mistake reopen it
okay I can create a new buffer there it
is
close it I can this copy paste also walk
for example this is select Oh sir echo
it also works you know now I press this
to copy you know then I can paste
somewhere it also works in browser so in
order to make that walk across browser
in Emacs you need the same keyboard
shortcut between these two apps in the
same situation like different browsers
so so so so here here
you know so this is one of the intricate
you know the one of the story you run
into when you dig into you know key
bindings key map instance like that so
it is a good thing it is actually a very
very good thing you if you have a
standard set of keyboard shortcut that
works across any app anywhere any OS
that simplifies things a lot not just
not just for normal people but for those
who wants to program your keys you know
but but as you know but but then you
have this bunch of nodes you know for
example Emacs people vim people they say
oh the browser Keys not good you know
the Linux people the tiling window
managers people each person each group
each community each each coat each
cancer they want to create their own
they think it's better so so that is
actually good because because the
standard set of keys are not efficient
like we talked a bit talked before you
know usually for example to control
close the window on Windows is out f4
that's you know many of the standard
keys are not good not efficient in any
way but so my point is you have this
conflict if you stick to standard
keyboard shortcuts you have many
advantages you know across you know any
system but if you have an app that does
you know that tries to be progressive
tries to tries to create something new
that's more efficient you know
throughout the old habit then you also
do have this problem because then it
doesn't work across and and even not
just for normal people but even for
nerds you want to create your key maps
it creates lots of problems like you
know so the so the reason I can prove
Mikey cap key my keypad to working Emacs
is because let me show you because in
Emacs actually set Emacs to use some of
the standard keys for example if I want
to open a new buffer I can press ctrl o
okay
so control oh let me show you my
keystrokes so saw start command log mod
okay so on the left window on this
window you'll see my oh my Emacs key
presses okay oh no second so I can press
arrow keys you can see arrow keys shows
up there now I press ctrl o okay
control oh you see that's opening a file
actually yeah it's asking me of you know
a file path to open so let's cancel that
now if I want to open a new I mean new
buffer new empty buffer so that's ctrl n
so let me do that ctrl n you see a new
buffer so this so I put this so you can
see well I put them in software keys
part of it is inks a ficus somebody
other others are in my personal key
binding so that way that's why my key
cap my key pad works in both Emacs in
browser okay that that's the point I
want to say I think that's about it for
today so Allen says do you have button
to hide everything on your screen and
pretend you okay no I don't have that
actually I don't like that you know like
on Windows you have these I believe it's
control D or was it windows D you just
hide every windows and show the desktop
that usually that's is very annoying to
me because I don't have nothing on my
desktop I don't use you know I don't use
desktop that way on a Mac you have a
similar key right I don't use it so I
don't remember what it is you can let's
see command option down on a Mac you
have a similar it just shows
you're let's see if I I don't have it I
turned it off you know it just basically
hides hide or windows I don't want that
because when that happens sometimes on
Windows I press that bad mistake then I
see no windows so what I like what the
I'm gonna do like you know we are
working you need some either in browser
whatever app you know you need some app
then you know where you are you can do
something you can switch or whatever so
wherever that happens it's very annoying
I don't use that anime wallpapers no I
don't have anime wallpapers I think did
I ever I would you know I would have I
think I think I might have when I was
younger you know but but you know what I
really like actually here's what I do
okay I forgot what's a key to hide oh oh
apps yeah let's see command edge command
edge hides the old the current okay I
don't remember command option edge okay
then you have command option edge I
don't do that let's try it come on edge
okay
it's always anyway so my desktop is like
let's see if I hide that I cannot hide
this because well I can make it you know
the desktop I prefer is just one color
gray gray and black Oh black I've been
doing that for like past 10 years but
you know I get now I started to get lazy
and you know I thought you know some
picture is okay because I am still you
know it's like I live I live in oops I
don't want to show this whatever is is
this this is Emily's keyboard
development history
I read that we talked about that last
time in anyway so what I want to yeah I
hate
I hate it when all the windows went away
because then I had to reopen each one so
I I don't like the the virtual space
either that never use it turn them off I
just want one screen it's already
virtual by the way it sorry
you can you can press a key to show any
app you want just by a single key press
I'm not doing that because I don't have
enough keys you see even even with all
my settings I don't have enough keys let
me show you where so you see one thing I
knowing about the Canisius is that they
got these function keys as tiny you know
tiny buttons they are actually still
mechanical keys now I'm not sure what
happens if I press them let's try did
press this so but it's it's inconvenient
to press you know tiny little buttons so
that killed about 12 keys for me so
that's very annoying so even I got the
keypad but still I don't have enough
kids otherwise if I do have the function
keys you know before I use this keyboard
then usually 1 2 3 4 f5 to f8 f5 f6 f7
8f a that those four are switching
applications so press f8 you are in
Emacs press f7 you are in browser you
know and f5 is terminal doesn't matter
where you are just by muscle memory like
you don't have to look by muscle memory
you can hit a key then you are in the in
the proper app you want supposed to now
another idiocy in key shortcut is this
you know that's what people typically do
on Windows in our Mac that you have to
look where am i oh I want to this time I
want to switch my oops I passed it okay
let me do it again okay this okay now I
want to disturb to press for time this
is idiocy okay never use that same thing
never use that so if you have F key F
you know F key set F 5 6 7 8 2 2 the
apps you use
often now because I don't have F keys so
but I do have one option like what I do
is I have let me show this again so I
have this key on Kinesis this is
originally page down but I programmed
that just to switch to the last app okay
whichever is the last app I mean because
when you switch app if you took key log
on switching you know if you do Killa
record your keys you will find that of
all the times you switch windows or
applications
I think 70% of tenth of the time is to
switch to the last app or last window
whatever it is so once you have this key
that saves you lots of the switching app
you know need so that's what I have
so I okay I think that's it for today
let's see what any more comments I've
been getting sticky keys yes I like I
think that's a great idea but I don't
have it on right now
because because what I found is that
sometimes it's stuck let's I have I had
that experience on Linux I think on the
Mac - and I think on Windows - sometimes
the shift you know when you are pressing
when you have sticky key on sometimes
you know because of a bug or something
you know some of the control auto shift
they stuck and you are not aware of it
so that when that happens that's a pain
so rent so I don't have it on you you
buy me one
every vine vine was sent to us a ok I
think that's it for today I think I
missed some questions did I miss some
questions how long I've been talking one
hour in time
it's okay yeah I think that's it for
today so let's let's shut down let's if
no more questions we shut down in one
minute now I'm going to go back to check
if we got any questions ok yeah that's
it
smash like and click subscribe click
notification bail ok show and so we shut
down in one minute one minute
thank you guys if you like my things
buy my things okay I got patreon I got
PayPal I got Amazon giftcard on my
website you know where to go okay sorry
dot info and I want to say I should do
some marketing you know my cleaning of
myself actually let me show you this
polyhedron this is fantastic
okay it's written in JavaScript I went
to visit this professor mathematician
friend in UC Berkeley yesterday so he
came from Germany he is visiting his son
it's okay so opening from okay yeah
opening from okay so let's open open
this polyhedron application so this is
in written in JavaScript it's easily
done you can do it in one hour so I'm
thinking some day I'm gonna do a
tutorial on this you know I'm gonna show
you how to do this now right now it's
you're showing just wireframe but you
can also do it so that it shows in you
know opaque which is you know
transparency so you can see both front
and back so you can clearly tell which
is back octahedron so this is in
JavaScript and it's pretty simple okay
we can
I can show you we can do a tutorial on
that so here is the actual code and here
is the JavaScript script code which is
200 lines so we are doing this because
well because because I'm helping them
professor richard parlays and the
professor Hermann Kasia they are great
differential geometries okay they are
you know the top differential geometry
they are retired they been retired for
like 10 or 20 years they co2 lectures
sometimes by anyway so they teach me
math and I'm helping them to some of
these you know write programs for it
they they actually also they also code
so they they wrote these 3d extra math
application but anyway so this is why
I'm doing this so yeah so you know
polyhedra is very interesting especially
you know for programmers so if you are
interested so if you guys you know I got
people ask me asking me about what
project to do so polyhedra
let me tell you guys this is the most
popular project you can try to work on
if you like graphics if you like in
particular if you like computational
geometry and this is visual you know so
you you can write this in JavaScript or
pick your favorite for a mean language
and use whatever graphics library to do
it this is very fun to do so that that
would be a great programming project but
are you interested it you might do that
bye guys yeah so Cody he drone let's see
what else
bye guys yeah that's it my me noob nunu
my ass no you can do it I'm pretty sure
it's see very easy you yeah it's well
you know for for a beginner of course
you have to take some time but you know
it's only two hundred lines of code but
like it's only this one for example only
200 lines of a code and so even if you
are beginner if you persist you can find
out you can figure it out
discord after party okay bye