welcome to another episode of sun talk
show today's 2021 May 31st the last day
of May 2021.
and today we are going to do random so
first 10 minutes or 20 minutes or
something I'm going to do uh emacs this
live coding okay essentially emacs
workflow so you are going to watch my
emacs workflow so let's
let's begin okay so let's go to notes uh
if you have questions comments you know
Post in the chat box chat box post
already post now okay so I can answer
them later
so I want to do some emacs uh first of
all some emacs workflow then we're gonna
talk about random so my
um
my
my keyboard my my keyboard uh my
keyboard blog math blog a bunch of blogs
so keyboard programming uh web dev math
Emax okay lots of things lots of
interesting things
keyboard you know um okay you know I you
know when I look at this my pages I'm
gonna start I want to start to talk
about them now
so uh of course first of all actually go
to appearances and magnify magnify 100
so you can see better okay so
so where do I begin okay so emacs let's
let's do some emacs okay when people
comes in then let's talk about random so
I want to do some emac stuff uh so you
are
the benefit of you Watchers is the is
look at my emacs workflow
okay so let's see what I want to do so
HTML delete tagpayer add to web page
okay that's one of the things I want to
do okay so let's see so let's begin to
do that okay uh
so let's copy that line delete go to my
emacs blog this is uh on the pink window
you can see the commands so open open
file fast from a bookmark so that's how
I arrived at my emacs box switch to the
browser then okay go to the top search
for section and add a new section paste
it here
delete the
Allied line so there it is so this is
the command I need to create a new web
page in my emacs blog for this command
okay what does this command do I did a
video a few weeks ago talking about that
look watch okay watch my screen you'll
see what does this command do so I have
a web page I press the key you see that
P tag is good you see done done done
done done
you see essentially it deletes whatever
tag is uh previous to the courses okay
so this is a very useful command if you
work in browser if you're working HTML
for example do it again you see this
code section okay let's show in browser
okay you see
you see that side HTML D tag pair so
that you see you see it's red because of
this code tag if I don't want the
contact I just press the key and it's
gone so that command is not delete tag
player very useful so I want to uh
create a web page for it for example
what do you mean by web page so go to
Kasai emacs tutorial and you go to okay
let's not let you go to the bottom there
is a entire section on HTML
uh you know those with the rocket sign
means it's a customized super convenient
efficient commands
so there's a section on HTML so you see
this whole section so I need to add
basically a add a page here so
so first of all I need to choose a place
but I can worry about that later you
know like which which position I want to
add a new
um new thing so this is about delete tag
pair okay so insert hack insta HTML tag
add paragraph tag Okay add it after add
paragraph tag okay so click on ADD
paragraph tag you see so we are going to
have a page similar to similar to this
okay so copy that copy that URL so let
me show you the you know the beginning
of my workflow actually so let's magnify
this so okay so you can see so paste it
here make a link copy the line paste the
line okay so we have two identical lines
now change the second line to a new name
so this will be emac HTML delete tag
okay
and the Emax HTML delete
tags okay
capitalize
the every word of the first sentence
okay so now if I put a cruiser here
enter the page doesn't exist so I have
another convenient command which is
called Kasa
copy HTML by link okay do it it will
copy this file to the next line whatever
you know the link so now if I press
enter you see it it's it opens that and
when you open that it's the content is
is exactly the same as the previous file
so I just open the file and go to the
xrd date and update the date so this is
a new one so you can see now it's a 2021
May 31st
so this is old refresh you see it's new
now the content part just basically did
the whole content part okay
delete refresh okay that's what we want
that's a template now
now okay I want to start to add the
content the content gonna be this part
okay go here go here go here paste it so
say this is a useful command this is a
command
here is a command
to delete tag pairs
to delete HTML tag
pairs okay then create a emac this
Source block that is that okay then we
need the code so I need now to get into
the code of this commands so what do you
do copy that describe function paste the
function name enter so emac shows you
the inline documentation for this code
HTML DD tagpayer then tap jump to the
source code there is the source code
magnify so here is the source code
now let's look at the source code do I
does this source code require other code
because if it requires other code I have
to say it on my web page I don't think
it does okay so let's double check
okay you need a sgml mod okay require
HTML mod so let's see what else
do do do do do do okay I don't think it
needs anything else so copy it copy it
then close it
so now we are back in the page
now paste in the Emax block showing
browser there it is
now
press the key to purify it refresh
showing browser so you can see its
syntax colored now there's one more
thing now every time I write the command
I need to add a UI out so when for
example when you copy this code and put
in your init so you can use this code
then
when you do describe function let's see
describe function okay describe function
we just did before so here's the
documentation and I want the URL here so
people can click it and go to the web
page go to my web page and so possibly
there's new update you know so I put a
date
you see the version date so people can
update
you know of course
of course uh alternatively you can put
on GitHub so you know people can
automatically update and this this
command is part of the
HTML mod so that is on webpage that is
on GitHub
okay so anyway
so we have so now we have the code but
now we need to add a URL so so we need
to delete the whole section here so
actually so press the key
to show the code to move the code
outside delete it we don't need it okay
so now we go back to the code
first of all we need to copy the URL of
this page so press the key done now go
to the code describe function
that okay jump to the code again then
put the version here okay now this is
how you do
uh let me show you okay
this is how you do markup in emacs
so when you when people do describe
function it'll show a link and people
can click on the link so now since we
added this we need to change the update
date so press the key now we got today's
date now we need to evaluate this
function
okay so press the key that's evaluated
now describe function again
you can see here's a function and
okay
fact the fact that emacs fact the
Alan McKenzie thing you see
this used to show a link this you see
this syntax you used to show a link but
now it becomes curly quote because the
Adam McKenzie one of the emacs
dev he he made it that way okay
so anyway so let me show you okay what
let me show you that that's a digression
let me show you what I'm talking about
so you go to emac this tutorial
practical iMac beasts and you scroll
down then you can see a dark screen
dark string markup so on this page I
show you how do you markup document uh
emacs inline dark string so if you want
UIL this is what you have to do
but now the atom McKenzie you know
created some
in emacs now now it's not showing
the link because because normally I can
just put a cruiser on here and press
enter and because this is supposed to be
a URL so this is the first time I
noticed this
um
so when did it change emacs 27 oh
oh should it could it be earlier I don't
know so I mean so this is a new thing I
I just found out that's a very annoying
super annoying
okay anyway so now we added the UI I I
have to fix it because that means all my
code you know all my code the link the
URL whenever there's a URL now it's
wrong so for example let's search for
URL okay uh
for example here is another function
this function is side size HTML in code
Ampersand region okay now copy that
describe function
show oh okay so it it shows a UI out
here so you can press enter you see it
opens the website
so what so why is it uh the thing we
just added not oh oh I made a mistake
that yeah sorry my mistake
uh okay my mistake there's no you see
that colon there's no that colon okay I
added an extra colon okay the code
describe function site HTML DD tagpayer
show it there it is there is there is
the URL so you can click it it's not fun
because I haven't uploaded the page yet
okay close it
anyway so here's a function what we want
we want okay copy it now go to this URL
page locally go back to it paste the
emacs code emac this code here showing
browser back to emacs qualify it showing
browser that's what we want okay now it
says here is the command now Edge the
here is not capitalized we need to
capitalize the first letter of a
sentence so do it done
okay let's double check what else
refresh what else is there something we
need to change okay this part we need to
delete so go down here delete that
refresh okay
that's it we have just created a new
page
of these very useful functions so other
people you know maybe emac users they
search online how do you delete the tag
so here is uh one way there are many
ways okay there are many different HTML
tml mods that uh support that function
or you know you can get them on mailbox
this is this is mine okay I find this uh
you know once you know emac based for
you know I've been coding emac this for
15 years but once you know it fairly
well let's say two years you uh
oftentimes you it's easier it's easier
for you actually just to code what you
want instead of looking at other people
you know trying to find other people's
code and find out how they you know what
what is how do you use them
so anyway so here is my code and now
there's uh remember we need to add it to
the to the navigation box
so it should be added to uh there's a
section HD on HTML
here HTML section we need to add it
after the add paragraph tags
fuzzy thank you again fuzzing
uh for five dollars uh hi guys FMS wack
one said something okay so okay so far
so good so now let's continue working on
this so let's search for add paragraph
tags so here you see compare
you see these add paragraph tags this
navigation box that correspond to this
this part okay in the code so I'm going
to copy these two lines
okay and I'm going to call XA find
replace text you can see in the pink
window because I find replace text okay
what do you want to find I want to find
these two lines and what do you want to
replace
okay cancel we want to replace a new
line let me show you okay so copy the
URL of this copy the file path of this
buffer paste it here so you see this is
a just the new file we just created
press the button now it becomes the
least an older list okay now delete the
tags you know remove the URL now we want
to say uh let's see DD tags okay let's
just say name it DD tags okay so we want
to add this new
least item in the ordered list okay so
cut that
okay now cook saw find text
saw find replace text again that's a
package by the way you can use it uh
it's our mempa so go to the previous so
I want to find this string it's magnify
okay
magnify so you can see okay you can see
the bottom okay I guess you anyway so
this this is a fine string such string
enter
what's a replace string replace string
is we want to remember add a line so you
see this line we just added
okay
uh yeah do that
now which directory use this directory
yes
uh what about file path regular
expression okay or HTML files yes write
changes to file yes fixed case in search
yes fixed case in replacement yes
make backup yes okay it's all done so
magnify so you can see here's all the
changes you can move the cruiser press
up Arrow or down arrow to it and press
enter you open the file
and you can see the changed position you
see here so
you see there are so many changes you
know uh
okay close it close move the cruiser
here close it close it expand window and
now show in browser again we back to
this page and if we go down
you see DD tags that's new now if you
click on ADD paragraph tags and you go
down
you can see there you see so we added
this new list item in all the navigation
panels of my emacs tutorial that's what
we want okay showing browser again
okay final check is this page okay here
is a command to delete HTML tag pairs
yeah that that's right that's right
that's right and the
and uh
um you you know I might need to mention
that you need H you need the sgml mod
now sgml mod is part of the
it's building in Emax
and the Emax default HTML mod is based
on sgml mod in other words whenever you
use HTML mod in emacs that automatically
loads HTML mod but
my question is if you call HTML function
without requiring without loading it
does emacs automatically loaded I'm not
sure so
so it's best to actually
explicitly say require HTML okay so
let's do that so now I want to go to my
HTML mod
so here's a HTML mod go to it okay go to
the top
s g uh sgml you see this required
statement copy it close it close it now
back to the page we want to add
there it is okay so now you can see
require okay okay
that's it now
copy the URL of this page this buffer
copy the file path of this vertical
buffer again you can see all my commands
on the left window you see there on the
Ping window okay so copy the path file
path close it now we are back in my
emacs uh blog so
uh so what I want to do is
um
paste that okay
make a link make a paragraph
this is new okay now we don't need this
part anymore okay showing browser there
it is new okay now one more thing I need
to add to the
s to the RSS feed web feed Okay so
okay so I'm just going to do it uh so
here there it is this is just a XML file
it just adds this block by this command
again I have so many customized commands
saw atom new entry that automatically
grab my blog page and insert an entry
into the web feed page you can see
this is a web feed page because if we go
to diet you can see the file name here
okay close that so here is the new entry
just added that's fantastic that's
perfect you know
okay close it close it show in browser
back to here now to Powershell
Powershell I want to sync
okay I'm gonna sync to my server now
let's see what's a comment Good morning
George good morning sweet Abby good
morning guys hey George what's up
okay so you know
so basically we are done with that
um and that takes 22 minutes you know
codeine takes a lot of time and uh you
know so you are looking at my keyboard
let's no I'm going to type password so I
don't want to show you know
me typing password so let's switch it to
my face
before we do that again I need to
mention as the you know you are looking
at some keyboard box so you are looking
at my keyboards this one is kinesis
Advantage 2. go to it okay search search
exotic you know search for my page and
read the reviews and buy it it's
fantastic okay and the other one is
Ultimate hacking keyboard okay here I
have full review here full review uh you
know
I'm using the ultimate hack ultimate
hacking keyboard as a macro pad yeah why
don't I show you before I show my face
you see this is the previous window okay
previous window is the most used command
and okay let me talk about keyboard so
let's switch topic you know normally
what you do is you alt tab let me show
you
old tab it means you see this everyone
is familiar with this old tab old tab
tab you have to hold it you see you have
to hold it no it's like where which
which window am I oh oh I passed it
oh I need now I need to press shift
shift
okay go back there that's one up
way okay
so don't you know so so what I'm saying
is that this old tab is very inefficient
it's not good okay first of all you have
to hold a key that's not good then
secondly it's two keys now I'm using a
fantastic Batman keyboard but normally
uh no more keyboard tab is over here so
you have you have two old you have two
like old then tab or or with you know
that's not good so first of all the
fingering key position is no good
secondly the way you have to hold and
you have to like like spend brain Cycles
to look at which one you is it you want
that's not good you don't want any you
when you know window sucks in this way
it requires you to do this often you
don't want that so the most efficient is
uh one single key press okay so the most
used when you switch Windows what is the
most used command the most used command
is switch to last window because that's
the one you use the most often doesn't
matter which application you are
currently for example right now I'm in
my EC in my um
uh you know the YouTube chat right and
supposed to now I go back to emacs and
and you know I type something
something and I want to look at you know
press one key back to chat so that
switch to last window is the most
frequently used command so it's good
it's very efficient to have one single
key you know assign a key to it but
which key to use that depends on your
keyboard okay so I have this my fancy
setup so I have this extra
macro pads so that's what I use but if
you only have Kinesis Kinesis keyboard
doesn't have that many keys you know
this function function keys are no good
too small and no gaps you cannot just
press it by muscle memory because you
have to look again this is a situation
you have to look because there are so
many small function keys adjacent to
each other so that's not good that's so
that's one of the flaw of the Kinesis
Advantage too but in general this is the
best one of the best okay that's why I
choose as my main keyboard
so so depends on your keyboard and
that's again that's an another reason
you know many of you guys like the 30
okay uh you know many of you guys
like the 30 crap
you know this this this this 30 40 crap
because they they it's it's all chords
your spider fingers
okay so that's so that so that's uh um
so that so so I'm showing you the macro
pack pad you know features of the
ultimate hacking keyboard you can you
can set this uh light to whatever you
like
uh for example
uh let's see let me show you okay
ultimate hacking keyboard got the
greatest software the most easy to use
and the most powerful uh software to uh
to um
two let's see where am I here to change
two remap keys or to create macro Keys
macro key sequences for example this is
what I use right now you see
you see so this one is a you see a tab
you know switch to last window okay then
you have copy URL let me show you a copy
URL okay which is this key for example
if I'm on this page
do it yourself keyboards and I want to I
need to get the URL for this page you
know what do you do normally you
normally do control L okay to move the
focus into the URL field then you Ctrl C
to copy it then you alt tab to go back
to wherever take your text editor then
you you know Ctrl V to paste it you see
now I just paste it
no so so and and I want to make this URL
so what I do uh I do this okay so you
see doing undo so you see this is a URL
and this URL is kind of usually got
issues because this is UI also it's not
just a fire path
uh you know for uh okay I'm digressing a
lot because I'm trying to cover lots of
things normally this is the file path
but if it's on a website it's on browser
you know here's a spec for you final
path for a URL uh in url format
but anyway I want where if I want to
switch this to an actual URL on my
website you see this is a local file so
I can do I can do just I can just press
a few Keys uh what oh wait
you see press the two key three keys
okay you see and this will work on that
as well press three keys you see and now
I have the URL but anyway I digressed so
I'm talking about how do you copy the
URL
with one single key press okay for
example I want I want to show people
this stack tile okay so I what I do you
see this key so look
then URL is copied I don't have to
control L Ctrl C you know so now its URL
is copied one more key back to emacs
right now in this case I need to switch
to Discord okay what do I do do I oh
this code which one is it oh oh wait oh
God God it's too small this one
idiocy okay don't do that
so I want to switch to this code press
one key you see I want to switch to
emacs that key I want to switch to edge
browser that key I want to switch to
YouTube the Google Chrome Empire that
key
you see okay so that key is currently
having a problem because
I'm not going to explain okay but that's
a that's a Windows issue by the way that
Windows issue I happened to have
written a an account of it on my
keyboard blog if you just go to keyboard
blog you will see the windows tax
taskbar which is idiotic in so many ways
anyway
you see so
I guess I'm you know in the past five
minutes I explained about the old tab
problem about how do you switch you know
the optimal way to switch to
um
to Applications okay so you see right
now I'm on
okay anyway so let's now
let's now I want to okay so let's go
back to so I am showing you my ultimate
hacking keyboard right I mean the okay
close the agent I don't need it anymore
uh I want to type my password so now
it's a Time
you see the man who is talking
okay so I'm gonna second
Tangled wires okay so hold on a second
I don't want to show my whole room
I want the narrow angle webcam I don't
want a wide angle webcam
okay something like that is
okay so there you go hi guys today we
have it we talked I talked about for uh
30 minutes uh you know time flies uh we
haven't done much
so let's take a break uh it's safety
okay
today's drink is tea
so that's about emacs you know command
and workflow and then then
comments questions comments
okay now now let's go back to the yeah
so I'm going to
so there you see it's synced to my
website okay now if you go to Chrome for
example open a new page uh emacs okay
Saudi emx
and go to it practical emacs tutorial go
to my blog
let's see my blog let's magnify go to my
blog
there it is 2021 May 31st
emacs HTML delete tags
there it is fantastic we just added this
today and you can see it's part of the
you see the navigation bar here
okay so that's it that's it yeah should
is there anything else
I have actually I have a lot uh good
morning but I have a lot of things to
cover you know
you know uh you know so many so many
things to do like more more than um
topic notes so you know you see I was
planning to do the unit code
you know like I have so many items to do
and these items I put here because they
they are suitable when doing them online
like you know what it like saw talk show
I do some work that's useful to me
meanwhile I will be also a good topic
for uh talk show
and so I have some so many of them and
each one each time I thought you know
today I'm gonna cover these five
in one hour but often just cover one of
them takes you know 20 minutes so we did
one of them today that takes 20 minutes
but I have so many
um others I can do actually yeah should
we should we okay what's a you guys have
to tell me what's the next topic should
we do another emacs or should we talk
about keyboards because uh this is
there's tons of things to talk about
keyboard okay
yeah let's talk about keyboard then
because as the you know because I do
emacs almost every in every one of my
talk show so is there any questions for
me let's magnify okay
uh greetings greetings by the way
because uh foot pedal for Kinesis okay
by the way we saw foot pedal so what do
you mean I have I did a review of that
and oh there's also a web page of that
on my website
so did you okay the name you got my name
wrong so it's not highlighted it's Saudi
you have to type the whole
line B okay I think did you have issues
with emacs when transitioning from Mac
OS to Windows 10 no not at all like no
zero need zero so I don't know if you
watched one of my episodes about two
months ago two or three months ago where
I talk about Windows emacs and windows
configuration that episode is complete
you know the the full hour is talking
about how do you set up things on
Windows and basically this the the the
the gist is that on Windows and Mac on
Linux emacs is the same so there's no
issue I don't know some people say that
emac has issue on Windows not really it
it is true that emacs on Windows is
slower than emacs on Linux
but anyway there's no issues okay I
don't find any issues
um
so anyway you uh so you know you whoever
are watching this you you you you want
to watch that one okay to about three
months ago uh emacs configuration for
Windows okay
you know doing video is kind of funny
because
um
how shall I say you know it's like a
Blog you know it's actually it's a human
um
it's a
it's a it's a right of passage you know
it's just a
you know what I'm trying to say is that
you might think that when when you write
an article a Blog for example you know
you study some issue uh you study in
depth for example today I you know I I
wrote a article about how to delete tags
in emacs
so ideally you write article on some
subject you might think okay because you
spend so much time you are basically
become an expert on that so you write
about it so you let other people know
and put on the publish it
uh for the public to see so that anytime
when the public have a question which is
the same topic they can see your page
and they can see oh that's how you do it
they got the answer
but it turns out that's not really the
case okay
there are two reasons for that
the first reason is that it depends on
how you write the blog okay so now we
are talking about kind of randomish
about some other topic a kind of a
related to social kind of social
um stuff okay
so so so when you write an article you
have to pay attention I'm just giving
you a summary okay you have to write
write it in your style
so anyway when you write a blog or what
a website a blog or article or essay
there are kind of two Styles one is blog
blogging okay blogging
do not write it in that style because if
you write it in a blog style like oh
today I woke up and I found this problem
Oh but I thought you know because I know
C uh I'm familiar with that problem but
it turns out it's not the case uh then I
recently I learned Haskell because I saw
on Hacker News has got something I
thought you can do it with Haskell it
turns out yes you can but there's this
issue then I solve it this way okay
that's a Blog Style
writing okay
if you want your
article or whatever you wrote to be
permanent that style is no good that
style after a month after year it will
be dead it'll be dead okay
so instead of it
but it has used uses okay it has a very
useful black star has its uh purpose
okay but anyway it when you write
something in a blog style it's not going
to last long you want to write in a
Exposition or essay independent essay
Exposition or uh the best example is
Wikipedia articles you see Wikipedia
articles each article
it's
one of the most important thing is that
it's independent like you don't have to
read this this prerequisite like math
books or any uh you know you essentially
it tries at least tries the best it can
encyclopedia style to to cover the
entire thing independently
you know as much as possible that is a
style that has more uh that's likely to
be more permanent of course it also
depends on your writing skill your
knowledge about the topic and you know
your technical writing skill or your
essay you know creative writing skill
depending on the topic if it's
programming language then it's technical
uh uh I mean technical writing okay
so anyway but so
you could you know we we could say there
are two Styles black style and
encyclopedia style the if you write in
encyclopedia style it's more permanent
okay that's one thing now given that
even if you know that
you know it's not easy to write in an
encyclopedia style because you know if
you are an average coder
when you write a uh you don't
um am I digressing
like
okay I just happened to see this
question one of the questions hacks I've
been enjoying your video on mythical a
lot when will you grace us with your
take on emacs hack calculator emacs the
promise Mathematica that sucks that
sucks donkey ass okay my advice is never
ever use it emacs hack
in summary let me finish I was what I
was talking about before writing styles
encyclopedia Style versus block style
okay that's one thing if the first point
I want to make is that if you want your
writing to be more more permanent try
the encyclopedia style okay that's my
first point now even if you know that of
course not you know writing something
encyclopedia style is much harder
because then writing blog is actually
more easy first of all you don't have a
goal because writing a Blog web blog
that's the origin of the word blog web
blog
started around 2003 2005 by programmers
you know it's a web blog it's web log
it's it's like it's like a Diaries you
know what you did today oh I woke up
today you know it's like you know you
can just start writing non-stop you
don't have to stop and think that's blog
you know just like a diary there's no
like you don't have to conform to a
certain style you don't have to uh
achieve certain quality you know you
just write it for yourself blog diary
that's the nature of block so writing
blog is fairly easy okay
comparatively easy of course a lot of
people especially today's generation the
millennial generation idiots they don't
even know they they don't they are
incapable incapable of writing a Blog
they are incapable of writing period
they can do videos you know
thoughts or the team team poor the idiot
very very bad part talking about
politics talking talking about memes
memes memes so idiot they they
they don't know how to they are in cable
incapable of writing and they are also
incapable of thinking
so anyway I digressed again so writing
blog versus writing uh okay first of all
so so
repetitors I think that's uh I think
that's a flaw I have
but the the advantage of being
repetitive repetitors is that I do that
because I want I really want to uh
Express certain points to you you know
so you can
um you know get you can learn it from it
hopefully
so anyway
even if you decided you want to write an
essay style so there are other issues
okay it's not just like oh I want my
writing to be permanent therefore let me
try to write the encyclopedia style and
that's it that's not really because
first of all it's hard it's much much
harder it's much much harder it's gonna
be 10 times more uh requires the time to
spend to write a encyclopedia style
writing second second second secondly
even if even if you know you are let's
say you are a professor you are let's
say you are a professor of of computer
science and you write about algorithms
let's say you uh with python or email
like this or whatever or any other
language even if you are the you know
the most knowledgeable person about some
topic you write it
encyclopedia style and you publish it
online
you are not going to get any much
traffic neither
because Google Google Facebook Twitter
and the millennial generation idiots
they made it that way so today even you
have the best article
you publish it nobody you know you could
you get no traffic unless you started to
become a professional in SEO in how to
do the how to do the spam you know how
to how to get on social network social
network expert the millennial generation
idiots
they made it that way
they collectively they they don't even
know I mean it's they are that way
because Google Facebook Twitter for Chan
educated them to be that way
so so they are that way they they don't
know what they think they're doing they
you know and they think they are good
millennial generation beginning that's
the beginning
so so even even if you are expert you
write an article you you publish it
today you are not going to get much
traffic because first of all there's
Wikipedia
you know this millennial generation
they saw your article they
just copy and paste your your article
from it and reword it reward it and
they'll put it on Wikipedia that's what
that's how that's what happened to lots
of my uh my article articles too
especially if they don't like you uh you
know in emacs community it happens a lot
too
um so that's anyway so I kind of
digressed um
so back to the topic yeah so I was
saying writing a Blog versus writing an
article and also
um
so it tends to all be ephemeral anyway
so I'm kind of digressing a lot so
there's a question about
emacs calculator
so I guess I'm going to
um
yeah Emax calculator let me talk about
that and that that'll be it for today
okay
are you still here Kyo Thomas Geo Thomas
are you still here
so emacs calculator don't use it okay my
recommendation is don't do not ever use
emacs okay so let me show you what emacs
hack is okay so first of all show the
Ping window
calc okay now we are in the Emax
calculator okay I don't know if you can
see well magnify so three enter two
enter plus the result is five and you
can do you can do Vector uh you can do
vectors okay okay I don't have the
yeah you know
um
three four
five I I suppose I never used it
how do you do vectors
yeah I never used it good I don't
recommend it okay
now emacs is one of the best
technology the best calculator
since 1980s okay uh yes I believe 1980s
at the time it's the best software
for doing uh mathematics not just a
calculator but RPM notation reverse
polish notation
if you use HP calculators you know what
I mean I'm not going to explain it is
another you know it's like the fourth
language it's based on Stacks okay so if
you want to do if you want to do
three plus two you say three okay first
of all let me let me get out of this
side I don't use it so I don't even know
let's do it let's start again
so if you want to calculate 3 plus 2 use
you type 3 then you press you type 2
then you press the plus sign that's how
you do you know that's that's called
reverse polish notation and it's
available on HP calculators okay uh
okay let me show you some articles let
me pedal my stuff okay sorry block you
go down then you have this section this
section on technology past and future
okay then you have this fantastic
artwork
this is retro this retro artwork and
this uh I forgot what how do you call
this style this fantastic artwork you
know it's future future yeah this this
uh this style is called futurism or
something
and this one is retro you know retro
that's how people imagine what year 2000
10 today is like back in 1980s
what a wonderful idea oh my God I'm just
gonna you know relax on this Lounge you
know drink uh pina colada or whatever
then then the girls oh my God bikini
girls in bikini lovely you know they're
walking around then I'm gonna have
flying cars what What a Wonder
instead you got Facebook and Google
censorship and politicians
ah
okay so technology future and present
okay so then I bought this calculator I
talked about let me show you and this
was a very interesting and uh okay and
uh you know look at this one this MIT
technology review this old guy you
promised me Mars colonies instead I got
Facebook now this this one is like 10
years ago
uh there's a date
anyway that's very funny that that's you
know that's what we are thinking uh my
generation or older even older
you know this Scott you got well we we
started to have ai and uh
does not seems promising I mean it's not
doing the
average people good it's doing the elite
the super Elite very good it's not doing
any of us average people good and that
thanks to the millennial generation
idiots
the and the social justice
most of the millennial generation like
that I like I like that
but you cannot really blame them because
they are created they are crafted by
Facebook by Google you know and Twitter
they are they they grew up that way
because the elite the Facebook Google
made it that way
and who is doing the Facebook and Google
you know the Google do no evil you know
back in year 2000 that's us the tech
geekers the Unix philosophy we
did it we did it we made you know we
joined Google back then when Google was
the good guys Google do no evil we
joined them we are sending open source
the song of the open source beautiful in
the future you know we are going to
create the technology world where
everyone is happy
h-a-p-p-y we're gonna have flying cars
we're gonna have Google do no evil
fantastic in Facebook
and Twitter you know remember Twitter
back in the early days they oh they they
created revolutions they made countries
you know doing better in some you know
potent Town countries
yeah
and today you know USA is falling apart
you know uh USA is falling apart and
China is rising up and most Americans
especially the white Americans a lot of
them are on on Discord have no idea
you know the white people are they have
two parts one part is like the social
justice scan
you know China is kind of okay but they
are gonna try to Bomb It Anyway the
other part is the red the conservatives
the Christians whenever China the world
comes up they they'll just say oh China
virus
now I'm going to now my YouTube this one
is going to be censored by YouTube
there's a good chance of that no I said
the word
and how do you have these idiots okay
and USA is falling apart
uh you don't know you know you should
look you know if you are American look
around you look around the the trains
the buildings the skyscrapers just look
around look around the trains building
skyscrapers the technology the the
cities in China uh the super computers
you know take a look the fastest
computer it's like more than 50 percent
of the world's fastest computer are all
from China
and lots of things you know then we have
white people then when they you know
when they see this they they they will
post YouTube about how China is gonna
fall
they do that well they have no idea what
is going on
uh they want to believe you know so
anyway
um
what what yeah what what was I talking
about so I was talking about calculators
yeah emacs so I bought this back in 2000
uh back in
1999 okay this this is uh the
the first graphing calculator made in
USA or the second one
the first one is Casio Casio from Japan
okay I bought this one HP calculator HP
calculator is still the best and then I
want to show you you go by okay and by
the way
I have so many so many things to say
this is my first programming language
okay I you see these two menus
each menu I don't know is 200 Pages or
something this is my first programming
language
the you know I learned programming on
this thing I never took any class about
programming or computer science I never
you know and I never went to high school
for reasons
so I I these two manuals I'm I'm
obsessive about reading manuals I read
manuals cover to cover every word
including the preface introduction
acknowledgment epilogue whatever you
know and colorful I need to read a book
given given a book a menu I need to read
from the cover and and inset and and the
how do you call this a proper name for
the if if you have a book you know on
the side there's a title right there's a
proper name for that
I solicit you guys uh how do you call
that this is a proper name for that
on the side of the book
you know so I have you know I read cover
to cover every word you know the
everything that printed on the book
I used to
um that's my obsession so I started I
read tons of computing programming
manuals uh always cover to cover so
anyway you see these two volumes uh
manual I read them entirely
and uh my first program written on this
calculator is solving the eight Queens
problems and here's the code okay so
this this code this programming language
for the
hp28s calculator this code is in the
same style I believe the of the fourth
programming language
f-o-u uh
f o u r t s t h
fourth
yeah
there it is
uh what what the fact I want to go to I
want to go to YouTube yeah fourth for f
o r t h okay so this is a kind of a
stack based language okay so that is the
um so you can go read it
uh and uh you know so this HP sub in the
eight Queens Fab now if you don't know
what is eight eight Queens problem look
it up okay eight Queen's problem that is
on a chase chess board you have to put
Place eight Queens on on it so that no
Queen checks each other and there are
many solutions so this is my first
program without knowing anything about
algorithm without knowing anything
okay without knowing what is the
character said what what is the
algorithm what's the meaning of it
what's the meaning of algorithm what
what is uh what is a float what is in
what is the programming language what is
a spec so I mean I don't know nothing
okay you just
you don't have to okay well that's it so
happens that's how I learned how I
learned things okay I happen to be that
way so just read the manual cover to
cover and you can do that that's yeah I
happen to do that
eight Queens problem and I also wrote a
musical problem okay so anyway so that
so I want to show you this page actually
so this page
where I show many of the calculator this
one I have right here
a cheap calculator ten dollars or
something maybe in Japan
uh you know I was you know when I was
small a team 12 or you know 13. I was
fascinated by calculators because you
see a calculator you see this these
symbols you see squared you know cube
root third power using you know
exponential log sine cosine you know
back then I don't know what those are
I didn't know what those are until I'm
22 also I'm kind of a late learner okay
so you know hyperbolic sign trig
functions so I was fascinated by them
because you know I was I would I would
think when I was you know 12 years old
11. what what kind of advanced math oh
my God you have to be so Advanced to
know what are those those buttons are
fantastic
this is the fast you know that's why I'm
a nerd I'm not like lots of you guys you
know you guys have your stories this is
my story The Sign of the Fantastic
lovely just obsessed I have to obsess
about them you know I have to have this
okay calculators
and and also the same summation sign you
know it's fantastic those symbols
symbology I love them that's why I'm
into Unicode in programming languages
and so anyway so today you want to buy
if you uh wanna buy you buy HP okay so
you want to buy HP Prime
and okay you want to buy HP Prime where
is it I show uh I show yeah HP Prime
okay so it looks like that
uh this might be old version okay so
anyway you go to my website and go buy
it okay so just search for Saudi
calculator
uh and then okay one thing you do not
want is the taxes Instruments calculator
made by attack the sucks comparatively
it's like thirty dollars fifty dollars
more expensive and it's slower
the the most effective the cheapest and
more the better the Casio Casio is the
best okay Casio from Japan Japanese
people they have uh their technology is
supreme
so if you want to you know for example
this Casio you know go you know just go
to Amazon and you put in your shopping
cart by eighty dollars okay so and it's
a color and it's faster than this TI 84
150 you know eighty dollar fifty dollars
more you know so anyway
bye Casio
if this is not powerful enough you know
get the HP Prime you know Casio doesn't
have the reverse polish notation uh but
HP only on HP Prime you have that but
you don't really need that okay it's not
a need so HP Prime okay so that's about
calculators and up and then
an image and let me show you about this
heartbeat watch okay I bought this watch
back in 1988.
for I think 250 dollars it measures your
heartbeat you put this belt on your
chest I used to wear this all the time
every day non-stop 24 hours a day uh for
for about for about 10 years
when I was let's say from 16 to 25 okay
because why because I want to be a bug
you know I'm you know like what what I
said I I'm a nerd I'm a rather extreme
nerd okay I'm a nerd I'm really extreme
so like today you might hear you know or
some young guy they started to put some
device in their brain so they are the
first they are officially considered the
first
um
hybrid humid yeah how they what's the
what's the word you know where like a
book you know where part of you is a
part your organized organism is part
biological is part mechanical
you know some there are some guy if you
search Wikipedia you'll find there's
some guy in Europe they put
kind of an antenna kind of a chip in
their brain so they can actually you
know there are a lot of people that do
that you know nuts like us and some
people you know a few years ago become
very popular is Google Glass right so
you wear that you can it's like a cell
phone on your glass you can take photos
all the time
anytime uh you know Google guys so so
the idea is integrating Machinery into
your body
so I used to I like that idea because I
am a nerd as well so back in 19
1988 I bought this watch and I wear it
all the time why because so I can't know
my heartbeat at any time I want
for that reason
so that's that you know by the way I'm
trying to find the model number so this
is a photo I took a few months ago I
still have it but I I'm not sure it's it
it's very good quality it's still
working but I don't know if it's I think
the battery is dead it's still working
for like 10 it worked for more than 10
years
but I don't know uh if it's you know so
I think I'm gonna throw it away so but
so one thing I want to know is is the
exact exact model name I cannot find it
and it's hard to search so if you know
if you are good you know if you can find
the model name let me know
okay I'm gonna it's not printed anywhere
on the watch uh but I took the photos
maybe if I open it maybe if I open it
yeah but that's too much trouble
and today of course today you have
heartbeat watch in you know fee bit you
know beginning with Fitbit and then
Apple watch this um
you know today I'm not so much into
becoming a book when you get old uh you
know
some of your ideas when you are younger
changed you know I'm still of course
very excited about technology but
I'm not certain about
putting you know I still I
am not so eager let's say you know I
still find it I I think eventually you
know I think I'm too old
but if I were young you know if I'm a
younger
I still probably want to do it like
integrate technology into your body for
example put a
let's say mechanical eye so you can have
whatever night vision you know uh eager
ego Vision or whatever or enhanced
supersonic Voice or year or years you
know detecting or things like that
or putting a chip into your brain so you
become a human machine hybrid you know
so you can you can do calculations you
know faster than electronic calculator
because it's it's you have a chip inside
your brain I think
I think we are going to you know
uh on the on the whole Humanity we are
going to do that I mean some at least
some people some part some at least some
percentage of population will will do
that eventually sooner or later it's not
something you can stop
and uh the ID you know and and off also
it's possible that it is necessary to do
so you know like Elon Musk you know Elon
Musk is one of the guy you know he do he
does AI research you know with his
companies you know uh Tesla and SpaceX
so he is often concerned about AI you
know about AI taking over so he's in his
thinking you know his solution is that
we need to be a technology so that we
can integrate you know the the
mechanical technology into our brain
so
so that you know the AI robotics they
can be superhuman but we are actually
becoming superhuman as well that's his
point so you need that technology
integration neural neural connection
with the you know machine
and I so so in that if that's the case
it's possible you know we don't nobody
knows okay but
if that's the case that means you know
we maybe it's maybe it may be necessary
to do that
we are talking about future we don't we
you know nobody knows what will happen
in 10 years in 20 years so in 50 years
but all kind of things may happen
unpredictable you know that's one one of
the interesting thing about future
future futurology is you know which I'm
very very much interested is that it is
basically impossible to predict the
future okay it doesn't matter how how
knowledgeable you are in fact if you are
in fact if you are the expert of AI or
something you're or if you are expert if
you are a mathematician or if you are a
technologist you know expert in
technology or your prediction tends to
be wrong okay
that that is the case if you if we look
at you know study past predictions these
experts usually have wrong you know
predictions
why is that because uh you know this is
another you know very deep topic
prediction of the future future reason
uh you want to uh so so so so so
basically future is not cannot be
predicted uh it's basically and
and I believe there's a you know the
mathematical Theory you know uh of that
the mathematical the math basis for that
is
for example chaos theory and Chaos
Theory and cellular automata okay now
you
you look up Wikipedia chaos theory and
uh cellular automata
your your you'll see the um why it's not
you you see the the mathematical Theory
why future is not predictable
even even if you know all the physics
the law of physics and the you know the
only way to know the future is to live
through it so that's uh
the math basis for it
so we were talking about calculators
um and uh and uh
okay so that's it uh there is a big
Theory it's being a taxes instrument
summarized they are crap but government
running decades ago right because they
were good
okay you know I think taxes instruments
they were great the reason I you know I
I'm not sure I think the reason they
become bad is because
um
the reason you know in 1990s 1992 1993
taxes instrument you know they are
calculated they came out with great
calculators and very competitive back
then 1992 around there that that that
was the time when I was in college
Community College
right here uh and uh you know so math
classes begin they you know people begin
to debate whether should you allow
calculators in class you know there's
always this kind of debate controversy
you know on one Camp people say oh once
you have that then people won't be able
a student won't be able to learn to know
how to do integration or do it you know
they don't know how to do things anymore
they become reliant on the on the
calculator
okay that's one Camp of
of Educators their opinion
the other Camp is usually yes you need
to yes you need to have this technology
in a classroom you need to let people
integrate you know learn how to use them
because
it enhances your ability to learn you
know you can graph you can see so that's
you know this this controversy comes up
all the time like for example printed
book versus Ink you know electronic or
tablet you know and lots of you have
opinions about that too
um no I know when this come up everyone
will have their opinions
you know the same people then then you
know then there's a group like uh Rebels
they'll say oh you know first of all
there's a group of nerds they'll say oh
they they always go within technology
you know they're gonna you know once you
have a iPad they're gonna throw away
they're gonna burn or throw away all
their paper books they're gonna have
everything I have had
then after a while then there's also
from this group they know they're gonna
say oh no technology is no good you know
they they're gonna throw away all their
iPad they're gonna insist everything
they have a book must be a paper
and this also happened when typewriter
was invented also happened when credit
card was invented people are insulted
you know
I'm getting another topic you know
when temperature was in
typewriters you know where you know it
was invented people I don't I don't need
typewriters thank you I can I'm I'm
fairly I'm quite capable of writing with
my hand thank you
you know there's a kind of an insult to
the okay to their ability to perform
something they don't you know I don't
need typewriters
you know then credit card was invented
no thank you I can write checks fine I
have great bank account I have good
credit you know I don't need credit card
so the people fail to see
you know they don't see the overall
picture that's often that is the case
remember there's a new technology then
when it comes to programmers the same
thing exactly the same thing especially
the Unix Linux people they want things
to be as hard as possible and wherever
there is something easy and new such as
Visual Basic or PHP or JavaScript they
will laugh at it will ridicule it
yeah that's you guys
uh
but you you know but Society but it's
you see the the point here is uh
technology advancement and all these
gadgets they are an inevitability now
remember that okay you may not like it
but your generation you or die
eventually soon soon okay I'll die
before you
generation styes then the next
Generation took over
and to them you know like today's
generation they grew up with the
internet they think
you know you know you know what I mean
right
so emacs let's get back to emacs
calculator you know emacs calculator was
the greatest calculator back in the
1980s
in 1990 Grace greatest not just kind of
it's the greatest one of the greatest
software in the entire world it's a it's
the best you know code in ability
capabilities and you know that's the
best but when when it's 1990s it's just
still it's still very good very good
even compared to commercial you know
computer algebra systems the emacs
calculator okay
but beginning in year 2000 and now year
2010 and now year 2021
emacs calculator it's okay is pure
worthless
okay let me tell you so instead of let
me get now now
those are my uh General opinions kind of
philosophical opinions now let me let me
give you a concrete useful practical
advice regarding
emacs calc okay so instead of using
email calculator I I recommend you use
python or any programming language
instead for example let's say let's say
I want to calculate uh let's say so what
I do
just open any buffer okay so um open any
buffer so save it a temp file okay
python okay now uh let's magnify okay
let's say I want to three plus five
first uh 11 okay I want to compute that
so just print
okay so I got 19 19 okay
so what if you want to do array okay no
I don't remember python so well so let's
not use Python because I don't code
python that much these days this code um
JavaScript I do JavaScript all the time
still
so let's so if so if you are calculating
your groceries you know it's easy to
just um
uh for example 19
1.25 or you'll be or your rent two
thousand dollars then you and then
someone paid you 100 1 200 and then you
bought a mouse forty dollars and fifty
cents you want to do your bills right so
you do that then you just um
uh sum it up okay uh
JavaScript is a pain okay so because you
don't so you you just submit some some
it up okay so
ah
okay so now you got seven seven sixty
dollars okay that's how you do so why do
I recommend using this instead of
instead of a emacs hack because when you
do a language first of all you have all
the history you know it's much more
convenient first of all you can edit
each part you know each part you can
move them about you can save as a file
so the keyboard operation is much more
better you have the full Emax power to
manipulate whatever whatever you want to
compute okay full power much faster okay
and then you can save to a file then you
can have you you can have another for
example this is a
let's say you can name variables today
list okay
let's say
tomorrow
pay okay let's say your internet bill 60
let's say uh your uh Bill Bill
120 okay so so then you can add them you
know
is so it's much more flexible and much
more powerful
uh what what if you start to need to do
math like like integration you know
usually you don't but what if you if you
need to or Matrix calculated K uh
summing linear equations then you load
the package okay I don't know how do you
I don't know how what how to do that in
JavaScript you know npm you you have to
find a package but anyway in Python it's
easier in that case in Python because
there's lots of these math libraries
so
advantage of using a programming
language to to do it is that you have a
full file you can manipulate every part
you have the everything you know like
history you can save it to a file and
you have it's much more flexible in how
you enter you know values or expressions
or complex numbers much more flexible
much more powerful and you can much more
permanent and much easier to manipulate
you know each part in what you want to
do
all that and plus plus you advance your
knowledge in a programming language
let's say you want to start to do Matrix
computation you load you find the
library to load to do a linear algebra
okay in python or you know there are
tons of libraries you load it then you
can do that so you advance your skill on
the other hand if you do the e-max calc
you know you read the manual in idiotic
manual okay and let's let's see
okay here's the emac calculation Emax
calculator idiotic manual because why
why it's idiotic because it's written in
1980s 40 years ago all the style they
are writing and the you know it's quite
idiotic you spend time to learn this
stack and Trail scientific functions
what the scientific functions okay
uh log functions well idiotic
they have a whole page telling you how
to compute you know how to use the log
function
so you spend your time you say spend our
day you know you know learning this it's
useless nowhere else you can use it
okay so that's why
I recommend do not ever ever use emacs
calculator okay I know again I know I
this opinion is contrary to the hacker
types in the emacs community like they
they will say you they will tell you
they are excited oh you should use emacs
activator and yeah
and you know I don't like them they're
idiots
okay uh I forgot to mention Texas
instrument okay I I digressed I I didn't
mention the point why
why taxes instrument calculators become
spad because back in 1990s early 1990s
they were very good product very
competitive and cheap and that is why
they become a required instrument for
every class every University every high
school you know in United States and
also because there are U.S U.S company
U.S rather by U.S made stuff it then you
know made in Japan so back then it was
very good so it kind of revolutionized
the education math education in high
school and in college
and it becomes required you know teacher
you you know usually they don't say you
know it you know the the teacher cannot
say you need to buy this specific model
you know they usually just say you need
to buy a graphing calculator it doesn't
matter what brand you know it's it's not
supposedly good
uh practice too but eventually
eventually it becomes convenient because
when you say a specific fake model in
your class let's say everyone guys you
know students you are required to buy
you know Texas instrument 84 this
specific model then the teaching becomes
easier you know the how do you you know
teaching becomes easier exercise becomes
more easier you know that's why so that
becomes that's why it becomes kind of
required so that's why the Texas
instrument becomes very popular you know
they made a lot of money but then so
they become fat that's when they become
super that that's when they become you
know
become bad you know all these others
they are faster faster you know faster
and cheaper than the ti but TI you know
they are not going to lower their prices
because all the schools in USA require
to buy our stuff so that's why they
become bad
okay so that's it for today so uh
so if you like my stuff donate okay
PayPal patreon Amazon gift card just go
to
sardi.info you go through my website
you know on the top page
on the top page then you can see
you know my uh patreon links or gift
card or PayPal thank you guys that's it
for today
uh okay that's it for today we shut down
in one minute
so how long have I been talking uh today
it's a long one 90 minutes I think
1 hour and 24 minutes okay that's it
yeah we I'm gonna shut down
foreign
bye guys
thank you
the keys
a question is the Toyota key used a lot
in programming
not really
do you think it could be used as a
modifier key instead
yes you could but I don't recommend it
because the Toyota key is far away
you don't want to use that as a modifier
key
okay that's it that's it bye guys
thank you bot