Hello guys. Hello guys.
Live stream begin. Start coding. We are
going to code wam language. So this is
my coding session. This is what I'm
going to code uh graphics programming in
wufam language.
Now if you don't know what is wam
language, watch yesterday's live stream.
Okay. There's introduction
and uh today I'm just gonna work on my
stuff and uh for anyone here
uh you can ask me questions, post
questions in the chat
or you can just watch me code. Okay, if
you're watching this offline, play at
1.5 speed.
So it's boring. Probably this video is
not what you want. Okay. So, I'm just
going to work on my website.
Okay. See, uh, video check, audio check.
Okay. So, this, you know, there's a lot
of things to do there. There's a lot of
things to do. Uh, what one thing
interesting is that today, you know,
hello, uh, Colonial T9. I'm good. Thank
you. You know, today with AI going on,
AI is becoming amazing.
um you know AI can generate videos but
also write code or answer any of your
questions.
So AI is amazing and uh basically AI
made tutorials uh obsolete. Hello wavy
line. Happy Friday. Oh yeah, today is
Friday. Maybe I should get a drink.
Should I?
Uh but but I've been you know this this
code I've been wanting to finish for
like two weeks. So I really need to
finish this code. You know the code
works. You know it works but I need to
make it like
condensed and exempl
exemplary exemplary so that people can
use this snippet of code to generate the
reflections of any curve with you know
very concise code.
Actually the the current code actually
works well. I mean, but I want it to be
more
um kind of more refined.
So, really I I I want to work on my
code, but you know, with AI today, um it
makes tutorials so obsolete. Let me
ramble a bit. You know, if I if I
continue the whole video rambling,
that'll be fine. You know, that's let
let the live stream do whatever, you
know. So today with AI it basically
makes tutorials obsolate.
Um
at least for the beginners okay it makes
any introductory
programming language tutorial material
obsolate.
The key word is intro introductory
because you know so AI you can like if
you want to learn Python if you want to
learn JavaScript you know let's uh let's
let me showcase my uh tutorials if you
guys have not seen so.info info on my
website. Okay. So, you go to go go go
down there's lots of programming
language tutorials. EAC listp fantastic
and powerful 10,00 pages. Uh uh
JavaScript in depth that's 1,00 pages.
Um HTML CSS SVG S how to how to write a
SVG clock. There it is. That's about 50
lines of code in JavaScript. So these
are beginning tutorials. Actually, let's
ask AI to write a JavaScript code. Let's
see how it does. That would be
interesting. Um,
you know, I think it will actually it
may actually write shorter code than
shorter code than what I have here. So,
you know, so I got lots of tutorials,
right? So, if you guys want to see that,
remind me. Okay. Right. Ask AI to write
a tutorial uh for creating a clock in
JavaScript
and using SVG. You see very interesting
because I am using SVG. SVG is a scal
scalable vector graphics technology but
but an alternative is using canvas.
Okay, if you guys don't know canvas, you
know there is the the canvas idiot
canvas which is pixelbased
while SVG is like uh XML element based.
So SVG is actually everything you draw
is actually a thing like a circle, a
line or whatever. Well, canvas is the
C++ plus idiots pixels, you know, you
just you just paint pixels like that's
good for gaming, you know, but the
idiotic technology
and Apple made it because they put they
the Apple pushed it because they want
iPhone to have games and replace um the
flash back in about 15 years ago, 2007
around there.
Steve Jobs. So anyway, so so I I
digressing all over. So um you got SVG.
So it would be interesting if you ask AI
to write a clock in JavaScript for the
web and see what choice it makes whether
it's going to use SVG or canvas or even
using the 3D um um that web um GL. this
that's another technology but that's
mainly for three-dimensional
graphics
um have you do you guys know webgl okay
so so that that webgl is a technology uh
but there is a library for webgl
um so webgl is a technology but there's
a library called um
since like 10 years ago okay Um
anyway, Web WebGL allows you to draw 3D
graphics like like like a game engine in
browser. Okay. In with JavaScript in
browser. Um so it would be interesting
to see what AI decide to use SVG or
canvas. Probably canvas. I would guess
maybe SVG. Well, so I don't know. But
also so also interesting to look at the
code what the code AI is actually do. So
actually let's write um let's ask AI.
Okay. Uh I started to ramble but that's
okay. So uh let's create a new question
and uh write a JavaScript code
for a clock.
Let's say analog clock
with second hand. Okay, let's add extra
magnify.
And by the way, you see this interesting
phenomenon you see on the web, the web
technology idiocy of the the zoomer
generation, the extreme idiots. You see,
you see this? I don't know if you guys
can see it on my screen, but you see
it's flashing.
You see this occurs on Twitter or some
other website. You see the JavaScript
framework, they have a situation where
like when your window is certain size
like this stuck in between something. So
they keep flashing. Can you see that?
Oh, it see happens if you shrink it. You
see? So this happen when you change font
size. So let me change font size again.
Wait. Okay. It's here. Wait. Okay. So,
wait. You see if I scroll down. Wait. I
You know, so when the font size is is
150, it's it has this flash thing.
Can Can you guys see it?
So, shrink. You see font size 140. Now,
magnify font size 150. You see that
flash? Let's magnify again. Then it
stops. You see
[ __ ] incredible idiocy of the
JavaScript the basically the Zuma
generation and the late Malay gen
beginning their the JavaScript idiots
their framework like they don't know
nothing.
Anyway, so that that's an interesting
phenomenon. Okay, let me show you again.
We it's a good thing. You see it doesn't
happen now. You see now it doesn't
happen you so so now it does you cannot
reproduce it so it sometimes happen you
know things like it flashes
very weird um
I'm glad I captured this we it happened
on the on my live stream so there's like
proof anyway so let's ask this uh AI
this question write a JavaScript code
for a analog block
with second hand to draw. Let's make it
precise. Okay,
actually we don't need to be but but let
me just do that JavaScript because I
want to do this one shot correctly.
Right, just to be sure, right? A
JavaScript code to draw an analog clock
with second hand. Okay.
Uh go down. do it. Okay. Ask AI Gork.
So, we didn't say we didn't say what uh
SVG or CSS. Wow. It's using CSS. It does
not even use SVG.
Fascinating.
Fascinating. Can it be done? Yes. Yeah.
Obviously. Oh, wow. It's even better
because yes, it's even better using um
you know does not like totally skip SVG
or canvas. It just use CSS which is a
hack because you in order to draw the
second hand and so on you need to like
do a rotation uh you you know you need
to do this transform kind of thing.
So anyway let's check if it the code
works. Okay, actually we are digressing.
So we'll go back to that topic. Okay,
the SVG clock. But meanwhile, let me
tell you guys, let's go back to what we
were saying. So I got lots of tutorials.
That's what I was saying. Okay, let's go
back and regroup.
So this is today's talk show. Is that
correct? Yes, we talked about SVG clock.
Yes. Um section. Let's go to the
section. search for that and uh let's
put the link here make a link and we
talked about SVG clock actually I was
talking about
my website tutorials for uh SVG and for
lots of other things okay programming
tutorials.info
info. Okay.
So, I was talking about my programming
tutorials.
Okay.
Uh
so actually so I was saying that
AI today basically makes all beginner
tutorials obsolate
uh Python, Pearl, Java, Golan because AI
can generate it. However, the issue with
AI generated tuto tutorial is that it's
um it's like just kind of superficial.
Um
actually it can be quite accurate but it
so how do you describe the the the
situation the you know like today AI can
really answer even difficult questions
about programming language because I've
I I've asked tons of questions to AI in
the past two years like like programming
language which like esoteric questions.
So AI knows okay and it can generate
tutorials on the fly. Uh in fact I've
done that in my live stream like you can
just ask it write a uh beginner's
tutorial of JavaScript or write a just
uh just say tell it to write a
JavaScript tutorial.
Okay, let's go back here. Uh
because we uh yeah, we want to do that.
Okay, so so AI can write a lot of
tutorials, right? Uh hold on a second.
So yeah, so let's just copy the copy the
URL generated the URL and let's copy the
uh question there.
merge these two and let's copy the code.
Actually, um this JavaScript paste it
there. Uh wait,
uh wait, this is not JavaScript code.
This is HTML code.
Yeah. So it actually um
it embeds the
um
oh you see all the styles for clock you
see. Okay. So where's the JavaScript
code? What? It does not even use
JavaScript code. Wait. So is there
update? Holy [ __ ]
Wow. So there's not even uh JavaScript
code. It's using animation. Is that
right?
Oh, holy [ __ ] Let's see what it does
actually. Okay.
Paste, you know. So, that's HTML. Paste
it. Yeah. So, there's HTML. Now, go to
the top and remove that. And uh
actually, so let's um let's pop it out
actually. Cut. Put it back. Actually,
make a new uh file.
Let's say gu ai
lock.html.
Okay. And copy it. Uh so that we make a
link. Okay. So we got a problem with the
link because the file name contains
spaces. So now let's change the file
name. So it does not contain spaces.
Press, press, press. That's done. And
that command is shown on the pink window
diode rename space to low line.
Fantastic.
Okay. So now open that copy it. Close.
Close and paste it. New file path.
Delete that. Make it a link and uh make
it a list. Okay. Now remove this. So now
we can open that and showing browser.
Let's see.
Fascinating. Beautiful. Amazing.
A little error, but on the whole is it
correct? Yes. Now, right now it's
California time. 4:00 p.m. and 32
seconds. Uh, stupid Microsoft. So, let
me show you. So um
clock
open Microsoft clock. So you can see
right now it's 4:00 32 seconds in the
afternoon San Francisco time. Okay.
Correct.
4:30.
There's a little errors you know this
this offset but we can fix it. But you
see another thing to notice is that the
second hand it emulates
real life clocks in real life where when
the head moves there's a little bit
shaking motion.
Can you guys see that? That's
fascinating. How how do you actually
Well, so it you know so it's so correct.
uh in fact it did this.
So there you know in order to do that it
must be you know like more complicated
code. So where's so here is a script. So
you can see
you see so there is actually JavaScript
right. So here's a script. Let's um hold
on before we change anything let me make
let me uh rename this file so that it's
got a uh
date. Okay. And uh and uh let's rename
um let's put guork AI
by GU AI and put today's date. Okay. So
that so that when we view this file
let's say 10 years from today it makes
sense.
Now open it.
Rename the title that. Okay. Uh, fail
search fail H1 H1. Okay, that's fine.
So, now we got that. Okay, open that.
Close that. Back here. Close that. Okay,
so now let's try to fix that. Okay, we
getting into JavaScript coding. Well,
but let me finish my topics first. Okay,
so I was talking before we were talking
about uh yeah, WebGL. So, there's WebGL.
So hold on a second.
WebGL we mentioned because we mentioned
whether AI is going to use WebGL or
um
or is it going to use um SVG or the uh
canvas. Okay. So there is SVG, there is
canvas, canvas intro and canvas versus
SVG. Let's open that.
Uh, I don't like canvas. Okay, canvas is
[ __ ] Canvas is pixelbased technology. I
hate pixelbased technology. So, here's
my basic links tutorial. Okay, showing
browser.
So, that's the things we talked about
today.
But um but I want to say that
so we were talking about how AI is
um replacing all basic tutorials and al
and you can ask questions interactively.
So it's like you have almost a
professional professor
that teach you teach you a personal you
know professor that's just amazing not
just teach you coding you can ask any
questions about physics chemistry or
mathematics or anything or even history
so it's
and the and the quality of AI the answer
it gave is
most of the time is like equivalent to a
professor
depending on you know in real life
professors some are not so good some are
good but some are not good teachers like
like some professor are good lecture you
know or teachers some are not but also
they don't like some of them they don't
have the patience like they don't give a
[ __ ] about you like you ask question
they just like brush it off they don't
really pay attention
But with AI you got you know AI can
answer questions any questions
tirelessly like you can ask it 100
questions or about the same thing even
if you don't understand you know it will
just ex keep explaining so AI is uh
truly amazing so anyway I was saying
that it's replacing basic tutorials
uh but it's not exactly the same as um a
good human written tutorial. You see the
the another distinction you make you
need to make is that you you cannot
simply compare AI written tutorial with
human written tutorial like asking which
is better because
there's a details just like professor
because when you ask you know you need
to ask because among the tutorials a
programming language written by human
animals. They are good and they are bad
ones. Just like books also books okay
before before internet there's books but
some good books are really good books
they became classic
in the field.
Some other books are just written by you
know someone who may be trying to make
money you know bad books okay or
misleading books or filled with errors
or whoever wrote it he may be
knowledgeable about the subject but he
lacks
you know he lacks writing skill or he
doesn't he's in a hurry you know in his
career you know he didn't pay much
attention he just want you know this
book done and he want to move on, you
know. So, there are a lot of reasons
there are bad books, okay? Bad books and
good books, books. Same thing with uh
programming language tutorials
since the internet. There are good ones,
there's bad ones. Today, for example,
there's a lot like
uh CEO, you know, like you ma made by
India, basically Indian idiots in in
India. Okay. They don't you know they
there's like tons of answering questions
programming tutorial especially Python
especially like for popular language
like how do you do this in Python what's
the difference between this and turbo
like if you ask that you'll see tons of
website mostly written by this Indian
they get like few cents uh an hour to to
to write that to copy and paste whatever
so in the past like 10 15 Okay. A lot of
these tutorials are written by
lowquality you know writers
and a lot of copy paste you know.
So
so for tutorials there are good ones
there are bad ones even written by
human. So when you ask the question is
AI generated tutorials for programming
languages are they better or are they
worse than human animal ones? You need
to take consider like like you need to
say, you know, on average,
you know, because compared to a great
one written by a human animal such as
me,
some of some some of my actually AI is
quite comparable, you know, but
but AI the the the the tutorials
generated by AI, even good ones, they
don't have like they don't have a
spirit. They don't have like a
particular view or particular
uh kind of human touch. Like in my in my
tutorial, you you can kind of, you know,
if you read my tutorial after a while,
you'll see there's certain you can you
can tell, you know, this is probably
written by by by this guy Exali
because there's certain style, there's
certain like there's a certain spirit
like he I want to tell you about
programming language. I like the way I
think about programming languages
but AI generated tutorial
you you don't have that it it is like
perfect even even though it it is
written in perfect
uh perfectly the writing style the
logical or the organization the you know
the grammar is all perfect and
and it's all technically correct you
could you know AI I usually do that you
know but then but but it it it's some
you know it lacks the the kind of the
human bias and stuff. Okay.
So that's one one of the difference
between AI generated u programming
language tutorial
versus a human one even good ones. Okay.
But also but that's not the whole story
because AI you see if you want it to
have a style or spirit you have to ask
you know you can actually ask write a
tutorial of JavaScript in the style of
actually you can ask it you you'll do so
very funny you know or in the style of
Donald G you know a famous some some
famous uh computer scientist it will
actually do that. So,
so good you know. So, so going back to
you know it's not it's not true to say
that AI generates generated stuff lacks
humanity. It is actually not true. Um
because this is an important question
because when AI generated some images
for example today
there's huge huge amount of you know
like you guys probably know right if you
go to you know Twitter you'll see huge
amount of AI uh generated like like this
you know this is virgining on girls okay
I mean so I mean so where is the um yeah
here here is Uh,
you know, like um
this is like a horror movie but
generated by AI.
>> Three years after a string of brutal
unsolved murders of local co-eds with
impossibly
the women of Delta Delta D will be
headed to the new space station as part
of NASA's project bust.
>> Scary.
Can you like can you guys see uh if I
make it uh
wait
>> what okay I probably disrupted you you
guys enjoyment sorry
>> years after brutal unsolved murders of
local co-eds with impossibly fat milkers
the women of Delta Delta D will be
headed to the new space station as part
of NASA's project bust
>> scary the titty killer just disappeared.
We're going to be 250 mi
up. The only person watching us get
changed is going to be a 60-year-old man
at Cape Sanel.
>> You know, I heard in space your boots
actually get bigger.
>> Why exactly are they sending a shuttle
full of sorarity girls to space?
>> Son, the only thing bigger than the NASA
budget after this is going to be the
strain on those girls sweaters. This is
like the plot of a movie written by a
12-year-old boy.
This is the first time I felt safe since
the titty killer.
>> You don't think it's him, do you? Who
else would go all the way to space?
>> Now listen, sweetheart. The boys down
here tell me you're flat as a board. If
that's right, you're basically invisible
to them. You might be our only hope.
>> That's funny. That's so funny.
Now you guys can go check it out. Okay,
this movie this this thing created by AI
is called um
>> after this is going to be the strain on
those girls sweaters.
>> The title. Let's wait for the title.
solve murders of local co-eds with
impossibly
>> TT Killer 5 ZG
that actually emulates the style of
movie titles you know so it's amazing
you know AI and you look at today you
look at the person generated by AI the
girls or or person whatever person
>> it's you cannot tell it's fake There's
no way to tell this like this,
>> you know, you you you you look at their
face, everything is perfect.
>> Uh
like for almost no way. Okay, I mean
technically maybe there's some glitches
here and there, but you but basically
there's no way to tell. It's generated
by AI. So,
so what I'm saying so people but people
have been saying for example today we
have AI generated singers you know like
there's a word for it like some of the
some people do
live stream
but using AI to do live stream
some people say AI generated uh person
lacks kind of a soul and I think that's
basically just force. It's simply not
true.
Um,
and this touches the on the question of
what does, you know, what is a soul like
what does intelligence actually means?
So that's another very interesting
question.
Okay. Now getting back to what I wanted
to say in the beginning is that you see
I was saying that
AI can write tutorials and the
difference between AI generated
tutorials and uh human written ones and
what is my point actually
I don't have a point you know after
going through this
um so what is the difference between AI
generated programming language tutorials
and the one written by human.
I mean is there essential difference? Is
there a difference? Is is there certain
characteristics that you can tell you
can like always just separate them?
Actually I don't think so. Um
you know actually I don't think so. But
yeah so that this that that's a very
interesting question you know. Yeah. So,
so actually since I am talking about
this and thinking about it now,
I don't think there's actual any
um
essential difference there. There is no
you know
uh no essential difference that
necessarily separate them apart. just
like
just like I think the images photos or
movies generated by AI. So in other
words, it's the answer is analogous to
what's the difference between
a let's say short movie of 1 minute
generated by AI or actual
actors. or people on the street.
I don't think I don't think there's a
difference. Okay. So this is uh this so
this this answer is actually very
critical. This this this answer is
actually fundamental
that there is no difference there's no
essential difference
like whatsoever between AI generated
things and human created things. Now
that includes
videos or images
like photos
of people and includes
tutorials written by programming of
programming languages written by people
and I think that also includes poetry.
Um that also includes um
um
yeah I think it just includes about
anything.
There is no essential difference.
There's no characteristic difference
between AI created things and human
created ones.
So that that is my opinion. Okay. And
that I think this is a critical this is
one of the most critical
opinion
in the AI you know the AI you know the
the the debate about AI whether AI will
have intelligence like humans or a soul
anyway so I don't I don't think there's
a difference so that means um
but so does that mean so so what I
originally want to say is that when you
read a tutorial, right, AI kind of made
programming language tutorials obsolate,
but I was going to say that well, not
exactly because
human written ones there is still
something.
But now I changed my mind. There's
nothing.
So
yeah, so that's amazing that for example
like even my tutorials,
you know, some of them I'm fairly proud
of. Okay. So my wam language tutorial uh
my JavaScript my eac list this okay
there are it's almost unique uh like 600
pages on eac this
uh because you cannot find it anywhere
there's no similar books okay um my and
also my JavaScript in-depth tutorial I'm
most proud of because they are the most
in-depth so Some of my tutorials I'm
fairly proud of. Okay. Wuam eag this for
different reasons. Wuam language. Okay.
Let me let me just like elaborate on
this. Okay.
So
I'm pretty proud of my wam language
tutorial. Why? because
because it is kind of a unique and
practical approach where you treat Wufam
language uh as a programming language
like the like all the other programming
language from like from the industrial
coders you know people who code the web
you know webdev from JavaScript coders
or from PowerShell you know the Windows
uh shell or bash ash or from pearl
python you know python people a lot
python people and goland uh like more
low-level or java like more compile
language people so these are kind of
industrial programming languages so
usually they don't have any idea they
are not in touch with wuam language or
any programming language that does
mathematics such as matl or uh even
symbolic ones like uh Maple or or Maxima
like 20 years ago. So these people don't
know about so-called computer algebra
systems. Uh and wam language is just by
by now it's beyond just computer
algebra. It's like lots of things AI and
stuff. So I'm proud of my woofam
language tutorial is because
first of all there are not many. Okay.
So if you look for wam language
tutorials out there, there are a few
books but none actually this is like
almost like practically zero. There are
maybe uh three or four you know like
there may be one book in English
language every four years you know
something like that and they become
obsolate of course because Wuang
language just like other programming
languages it has new versions in you
know so anyway so so the programming
language tutorial on wam languages is
almost non-existent very rare okay But
however, there's a wolf research website
there. You know, there are documentation
and tutorial. There's like literally um
last time I counted it's like over over
I think it's over a few million pages.
Okay. Not just one million because
because
anyway it takes too long to talk about.
I'm I'm pretty sure they got over a few
million pages on their website, the Wuam
Research. So, they are huge and they
also have a uh practical wam language.
Okay, you search for Wuam language
tutorial, the first thing you will find
is their page. Okay. So I mean they got
two like two prominent ones is um
who wrote this one to data science
learning wra from zero. Oh that's
interesting.
Okay so what
god I'm digressing all over. Is anyone
find it find this uh interesting? I'm
like digressing all over. Okay. Not many
people watching. So, Wuam language
tutorial you the the prominent ones is
that uh first of all there's one written
by Stephan Wu okay uh it's online free
okay so you just go there uh where is it
um there's a link in print and free on
the web okay so it's called uh you know
I wrote a book so by Stephan Wuan
uh let's turn on JavaScript
Okay. Stefan Wuam, an elementary
introduction to the Wufam language.
Okay. Now, this book is great, but it's
not really focused on programmers
like if you came from,
you know, it if you came from, you know,
it's not really for hardcore
programmers. That's what I want to say.
Okay, like you if you really came from
hardcore programmers, your idea of
programming language is uh variables,
functions,
uh references maybe and you know list
data structures then this book is not
like that. It's rather it's like it
teaches people without programming
language background including technical
people. For example, there's a lot very
technical new young people that do uh
video processing or voice processing or
you know editing you know so uh or 3D
modeling but they are not programmers.
Okay. But they do all this technical
programming stuff. I mean they are not
programmers but but but they do lots of
computer very technical computer stuff.
So it's kind of for those people but so
if you are came from Java or C C++ or
Python this book is like
not uh does not fit. Okay, it doesn't
really teach you to use buffam language
in a way like a real programming
language. Okay, that is kind of my
review of this book. It's not too long
this book. So anyway, this is for like
general introduction like for technical
people to wam language. You can you can
after reading this book you can learn to
use it like ask it you know do all sort
of things
but but you you you might begin to code
it but it's not suitable okay you don't
know much about it
and another tutorial
for programmers okay if you just search
for wam language tutorials for
programmers There is one again from um
official Wufam research website the it's
called fast introduction for programmers
the wuam language okay spend a few
minutes with this tutorial to get up to
speed with the foundations of wuam
language okay so uh what oh god
wait is this the one I'm looking for uh
Yes.
Uh what
video? Yeah. So, so this tutorial this
is for programmers but in my opinion
it's
it's um
you know I I you know I I don't you know
I I think it's just basics. Okay.
So they for each chapter they also have
a video version. Video version is only
uh four minutes. Okay. So anyway so you
can try this tutorial. So I think my
tutorial is great because it I go in
depth in uh into strings, regular
expressions, number arithmetics, number
uh you know and uh boolean and list data
types data structure and uh stuff like
that. Okay, that's why I'm most that's
that you know that is uh why you know
the the the aspects
of what I like I I I'm proud of my
tutorial for Wuam language. Okay.
Oh my god, I'm going over this. So why
why do I think my Emac this tutorial is
great? Because basically it's unique. I
mean basically because there is no uh
well actually you know so there is no if
you want to learn Emac Lisp not other
list but EMAC
you will not find uh many by like today
I'm not sure I mean there might be one
resource one book or maybe one
there's no compreh there this basically
there's none okay except my
my book Okay, Emac Lisp teaches you Emac
Lisp and in depth fairly uh because
there are some 800 pages just for this
not counting Emacs. Okay, this is Emacs
tutorial, Emacs init tutorial, Emacs
keys tutorial. Then there's eac lisp
this basics on um on strings on numbers
boolean variable conditional loop and so
on. Okay. And then there then you have
another chapter on the EMAC bisp which
is more um
focused on
features of emac bisp that does not
exist in other programming languages
such as a buffer or editing text or move
cursor or uh search text you know
because other programming languages are
not a text editor but Emacs is. So you
can move cursor, you can search text,
you can mark region, you can cut copy
part of the region or text, you can
create a new buffer string or you can
convert part of buffer to a string or
vice versa. You can process each line of
a buffer, you know, and then you can
also
ask user question uh and you know like
how old are you ask user for input. You
can switch buffer. You can create new
buffer. You can save file read save.
Okay. So you can uh all these things you
can call a shell command and okay. So
this buffer thing buffer and cursor
position they are not available in most
of the programming languages because
they are not text editors. So this this
these things are unique to Emacs this
programming language. Okay. So anyway,
back to so my program my eaglist
tutorial
I find it I'm proud of it because it is
fairly unique and it's also I spent like
basically over 10 years writing it. I
still update it every day.
So that's great. And my Emacs tutorial I
think is also great. There are a lot
there are a lot Emac tutorials out
there. Okay. But mine is like the most
comprehensive the most
number number of pages like um you know
together Emacs and Emac this I think I
have over a thousand pages.
Okay. So yeah together Emacs and Emac
this I have over 1,000 pages tutorials
on them.
Okay. So my emac list this tutorial and
woofam language they are kind of unique.
You will not find
in-depth tutorials about these two
languages much elsewhere. Okay. And I'm
proud of my JavaScript tutorial. By the
way, you see this uh funky thing because
the font is huge. Okay. Now you see it.
Okay. I like, you know, I'm proud of my
uh JavaScript tutorial. It is because
it's actually the most in-depth. It's
far more in-depth like to the hilt. It's
far more in depth even my eaglist and my
wuam language tutorial because
JavaScript
uh
kind of far more in-depth and more
technical because I've read all the
several editions of the JavaScript
specification ex and JavaScript is also
extremely complex more complex than uh
wam or emac these lots of words
package okay JavaScript so That's why
I'm proud of my JavaScript in-depth
tutorial because it is the most one of
the most in-depth in fact compared to
all possible out there Mozilla or
whatever JavaScript books you've seen I
would consider mine is one of the best
like
top three. Okay, if you can pick
the best JavaScript books in the world,
pick three of them. Uh I would say mine
is among them.
In my own opinion, it's the best of
course because I prefer my own style.
Okay. So that that is why I'm proud of
that one. Now my Golan uh tutorial is
pretty basic. It's just for beginners.
Okay. But but I I'm also pretty proud of
this one because it's um because it's
written in a way I believe is the most
logical and in also in my style. What
does my style means? Style means no
nonsense, no storytelling like hi guys,
you know, oh I have experience from C++
and in C++ it's done that way. Goland
doesn't have that and also because of
that language I you know this like
talking oh today's a nice day uh one
time I heard a story from a sage he says
a function is something uh and I think
function is this or that you know
[ __ ] idiots I hate storytellings you
know like hi guys you know if you want
to download you know learn go you have
to go to this place to download package
you know then click this to install and
you are great you are Good to go and
it's a beautiful day. So, let's learn
it. You know, Golang is the most power,
you know, like the verbiage, the [ __ ]
idiots handholding like they they want
to tell you a story like, you know, a
lot of a lot of u tutorials are like
that. Let me let me let me show you guys
one of them.
si.info.
Uh,
so let me answer your question in a in
in a second. Okay.
Okay. JavaScript book review 2023.
There's one of the most idiotic book on
JavaScript. Okay. Now that that is
this okay eloquent JavaScript
this is a storytelling style. Let me let
me read a a minute or two to show you
what I mean. Okay. Now this is a a good
book but it's this one eloquent
JavaScript is by uh Marage Hburg Beck.
He he's a JavaScript expert. Okay.
Eloquent JavaScript the book. This book
is for beginners
kind of for people like never programmed
before that class of people. Okay. So if
you are not familiar with programming at
all then this book is for you. Okay.
So that is my judgment. However,
personally, I don't like this book
because
and this is why why I'm talking about it
right now because it's in a heavy
storytelling style. Okay. So, let let me
let uh let's try uh let's read some uh
some some chapter. Let's go functions.
Okay. Okay. First of all, a quote
functions. People think that computer
science is the art of geniuses. But the
actual reality is the opposite. Just
many people doing things that build on
each other like a war of many stones.
Donald Guth. Okay. So it used to be a
thing where you begin a chapter by a
quote. Okay. In this case he used
Donald. He's a famous computer
scientist. Okay. Then he you know he
insert a diagram of bees bees and ferns.
What's the relevance of this? I'm not
sure. And what what is the relevance of
this quote? Well, it's kind of like
gives you you know makes you happy. What
what is the relevance of the quote which
is like few hundred words of this Donald
G in this chapter of functions. What is
the purpose of that quote? The purpose
of that quote is kind of like make you
feel uh comfortable, you know, make you
feel like put your mindset in a, you
know, computer science. Oh, this is this
interesting story by Donald Gruth. So,
in this chapter, we're going to start to
learn something about functions. Oh,
heartwarming. Warming warms your heart,
does it? Oh, it's not created by
geniuses.
So if you are an idiot that's you know
it's good that's good it's this is a
good this is a book for you
[ __ ] [ __ ] I despise this storytelling
style okay
now I'm not saying you know I'm not
saying I'm against beginners or against
people who are not geniuses you know
they can all learn but you don't need
this unnecessary
I mean well depending on the taste you
know Some people enjoy, you know,
reading like you like, you know, you you
you you prepare a cup of coffee, you sit
under a tree, you start to read
programming, you know, books like
enjoy en enjoy the weather. Maybe maybe
that's that's for you. Okay, but what
I'm saying is that this is not for me.
Okay, this is idiot storytelling style.
That's what I'm saying. Okay, let's
continue one more. So it says begin you
know let's get to the content. Functions
are one of the most central tools in
JavaScript programming. The concept of
wrapping a piece of program in a value
has many uses. It give us a way to
structure larger programs to reduce
repetition to associate names with
subprograms and to isolate these sub
subprograms for each other. Okay. Blah
blah blah blah blah blah verbiage. Okay.
I don't like that style. Okay.
But otherwise, so so that's uh that's my
introduction to this book. Okay.
So, and what I'm saying is this
storytelling style which I do not do.
So, what is the style of my tutorial?
code
concise to the point
correct. Okay, I want to express
something and and easy understandable,
the most easy to understand.
Okay, so for example, you can check out
JavaScript in depth. This tutorial is
written in the most simple way you can
understand. There's no obstruuse jarens.
There's no use jar for the jargon sake.
There's no abuse of jarens to make you
think this is written by a genius like
the Python [ __ ] Python people do
that. When you read the Python
documentation full of jarens
unnecessarily so and also the Haskell
programming language like full of
computer science jarens unnecessarily.
So that's their style. Okay. So my style
there's no you know if if you if there's
a jargon you do not need it it's not
need it's not used okay simple way to
understand everyone can understand
standalone code examples for every
concept every page there's a stand alone
you know like like every you know like
copy you know like that that that you
can run
no extraneous jargon no design patterns
No fat. Okay. Like what the [ __ ] is
design patterns? Oh, design design
patterns is a is a practice in
programming industry. Something people
think they are solution to everything.
You know that's what design patterns
are. You know there's a book by the way
there's a book that's that's heavily
using the design patterns thing.
Uh okay I digressed to nowhere. I
digress. you know this book professional
JavaScript for web developers by
Nicholas C. Zakas
he's the head of web engineering at
Yahoo for like five or 10 years back in
you know but when you read book it's
when you read this book everything is
explained in terms of like patterns you
know like okay you know p patterns okay
uh this is uh like this is some pattern
like the design pattern thing that's a
code
like everything like everything this
book is trying to teach you in
JavaScript it's like he he he he explain
it in terms of some design pattern thing
okay [ __ ] idiot complete idiot I
would say
you know but but he's a great coder you
know otherwise he wouldn't I I'm pretty
sure you know I you know there's no
doubt he's a he knows JavaScript but it
is like the thinking or the style of
tutorial is like [ __ ] up
patterns, you know, like you you the the
way you see the language, everything you
you see it is like as as like pattern
like thing. Okay, the [ __ ] idiot. Oh,
these are OOP people, object oriented
people. Okay, so actually I digressed
all over. Um like
uh each like each of my digression
became
almost an hour digression. So this video
is going to last you know it's it'll end
in 10 hours. Okay.
Uh so I was talking about Okay. So I was
talking about it's um
yeah I was talking about the tutorial
writing styles. Okay. So my tutorial
style is most simple way written in the
most simple way you can understand
standalone code examples for every
concept written in a code style. No
ninja no zen no joke. No telling a
story. know make make you comfortable by
citing gluth that programming languages
are not geniuses you know like here
okay so like extraneous quote and
extraneous insert of a diagram what does
this diagram mean like bees bees and
ferns does it help you understand
functions in JavaScript
does it I don't think So
make but make you kind of happy.
Okay, that's extraneous like
storytelling. Ninja and Zen [ __ ] Okay,
you you you will not find one such sent
sentence in in any of my programming
language tutorials. Okay, in JavaScript,
in Goland, in PowerShell, in Python, in
Pearl Ruby, those are not good by the
way, but I haven't get to those yet in
Emacs, Ebank, this in Wu, you know, you
will not find a single line of this um
verbiage
in my tutorial. Okay. Next, no
extraneous jarens, okay? No design
patterns, no fat. I already covered
that. Next, no framework, no library,
pure standard JavaScript that runs in
browser. Okay. Now, this is part
particular for JavaScript for my
tutorial because JavaScript, you know,
usually um involves framework, you know,
today and also for my JavaScript
tutorial, it it is in in depth, okay,
based on the JavaScript language
specification
for correctness. Okay. So,
so back to um
so we digressed over. So what uh back to
uh so you know I was talking about why
I was talking about why am I proud of
my some of my tutorials and for what
reason. Okay, that is the thing I'm
talking about. Close that. showing
browser.
Okay, let's write it down. So, let's
make it um
like let's create a table of contents of
what we were talking about today.
So, we digressed over. So,
we were just talking about
Why I am proud of some of my programming
language tutorials
and the specific
reason
reasons for each. Okay, that is what we
are talking about
in the past uh 20 minutes. Okay, now let
me go back to the JavaScript. Let me let
me go back to this page. This is the
index of programming of my programming
language tutorials. Okay, so make a
link. Okay,
so we were talking about that. Then we
were talking about um the storytelling
style.
Okay. And we gave a example of the
storytelling style uh programming
language tutorial by by that guy by um
by this eloquent JavaScript guy. Okay.
So, hold on a second.
What? What?
Okay, that's my JavaScript tutorial and
I wanted to go to
uh JavaScript book review. So, let's
copy that.
And uh that also we talked about uh
that's something significant that we'll
show you in a minute.
And we also talk about we were talking
about the eloquent JavaScript. this
script.
Oh god.
Let's let's let's not uh
let's just copy that
fourth edition 2024. So he's been
updating his tutorial
um so that
okay so let's link it
uh so
so we were talking about so let's
summarize so I were talking about why
I'm proud of my programming language
tutorial and spec and the specific
reasons for H.
Okay. So, let's go uh elaborate. Okay.
So, I uh explained
language tutorial. Okay.
Okay. So,
okay. So, hold on a second. So, wait.
So, you need that that. Okay. So
draw.
Okay, I think the questions are piled
up. Let me answer the question. Okay. Uh
why didn't I use swboard data hand?
Well, that's because it's just I I got
um because I got personal
problems, you know, the um
so this is a major project in order to
do. So, but I got like I got lots of
things I need to
kind of So, it's it's kind of a um
procrastination issue. Okay. So if you
want to know so that is the reason. So
like this been like he gave it to me two
years. I I really like it. I really want
to use it but
but it's kind of a project you see
because you can't just hop onto it and
start to use it because you need to
learn and you know and which is very
interesting. You know usually I get
started if I just touch it like every
day. Um but but then but if it's a
project which is this is like because I
have lots of plans then it started to
get delayed because I got
I got lots of code to do uh in AI and
mathematics. So that is kind of why I
have not um used it. Okay. So I hope
that answer your question. That is the
uh
Diego. I think I know you Diego.
Uh I think uh on on is it on Twitter or
some something a bit
Okay. So I I think I rambled all over.
So uh God, I don't know what. So let's
see. Uh let me just finish the questions
then.
What benefit will wam give me as a
hobbyist programmer? Oh, that's the best
thing. Wuam language is the best for
hobbyist programmer. So, let me just put
it shortly. It gives you one programming
language. Think of it is a the most
powerful
calculator on earth. Okay. Today is a
bit more beyond calculators because AI.
So, it's kind of answers to any any
question. So, you can you think of it.
But wam language is not like AI chat
chatbot. So it um anyway think of it
just like the most powerful
like tool a person can have
uh like think of all programming
languages Python all of them combined
and all so easy made so easy and
consistent
to use. So that would be wam language.
Okay. 30 years ago that kind of idea is
in lisp programming languages
because lisp is a programming language
is like you just have one thing okay one
system one thing that will just do
everything anything everything possible
okay it's just consolidated into one
thing that is lisp not eac lisp but that
basically eventually lisp died so it
became kind of became common disp but
common disps of problems lots of ugly
[ __ ]
So anyway the the so why why would uh
wolf language benefit you for hobbyist
it it's the greatest for hobbyist
because as a hobbyist you you might have
as I assume you are a nerd so you are
you have interest in physics in
chemistry in diverse things in uh
neuronet networks in uh in all sort of
algorithms in programming in graph
theory in mathematics in differential
equation. So you want you want one thing
to do them all. Okay? and in the in the
most easy way. So you don't have to
spend a lot of time to like like Linux
you know um and figure out you know ask
questions you know that would be wam
language okay that is why I bought it 30
years ago when I was young I wanted to
be a great mathematician
I just want one tool I want the best do
everything
is emac script easy to learn for a nonp
programmer Um
it's not called Emacs script. Okay, it's
called Emacs Lisp because Emacs script
that confuses with a JavaScript uh
because the official name for JavaScript
is ECMAS script. Okay, very confusing e
ECMA script the that's the official name
for JavaScript the programming language.
Uh, and so ECMAS script. So it kind of
sounds like the emac sounds like
sounds like Emacs, you know, lisp
programming language, but Emac Lisp was
never called a script. Well,
technically, I guess it's a it's a
scripting language using Emacs, but it
was never called script. You just say
lisp. Okay, so emac lisp or elisp in
short. So is so you are saying is it is
easy to learn.
I wouldn't I I wouldn't you know it's
not difficult but but if you really want
to compare which is easier to learn
let's say compare to like what to Python
and to JavaScript.
So among these three they kind of all
the same. Okay, I mean that I mean not
the same but the level of learning
difficult how easy or how difficult to
learn them compare EMAC this and
JavaScript and Python for example among
these three
I think they are in the same level of
difficulty
uh it's just that they are quite
different because when you learn
JavaScript
you just not just the language you know
then you have to learn the DOM
Okay, when you learn JavaScript, you
have to learn
JavaScript by itself is very convoluted.
You know, variables, strings, then then
properties, then objects and
inheritance. It very complicated because
bad design. But then after you learn
JavaScript, you learn a lot of time as
you go years after years. Then but then
you then the actual coding of JavaScript
relies on DOM which is the browser uh
functions and stuff that is another
chapter. Okay. So
learning JavaScript to actually write
practical web websites is actually
I would say the most difficult learn
Emac this and Python.
Okay. Now for Python that depends on
what you do. I mean Python I I I so if
you just write hello world you know
Python
um
so Python that depends on what you do
but if you just write pure tutorials or
I mean academic toys for example the
advent of code then Python language is
not not hard. Okay, not too hard
easy. But then depends on what you want
to do actually with Python. Is are you
going to do webdev? Are you do are you
writing a server? Are you writing you
know this artificial intelligence? Are
you writing a chatbot? Then it becomes
you know then then it becomes more
complicated because you have to download
the right libraries. You got the right
environment. And then you know fairly
can get very complicated
right for example if you want Python to
uh write webdev you know you need a
framework almost uh so then learning a
framework is the entire thing okay and
same thing with JavaScript
now emacisp
well the eag list then you uh then the
issue is that then of course you deal
with emacs Okay. So everything you do
is in this text editor environment.
Okay. So you have to learn new concepts
such as cruer, you know, like this is a
cruer. How do you delete text? How do
you, you know, grab uh text between
different positions, grab them into save
it as a string in a variable, things
like that. So and you can control the
font size
uh you know
anyway so among
JavaScript python eag this I think the
difficulty of learning them is kind of
the same similar okay and also then
compared to Java or C or C++ okay uh for
example Java and C++ that would be
actually somewhat more difficult I would
say because they they are compiled
languages and they and Java is like lots
of OP [ __ ] C++ is a magnitude worse
worse.
Okay, because C++ is like just pure [ __ ]
like Java. I mean like JavaScript.
Okay. So if you learn C++ or Java that's
that's that's a magnitude more difficult
than JavaScript eagisp or Python. Okay.
I'll stop there. I think that answers
your question. And of course by the way
I have an article on that.
search for
which programming language is easier to
learn. So I have an article on that
uh
you know I have like thousands of
articles I have like 10,000 articles
written in the past 30 years. There it
is. Which programming language to learn?
Which programming language is easier to
learn? So this one is written in 2019.
Is it actually up to date? Um, no. I I
think I I have
uh quite a few uh additions I wanted to
make but I don't have time. So anyway,
this article which programming language
is easier to learn 2019.
So I rank them easy Golan, Ruby, PHP,
Skimisp. Okay, that is true. That's
those are easiest
other wa language python e-mac this
powershell okay actually powershell well
I would put powershell to be more
complex okay powershell I turned out is
fairly complex then complex java
javascript closure pearl ok or camel has
okay now when you rank when you rank
how easy is to learn for programming
language it's It's uh it's not too
trivial because you see my list is kind
of simplified. I simply put them into
different categories
but but in reality it depends uh it
quite depend on quite a few things.
Okay. Um
you know it depends on quite a few
things. for example uh in the complex
category or camel and Haskell
uh well you know there's difference
between them okay so anyway then another
part so anyway but roughly I would say
this okay this this is how I would rank
them but then there is also which
programming language has best
documentation okay that's another
article then which programming language
is more expressive but remain and
readable. Okay. Then here is my rank
and
frame language powers. Well, you know,
so this is also another thing that's
difficult. So
I'm not sure you know. So I you know I
wrote this like at one time but now I
look at that
language is not easy to read. Okay.
because when it gets complex it can be
really hard to read. Uh so this is in
well okay so but the question is not
just readable it's but it's also
expressive you see if the question is
only about readability like which
programming language is more readable
how do you rank them then Python ranks
at the top it's the most readable okay
Python at the top and I would say and
and Java
Java and Python. If you only think about
readability, Java,
Golan,
and Python, they are at the top. Okay,
these three.
No, but you don't want just readability
because then because in in the case of
Java,
all these other languages, you write
something in one line, but in Java, you
need 10 10 lines.
So, is that what you want? So if you
have a program that's 10 lines in in
Ruby, Python, scheme, uh list, but in
Java it's 100 lines. Is that what you
want? But it's readable. It's more
readable, but 100. Is that what you
want? Not necessarily.
So you also want to consider
expressiveness.
You want to be able to make it short,
you know, packed pack content into a
line. Then then wuam language became
like became all of a sudden like be
became 100 times more than all of these.
Yeah, that is true. That that that is
true. So expressiveness. Okay. Because
wam language you know you you have to
watch my tutorial live stream hundreds
of them.
Uh it it packs you know expressiveness
and uh
yeah.
So but now the question is
if the question is just which one is the
most expressive
then wufam language is at at the top.
Okay let me let me tell you. So wuam
language is at top beyond all the
others. So one line wam language the
second most expressive would be
one line of wam would be 100 lines of
that. Okay. The second one would be um
The second one would be okay. I
Oh [ __ ]
Oh god. [ __ ]
Okay. So, how long have I been like uh
talking without showing my screen for
for for a long time? Oh, [ __ ] Uh wait,
did I what was the question I was
answering?
Where am I located? USA. Of course. I'm
in California. Why don't you use a
smartboard? Okay, I answered that. Oh,
yeah. I was answering that question. So,
uh,
okay. I think, uh, [ __ ]
you know. So, anyway, we digressed over.
So, okay. So, so this is what I think
about programming languages. Okay. So,
so the question is if you which which
programming language is expressive then
if I'm at the top for sure then the
second would be um let's say the most
expressive that would be not emac this
not Java the Java at is the last at the
bottom okay the least expressive okay uh
JavaScript
Golan is also not expressive Golan is
like template is like Java. Okay. Uh PHP
not really. Okay. Pearl. Okay. Pearl is
on top. Pearl. Ruby.
Uh
yeah. The most expressive after wolf ram
would be ruby
and pearl.
Okay. Uh and you know and maybe scheme
and closure. Okay.
Okay. Okay, that that is if you consider
expressiveness
but then the question here is
which one is more expressive but remain
readable you see then the then it's
become more difficult then I guess I
gave this order okay wan powershell ruby
uh scheme anyway
this is a crazy uh I mean
okay so I
So that's the answer about is emac
script easy to learn okay uh to a nonp
programmer okay so then you are talking
about a nump programmer in that case
um are you still here
for no nump programmer there is a book
for eac this for nonprogrammers okay
it's it's it's called um control hi
Right. So in Emacs you can uh it's this
one. Okay. An introduction to
programming in EMAC list. Okay. It's
written by uh by this guy who died about
six years ago.
What's his this guy? It's very annoying
that the GNU [ __ ] the richest Roman
they don't put author's name here. It's
like everything is just that gnu meaning
like it's like everything is
automatically created to Richard
Strowman. [ __ ] the guy. You know, you
you you should put the author name here,
okay? Like who you know the guy, you
know, he passed away. Okay. So,
and okay, so I can show you
uh book.
Okay. So wait um
uh died search for died programmer this
programmer Daniel wine web died author
of intro to emac this robot J chassel
died he died in year 2020 20 uh 2017
okay 2017 about 10 years ago so there is
this book this is a book for e for
introduction to eag like this but it's
for people who have never programmed
before never like you don't know what's
a variable you don't know what's a
function then you can read this book
okay
I write a little about Python oh here
fantastic so okay so if you write a
little about Python then I do not
recommend this book I if so if you are
interested in uh emac this I would
recommend and
just my book. Okay.
Yeah. Actually, so if you if you know
some Python, then just read my Emac this
basics. That's what I say. You you or
you can try to read this book which
comes with Emacs in every Emacs. Just
start Emacs. Press control I. Okay. Uh
wait control uh close that control I
then you go down there's a eag this
intro this one an introduction to
programming in emac this is written by
this guy Bob Chassel Robert
Chassel okay he passed away
uh it's the same book but it's bundled
in every Emacs okay but so this but this
book is for nonprogrammers people who
never programmed before. So what you'll
find is that very tedious and verbals
like like when I was learning eag this
about 15 years ago I tried to read this
like like you have to scroll like hund
like after 50 pages maybe I learned
something you know like what what does
how do you uh create a variable in Emacs
then you go 50 pages it talk about
things you already know what's a
function what like what is a variable
then you know then you learn maybe one
thing so I stopped. I actually didn't
read this book. You know, it's like two
verbals like idiotic. But it's designed
for people who never programmed
before. And every time you hear, you
know, people ask what book to learn Emac
this you you will hear this mentioned,
right? But you actually you never hear
you never I never heard anyone who
actually read this book and say it's
good. I I don't I don't think I ever
heard of that.
Uh okay. So that's um you know you know
but the book is I mean it's written in
you know English is good but you know
organization but I I think I I find it
too verbose. Okay that's why. So
okay. Uh so probably that's it for
today. So let me just clean up what we
talked about. So I want So we talked
about that go back to my talk show. So
this is topic is about um
uh we document what we talk about. Okay.
So this link um
is
emac this difficult to learn. Okay,
that's one question. And we also talked
about
which programming languages
is easy to learn. Okay, that's also what
we talked about.
Okay, we talked about that because EMAC
basics, that's my tutorial copy. We have
it. Uh,
okay. So that's my uh that close. And
what is this? Uh that's today's talk
show. Wait, is that
Yes.
Mhm. Wam language tutorial. Do we have
it?
Uh so we were talking about
we haven't checked the JavaScript. Well,
we we did uh JavaScript code. Okay.
WebGL. Yeah. So that is so that is about
will AI write JavaScript clock using SVG
or canvas?
Interesting question.
It turns out it use none.
It used neither. Okay, that that was the
question we asked. Will AI write
JavaScript clock using SVG or canvas?
Interesting question. It turns out it
uses neither. Okay, so that is that
comes before that.
Okay, then we talked about Yeah, that
that web actually. So um
okay. So
okay we started talking about
JavaScript.
Uh what is this? Uh
okay so
merge the section.
Okay remove the date.
remove the todo. Okay. So we talked
about SVG clock then guac then we uh the
guac code result. Uh why so I started to
talk about why I'm proud of some of my
program language tutorial. Uh so wuam
language JavaScript. So we mentioned
emac this wam language javascript. Okay
we talked about those three.
Okay. So, uh,
so let me just, um,
uh, you know, this live stream, you
know, what I wanted to say is that I'm
not sure what to do in live stream
anymore. Uh that's why I started to talk
about
uh how AI made programming language
tutorials obsolate
because today you know anything you want
to know learning you know anything about
learning or something you just ask AI
okay so what is the purpose of life you
know like uh you know programming
tutorial from language like you don't
need me to show you you know I spend
hours to you know like code this
you can ask AI
uh so is it the human touch you need
well maybe it's just that you know just
like so you can watch another human uh
talk about things
so there's a question about uh
what's your opinion on California OSH
verification law. What What is the OSH
verification law?
What does OS stand for?
So with AI, you know, I I detect this
significant change in society, not just
me, you know, but you know, since like
two years ago, since a year ago at
least, you know, this it seems like
Twitter traffic went down
because today, you know, you don't need
humans to teach you. You don't need you
know all the like question and stack
overflow is all gone you know it's all
kind of dead or quora because you can
just ask AI and AI will give you the
answer is will be 10 times more correct
than a human being right so you don't
need any tutorials so what are we do you
know what are we here you know live
stream or whatever what are we here for
it seems just
just for the sake of like in a bar
chatting to a human like for
entertainment.
California digital age assurance act.
What the [ __ ] I don't I think it's
[ __ ] Okay. Already signed by Governor
Gavin. That that is the biggest criminal
in USA. Gavin Newsome. Okay. So one of
the most corrupt [ __ ] in USA but there's
something interesting I learned in the
past years about politics
you see because this you know Gavin
Newsome he belongs to a group but we
normally say the Democrats okay like in
USA you have the dem democrat versus
republican or the left versus right you
know it's heated fight
So but what I learned in past two years
those are just like fake
a bit more complex. Okay. Uh but hold on
a second let me finish this this this.
Okay. So this digital age assurance act
started by Gavin Newsen signed by Gavin
Newsen while signed requires all
operating systems including Windows,
Mac, Android, iOS, Linux and Steam to
collect age information during account
setup. Oh [ __ ] Oh [ __ ] What a [ __ ]
extreme scum.
What? And this what? This this is also
only in California. This
this cannot happen in U in USA, right?
And this but this is also only in
California. How is that possible or
legal?
So does that mean you know before I
install OS I just move to you know I go
outside of California then install it
then come back here or something and
also this operating systems requiring an
account to install is is the most nasty
thing you know starting with the late
Malaysenian Zuma [ __ ] like they
they are really [ __ ] they Oh no,
nothing. They they they kind of allowed
well they begin with the late Malay
genen. Okay, late Malaysian that's the
that's basically the social justice war
years
that generation. So, so in year 2016
they are around age 20. These people
created the situation where you begin
when you install operating system you
started to need account
you know you shouldn't need a account to
even install operating system not even
to answer like how old are you like you
don't first of all you don't need an
account to do it but this late Malay
chen begin with the social justice
warriors
[ __ ] idiots you know some some of
them are idiots. Most of them are
idiots, but some of them are just
extreme criminals like the Mark
Zuckerberg.
He kind of began it all. And Jack
Dorsey, Jack Doors, the guy who created
Twitter, okay, they kind of set it set
the whole thing up. extreme scums. They
started to have then they started to
have like uh app stores like every every
software must be uh centralized from app
store you know right if I talk this you
I don't know how you guys feel you you
guys feel like I'm strange right
it's like it was there's no app store
before before let's say 2010 you don't
go to like centralized
place to download software software you
you should be able to download anywhere
but then they started to have app store
beginning with Apple of course Apple
then like everything is on app store
like it's it became impossible for you
to install a software from other other
place
became a norm so app store became a
thing so you you got app store for
apples for different operating system
then Microsoft have one then the Linux
[ __ ] also have one you know
um so this incredible downfall of the
state
so age you know so they require a so
that's uh key requirements s
self-reported age
no photo ID or official recognition is
required what the [ __ ] idiocy
so first of all this law is no good then
no photo ID require Then what? Then what
is good for? What is it good for?
The operating system must categorize
users into one of four age groups under
13, 13 to 15, 16 to 17 or 18 plus. This
extremely collapsed, you know,
enforcement and penalties two 2,500 per
affected child.
You know, this this this is the collapse
of USA. Okay, that's what this this is
collapse of USA. First of all, it's not
effective. It's like
if you going to require age
verification,
then you need photo ID and face
recognition, but then it says no, it's
self-reported age, you know, it um
do not require photo ID. Then what? Then
then this law is like useless.
So, it's not effective. First of all,
it's it's just it's just a show.
But then, you know, you got this two
two,500
penalty. This is like a collapse. You
know, this is this this is this is a
indication of the collapse of USA. Okay.
That's what I think.
Uh okay. So, let let me go back to about
talking about the Democrat versus the
Republican. you know, it's a thing, you
know, right? The social justice warriors
back in, you know, 10 years ago, they
started this all things. Um, are you in
Brazil?
Uh, okay. So, so they started this uh,
you know, social justice war years, you
know, for example, the black life
matters or the in USA you have feminism,
then then trans, you know, gays and
trans and stuff.
uh sex is a construct then you have to
say a pronoun you know that you know I'm
I'm called the something that my name is
dragon you must respect me call me a
dragon things like that
so this collapse of USA then um so I
thought you know so you know these are
lefties right they sometimes they they
uh the the right
the right-wing people call them
communist. You know, there's a hatred of
communism. So, there's a big fight.
But then the war, you know, the certain
mass killing happened in Middle East.
Okay. In the past two years,
then the the the things started to
change. You you started to know lots of
things. you you know I don't know
nothing about it two years ago but but
then I started to read every day you
know news video
then you realize there's there is
something you know the left and right
that's not that's not a thing okay
so I I don't I rather not you know I
don't want to go into the detail But
but but this this this war between left
and right, what you know what I want to
say is that um
it's hard to it's hard to say. It's hard
to make sense. Okay. It's hard to make
sense. But one thing
sure is that you know you don't want to
just blame left. That's wrong. That's
That's a deep state trap. Okay, that's
not what actually happens. It's fairly
complicated.
Okay, I think I rambled all over, but
let me go back to like summarize create
a index page of what we talked about.
And that's it for today. Um,
thank you for mentioning that that OSH
thing
canvas. So, we talked about
uh
[ __ ] So, I'm not very happy with
today's live stream
because I'm rambling all over.
No go
uh and uh basically useless. It's just
random. It's basically random chat. You
know, there's a lot things I talked
about today.
It'll be much useful if if it's
organized into, you know,
several videos.
Um
anyway I in general I just I you know in
general like I do not feel good lately
in in the past month
partly is because all the war you know
like today there's another war going on
that's the biggest uh very depressing
um so That's that's you know that's one
thing but
so I'm not too happy. Okay. In the past
a month in the past month I haven't been
too happy.
Um
so anyway let let's get back to this. Um
so actually now I forgot what
I were I were talking about before.
So I talked about
why I am proud of JavaScript. Okay. So I
talk about emac this wolf ram in
JavaScript. Okay.
So
so I talked about why am I proud of my
JavaScript tutorial. Okay. Then I talked
about why I am proud of my language
tutorial, JavaScript tutorial is because
basically
most in depth
of all my program language tutorials.
Okay,
that is why. Now why am I proud of my
woofam language?
because
um
one language tutorial is rare and mine
is rather unique.
um rather the only one
focused
for industrial programmers.
Okay,
that's a that's a reason specific reason
why I think my wuam language tutorial is
great. The only one focused for
industrial programs programmers is uh
Wuam.
Well, anyway, so I talked about that.
So, let me go back to let me show you.
So, let me elementary. So, one of the
book is elementary um
introduction by Stanford Wolf, which I
mentioned. Uh let's go. Um
so, actually I have a review. So, I
wrote a review. So then I so we I tal I
also talked about
a review element of Stefan Wuam's book.
Okay.
Then I also talked about so close that
then I also talked about so close that
then I also talked about Yeah. So here
which is the uh fast introduction
language fast intro. So I I I I
talk about this this so this this is
similar to my book okay like wra
language for programmers for industrial
programmers
for example you came from Python Java or
C++ or you know
so and what I'm saying is that um this
is not in depth okay
So what I'm saying is that
so copy that. So let me let me do this.
Okay.
Right now I'm like um what
I'm like writing a index of the things I
talked about today. Any more questions?
Okay.
by wolfam research.
Okay. So that is the um
this is close to mine but I think it I
think mine is better because
um
this is this is close to my tutorial.
But I think
it is not in depth. Okay, that is the
reason
that so so let me summarize
again. Repetition.
So who else are here still? Do I make
sense?
So again, so repetition. So let's see.
Um, so we talked about Okay. So uh
programming languages practical SVG. So
the beginning the reason we were talking
about this programming language tutorial
is because
we haven't wrote that that's the
beginning that's the origin of all this
talk about programming language
tutorial.
How AI is making uh today's AI is making
programming language tutorials obsolete.
Okay. That is that's how we begin to
talk about tutorials. Okay. Then then I
start to talk about
what is
what
the difference between
programming language tutorial written by
AI versus human that is the essence
that's essential question okay and
eventually after like 40 minutes we
discovered
interactively dynamically we discovered
that
after some 30 minutes talking and
exploration.
I discovered
actually there is
no
essential difference.
Okay. And I think and and uh
great not theory insight. Okay,
there's no difference.
And then we talked about like AI
generated. Then we talked about AI
generated um
you know that uh almost like porn. I
mean, we were talking about AI generated
um videos.
Okay. So we were talking about that.
Then we were talking about okay huge
digression into
uh my tutorials SVG and WebGL canvas
versus SVG and canvas tutorial. Then AI
generated code. Then um why am I proud
of my JavaScript tutorial or warm
language tutorial or and then a review
of
okay then my review
uh Wam's Stephan Wam's book this one and
let's put uh put here
and uh this this is a book title. Okay.
So,
that's a book title. Okay.
Okay. So,
review of that.
So So I did a review
of Stefan Wuam's book. Okay.
Then I did a review of the fast intro in
introduction to for programmers re uh
tutorial by Wufra. Okay. Then I talked
about JavaScript other JavaScript books.
The um Okay. So we talked about
the storytelling style of books. Okay.
So that is even before wolf map. So
uh well so wait
okay so hold on a second.
So we
okay JavaScript tutorial. So,
so that
that
that Okay. So,
do you guys see what I'm doing? I guess
not. But it will become clear pretty
soon.
JavaScript book review and which uh
programming language is easy to learn.
So, we did this um
so we did this. Yeah, we were talking
about this JavaScript. Uh,
what
[ __ ] did we
Okay, so let's
AI generated videos. Yes. So that is the
URL.
So you need to give it a URL.
So that's a thing. Okay. Then
then
we talking about tutorials. Um
so we AI write JavaScript clock. So
that's a different topic. JavaScript
clock. Okay, that's very interesting.
Uh so
let's put that there. So that's the SVG
clock.
So we were talking about SVG then we
started to talk about this clock. So let
me show you guys what's up there. So you
see today's AI is making programming
language tutorial obsolate. That's the
beginning
kind of talk. What's the difference
between programming language tutorial
written by AI versus human? We spend
like 30 minutes on that. After some 30
minutes talking and exploration, I
discovered actually there is no
essential difference and I think this is
a great insight.
So there is no uh there is some uh
uh no essential difference and I think I
think there's a spelling error. There is
is there is no essential difference.
Okay. Double is
okay. Refresh. say done fixed discussing
about AI generated videos. Okay. So that
video is is like AI is almost doing porn
and uh that's related because we want to
see the spirit. I mean can I can the AI
generated stuff have a soul? The answer
is
yes because soul is actually not well
defined. We always think you know
there's a difference because this one
got a soul but actually no because if
you have a blind test of two things you
can you without knowing you know which
one is human you cannot tell which one
is got the soul. Okay. like
then we uh talk about so SVG SVG and AI
so uh AI generated clock where is it
uh where is the AI generated clock
we did this today where is the clock um
where is the code.
Oh [ __ ] Did I override it
back
clock
there? Okay. So, it's here. Yeah. So,
this AI generated clock. Let's put it
here.
Amazing.
Yeah. So, there it is.
So, that AI generated clock. We haven't
got to fix it. Oh, there's interesting
thing. We want to see how it how it
creates this um this thing.
Uh yeah. So that we have we haven't
looked yet. But very interesting is that
it um
so it's amazing. It just use uh DSS. It
doesn't use SVG at all.
Oh [ __ ] How advanced? Incredible.
So, this is even better than mine
because my my SVG clock actually uses
um SVG. I mean, yeah. Yeah.
You know, I actually use SVG. So if you
do not use SVG is actually simpler. Um
but SVG is kind of the
proper way because
SVG is designed
for graphics especially this line
graphics line circles. Okay.
Well, you can use C CSS for simple if
your clock is simple.
But let's say if you wanted to
let's say if you want a clock with
kind of transparent casing showing the
internal
delicate
gears of a watch.
In that case,
CSS would not be appropriate, would be
too complicated, would it?
Anyway, so it's very interesting that AI
just uses um CSS
and we haven't figured out how it makes
the hand second hand shake. So that's
something we can try to find.
So set interval update clock every uh
every 1 second uh or was it 1
millisecond
I mean so here's a code so second hand
update
so update so you want to look at this
function okay update block.
So this function is very short. [ __ ]
extremely
short.
30 lines of code. Jesus.
And and and amazing. It's using uni
code. Can you see that? You see this
this unic code degree symbol? It's a
that's a unic code degree sign. Okay,
that character.
So AI is generating you know uni code
degree symbol there. So 6° per second.
What is say saying 6° per second?
Uh okay. So it actually creates
comments.
Okay. Okay. But update clock. So, so now
new date then second now second minutes.
Okay. Then okay. Every time you get a
new date
then you have seconds, minutes and
hours. So second degree is how many
second? Oh
wow. So simple logic.
Second degree = 2 seconds * 6.
1 second is 60°. I see. Is that right?
Yes, that's right. 60. That's right.
Because 6 * 60
is 360.
1 second. So 360 is is the all the
degrees in a circle. So that is why
right 1 second is 6°. So it's simply
time six. Okay. And minute is equals to
um
minute degrees
is equals to
6° per minute plus 0.1
degree per second. Okay.
The mini hand, then the hour hand.
Wow. So, it goes by degrees. Then you
just Oh, okay. So, you just rotate. You
do the style transform.
Okay. But what is the Okay. So, the the
the elements are these. Okay. The second
hand. You see these are the elements.
document query selector that selects
element. So now you need to look at
Wow, amazing. So this is truly
this is good. Okay. Syntax color it
show.
Oh, okay. It doesn't syntax color
nothing close it. Um but
but okay. So where's the numbers come
from? So you want to look at the um
so the code here does not include the
numbers. Okay,
but the numbers must be in the CSS. So
here is a CSS. Okay, CSS is only 100
lines. Okay, now let's
uh syntax
formated pretty formatted
and uh so here is body is clock. So we
want to look at the numbers. Okay,
hand, our hand, mini hand, second hand,
center dot. Now what is the center dot?
Okay.
Numbers. Okay. So, here is numbers
position.
Oh,
wait. So, wait.
Okay. So, why is it position absolute?
Okay.
Uh numbers optional but nice. Okay. So
wow amazing position absolute number
span. What is this
now? What what are the uh put it back.
Search for number.
Wait, what is the number? So those are
the number styles. So but so this class
are numbers.
Okay. But
so these numbers are
you see if you remove it, refresh, it's
gone, right? So you put it back. Um
so the numbers let's see the numbers
each one is just a number. Okay then you
say transform rotate translate. Okay you
translate
and rotate.
You translate and rotate.
Amazing.
Uh amazing the AI really.
So the number
span
there is no span in it. Now there is
number then span type number span.
Okay.
Then so number then anything children
span
position absolute width and height.
Uh
Do you fix this though?
Okay. So, you need to find where is this
clock
clock center dot then
Okay. So,
maybe put the number outside.
No.
X and uh X and Y
numbers clock.
So you got numbers class here. Then you
got class hand.
Amazing. Truly amazing.
Okay. So, I was trying to fix this, but
um
Okay, I need I need a break actually.
So,
So we were coding this but we didn't do
any of that.
We were just digressed about AI.
So the nasty question
AI is here. What we going to do?
Oh god.
Okay. But but right now you need to fix
this. So what is this?
So Okay. So right now,
okay, here's the thing. Let's focus on
fixing this. Okay, let's see if we can
do that. I'm pretty sure, but
Okay, hold on a second.
I need a break. So, be back. Be back
five minutes.
Okay, I think let's have a drink then.
Let's have a shot of
this quart. Okay, that's that's Chinese
vodka kind of.
So this is what live stream is for for
entertainment.
The chocolate. A friend gave us
chocolate. Chocolate.
Okay. I think my wife is back pretty
soon.
Okay. So, let's
we're going to fix this. Okay. Fix this
JavaScript
chocolate. Okay.
So, first of all,
our hand. So first of all well
you see here's a code you know show in
browser that's code pretty short you
know whole thing is 150 lines okay
the JavaScript is here it's only 30 30
lines okay
put it back then the CSS um then the
HTML is only 20 lines okay
basically this whole thing. That's just
so simple.
You You just got a clock. Okay. Then you
got uh let's highlight it. You just got
a clock. Then you got center dot. Then
you got numbers I class. Then you got
our hand meaning hand second hand. Okay.
Now let's look at the
so let's see. So this this whole HTML
you see if you delete it refresh this
organ just this HTML simple.
Now this center center dot you see
search for center
do we have center dot doesn't even have
a style. What?
Wait.
Uh it does. Okay. So, so center dot is
um
refresh center dot is that. So, center
dot and
the uh center dot and the hands. Let's
look at the hand. Okay, let's look at uh
hand position absolute.
Absolute m means make it a own layer.
Okay, so let's fix this. Let's just fix
it. Okay. So, you go to my CSS tutorial.
If you have something, say hi. Say hi.
Okay. You go to my CSS tutorial and uh
position absolute. So, that's about
layout. So, layout and layers. Okay.
Layout and layers. Position attribute. I
mean all property. Click on that.
So, position you got uh static,
relative, fixed, absolute. Absolute
means new layer. Okay. Relative to its
containing block. Okay. Okay. Absolute
is the most complex one. [ __ ]
Okay. Go back here. Close that. Close
that. Okay. hand position absolute goes
into its own layer
bottom left uh and uh 5050. Okay.
So it goes into its own layer and the
own layer is um what is the parent
because this bottom and left percentage
they are relative to the parent of this
thing. Okay.
So if you search hand, our hand, mini
hand, second hand. Okay. So the parent
of this thing is clock.
Okay. So they so their position are
relative to this clock's position.
Okay. So let's search clock. So do we
have clock? Yes, we do. So the clock's
position is this.
Width 320. Width, height, background,
border, radius. We don't care. We don't
care. We don't care. Position relative.
Okay.
Jesus.
Yeah. So, so this is like what the [ __ ]
Okay.
Put back. Uh, make a backup. Okay. So,
we start to change this clock.
Let's see. Uh, well, put it back. Um,
yeah. So, you see that's why this that's
that we kind of already fixed it. What?
Okay. So, we
Yeah. So, that that is a problem. width
and height.
Okay. So, put it back. So, refresh.
Okay. Width and height.
Uh, let's get the border. Okay. So,
border
what?
Border radius 50%. Wow. So, that
actually that does it.
So, but anyway, so let's let's uh let's
do this. Okay,
let's replace the clock by
X clock. Okay, so so that way we don't
confuse with other things you see.
So it's more unique. Okay, show. Okay,
same problem.
Now um
okay actually so why don't we just focus
on getting this fixed instead of playing
around. So okay so width and height if
you delete it.
Okay wait
that's a clock. Okay.
Clock width and height.
Wait, why is that?
Now, what color is this? Let's just say
red.
Okay.
Okay. So, that So, this is the border.
Border radius. Make it round and box
shadow. We don't care. Okay. So, but
this width and height and uh
crocs got width and height and uh
and hand is correct. Hand is correct.
But the thing that's incorrect is a
number. Okay, it's a numbers
optional ind that. Okay, numbers. Okay,
optional. Delete that. So, let's rename
numbers to X numbers because that way
it's more unique. Wait. Yeah. Yeah. So,
three occurrence. Okay.
One, two, three. Okay. Now, this one is
part of the HTML. So it number is a dive
and let's it's got a bunch of numbers.
So let's let's say TDT. Okay, let's just
for experiment. So there it is.
You so so you can see this TT let's say
ABC. That's kind of the
center. Okay. So now you can see the
whole numbers got moved to the right.
And I started to see the problem.
But why is the AB singing? Um,
but why is it above? There shouldn't be
above, right?
So, because when you have let's say
uh
Okay. But anyway, this number
number spam.
Okay, that's another position absolute.
Let's just say number. Okay, position
absolute.
Now, what does absolute mean? Absolute
means relative to its containing block.
Okay. So, so number
position absolute absolute relative to
the containing block. Okay. And uh you
are uh you forgot to say left and right.
That's why you are incorrect.
That's right.
You forgot to say bottom or left.
You see? Because whenever you say
position absolute
you have to say top bottom or left right
for alignment.
Right. Yes. Right. Yes. Right. Because
when you say position absolute which is
this one. So absolute. Let's look into
the detail. Uh what?
So position absolute you need to say
a goto
gambe.
No gambe, but cheers.
Okay, so back to position. Position
you want it to be um
absolute means relative to the parent
block. end in uh in its own layer. Okay.
So, position is quite tricky
and powerful but it's it's I don't think
it's well designed very complex. It's
the most
CSS position property is the most
complex part of CSS cascading
stylesheet. Okay, let me tell you guys
it's the most complex part
more complex than uh than than the flow
than the grid than the which I don't
have it's a new thing I I don't have a
tutorial yet actually it's been around
like 5 10 years anyway position is the
most complex thing in cascading
stylesheet
and well it's powerful okay but it's not
good well designed okay so position
possible values is you got static,
relative, fixed, absolute and absolute
is actually the most useful because it's
it it create it puts the elements in a
new layer independent of what comes
before or after. Okay, so it becomes a
new layer and but it is positioned with
respect to
its parent element. Okay. So it's you
see in a new layer
but not with respect to the window like
for example when you have position fixed
then it's in a new layer like this menu
you see doesn't matter where you scroll
that menu stick
to a fixed position with respect to the
window or view port. Okay. So doesn't
matter what's what size is your window.
You see that that thing is always on the
top right corner because I have position
fixed
and
right zero top zero. So it stick to
right hand side and top.
But when you have position absolute it
goes into its own layer but it's
relative to the parents. Okay. So here
is position absolute for the number
and relative to the parent. But however
you don't have the left and right top
bottom thing. Uh so let's go to
absolute. So you you need to say um you
see you need to say this uh
left right or top bottom. Okay. So it's
missing.
So when you are missing uh let's add it.
Okay. So uh actually
okay. So let's say top uh let's say top
zero uh left zero. Okay. Put it back.
Show in browser.
Okay. So number
time zero is it uh zero should work. Uh,
px. Okay.
Refresh
position top. Let's say right
does not change a thing. Height, uh,
text align, color, font size, but it's
respect to the parent. So what is the
parent? The parent is X clock. So does X
clock has a um So what is X clock? X is
dive. Okay. So X clock got width
height 320. Why 320? Like what do why is
this strange? I mean that's Can you say
500? I mean just can you talk?
Okay.
There. Okay. Well, then you need to
change hand size. The clock hand size.
Okay.
There it is. Uh width and height. Okay.
Uh what the heck? You know, then clock
uh hand is you know with height.
Okay.
So but uh but
but for all the talk you did not fix
this.
Jesus. Okay. So let's quickly so if our
goal is just to fix that. Can we uh
actually quickly?
Yes. I think so. Uh we want to go to the
number part. Let's say right and left.
Uh okay. This should be top, right? Top.
So, top 50 uh 50 pixel.
That works. Let's say 100 pixel 200
pixel.
Let's say uh let's say percent 50% or
something. Okay. Showing. Oh, that's
almost close.
Okay. So 50% 297
46%.
Okay.
Okay. 42%
kind of right.
And uh what about change the left? The
left is going to be uh 50%. Let's say
50%.
Wait percent. Okay. Okay, that's uh
20%.
Okay, 0%.
Okay, then is right.
Okay, right.
10%.
Okay, close. uh
12%. Okay, it's very close. Now, let's
remove the XYZ.
Remove that the things that we added.
Okay, close.
Good.
Anyway, right now I'm in a kind of
zombie state because I don't enjoy this
is like
wasting time.
Uh this number. Okay. So, you need to
like because right now this is just
hacking. So, 12% that's too much,
right? 10% actually. Actually,
it's kind of works. Okay.
And uh
one more thing you see the numbers
you see they use SVG you know they can
use um
well yeah they use the they use CSS
transform
to rotate the numbers
you see but you don't normally you don't
want the numbers rotated
you want the position of the numbers
rotated the numbers themselves. You
don't want them to
twist
their orientation
just
so you know we can fix it. So, but how
do you so how can you have
numbers such that you change their
position but you do not change their
orientation.
How do you do that in CSS? Easy.
Just use position abs. Uh wait wait wait
what?
Just use position absolute you know like
we were doing.
So, so, so you remove this um
remove this rotate and translate. Yeah,
actually you don't need rotate. You just
need translate. Can we do that?
Actually, it should be easy.
And no, wait.
Uh what
now? What is the order?
Oh god, this [ __ ] stupid. Okay, this
AI code is not too good.
You should be able to remove the rotate.
Then in the translate, you need to put
the number there. So, so what you do is
Yeah. So, so this number will be s
cosine. Okay. So, these two numbers. So
each one you want to translate and those
numbers will came from s cosine and uh
can you actually have s cosine in from
CSS?
Um
I think you can you know let's ask AI
cosine let's say sine cosine in CSS
translate you know let's just ask that
brave browser I recommend brave browser
and brave search okay yes you can use
sign cosign function directly within CSS
translate. Oh,
Cheers.
Okay, I'm starting to get drunk.
Uh, okay. So,
yeah, but Okay. So, you have to use
calculate
Oh Jesus, CSS is really getting complex.
You have to use calculate and uh Okay,
that's another good question. Save.
Close. Okay. So, we also talked about
uh we talked about lots of things but we
did not actually even
uh
we did not actually even finish writing
a index of the things we talked about.
Okay. But here is the AI answer.
Not what we want. Okay.
Excuse me. So, save it.
So, he's talking about um you see he's
talking about um
Okay. So he's talking about let's see uh
let's go to CSS
search for CC
calc so in CSS you got this calc which
is a function in CSS which is rare
okay so you can use that to compute but
uh but what is so you can you have
arithmetics
uh but you can also have s cosine which
I did not mention so my tutorial is
getting outdated.
Yeah, it's annoying. And also, you know,
I've been thinking about this because if
you are a writer for programming
language tutorials,
you have to update it every few years,
right? But it seems like like it's it
never ends. Okay? So if you have a
tutorial for a programming language, it
looks like
the update the changes to the
programming language almost never ends.
And
the interesting thing is that
it's not necessaries necessarily. So in
other words, people are adding things
for the because of power struggle due to
politics, not because the programming
language truly needs to change
or have additions.
Okay, very interesting question because
you know if you are a programmer
or a programming language tuto tutorial
writer you know you thought you learned
the programming you know language you
mastered it because let's say you coded
for five years or 10 C++
Java you know JavaScript or even Python
but after five years you noticed oh they
made some change
uh I mean they made some maybe you know
like somewhat significant change
and typically and of course you accept
it
obviously because as life goes on things
change you know I mean computers improve
and so you have some bug fixes and so on
it's very common in operating systems
and so on
but you but then you realize when you
are you know 20 years old then you are
25 years old. Then you are 20 30 years
old. Then you are 35 years old. Then
then you are 40 years old. Then you are
45 years old. Like your life passed
and and then you are 50 years old, you
know, like me 50 something. Okay. So
your your life is almost done. But but
you you started to see you know all
these changes. But they you you started
to see they still making changes.
Like to you, you thought you you've been
there, right? You've been there for 30
years, 40 years. Like the first change,
obviously, it's necessary, but then some
change, then some change change. So
again, again, then you start to see,
wait,
why are you changing them? You started
to have that question that which is what
I do because I wrote so many programming
language tutorials like CSS for example,
you thought it's done. you know, you
thought it's like
what possibly things do you want in CSS?
Okay, you got grid, you know, they but
they still change. They they they have
new units. Like for example, a few uh
month ago, we talked about the new units
cap cap cap IC, right? Wait, we got a uh
this one should be our IC. Okay. So, do
you actually know what is a unit IC? You
know, it's becoming like
incomprehensible.
Okay.
That is the problem.
See? Okay. So, this this is this should
be all I see. Okay.
You see here all I see height of Chinese
character for water. Okay,
for the of the root element. So you
notice that they actually do change
and then you start to think about are
they going to ever stop changing CSS
and or HTML like HTML you thought you
know it's kind of done right I mean what
else you want to add but they they do
actually make a change and then I
thought about this you know I started to
really think when when does a technology
ology like uh let's not let's narrow it
down. Okay, let's be precise. When does
a like programming language or markup
uh language like HTML when uh or uh for
example Java, Golan,
J, Python for example like when when do
they when should they or do they like
should they should the change be
forever?
Several questions regarding change
like
should a programming language have
changes every year forever? Is this like
forever thing forever? Forever and ever
until you die your son, your son's son,
grandson, your grandson, they will still
change. Is that true? That's one thing
you think about. Okay.
So it turns out, you know, so I started
to think about this. Uh it actually kind
of yes.
Well, yes and no. Like usually
the answer should be no. like because
because you don't want a necessary
change you know you you want you you
want for for example for a programming
language let's say Python
you want the change only when it is
important new feature new phenomenon in
computer uh in computer hardware you
know in programming science you know in
programming language design in the
science of programming language
design you know you started to think Oh
actually we if we have that it would be
much better a new feature for the
programming language right you thought
about that
but that that doesn't happen often so
but but how do you know because you know
after 10 years after 20 years you nobody
can predict the future what you thought
of
you know what happens in 20 years you
may never thought of you know it's like
predicting the future like what will
happen in 20 years like nobody actually
knows about the AI you know real AI what
will happen to AI we we we have we know
we don't know like right now we are just
you just hear lots of people babbling
you know but I mean the question is like
we so we are poing language change
forever
uh and is that is that right should it
change forever
and that related question is when will
programming language die like it does
happen in real life as far as we know in
history because many programming
language died. new language came by. You
know, Python,
you know, Pearl one time is the most
popular language, the top three for 10
years, over 10 years. But Pearl, Pearl
basically died like basically gun dead
gunfac
uh language. Okay. So you so you so you
you started to see um
pro some programming language will die
and for example Golang is pretty new
only 10 years old like 15 years old.
Okay. Um
so the question is like will it forever
change and then you started to realize
it's kind of yes and no. Okay. So yes in
some way but because why? Because
technology
will forever improve. It's almost like
forever. Like the question is will
technology ever stop
evolving? The answer to that is more
obviously no.
Like in 10 years we'll have technology.
We'll probably have technology we never
dreamed of. Okay. In 10 years or 20
years.
But the but the but then then then then
you kind of realized that's kind of true
for programming languages because for
now you you can never thought of what
what will happen you know what what is
it like in 20 years but we do know for
sure almost for certain
in 20 years the technology will be quite
different you know there's new things we
cannot even fathom
so if That's true. Then obviously it
will have some effect to programming
languages, right?
So will your programming language change
forever?
The answer is probably yes. Okay. So
forget about you learning a language,
you master it for 10 years. No, it's
going to change if you don't update. So
if you wrote a book uh of a on a
programming language or tutorial, it's
going to get outdated. Okay? It's so so
it's going to get outdated in five
years. In five years for sure if you
don't update it.
So then the other thing is but then but
when you look at the question you also
realized
many of the changes are not necessary.
Okay? Which which is the case for CSS.
Okay, like you you re you you look at
the changes, right? There's the you know
the standard update you can read about
them. You look at the changes then you
realize
some of the changes are not really
necessary like what the [ __ ] they doing.
Then you you you realize that some of
the changes are result of our struggle
you know like this standard organization
or versus Google commercial organization
or versus Apple they have some fight
they have personal you know they have
their own interest because they want to
make more more money right and Google
especially Google because Google like
almost all the technology for the web
the JavaScript HTML CSS have major
impact by Google by Google's behavior
and choices major because that's how
Google makes money. So Google actually
spent major money million millions
million tens of millions of dollars and
effort to to change CSS
JavaScript and HTML in browser and
especially the dome the browser standard
the the dome and boom the docu document
object model and browser object model
okay it's a heavy impact by Google so
but you so when you look at the question
must programming language or or or
protocol they change every year forever
then you kind of realize yes because
technology changes forever.
Therefore programming language must also
evolve forever or and thus they will die
and new ones will born when when old
ones becomes too difficult to change.
You you realize that that's one thing
but you also realize that some of the
changes are not necessary they are
result of power struggle by these
organizations. Okay. And I I think I to
me I felt that that happens through CSS.
Okay.
Um
to some degree. Okay. Maybe not not not
everything, but um
anyway, I think I'm somewhat
one shot of the
so let me answer the question. Um
beat town says, "My boss said he might
force us or to use GitHub copilot in VS
Code.
How do I pull off um how do I pull off
creating a shadow coding environment
with Emacs and a gentic AI?
I don't know. I guess you just you know
that that's interesting um comment.
So yeah, that's a you know that's an
interesting situation with the AI
co-pilot.
um you know AI writing code
what will happen to that
how effective is that
and what kind of impact it has it has
tremendous impact already but um but we
don't know for sure you see there's lots
of questions we don't know we you know
and there's a lots of fat and fake
information they are spreading like some
will say oh yeah AI is replacing all
coders. It's not true and actually we
don't know you know lots of these things
actually nobody actually knows. So
copilot and VS code of course VS code is
the most popular text editor for
programmers and copilot is part of it is
becoming you know m
sorry about that you know Microsoft is
promoting copilot very much.
Yeah. So anyway, I don't know how, you
know, I don't know what's going on.
I mean, I know what's going on, but I
cannot It's very It's like nobody knows
how to predict
uh
what will happen. Nobody knows. Okay.
as far as Emacs, you know. So, I'm a fan
of Emacs, of course, since because I've
used it so much for 30 20 years since
1987.
So, it's almost like 85 almost 30 years.
So, I've been using Emacs for almost 30
years.
I looked at VS Code. So um
you know but one major issue with VSCO
is because because it's a commercial
entity you know it's a giant commercial
organization therefore it's going to
bloat forever it's like absolutely going
to bloat I mean inefficient code for
sure you know for example we start VS
code just one file nothing else we just
open one file file actually two files
because of the automatic release notes
file okay we only open two files
nothing else and I don't I don't have
special extension installed I don't have
like
oh god downloading update you see it's
still it's still downloading update you
know I don't have any extra packages uh
installed but opening one file it's
taking 700 megabytes of memory. Okay.
Now it reduced to 500 megabytes.
Many processes you know it when you
begin it's 700 now it's like 460.
But if you look at Emacs
which I have um where is emac and see uh
wam language is only 80 megabyte. So
where where is emac there? Only 41
megabyte. You see? So how many files I
have? Not many. Three. Okay. 40
megabyte. 40 versus 400. So VS code is
taking 10 times more memory just just to
start. 470. 10 times more memory. I've
been you know this Emacs instance been
around for over hour, right? But VS code
is like 10 times more memory
that so be beside anything else the very
fact simply the fact that VS code is
created is a creature of a big giant
corporation million billion dollars
corporation Microsoft
it guarantees for sure there's no way to
escape it guarantees the VS code is
going to be bloated okay because They
they you know it's written by
programmers for hire right you go there
it's your job you you get a lot of money
you go there you just code you don't
really love the code that much you just
you know code whatever you know so that
it passes you know it passes your
um testing suit or whatever your your
your boss will look at your code you
know for your salary you know review or
whatever, that's all you care. So the
code is not really loved and therefore
you got bloat.
Well, for c for for hackers things like
Emacs, usually that's not the case
because for example, as you know, if you
don't know already,
uh my code is like my
fly keys and all my packages is like the
most um supreme tight tightly controlled
ideal code
there ever exist.
Let's let me delete my uh backup files.
Okay. So, for example, I have wait press
uh press. So, I have this custom command
to delete Emacs backup files
of all subdirectories in the current
directory and make a report. You see, it
doesn't ask me, are you sure this is a
file? It doesn't ask that. You see, you
just do it. Uh I think I live streamed
this uh did I a month or two ago? I
forgot. I forgot. Anyway, so now if you
refresh, you can see all my backup files
are gone. So anyway, these are my own
files. So this code, right? So because
when when when you hack when you um
write your own software, it became a
thing of love. Then it become a truly a
craft like artisan artistic craft
you know that's why that's what nuth
Donald
the eminent computer science scientist
is talking about the art of programming
but with corporations code that doesn't
happen much because you go to the job no
like nobody cares you wrote it your name
will be replaced it's not even in the
credit you know like for example Apple
you know they don't they don't care
about you this huge corporations right
they just care about
money you know they just want to make
more money and all you care is like you
you know you care only about money only
too you go to work you do whatever
and you get money that's what you care
you don't care about because you know So
that's VS Code
and it is most popular. Well, why is why
isn't Emacs popular? Because the Emacs
idiots, they got lots of other problems.
Uh anyway, open source problems. Okay,
so
what am I talking about? I think I got
to go.
Okay. So, uh I
kind of rambled. So, did I update the
update page? No. So, update today's
date. Today's date is being updated.
That's good. Close that show in browser.
So, did we finish writing the history of
what we talked about? No.
Okay. So
anyway, I'm unsure about these uh
unfocused live streams because then
I talked for like 3 hours. Wow. Today I
talked for three hours basically just
random.
And when you look at people like online,
you look at other streamers like today
today so many people stream even
professionals you know you you look at
their stream like nobody watches them
few hundred
even like for example wuam research
videos or professors professors talking
about giving a lecture about math or
something you only they only have like
200 200 views
uh which is the same situation with my
stream. So,
so I think that happens you know there
are so many streamers that happens all
over with millions like millions
actually I think millions of people were
doing streams and you know like some of
them even only 10 views 20 views
Okay.
So, let me just um do whatever that
The story of telling style uh tutorial
the storytelling. Okay,
the storytelling
should have a hyphen in between them
because otherwise the meaning is
changed. Okay, it's about English
athography.
So the storytelling style of tutorials
uh one example is eloquent JavaScript
written by Maragin Havbec.
Maragene Havbec I think that's a
northern European name. Is that right?
That I think Scandinavia like somewhere.
Is that right? Let's ask uh AI.
Okay. Let's ask guac because I um
Okay, guac.
That's JavaScript code we did today. We
asked that for um this is uh
what's the origin
re uh origin of the name
Maragin Havbec. I think it's like
northern Europe, Scandinavia.
Maring Havbec is a well-known Dutch
programmer and author.
It directly tell you who it is not just
the original of the name known for
eloquent JavaScript and projects like
code mirror. Okay. Oh, I haven't heard
of code mirror. I know he wrote some
other things.
Okay. So his first name is Dutch origin.
Oh, okay. Imagine first name. Habbeck
surname is a Flemish Dutch family name.
Okay. Typical of the low countries
Belgium and the Netherlands.
It's likely toponymic
derived from a place name.
Toponymic.
Okay. Okay. Belgium and you know Belgium
Dutch. That's kind of the area between
the England and the German.
Now, it's very interesting because I
always been thinking that the the white
men are the Brit and German. So, let's
ask some more question.
Um,
is the Dutch people uh mix of Germanic
and Brit?
I don't know if that question makes
sense, but let's just ask it.
It's a power of AI. Okay. No, the Dutch
people are not really a mix of Germanic
and Brit, meaning Asian Britain, Celtic
Britain from the British Isles. The
Dutch are predominantly Germanic in
their ethnic. Right, that's what I
thought. Linguistic and genetic origins,
which with roots tracing back to Asian
Germanic tribes like the Fians, Saxons,
and Franks. That's right. who settled in
the low countries modern Netherlands
starting around iron age especially
during the migration period okay that
makes sense because that's what I
thought because the Germanic you know
that they are the Germanic people which
later on moved to the Britain or invaded
Britain so that's why you got the Saxons
Anglosaxons
okay
anyway so So and also notice the
interesting word low countries that that
is actually proper now that's
means modern Netherlands okay
Netherlands literally means like low
countries I think cheers
genetically modern Dutch people cluster
very closely with other northwest West
Europeans especially especially northern
Germans, Vicians and to a lesser degree
Scandinavians. Okay. DNA studies show
strong continuity in the region from
prehistoric Germanic migrations with
some pre-Germanic
earlier western European hunter gather
and farmer input that was largely
overritten or absorbed. Okay. is often a
minor Celtic or or pre-Germanic Celtic
influence.
Okay.
The Asian Britain's pre- Roman and the
Roman era Celtic inhabitants. Okay. Are
not a significant direct ancestral
source of the Dutch.
Okay. Okay. That answer the question.
Okay. I think maybe that's it for today.
Let's see.
Okay. So,
oh god.
Okay, that's it. I think that's it.
I got 18 uh notifications.
Okay.
Oh god.
Okay. This So this question is
unsettled.
So I got this issue about the live
stream and I don't have the full answer
yet. But in today's live live stream
actually I I did came out way away with
a significant answer that is what is the
is there any essential essential
difference between AI generated
programming language tutorial versus
human uh and the answer is no
and uh same thing applies to other
things generated did by AI including
videos and images.
So that is a that's a that's a fruit.
Okay, that is a important
result of this live stream because I was
doing philosophy
live
and came to some understanding.
So then today we talked about we we
talked about like lots of random things.
Not random but um
okay so
we talked about lots of things. Okay.
Rather
I would not I don't want to do that
because overall I consider it's somewhat
wasted because you don't have any goal.
You just rambled.
Um
okay. But um but then there is the
question about
I mean relatively okay relatively
because people human animals they do all
kind of things we can there's a question
like what is time wasting what is not
time wasting you never know like if you
look at you know like
women they go to shopping you know They
they like to do that kind of thing to
you to a two guys. It's like wasting
time.
Uh meanwhile our guys they do you know
some guys they do enjoy bars and uh you
know buddies playing card games or
whatever games. Uh and that in a sense
is wasting time
you know like but to some people they
have fun and to some people they have
essential needed fun because human
animals are social animals like dolphins
you need socialization
to be
healthy. Okay. Because without human
touch you kind of withe and die off.
So you kind of need to talk to other
humans even for nothing. Like we we we
you know we we we we were talking about
wasting time. We were consider
considering what is wasting time. What
is not wasting time? I'm thinking about
you know my live stream. Am I I'm just
wast I wasted my time. I shouldn't do
that. You know, I failed bad for it. But
then you think about
what does human animals need? Well, a
lot of people they they need they just
need to talk to people. Okay.
So what so what is wasting time and what
is not wasting time? That kind of became
uh dependent that that's dependent on
what is your goal. Um it's not absolute.
So in other words, me doing live stream
like this like right now mostly
monologue
happening to myself. The question is is
it wasting time? Um
not really. Yes and no. Okay. Because
even if I do not do white live stream
and even when I'm happy,
it is often the case that I do this kind
of monologue by myself
because that way I can resolve some kind
of some philosophical questions. Most
people are not philosophers. Okay? So
most people don't don't think about
these kind of questions.
which is common. You know, some people
are scientists, some people are not.
Some people are lawyers, some people are
business people, businessmen. Um, some
people are carpenters, some people are
technicians, some people are whatever.
So, but for philosophers, thinking about
these kind of questions is essential,
you know, for philosophers and I'm kind
of philosopher. Okay. So it is true
often that I talk to myself like this
monologue often.
You know to to many people you think I'm
crazy but actually not. So there's a
Microsoft update. What the [ __ ] is it?
Secure boot allowed key exchange key
update.
Painting restart.
What?
Secure boot allowed key exchange.
So this is questionable. What what does
this mean? Secure boot
because secure boot is one of the kind
of critical um
part of Microsoft. So I want to know
what exactly is this? Let's ask AI.
Secure boot allowed key exchange key.
What does that mean? Secure boot allowed
key exchange key update. The secure boot
allowed key exchange key update is a
legitimate legitimate
security update for Microsoft for
Windows. Yeah, of course. It appears in
Windows update as an optional or quality
update often requiring a reboot to
configure installation.
What is secure boot and KEK?
It's like a low
uh secure boot is a UEFI
firmware feature
that ensures only trusted digitally
signed software like bootable order and
can run during startup.
Okay.
So Microsoft's original KK K stand for
key exchange key.
Oh
is is set to expire in June 20126.
Oh okay.
Okay. So this is important.
Okay,
I'm unhappy. Okay, I'm unhappy and kind
of stuck here with today's talk show and
I wanted originally
of course to code this uh wam language
nefoid but it's been delayed and
delayed.
Okay. So,
can I do some code of that tonight?
Maybe a little bit, but mostly it'll be
tomorrow.
And uh then um
okay, then the other thing I'm thinking
is there is the time of live stream.
So, should the live stream timing be
changed?
Okay.
Okay. There are some things to think
about. Okay.
So,
this this live stream is kind of
experimental because I've been, you
know, by now it's 3 hours and uh 20
minutes.
Very interesting.
Okay, we need to do a lot of code. A lot
of code needs to be done.
Okay, bye guys.