good morning guys
welcome to another episode of talk show
so I'm waiting for people to come on and
today I think today we gonna do mostly
answer questions you know I have been
cycling likes our talk show hours like
round the clock you know 24 hours of the
[ __ ] so people around the world can join
me anytime and
so in the past week we haven't been
doing it
in the morning
hey good morning Isaak
good morning from Northern California
and good morning to Southern California
that's
good morning to UC Irvine
so I think hey Jack you great to see you
again so I think I'm going to do some
Emacs today I don't know so I have some
topics here I might talk about and you
know so if you guys have a question you
know or if you want me to talk about a
topic
just type it oh you have to go to a
class soon so what class is it today
so Isaac is studying computer science
and
engineering
and we so I have some top topics here I
might talk about any one of them but
also on top of that there's a bunch of
things there's something about Emacs
something about JavaScript about
programming languages about learning a
natural language like English or French
you know I I tell you my tips techniques
to learn a new
human language so
Jack says it's 11 o'clock
11:30 page in time
which is Monday right Monday night
so Jack says he's studying he's going to
informatics
like teaching people about how to work
in a team to develop software and stuff
this is such a thing oh my god what what
what what has classrooms becomes today
in computer science info matrix is that
actually a word or
because that seems like info matrix oh
you know
informatics that's interesting like
teaching people about how to work in a
team to develop software and stuff
that's it's a questionable class topic
these these days you know if you are
learning computer science or any hard
physical sciences you know like math
physics or engineering
you
you know you don't want to study like
how to working a team that's that's kind
of that's kind of getting stupid you are
a Q you should be learning I mean also
class computer science you should be
learning about hard cost of computer
science you know in math
it's just one class requirement yeah
even that I think it's silly I mean the
basic skills of collaboration with other
human animals okay that is a basic skill
I think you know that is usually usually
you learn that from
you know collaboration like it's I think
it becomes very city to actually teach a
course about that because you know you
you work with people that's a basic
human skill you should have learned that
I mean in general okay that the people
should have learned that in
in you know just interaction with people
you know by Inc by college you know
we're talking about college like
University that's after you know
after middle school you know after high
school then you go to college is
supposed to be you know
like real knowledge
so yeah I think
you know the education system in USA is
going down pretty bad in in the past 20
years like today's college students I
don't think they really learned much of
anything
also by the way
well I mean for those of you for those
of you if you have not decided I mean if
you are young guy and if you have not
decided whether to go to college my
advice is that if you are studying
computer science or even mathematics
don't go to college you don't have to
okay for those of you are like you are
not undecided okay my advice is you
don't have to you don't don't go
especially I mean if you are studying
computer science
specifically
there is nothing you know college is not
teaching you anything you you know if
you want to do computer science or
programming as a career
even theoretical computer science
there's no need for college oh you all
it takes is your interest your strong
interest in the topic
then you can learn on your own your time
is much better more efficiently spent
you know instead of going to college
because going to college you have to you
know
commute and stuff anyway
so well so yeah let me actually let's
see how many people watching five people
okay hello guys say hi here okay and let
me know what topic you want me to talk
to talk about but meanwhile let me just
start working on something you know sure
some emails probably because
it's morning a lot of people following
me for Emacs let me talk about
um we see which topic HTML 4 let's talk
about HTML 4 French said
okay let's go to
JavaScript blog
okay now
you know Google HT so so in jump in a
web site you have this thing let me show
you you have this thing
API
ok you can see you can see there are
several panels here and you can this is
JavaScript API this is basically Java
not JavaScript Java documentation so you
have you know Java packages you can
scroll around over here for example pick
that one then at least this the the
stuffs related to that topic and then
you can click here
then magnify
okay it does work so you have you know I
mean the point is that you have several
frames you know and
once you click on one of them it's
remained highlighted you see I mean each
each frame acts independently
let me answer that question in a bit so
so you got this is called frame set now
this is a technology invented by
Netscape back around
I
forgot Wayne was a demanded maybe in mm
bye-bye - yeah maybe 1997 or before
so but however
basically Google killed it googa googa
in the web dev community cured it so
this is the this is called iframe and
this FM is in the HTML 4 for standard so
let me show you so you can go to I have
a tutorial here H this is called not
sorry not iframe it's called HTML
frameset okay so you can see it's like
this
so basically the idea is that you have
you have independent panels and you can
actually adjust each panel size in the
browser however you want and you can
click to switch
you know like index of topics you know
just just like this javascript
documentation page this is very
extremely convenient and it's part of
HTML 4 standard HTML 4 is basically used
through our mm
but however
Google killded Google decide kugo and
the web dev Google convinced the web dev
community saying that the French set
idea is bad okay why is it bad because
the main reason is they say is that it
it makes such engine hard to find stuff
I actually never try to understand
what's the reason you know I I never you
know took the time to study it in detail
but anyway you know the web community's
decided this is not good so they they
cured it so it doesn't exist in html5
anymore you know
html5 began around 2008 also so it
doesn't exist anymore so nobody is using
it today except
except the Java
documentation
however it's not going to it's not
likely to go away though because you
know the web
it's probably you it's not likely to go
away for the next let's say 5 or 10
years
but anyway it's it's no longer
html5
and in html5 you you if you want to try
to do that you use the iframe
iframe is like you can create a window
with within a page and this window is
basically a HTML page by itself
but it's very bad it's
it's very bad
basically you know this frame set is
very useful especially you have like for
example let me show you my Python
content okay so you see my pattern
content you I'm not using frame set I'm
just using
I'm not using frame set okay i'm you
just using CSS to have these so you can
select a topic
actually let me show you this in Safari
so if you guys have a question just ask
it okay
so in Safari
oh
not open link in Safari but
Safari open in Safari
so you can see so I have this but
however if I'm over here I click this
one it's not highlighted you know I
don't know which you know which page I'm
on but however if you are using friends
said you know you click anything
it remain highlighted for example let's
click that you see
does it
oh actually it doesn't
well anyway
okay I kind of lost what I'm saying but
the basically what what I'm saying is
that this iframe is very bad and and
basically to this day there is no way
it's it's even with JavaScript it's it's
basically impossible to duplicate this
wonderful friend set feature and what
one of the most important thing is that
you can adjust any of these panels any
any way you want for example if you
don't want the bottom one you can just
like you know drag it down and you know
okay that's that's about FEM said I kind
of lost the trend you know I you know I
kind of lost what I really want to say
but
basically they you know Google they cure
the frameset feature and and that's
that's bad
so let's see just one crash so jack says
the
cannot be visited oh sorry thought or
cannot be visited because China Bank
banned me that's why
because I have some stuff on that domain
name and they you know it's sensitive
topics in China so China you know banned
sorry doc long ago
so do you have do you use front web
frame
web framework like react and view no I
have studied react and I think it's very
good but however I
haven't used it because mostly because
you know I'm what not working for a
company and for my own website
it's mostly just static HTML
and if I want to use JavaScript for
example
let me show you let me show you an
example of JavaScript I I have written I
talked about this last time but
let me just show you sorry info go to
Unicode
here you can type anything let's say CH
I
okay now this shows all unicode
characters that contains the
contains the letter sequence CGI
let's try coma actually let's see
[Music]
comm100 mouths try qu e
s
so you can see all the words question
mark
let's try something
let's say one oh and E
so anyway this this is written in
JavaScript but the way I call JavaScript
is usually it's basically
vanilla JavaScript no framework no
library's no nothing everything I could
manually by myself
yeah yeah JavaScript yeah
yep so that's
okay I kind of lost track what I'm gonna
talk about so let's close that
cross-eyed framework
how is everyone so
so what would you what you up to
Jack
Jack is in China
so any okay let me ask a question then
let's see what what else okay I'm going
to change my you know this is cuz this
is my channel is called a talk show but
I think I'm going to change it to TV you
know it's a shorter name is kind of more
more recognizable TV
so let's talk about interface design you
know say there are so many to talk about
the thing is you know we when I want to
talk about something you have to get I
have to get myself started like
because otherwise you know I just
okay let's talk about peepshow windows
these are usually interface designs okay
I'm actually near my Steve time you know
after the talk I'm going to go to bed
so user interface design you know you
know user interface you know the the
programmers the the entire industry is
usually very idiotic you know they have
like no idea what you know when they
went when it comes to your user
interface you know
especially especially those those
so-called user interface experts you
know you see them all every day on
Twitter and hacker news and so on and in
these days it's called there's a new
jargon called
UX you X the X means
experience like user experience so you
said you know it's used it's used to be
called user interface UI
I mean the you turret the the concept of
user interface is that you know you when
you design a website or any application
or software you want to you know there
there's some kind of art and science to
user interface design because you wanted
to be intuitive easy-to-use
readable
you know easy to read and so on you know
things things like that
because
if you have a bad user interface you
know people people don't know where to
find information
things like that so that's called you
use an interface I mean that's a very
general topic and
you know part of
part of the software you know you have
to do that but the thing about hey
Danielle
so but today they have the new new
jargon concept called UX user experience
so what does it mean it means you know
they it's supposed to mean that when
people using a software or website you
know apps you know
they they have you know they they want
to focus I mean one aspect is the users
experience like when a person uses your
software does he or she you know
actually enjoy it or does it by God does
it does does he find it difficult to use
so that's the idea you know you know
user experience
abbreviated UX you can find it a lot on
Twitter like you or if you just search
for you UX for example
like every day they are user experience
design yeah that's that's poor [ __ ] you
know all these articles it's I can tell
you is pure [ __ ] you know I also
have a some kind of obsession with you
user interface these are you know
besides you know writing systems
programming languages design unicode you
know anything related to that
including user interface and
so anyway this article crap
okay Lexus UX user experience
UX for beginners yeah all the all these
crap you know websites they are there
because they just want to make money you
know they if you go there their content
is garbage you know all these these
these I can you know I can tell right
away and this you know
they just want you to click it so you
know they have ads there and they make
money and these topics are you know
popular especially you know they are not
kind of non technical
topics and a lot of people just you know
go there and anyway so
so the first of all UX is extremely
idiotic concept you know basically it's
just covered by UI you know it's it's
the same thing that says you use the
interface design includes user
experience you know obviously so why do
they have UX you know why do I have user
experience the face it's only because
marketing well anyway so so one of the
user interface
idiocy okay is a peepshow windows like
tiny window you know our screens gets
larger and larger
you know excluding the phone okay but
for the monitor you know in general they
become so large so many pixels you know
back in 1991
I bought you know basically the high
high-end monitor made by Apple you know
apples monitor let's see Apple 13 inch
monitor I bought this in 1991 and guess
how many pixels pixels are there
I
was hoping for a Wikipedia article but
Apple displays yeah so I bought this one
in 1991 and it only has
640 by 480 pixels
this one
and it costs like I think it was a
thousand or two thousand a thousand must
be the this monitor and this is a
high-end color one you know back then
color monitor is even rare and
but you know today you got you know lots
of pixels
so the the monitors gets bigger and
bigger however
you know like on Windows when you want
to for example Internet Options you go
options then they it pops up this small
window and you cannot enlarge it you
know it's extremely idiotic you get this
the cross true phobia kind of thing so
you have to squirrel you know through
these boxes and click this little boxes
like you know my monitor is respeaking
but they'd if they create this window
that's not resizable extremely idiotic
to this day like today it's still in
Windows 10 is still like that and here's
another example this is installing of
Oracle VM VirtualBox
you know this this tiny window you see
you cannot recite resize this whole
window you are forced forced into this
tiny window and especially you look at
these parts you have to like scroll left
and right to see what it says there and
here's a modern example Twitter
you know I cannot I cannot possibly
understand how this idiot idiotic people
is supposed to be programmers yeah I
mean all the other user interface design
knows they came up with this okay this
this example is Twitter like we can you
know for example I'm going to for
example let's see
okay this this
post I enjoy I open it
you see you get this you get this tiny
window like what the [ __ ] is is you know
you know my monitor is this big and but
but I'm forced into using this this tiny
pop-up window and you cannot even like
enlarge it you know for example if I
fullscreen my window that remains
remains the same size
you know this is all so these are like
total complete idiocy and but but
somehow they are like they are embraced
by all these hacker news like hacker
news every day you hack a news flash
started this this needed' program it
idiotic you know goop
you know and also you know every now and
then you will see you know user
interface gurus they write blogs and
every programmers is oh yeah we need to
do that it's you know it's just
incredible impossible to believe and
also here is you know here see another
example Google+ peep show window you
know on Google first which closed down
few days ago when you want to make a
post it pops up this tiny window for you
to type I mean what what's the deal with
it and a lot of examples this is Google+
you know you are you know they are like
there you know there are tens of
comments right but you are forced into
this little box this this little
display you know port kind of then you
have to scroll
and here's another example this example
is in Stack Overflow
you know when they show a code then you
have to scroll over here
left-hand 11 right
I mean let me look at this case you go
to stack overflow
your my monitor is big okay I mean even
a window size is big so you know showing
code is very common it's like you know
almost on every person so that stack
overflow so you see an answer you know
code answer there then you have to like
move your hand to the mouse or something
or other device to score the horizontal
swirl so that you can read the rest of
it
this is complete idiocy okay of course
they have reasons like for example in
this case their reason is that you know
the proper user interface design is that
you should never
I
mean everything should be visible
therefore therefore they create this
left and right Scapa you know if you
want things to be visible it's easy you
you know you you put you use CSS to
create a
automatic wrap
hold on a second
my roommate
so I'm gonna look at the comments just a
second but let me go through let me show
you example that so I'm starting to talk
okay that's good but I'm I'm trying to
reduce my repetition like a Frank you
know do you guys so you guys find me
sometimes repetitive like for example
look at this my JavaScript my Python
tutorial okay now you see the code I
mean that you see the code here now
suppose I have a narrow narrow window
you see you see how they
you know
ignore the side panel for now let's just
say let this let's say
this window okay now you see now if I
shrink it you see the line just just go
to the next line they just wrap around
while meanwhile they are still
technically remains one line for example
this line they are one line they are not
actually two lines however they are
simply displayed as two lines I mean
this this can be done with CSS okay so
this way when you look at you know you
go to my website you know web website
design like that you don't have to like
look at the code then then there's a
squab our town and then you have to
score it left and right it's extremely
idiocy okay I don't you know I cannot
the the the you know the
the painful thing about this website is
that they they are almost always created
by these gurus you know web design gurus
and they are chanted by this you know
suppose the expert you know like every
programmer every web developer okay they
all say okay you should do this like
like this this example you should do
this but this is just bad you know
so in general the industry programmers
they are like that they would you know
they you know you look at many of their
opinions they think they are great but
actually very bad and in fact this is
you know so this is one of the issue in
the user interface design keeps your
Windows but I have collected lots of
other examples
in this web design
index page you know here's a table table
of contents
all of these are other examples
okay let's read the comments hey Matt
great to see you rise of the idiots so
so rad says we had CUA
CUA and hig Act
then webcam and standards in
documentation went out window went out
of the window then phones and touch
tablets now
designers rule they are no rule no.2
tips act
yeah yeah it's true so you know see you
a stand for CC you see you a is Asian
thing T created by ibn
you know it stands for common user
interface because back then
you know this is like late 1980s or
early 1990s back then
you know because back then you know
software almost every software they have
different keyboard shortcuts they have
different way different kind of menus
you know today the menu is kind of
standardized you know you have file edit
and others but back back then every
software is different so they created
this CUA standard and
hig is opposed human interface
guide which is very popular is it has a
huge influence on the impact on the
industry
so yeah so those are the early days of
user interface design you
you know back then you know
graphical user interface is actually
pretty new you know from Apple popular
popularized by Apple so you know those
are critical important ideas
so Daniel says hundreds of millions that
people have tried and they abandoned
triggered
you know so let's I mean let's take take
this Twitter example let's get concrete
you know so you see these tweet of
forces you to use this little narrow
window now I understand on a phone
possibly for ease of implementation
reasons you know
so-called
what they call it today you know like
but anyway so suppose for ease of
implementation reasons so that they can
write one code that works on phone you
know very tiny screen works on desktop
you know so we regardless of monitor
monitor size now now if that's a reason
okay I understand you know maybe they
sacrifice the desktop
but however you know they have you know
Twitter is not a small company they have
lots of money I don't you know I don't
think that's the reason
so you know if you think yeah so what do
you think you know why why is Twitter is
like doing this
do they actually think people like it
you know one of the reason that drives
all this new I you know this stupid UI
and UX thing is that
you know often they they're they're Co
is not actually
they they are Co of creating UI or UX
okay it's not actually make the user
happier okay that's part of the they are
but that's not the main goal many of
these commercial corporations they are
menko is actually to create the UI such
that such such that you will use this
software more ultimately they want to
make more money okay so they want to
create a UI so that that gets you to
interact it interact with it more like
more clicks and more stuff you know
that's you know ultimately more money
that's that's the main goal sometimes
this call
conflict with the goal of a UI that
makes you so happy so I think this is
the one of the main reason in many of
these user interface design evolution
cases where the user interface simply
went worse get worse and worse
and and you know there I I have quite a
lot other examples one of them
one of them is the grey text in white
background
this became fashionable about about 10
years ago now but by now it must be ten
years old you know like but before
let's say this beginning in 2010 okay
let's just say in begin 2010 so before
that you you never have the idea of
great you know make the text gray in a
white background but it's it's it's like
a fad it's like a fashion okay since you
know 2010 or something like that then
everywhere psy began to make gray the
text way
you know like some of these are just
unbeatable you can you have a hard time
to read it look at this one orange text
in gray background
and you know the hateful thing about
these things is that
it's it's it's you know it's fashionable
it's not just fashionable it's widely
popular and it's spread its spread
liking every company and by every
program you know
you know and some of the this space is
literally reading unreadable
you know
so that that's another example of the
user interface issues with this you know
this somehow this industry
movement trend
so let's go back to read the comments
Twitter made chatroom scalable
Twitter made chatroom scalable social
media more approachable
by introducing a simple feature that
users was certainly not asking for
140 characters limit
the 140 character limit originally was a
limit of the phone SMS protocol yeah I'm
pretty sure of that
well I mean I mean yeah I mean I judge
it I just want to mention it you know in
case people don't know originally
Twitter was you know I think it was yeah
it was designed on a phone you know
there's on the phone back then you know
in 2004 2006
you know the you know phone is not like
today's phone you know we we don't have
smartphone yet or smartphone is not
popular yet you know that you have text
messages you know SMX
SMA SMS I think that's code so there's a
character limit so that's how it began
today they can make it you know they can
make make it you know 1,000 characters
limit but they don't want to because
again because I I think
pretty sure it's because to make this
dish it I mean
their goal is to make money so so
everything is considered with respect to
which way can we make more money so I
think that is a reason they are ran out
their limit is 208 characters I think
that is a reason they don't want to
extend the character limit because you
know they they you know I think they
decided 280s you know is the optimal for
making more money for them right now
Benjamin hey Ben Texas harder to read if
if there are very wide columns it's
nicely wraps after about 15 watts yes
that's true
yeah and that that's true but and but
also I like to mention another thing is
that it's actually not easy to do you
know I
mean it's it's it's easy to do
technically it's trivial but however for
example for example my website let's say
you know my page
you know if
it's
yeah because the the reason is that I
mean you know the monitor size the month
with various by great lot you know son
you know and it changes over the years
so
so it
yeah I because I have run into this
issue and I thought about it it's it's
it's really hard to come up with a
simple and systematic
way of or set of rules that works for
every monitor
because for example you know for example
I have the you know I have the site pass
like right now my wife website you have
the left sidebar you have the right
sidebar then you have the middle but if
the tick if the text is smaller okay for
for example right now but if I expand a
window
then the text is gonna go over across if
I have let's see if I have a longer
sentence now here
but I mean the text is going to extend
across over here that's just too long
but if you force a maximun like let's
say no more than 80 characters then you
got other issues then you got like you
know like
you got other issues like
like for example if you have a text
that's essay okay
HTML history
well basically basically what happened
is that all the text becomes just you
know only one column of your screen the
rest of this is just blank
so there is like no really no way to
make it work for any size of window
screen size size
so let's see
a battle by the way this is called
hey look at look at my website you see
if your window is too narrow the right
panel disappears now if it's even
narrower the left panel also disappears
that's called
well what's that what's the word
there's a word for that
oh I know where to find it so let's go
to web dev tutorial
visual CSS then you go down your C
media query ya media query
responsive design yeah that's a phrase
responsive design
yeah we flow a flow is another thing
actually
but anyway you see how this this this
way works where the right panel
disappears
wins to narrow the left panel also
disappears that
that is actually called like responsible
responsive design that is that's a term
used to mean that you just write one CSS
style and
and
exactly what's the width of your columns
changes depending on your window width
that's what they call it it became a
fashionable thing
but let's go back to
web design there
so
okay
I'm near my sleep in time so let's see
web oh and wait we chat also boring I
see rise of the idiots
YouTube watch what's that video
let's see show
oops
I'm not sure what is this video oh
okay
go back
okay the messages just went out
[ __ ]
so I don't I've been talking eight
people watching
yeah I'm kind of lost today's topics so
you guys ask me questions you know so
yeah today is supposed to it's supposed
to be a
questions session because I was thinking
you know there are several people Emacs
people my Emacs followers you know I
thought they're gonna ask me Emacs
questions
so let's see
Texas harder to read okay web all right
so videos Google design good design is
easy to digest
yes
reflow okay we ran out of comments okay
okay let me talk about yeah so let's
just talk about something about
designing since we are on that topic
typography sucks okay that's a big issue
you know I'm kind of tired so I'm not
too energetic to get excited to talk
about this but this is
this is one of the big issue you know
like with people in the design community
in specifically typography they they are
like they have a group is they are like
again
where they
they promote typography as if you know
as if it's the greatest invention the
most critical invention of humanity
there yeah the type type of typography
kind of group you know they are kind of
like a
sort of elite group it's like how you
have it's kind of like so it's kind of
compare analogous to the Emacs users
group or the vim users group where you
know Emacs and being people they think
oh this is critical this is important
this is the greatest tool you know but
actually if you step outside and and if
you look at the whole world or the
country industry you know he max is like
disposable it is it's it's the least
important thing it's not you know it's
the least important software like if
Emacs got wiped out today you know
nothing happens to the world people just
use vim if we got wiped out you know
let's say you know a snap-in finger it
disappears then people just use other
editors they just well you know they
might cry and but they don't just start
to use Adam or microsoft visual code
it's like there's no problem problem at
all but however I mean as a contracts
contrast in comparison if PHP
disappeared
then there's a huge damage to the word
you know the stocks the stocks will go
down you know there's gonna be
disastrous asses disasters you know
people will die possibly you know you
know so so this by this comparison you
can actually see which one is actually
more critical to
humanity you know or if Jeb javadi's
disappeared or you know or C programming
language or or your goal and disappear
or Python you know any one of those
programming languages so far more
importantly young Emacs exactly you know
even if Google Chrome disappeared or you
know any browser you know Firefox
disappeared so anyway so so in
typography communities this kind of
similar kind of a you know a small group
they think they are
Allegiance I mean they did they think
type of typography like it's very
important in the same way it's like okay
it's kind you know sometimes you run
into chrome areas and grammar and as
Nazis you know if it's so called America
Marion's you know they are picky about
you know everything about
grandma
but in fact in reality you know if you
actually look at the world in your acne
in reality if the grandma is not really
important it's not important at all
in fact if you look at
vast majority of writings they
automatically
they are not grammatically correct
basically vast majority of writings
okay still night people watching that's
so what should we talk about today so
anyway so okay down on earth Steve Jobs
you know there's a video here you
actually you you might want to watch it
you know when I talk about these topics
for example web design
well actually a lot of my opinions you
know
typography sucks and
you know gray I'm on white background
this issue or the peep show window issue
sometimes like if you show like
something for example some of my
followers they actually disagree but I
cannot like I cannot fathom
how is it possible because for example
type typography I'm sure some of you
probably disagree you probably think oh
type typography you know you you are
really kind you you really love about
you know the topics of typography like
Kearney's you know which fun to use you
know you spend a lot of time to pick
that you know just the best one - for
programming you know you and you are
obsessed about kerning you know like
Connie is is when
kerning the best example of Connie's if
I let me magnify
so this is Fi but in some font they
connect the F and I and that is called
kerning let's see if I can find an
example
let's
[Music]
okay so what's the command
um wait
okay it's a cha
ok if I
yeah I cannot you know this it's called
Connie ligatures it's called ligatures
well the
easiest way to find it is Wikipedia
so you can see
typographic ligatures that's what it is
so you see this F I the F the ice
becomes like under f you see so it's
it's like it's almost like the two
letters are merged together
and there are other example for example
here okay it's like you connect them
together why they do that because back
then you know a few hundred years ago
yeah it's somehow it's just developed
out of
typographers
they do that because they think it's
more legible they think it's yeah they
think it's you know it's easier to read
that way but actually I you know I don't
think so they I don't think there's a
scientific data that says you know the
ligature is actually easier to read and
kerning the the word cunning means that
when you adjust two letters you know in
micro pixels like just put them together
like that you know the ligature case
that's called Connie you know so a lot
of programmers it looks like you know
this elite type of programmers they
seems to have obsession about these
things like they they get excited about
oh you should do kerning here or there
it's actually Oh [ __ ] it's worthless
it's the most worthless
thing
yeah so you know photo type typography
for example this
so let's go -
lets go / new window
they fit Isha's aesthetic yes
so pain says I don't think anyone
outside of the typography community
cares or even notices different types
exactly that that is exactly what I
think as well
so I would say in a similar way you know
most you know vast majority of
programmers don't care about emag stuff
you know it's like I'm like well I'm a
Manny max fan okay and of course I like
Emacs but I do not I do not have you
know
you know like in real life like a walk
you know you don't really even you can
really
talk to your co-workers about your
excitement about Emacs unless you kind
of know the co-worker but otherwise is
rather offensive you know
and people know that even the eMac
loving people you know but they keep
saying Emacs is great or that or you
should tell people to use Emacs in
reality you can't I
mean even if you tell your friends to
use Emacs where he is using you know for
examples let's say Microsoft stuff or a
tomato
you don't even do that much you know
because
you know
but I mean basically overall it's just
not important that's the point it's
really not important what editor you use
but but to the Emacs community people
like we see on reddit you see the way
they get excited they they talk they
live like the way they talk it seems
like they live in a different world in a
pub oh so in the same way
in the same way you know the the
typography people like when you
when you are interested in InDesign or
fonts well I am okay I have some
interest in that so I you know you study
them you look I'd read you know Donald
Knuth's typography books I read his tech
surf
so you and Steve Jobs who is also a big
fan about typography you know the beauty
of it and
these people and look at this this is a
very famous apparently it's a very
famous documentary about
Helvetica well that's the title of the
documentary how America It's Made in
and
someone you know oh
okay it's been taken down again that's a
problem with YouTube but I'm sure
there's someone else must have put up
another copy but anyway that's a famous
document document documentary you know
you watched a lot documentary you see
these tight you know typography people
designers they grow a fight how critical
how important how beautiful it is
typography I mean the way you look at
the way they talk it's like they say the
typography influences your thought you
know it's like total [ __ ] but they
but they really it looks like they
really mean it you know it's just like
you know analogous to the Emacs people
when when we okay talk about Emacs we
see we get excited you know how
important is you know your buffer stuff
or whatever it's not really important
yeah so there is a type typography issue
and you you see this in
programmers hacker you know the hacker
types form such as hacker news or read
it often you know every every year every
few months you will see someone will
post a blog about type typography and
gets lots of thump up and everyone is
like talking about it gets excited oh my
preference my my favorite font is this
or that or favorite I didn't like this
one because it's little things
so yeah that's a kind of that's a
situation this niche
groups how do you call that you know
these niche groups who think their stuff
is important the and actually it's also
similar to
photographers and photography you know
in in the photography community you have
this kind of small group of like elite
photographers you know they think they
think
photography is like the greatest art of
the great art form then you know they
get into details about how you should
you know the photo the design of taking
a photo and stuff it's all [ __ ]
okay this see the comments
okay so that's how I've been talking
let's see if people is like oh
my god I got more and more people
watching ok when people start to drain
though then then that's it that's the
time to say goodbye for today
so for now let's continue for a bit so
so you got these
typography things
okay well since we are talking about
type cuvee let me let me let me cover a
few things now there's a issue about
series versus sans serif font okay
now youyou guys know what's a serif
versus sans-serif right
well I'm not going to explain well
should i most of you probably already
know because should I explain should I
or should I not should I stay or should
I go
that's a song
that's a song talking about
okay what am i doing now yeah I'm going
to show you I need to go to my CSS
tutorial so go to language tutorial
CSS tutorial here CSS font font family
no we don't care okay here not this page
let's let's go to a standard web font
no
Google web fun okay let's just go to a
font family
okay just straight lines I mean it's
lies without decoration Sarah feels like
with little decorations on the inner
corners and edges that's called serif
font and here's sensory fun so what what
about this well it's this a long long
standing question about which one to use
like is serif font more readable or is
it sensory far more readable
so you know it's a design it's some
questioning web design it's you know
it's a perpetual question you know web
designers are asked that question often
now I can tell you I've been studying
this subject I've been looking into this
question for a long time since
1992 something like that they're
basically there is no scientific data
that's
you know one of them is more readable or
legible okay there's not
they are like a few very very small
handful of academic studies papers
published about this question but there
is no conclusive
there is no conclusion there is no
you know majority conclusion one way or
the other I mean you can search the web
you know you know you can you know type
you know Siri false and sensitive which
is more legible
and you already you know
you know some website we will say these
somewhere website we will say that
eventually you will find some website
that actually studied you know all the
other websites or in books and stuff and
and she I believe there's one
female that talked about that there's no
conclusion and you can also video but
anyway every every two or three years I
I take a survey because because I'm
obsessed about these issues you know
even I you know I don't like them but
still you know like for 20 years I have
I studied typography you know a thirty
Donald Donald Knuth's stuff I use Apple
you know all 1990s I use Apple you know
I read you know Steve Steve Jobs
opinions by the way I respect Steve Jobs
opinions and I'm also very interested
about aesthetics so well yeah you might
see me you know teased about these
issues but actually I am concerned about
aesthetics that's why I'm studying all
the things about Web Design you know you
I and you know I look at what people say
you know why and stuff but anyway so
back to the topic when I was saying oh
yeah so every two or three years I
survey the major websites such as Wall
Street Journal New York Times Washington
Post and
you know first of all you you go to
Wikipedia and you do research and find
out let's say okay the question is okay
what's the top five most read most poppy
popular publications you go research
that so I have done that basically it's
it's these Wall Street Journal New York
Times Washington Post Oh a times
yeah that's that's basically the top
four actually also
they they are a couple others but anyway
there's circulation changes you know
over the years but but these are the big
ones
and also Time magazine is popular
scientific America is not really that
popular but
but it's a popular magazine for
scientists you know or people interested
in scientists anyway every few years I
look you know I take a survey of their
websites and let's go see to see if they
are using Siri font or using sensitive
and
you know so I so this is a report this
this one is written in two thousand two
thousand sixteen so let's talk
now for Syria in sensory found basically
usually okay usually you separate your
webpage or publications content into two
two groups one is the header the title
okay these are the title header title
header okay this this that's one thing
then the body text is another thing so
typically
traditionally okay from 1990s
traditionally
you
you you use Siri for one of them then
sensory for the other part okay that's I
forgot which one is which or you if
there is a consensus I forgot but anyway
look at this okay this is Wall Street
Journal they are using serif or
in title and also the body text
on my website it's all sans-serif you
know before you know before in two
thousand miles of mm it's a seraph but
you know I used sense sense serif now so
anyway I surveyed them and and I made a
report so sensitive
those who are using sensitive body text
includes this you know big websites
then here's a report on the title the
font used for title text
so most of them are serif except USA
Today uu USA's today is kind of special
they they like San serif
ok another issue about web design is
fixed fixed layout or flow
what is fixed layout fixed layout is
such that for example my website is flow
you can see you know as I move around
you see the text kind of changes the
fixed website is such that doesn't
matter how you resize your window they
they well I cannot
for example this
well I don't have an example right now
but these two website these two website
the aid is the part there used to be a
fixed layout fixed fixed layout means
just like me it means like a newspaper
okay like a printed newspaper or book
printed book
you can they never you know they are
they are never changes you know doesn't
matter how doesn't matter how you resize
your window their layout doesn't change
if your window is too small you simply
cut off you know part of it if your
window is large you know you simply get
blank space around it you know so they
are like fixed you know they don't
change that that's the meaning that's
why they are called fixed there
it's rare today you don't find it you
don't find fix stay out today
yeah it's pretty much gone
you can still find them some of them
but but however
however most of the website throughout
up to 2010 for example they or they all
prefer fixed layout actually even today
for example this trader it's actually
fixed layout you see doesn't matter how
I change my window it's fixed you see
the word on
here then it wraps to the next slide it
never changed changes the rat it's a
fixed layer even if if I exit this
pop-up window
you see this remain this width it
doesn't change
visitors it yeah it doesn't you know the
wrap always stay at the same place so
why do they actually web designer
designers they tend to prefer fixed
layout
because in fixed layout like PDF ok PDF
is a great example of fixed fixed layout
commercial websites or publications they
always prefer fixed layout because then
they can they can control exactly you
know which picture or headlines or which
boxes are where
yeah they can control you exactly you
know everything where is you know which
one goes where and especially designers
web designers designers or graphic
designers for example a magazine a
magazine you have a bunch of
illustrations right
and the designers of course they they
carefully place they want the exact
positions for everything you know to
layout the magazine for magazine for
example
so
so they have like total control of the
aesthetics that's what it what that's
what design designers like this is
supposed to nerds or engineering types
like maybe like us okay we we tends to
prefer
logical layout okay we don't care about
which which thing is well that we don't
care we only care about we have titles
you know then H you know the first
section first level of headings then we
have no subsections that we care we we
want things to be logical okay
the HTML HTML was designed to be for
that purpose you know because it was
created by nerd it wasn't designed to be
you know fixed layout and even CSS
is not really designed for a fixed
layout you have lots of problems
that's why a lot of people
anyway so so HT HTML was created so you
know by nodes it's designed for you know
the logical they are not fixed layout
but however commercial publications and
designers they always almost always want
fixed layout
and that's one of the reason
you know like PDF PDF is very popular
you know it seems a lot people actually
rather prefer to read a book in PDF form
as opposed to HTML I
think there is a actually a good reason
why publications either in print or a
website they prefer fixed layout and and
maybe therefore the designers prefer fix
they are because when you have a fixed
layout you actually have full control of
everything you know
as well as for readers you know when you
read a book when you when it is in PDF
view
you know things don't change depending
on what device you are using it
so hi guys are you guys still there so
do you guys prefer PDF or
or the you know floor layout you know I
like I have people asking me for my
Emacs tutorial to be in PDF layout you
know in PDF they want a PDF versions oh
my gosh I got more and more readers
more and more people watching so who are
you guys watching say something type in
the comment box type any anything okay
any you know questions comments opinions
just type it when I'm talking about
something and just type it
okay so so there is fixed layout versus
floor layout so that's one thing so I
was doing a survey you know when you
look at other publications you want to I
want you know I want to see whether they
are using fixed layout of
flow layout you see okay so actually New
York Times look here New York Times and
USA Today they are using fixed layout
let's check them hard
New York Times okay
let's go here
New York Times
yep that's the one
so Ben prefers float
Janice prefers anything or were you
talking about something else okay
Ben says what's the point of serious
decoration I think I
think serif decoration they evolved out
of
legibility I think I forgot
but you can find the answer on Wikipedia
like if you go to Wikipedia they have
like history let's look at that in a
moment let's look at New York Times so
let me try to resize a window and see
what happens
you see this is a fixed layout you see
this is what happened oh wait
yeah they have
them in terms of the my auto click so
they do have
responsive design
but however
you see you see that way
okay there maybe
okay so well I'm not sure how do you
classify whether it's fixed or
flow because today with responsive
responsive design
it kind of became a borderline I mean
this it's not as clear-cut as before so
anyway that's New York Times so the
history of serif
let's see
serif I
think it's developed for legibility
let's see
like originally you know his history
originally letters do not have serif
okay here's a good you know Wikipedia
always have good information
for non-political things okay my brother
my my
my computer is getting slow let me close
some window close window
okay so let's see so this is serif so
you can see the red part out of serif so
so what's the history of Syria
but originally all letters or alphabets
they don't have serif serif were added
so serif originated in the Latin
alphabet with inscription lettering
words carved into stone in Roman
antiquity the explanation proposed by
father Edward Kartik in his 1968 book
the origin of the serif is now broadly
but not universally accepted
the Roman letter outlines were first
painted onto stone and the stone covers
followed the brush marks which flared at
stroke ends in corners creating syrups
okay
so this is what what year is wrong
okay well anyway that's a history of
serif
okay so history of series so let's go
back to so I mean if you are watching
12 I think we're gonna end like
like I've been talking for six seven
eight 18 minutes I cannot count anymore
Siri buzzes sensor so so what what do
you guys think any any thoughts what's
your opinion what's your rent what's
your gripe like what do you want to say
about type
topography
Dani hey Dani Dani Pato says have you
used vs cold yet why do you think he has
such a booming usage what could a max -
or learn about it oh I have great
opinions about that no I never actually
used the yes code weight
vs code yeah I actually never used it so
there's my Microsoft Visual Studio that
was the you know the classic from 1990s
to 2000 they still have that but then in
the last maybe three years they created
the Microsoft vs code which is
which is kind of like Adam editor from
github you know github made the
automated it's written in JavaScript so
Microsoft also did it
using the framework
electron yeah there's a JavaScript
framework electron
basically it's based it's actually it's
just a Google Chrome browser it's it's
that that's the that's kind of the the
foundation so you have Google Chrome
browser running JavaScript
that's that's that's your editor so Adam
is is that one example and vs code for
Microsoft and I have tried Adam but I've
never tried vs code
and what do you think it has such a
booming usage
well I one thing I can say for sure is
that the reason Emax do not have
are not very popular because Emacs
people because Emacs people refuse to
change it
so in you know because first of all the
Emacs way the Emacs you know when you
use Emacs there's lots of jargons the
buffer the the the cruiser they call it
point and you know a fire there you call
buffer then you know you know you have
huge bunch of jargons then you have
highlighting is called
mark you know
mark yeah and
let's see
yeah point in mark you know kusa is
called point Cuza position is called
point you know because it's from 1980s
on you know late 1970s 1980s so it's you
know you have huge amount baggage but
also
even that I but but Emacs is still
wonderful it's really powerful and
flexible it's really great it's still
reasonably I would say great despite all
the many packages
but the other thing is you know the
Emacs people they are proud of it you
know they refuse to change
they refuse to change so for example if
there's a one recommendation you know
how to make Emacs popular I can say this
one thing if Emacs today Emacs people
just changed make the copy copy cut
paste undo shortcut with ctrl C for copy
ctrl X for cut ctrl V for paste ctrl z
for and do just do that you do that out
of the box
and then the Emacs will be I guarantee
will be twice as popular within one year
okay I guarantee this just make do this
out of the box
I don't mean you know don't you I see
you a mod no see you I see you a mod is
a mod in Emacs is a hack okay it's a
hack to makes Emacs use ctrl C for copy
you know control X for for cut it's a
hack and it doesn't work well it's got
lots of problems but get the Emacs
developers you know to make Emacs so
that you have these copy cut paste keys
same as you know the standard team
standard Windows Microsoft Windows or
Mac you know Maggie is the command
instead of control you know just use
this standard keys I guarantee within
one year the Emacs users new surveys
will turbo okay but this is but you know
I've said this since 10 years ago at
least you know 15 years ago I've said it
repeatedly you know every time it's a
flame war it's a big flame war you got
hundred people replying arguing you know
some people come in your TRO and you
know it's hope is hopeless is there's no
it's it's very hard to get that to
change of course then people start with
a disagree and these stupid hackers
really truly idiot okay and there's no I
do not doubt at it you know you on this
issue you you you can decide you you
have to make a decision if either I'm an
idiot saying these things or they are
okay so this Emacs developers
there's no way for me to change my
opinion on this today because I've
studied the issue in detail for 20 years
so you know
the way the reason Emacs people do not
change you know the because because the
Emacs dev community there is got a lot
problems for most is a problem of code
I'm not going to go into that because
then heck I will be less convincing
because then it relates to open source
you know the open source and free
software ideology you know
you know so so let me say well so let me
just say this okay if you want things to
improve okay first of all you throw away
ideology you may actually you know you
may like free software foundation you
may like open-source okay I'll accept
that okay I even like that you know a
lot of that those ideas but first of all
if you want really to tease to decide
you know
what you know decide on facts or what
would work okay first of all try you
know throw away your ideology consider
you know you don't care you don't care
if open-source fails you know let's say
you know imagine if you love open source
or free software foundation just imagine
for a moment you really hate them you
hate their ideas okay just imagine for a
moment then let's think about you know
start to look for answers how do we how
can we possibly improve Emacs you know
it would you know if we change the copy
cut paste and do keys to the you know
to the cui or Windows with let's say
Windows way actually actually all Linux
is using that key to you know so if we
change that key would it actually
increase Emacs user base you know just
think about these issues and think think
try to use scientific method you know
try to throw away whatever biases you
have you know then you might find some
answers better you know
that's you know that's you know it's up
for up to you to do this to think about
this if you really want to
seek answers that's true you know
okay Jan
what is the kind of simulation
Chinese anything Chinese says
Chinese says I was making a joke I like
Oakmont layout
okay just got an idea it would it would
be cool to browse web in OGG
brass webbing oak like what do you mean
like maybe not convert existing website
but create an easy way to create such an
additional benefit would be they would
be easy to convert for local using Emacs
that would be very hard you know you
want to turn HTML to org for all the
website it would be almost like
impossible well because in website you
know you got CSS
not even you know let's ignore
JavaScript for now but actually most
websites require JavaScript these days
but even if we ignore JavaScript you got
CSS which does you know lots of things
you know CSS they can do lots of things
you know they like the oh these are CSS
you have 2d transform you have you know
so let me just look at these all these
are CSS imagine you want to put them
into oak mud you know
oak mud is you know like fan text you
cannot you simply cannot
I
would actually prefer you know I've
wrote articles about there's a
transition I real article about
Emacs actually should migrate to HTML as
its
standard documentation form and of
course this is controversial but you
know I've been talking about it for over
15 years it's not gonna happen anytime
soon
and you may not agree of course I have
to do a lot of talking to actually get
you started to maybe possibly think
about it to see if you agree you know
most I mean you probably do not agree
but I being you know I think HTML should
be Emacs
default docx format today because tech
you the text info format is like Asian
you know thirty years old nobody knows
about it you know yesterday's forever no
particular you know it's Asian it's a
relic you know
and an oak mud okay old mug Oh Oh Maude
is great okay Oh Claude is great it's
useful but
yeah I'm not saying we should be pesach
mud bog mice it's very useful to steel
but anyway wish what we should have is
that we should push Emacs to support
HTML more like natively so that when
this happens we can actually read all
the websites in Emacs and other
documentation will be you know in HTML
we can just you know read local copies
in Emacs including or Python or whatever
language : whatever you know because
they are only HTML and PHP and Java you
know then you can you can read them in
Emacs pure text that that's going to be
a pure joy now of course we have you
know the you browser and you know but
they don't really work you know well
the the really we what we really want to
do is actually to push Emacs to
really support HTML in some native way
but
but that's not even a priority but you
know like I said you know Emacs dev the
culture has lots of problems it's almost
it's almost like stagnating you know is
going nowhere
so what do you think would imac be twice
what Emacs be twice as popular in a year
if they would change command c controls
the yes
did you delete war by pressing control
now I think Emacs would in like turbo
its users if we just just adapt the
copy-paste
you know copy/paste cut and do commands
key show cut show cuts now about delete
world and by pressing control in say
report I think that all emacs already
supported
yeah I mean the question is how do you
move crews around and how do you didi
what the emag already support that in
the same way that Windows and Mac
- you know based pretty much the same
key I think that part so Janice says I
think different people use different
tools I don't consider Emacs a text
editor usually we consider whether this
interpreter
C basis yeah yeah
the other thing I really wish is I wish
eMac this would improve
you know then we can really do a lot
with it you know we can really you know
like today Emacs is like irrelevant
thing you know as a software is truly
relevant to the world okay if Emacs go
away you know in a second nothing
happens to the world but however we if
anyway that's that's anyway
so Daniel says if you are coding PHP or
Python or JavaScript you are an IDE
you use an IDE and few users for Emacs
honestly the plan for Emacs is together
to support me as code plug-in I
wouldn't want that I don't want you
access oblivious book but actually if
you called PHP or Python or JavaScript
those languages is Emacs is is very good
a lot those languages so Daniel are us
like C coder or C first first or
something like are you
system programmers like low-level or are
you more high-level but anyways PHP and
Python and JavaScript Emacs is very good
at you know that those are the languages
I do you know I of course I stick with
the Emacs I actually never used ideas
much
not in my life actually
and then I'd rather not Emax support
here's code you know the I think the
critical thing is to improve email is
you know because we can code eMac B's to
do we can you see Mac this to code so
many things like I mean like I live in
Emacs right everything I do you know all
the
7000 web pages HTML I created manually
in Emacs you know with you know with
commands and tours I wrote so we can do
that we don't want the EBS called
plugins we want we want to improve emag
lists from the language so that we can
actually do more and easier that'sthat's
my opinion
yeah I think web stuff for folk web web
dev Emacs is very good the only thing I
know Emacs is usually not suitable is
Java when you kochava
most people you know you in you need
other tools
yeah crowd is also a bad thing another
thing
crowd
ok so what's up what what else guys I
think
yeah that's it for today
kind of a tired end we are losing people
80 people watching so
any ok when any more questions feel free
to ask let me answer one you know if you
have questions one more question or two
questions
this is a great opportunity because I
don't know when I'm going to go on in
the morning you know next time I should
have a fixed schedule you know so I can
announce it early you know at this state
and this time you know I'm going to
start we're gonna have a talk show star
TV and we can you know talk about this
topic you know then people who are
interested in that topic can come online
but ok any more questions
thank you for coming thank you guys rat
rat soo great to see you again and
hygienists first time seeing you here in
hi Benjamin first time seeing you here
so thank you all guys for coming by
hope to see you again next time bye