Hello guys, welcome to another episode
of Kar talk show. We are going to code
wam language today. Uh I'm going to show
you how to do animations in wam
language. Look, look at this beautiful
fantastic
animations. So let's start wam language.
Okay, so I already got it started.
Um let's let's start a fresh. Okay,
let's start a new
session. So animations. So there is one
then uh okay new notebook and if you
don't know already just go to my website
I have a complete tutorial on wam
language and where to download. Okay
start wam language notebook. Now it's
the kernel is launched. Now let's show
you some more animations. So you can see
that another one snowflake.
Beautiful. Stop. Uh let's show some
others. So this one is done 30 years
ago. Those are 30 years ago. And here's
another one. Flashing diamond animation.
Now when you generate an animation in
Wam language, you can export it. And you
can export it in GIF in MP4 movie uh
format
uh and you know in variety of formats.
Okay. So here is another one
play and you can also generate a
sequence of images in SVG format. Then
you use JavaScript to create a player
like right now. So the advantage of this
is that you can go frame by frame like
I'm doing you know I'm scrolling the
mouse wheel mouse wheel up. So sometimes
you want to see the detail beautiful
details of it. Okay. So for example
let's say uh okay let's say this
one this
one. Copy the code. If you are watching
offline play at
1.5 speed. Okay. So let's uh there it is
the code. Let's magnify
and control shift N to make it um to
make it type set. You see type set is
beautiful. You uh you know they are
dynamic with dynamic formatting. You see
they cut the lines at appropriate
places. You never have to press indent
you know or tab or space. Okay. So now
evaluate the
code. Oh okay. So yeah. So it's done. So
you can see it stop that. Okay. So go
here. Stop.
So there it is the
animation. You can play it forward
only or you can play it
backward or you can loop forward and
backward. Okay. And and you can adjust
the speed. Press that to adjust the
speed. And let's loop backward and
forward.
Okay, stop. Or you can drag the slider.
So this is fantastic wam language
animation. Okay, uh let me show you from
scratch how to do that. You see I have
right now we are doing this animation
fancy animation of a curve of a charco
which we uh which is a plane curve uh
which is also known as spyroraph we
talked about in in few days ago. So go
watch that. So this is a fancy animation
involving the curve the blue the blue
one you see and also the normal lines
that's the red lines. Okay, but we're
gonna show you how to do animation from
scratch like moving a rectangle things
like that or you know rotating a
rectangle very simple. Okay. So, so
first of all you go to kasali.info wufam
language tutorial search for it you'll
find it and you can download it and uh
wam language in depth this complete
tutorial from scratch if you already
know a programming language. such as
Python or JavaScript, you'll be uh have
fun. Okay. So, and this is actually in
depth. It it it it it's um it teaches
you how to program how to understand
Wufam language because Wuam language is
different from all the other other
languages such as C, C++, Java, C sharp,
JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Pearl, PHP,
Bash or Hascal or even Lisp. So it's
very different from all of them. Uh,
wuam language is a symbolic term
rewriting system. So basically what it
means is just uh every syntax it just
you know it just keeps replacing the
syntax to get the result. Okay, kind of
like list macros. Okay, so download it.
Okay, download it free. Um, you know,
read about the details about wam
language, Mathematica, Wuam engine, Wuam
script, script, what's the
differences and
uh, okay, and there's a full tutorial.
Okay, so let's begin. Uh, so Wuam
language in depth. So today's uh, so
show today's talk show. Let's uh, put
the link here.
showing browser. Okay, let's do a
animation. So animation um the easy uh
you know it's very easy. Um so you all
you have to do is just say let's save
it. Okay, untitled one X untitled one.
Okay, now
um let's see uh so animation. What do I
want to show? Uh sine wave. Okay, let's
plot sign. Okay. So I'm also using kasaw
wufam
mod in emac that allows you to code wam
language in
emacs. So the key is that and here's the
documentation. So you got all these
commands all these commands. So let's
jump to the source code. Here's a source
code, 3,000 lines, but most of it is uh
the Wuam language function names because
Wuam language has 7,000 functions built
in by default out of the box. You do not
even have to load a single library. So,
7,000 functions. So, okay. So, go to the
top and go to here. Open that URL. Here
is a homepage for Kasawuan Mod. It's
free on GitHub. Okay. Download and use
it uh together with Wuam engine. So
let's paste that there.
Okay. So now we're going to show
animation show sign. Okay. So first of
all let's start um let's start a wolf
which code in
um in uh Emacs. Okay. Pop it up. So we
want to plot sign. Okay. Plot
sign uh let's say
x. Okay. So uh x goes from 0 to 2 pi.
Okay. Now go to the notebook. Show it.
Fantastic. Next we going to animate
this. So let me show you a different uh
plot. So when you study pre-calculus or
anal you know or calculus you know you
can have like a variable like what is
the effect if you put a variable inside
the argument to sign so three looks like
that what if you have four so you can do
so okay so let's type it here
table okay table I want the table of
sign two arguments the first one is
expression which is plotting sign the
second one is a list let's say I want t
here t here t goes from
uh let's say zero to one
uh let's not say zero because sine zero
x that be that would be
um so It's going to be zero sin 0. Sin 0
is zero. So it's going to be flat or
just a line. So we don't want to start
at zero. Let's say um okay. So let's do
that. 0 to one in increment of 0.1.
Okay. Copy
that. Select. Select. Select. Paste. Run
it. It's going to generate a sequence of
graphics.
So you
see but now you can notice the plot
range changes. Uh oh no it doesn't. So
so that's a difference. Okay. So table
shows generates a list of things. In
this case a list of pl uh a list of
graphics because this plot returns a
graphics like
that. Okay. Table generates a list of
graphics. Now you want to animate it you
know. So let's we can do that. Uh let's
say uh let's let's put some
commentary plus sign curve. Okay. And
this one um okay then this one
is generate a list
of sign code. Okay that's table
then. Okay then we want to animate it.
Okay.
uh show animation
of of a list of graphics object. Okay,
that's how you do it. And here you want
to just say list
animate. Very simple. Okay, so let's
copy
that. So this animate is a function and
what that function does uh wait uh wait
so you're missing something.
Okay, this animate is a function and it
takes an argument of a list of graphics
which is that. Okay,
so let's copy
that. Paste it
there. There it
is. So you can
see this list of um animation. Now you
notice it jumps a little bit. You see we
don't want that. We want the frame to be
fixed. So how do we solve that? We
specify in this plot we specify a plot
range. Um yeah so it's fixed range
otherwise it's automatic determined by
you know what is the content of the
plot. So you want fixed plot range which
is kind of the frame. Okay. So, plot
range
uh takes a arrow like that and takes a
list. Uh the list contains two things.
The first part is x form. Let's say from
zero to
uh seven. Okay. And y goes from let's
say
-1 to one. That shows the
uh range. So we can try it
here. Uh do it. So now you see it
doesn't jump
around and you can play it back and
forth. Let's back and forth and speed it
up. So this we so this kind of show the
effect of
changing the t inside the sign
parameter. Okay. So this is so this
animation feature is greatly very
powerful because then you can you can do
um x² x x3 power uh plus
uh
plus uh 4
x^2 let's say minus
4x^2 you know so you have complicated
polomial you can plot it and you can
have also have a variable variable let's
say this is
t and you can change the uh you know any
of the constant or variable so you can
see how it changes the graph
uh you know so we can um you know let's
just for the sake of completion let's
plot that okay so back here so this is
the expression copy it
um so we want to plot. Okay. So, so this
time so it's it's this expression
uh plot that not
sign x goes from this time let's say x
goes from -5 to 5. Okay.
Uh and we can do
that. Oh, then we forgot to change the
plot range. the plot range let's say uh
-5 to 5 then y goes from -5 let's say5
to 5 okay shift enter to
evaluate okay so it changes slowly now
if you say
tar you know it's going to change let's
say 2t
okay so this is fantastic And it also
show it can do in 3D. So let me
summarize what's going on. Okay,
summarize how to generate animation. So
you so all you have to do is
uh you can plot something it you know
this creates a graphics but it could be
anything. It could return a number or
whatever. Then you use
table to generate a list of them. So you
got a list of numbers or list of
graphics. Then if it's a graphics then
you put you just put it inside list
animate. Okay. So uh so for example uh
let's name it. So it's better um uh list
uh x
graphics list equals true. Okay. So we
can do that then. All you have to do
here is just say
that and we want the plot range. Okay.
So,
uh plot and plot range that okay
so and here we don't need that. So that
okay then delete that. Well that's poly
nominal
also. Uh
so like
that. Okay. So
now select all. Let's let's
um let's let's put a um old four. Press
alt4 to create a
subsection. Okay. Fantastic.
Uh, actually delete the whole
subsection. Code four
subsection
something. Paste it. Okay, here's our
code. Press shift enter to evaluate
it. So, first of all, we got a list of
the graphics. Then we got the animation.
Now, usually, you know, this list of
graphics, sometimes there's hundreds of
them. You don't want to see it. So you
put a semicolon at the end to suppress
that
output. Okay. So then you got this
beautiful
comments. Uh you know if you are here
say hi say comments. Okay. So so
now we created an animation by creating
a list of graphics. Then we just use
this animate. Okay. Now another way
another way is to uh just create
graphics directly. So let's let me show
you. So uh this so this would be
interactive
graphics. Uh so that that so how do we
do it? So instead of table so you see
here you use a table and two arguments.
The first one is expression. Uh but now
let's say uh but now you say instead of
table you call
manipulate. Okay manipulate basically
takes the same kind of argument as
table. So manipulate it you know takes
two arguments. One is the expression the
other one is the variable and what you
want it to change a
range. Now manipulate is just like table
but instead instead of creating a list
of things it just create a interactive
graphics where each
frame you know is one of the variable
value. So we can do that. So let's say
manipulate. So let's let's do it here.
Press show it. Okay. So you got So you
see now you don't have animation but you
oh wait you do but you open that. So now
it shows the value. So you can drag the
slider to see how it changes.
Okay. Now let's change let's make it
more fun. So instead instead of t goes
from let's uh uh let's multiply two.
Okay. So this way it's actually uh
moving
graphics
now. So
so Oh yeah. So let's change t the value
of t. We want to go from zero starting
from zero to
um to two. Okay. Now shift enter. Now it
looks kind of that means more fun
graphics. So you can see let's drag the
slider. Fantastic. So this is you know
sign which is a fundamental
uh actually it's the most important
function in mathematics almost
essentially like effectively the most
important or top five top three most
important function. So when you have
sign you have wave. So you know radio
frequency whatever it's all waves you
know physics and
stuff. Hey Diego good morning sir. So
fantastic. Now you so you can now you
can also play as
animation and let's say loop back and
forth. Okay. And let's increase the
speed. Fantastic. So you so when you
have a argument inside sign it creates
uh it changes the frequency. You can
also change the amplitude by changing
the thing before. Or you can make it
more complex. Let's say sin x sin x
overx. Let's say let's try something
like that. Okay.
sin
x
x Okay, now it's going to
be more complex. I think it's going to
be sign of sign.
So, okay, shift enter. Let's see why it
looks interesting. Let's
see.
Play back and
forth. Fantastic.
Okay. So that's manipulate. Again
manipulate just take two things. One is
the expression. In this case it's a
plot which generates a graphics. The
other part is the variable you variable
and range to change.
Okay. Uh I got a call. So hold on a
second. I'll be right back.
Hello. I'm
back. Check. I'm
back. Okay. Fantastic. Is it fantastic?
Let's
see. So, we got the animation. So, let's
copy. So, manipulate. Okay. Manipulate.
Super useful. So let's put it here.
Here's a more complicated example.
Fantastic. Okay. So we showed two ways
to generate animation. One is just uh
stop that. Stop that. One is just um
create a list of graphics then just say
list animate. The other way is just
directly use manipulate. So you know
okay so both way
um
works. So now what about exporting to
uh to uh MP4? Okay. So for example this
one you can just export copy that. So
you just say let's say let's set it to x
x equals 2. Okay. Shift enter do it.
Okay. So now you got a value now.
Now you just say uh let's type it here.
XX equals to that then uh
export export export takes two argument.
The second argument is whatever you want
to export which is xx
here. The second the first argument is
the file name. Okay. So let's say uh
sign of
signp. Okay. Copy
that. Paste it. Run
it. Okay. 20 seconds. 10 seconds.
Okay,
done. Now go to document f uh document
folder.
Uh let's see where is it? Uh sign of
sign. There show in the explorer. There
it
is. Close that. So you can just open it.
So let's open it. Sine of
sign.
Yeah. Okay. So wait. So copy that. Close
it. Put this back. Syntax color showing
browser. So that's what we have done so
far. Now move down. Paste the file path
of the MP4 movie we just generated.
linkify it and uh move it to the current
directory there. Okay. Sign of sign now
show in browser. Move down. There it is.
So you click on that. That's our
animation.
Fantastic. Uh so if you want to loop you
have to say loop. Okay. Let's say
refresh play.
Fantastic. Okay. So now we got the MP4
animation, but you can also do it as GIF
animation. So GIF do it.
Okay, it's done. Go to documents
folder. Refresh the browser. There is a
file. Open it. That's a GIF file. Open
in the GIF uh in the in the image
viewer.
Fantastic. Fantastic. Ctrl H to show
original
size. Fantastic. Okay, cancel it. Copy
the file path. Close. Close. Now, let's
put the GIF animation here. Link it. And
change the file location to the current
directory. Okay. Show in browser. Go
down. That's MP4. And here is give
automatic. Now you see if you don't want
the sliders to show. You see this these
sliders are just part of the movie. They
are not active. So that's what you get
when you let's stop it. Okay. Uh give
you cannot stop but you can actually
uh give right
click. Uh oh you cannot stop GIF or
something I
forgot. Anyway that's a browser webdev
issue. So anyway you got a GIF. Let's
see how large is the file. Okay. So,
show so
kilobytes and uh the MP4
is is much smaller 99 kilobytes. You
know, it depends on the uh animation.
Sometimes one is larger than the
other. Okay. So but but typically MP4 is
much more efficient but MP4 you know is
not always the best because when you
have GIF the pictures are crispy but
MP4s
uh you know may not be because when you
have line graph line graphics okay so
anyway so you got animation you got uh
MP4 animation that's how you export now
but you don't want this bar so in that
case if you don't want this you know in
active bar you just use the
uh generate a list of animate so you you
you know here we have a list of
graphics so you just say uh let's go
back to uh wam language let's go back to
code it here okay
so show animation and export that okay
so export
So export just a graphics list. Okay. So
that's what you want to do. Okay. So
copy
that. Paste
it. Do
it. Oh, you forgot to suppress the
images. Okay. But anyway, there it is.
And uh
now go to
documents. Uh search for sign. There it
is. Copy the file path. Close. Go back
to talk
show. Paste
link. Showing
browser. Uh wait.
Oh,
here you see now you don't have the the
the inactive slider at the top. Okay, I
think that's it. Why don't we show
something like uh fancy interesting or
you know uh wait what is going
on?
What? Uh file
exist. What am I doing? Oh, there's
already that file. So, you got to rename
it. Then move to the current directory.
Okay. So, and uh the wolfam code. Now,
let's clean it up. So, you got
export. Okay. Export. Yeah, that's good.
So, you can also export to GIF. Let's
just show
it. Okay. Put it back. Syntax code.
showing
browser. Okay, I think
that's that's it. We Oh. Oh, yeah. Okay.
So So now let let me So let me show you
how to um program
graphics because so far we used a
builtin plot function to create
graphics. But what if you want to draw
your own graphics? Let's say you want a
circle moving here and another circle
moving here and they collide or
whatever. Okay, so how do you do that?
Very easy. Okay, let's let's start the
code again. So let's copy this, put it
back, color it, go to the bottom, and
let's let's start a new section here.
Paste the code.
Undo wam language code block. Paste it.
Okay. So now so what is uh so this is
uh create your own
graphics for animation.
Okay. Okay. So let's code it. So let's
say
uh move a
circle. Okay. So you going to do so
graphics circle is represented by a
circle. Okay, circle takes
uh uh center let's say 0 0 and radius t.
Uh radius is let's say one. Okay. Now to
uh show this as a graphics you just call
uh graphics function and put the circle
inside.
Okay. And you want to say
axis true. Okay. Copy
that. Back to
wra stop all the animations because
otherwise it's
um cycles CPU. So run it. So you got a
circle. Now you want to move it just
like before you use a table. Okay. So
but instead now the table the expression
is going to be that. Okay. So we want
the expression to be a graphics of a
circle and the circle let's say we want
to move it from the center to 01. Okay.
So, so that will be a variable t. So, t
will go
from zero to one in increment of 0.1.
Okay, that will create a list. And then
you also want to say a plot range.
Okay, uh I'm not sure this works here,
but um let's copy the plot range.
Okay. So,
something like that.
Okay. That will give you a list of
graphics. Let's just try it. Fantastic.
Oh, no. So, you got something wrong.
Uh what is wrong? So
circle t radius
one. So t goes from zero to one in
increment of
0.1.
So let's look up circle documentation.
circle XY R okay center and
radius okay then you also can do uh
generate the elisp okay that's not
okay okay but why are we getting an
arc oh right we are moving up so with
The position of our parameter is
incorrect. So we want to t0. Okay. Shift
enter. Fantastic. Now it's it kind of
moves. So let's say t moves from zero to
um let's say uh t move from zero to 10
in increment of one. Shift enter.
Fantastic. See? So
now, so this is good. Copy it.
Copy. Move a circle. Okay. So So now we
just this animate just like before.
Okay. Copy it. Uh and uh we can in fact
do the whole thing. Moving
circle MP4. Okay. Copy
all to go
here. Go here. Paste. Uh well, copy
all. Paste. Shift.
Enter. Fantastic. Let's see. Fantastic.
Okay, that's how
you basically uh create your own
graphics. This is and then animate
it. Okay, so I think that's it. So if
you want to know more about creating
graphics such as
um such as you know these kind of fancy
things we have
or yeah let's show some yeah let's do a
fancy one. Okay then we close. So put
this
back. So, so if you want to
um know about how to create complicated
graphics, we have a tutorial before. You
just go to Kasaw Wuam language um Kasaw
Wuam language in depth. Then there is a
section. Okay. Go to the wam language
copy. Uh hold on a
second. Wam language tutorial. Yeah. So,
yeah. So, actually I want that link. Wam
language tutorial. You go to the video
tutorial. So, I've done like over 100
videos. So, there's one about how to
program
graphics. Uh, so you can
program. So, so let's do a fancy one.
Okay. You can create complicated ones
like that. This is actually my
favorite. Okay. And we we did this live
live stream. Uh you can find it live
stream. What date is
it? 2021 August. So go to YouTube, you
will find it. Okay. So paste it. Run it.
Fantastic. And and beautiful. So you can
see you can rotate
it. Uh but now let's do something. Let's
animate it. Okay. So yeah, let's let's
try to do this fancy
one. This this is called geometric
inversion. Okay. Uh now if we change
your parameter it's going to
[Music]
be yeah we can you know let's just see.
Okay. So show in
browser um yeah create a new section
here.
If you like
my tuto tutorial and videos, go tell
your friend, post on your Twitter, your
blog, okay? And uh donate to me, okay?
So, you know, go to
si info and scroll down. So you got
6,000 pages of programming information,
uh technical unic code, character
frequency, uh programming languages,
keyboards, you got um logo
design, you got well mostly programming
language tutorial. Okay, so you got all
these languages and you got mathematics.
Okay, lots of mathematics.
Uh, so you can pay me, you can get the
entire site in a zip file. Just pay me
$300 via PayPal. Use my email address
there. Okay? Or just donate to me Amazon
gift card and PayPal or Patreon me.
Okay? Thank you for that. So, but now we
want to
show So, what we want to show? We want
to do this animation. Okay. Yeah, let's
do this animation. So, um Oh, yeah. So,
but
um so when when is this uh 20121
August talk show? Okay. Go to the
directory. Show that date. There it is.
So there is a talk
show. Uh there is the talk show there.
There show in browser. Yeah. So we did
this
live 2021 August
1st. Beautiful. Okay. But we Yeah. So
let's let's do the animation. Okay. So
actually copy that. Copy that. Close
that. Close that. Uh go to today's talk
show and uh paste a link a reference to
the previous video. Now let's do the
code. Okay. So what this code do? Let's
um copy it there. So you got formatted
code kind
of. Okay. So you want to manipulate. So
just like
before we call manipulate two arguments.
The first argument is a expression which
is that. Okay. So the second argument is
a a variable that changes parameter. But
what we want
to Okay, that's easy. Let's change this
one
0.8. Okay. So make it
TT. Um but before we do that, make a
copy. Okay.
Cut, copy, paste.
Okay. Now change this 08 0.8 to TT and
uh manipulate
TT goes
from TT goes from 0.8 to uh let's say
from
0.1 to 0.8.
Okay. And
uh I think that's it. Okay. So, but this
will involve
uh Okay, I think it'll work. Okay. But
the the code is kind of
ugly. And we also need to fix the you
see we you see kinds of the frame moves.
So, we need to fix the frame. Uh, but
anyway, let's try this. Okay, you got a
problem. Oh, yeah. You forgot to copy
that. Paste. Okay. Shift
enter. Fantastic. That's what I was
expecting. Okay. Now, show the
widgets loop back and forth.
play. Yep, that's what I want. It It
increases the cube
size. Yeah, beautiful. So, if we
Fantastic. Okay, I think that's it for
today. Uh yeah, thank you guys for
watching. So, goodbye and uh so we shut
down in a minute in a minute. If you
have questions for me, ask it
now. Okay. And we Yeah. So, so I'm going
to Wait, did Wolf Language just crashed?
Oh,
Or did I just close
it? Let's open that. Yeah, I didn't
save. Okay, so let's let's just run it
again.
Uh oh, wait. It's here. Okay. So, select
all. Select all. Paste. Shift.
Enter.
Okay. Run
it and save it.
You know it would
be beautiful. There's another thing to
try. Okay. So, first of all, click on
that shift control n to type set it. And
now I'll make it whole thing smaller
100%. And uh let's
see shift n to run it again.
I want to do a add a screenshot of this.
Okay.
Stop. So, we can copy
this. Okay. So, now Yeah. Yeah. I think
I'm gonna stop. How long have you been
working with WA language? Hey, Frenzy.
Are you the frenzy? I know. I have been
working since
1992,
1993. I've been coding wolfam language
especially in the 1990s. I cod it every
day. Uh
so okay, thank you guys. Uh
bye. Yeah, that's it.
Uh
stop. Yeah. Okay. Shut down.
Uh we are
done. So delete that. Delete that. Put
it back. Syntax. Correct. So there is
today's talk
show. Oh, middle of night. So yeah, I
should change, you know, usually, you
know, I haven't so so so in the past
year, usually I do local time at noon,
San Francisco time, noon usually. So
that means it's like uh you
know, I guess middle of night for you
guys.
Um, yeah. But so if I do it in 6 PM
here, San Francisco
time, then that would be that would be
like 3:00 in the afternoon for you guys,
I
guess. Kasar, is there RSS feed for your
site? Yes, of course. If you go
to.info, you can see I have like seven
blocks there. Uh there's keyboard block,
there's RSS, you can
subscribe. RSS is kind of dead. Nobody,
you know, like very few people even know
about it. So, Emacs blog, there's RSS
feed. Uh programming block, it's all
about programming languages. So, there's
RSS feed. Then, webdev block, it's all
about JavaScript and HTML, CSS, and
website technologies.
So there's a RSS feed then there's also
math blog you know look at this
beautiful we did few days ago this kind
of sunflower pattern technically called
hypotcoid the nested evolutes of
hypotrocoid that's what this sunflower
pattern looks like I mean yeah I mean
that's a name for it and you see this
equation. Fantastic. So, math blog
there's
subscribe RSS feed and unic code blog
this RSS feed. Okay, so uh that's my RSS
feed. Bye.