good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
we are going to code emac list today
pure emac this fantastic e max lisp
okay so let's begin let's so this is
gonna be condensed emacs list
live coding and tutorial so what are we
going to do we are going to show in
browser
we are going to write
one or two or three commands
one is narrow to region xor narrowed
region a customized version of it
one is sort lines a customized version
of it
and another one is different it's
highlight unicode highlight all
characters that's not
uh ascii you know such as emoji
arrow
uh math symbols you know highlight
unicode
so one you know
uh 30 minutes to 40 minutes coding and
today is 2022 january 22nd
okay let's begin okay so if you have
questions for me
related to emacs or emac this post it
now okay so let's begin so i'm going to
so uh i'm going to the pink window shows
all my commands
cores and keystrokes like uh so
uh so let's begin okay so start emac
list
so this is the the first one we are
going to do some narrator region i'm
going to explain okay so just open the
buffer
any buffer will do you know just open
our buffer
and let's
let's um so you are looking at i'm using
xa emac be smart because imax really
smart okay so
d for different expand define function
and the function name is narrow to
region good good
now
dot string all important so
so now to regen let me explain what that
is okay now you there is a command in
emacs called narrowed region that lets
you focus on particular section of your
buffer for example let's say i have
several of these so i want to do find
and replace for example i want to
replace or region the word region to
something else
but i only want to do it within this
paragraph so i can make a selection
and call narrow to region
you see the buffer only shows this part
and you can see the command is over
there narrow to region okay
so
now you can do
query replace for example region r e g i
o n in the mini buffer replaced with x x
for example do it replace
for all so now it's done now if you move
to all the way up it won't let you move
because
e max right now is limited to this
region so now when when you are done you
can call widen okay do it
and scroll up you can see now the other
parts so you can see the white and white
is the command you can call it by meta x
white okay
uh so
okay so so so that is the that that is
what narrow to region is but however
however let me show you let's go to star
talk show okay today's top show you know
so you are right now looking at the say
today's talk show page which is uh you
know this html and you can see this is a
buffer
now if i want just to focus on these two
parts i can make a selection
you know uh
i can make a selection then narrow to
region now any anything
i do will be limited to this
but when but the other parts are still
there so the problem i mean what we are
going to do is that when you call out
region
you have to make a region first you have
to make a selection you know start a
selection then move your cursor for
example up to here then narrow okay now
widen again you can see you have to make
a selection first but oftentimes
you want a command that
you don't have to make a selection
because make a selection
involves you know two or three more
keystrokes
so you want it if there's no selection
you want a narrowed region just work on
the current
block of text
defined by separation of empty lines so
you see this empty line here and this
empty line there so you can just call
the command and we automatically narrow
to this part without having to you know
without you having to make a selection
you know especially with the mouse it's
more tedious okay so that's that's the
reason we are writing it so let's begin
writing it
okay so now at region let's uh begin
okay so now treat region
uh first of all you want uh
if
you want to check if there's selection
first okay so if
uh let's put some documentation here
okay
same as narrowed region
but if no selection
now to the current block
okay
that's a documentation version today's
date okay now let's begin now first of
all
the first thing you want to do is check
if there is a selection so the way you
do that is
region
active p
expand expand good
region active p means
p in emac this command convention and in
this in general when a function ends
with p or a variable ends p that p
stands for predicate
that can form logic so basically
practically that means this function or
variable
this function always returns either true
or false so if it ends in p that's a
convention it returns true or false or
the value of the function is
of the variable is true or false so if
region is active
then
then you just say
narrow to region
okay
and narrow to region two arguments two
positions region beginning
and the region end
okay
and you don't need the save restrictions
so let's remove those okay so hold on a
second so remove put that here so
what
okay
narrow to region so if there's a region
narrow to region beginning and region
end now
if there is no region
then you need to
you need to find the position of the
of the
of the empty lines beginning and empty
lines
of the beginning of
two empty lines like right here
and the end of the region
is right here you know they are
separated by two empty lines so let's go
to my emac this tutorial so you search
for practical emac disk
and you find
and and the
practical emac list and you go to
there is
a code
so
get text block
right there click on that so this is the
code you want let's copy it
it's already written so
it saves time so let's paste it here the
essential part is
is uh
this okay so let's cut it
and uh put it here
let's
remove that
predefined code okay so when there is no
no region this is the part you want
okay wait
this part gets you um
hold on a second so this part this this
so this
block of text they returns the beginning
position of the block
and end position of the block by
searching for two empty lines you see
search
regular expression search backward
you search for two empty lines then you
move forward so that's the beginning of
the
of the
block
and the
and when you found it you set the point
p1 to it by the way yesterday we we did
we explained this whole thing because we
did a similar thing uh two days ago
uh so watch that
so yeah just in scaffold yeah all the
code you know you can just find on my
you know this that's the best thing
practical emac these thousands literally
over a thousand pages and examples
uh a fast way to learn emac list
and emacs so if you like my stuff you
guys or whoever is watching you you know
you know you can support me by
star emacs tutorial
buy it
it's fantastic it's a gesture and you
get it you get the downloaded you know
you get the fast version and
so full of emac these tutorials and
examples and advanced e-magnets and
writing how to write a major mod
and i did several videos by the way this
so this one is yesterday so let's let's
focus let's go back to the code okay
let's
finish this
so
so once you find the beginning position
of the paragraph or block you set you
know to p1 so you need a variable
so let's make a variable here okay so
let's say
yeah so let's let
let is a local variable
and say let's declare two variables p1
and p2 you don't need the dollar sign
but i use a dollar sign for variable
because that way
in sub emax least mod it's highlighted
you know so it's easier to see all the
variables
okay so
copy that
paste it here
prettify the code so here's the code
so let p1 and p2
save excursion save excursion means
whenever you move cursor when your
function is done you should move the
cursor back to where it was otherwise
user gets confused you know user calls
your command your command
moves the cruiser in order to do
something when instant
normally you should return the cursor to
wherever that cursor was so that is what
this function save excursion is
so
you can look describe function okay
let's show the pink window describe
function save excursion then you see the
documentation for the save excursion
function okay so let's save excursion
then you search for the blank lines
search for the empty lines then you set
p1 in the same way you search you know
you search the end of the empty lines
then you get p2 set it then
okay then
now the code is a bit nested here so
then
uh you wanna so then you just say narrow
to region
p1 and p2 and you don't need the save x
restrictions so
okay so that is it i that is it actually
so let's um
let's let me clean the code remove the
remove uh redundant part for example
so
okay that that's it so
evaluate the code you can see i'm
calling run
run current file but you you can also
call
uh eval region okay so
so let's try it okay so let's say if i
put an empty line here
and my cursor is here
now if i go narrow to region
it should it should just narrow to that
part okay
without making any selection okay so
call it
wait is that right
undo
uh
it should begin here and end here
because there's no empty lines in
between there so let's do it again so
make sure we got the code correct
okay it should okay let's do it
oh okay okay i see i'm not actually i'm
i was calling narrator region i was
encoding our version so now let's call
our version meta x
xor narrow to region you can see in in
the mini buffer middle extra narrative
region
fantastic
widen now let's let's put the cursor
here
and it should narrow to you know this
part
i mean i external to region fantastic
widen
okay now let's let's let's uh try do
some uh
you know edge case testing so
show white space so let's say the buffer
does not have a
long end at the end when you con when
you call your command what will happen
because it's trying to search for empty
lines so let's try it
sign out region do it
fantastic it works
widen
now what if there is no
lines in the beginning so
do it fantastic it works so okay this is
done so we got this function done now
this function is going to be part of
sapphire keys so let's put it there so
let's
delete it wait uh delete it
now
call describe key then press a key
that's one of the functioning stuff like
keys so i press this key
this key called saffly command oct
command mod activate
and then
so that the documentation pops up so i
can just tab to the link
softly keys dot el to the file press
enter
then i'm seeing the source code so this
is one of the fastest way
now here's a tip okay this is the
fastest way when you want to open
some emac list package file
you know as opposed to
call open file then type the directory
path but you you don't remember where is
it the file located so you have to you
know type completions directory com you
know that's directory completion that's
tedious
so instead instead you just call
describe key
so you he is you can see all the
commands here you call describe key
then you type the key to one of that
code from the command in the in the
package then you'll show you the
documentation for that
function then there's a link to the
source code where is it defined then
press enter so that's how we got here
so
so now let's open a new buffer paste it
so this is our code okay
and let's
let's
list matching lines let's list all the
functions in this package let's see
where do i want to put it
i mean what order which position so
let's see comments and questions
okay so let's put in
narrow to region so this is some
customized narrative region where should
you put
it
you know you want in usually you want to
put it where
of other functions that does similar
things like user
okay let's see
space to newline field and field
up case region toggle case delete
backward char copy or forward forward
punctuation
uh
end of line of block beginning of line
or block
okay somewhere here okay
copy or cut or paste or paste previous
show kyo ring
okay let's put here forward smart quote
okay
so let's
put it
yeah okay let's put it here paste it
there it is fantastic so narrow to
region
now save the file
now
you want to
now in software keys there's a key
that calls narrow to region let me show
you describe key
space n n
you can see
space n n runs the command narrow to
region
i want to replace that key by calling
our own function our own version of the
function
okay
search for narrow to region
copy sun
out region
search narrow to region okay there are
so many okay so where is it
okay
uh
there it is
okay so you see that line
now you want to replace that by xanar to
region
now
fantastic
so this is stuff like keys now it just
improved okay now let's go all the way
to the top and modify the version line
so
today
insert today's date timestamp
date and time in seconds
then increase the version should we well
yeah it's because it's a new feature
so
a new version of xrfi keys
okay it's on github so let's let's push
to github so
you know you guys can see the code right
away
so okay so
but first of all right now you are
looking at xr packages so these are all
my uh packages remove the
backup files delete them so this is all
my packages but i have a dedicated
github for soft light keys
so open that and call the command
that will copy the current file into
into the directory of sapphire keys on
on you know a dedicated kit for sapphire
keys okay so
we just copied and now let's call
vc diff
see what's the difference between the
the current version and the previous
version in git
so you can see we changed the version
date and we changed
you know so this is this entire block is
new start narrow to region
okay
and some other fixes okay uh
yeah some other fixes i did before
so anyway so it's there
so okay that's good
go to isiah emacs show the fastest most
convenient show written in emac beast so
you see when you master emac list
everything is possible
so now
git status
git add
git commit
okay so you want to say xrfl keys okay
so you want to say
new
okay so
what's the name
saw narrow to region okay
nukes are not region this
okay you cannot see it but um
okay so
get
commit message stuff like his nukes are
narrow to region okay
enter fantastic now
get pushed
okay now it's on github stuff like keys
download it and use it and it's free
okay we finished one job
now
let's close close
okay so
narrow um
i want to
i want to update the key so i can use it
myself
uh let me show you so so right now i'm
in this soft light defined keys you know
that's the heart of soft flag keys so we
need to
evaluate this function you know because
we made a change so that i don't have to
restart emacs i can have it right away
so do it
okay
so now describe key space n n
it says
runs the command saw narrow to region
correct fantastic
okay so that's one thing done so let's
get on to the next thing close close
close
uh
close don't save
undo this is this is our pad you know
the temporary pad now press a key to
make them go back to the sound talk show
page showing browser you can see the
code here as well
and
color it
back to browser refresh fantastic color
okay next
how long have i been talking 22 minutes
we can do one or two more
comments and questions emacs master
peter gade the dude
fantastic next
write a sarso lines that works on
current block if there's no region
okay
this is very similar to two previous so
we're gonna do this fast silent
uh it's like silent movies you know um
silent era asylum movie so let me just
do this quickly
the fun
uh the command name would be
[Music]
exacto lines okay
put here
paste
like so lines
but if no region
do the current block okay
version
date
okay that's
the yeah that's the that's the command
so
again
just like narrow to region
open a new buffer open a new window
let's go to
now let's let let me show you some uh
variations okay so
describe key let's jump to the
definition of narrow to region uh
sapphire keys okay what what is this
okay so
so go to sapphire keys
search forks are narrow
okay here's uh now remember in this
in this examination region we need to
find the beginning and end position of
the text block
and we did that using this
this code but there's an easy way okay
so
there's a because i have already written
a package
you don't need uh you know all these 10
lines so there's already a package so
let me show you
um
search for
block okay
there okay so let me just show you um
yeah let me show you okay so
so you see this block of code will find
the current um
the position of the beginning
paragraph and end position of n
paragraph now
you can do that by this one single
command star get bounce or block or
region
target balance of
a block or region yeah
so let me show you how this works okay
so
so saves you a lot of code okay so
so this command will return a vector of
three things
beginning position
and position
uh
no it returned two things beginning
position and end position what are they
if there's if there's a region
these positions are of the region if
there's no region these positions are
the beginning and end of the current
block
so
these two lines replace these 10 lines
okay
so let's uh
yeah so we
delete that so
delete that we can actually put it here
so
so now we got the
um
yeah so now we got the block now sold
lines okay salt lines
now we need to call salt lines okay
now first of all look at the
documentation of sold lines describe
function sort lines so lines so here is
the syntax of solar lines
okay begin end is going to be
p1
p2 that's the beginning and end position
now what is reverse reverse is true or
false okay so lines in the region
alphabetically
reverse the neo
means descending order okay so reverse
is true
t
is the convention in e magnesium to
stand for true t the variable or symbol
okay
so
okay so that's it for this code so
simple so nice so if there's no
selection just simply sort the current
block of text okay
about the region
now let's move the cursor here first of
all copy the function name put the
cursor somewhere here call it
paste it exactly lines okay
do it
fantastic
now let's copy it duplicate and let's do
it again
go ahead it you know we if we call it
now it should sort the lines here
so put this cuz somewhere here call it
so lines fantastic it doesn't you see it
doesn't go up and it doesn't go down
saves you time you don't have to make a
selection first
you know it's annoying in emac
in emacs you know the emacs list
the emax command so lines
it requires a region
but if you don't have a region
the behavior is kind of chaotic
unpredictable you know it's not easy to
figure out because i've tried you know
for example
um
uh because um
because for example let's call salt
lines you know now we don't have any
selection
so let's call sword lines
okay
so
what we are
i mean which region is
going to sort sometimes it's
it's the beginning from the beginning of
the buffer to your cursor position
sometimes it's from the your cruiser
position to end of the buffer it depends
so it's
confusing so let's try it do it
okay that does it didn't do anything so
apparently if your cursor is
on the empty line it doesn't do anything
so let's put the cursor here
go ahead
you see it sorts
okay so
so the behavior is that it sorts the
previous two
marks yeah i think that's
that's the behavior
so anyway we want this one you know
without region just sort the current
text block
okay so now
we're gonna
we're gonna copy this and put it to
start like keys okay do it
again
these matching lines list or defend and
see where do we want to put put it okay
search for narrow let's put it around
the narrow to region okay so put it here
there
okay and also let's modify the narrowed
region we don't want this uh this giant
block of code instead we can just use
this
you know these two lines okay so let's
do that
okay so that's it that's
um so now we have added
exactly lines
let's add a key to it so search for salt
lines
okay so you can see this line
i want to
now it's going to be exactly lines
fantastic
evaluate this region
okay we did it now we've done uh two
things now let's see
yeah now let's
now we did two functions okay
make a backup close it close it close it
put it back to the html syntax color it
show in browser
what
wait
syntax client
expand the buffer
showing browser
fantastic we finished one function and
two functions one more okay one more
uh we talked for 30 minutes one more
highlight unicode so this is a bit
different okay so let's begin to write
it
close it reopen
let's begin to write it
define
the function name
highlight unicode okay documentation
height
highlight
unicode
characters
highlight all unicode characters in
current
block
or selection
okay
version
date okay
again we need to make a selection of the
of the current block okay so let's copy
code again
okay here copy the code
by the way so that code that code get
bounce
of block or region
is in one of my packages you can see so
you are looking at the source code of
that code
and if you look at so this command this
function is calling this
function to do the work so if you go
there
go to the definition of that function
where is it
here
you see
that's the function
basically just like we manually coded
before
it's doing it by searching uh searching
for
two empty lines using regular expression
and this package you can go to the top
you can see the url here go to the url
open it
show in browser
uh wait not because i fly keys
uh what
okay wait no that's not the command what
oh never mind i defined it in soft like
keys okay but but anyway there's a
package
um
and let me show you here okay
so general purpose elise util
this one
get thing okay
so socket thing this is a replacement
for the bld emax thing at point
because thing at point it's got some
problems it's very useful
but
it doesn't for example it you cannot use
it to get the beginning and end position
of the current
block of code
that's why so i wrote this one so if you
like it you know buy it it's open source
okay so
what is it we are doing now so get block
of code yeah so we need to um
so let's get uh
okay close it
so
oh yeah so the so we want to write
um
[Music]
highlight unicode
so first of all
okay so
so we declare local variables bounce
that's beginning position basically p1
and p2 that's the beginning position in
the end position there
i think i had a mistake somewhere
so p1 p2 that's our local variable
then
yeah okay so never anyway so
narrow to region we don't need
so we define p1 and p2
and now
so now we got the beginning position and
end position so now we just search
forward
we want to search for any character
that's not a unicode
okay search for any character that's not
unicode so the regular expression is
going to be
[Music]
this okay
so
the square bracket in regular expression
means anything
any of the character inside it
okay
then inside it
if you begin with the correct that means
not whatever follows okay it kind of
reverse so
not every any anything follows and what
follows you give it a square bracket
colon ascii that means any ascii
character
so
this regular expression the you know the
whole thing considered
it will just find any ascii character
for example
it will not find things like
things like pi
alpha greek
emoji
uh you know like
copyright
uh those are unicode so you will not
find them
so anyway so you want to find a ascii
you want to find an ascii character one
or more okay
so
so let me do this okay uh let me do
write this quickly so narrow to region
okay p1 p2 so we work in this region
then we say
go to char go to char move cursor to
point mean
to the beginning of the buffer basically
then
we want to say while
okay
why or something
while we search for a character that's
not
ascii
then we don't want to replace match we
want um
search for character not ascii then we
want to highlight okay so how do you
highlight you go to uh
emac this tutorial
practical emac these
emac leaves this by the major mod then
you go down
uh we
covered these two days ago
overlay highlighting okay that's what
you want
and basically you just want this
line of code so let me copy that
so i
so in two two videos ago i explained
this okay so i'm not going to explain it
now so let's just do it
so basically we
create an overlay
kind of overlays for highlighting so we
create an overlay technically it's
called overlay so you need two positions
beginning and end so beginning position
is p1 our variable end position is p2
are variable
so wait
wait okay so actually let me
let me start over so big so
once it finds
a unicode sequence
okay
a character you know any unicode
sequence so
the regular expression search for word
emacs will save
the beginning position and end position
of the matched string okay so how do you
get that matched string that's a match
beginning
zero and match end zero
so
match beginning zero that mean that
means the zero means the whole string
that means return
the beginning position of the matched
whole string okay and similarly for
match n so let's so that's what this
overlay should be here
so overlay make overlay match beginning
okay
then then
match end
okay
and face
not bold highlight okay
we need the default face let's see
face
define phase
so
these are build in face face means a set
of
font color background color font size
things like that that's a face
so one of the building phase is
highlight h-i-g-h
okay spelled out fully highlight
okay
so
make overlay so let's let's make this
easier to see so it's pretty fine okay
pretty find the code
so
make overlay beginning and end position
that's okay so
then face highlight okay then we don't
need to active okay
so
okay basically that's it that's the code
that's the whole code and it's
so while search that and optional okay
bound
neo
no error true count we don't care okay
that's the whole code
so let's double check
okay
highlight unicode
highlight any unicode okay highlight
highlight or unicode characters in
current block or selection okay
now p1 and p2 are the beginning and end
positions
now we call these target bounds block or
region to return the those positions
may be a selection or no selection it's
the beginning and end of paragraph okay
then we save restriction then we narrow
to region then we go to the beginning
then we start to search
and
while if it's found
make an overlay color it okay that's it
evada eva region now we need to test it
so how do we test it
you know we can test it right here but
it won't do anything because there's no
unicode in this buffer so but we can try
call it
highlight unicode do it nothing happens
okay so let's go to
so let's open unicode emoticons okay so
let's let me show you okay
okay so
showing browser so this is my one of my
website html so
let's
so that's my
okay this buffer is too big it's kind of
very big so let's go to something
shorter here hands
okay
so
uh let me go to okay so let's close that
cut copy the url
open the file so here is the file
so you can see all the unicode but let's
copy it
open a new buffer paste it
so that
and right now it's in html mod that's
why you see them yellow so let's turn it
to the
um
fundamental mod
you know fundamental mod is a mod with
no features basically that's uh like no
mod okay so now you are looking at this
file you know typically when you have a
file from internet or whatever
you know sometimes it's quick it's
important it's very useful you want to
know
weird characters like sometimes there's
invisible unicode characters like
non-breaking space things like that so
you want to be able to be able to see
them
you know one of the things you can do is
turn on the
uh turn on the
show white space
in you know but use but some of the unit
but the unicode is not highlighted you
see that one uh so that's why
you want to write the command highlight
unicode you know that's what why we want
to do that highlight unicode okay so
let's try it so you can see there's some
unicode here here
and here turn off the um white space
okay so you can see here here
and here
um
so let's call the command all those
characters should be highlighted okay
cool
highlight unicode do it
failed
wait oh it different success success you
can see you see those characters they
they are highlighted okay so they
so this command only does on the current
paragraph you know the current text
blocks remember
comments and questions okay there's some
comments okay we're gonna uh and i'm
gonna answer it in a bit okay
almost done okay so unicode you get
success
so let's make a modification to the code
to our code because
usually you don't want to do it
in the current block of code you want to
do it to the whole buffer okay so let's
begin so let's let's do to the whole
buffer
buffer okay so p1 and p2 will be
max okay basically that's a buffer
beginning and buffer end positions
okay
that's it
okay if i buffer
now switch to our
uh to our code you can see
there's lots of you know
unicode you see lots of so let's call
the command
it should
you should do
highlight all the unicode characters not
you know in a whole buffer so call it
do it
uh what did we call yes uh okay it
worked
you see
you see all those um
it worked
but i don't like the color okay so
let's save this file xx today's date
so we can open it later close it reopen
so the coloring is good now back to our
code now i don't like the highlight
color we want to make it more
stand out
so let's say red let's say background
red or something
okay background red so let's go back to
the um
we are almost done let's go back to the
xr emacs tutorial where is it yeah
okay let's go to xymax emac this
tutorial
show in browser
then how to write the major mod
define face let's see if there's some
predefined phase we can use
default bold italic body italic
underline shadow link highlight
error warning
okay let's try let's try warning okay
because we wanted
uh we wanted
warning so what's the example of warning
i
so let's see so you can what you can do
is
this faces display call the command
and emax will show
or example predefined faces in emaclis
so we want something standing out like
that
so this is custom group tag one that's
no that's not good custom invalid
something bold
diet warning
diet warning that means you have to you
have to load diet so
i do incomplete regular expression
so
you want something
termed color red okay no
trading white space okay
you know so if you're gonna use some of
these that means you need to load those
package i don't want to load those
package because
because
defining a face is just four lines of
code you know i can just define a face
myself
so the preference is that
the preference is that you want to use a
face that's already building and loaded
by emacs
then
then you pick a package i mean the
package should be something everyone
everybody uses you don't have to load it
so anyway so i'm getting a bit um i
guess
where's warning let's search for warning
okay direct warning front lock one if
okay this one fantastic this is fun lock
is everyone loads phone lock so
so so that's the face we want front lock
warning face
fantastic
okay close it
so close it let's go so here it's gonna
be front lock warning face
about the buffer
go to our test file this one that's
right magnify you see there's lots of
unicode
here
and uh
and that
see so let's call it
faces this this uh
highlight unicode do it
fantastic okay
you know you see here
and uh
okay so
okay so this is
not too bad uh
you know it would be better if they are
more standing up like a background color
or something or big font but this is
this is good
good and then enough for our first
version okay so this is fantastic done
so
now we
copy this uh let's clean up the code
okay remove those comma shrink make it
shrink
highlight the all unicode characters in
current block in current buffer
okay let's say buffer
okay not selection let's just say buffer
okay
actually selection is good okay anyway
that's what we have so
let's
that's good enough
back to
the html page
syntax client shown in browser
so today we did three functions one two
three and let's put highlight unicode
into
where do we want it
that's it let it be for now okay
thank you guys for watching if you like
my stuff buy my emacs tutorial okay and
donate paypal patreon and stuff
five so we did 15 minutes we did three
emac this functions fantastic so i'm
gonna read comments we close in in two
minutes
so have i used
x e max
yes of course i used xe max
for
for five for six years
from 1980
1998 to 2005.
so i used xe xemax
for five four seven years okay
to
2005 or 2006 then i switched
to glue emacs
because
xe mac xd max is kind of dying because
mostly because unicode support gnu emax
has always been inferior
you know opinions differ but
i think google e-max has been inferior
you know so that's history okay so
that's another topic
uh let me show you sardi xe max so
usually if you want to know anything
what i think of just search for for my
name in the
that topic world okay so here's the
article my experience of emacs versus
xemx and another article gnu e max and
xemax schism
so this is the granddaddy history of
open source
you know open source uh you know
emacs
gnu emacs versus xemx is considered to
be the first big example of the
fork okay like folk
anyway today's you know
today's attitude towards four kings is
is totally different because of git
github
for commercial grid greed reasons so
anyway so here's an article about xc max
so yes i used it i used it for seven
years and it's much better
it's much better in a lot of ways than
guru emacs so i have a list of them
uh historical merits of xc max
okay i'm not going to go over so because
today's emac this uh so
uh what about
s x e max x x
s x e max i never used okay i understand
it's a by a guy i you know i was talking
to him on irc
about 15 years ago
just a little bit um
so he's a guy he's a fanatic okay
sxe max the guy who created it
i don't know what's what's happening to
that um
i haven't heard them you know this is
long ago this you know this is 15 years
ago so today's generation is totally
different you know the hacker generation
those x emacs
and you know those generations are dying
out you know it's gone so today you have
the male engine and programmers and the
zoomers
they don't they don't know uh they know
much less
so anyway i don't know what's going on
with the sx emacs i don't i don't think
it's really
that much going
x emax has been dead for many years i
mean like yeah basically dead
what do you think of them compared to
glue ems okay that is my answer xe max
so back in 1990s so this is early you
know this is basically during the whole
1990s
xe max is superior in every aspect lots
of features you need
you know and they are only xemx they are
not in gnu emacs why
the
phonetism of free software foundation
you know the free software foundation
and that phoneticism so they don't do
nothing they don't do anything you know
you have to donate you have to
you know reach a snowman
uh
you know they focus on ethics they focus
on their ideal of ethics they don't
really care about anything else
so but meanwhile
the history of xemax is commercial based
because you know the lease machine the
big history this machine this machine
corporations and all that this creates
lots of commercialization and the xe max
is beginning it was known as lucid emacs
and lucid emax is started by at least
at least
company ai company that says doing
artificial intelligence
and
so this is around 1990
just about the end of ai
period so they are they cannot make much
money then they started to do a ide for
c plus based on e max
so
so they they you know they they work on
they they want to make new e max to be
the best
c plus first ide okay
so they worked on that
and they talked with the gnu people you
know
i mean the the intention is that you
know they are off uh into open source i
mean the not open source but the free
software foundation the intention is
that we're gonna make this great
free software and we can sell you know
that's uh you know you can sell free
software you know
anyway this is long history but because
today's generation you can even know you
don't even know the difference between
open source and free software foundation
they are big enemies you know if you say
thank you richard solomon for your open
source you'll get very very very
offended he'll say yourself you
know they are big enemies free software
and foundation under the open source
open source is beginning by esr the guy
esr kind of
i would say kind of
uh you know i don't yeah i don't think
he
he's
i'm not going to talk about that okay so
that's another day
so anyway so
eventually
the xe max and the you know xe so here's
another famous guy uh the
jwz okay jamie zawinski he's a cocky
type of guy you know i
admired him for actually you know i kind
of uh you know i like because i mean i i
um
jwz not jzw okay he's i mean you
probably heard of him because he's
famous for the dot-com you know so
there's wikipedia and his his website
looks like that for the past 30 years
2020 for the past 20 years since
you know this is a theme
beginning with a matrix movie you know
uh kind of so that's you know jamie
zawinski so
so jamie zorinsky he's a famous lisp
coder
and he is the main coder for xemax the
lucid emacs it's not called xemx it's
called
lucy emax
so they started to you know
collaborate with
free software foundation google e-max
and they
they enhance it they patch it back but
eventually there's a problem because
communicate you know for many reasons
they started to have problems
the then richard stowman
claimed you know you need to do this
these this
but today they are you know they are a
for-profit corporation right but they
anyway long story i cannot do justice to
the story without screening up the
details because
because to the young people today you
don't know what's you know you don't
know what's going on
so anyway here's a
here is a discussion of the schism by
ben wing ben wins the next
leader of
xemax after jamie zorinsky okay
basically richard stoneman is just uh
very difficult to work with very
impractical you know even though the you
know you have a commercial entity
that's willing to help you you know they
have money they they're gonna they don't
you know they contribute a lot but
you know eventually richard stowman
working with richard stoneman you got
problems richard stowman have problems
with all the linuxes you know
and
all the
debian you know
in the beginning they they all say
richard someone is the god you know
please be our uh chairman or something
then after a few years there's always
problems then eventually people voted
richard stoneman out
and now
after 10 years after 20 years today you
have the marine chain there's something
else social justice
then
they claim richard someone is a
rapist or whatever
so golan golan you know yeah i like
golan but golan
you know golan is not you know i like it
but it's not a language i actually code
that much every day uh so
in order to do golan i have to
be familiar with it uh so
you know otherwise i'm gonna be stuck in
my talk show
often
so dollar sign doesn't mean anything in
magnifice but in my case i use it so
that the variable stands out
in
emac this mod
okay bye guys bye my tutorial okay
donate me buy me a drink
bye
so we shut down in two minutes
so three emac this code fantastic okay
so
let's close that close that don't save
because that
fantastic holy emoji
okay bye