good morning welcome to another episode
of Zatoichi Oh today is June 20 2019 we
haven't had this for a while I've been
skipping for the past two or three days
but we are back and today we are going
to do this let me show you what we're
gonna do we're gonna talk about the Lisp
issue we cannot talk about JavaScript
SVG coding drawing a lisp a circular arc
that's one thing we cannot talk about
and we are also going to talk about the
use of math symbols in programming
languages function function names so let
me get you to what we're gonna show so
Casali javascript blog okay we go to
saudi javascript blog and you can see
that's my web dev blog and there's a
bunch of thing this we did I finally
coded this completed and this is great
so you go there so that's what we're
gonna talk about this thing okay so this
thing let me show you the other thing
we're gonna talk about so the other
thing is sorry sorry blog ok programming
blog we go to the programming blog and
there it is you go there and a bunch of
very interesting highly interesting
Unicode stuff you know Unicode and
symbols and syntax and you know and
writing systems
that's all related to these symbols so
the earth topic
we are going to talk about is the use of
math symbols in programming language
function function names I have some
examples here let me show you google ads
google ads every every page on every
page you know Google ads that's anyway
that's another topic we're gonna talk
about that some other day you know the
anyway so so math symbol is function
names in Python Java you know JavaScript
Java Haskell Perl Python Java goal and
all these languages so these are the two
topics we don't talk about let's begin
with these circle arc so if you are
watching say hi let me pop out this yeah
so if you're watching say hi
so this oh but before we do that
actually I need to let me let me talk
about let me type what we're gonna do
JavaScript SVG drawing Elise hawk and
math symbols in programming in function
names Python Haskell Hecht oh it's full
okay that's the topic we cannot talk
about so let's begin with a Java Script
let me show you this demo first I
finally did this you see so this this is
interactive application you can adjust
the center then you can adjust major
axis or the minor axis then you can
adjust at what angle you know at what
angle you want to begin and how much
sweep you want for example let's let's
say that and we can do that you see
and then this is rotation how much the
whole thing is rotated you see so
finally I did this I'm very happy with
it and there are several interesting
things to talk about the several aspects
we we can talk about again if you are
watching say hi that would be that would
make the topic you know that talk much
more interesting you know when you give
me feedback any opinions or anything
feel free to type it so this JavaScript
so we can talk about I can give you a
tutorial a short tutorial on SVG SVG is
the scallop scalable vector graphics you
know it's used to draw clock so anything
lying oriented for stock tic
you know graph math plots planting
mathematics curves
you know functions curves SVG is
suitable your bar charts you know pie
chart you know things like that so SVG
is the technology so I can give you a
short tutorial on SVG and also I can
give you a short tutorial on JavaScript
and how to script the Dom such as how is
this program is written let's look at so
that's one aspect I can talk about
tutorial the other thing very
interesting about this thing is that the
SVG spec ok that that is arranged and
why I started to write this application
the SVG spec is one of the worst SPECT
possible okay so let's go to SVG let's
go to my local web site so it's faster
to load well except I don't have
JavaScript on in Firefox so that why not
it's just okay let's go to SVG so you
see SVG technology
this suspect it's got the you know
sometimes way up if you are a programmer
you know sometimes you programming some
technology or programming language you
know you have books right you run into
bugs or no documentation it's very
frustrating you know you spend hours or
days so to find a bug and eventually you
the bug is caused not by you but by
because you know some idiocy of the
programming language or protocol or
whatever so you know and in such example
are you know huge turns of example of
these kind of thing in JavaScript and
Dom technology you know it's very
frustrating you know the browser doesn't
you know support it doesn't follow the
spec or the spec is simply stupid you
know as a programmer you are probably
very familiar with this good morning
Danielle on heaven yeah we haven't had a
talk show for a while how are you
so SVG so sometimes you got you know
lots of problems in technology and there
is one example in SVG that's egregious
okay egregious what is so what is the
problem the problem is when you want to
draw a circle you can do like this okay
it's very simple that's all you do you
put this in your file and show in
browser and it draws a circle and if you
want to draw an ellipse you can do as
well you oh you have to say is that you
know a lisp then attribute CX CY equals
2 then rx ry which is the major axis in
the minor axis so you know it's very
simple to draw a circle it is however if
you want to draw a pie chart you need
you know as an arc of a circle you
cannot do that you know you it is
possible but it's extremely difficult it
is extremely difficult that is why I
finally wrote this app
to do that you know this is this is the
app that allows you to troll for example
it's making 100 here and make it you
know like if you want to draw a quarter
of a circle it's very difficult Lin okay
so this is a major problem why does this
happen you know it's I'm going to
describe the problem in detail but why
does this happen because SVG you know
when I was younger I thought all these
standards they are created by all the
experts you know of a particular field
for example you you know we have you
know Internet HTTP tcp/ip things like
that so that's internet for logo and
email protocol and you know chat
protocol that's how the internet works
you know we got all these things works
on the surface it appears it just works
wireless you know Wireless and
everything but beneath its extreme
complexity anyway
when I was younger I thought you know
all these protocols and standards and
language design you know Python Ruby
whatever tasks are they must be designed
by expert you know like maybe a group of
expert committee you know it gather
together and talk oh how to solve the
problem for the world and they
eventually they design a thing that is
the standard you know protocol but as
you as Ike as now I know as you grow
older you know that's not like that at
all so how did this but how did this
standard spec specification came around
mostly its social issues okay it's
nothing like UI you know you might you
know I think you know experts get
together and design the thing it's not
like that rather it's mostly okay the
major reason the the standard form how
they form is because one the
most important critical reason is that
corporations greedy money oriented
corporations they want to make something
they want to make money they want to
sell it they want to you know they maybe
they created the language in technology
or whatever for example Microsoft you
know everyone hates Microsoft you know
you if you are my followers you probably
hate Microsoft you know for example
Apple Apple is very well known for it
you know Airport everything is patent
patent and greed and you know they
although they they they usually do
extremely good design but still they
want to make money money is the main
thing that drives Apple as you know as
well as Microsoft and today we have
Google you know Google is the company
that was you know supposed to know Evo
and today it's the most evil possible
and the most powerful and evil company
they do you know they their browser
Chrome browser before it's like oh let's
follow standard but now they
intentionally do devious things so that
nothing rinsing of the browser
they only even in Google Chrome browser
so well how did the standard came from
you know you know so usually the one
most major reason is that the
corporations you know money-hungry
corporations they they created you know
they publish it and you hope that all
the people will use it as a standard you
know like now this is our standard you
know for example Apple has Swift
programming language
Microsoft has the direct3d you know
what's it called direct3d yeah for great
you know computer graphics games you
know in terms of things you know file
systems NTFS file systems Apple says
they are proprietary file systems you
know and if they publish it as a
standard often the reason is that they
want you to use
but but meanwhile eventually they charge
you like annual annual developed
developer fee you know for Apple is like
hundred dollars or something you know at
Microsoft the same and so many so many
examples javascript for example where
does javascript spec came from could I
make a pie without pie okay so where
does where does JavaScript spec came
from it came from because Netscape
created this language they want to sell
it and you know and back then this is
1995 when open-source is becoming you
know coming on the scene so the Netscape
wants to make a standard so that you
know anyway and and jump subject I mean
we're not going to talk about JavaScript
history because I talked about that for
you know several times and also as you
know Java you know also money-hungry
you know Java is like hey one time it's
oh this is open source at one time it's
this is a trap you know richard stallman
says JavaScript Java is a trap
now now then you know after after some
Microsoft eventually released it as like
some sort of true open source then
Richard Stallman says Oh Java is now
that he endorsed it now then Microsoft's
got sold to Oracle why because money you
know otherwise you know you wouldn't be
so you said you know you sell when you
are failed when you failed but yet you
still of course there's still money to
get by selling your company so they saw
to Oracle and then then Oracle you know
Oracle is another you know big money
greedy company so they they did
something then they screwed up you know
so now it's make Java Scooby is no
longer open source it's like borderline
you know yeah like it becomes no longer
that doesn't you know the many depending
on who you ask
then there is Google of course greedy
Google you know they developed their
Android phone based on JavaScript
Android OS why because because I'm well
that's history ad yeah well because
originally because you know the Google
founders he know Java Java the language
you know that's how he learned at
Stanford University so Java you know so
and then Google starts to you know use
Java for Android and that's how Java
becomes popular you know Java wasn't it
was about to die
Google saved it twice the first time is
around 2001 when Google decided you know
they are going to use Java for their
cooperation coding
Java is their main language then around
2000 let's say 2008 also you know when
Android came up Google decided you know
we're gonna Java Java the language is
the language for the Android operating
system and so Google actually saved Java
twice
that's why Java is still today the most
popular language by the way Google also
made Python popular twice the first time
is 2010 when Google decided you know
Java is the main language while Python
is their main scripting language back
then the other choice is Perl you don't
have much choices then around 2000
around then around 2010 let's say Oh
2011 Google again made Python popular by
they decided because AI became you know
popular the data mining the you know the
AI you know the artificial intelligence
so Google decided they are going to you
know Python is their main language for
interfacing with you know machine
learning stuff by the way that be of my
thing
in learning code is typically written in
C or C++ I'm pretty sure I think yeah
not not in Python Python is usually
almost used you know use just as an
interface so anyway I digressed a lot so
we were talking about we were talking
about how how these standards or you
know languages specs they came to be you
know so I was saying you know they the
major reason the major drive is
corporations and money greed you know
fighting there's a lot you know serious
infighting like lost you you know
million dollar loss you if you did
something I don't like
you know I'm Apple for example if
Microsoft you did something I don't like
I see you for million dollars because
this this is critical money is talking
and Microsoft did something you know
then Linux try to do something Microsoft
doesn't look like you know the issue
similarly fold you know some
Microsystems local Google Apple you know
they you know this is kind of like
common you know typical happenings so
because of these that's how programming
languages get created and programming
you know technology get created because
of these now of course there are a lot
academics they also create you know some
design languages for example scheme Lisp
for example the racket today is known as
racket and many others but typically
they they don't survive okay they don't
they don't survive it is the big giant
greedy corporations they are things
survive for many reasons you know one of
the reasons because the cops has money
you know agreed is based on it you know
they they make money everyone make if
everyone has squid everyone you know
needs to survive you know like money is
a drive food is a drive the comfort you
know living is a try for everyone so you
know sometimes you have got these
academics they design things
usually they don't sell you they don't
they don't become popular they die out
because you know for many social reasons
one because you know because you know
this billion-dollar corporations they
have far more resources to market their
thing then you are little you know one
guys think that's one reason the other
reason is that these academic things
typically at least in America they are
like they are began by this open source
kind supposedly kind people they are not
greedy okay and in some cases you know
they you know they like open source of
free software so they are based on
communism ideology so what so what is
the end result nobody gives a you
know people just use your stuff four
three three software three means
everyone can download it you know no pay
that's what it means practically so you
don't you don't grow you know like Emacs
you know you mag list you you don't have
support you nobody cares about you but
but you based on those the ideology of
you know more oh you know some kind of
moral ethical oh we are ethical so you
trying to survive or spread your
software based on that and the reality
is nobody gives a so it's so
typically the academics stuff they don't
they don't survive I don't mean just
that they don't yeah they don't survive
because you may not know because right
now or everything you know like they're
let's say there are hundred things you
know about programming on hundred items
languages photos whatever
suppose you know one hundred of them
chances are 98 of them is all from
corporations maybe two from academia
okay big why but actually in fact they
are a lot from academia but they all
died out because you never heard of
that's the thing I want to say you never
heard about them because you know they
don't you you know because that's the
thing about you know
popularity you don't even you don't know
they their existence you know unless you
like to take the time to research you
know history oh you know what what
happens so anyway I digress a lot so
back to so I we were talking about the
SPECT how they got written how they
becomes standard so dom SVG so so how
they became standard okay and the other
thing so why are we talking about SVG I
mean what's the problem with the Elise
drawing Lisp
let me show you okay but first of all
what I want to say is that it it's just
extremely bad like when you code
you know DOM and web stuff on line here
just you know sometimes you look at the
spec you know what what you know what
the they doing this you know it's
strange you know or that anyway okay
that's digression that's about that now
let's talk about the SVG why does it
what is the problem actually okay so let
me read the questions the neo says
people that know people that know
trigonometry are probably going nuts
right now because they are highly strong
crowd so okay so he says is that a
wordplay on the strong like a like a
string like you like you using strains
going around like measuring you know
stuff so anyway let's talk about I think
I rambled quite a bit today so 20 23
minutes we talk about let's talk about
let me discuss why javascript SVG suits
I mean let me discuss what is the
problem with the SVG okay so so you want
to draw an arc of a circle let's say a
quarter of an arc of a circle okay you
want to draw a quarter of an arc of a
circle kind of like that
okay so so we have you know kind of like
that and you you cannot do that you
cannot say you know circle centered and
radius then you know how much you want
to draw no you have to do what you have
to do is you have to use these path
elements let me show you okay
SVG path element now path element you
can see is this you say path then you
give it a bunch of D you know M L like M
followed by two numbers al followed by
two numbers then there are other
commands M there's a there's others but
anyway so this syntax is rather fairly
complicated okay let me explain
so m m like mountain m followed by two
numbers that means move the pen to you
know those two numbers coordinate then L
means draw a line to that point you know
from the previous point so M is move the
pen to L is draw a line - okay so that
is the syntax of the path element which
is fairly complex then so besides ma
and our this M followed by two numbers
and alphabets numbers those are called
commands you know technically the jargon
for to describe those those are code
commands the path is a element you know
HTML element so then you have the D
attribute t4 draw I guess so the path
element has a D attribute then the value
of the D attribute is a string then you
have this M number L number stuff you
know that's how you create a path
now now the path element is very complex
because then because you can actually
draw curves like elliptical arcs or
quadratic Bezier curves or cubic splines
cubic Bezier curves you know it gets
very complicated but however they are
all using the path elements you know
path T equals students named extreme'
you know we have M L we have Q we have a
we have H you know very complicated but
back to the topic how do you draw an
ellipse so the way you draw an ellipse
is by using the path element for example
we are drawing have a release here so
what you do is this so there is one of
the command is a followed by one two
three four five six seven seven numbers
that's how you specify a lisp inside the
path element so it's you know it's
fairly complicated so good morning good
morning
che Jung do Jeon deal I thought it's a
Emacs show yeah normally we talk about
Emacs but today we're gonna you know
today's topic is the JavaScript and math
symbols so so if you have a Emacs
question you can post it okay I'm like
maybe I'll answer it at the end but
otherwise I'll talk about it you know
next day's topic so anyway so to draw a
lisp you have to use the path element
and it's very complicated you have you
you have to type capital a followed by
seven numbers now what are the seven
numbers they are rx ry those are major
in minor axis
then rotate is the number how much you
want to rotate it is then large arc flag
and sweep flag those are you know either
102 a very complex then the last two
numbers is XY where the list ends so I'm
not going to explain these seven numbers
what they mean but you can understand
it's very common you can understand you
can see that they are not the typical
you know the least you understand so so
you have this you know I'm not going to
explain you know you can check out my
website here and read about it I
explained in detail so here is a also an
interactive thing you can you can show
you see it's very very complex it's so
how cool what I want to do and this is
very common okay you want to draw a
quarter of a circle so so how do you do
that it turns out it's just you take you
hours and paste to figure it out you
know you can you cannot draw an arc of a
circle like a pie chart you cannot draw
it so that is the problem so I spend
days you know to try to find out and
eventually that's how I wrote this
application you can see finally I
succeeded you know I understand the full
thing and I know how to draw it and by
the way this is just a path element just
like you know the trick is you know
figuring out what numbers you know it
should be you see the way these seven
numbers work works is that they are
based on let me tell you what they they
are you know they are based on it's
complicated let me show you what no more
you list means okay so normally we have
a release like piece okay let's say like
that
and normally you know an Elise in a
standard position like x-axis y-axis you
have this shape and from here to here
you know it's called X the major axis
okay the horizontal axis the x axis is
the the length from here to here is the
major axis and from up and down is the
minor axis so you can for example you
can adjust you can you can get a circle
you know you can for example then you
can get you know different shapes of
elese when the major axis and minor axis
are equal in size then you get a circle
so to specify a Alysse normally all you
have to do is you specify the center you
specify the major axis the length and
minor axis then you specify which angle
you want to begin to draw it you know at
what point you want to begin to draw it
then how much of a sweep you want okay
then finally you say you rotate the
whole thing you know you you want to say
how much rotation you want the whole
thing so you have how many parameters 1
2 3 4 5 6 7 7 parameters this is a
intuitive way to understand Elise to
specify a list in fact this is the
standard way to you know to describe and
you list in mathematics you know when
you do algebra when you do an analytic
geometry which is precalculus or when
you learn calculus you know you know you
you study you know you understand this
but in the SVG spec remember its path
followed by seven numbers these numbers
are not nothing like what we had in
these seven numbers okay the the way
they specify it is that they specify
list by a starting point
you know the point thus it is begin and
the end point then you specify major and
minor axis then you specify rotate which
is the final rotation then you specify
these two pooling numbers like it's you
know it's very difficult to explain
actually so so so you can see here this
is how they specify it is you know so
normally we specify it is by giving you
a center once you have a center
everything is easy to understand but in
the SVG way you don't have a center you
know you have started and then then you
have this arc you know you have to give
a pooling you know large arc flag sweep
sweep flag to determine which party that
you know and I've never you know I
studied math you know I'm a math fan for
20 years I never seen this thing but
then when you go to the SVG spec let me
show you
I talked about this before they like
this is a SVG version one SPECT you
actually you can go to SVG version two
SPECT SVG spec right now it's version 2
version 1.1 is like from 2001 also but
anyway but SVG's version 2 is not
popular yet you know meaning that most
browsers do not implement it so let's go
so we go to SVG spec version 2 and you
can see let's go to Elysee you know
these specs are so you go to the path
element
you go to the path element and one of
the commanding path element is the is
the elliptical arc so you can see you
can read you know here there is
extremely complicated parameters nobody
you understand it you know you can spend
you know I you know I challenge use try
to a hang back Daniel I challenge you to
code this Elise you know try to draw a
quarter arc of a circle well anyway the
so they have a implementation note here
they'd here they explain how do you
convert Elise from the center based
parameterization to the the way SVG
defines it
it's all crap you know they don't like
don't believe what they say here like
like they have a article here they have
a article here somewhere like notes they
tell you like they try to define they
try to explain you know for example they
have a notes here annotation it's SVG to
requirement make it simpler to draw an
arc draw arcs in SVG path syntax you see
the you know they have these notes
because it's a problem pie chart is very
common but few people can understand it
so they have a note here but however is
not you know they they just have a note
to themselves it's not anywhere in the
spec you co cannot do it you know
there's no easy way except you write a
function to you know translate those
parameters so they say so the SVG spec
says you know have no this is so you
know it's stupid but also there's some
where they say that you know somewhere
they say that the reason they did it
that way is because it's more consistent
with lie with their path syntax I don't
think that's a valid reason I think I
think lots of these documentation you
know when you read specification
standard specifications lots of it is
crap is garbage the writing style the
just almost about everything is garbage
and actually the SVG 2 standard came
from are written by one of the author
which is a woman who described her let
me show you which which who it is
editor's Emilia Emilia Bellamy Rhodes
okay
supposedly she's an invited expert as a
credit on the SVG spec so she wrote a
blog
that details how she got into the SVG
you know how she became involved and if
you read it it's kind of a sad story
it basically is like SVG the way SVG 2
is created is not anything about you
know it's it's not like anything that
makes sense it's like nobody cares about
SVG no browser implemented you know like
nobody then tried they try to do it you
know from this country beautiful Ike
typically not paid you know then they
just created other blue like they don't
have accepted expertise for example
Amelia you know she's not a
mathematician she's not experienced in
I'm not sure she even has you know
graphics programming experience but
anyway she but she is good because she
study you know if you read blog she's
good she's you know she learned studied
the full details of SVG so she became an
expert you know and she got invite
invited and they just try to do things
like other blue so it's nothing like you
know one would think that it's you know
these standards are created by experts
you know so this is my opinion that most
of the these specs are just scrapped
garbage okay so that's about let's see
six people watching good so any comments
opinions posted okay the more opinions
in comments the better I can you know I
talked to the about the topic but anyway
so so we just explained we have just
explained
I suppose we you know we have a basic
tutorial of SVG we explain the path
element we explained why it is so
difficult to create and pie chart in SVG
and I also gave my appeal
about how standard Specht are you know
typically just pure crap
they are nothing you know don't like you
know these standards like typically
program especially the Linux you need
people days they always say oh follow
standard follow standard you know the
standard 10 you know usually it's just
crap you know it's not good and also
standards although they are not
corporations the standards bodies such
as w3 they are typically backed by money
like typically they are nonprofit
organizations but they are driven by
profit that's usually the case
so clearly Craver says just got here no
opinions yet great okay great so that's
about the topic about this SVG and Elise
yeah that's that concludes that this
topic now let's go to the next topic
which is which is the fun part kind of
so math symbols math symbols as function
names in Python JavaScript Java okay let
me show you the that code for the Elise
so let's go to my JavaScript blog let's
go to the Elise Park so this is the page
this it has JavaScript turned off but
let's look at the JavaScript code so
here is the JavaScript code it's
magnified and you can see so you define
a you know this is the JavaScript code
I'm showing you just you know for fun
this will lead up to the use of UC math
symbols in code such as that you know
Delta P and we have you know Delta V and
theta and stuff pi you can see PI here
okay so this is JavaScript you know
these are convenient you define cosine
equals through math math Darko's i saves
typing this side and now you can define
pi you know by the Greek letter pi for
math dot pi so that's very convenient
then you define the matrix this is the
matrix function to multiply a vector
which is essential when you do any kind
of computer graphics you know computer
graphics so you need to so you have a
matrix function then you have rotation
matrix
then you have vector addition
you know vector a B C D equals to 8 plus
C plus P plus D you know things like
that vector addition then you define the
U this function here so anyway I'm
showing this just to show the code for
fun so it's it's about hundred lines of
code so that's that and then we are back
to the we are back to the math symbols
function names in Python Java JavaScript
and Haskell and Emacs Lisp and other
languages okay so so this is interesting
because you know if you look at the
release code you know for this code you
can see we have used the symbol this
symbol is convenient because you know
actually it matters because then when
you have lots of math expressions symbol
condenses the whole thing for example if
the whole vector ad can be just one
symbol let's say if I replace it by let
me show you so vector ad is a function
now let's just replace it by of symbol
let's say circle plus okay reverse
replace replace you see now it's simple
now if the matrix x we also replay
by a single symbol let's say circle
circle times okay okay so you know that
makes the thing much simpler and and
similar we can do that for that you know
because when you when you read math you
see you know you see a bunch of you know
symbols if you try to expand those two
words you know it's gonna be unreadable
so anyway so so that is why it is
important for languages to support
symbols as variable names so we have a
PI here so we look at so we want to be
able to use pi or alpha gamma you know
beta beta theta for variable names very
convenient especially when you do sine
cosine trigonometry linear algebra for
computer graphics you need lots of
angles and goals are usually represented
by sine cosine you know by alpha beta
theta Greek Greek letters you know when
you see a Greek letter
you know it's Radian you know it should
be on angle not not degree for example
so that's convenient
the other thing communion is that you
want to be able to use a symbol as part
of the function name then the other
thing is that you want to be using
operator meaning that for example vector
ad for example let's say magnify so
vector ad instead of a vector ad for
example we are going to vector add two
vectors
one two okay three four this should give
us this should return one plus three is
four 2 plus 1 3 2 plus 1 plus 2 is 4 2
plus 4 is 6 this should give us 4 and 6
so instead of writing like that we could
use if we could use just that you know
this is much simpler or some even that
let's remove the ok for example instead
of that we if we can write that is
simpler even better is is that if we can
define an operator so the whole thing
will be written like that you know like
this
symbol with Unicode name with math
symbol okay normal okay so this is so
named with math symbol that's good
the best is to define to be able the
programming language allows you allows
you to define operators and if it can
use unicode's math symbols that's the
best so that's what we want so i
surveyed you know different languages
you look at you know Segal Cola and Java
JavaScript Python Perl Ruby ok Mahaska
eMac B's Judea Mathematica so so here is
the result so let me tell you what
what's going on typically summarize let
me summarize
you know what's going on first of all C
is the worst C supports none of these
except if you do you know if you use
special compilers or special extensions
the standard C or you know the classic C
does not support any of these now in
most other languages for example goal
and Java JavaScript Python and Perl you
can have unicode as a variable or
function name so you can have you can
have these however there is an exception
for example you can have alpha
okay there's a one-issue you can you can
use a Unicode character except one
condition is that that Unicode character
must be a letter
you know Unicode each character is a
property some problem some characters
are considered a letter for example
alpha beta
you know Greek letters let's look at you
know most of these languages Chinese
characters Japanese characters Korean
characters riebeck you know Ethiopia
Indian Bengal I or whatever those
characters are considered letters okay
those are letter characters I mean each
Unicode character has a property so
these are considered letters however
some other characters such as such as
you know dim bats stars you know these
these are not letters so you cannot use
these symbols as a you know as a
character in your variable function name
you cannot use stars you cannot use
crosses you cannot use for example emoji
because they are not letters the and you
can the most devastating is that you
cannot use any of the math symbols as
function names as you know anywhere in
your function or variable name because
these math symbols they are not letters
you know they are not classified by
Unicode as letters they are classified
as symbols so all these you know
operators you know you cannot use so
that means you cannot use this you
cannot you know do these in in most
languages so that you know so that is
you know includes Co Java JavaScript
Python Perl Ruby you know they all allow
Unicode in here in
in names but but only letter characters
then at the next level you have Ruby
which allows math symbol in names and
you have eMac this Judea in Mathematica
they allow okay so that's better
so in Mathematica or Ruby this is
allowed you know this is allowed now
let's go to the next step the next step
is does the language allow you to define
operators most languages know except
Python and I don't know about Ruby
so anyway Python or camel has cow Julia
Mathematica allow you to define your own
operators so that means they can you
know you can define for example you can
do this define your own operators using
SC just for example how long should be
here for example let's say first plus
first okay oh you can say V plus okay so
you know we plus stand for vector plus
vector addition so you can define this
you know so Ruby so so Python can do
that or camera can do that Haskell can
do that you know you can define your own
operators this is better but however
there's another condition that is do
they allow Unicode symbols as operators
that's the next level you know and and
at that level only Judea as far as I
know Julia and Mathematica allows that
so that's that's about that that's
interesting about so so why you want
this you know the because when you are
you know most programmers are industrial
programmers when you go hack hacker news
or or reddit the masked vast majority of
things you see people talk about they
are industrial programming they are you
know vast majority most people are they
are not math oriented or scientific
programming you know industrial program
is for example game programming games
networking programming networking
protocols you know internet programming
AI programming you know machine learning
AI whatever Google is doing Facebook
they are all industrial programming vast
majority you know programming web
browsers programming applications
programming Linux kernel operating
system drivers and web dev you know and
web server they are all industrial
programming so but they are not
scientific programming scientific
programming support mean
for example machine learning has a lot
of scientific programming involved and
actually gaming you know the algorithms
using gaming linear algebra computer
graphics and many research in physics
and academia you know in by used by NASA
for example NASA sending people to space
and you know you know the companies that
sends rockets and stuff anyway so we so
the point is when you do mathematical
programming this becomes rather critical
because let me show you some math stuff
because then that's that there be it for
today because when you do math
programming let's see syntax OOP let's
show you some you know math programming
so you see this is this is math code
this is this is creating a find that
angle between vectors so in in
mathematical syntax you can do it this
way like this you know it's so actually
two-dimensional but you can also write
it this way you know if you wanted to be
one-dimensional only know that you can
have pie here then you can also do it
this way this is the least readable this
is all purely nested brackets and this
is similar to Lisp this this code can be
converted to Lisp
so in Lisp syntax it looks like this so
when you have lots of let me just show
you an example let's say you know three
first let's say in traditional notation
three plus four times five you know
raise to 6 let's say how you do that in
this it's a problem you know so in this
you're gonna do is you're gonna direct
first three four then times
okay wait times first before then or
power then power wait first three four
times five then power oh wait wait so
this is like that five six
so we have here
normal math notation then we have the
list notation you can you can tell you
know which one is easier to read you
know in math let's say math you can see
lots of you know and let me show you
some typical math formula let's see go
let's go to images you know yeah so we
got a bunch of math formulas you know
now this very simple expression in this
it becomes that like that
how you gonna do any so let me show you
another it's unreadable already you know
this is unreadable this simple
expression in this syntax is unreadable
let me show you another no more no more
functional in programming languages okay
then we have so we're gonna write first
plus three four times
power five six so this is how you write
in normal programming languages now you
might object you know wait plus is not
like that times it's not like that but
you know we are we are making examples
because when you when you do math for
example these expressions are not just
plus and minus for example the numbers
are not numbers those you know when you
when you get for example they may be
vectors they may be vectors for example
this this five six three four they are
vectors they are not numbers so you
cannot just write you know first three
four in programming languages you know
like like our JavaScript the example
when we try to write you Lisp function
so this is how it looks like in normal
foreign languages it's not readable you
know if you simplify it it might be
looks like that you know it's not
readable so you need infix notation that
so but why do we need unicode because
when you are doing vectors for example
if these three four five six are vector
R vectors so you are not doing no more
numbers so you need you you might want
to have a special operators to you know
so you can see oh this is motor proc you
know multiplying vectors so you know
adding vectors okay or complex numbers
okay that's it for today that's the two
topics we want to cover that's it so
thank you for watching any questions and
comments hi hi who can sue okay
oh can see - where you from who can see
- I see you got a goal and mascot as
your paw file so that so that's it for
today I'm going to have I guess I'm
going to get dinner so today we talked
about the we talked about the drawing a
lisp in JavaScript and SVG technology
then we talked about a short tutorial on
how you actually do it a short short
tutorial on SVG then we talked about the
complexity of standards what how they
form you know where they came from the
standard standard organizations and
standard bodies specifications then we
talked about the use of math symbols as
function a you know math symbol in
function names in different programming
languages why we want that what is the
issue and a survey of which language
supports what you know and yeah that's
that's what we talked about today
and lastly yeah as part of the history
explanation we we explained why is it
necessary when you do scientific
programming why is it why is it
extremely convenient to have to be able
to define operators and to be able to
use math symbols
okay who can who can sue who can who who
can choose sales hope you can do some
list tutorial in the future yeah I can
do Emacs Lisp
yes I did one a few months ago I think
you can find it if you search for have
using that one so if you go to my
YouTube you know you'll find a I did one
tutorial about teaching eMac lease you
know from the beginning so I think I'll
do another one yeah should do another
one soon okay that's it thank you guys
for watching so you know if you like my
stuff
support me okay go to patreon you know
put five dollars you know a month or buy
my JavaScript tutorial yeah my
JavaScript tutorial is the JavaScript
in-depth you can learn everything about
it you know JavaScript in-depth yeah
okay thank you guys I have a good day
bye