good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today is 2020
June 8th 6 o clock 6:20 p.m. San
Francisco time I wasn't prepared so
everything is [ __ ] up so hold on a
second I mean just the video I hope oh
yes doesn't crash
Evy has often more functions so now
finally I'm streaming right I'm
streaming alive and okay so I forgot
what what what I was saying
so yeah I'm going to show you today's
background image
today's background image is by this guy
he's comics artist and his comics is
called the Perry Bible Fellowship now
his comics he draws a very dark stuff
the darkness of humanity via his comics
you know you look at his comics you look
at the drawing style you thought it's
funny you know it's comics comics is
mostly supposed to be funny but his his
is very different unusual and and that
is particularly you know that is his
theme that is his title and he's the the
guy's name is Nicholas Coolridge okay so
that is today's background you can look
you can look at his website so I copied
some of his comics to my website in
about ten years ago 2050 2005 I actually
emailed him and asked him for permission
you know I don't grab you know I usually
ask them for permission to put them on
my website so he said okay so I had a
few then I added six three more later on
anyway so this is 2005 and he has a book
you can go to his website
okay PBF comics calm very dark okay he
said he's got a book you buy it on
Amazon you guys you guys buy it the
Perry Bible Fellowship the darkness of
humanity that is his thing so that is
today's background so what are we going
to talk about darkness my old friend so
you know dark black and white black and
white is the most fundamental color
because when it's night it's dark you
know it's black pitch black before the
modern society you don't have lights you
have candles but you go outside it's
pitch pitch black you can actually see
the stars today you cannot see the stars
for many of you guys Millennials who
lives in a city you've never seen the
sky before and actually that applies to
Chinese people in China because of the
air pollution the the worst air
pollution in a world is China especially
in a northern area Beijing and you know
you know the day so over there the the
the sky is is clouded it's it's not
crowd its you know it's a acid or
whatever you cannot see the sky so when
Chinese people you know sometimes I've
met Chinese people friends you know
online friends who came here to USA and
they all say oh my god I can see the
skies you know stars in California you
know California Americans you know
although we teach about air pollution
all the time oh you know carbon Deoxys
dioxide die dioxide or you know the
carbon emission from cars and smog you
know smog we complain about that all the
time but it's actually actually in
California in Mountain View at least
where I live it's very good you know the
sky is clear you can you I go outside at
night after a few hours I can see the
sky clearly and when you when it's pitch
pitch black you can also see the Milky
Way
now how many of you have seen Milky Way
raise your hand okay when I was a
college student a student 20 years ago
in 1992 I took a astronomy class you
know I took two astronomy classes one is
a solar system the solar system about
our you know Earth Venus Mars you know
Pluto
you know the planets solar system then
there's another astronomy class called
interstellar astronomy
I forgot what's the name but anyway it's
about the universe you know outside the
solar system so they divide astronomy
the beginning of beginner class into two
sections solar system and outside so the
the professor this is full year college
right which is actually 20 minutes drive
down here very beautiful it's on top of
a mountain here for hero college so this
is 1992 and the professor actually asked
you know how many people have seen Milky
Way so I I actually raised my hand but
actually I by mistake because I have not
seen Milky Way before but one day I went
to a California desert you know let me
show you California desert Google Maps
okay let's go to Google Maps let's go to
Bing Maps for a change
okay Microsoft
so what is today's topic guys what do
you guys want to see you want to hear I
talk you listen you watch you enjoy the
show so we have here California so let
me show you so this is where if this is
Silicon Valley by the way for those of
you an American ok here is Silicon
Valley right here so this is San
Francisco ok let me show you the big
picture now you would always need to
look at things from you know to see the
big picture otherwise you don't you
don't see you only see trees you don't
see the forest ok like the Linux and
Emacs and you know idiots
so here's San Francisco and you can see
this is USA right so he's California on
the left the west coast the West Coast
the west coast
that's what they call it and on the
right side New York that's East Coast
cost so in California here
and you have two big cities San
Francisco the home of the hippies
okay that's San Francisco then you have
Los Angeles down there Los Angeles Jesus
is the Hollywood okay and but you look
at here over here Death Valley
you see Death Valley Death Valley
now that that is a giant desert okay
Death Valley so you drive from San
Francisco you can drive over there
basically when you drive inland you know
the the heartland of USA there are those
are not big cities so when you drive to
the rural places you at night there's no
streetlights so he it's pitch black so
you can actually look at the sky and you
see thousands of stars and you can see
Milky Way by the way so you guys know
what's a milky way okay so so now we're
gonna have a little sauce a true corner
I'm gonna explain to you guys what is
Milky Way
okay what what questions do you have
what questions do you guys have you guys
don't have any questions actually
actually okay Milky Way okay Milky Way
oh [ __ ]
thank Google type okay questions a
interaction that's what stream live
stream is for interactivity you know so
then you have you talk and we get lively
live you know we get colorful so you
don't talk we don't get colorful Milky
Way
let me tell you let me just tell you
what is Milky Way so we so we have the
solar system AG yeah he's gonna take a
lot of time to explain that you know
Milky Way solar system so we have
basically basically we have a Sun a
giant fireball a Sun then we have earth
which is rotating around the Sun then
you have other planets rotating around
the set now the Sun you call it a star
okay a star is something that close when
you see stars at night those are or like
Sun you know they basically a fireball a
huge giant fireball they it glows that's
why they shine Trinko the reason they
twinkle is because they don't actually
drink oh it's because of the the
inference and so on okay so anyway the
Sun is a giant fireball then you have
planets you know we have about eight or
nine planets so you know revolving
around the Sun and the earth is about is
the third or fourth you know you know
you look at Wikipedia or tell you
everything about it solar system solar
system the Sun you know the Milky Way
there it is a picture of Milky Way so
anyway the solar system so so the Sun
then we have night planets revolving
around the earth okay then we then
that's we call that solar system
you know Solar means Sun house okay then
so that's a solar system but actually it
turns out you have lots of that you know
hundreds thousands tens of thousands
millions you have millions of other
solar systems just like similar to ours
you know you have a star in the scene
center then you have planets revolving
around it so that's other solar systems
planet system you don't go a solar
system oh you know our planet system is
called solar system then you have a
similar so it turns out you know all
these sponge planets systems they they
they form clusters
you know they it's like they they are
gathered around each other for most
forms a group they are positioned
together like nearby each other like a
neighborhood like a town you know then
then there's empty space okay so it
turns out it just happens like that so
lots of planetary systems
you know gather around so when these
whole bunch of planetary systems you
know are together near each other this
whole thing is called a galaxy okay so
here's a galaxy okay so I'm going to so
this is such a true corner astronomy 101
you know I explained this you know
because I'm getting old
you know I'm 50 something so this like
you know I learned these twenty years
ago thirty thirty years ago and but
actually you know a lot of people don't
know you know lots of including I'm
guessing including lots of you
programmers who is watching my show
we are we
what's going on with my mouse okay auto
click I want to turn auto quick
did chrome just froze
okay so we are back here I mean let me
turn this off
stop paying
save resources fruit of the once and
future planet yeah Pluto is
controversial controversy
you know Pluto is considered a planet or
not a planet okay so let me get back to
the okay
speaking of Pluto I have an article on
that - shut up so wait wait what are we
doing so we want to go to sorry Unicode
okay Unicode we have ancient symbols for
the planets
you want to go to let me show you
culture money circle okay vehicles
things tech office user interface clock
music flags sex stars cross games shapes
and what weird where is the planetary
system culture keyboard common
punctuation money circle arrows
wait where's the planets astrology there
it is astrology the Asian science of
astronomy okay the girls love it oh you
know you look at girls magazines this
astrology every day you know and and so
so Asian symbols of the planets so you
can see we have mercury we have Venus we
have earth we have a giant [ __ ] and this
is called Mars and we have Jupiter we
have Saturn Jupiter power Sailor Moon
speaking of Sailor Moon we need to show
another article
of course you need to go to some music
Sailor Moon
and I have pictures human animals in
their songs
indeed search for
there we have Sailor Moon here is Sailor
Moon which is our moon now you know a
movie say it's kind of a rock revolving
around the planet no so I was saying you
know these things about basic astronomy
actually a lot of people don't know
including the programmers you know you
look at programming programmers the
linux people the Emacs people you know
the you know whatever this has scar
people they're talking about programming
hotshot there they are like Hot Shots
every day they tell you what to do
programming idioms in styles [ __ ] but
actually many of them don't know a thing
about astronomy so basic astronomy let
me get back to the basic astronomy so we
have planets systems or a bunch of
planets it's called a planet system then
we have lots of planet systems they they
are together around each other now that
collection is called a galaxy okay
there it is Wikipedia Arco as a galaxy
so it's a huge huge collection of planet
systems each each system has one or more
sense ok fireball so we have a galaxy
and it turns out galaxies you know we
have more than one galaxy so there are
so many there are thousands millions of
them it turns out galaxies also are like
connected together like they are near
each other so you have one galaxy here
one galaxy there and another they are
all near each other so galaxy turns out
is also crusted clustered around each
other ok so that's about that's about my
reach
ok that's that's what I'm going to say
about astronomy that that is all so our
galaxy the the galaxy we are in you know
the solar system you know a galaxy is a
collection of Planner planetary systems
for example you look at this picture you
know it's a bunch of planetary systems
and one of them is our own solar system
so the galaxy we are in that is called
Milky Way
ok now you understand and you can
actually see it you know if you go to
some rural place where where there is no
streetlight then you you look at the sky
you know clear sky then you can see this
kind of thing this kind of a stripe
so that is a milky way why do we why do
you see it why does it looks like you
know like a river in fact the Milky Way
in Chinese we call it silver river
silver river
you know it it looks like a river so in
in America you know you call it Milky
Way it's like white you know a strip of
thing why is it a strip because now
remember a galaxy
now remember a galaxy what's going on
okay krummy stuck everything is stuck
am i doing okay
so no comments so what why does milky
way the question is why does Milky Way
looks like a strip well because you see
our galaxy it turns out where many
planet are you know when you look at the
solar system the planets revolve around
the Sun and it turns out they basically
overlying a plane okay so you know the
here's Earth here's Venus here's mercury
and here's Saturn Jupiter it turns out
they they all more or less slicing a
plane why is that because gravity I
guess that's like I guess it turns out
that's how gravity works that way I
don't know yeah I'm pretty sure but I
don't know exactly okay so it turns out
that way and also remember many
planetary systems are collected together
to form a galaxy and it turns out the
entire galaxy
overall also has also has a flat shape
so they are almost all like a plane so
when you saw so this is so this is
galaxies so when you look at our Milky
Way
you know we uh it turns out we are
looking at the Milky Way from the side
so you know so that's why it becomes a
strip okay that's about astronomy
anything else
comments they might like sir going check
test type so Pluto you know Pluto was
once considered a planet but then as we
know more we started to have different
opinions many professional astronomers
they don't they no longer consider Pluto
as a planet because well mostly because
you know it does just does not satisfy
many of the characteristics of planet
such as such as what I don't know you
know you can read Wikipedia for the
details and here is a bit about politics
should I talk about that you know so so
he you know when we talk about the these
symbols for for planets for example vina
female you know the Venus is a female
sign he's also used as a female sign and
Mars is also a male psyche so you can
study the etymology of these symbols why
is Mars
you know represented by an arrow upward
arrow why is why is Venus represented by
this kind of you know a circle above
cross and also another question is why
is Venus also a female sign why is Mars
also a male side so you can trace the
reasons you know why is it that way and
we do find we do no have basic idea why
it is that way
yeah okay so the female sign originally
was used was a symbol for Venus it
didn't you know the female sign is used
later same thing for the male sign it
the first useful for female in the male
is by a boat on a boat honest Swedish
botanist you know he study planets his
name is Carl Linnaeus called Liana's
Carlene and Ling Ling and in in Al's
call him as something like that okay so
I guess this is bowing to you guys so
it's so anyway so he is the first one of
botanist who used Venus as female symbol
and masters male symbol and since then
that became a standard but if we go back
then why is the female I mean why is
Venus sign looks like that I mean of
course it may be seedy I mean the sign
needs to have some shape this this is I
mean we aren't there may not be a
logical reason but however there is also
but usually there's a reason like
inevitably there's always a reason why
it became that way so why is the female
symbol this way it likely because
because Venus okay so I did some
research on these so you can find you
know old Ovation books
so the first association of Venus with
this symbol
apparently appears to be this this book
okay
the arrangement of the symbols of the
planets by motor 1934 yeah so it's not
is it's pretty recent anyway I don't
know the details
yeah so I don't think we know exactly
why but anyway I did I did research you
know why I do the research why did I'd
started to do this because when you talk
about let me let me give you a simple
reason why okay so it began with this
book as far as I know 1934 you know it
drew these pictures to represent the
gods
you know Venus Mars or those or these
planets they are named after Greek
mythology gods gods and goddesses then
eventually they become simplified by a
symbol
I'm trying to find yeah that's that's
essentially that's that's as far as we
know okay you can look up Wikipedia by
the way Wikipedia we are not tell you
much more than I just did because when I
did this research a few years ago
Wikipedia doesn't say much you know I I
had just had to spend you know a few you
know hours a few days to to find this
stuff but why am I looking into them
it's because the social justice scan you
know I used to have comment system on my
website like you can go down to the
bottom and you can start to comment on
it you know type what do you think on
this page so I I have a Unicode you know
this is my unicode page and I have a
page about sex symbols let me show you
why do I have a Unicode page because I
love symbols symbology since I was like
young like 13 also like when when you
look at dictionaries I do remember in
you know in Chinese English dictionary
and also English English dictionaries
such as Merriam Webster's you you know
when you read a dictionary you thump
all the way to the back usually there
are appendix appendices or indexes so
for example there will have a appendix
page or section that lists all sort of
symbols they are not words the symbols
like you know section sex symbols or
chemistry symbols or other symbols so
you know many symbols you find today on
Unicode for example let me show you a
few
for example code stars cross okay cause
stars culture for example many of these
symbols are ancient like 3,000 years old
or more
for example this symbol costs of love
rain many of these costs and also let me
show you some of the some of the you you
are familiar with today
for example this snake sign you should
magnify okay these for example this
snake you know cat uses this this kind
of science you've seen in many medical
facilities you know in medicine
the this one's staff of Hermes you know
Holmes is the is the god of I don't
remember anyway so these many of these
symbols are Asian for example this one
ank that's from Egypt in Egyptian so why
are we talking about symbols yeah so I'm
interested in symbols when you look at
you know since I was King you you open a
dictionary there are appendices you know
the old dictionary not today maybe not
today but let's say in the 1990s you
open dictionaries in the back there are
appended appendices about all these
different symbols and also let me show
you let me show you a few okay very
interesting symbols common okay
punctuation yeah oh these are you'll
find them in the back of the dictionary
for example you are familiar with the
copyright sign you know the read the
registered trademark sign the trademark
sign and paragraph science section sign
and dagger double dagger things like
that and this flow heart very common
so I'm fascinated by them you know I
so I usually you know dictionary I look
at the appendices you know read about
them I mean I'm interested in symbols
and in and also today you have math
symbols okay math symbols they are
spectacular we show you some math
mathematics
now math symbols they are like written
by God edged in stone okay thou shalt
not you know so these these are math
symbols so you look at addiction so
that's why I mean you know so I'm
interested in symbols and also you know
so you have six symbols so I have this
page you know I write them out then you
know what happens so I started this page
about ten years ago yeah ten years ago
then today you have you know the social
justice people you know the the LGBTQ
lesbian gay orgy
P
what wait LGBTQ lesbian gay be bisexual
t transsexual q QE squared
you know they added Q and they also they
you also wanted to add a bunch of others
anyway so so that phenomenon you know
past you know let's say five years you
have this gender thing everyone is
talking about gender so when they so
people start to come and on my page all
sort of [ __ ] comments okay they are
telling me oh no you are wrong this is
this is not you know transgender you are
this is not threesome okay this is this
is transgender and everything is
transgender
this is transgender this is transgender
you know they come and you know they are
they are very they are phonetic very
extremely fanatical so so it's like all
my comments on this page people are
talking about this gender thing you know
they did they don't they don't
understand history they don't they care
about astronomy they don't care about
nothing all they care is about gender
this is trans gender transgender this
you are wrong oh this is you know you
you are you are nasty you are yeah
that's what they are saying these four
kids
so and and also feminism you know family
feminism is a bit early us began you
know in sixty so earlier thirty so you
know you have but what I'm talking about
is today's so-called third wave feminism
or today we have fourth fourth wave
feminism so they they want to talk about
the female sign like the origin of the
three male sign anyway so Z trunk crazy
you haven't seen you for a while how are
you doing so okay so maybe I'm thinking
it's change topic I'm okay I'm I kind of
rambled so much ramm boat for 30 minutes
about astrology astrology and Unicode in
the symbology and
so Z trunk crazy some say something
where is part
so let's see what we're gonna talk about
next and if nothing much you know I'm
gonna shut down maybe in five minutes
you know we don't have to it's like we
don't have to do one hour every day
so Z Tron crazy is fine
I'm fine to Z Tron crazy who is part and
part body is crazy why why is he not
joining this code we you will you join
this code robot is sleeping okay
good morning I'll cook okay that's about
that's about astronomy and stuff and see
what else so let me just copy my page
and end
okay so Sailor Moon Sailor Moon is quite
quite fascinating it's you know it's a
phenomenon in Japan and also they came
to America in starting in 1990s so you
have Sailor Mars Sailor Mars Sailor
Venus
Sailor Moon Sailor Jupiter sara mockery
you know they are girls they are
supposed to be teenage girls like
thirteen fourteen but they are very
highly sexual okay I'm getting into a
taboo topic you know the American taboo
the Americans Shepherd the trepidation
about
Ted oh you know the [ __ ] American
[ __ ] the white people I don't know if I
should talk about it you know but you
see that the thing is the interesting
thing is you know you are looking at it
right now Sailor Moon
extremely popular all over Japan and
also in America as well but but the
American they have problems they cannot
think clearly about these kind of things
they don't you know I can I can tell you
why because partly because of Christian
ality anyway I'm not sure anyway so you
look you look at Sailor Moon you know
they are supposed to be teenagers and
they are highly sexual and why is it you
know look at short short miniskirts and
and and you look at you know you look at
their show you know you look at their
transformation you know the
transformation to become powerful it's
incredibly City but also they make sense
because that you know young girls that's
what they want that's you know sexual
maturity you want to attract males for
the passing on you know to pass on to
further proliferation of human animals
without this you will not have human
animals so
you know young girls you know young
girls in Japan you know also in America
you can see young girls teenage girls
they they put midnight nail paint
Heidi's attractive you know they they
are crazy like the girls they could they
look at makeup tutorials they are like a
medium millions of them on YouTube
that's what they do
section sex sexual attraction okay
that's in that spy ology so anyway in
Japan you know you have set a movie and
you know girls watch it girls like it
but in America girls also watch it watch
it
but it becomes like you you you can only
watch it secret secret feel like
otherwise the people will laugh at you
you know a lot of people will make fun
of Sailor Moon American people the white
people anyway so I have collected you
know here so here is Sailor Moon
transformation you know you look at
it basically it's you know girls fantasy
it's like you know makeup you know you
actually hear hear them makeup you know
in the world makeup and also all that
kind of thing
it's it's fascinating to me but also the
the American you know the white people's
mentality about the it about this kind
of thing is also very very strange you
know American taboo you know about these
kind of thing is also very strange and
also very fascinating and precisely
because of these today we have these
social you know partly in part because
of these today we have these social
justice in all the focus on genders and
stuff anyway that's about ceremony and
and then then you have the Disney
Princesses okay that's about that I
think
Zeit from crazy says in germany it is
now 4 a.m. yes I know and she says I
like the short skirts on them because
the leg the legs look more long than
usual yes of course I like them too
that's what you know that's what
miniskirts are for it's you know that's
that it's the sole purpose of miniskirts
and in fact that's the purpose of skirts
skirts are for skirts women typically
women wear them because to show their
leg legs I mean let me explain so you
know it kind of person me you know so
for sexual attraction you have tits and
you have [ __ ] right those are sexual
organs they are sexual organs they by
design by evolution they attract males
because for those guys who are not
attracted to them they don't they don't
get to [ __ ] you know they don't they
don't have as much many children then
they die out so so that is why every may
not attract it to tits and [ __ ] you
know it's building you cannot you know
you cannot escape it yeah you can you
can become gay then you die you know you
don't have children then you die so
that's tits and and [ __ ] so those are
sexual organs but what about Lakes why
is it that lakes are you know super
attractive to males so I have been
puzzled about that and then
eventually I understand now I understand
why why because let me tell you okay but
let me also mention another thing before
I forget let me just type it intimacy
okay I talked about this one time before
bye
there's a book called intimate behavior
by zoologist Desmond Morris okay so I
highly recommend this book this book
looks at human sexuality from a
zoologist point of view so basically you
are studying human sexual behavior human
made made ship as if as if you are an
alien you know you are a scientist from
our space outer space you came to earth
you saw human animals you try to study
study them what they do why are they you
know how they procreate you know so this
book I highly recommend so I read that
in about in 2000 2005 or so anyway back
to the question about why his legs
you know women girls makes attractive
why very simple okay that you know
because I was thinking legs legs are not
a sexual organ what then why is it
attractive why you know well the the the
the the reason is very simple the reason
is because female in general their body
has less hair and male has more hair
especially on the lakes okay the lakes
is very apparent for female you can
easily tell which leg if you see a pair
of legs you can easily tell it's male or
female
because of these and nothing else just
only because of these legs you know
girl's legs becomes super attractive why
because they tell you you are looking at
a female okay that's all it is you are
you know you that's why lakes are
attractive it simply tells you you are
looking at male or female so it you know
it it's attractive to males not
necessary females because you know
that's also why women shave you know
their legs why do they shave it they
already have less hair because if they
share it then they want to emphasize you
know to make it more even more apparent
so that's excursion into sexuality
I like okay so Z Tron crazy says before
the stream I watched a makeup tutorial
okay anything else you know today okay
so speaking of makeup you know today we
have entered a new era yeah we could say
that the let's say in the Millennials
okay well
anyway at least the white countries have
entered a new era that is that is you
know part you know with lots of the
social justice warrior ideas you know
you know LGBTQ and trans you know
transgender and people began to have
less children you know they don't want
to make children didn't want yeah and
people actually have less sex you know
yeah and people watch home phone a lot
more not necessarily because phone
caused people to start making children
that you know that that may have
something to do it with it but anyway
the the reason seems to be complex
anyway today what I'm saying is that we
we could say that starting in 2010 we
have humanity have entered into a some
kind of new social era where people are
less prone to make children you know you
don't want to have children less than
this and also people are
you know remain single they don't get
married they don't get married many of
them don't get married
starting with Millennials Millennials
generation and they you know after you
know and also they have less children
and and they don't want children
and also many males you know the male
sperm count has gone down for some
reason we still don't understand that we
understand why people don't want
children in general because when once
you get educated you don't feel you know
getting you have to have children is
kind of a primitive urge you know anyway
so then so you have this phenomenon
phenomenon but also another phenomenon
is males becomes gay you know a lot you
know we have a lot of gays today and you
know aside from political issues you
know I don't like the social justice
people you know they talk about things
but for now we are not talking about
political issues we talk about people in
on earth in general so we do have a lot
more gays because we're in part because
scale is now openly upset acceptable in
in white countries in least and then but
not just scale we start to have a lot a
lot of transgenders or at least on the
news and male and female you know they
they want to try to make them the same
you know like it's not like before males
are in general masculine you know you
want to be a male and in fact women are
attracted to masculine guys you know
like guys you know with muscular and
very tough not not not some wimp
you know today like computer nerds
programmers okay they are wimp or
millennial generation this or that
so before you have very feminine you
know women and very masculine masculine
male but but today let's say since 2010
it's much less of that so so what I'm
saying is that I think we do you know
the society have entered some kind of
new era and this you know there are a
lot reasons for that but part of the
reason is because technology well the
primary reason for this change is
because technology technology changed
things in society
whenever society changes you know you
know has 200 2000 years whenever society
changes it's almost always always
because of Technology technology changes
Society ok I feel I feel lonely it's
like I'm doing a monologue no
interactivity
so how long have I been talking 15
minutes I can talk a few more I guess
yeah so I'm saying you know so society
as a whole human animals on this earth
have become somewhat wimpy hey good
morning George George we don't have a
topic do you have a topic I'm about to
end stream so anyway so yeah people on
earth we have entered this age where you
know you have less men real men and you
know women but you have this gender you
know transgender in gay stuff and what
what what do I want to say about that
it's um so on one hand of course I don't
like them because they this change has a
lot to do with the you know a certain
party political party elite people they
are pushing it they are using sex or
gender as a weapon you know they are
trying to get more power for themselves
that's that's part of the reason so I
don't like it
but despite that when we are the SJW -
ends yeah that's a good question so
politically speaking you know they are
very powerful today the leftist people
you know for example in USA they run all
the tech corporations Google Twitter
Facebook you know they control
communication your phone Android or
Apple including Apple you know they
control everything they monitor you they
know where you are
they have record of you everything so
they are very powerful and also
including all media corporations New
York Times CNN most you know vast
majority of them they are controls they
are controlled by the elite leftist
people and they are pushing the SJW
narrative you know every day is about
gender about you know male and female
there is no sexual there is no
biological difference you know they
actually say that they claim that there
is no biological difference you know
they claim lots of things and they also
they are actually criminals they they
they they censor they forbid any
publication if you disagree with them if
you are a buyout biologist you study
transgender you publish something that
disagree with them they ban you they
fire you they are doing that because I
you know looking into so anyway that's
you know that's the politics so the
question you know one of the question is
when we are they when we are this party
for that's a good question nobody knows
okay but I think that will fall sooner
or later okay I think because when you
are so bizarre when you are so remote
from reality you are going to crumble
eventually you know sooner or later you
know when you when you dare to claim
that you know that there is no no
biological difference between male and
female that's like very far from reality
you are going to come back sooner or
later just just like the you know the
Cultural Revolution in China you could
you know by force by you know political
power you can you can force it but not
for very very long so so the social
justice can I think they will go away
you know maybe five years maybe ten you
know they will go away and all these
gender talk they they'll go away like
they they will lose power okay that's
what I think that's on one hand about
politics on the other hand
you know non-political issue is that the
question is we are today's you know
wimpy men I mean let's really this way
we are we are males and female become as
before more masculine masculine and
feminine you know like today a lot you
know we have a large case and
transgender right people you know and
and millennial young men they are not
very masculine but the question is in
five or ten years let's say in ten years
we will we return to you know we have a
comeback of masculine you know the
definite sex on that I don't know for
sure and I don't know for sure because
because we have you know I think one
thing we have to understand is that
things happen that way because
technology technology made us made our
life and you know the living style very
different from let's say without
technology so if you don't have
technology males have to go out and walk
in a field very harsh very hard you know
you have to be masculine you have to you
have to fight you have to kill
woofs tiger you know you have to bring
food home and female has to has stay
home because they are physically weaker
than male they have less muscle mass
they have less bone density and so on so
female stay at home take care of the
babies
so this is with our technology but but
now we with technology we don't need
that so we kind of
you kind of lost the you know the need
for a very sharp characteristics
difference between male and female so
the question is but in 10 years in fact
in 10 or 20 years what will happen yeah
I don't know about that for sure
so so so in other words in other words
what I'm saying here is that I'm giving
some credit to the trans or gay movement
okay on my hand they are they rose up
because politics power struggle you know
I hate them I think they will go away
they will lose their power in ten years
or so but on the other hand it is also
true that as technology you know
advances we become more and more wimp
wimpy we kind of don't need to be male
and female anymore because soon in fact
today we can do if we want to we don't
need a pregnancy anymore we can have
like the matrix you know or artificial
womp and you don't actually today you
don't need even have to have sex anymore
you can have artificial you know you can
draw the sperm out
you know you can you know and inject it
to you know then take the eggs out from
women then you put them in a other
visual warm but you see for that to
happen is in human you know so we today
we see that as in human you know we see
the matrix the movie where you have
millions of artificial wombs
oh Jesus
so I guess I turned off my sound for
like [ __ ] 10 second 10 10 minutes
when did I lost the sound two minutes no
sound
do I have sound now
check check Sony's back Sony's back
okay those sound for three minutes what
the [ __ ] I've been talking I don't know
where what I know I don't know what did
I say so anyway I was saying so so we
digressed into you know from gender
issues from name into a summary okay
let's wrap up we closed down in five
minutes okay copy that go through my
Emacs page magnify I'm going to show you
I'm going to shut down but we are going
to wrap up wrap up and show what we
talked about today so we talked about
astrology astronomy okay so so we talked
about solar system solar okay solar
system planetary system Milky Way galaxy
okay okay and we can cross this
Wikipedia page is solar system galaxy
then we talked about astronomy symbols
of course from solar systems to
astronomy symbols
I don't have the page somewhere okay I
already closed it so anyway let's paste
a link here male and female symbols
Unicode cross
math symbols and cultural symbols
and we talked about dictionary
appendices these symbols you'll find in
dictionary appendices okay
copy one more okay so we were talking
about solar systems then being galaxies
in Milky Way then we were talking about
astrology symbols I have a link here
somewhere astrology symbols in astronomy
symbols then we started to talk about
gender symbols you know the male symbol
and the female symbol male is the mass
symbol and female is the Venus symbol
then we started to talk about gender
then we started to talk about you know
the social justice the politics of
gender and then we digressed into yeah
then we start to talk about Sailor Moon
because you know these you know you have
Sailor Venus
Sailor Mars Jupiter Sailor Mercury then
we then we talk about you know the
gender politics then then we talk about
we are entering humanity human animals
are on this earth is entering into a new
era where masculinity and femininity
reduced you know greatly reduced instead
you have gays in you know trends and
wink guys you know and and you know in
tomboy tomboy is girls so a reduction of
that so so there's a political power
struggle aspect of that but there's
another aspect that is the you know that
is the be you know we have this
situation not just because of the
politics but because technology you know
technology made us you know you don't
need to be male or female
anymore so I'm kind of giving some
credit to these social justice facts you
know although they push for it they
force force this kind of you know
nonsense on us but part of the reason is
because technology actually made it that
way in you know partly because we don't
need to be male and female anymore and
then we then we talked about the matrix
you know because technology can you know
we don't need sex anymore you can just
have you know take out the sperm and
eggs in and incubate bait them in a
artificial one
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
I guess closed closed
so yeah I was saying congratulations to
Vanya you are getting a girl a woman and
you are going to have babies
congratulations that's a good thing I
think
I hope actually I wanted to oh yeah I
want to I want to have you know I want
to have babies but I don't know
okay thank you guys have a good day bye