welcome to another episode of saw talk
show today's 2019 October 29th in USA
Tuesday 3 o clock p.m. San Francisco
time sunny California good morning guys
and today we have several topics
prepared and today we are going to try
another episode of melodious Ness of the
voice and pleasant kind of like feminine
voice now feminine here does not means
vocalization of the female but it means
rather kind of gentle kind soft voice
you know encouraging kind of those kind
of mentality when when when you talk and
so we can try that and no swearing no
[ __ ] Jesus you know YouTube they said if
you say the swearing word within I think
30 the first minute or the first 30
seconds then they gonna censor your
there's no ads for your YouTube things
like that but apparently maybe I already
violated that so let's try you see the
female about feminine voice this
approach to doing a talk show is that is
that you know it's the antithesis of my
nature of our talk show because not talk
show it's not it's you know it often
it's swearing and aggression and anger
and the minx makes you feel
uncomfortable this is the opposite of
ASMR that thing on YouTube and
you see but so I'm trying to I'm going
to switch to a melodious for a small
socially acceptable speech like Jordan
Peaks Peterson or Sam Harris you know or
the bunch of other people when giving a
speech in Universal universities or
stuff or even programmers at Google i/o
they give a presentation so you have to
talk in a socially acceptable way that I
can do but but in particular today I'm
trying to be feminine more feminine
voice in melodious and the present that
requirement you see that let me
delineate the lineal Nate the
differences that requirements is not
just soft a voice that doesn't cut it
you so you know soft voice is not the
thing the gist
the heart of it is that you have to
change your mindset into a sort of
gentle kind helping mentality when you
talk about something so instead of for
example if I have issues with Linux or
open-source I think they are fake news
the further you know I'm not against
open-source itself but rather I'm agin
is the fervor of open source that is
fanatism and that that is the part I
think that is where open source and free
software foundation they do us wrong
it is a phonetic ism because once you
reach the status of fanatism encode you
cease to think you cease to reason you
you know you are just have one track
mind so that is my typical that that is
my opinion right but if you you know so
typically I just say [ __ ] UNIX [ __ ] but
if I'm going to try that in a socially
acceptable way you know how would that
come out that would be like I think I
think open source
my is a great idea but in some but today
it has become less of a good idea today
because of many force information and
the mindset of want to believe you know
so that's the way you put it gentle and
and and in the end in the melodious and
feminine voice okay all that you see I
have I have to put an effort to do that
because that is not my nature sabar says
we didn't see that your first 10 seconds
of The Scream I don't know what's going
on it's YouTube you know YouTube I don't
know what why is that and let's see if I
am is my mouth synced because maybe
there is some problem so anyway that's I
think let's get on to the topic of the
of today what do you think of the
concoct a native programming well yeah
like this allowed to talk about that
okay it's synced thank you and Emily
Emily good morning so let's get on to
the topic today and yeah so Tomas walk
good morning Tomas was a sparrow 6 is
Naraku
what does raku mean and Bob saved
something and part is now a nymph an but
you have to spend 10 years to learn name
but I rather I think Julia I would
prefer Julia much better than name
because name no just just go with : ok :
if you want you know : is the main you
know is actually something that's doing
something named Julia
scheme they are kind of this nish you
know they're gonna they're gonna be nish
forever like after 20 years when you
become old when you become a an old fart
like me okay I'm already screwing of the
feminine voice that gentle person tation
when you become an old fart like me
you're gonna say you're gonna ask you
then you're gonna see a name like 20
years from today name is maybe it
doesn't exist anymore oh it's still like
you know you see younger people they say
you should learn name you know name is
arrogant or whatever that is that is my
experience with scheming disp you want
to go with something okay here comes the
reason I mean why is that why does this
elegant languages they renamed nish I
have Arco about that basically it's
because not not because the language
itself it may be a great language such
as skinned knees but the problem is with
the associated people and community yeah
that is the thing you know the ideology
thing because because certain languages
name possibly okay I'm not too sure but
let's say but I can say for sure scheme
this you know it's considered the best
language since 1990s scheme please
today it's like nowhere it's it's is
dying and even the the people themselves
are changing to pirate you know Python
syntax and all that so when you've a
Kurdish language such as Haskell name
okay Oh Judea the secret you know Judea
is a sad story I that when it came out
ten years ago I thought this is great
you know fast and it's gonna be it's
gonna be mainstream but it's not I
looked you know what I've seen is that
it's it's rather very very niche okay
it's like it's I'm guessing it's going
to be the to have a future just like you
know the scheme displeased like
in this niche little group you'll never
see anyway that is a problem so so why
do certain languages fall into that fate
my guess is that they it is not about a
language because skimmed is is truly is
a great language and so I can say for
name and Julia even I don't know them I
suppose that is true I am pretty sure
but certain languages has a certain fate
you know the basically these are the
hacker types languages for example PHP
JavaScript these two are the top number
two programming language that the hacker
hated to the most extreme if you pick
the top number two languages the hacker
hated in the past 20 years that would be
PHP and JavaScript however both of them
become the number one most popular
language okay let me get back to my
point so why is certain languages has
the fate of falling into deep you know
into this little used little-known group
it is not because the language because
Java because JavaScript and PHP they
really sucks you know they'd at least
sucked back then but the scheme is for
example and maybe Julian named they are
they are technically great languages but
however they have a bad bad fate so so
why does that happen in my opinion it is
the people the community they attract
nerds and these nerds they don't
understand society like I discussed a
few few days ago with an example of sage
math they are user interface and also
Linux you know it's never going anywhere
on this top for 20 years now I mean I
know some people like Matt I mean you
might be thinking you haven't used the
latest Linux you know it things has
changed no it's not so anyway so let me
get focused but on the reasons okay so
certain languages has a bad fate being
forever in a niche not popular not
because the language
Jews bad but rather because it attract
it attract the community of those
languages are mostly these hacker types
nuts you know talking about UNIX
philosophy everyday or list machines
everyday I mean you guys know right
because that is my that is my circle
that is my community these people
typically technical people nuts you know
geeks nerds and in the socially awkward
they don't understand how society works
so so when that happens so so in this
community for example has cow named yeah
you know maybe Julia and the scheme for
sure this in these communities what you
see every day is these people they are
trying to promote it you know and they
have they also have they have lots of
problems because they don't understand
society these nuts they they don't
understand
so they meanwhile every day they are
attacking go they are attacking you know
the mainstream attacking Microsoft
whatever Microsoft they just attack it
you know in this in the in this attack
attack attack and and if you if you are
not a nerd personality if you are not an
o-type they don't like you neither they
attack you know this is what social just
is cool you know you know they they they
think of that way so you so you you end
up with this for example scheme niche
niche group they you attack everything
and every time you have a question they
tell you Oh have you tried monad have
you tried to tell recursion have you
tried you know these fancy whatever
jargons you know so it's not it you know
it's not practical it's in it's not good
for the growth of the language and and
also these nerds they don't want the
same Society so they don't understand
marketing marketing how to promote
yourself so every end and also most of
the time they are against marketing like
for example in Python community around
2005 Python do not have a logo and I
think it's you know you should have a
logo and and you got a bunch of
I'm programmers we don't need a logo why
you shouldn't need me no go but then
later on Python got a logo same thing
with the Lisp list community when I say
you know this we need a logo you know to
represent ourselves to kind of you know
but the typical nerds reaction is that
logo oh you know that it's a marketing
it's you know they so they they don't
understand society so the it is they
made the language niche and have this
code status like Emacs vim Emacs vim
Lisp Haskell you know it makes them into
is these codes status and they almost
you could say they implicitly force out
any growth of the language because they
want the language to it's it's almost
like in they implicit implicitly want
the language to stay forever niche it's
almost like it's almost like that's
their imprint in direct purpose you know
that's their go that's a problem so
after ten years today you know part you
guys when you get old you know you're
too you know you maybe you are a manager
or maybe you'll be rich you know but but
you know then you see young people and
we need to do name you know it's maybe
20 years old later 20 years later it's
still around and you still niche that's
a problem so that that is the problem so
that is why when it comes to you know
what language you want you know a lot of
people you know young people especially
always have the question which language
to learn which language to learn what's
your recommendation of yours what do you
think so so so you so my my opinion
would be so that's that is why I like :
very much because : the technical
qualities of a goal and why I love goal
and okay that's actually one of the
topic we want to talk about so so why do
I like goal I'm first of all technically
it is pretty good okay
not not your best language I mean every
nerds everywere of you have your own
opinions often very often did there are
there are several blogs blogs attacking
: because they say oh now we have 30
years of under the understanding of
programming language research but Golan
is like xxx still sticking to 30 years
old ways and brats okay so Golan
technically it's pretty good okay it's
not your favorite you know Haskell or
whatever monad okay but it's pretty good
solid it's intended to replace tsipras
first I think they did a good job it's
technically pretty good it's supposed
functional programming you know normal
functional programming not extreme like
Haskell home or ml okay mo f sharp you
know things like that so it's pretty
good technically and that goal and
documentation is perfect it's fantastic
it's the best it's one I would say one
of the best three let's say I've ever
seen in my 30 years of computing the
goal and documentation so which
documentation are the best technical
writing : I would include it : goal and
mathematical documentation Java
documentation I hate the Java language
but Java documentation is one of the
exemplary superb technique of writing
okay : duck fantastic Mathematica talk
fantastic Java doc fantastic well
written focused and you know perfect
technical writing and PHP talk I would
include also because PHP talk is one of
the most of them all the most practical
documentation because by that what what
do I mean by that because if you are a
programmer you know you working a job
you have to look up talk every day you
know what does it do PHP has the
documentation PHP has the orientation
that is focused on what you need to do
you need you you are doing your daily
job you have turns up problems issues
you know questions protocols you have to
look up and and you need to code right
so when you have a question about PHP
documentation or function you look up
it's right there and it explains almost
always exactly what you want with
examples too so PHP dog is one of the
best too so so : Mathematica doc Java
doc phpdoc now these are very different
languages you see I'm not favoring one
or the other
these are very diverse different
languages you know and and I don't like
Java oh I hate Java but however they are
documentation is perfect and also each
one of them their documentation is
actually in different style so you can
actually see here as an example of
different technical writing styles yeah
they have different style that means
different styles of writing different
styles of organization different styles
of approaching to language documentation
for example Java is very Chavez stock is
very you know it's
opie and it's it's very professional
what you would say Mathematica is more
you know anyway very different
approaches in in technical writing but
openness organization but also also the
formatting you know like if you are
writing a tutorial documentation you
would be concerned there's a lot
formatting issues for example my web
page you know have particular formatting
Styles you can see you know this is my
tutorials of Java okay so let's go to
JavaScript I just I just want to show
you my website so go to my website by my
tutorial okay so support me so
JavaScript for example let's let's look
at some of the so anyway so this is so
when you write documentation there's
also a formatting issue like how do you
format your code how do you do you think
hex color them or not that's mine
but also but how you organize you format
them so Java Mathematica :
PHP they all have their own style so
it's very interesting in and okay so
these are the good documentation on the
other hand the word start talk is Unix
man pages UNIX man pages Apache
documentation that's a1 Apache
documentation is the worst if I have to
pick one worst in the entire programming
industry in you know I read the entirety
of Apache dog in in 1989 to 1992 because
I actually have - what do you call
surgery you know I have to die me Apache
module so my god so main pages was
Apache dog is the worst what are the
other other Python Python doc is also
one of the worst okay
and JavaScript is also worse because
first of all JavaScript do not have a
documentation because of the nature of
the language it became you know the
Akuma script SPECT then mozilla tries to
document it you know then you have bunch
of tutorials there's really no one you
know documentation doesn't exist except
except the suspect you know the Akuma
script SPECT which is language SPECT
which is unreadable it's not for
programmers anyway so : why I love Golan
so technically it's a it's a good
language it's it's pretty good supports
function of programming is reasonable II
have the best documentation and it's
also compiled or as a scripting language
you know you eat you know it's it's
intended to replace C++ so you compare
it and once you compare it you can send
it to your friends on Mac Linux and
Windows it runs without needing to
install : oh you can use : as a
scripting language like I've shown many
times you know just script you can write
a find/replace programming hot 100
you know and and it's fast five times
faster than Python Ruby JavaScript so so
all these reasons why I love : so okay
so so let's let me show you actually
let's start to create my my topics we
talked about about we I already talked
quite a lot I think why I love : okay
why I love golden is one of the thing
I'm talking about today and yeah so
actually we were talking about why some
languages forever nish have the fate of
being forever nish okay that's one of
the topic and and why I love : why I
love Golan so what are the other things
I started to talk about feminine voice
okay then that digressed into this
actually feminine voice is dramatic I
didn't know what I meant is socially
acceptable way of speaking
except our socially acceptable way of
public speaking okay we digress into so
many and we haven't started to talk
about today's real topics yet and I
haven't read the farces meme is 120
times faster than goal and that's
[ __ ] what about 10 times faster
[ __ ] what about two times faster
[ __ ] : enemy are the same speed okay
if you want to talk about faster than
that this is impossible because : in
some depending on what program it's the
same speed or si
okay so you wanna test show me a test
yeah show it show it show some you know
benchmark show it let's talk about that
okay so anyway why I love Golan
so I actually so so let me finish you
know let me finish the train of thought
here and goal and so let me copy why I
love Golan okay right there so let's
copy that split the window open that
page go to the top search for goal and
go to the top search for goal and why I
love Golan okay so that's why that's one
of the topic we talked about so why I
love Golan so actually let's go to the
page simple language and also it's
simple so you can run it script it or
compiled but the most okay here's the
thing I want to say the most important
thing
one of the critical reason I advocate
Golan you guys I you know I recommend :
for you guys to learn is that Quran is
very simple : is one of the simplest
language so I recommend : is because
this important reason and what that what
is that reason Golan is mainstream okay
: is like Cece firs versus mainstream :
has ten times more users and jobs
then then closure has cow Julia name
combined okay so that that is kind of
that that is the important that that is
the most important thing about Golan it
it Golan is something that matters okay
yeah you can stick to Julia you know
name or whatever this is this a [ __ ]
you know they are hundred there you know
they are terms of languages out there
that's elegant and so on and you know
loved by nerds but they have a problem
the problem is they are kind of there
for ever being nish you know in ten
years twenty years they are
we manage that that is a major problem
you want you want a language that you
can you know that that is a widely used
that is to say you know why do you use
so that is why I very much support :
what about name you know I don't know
name but I heard it's similar in nature
with : you it's kind of very fast typed
can be compiled or can run as a script
you know many share many nature share
many characteristics with : so name very
fast and elegant I heard many of you
guys say it okay except but but I you
know I don't feel like I want to learn
name because I know because from I see
you know name is just one of the another
scheme this you know in 20 years you'll
still have young people oh you should
learn name name name meanwhile : has 100
100 times users you know name you learn
name you don't get a job daddy that is a
problem so that is a problem remember
guys when you think about which language
to learn unless you know maybe maybe
most of you already are a hermit like me
you know you stay home you don't work in
a day job you know you do you know you
you you you you you plant tomatoes you
eat your own veggies you know maybe you
are that type of guy I know some of you
guys are so if you you know if you are
like that well then what you know you
can learn you can do whatever language
but but yeah so so that's you know but
most people are not like that and you
have to survive and you know you have to
surviving in via wood so that so that
that is what I'm saying you see : that
that has a value far significant value
in society then then name you know name
julia has cow skin this combined you
have to realize like 10 times not just
10 10 times is is an understatement
it has
one hundred times most value
significance to society on a whole then
name Julia :
you know this culture combined that's
the thing that's the thing you have to
understand and they are not like math
for example if you create a math theory
nobody understand it nobody use it you
know there are a lot a lot math theories
in differential geometry topology right
in algebra but they are significant they
are permanent they are forever math is
different from forming languages so you
have : I mean you have scheme this you
know name Julia okay that's great but
it's technology it's really by itself if
nobody uses it doesn't really have any
much value they are you know they don't
you know even proof systems like [ __ ]
nobody use it doesn't have really much
value it's you know different for math
you know so that is that is what I'm
saying so that is what I'm saying about
Y so that is the topic we talked about
basically for for the past 30 minutes
well yes 30 minutes already so the topic
is why some languages have the fate of
being forever niche okay and and at this
point let me show you an article which I
wrote about scheme because I was you
know I was at least fan you know I love
Mathematica that that is my most
favorite but but but today I I have lots
of you know I like colon as well but
let's say anyway what I'm trying to say
is Lisp I also like list very much
because mostly because he's functional
but you know you see for the past 23
from 1990s to 2000 I witnessed that at
least you know at point we think Lisp is
going to be everywhere everywhere it's
not it's just it's just dying yeah I
mean is today Common Lisp scheme is you
can say it's dead
you have closure you know that's some
you know it
hanging there you know that that is a
problem so you know what I'm so what I'm
saying is I witnessed this in 20 years I
really something I really want to
believe it but it doesn't happen it's
that that is a problem that is a problem
you want and in the information again
you know compare JavaScript PHP these
two languages every nerd bad-mouth about
them every day you can see everywhere
else it sucks
oh java script sucks PHP sucks is the
worst language you make fun of it every
day for the past 20 years but they are
they they are they you see they became
they became the most popular language
it's not like you know Google just push
it push them it's not like that they by
themselves you know they become the most
popular because they actually are
practical they relate to people they let
people do things for example PHP why
because first of all it's very easy
language simple no you know no no of
these chalk and concepts Mona tail
recursion you know oh oh oh marcos you
know they don't create PHP don't do that
they focus on extremely practical things
you need to do even though it's very
lousy actually it's not bad especially
today PHP is I think in my opinion is
one of the I mean it's it's a good
language okay today so PHP you know the
reason they become the most popular from
from year 2000 to 2010 PHP is the most
popular you know every website is
written in PHP Wikipedia for example and
and and Facebook
remember Facebook the most popular
social network website is written in PHP
you know it is PHP that made Mark
Zuckerberg which he you know he he's I
don't think he's a great programmer he's
not a great nerd but he just used PHP he
get on he do things that's that's an
important thing you got a writer app
that the population love that you know
that that is the important thing on the
other hand me
you know studying Emacs keybinding Emacs
combining keyboards you know this this
syntax and I become this homeless guy
you see that that you know so that that
is the thing you want to you know you
want to consider what yeah so I mean so
you want to consider the the viability
the value of a premier language with
respect to society how you know how
important what what is truly important
you want to think about that for most of
you for me I know we also are very loved
we very much concerned about the design
yeah that's important too but but you
have to put some attention about the you
know social aspect of things so that
that is my that concludes the topic of
why some languages have the fate of
being forever nish
okay yeah so I wanted I wanted to
mention of article I wrote sorry scheme
failure so I have a written article so
this this article programming scheme and
failure I don't I'm not sure this is the
one no this is not one so let me try to
find it this one so this one is written
in 2009 language the Tarot is language
purity code and deception so this essay
is roughly a 10 years personal
retrospect of some languages in Patrick
scheme and Haskell I learned far more or
camo in the past two days then [ __ ]
two months I tried to learn Haskell with
ten years of I want to believe in
Haskell
the Haskell problem is similar to scheme
this being academic and Ito industrial
environment and in bah-bah-bah so on so
anyway so I this this also this article
I described 10 years of the experience
witnessing the popularity of languages
you know what the language is I really
want them to succeed and you know and
how they've fared at the end it's it's
kind of a sad story so Haskell is one of
them but mostly this article I'm talking
about scheme scheme Gaia
you know even today I've you know I've
got people talking to me they are still
like they don't know ok they are young
people they don't know
Caio I mean they don't know the history
of Gaia but to them I can see it you
know in a way they asked me the question
they don't know what is it is they think
Kyle is gonna revolutionize Emacs it's
it's pretty sad story Kyle is one of the
worst implementation of the scheme and
lots of things ok I can talk about this
for one hour so this our code you know
you might check it out it kind of
reflects it it's an alternative take of
what I am talking about today why some
languages have have the fate of being
forever nish
and in this article you will also some
part of history history about Kyle about
Emacs about scheme why you know what you
know and yeah so that that that is about
that so ok that finishes the topic for
that 20 minutes and now I have
so we talked 40 minutes for that now I
have tons of comments for me to go
through and today's main topic is
actually this main topic let's see and
today's main topic Emily asked
something about oh it's risk it
okay laptop keyboards in phone ID stuff
phone ID stuff
let's okay so phone ID stuff okay so at
this point guys comment ok comments if
you have questions let's see what we're
gonna talk about next
so this is tea tea for today
c'mon easy Trump good morning Thomas
Thomas
whoa Thomas where are you from Freddie
good morning to Germany good morning
Alan - in California good morning Emily
Emily where you from good morning AHA
maps from Germany good morning hello
beautiful people from Zach Czech
Republic I think I don't know how do you
pronounce that sorry what you actually
there I mean are you in Czech Republic
or were you born there so but what erm
you hello hello beautiful people hello
beautiful people good morning Justin
good morning to Canada I work with a guy
who loves Julia but we all known him
some essays you are free to join the
Linux crowd and make a change
that's what Dina open-source people say
I understand what where you came from I
understand but you know yeah so you are
saying you know basically the mentality
that that that is very common you know
like that can be that can be exemplified
that mentality is well known as the
phrase where is your code like every
time you people criticize Linux then the
Linux phonetics open-source fanatics
they will retort where is your code like
you like Linux is open-source you know
you need to country to contribute in
other words they are they are propaganda
they are putting out a propaganda so
when you criticize the Linux you know
this is bad design they don't they don't
want that even if they don't consider
the validity of your criticism they
ignore it that's a problem that is one
of the reason why Linux forever is
terribly designed bad in so many ways so
every time we when someone criticize me
Knox
people do you know the Linux fanatics
they don't consider the validity of the
criticism rather you have
you have a current of retort varying
that criticism saying yeah you know is
so many different styles one of them is
wears a coat in that particular one it
means you know they want you to be you
know this is open source you supposed to
support you are not supposed to just
criticize and and and freeloading you
know
so anyway that is one of the problem and
you know if you apply to me you know on
Linux crowd I contributed Emacs for 20
years of my life I don't get no pay well
okay 10,000 when I was when I was about
to die people have donated to me
altogether like 7000 twice okay so in 20
years I got 7,000 you know they'd say
$10,000 just de set de set de said mi he
said justified and every you know so 20
years I spent you know five hours a day
contributing to open source all my
source code is it's open source so then
people but you see that's a problem you
see the Linux fanatism you don't see it
you don't see it's also like today I'm
talking about Linux you know the issues
but then you say oh but you are free to
join the Linux crowd I don't blame you I
mean you don't that is very typical
reaction no so so what is your answer
you know what have you considered I
contributed to Emacs packages and
tutorials material is the most the
number one puppy know most popular Emacs
in the Magnus tutorial for the past 15
years okay does that have you ever
consider that how much time you have to
spend to do that and you know me Adam I
don't I don't have a car I don't have a
doctor I don't have insurance next day
tomorrow I'll be gone if I fail down
from bicycle that's it for me so so so
the typical Linux reaction then when you
criticize they say oh yeah but you but
you are always free you know that the
kanto the
more gentle people there they will say
you know when they see you linux
criticism at season they'll retort oh
yeah but you know but you can you know
you know you can make a change you know
help help us make a change the the then
the node type we will just say where is
your code then there's [ __ ]
you know go [ __ ] yourself go [ __ ]
yourself you are scum you don't know
Linux you are just freeloaders you know
these type of people do different you
know but but you know so that's let that
that is Linux finishes fanaticism that
is a problem
okay masses can you actually spend what
a monad is in a few words I actually I
cannot I can tell you the basic concepts
but I am I am not qualified Justin can
you do that just means a Haskell
programmer he can he can he can tell us
you know maybe maybe not in few words
but Justin do you want to give a shot
Mona is yeah I am NOT going to work
because I'm not I don't really know it
well
hello beautiful word topics I would like
you to your opinion is number eight
let's see what is number eight so okay
let's start to answer the the topics
today so that is what let's see what is
number eight number eight is very
interesting I want to do that so let's
let's do that
number eight okay and also Emily asked
about phone let me quickly cover that
phone
the modern society phone there is a very
interesting let's so let's go to
programming there here it is let me show
it with view image and go back here and
and view image okay so modern phone you
have ID every phone every phone hardware
has a unique ID basically global unique
ID so every phone has a unique ID and
that idea is called IMEI International
Mobile Equipment Identity so every time
you move around you take you know phone
in your pocket you drive or whatever you
go to a different country so you move
around in your city the by the nature
how phone how cell phone works you are
being tracked it has to because it's
requirement of the technology because
the because phone is based on radio wave
and radio wave you need local stations
radio trance you know they call cell
towers that you might see if you go to a
street street there's a tower that
transmit that that that's what makes
your phone work cell phone but that
those towers they have limited range
they cannot be you know very far what's
the range maybe I don't know five five
kilometers or something so every time
you go around or less
anyway you you go around the phone the
phone companies nose even if you don't
get any call you know even even if you
have all apps you know off it has to
know because it needs to connect to the
cell towers so you know connect to the
nearest cell tower so that that is the
international mobile phone identity
that's one of it the other identity ID
is international mobile subscriber
identity I am si this is basically your
sim you know your SIM card that
identifies the user of the phone so you
have these two identities white why are
these interesting because so it so in
modern society you when you use a phone
even if you are not calling it tracking
is tracking you everywhere
now what we want so so what this company
and these companies you know the cell
phone companies though they and and also
the applications like Facebook Twitter
Google they store all this information
permanently that is a that is the thing
so all your move about if you as long as
you have a smart phone even if you don't
use it if you know even if you ya don't
use it you you you carry it it knows
your life history of where you are and
ideally they these companies can delete
an information you know after after a
week let's say but they don't they don't
because they know they realize that this
information are valuable to you know to
to characterize each person so they can
focus advertisement and so on or they
can sell to the government to control
you so that is a problem a problem and
so what what is interesting you might
check out check out is that recently
Snowden talked about this on Joe Rogan
show so let's show it show you
YouTube let's go to YouTube okay
so YouTube you go to Joe Rogan clip Joe
Rogan clip okay because Joe Rogan every
time he does interview he's got you know
it's like one hour two hour long so he
has another channel which is just clips
of his interviews and if you go there he
about three days ago he interviewed
Snowden and Snowden talks about it so
there it is so you might check that out
let's see where is it
so Snowden Obama state is building guys
know your cell phone spy on you okay so
this our this video you might check out
this Joe Rogan idiots I truly dislike
dislike this Joe Rogan guy he's he's a
bufang you know he's he's a true idiot
okay I'm sorry to insult his
intelligence but he's just truly of low
IQ it doesn't know about anything when
he interviews he does not do homework he
does not know anything but but often he
interject the interviewer you know
wherever the interview I have something
interesting to say the Joe Rogan comes
on and talk about idiotic things and and
you know Joe Rogan I don't like this guy
but however you know he's doing the
interview is very interesting and he
make a lot money so this video for
example this creep by itself is four
million views this is like five three
days four days ago so you might check
out this video okay so Snowden he knows
as though this stuff well about cell
phone obviously because he's part of CIA
and FBI but but does information he
talked about is not is not secret at all
if you study phones you know about this
all all the time even back to back in
two hundred I mean
20 years ago I got I used my cell phone
a dumb phone back in 1998 okay I'm the
first when nobody has a cell phone I
have one I'm I'm I'm a hacker okay so
back then in 1998 to 2002 I was in a
dot-com you know I'm the I'm a hotshot
I'm a big program i i have root password
to 20 mega boxes you know the service
control I control the livelihood of
people so I have a cell phone back then
you don't have you don't have smartphone
like today but you know that you have
the Nokia kind of cell phone so when you
have cell phone you study I did study
you know part of a little bit about cell
phone the cell towers how they work so
he attracts you so anyway check out
Snowden's video he gives a good well
presented
you know articulation about the phone so
that is about phone for Emily one of the
topic Emily asked so that's the next
thing let's talk about JavaScript
because this is this topic is
interesting and I can do it easily I you
know I can do it well but let's maybe
let's look at the let's let's have some
let's look at the comments and reply so
bar says if nobody uses you do you have
no value that is true you see happy you
know I don't know what's what you are
saying maybe you think you you know your
heart retorting my point that is
actually true because value is not
defined what when you say value
something value for example my mouse you
know is here's my mouse or my keyboard
or you can say me you know you can
anyway let's say some sub-object so you
see let's see
it's this vapor thing so when you have
something you want to judge the value
value what does it mean it it has that
depends on who this has some value to me
but I don't really you know let's not
say that but the keyboard let's say my
Kinesis keyboard this has great value to
me I would for example spend $300 for it
but to many of you to to vast majority
of people who don't use a computer it
has zero value you see I I would you
know spend $300 on that but they if you
give this to them free there you have no
use no value to them that's what the
value means so value implicitly when you
say value of something implicitly it it
has a target like with respect to what
to whom in general when you don't
mention anything about it when you just
say what's the value of something
basically the implicit background is
with respect to all the people you know
maybe in the region in your country for
example when you talk when I talk about
value of something you typically I mean
USA so typically with respect to you
know USA people for example for example
when you for example let's say example
the value of the English language okay
to to to us Americans especially Native
Americans that's critical without
English you know you you don't have
language to communicate anymore you
become immediately your society collapse
if English disappeared tomorrow you know
immediately
basically all english-speaking countries
crafts so English the value of English
language is tremendous it's the the the
Omni you know that the most important
than everything almost in
english-speaking country but but not in
China not in Japan
if any English disappear they well then
they miss you know it's a big part of
humanity but they keep going you know
that's so value is very dependent on our
regions and on the people so when you
say you know what what is the value of
me you know usually you don't you don't
you don't say the value of a person
because first of all that is morally
apprehensive people you know people
don't want to put a price tag on um
people but but but technically you can
judge that for example a value of a
homeless people who is you know homeless
jobless for thirty years is this then
the value of say Google's Google founder
okay no Steve Jobs okay now people don't
usually say that because you you know
it's part of the more oh you know and
and it's it's reasonable you know you
don't want to like start to compare put
a price tag on the value of people but
but that is actually you know if if if
you want to think about that maybe in a
philosophical context which is what I'm
doing it is true some people you know
for obvious examples you know homeless
people they are not as valuable as you
know president of USA or president of
any country even though the homeless
people may be maybe a better person but
I mean we're talking about value you
know that the the you know we forget
about other thing else for the moment so
anyway that's the value of so value is
not just what is the point what the
value of a person so for for example the
value of me what is the value of me not
much really
okay so guys want to talk about
JavaScript let's go on to JavaScript in
okay so there is a lot questions I can I
cannot answer every one of them the Neo
landlord is haven't seen you for awhile
the new language
okay so so am I so okay so okay so what
is the how long have I been talking I'm
thinking maybe the JavaScript god this
JavaScript topic has been delayed and
delayed but actually actually that's
maybe let's just do it now
inject some technical aspect into it I
mean technical part of my talk show
about that okay so so anyway this is Joe
Rogan's you guys should watch check it
out it's great I think but you might
like it
but but you don't use a phone right I
mean like really you being tracked all
the time part so this this Edward
Snowden and let's see oops
Joe Rogan god I don't like that guy so
so that's that's this move on to
JavaScript okay I'm gonna keep my eyes
on the comments so if I did if you want
me to address something put it then I'll
see it because there's too many comments
for me to go through if you have to
repeat it to it
good morning Kathy thank you so
JavaScript so I want to actually this
javascript is gonna be a big topic
because there are some several things I
want to talk about so I'm guessing sorry
guys maybe not today because today it's
already
it's today's already we talked about for
one hour okay so tomorrow let's I
javascript is that that part is gonna be
my first topic tomorrow okay so so
what's up so maybe that's it for today
I'm thinking so it's close that 16
people watching JavaScript
yeah so that's today and so let me just
read the comments and answer the
comments and tomorrow first thing we
cannot do the JavaScript and what is 17
language barrier okay let's do 17 then
because that is non-technical which
which kind of fit fit into today's talk
you could be Joe Rogan with your brain
but your organ beat you with Brazilian
Jujitsu not your organs I don't is
idiotic and he's idiotic but this is
just not that he doesn't he doesn't look
into things he doesn't study ok he's
also he's brainless you know and he's he
know it you know I'm not criticizing I
mean you know there are there are tons
of people smarter than me ok but anyway
he's a brainless guy but he's this he he
wants to comment about his opinions like
collecting poor Tim who is another
YouTube star ok he he's like oh but I
think socialism or something but oh yeah
I do agree joe rogan idiot you know how
you know I don't feel comfortable
scolding him that too much because he
saw how shall I put it so you know he
just you know he's someone he makes
money he is kind of lucky actually of
course he also walk he does well his job
compared to others it's actually easier
thing Alice but you know what anyway
he's successful he does interviews you
know he everyone is different he does
his things and and of course most people
vast majority a majority of people are
not programmers are not nerds so they
they watch my video they would find it
valueless like what what this guy
talking about
but your Ogun he does it's it's it's
it's truly more valuable to vast
majority of people because he interview
you know one of the things he does he
seem to view other people and that is
the that is most of the value is from
that he interviewed the other people or
the other slit celebrities politicians
you know they some people want to know
you know so so Joe Rogan but he's like
you know like one time he's talking
about kung-fu right now kung-fu
it's become has become a big topic in
the past three years now many of you may
not know but it's a big thing in China
because kung-fu you know when you swatch
movie Kung fuey saw these elegant
beautiful moves and and lethal you know
fantastic martial arts but not in
reality because because in since about
two years ago this this guy from MMA
mixed martial arts you know you fighting
a ring there's a lot videos of that you
can actually see my YouTube
recommendations because I watched quite
a lot of that you know boxing or MMA you
know fighting is recommended I hate I
really hate the Google recommended they
plaster all sort of things into your
stream where but actually
often times they actually are good you
know but but but what they do is that
they make you into a kind of a thinking
you know just clicking person
brainless so I try to avoid you know
clicking anything recommended by Google
so why is it like sometimes they'll just
have a lot MMA a martial art stuff in my
channel recommendation what is this okay
this is a lot movie recommend you know
there's another thing okay let's focus
on the kung-fu thing martial arts like I
don't I don't find it here so but anyway
you type MMA you'll see lots of it yeah
the fighting in the ring and they are
very brutal you know one one punch you
you can MMA there's also FC you know
this was you know the championship you
know there are few of them very brutal
so the the controversy about two or
three years ago is that there's a
Chinese guy in China who does MMA you
know kind of thing and he got into a
ring with a so called you know kung fu
master you know in China when you when
you search kung fu usually you'll see
you know like old Asian master how they
can do things to you so anyway he got
into a ring and beat that guy up within
like 30 seconds or 20 seconds or
something
Peter kung fu master so and he became
that this guy who exposed all these kung
fu masters there's quite a lot they you
know they may make money did they try to
teach Taiji especially Taiji you know
and la cerva so he exposed lots of them
and it becomes
a problem because the government the the
Chinese government they don't want I
think I mean the Chinese government they
have some issues about that because they
want to you know kung fu is you know the
Chinese tradition they want to promote
it they they don't want it to become to
collapse so there's a big talk you know
like in China oh if you are Chinese if
you are guy following these kind of
things there's a big controversy going
on for the past few years
basically kung fu has been the the the
imagery of kung fu like when you see
movies Tai Chi is its class collapsing
and people start to ask you know is kung
fu is just a fake news like a mystery
from the beginning or is it actually
something real you know historically I
mean the thing we know for sure today is
like today's kung-fu masters they are
mostly just [ __ ] you know they
cannot fight you you put them into a
ring the MMA people will beat the bit
ahead of you we will knock you out
within like 20 seconds that's reality
but the the next question is okay so
what's the value of kung fu today maybe
hundred years ago do they actually has
some Mad King are the actual you had are
they real
oh it's just all for movies so so that's
a big controversy okay my opinion
obviously you know they are who they are
they were real but not today it since
the past 50 years you know modern
society you no longer require the
self-defense that much you know you have
cops you have law it's so it's good and
you have guns you know basically guns
yeah guns eliminated all the martial
arts basically so gotten put so in the
past 50 years kung fu is kind of it's a
lost it's gone it's it became just a
show for you know wushu competition is
kind of like a sport and the same thing
similar to karate and lots of others
they they became just a either a showman
showmanship sport okay but in my opinion
they do have they were you know they did
say hundred years ago they was they were
serious they can kill people and I would
hold the opinion that hundred years ago
the kung-fu people may you know the they
probably probably will take out the MMA
you know champions that is my opinion
hundred years ago if you say that not
today because hundred years ago when
guns are not popular yet that that's
that's comedy
why because why do I say that because
kung fu' there are many things you can
do that you you can go to extremes in
fact you know like with the internet we
see a lot of extremes like we for
example in the sex department
you see people to things you know that's
right such as eating [ __ ] you know there
are people into that and also we see
lots of weird things you know internet
we can see but hundred you know imagine
100 years ago
anyway that's getting that's I'm getting
into too much of of just my own thing so
I guess where nobody's really interested
I think so whatever so ok back to Joe
Rogan but anyway one day you know he
made comment about going food it's just
idiotic okay it's just the show that's
it so you know he doesn't look he
doesn't know history
he doesn't even attempt to look at
history you know one day Joe Rogan just
says oh yeah gone food a you know they
showed maybe they show he shows some
fake you know kung foo you know one
point death creeps you know things like
that obviously fake so he showed that a
oh yeah he'd laugh at kung fu and karate
here but the thing is he doesn't even
attempt to look at history or things
just like his opinions common idiotic
opinions about everything not just confu
like I've watched quite a lot of Joe
Rogan's like thirty videos of fifty
clips over the past four years is easy
always make the most idiotic comments
plainness and often you know often when
an interviewer you know usually we are
interested in the guy he's interviewing
the the guy started to talk about
something interesting then Joe Rogan
interject then killed that that whatever
whatever he's talking about you know
this is [ __ ] idiotic Joe Rogan and you
know this is so it's not my type okay
it's not my type what I mean be what
what what do I mean because every time
you opened the Joe Rogan media okay
let's go let's go here okay you look at
look at the beginning clip the [ __ ] is
that
that you were going experience with the
[ __ ] you know this is a version to me
this face this style this is a I'm a
versa to it did you experience the [ __ ]
what the [ __ ] are you so he's you know
he's the type of guy to impart you know
drink beer and it's not my type that
that is the thing which is fine you know
the like sometimes I mentioned this this
intro fits you so you know I you know
I'm a schizoid so I'm kind of unusual
and I'm not actually I'm not high I
don't think so you see I'm a schizoid so
you could say technically I'm a
personality disorder
you know I'm psychological have problems
but one of the thing is that as a
schizoid I don't I cannot I'm incapable
of
enjoying normal friendship like you know
you go to a bar you have a drink or guys
you know get together play poker
I cannot you know I'm incapable of
enjoying that in fact it makes me
nervous that's the thing so when I look
at Joe Rogan you know that think you
know he hang out with his buddies okay
yeah that's okay
but so this is but it's that's not I
something I can do I cannot do that okay
I get together with people even you guys
okay I cannot talk about anything that's
not technical you know I have to I talk
about you know philosophy
maybe physics programming the future of
humanity AI other than that that's it I
cannot do small talks I can you know and
the the the you know the the guys
getting together playing poker I cannot
do that I give me it makes me nervous it
makes me and everything I say oh the
joke whatever I did the joke you you
know those type of people they mentioned
I don't understand everyone is laughing
I said laughing and why I'm trying to
maybe if I try to make a joke nobody
understands you nobody laughs you know
this kind of like that so that is so
okay so that is what I would say about
Joe Rogan it's you know it's not just
not my type so the Julia project will
participate in Google code 2009 you know
Google code is kind of like a good thing
back in 2008 today you know I think you
know why I see that it's like Google
[ __ ] off you know Google you know that's
that's what I said about all the open
source is just financed by Google more
blackjack or you late guy Jack oh really
yeah I I went to Fred roulette in Las
Vegas did you know I did I talked about
that I think I did a few months ago
so anyway I think that's it for today so
yeah let me just go get on Christians
and so tomorrow we're gonna focus on the
JavaScript thing because that may be 30
minutes because I'm gonna talk about a
related thing about mapping functions
the semantics of math in for each so
18:9 topic a 18 night so for example
it's Pacey here to see topic alien 9
JavaScript loop for each with break
functional programming replacement map
for each how to do how to do breaking
when you use if you want to do
functional programming style things like
that and another thing is programming
language syntactic and semantic
differences of map function so that's we
get into tomorrow so today that's it for
today I think to three minutes small
yeah I'm over rank so I try to think so
you just did not meet the right people
to have small talk with about things
interest you
yeah maybe yeah I don't go out I don't
go out you know that's part of the
reason but YouTube is empowering me
thank you google
yeah because you know I started to do
YouTube and you get to see my face and
you know you get to know what I think so
you guys do you guys have a video you do
you do guys do video posted okay if you
can post it so I'm just gonna check out
all the comments addressed to me
and that's it for today
you know joe rogan why i try to find a
fight he was in a parent's apparently
you don't see that in youtube you know I
tried to find he's you know past MMA
fight or whatever apparently you don't
see that so he's you know I guess
average MMA fighter if Joe Rogan offered
you a joint would you smoke on here yeah
I would I would if Joe Rogan interviews
me I would but I already say bad things
about him he's gonna you see so I'm not
like against Joe Rogan you know anything
like that
yeah just find you know he's just not
not not my type that's the best thing so
yeah I mean we we can hang out I mean
the thing with that is that you if we
hang out yeah like you know sometimes I
meet people like we have but this after
after 10 minutes you don't have much to
talk about anymore anymore you know the
basically the type of people I hang out
you know if I don't have I don't really
actually hang out at all but sometimes I
go out with people programmers you know
have a coffee from our the typical thing
is that I need the people that I need
the person to be programmers because I
know from experience you know typically
if they are not or it or not
mathematicians own you know they are not
technical people then there's nothing to
talk about like whatever they say I
don't have any comments you know this
becomes is like nothing to talk about
dead you know dead
Okaw it becomes awkward situation and
they talk about something I try to you
know honest try to reply or you know
give my opinion you know the normal
thing I have then it doesn't work
because there is
became say like a competition they start
they become the people you know
non-technical people they become
defensive like oh you make what you said
is not true or whatever they become but
but they don't know technology like many
you know then then tech people we are
talking about people who don't know ever
even know what is the browser they don't
know what is Google they don't know what
is copy/paste you know these a lot of
people you go to most people are
actually like that vast majority of
people you go through the street you
know less than 1% are actually technical
programmers or engineers so you go you
talk to them they you know everything
you say it doesn't you know that's you
don't mix I don't know if you guys feel
like that maybe some of you too did you
hang out in second life hang out yeah
hang out in second life is different
though because people don't actually see
your face that's a bit different you
know it's not like real life okay so
that's it for today thank you guys for
coming great talking bye guys bye guys I
think maybe I'm getting high yeah I
think I am because when you do this you
cannot think anymore and cannot think
anymore it kills your capability of
thinking of thinking you become this
just I don't know yeah definitely
say goodbye and goodbye Z Tron crazy bye