good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2020 first july
14th uh 11 20
san francisco time and we are going to
do emacs
emac this coding in the beginning i
guess and
then randomish so if you ever get any
questions post in the chat
box okay so
uh i'm not sure what we i'm going to do
okay so
there are several list commands that
you know okay one of the one of the
command i want to do is uh
backslash two slash okay let's begin
writing that okay
uh let's go to talk show today's talk
show and
let's write this backslash to slash okay
so show in talk show so you can see this
is today's talk show page turn on
javascript
refresh uh and then
go to notes okay backslash to slash okay
copy it here
show you can see there that's our topic
okay
so let's begin writing that and i want
to talk about
several things um
you know lots of lots of interesting
things uh so
but let's let's not dribble
and let's make the talk condensed so you
have
full of content if you are watching my
excite live show talk show
in you know uh not live you can
make it play speed 1.5 okay
so let's start so backslash slash so why
do you need that for example
you know in you know in windows you use
the um you use the backslash
so often you know for the path so often
you want to change the stash to
backslash or backslash to slash
so so i want to write the command so
we encode it replace the backslash
because otherwise normally
if i want to replace all the stash by
backslash i have to do
you know for example uh what i have to
do is uh
you know interactive query replace slash
and type then backslash and
enter then say everything okay so that
command is query replace
that's the most frequently used command
in emacs okay
here query replace but however there is
another command you can
call replace a string
okay so called replace string
and backslash to slash to backslash
and you'll do it one shot so this is
saves you one key stroke basically
anyway still tedious because then you
have to type slash and backslash and so
on so let's write the command okay
so we are going to write the command uh
define function uh xsa
let's say slash to backslash
okay slash to backslash
okay we're gonna do this quickly
comments questions okay well not until
you spend an evening fixing
xo exactly that's a linux pane
version today's state now the power of
supply keys we start to get the end the
power of emac beast okay so we're gonna
write this command
we're gonna write this very fast okay
i'm gonna write this
um let me show you okay yeah let me stop
talking and just write it
read it okay so we want to write the
command slash to backslash
so uh first of all you have to uh define
you you want to specify what region you
want okay so
so let's do that search backward search
backward for
uh space
or line return okay actually research
backward
regular expression space or line return
so that's going to be like that space of
line return
okay optional bound
uh no bound no error we actually we
don't care
we don't care about that search backward
then
p one p two position one position two
that's the cruiser position which is the
integer we define two variables
then set p1 to be point that is the
current cruiser position
so we search backward until the cursor
reaches a
space or line return actually let's say
skip let's actually call this command
skip
char backward okay uh
[Music]
space or line return okay uh that
and limit none okay so that will move
coin
uh that will move point two before the
character space
or line return or tab okay
then
[Music]
actually that's not what we want okay
yeah uh stupid me uh let's make the
simplest case okay
because uh i'm showing you to
to beginners basically so let's say
user maker selection first so set point
one
to uh region beginning position
region beginning
region beginning okay
so that's the region beginning for if
you have if you say the mark you have a
region right
so we set p1 to region beginning and set
p 2 to region end okay
then we gonna
then replace string okay
replace string describe variable
describe
a described function here you see the
function of the
function so here is the syntax let's
copy it
properly so form string so let's
look at that so this is um
okay we don't want we don't want to call
this function because this function is
defined in
emac list so it's a higher level
function so
but in general
often it's better to use the c function
so we don't want to use the higher level
because when you use higher level
functions it does
kind of lots of things and slower so
so if we don't use this uh higher level
function what do you do
you do a while uh while this is what you
do okay
so you go to emac this you go to my
tutorial i can show you what to do so
so here's emac this tutorial so there is
a section
on how to find and replace string
in the region okay so that will be go to
buffer the interactive find replace text
right there okay so right here so click
on that
so here is the idiom the emax idiom for
find replace text in a buffer so okay
so let's just copy that paste it here
and also copy the url go to the talk
show
and so paste in your talk show so we
have a
record of what we talked about you see
okay close that close that close that
now we back in the list
code so we we copied this idiom
search forward string okay so go to char
so go to char so okay so first of all
purify the code so we did that
then go to char go to char point you got
go to job p1 actually
we want to narrow to region ah okay
i talked too much save restriction am i
doing okay
save restriction narrow to region p1 to
p2
then then put this
inside okay then go to char such
case you know for search case case fault
search
uh neo okay we don't want case for
uh we don't want emacs to automatically
determine the case
by some smart way so we just want we
want literal
so uh so then go to child point mean
then while search for
word while search for word for the slash
okay and what is this
uh so describe function wire search
forward bound no arrow
uh bound neo no arrow true
do we want arrow
uh near okay we need to know that so we
search forward
then we replace match by backslash
so backslash in e-max is you need
double backslash okay then
we don't care about that we don't care
about that we don't care about that
prettify the code let me explain okay so
here is our function
so let's let's um
here is our function two variables
position one position two uh and they
are the
region beginning region end and then we
narrow to region
then we go to chart point minimum that's
the beginning of a
buffer position then we
while search forward if it finds uh
slash
if that's true keep doing it and replace
it by backslash okay that's it
uh remove remove that remove that
remove that that's it that's our code
okay eval the buffer
we are done okay about the buffer now
let's
copy let's copy some uh
windows um okay
let's go to let's go to
powershell okay so you are looking at
powershell pwc
is the current path okay let's see
cd web cassady info
okay comp okay
so pwz so that gives you
the current path you see on windows it's
backslash
so copy that
let's paste it here actually we need
slash okay so anyway so let's
paste it here okay so that's a current
you see here's a path we we are going to
try the command we just written okay
call it meta x first of all we need to
make a selection so
let's do that meta x
x two backslash okay
do it invite it use
a backslash in replacement text okay
uh
wait why is that
okay so so okay so
so invalid so that's uh basically we run
into the truth peak syndrome the pain in
the
ass of emac lisp so basically you just
need
four backslashes for one backslash okay
i'm not going to explain well the reason
is that backside
you know the reason is because the when
you call replace match
it has special syntax for backslash for
example backslash one
means the replace the first captured
pattern
backslash two means replace the second
captured
pattern so so backslash backslash means
i think it means something but anyway
let's try first
four backslashes okay so evaluate the
code
eval buffer again you can see the you
see you can see the
the command i call in the pink window
okay so now
we're gonna we want to replace the slash
by backslash on that on this region
call it do it
fantastic it worked okay
so now that's not good enough because
okay let's undo okay watch this okay
undo you see now it's back to slashes
again
now it's not good enough because before
we call the command we need to make a
selection first i don't want that
i'm a lazy person okay i want just i
just want to call the command here just
work on the let's see it should work out
you know
so here comes the design you know you
use the inter
phase design issue what do you want the
command to do
when there is no selection do you want
it to work on the current
line or do you want it to work on the
let's say the current paragraph or
whatever
uh so that's a design user interface
design issue for example
for example if i'm working on html so
what do you want
what do i want when there is no
text selection
let's say work on the
i think current line is a
good default okay so okay let's
let's decide okay so let's start to
write a documentation
replace slash
by backslash on
current line or region okay
so when there is no region you just work
on the current line okay
now we're gonna modify the code to
accommodate
the new specification okay
so so before we have this this is
assuming we have a region now
now now if there's no region
if active
uh okay
region active p so if region
is active then you do this okay
copy that paste it here uh
predefine the code so if there's a
region
then p1 and p2 positions are region
beginning and region end if there is no
region then what you gonna do
we are going to when there is no region
okay
then easy trivial set
p1 equals to line beginning position
okay fantastic and set p2
to line end position fantastic
prettify the code everything is
fantastic in
soft fly keys and emax mod
you can see i'm using xr emax mod so
all you have to do so you see if your
formatting is screwed up all you have to
do
is press tab
okay it purifies the entire uh
entire you know entire function
okay press tab you see you can see
tab emac is complete or
indent
you see because for example if i if i
type d
here uh
okay let's say d e okay then i press tab
then it's completion okay you don't need
extra packages everything is built in
emacs when you use x
emacs list mod
so you can use you can see i press the
tab you can
have uh let's say def
you have you can have all these
functions beginning with df
define var define function prompt define
a brief you know whatever
but if you want to defend you know it's
even
easier you just type d then press space
then you have different then you press
space again
whoo you got the template
it's better than white snippet guys okay
okay that's uh so okay now now we are
our function is done
evaluated now tested okay so now again
move the cursor here and call it
exact to backslash do it fantastic
it worked now now what if there are two
lines now
what if there's a selection so let's say
you just want to
let's say i just want to i just want
this part to
to to replace okay call it again
do it fantastic so
past unit test unit test passed
okay so now is our code code okay so
uh delete that and copy it back to
startup show page
move the cursor here paste it show in
browser
fantastic now press the button
to syntax color in html show in browser
fantastic we are done with this code now
there's not there's more to do so
any comments no comment well most
language okay windows backslashes are a
real pain in the ass
in most programming languages
unfortunate design
that's true but however before you start
to hate windows let me tell you
you know let me tell you that that
um that perspective how window
backslashes is a pain in the ass
is from the unix perspective
the unix [ __ ] it up in the first place
actually that's not true
you know so we have the question you
know we have a file path
file path or url path you know look at
the url path
you know so there all you know the
separator is the
backslash but you have to wonder
why is backslash you know why why you
know because
is that a good design you know you have
to think about that
you know if you assume the backslash is
the white
the right way of course the window
[ __ ] it up microsoft
[ __ ] they [ __ ] it up you know
they make everything painful they are
trying to do their own ways
always but why is why is slash
the the you know the proper way is it
true
you haven't thought about it let me tell
you
so if you actually think about it the
slash
is actually the inferior design the [ __ ]
the unix
[ __ ] okay the slash is the infuse
your design
why because when you want the
separators for the path or directory or
folders you know
uh you want to think about that's take a
geekers
in society wanted to do that because
average people mom and pop
you know they write novels they write
fictions they write
you know something this
that okay they you know they slash is
a common slash is the more
frequently used character
in human languages than backslash
okay you got that so normally when
people write you know you you want the
stash you don't want
you know you want this you want you need
to use the slash
for example in file names you know today
in unix for example you cannot
have a slash in file names if [ __ ] [ __ ]
things up you can technically
but you then you have to escape and all
that okay but
anyway the point is that for most people
the slash
is the character you want okay so but
for the tech
geekers the programmers the hackers the
c
c plus plus idiots you know they
are like one percent of society
0.11 you know programmers you know
engineers they are not
their need should not be should not have
priority
over the mass people the people who use
computers
so if you want to design the
separator for the for the past separator
it should be you know you you probably
uh the backstash
is probably a superior choice
okay you know something like that
you want to think about these okay so
you want to
basically you have to think about that
on the mac okay let me tell you
apple computers mac they have the best
design
since the beginning on the mac
the the the separate mac os
mac os uh classic okay that's a 1990s
smack os okay
the separator is the colon okay
for uh let me show you okay so on the
mac this is the
separator okay so on the
mag the path separator
is the colon
okay that that's mango is classic
uh but since mac os x you know the
unix-based
you know the unix-based thing since 2002
they
changed that but however it's not simple
you know
you see let me tell you about history
okay so
in 2002 mac os 10
come out the mac osx you know
so they they say they adopted
the you know the industrial solid
industrial standard unix
[Laughter]
that's the marketing you know that's the
mac marketing
thing so there's a databa basically they
adopted
the um the bsd micro
kernel the operating system okay so
and they also adopted they didn't adopt
the file system
but however they adopted the
kernel okay let me show you some uh
let's search for
unix pestilence okay so we start to
digress into some of the interesting
things kind of depending on what your
uh so any questions comments
no questions okay so so let's look at
the unix pistons we talked about this
uh a few times let's turn on javascript
turn on so you can see unix pestilence
star talk show the unix pestilence
that had that damaged in computing
industry for
uh in a perpetual way
uh perpetual damage you know
pervasive damage to the computing
industry unix
okay so so what i want to show you
now is the some history about mac os
x okay so you can see freebsd
i love this uh you know this artwork
freebsd you know so apple here's the
apple logo back in
1990s uh
and you know and mac osx then mac os 10
came out 2002 and there here is a poem
let me read it out for to you mac os
x one of those unix beauty and beasts
now unix complex i love
map i love apple os i
hate all unix now with
s x love hate a miss
the sea of fanatics unisys
and open source beavers
and butt heads making all the noises
yeah that's back then when mac os 10
came out and all the people like you
guys
need to talk about izmigos x unix
or you know you know then think
different
voices clamoring all over places
beauty and eunuchs mary's in peace
now you you remember think different
you may not remember the you know the
time goes on as i get old
soon about to die you don't remember
things but you know
history you hear history from old people
from your granddad okay
so here is um think different do you
know what is think different
so that's a that's a big thing okay so
let's we
for this we need to go to arts
okay again turn on javascript
arts goes in the shell and stuff in some
arts
and we go to humor
okay so you go to humor then you
have several interesting things and
let's look at this
uh this this motorola commercial
marks apple 1984 okay so
very interesting okay so you might check
it out i'm not going to go through
now here's 1984 apple's commercial
okay so here's 1984 apple's commercial
let me show you some interesting things
okay let's go to the iconic moment
where she a female that's important by
the way
if it's a male it doesn't work the whole
the whole um movie
the whole uh
how do you say movie scripture or
whatever the whole thing
must be a female okay girls
like this connects to how i talked about
why girls is
everywhere get girl is the most
important thing in humanity and
anyway so here is your girl throwing a
hammer
and smashing this head this head is
supposed to be microsoft
now this is 30 years ago 1984 okay
1984 commercial you know big in you know
this this commercial is in the marketing
community which you are not in okay but
you are if you are marketing you
if you are a salesperson you know you
have to study
you know salesperson in their community
they have their own jargons and stuff
so this commercial is considered one of
the most
successful marketing uh
you know marketing material the tactics
or whatever
anyway so then then apple becomes
you know then motorola makes fun of
apple so
you know so we have the apple world
everyone is on the
apple ipad iphone i had you know i had
said whatever and again girls okay
so again let me mention you see you see
another
beautiful girl uh which is the main
you know part of the men actually the
main
point or uh thing of the video without
her
the entire video collapse collapsed
okay so this guy is trying to send her a
flower
okay so anyway so this is motorola uh
you know this is this is uh 2011 10
years ago
motorola making fun of apple okay but
now the point i want to show is the
thing different
think different i don't have a i don't
have a uh article about that but if you
search
you'll know what i'm talking about
okay yeah xerox park okay so so
let me go back to uh what we were
talking about think different
voices okay so then
the poem my poem in my dream os
there is no unix beauty and elegance
without phonetics okay that's 2002
the poem i wrote about mac os 10
and again in about five years ago mac
apple dropped the x now it's just mac os
again
so anyway so in 2002 apple adopted
the you know actually there's another
thing i want to show you the funny uh
here okay
so apple you know made this ad
sends other unix boxes to dev new back
in 2000
uh 2002 all the magazines
so here is my the screenshot of my mac
in 2003 okay so you can see it's running
you know you have the top you have the
other unix commands
so again it's borrowed from the bsd
kernel okay
and associated tools such as the
t-shirt tc shell okay in the beginning
apple is
using tc which is from bsd people you
know which is a
xiao based on the c language
c you know c and unix they both strap
each other
shout out then then tc xiao got dropped
then bash become
became the default uh shell because
tc shot sucks okay bash becomes the
default shell
on apple mac then about
five years ago or three or four
bash is good now the default shell is um
the default shell is tc xiao again i
think
is that right am i oh my i forgot you
know
look up wikipedia you're fine why
because spash
because bash belongs to gnu the gnu
let me show you another thing okay
so emacs so you go to in my emacs blog
i have a later latest entry
uh this gnu pepe i love this artwork
no that's so cool okay you know the gnu
is not unix
remember now you have to remember
history okay remember who is your dad
remember your ancestors please pay
respect
so gnu the you know why is it
what does gnu mean you know the free
software foundation project name the gnu
what is what does that mean well it
stands for
you know the hacker edc so-called
recursive acronym
which is one of the hackers idiocy
because
recursive acronym does not exist
in english literature it is
created invented by the hacker idiots
you know they think they are shakespeare
so they
you know created recursive acronym and
php
you know pretty home page long story
they also adopted you know recursive oh
php
is a recursive acronym php stand for
php hypertext processor
recursive acronym okay loved by hackers
over the you know
they think they are doing uh shakespeare
but anyway
gnu is a recursive acronym so what but
what does it stand for
it stands for gnu is not unix okay
now remember this is important gnu
is not [ __ ] unix okay that's what
they stand for
so most people you know today's young
people you you
oh oh gnu free software the nation yeah
they support unix
no gunu the original the the
the birth of gnu is gnu is not [ __ ]
unix
[ __ ] unix okay gnu is lisp
philosophy wise okay so
and and and and you may not know what is
you know unix uh okay so let's go back
uh lots of history here
so you may not know what is unix unix is
a commercial entity
just like microsoft and google today now
you're looking at history you know free
the berkeley you know
uh so you so you can see these comics
this this is the
you know kind of history of uh bsd
freebsd okay
so what are they doing they are poking
dots
you know dorsis micro bio gates dots
and they are poking this thing what what
is this thing that's a t
and t okay that's the that's the empire
that's the phone you are using the phone
networks
so gnu is not unix okay remember the
name gnu is not unix it's not unix
philosophy
[ __ ] gnu is not emacs is not
okay but today you don't know you think
oh open source free software they are
they they are friends and the gnu and
eunuchs are friends
[ __ ] idiots okay so
so and pretty girls of course i love
them
and unix is okay so back to uh what we
were talking about
the the um we were talking about yeah
mac os 10 you know they adopted bsd
right they adopted bsd kernel
but they got a problem they got a
problem because on the mac
you know you you need certain backward
compatibility on the mac
the separator is the colon okay
the the you know the file separator is
the colon it's not the slash
so there are a lot of file names folder
names
they have slash in them but now you are
switch
switching to the unix kernel and
switching to the unix shell
then you have the you have you got a
problem because
lots of file names existing file names
for 10 over 10 years they
they are using they have slash in their
path
then but and oh but on the other hand
the unix
you know the tcl they they they
you know the slash is a firepath
separator so what you're gonna do
you you you got a problem so the mac
people they do engineering they do great
they do they did a lot engineering so
that on the mac
file system
such that the result the consequence is
that
you can still use you know the colon
is still the firepass separator
but however underneath so basically they
created a layer
so underneath you are using
a slash but uh
but the colon is still the file
separator okay
for file names so anyway so
you know you can look up wikipedia you
can you can
you can find what i'm talking about uh
somewhere in wikipedia okay so anyway we
did this
uh so let's go back to talk show uh go
back to talk show show in browser okay
let's paste we
something we talked about okay uh
we talked about let's see
find replay stream buffer okay so we
talked about that
we talked about uh okay so we talked
about
unix pestilence the history of mac os
x paste it here
then we talked about the this funny ad
this this uh significa
well kind of significant ad for the
apple
okay and we talked about the apple 1984
commercial and motorola making fun of it
so why is this
this is interesting because it
captures you know illustrate history
because in 1984
you know the people you you know most of
us we
our conception is that microsoft biogas
is the evil empire
and uh but now after 20 years
apple apple is considered the evil
empire
uh you know okay
so that's why that's uh some of the
interesting things
then gnu pepe okay so that's also
interesting artwork artwork
wise and also gnu um
you know the the history of gnu the
naming of the
the gnu okay so we also talked about
the mag separator okay let's just let's
just copy that
okay show in browser okay uh
what's okay no comment
so yeah so back to you know i'm kind of
replying to your comment about slash
versus backslash
so slash you know again i despise
the unix and see people because
has anyone let me ask you guys the
question has anyone
ever looked into or thought about
why did unix you know
the people use slash you know
i actually i haven't thought about it
myself
but i've thought about many many of
such design issues of the unix or c
and for my experience of looking into
them
the question usually is there's no
reason
okay it just happened to be because they
thought it
it works it works that's what
many designs and in unix and see
is like that it just worked you know it
just happened you know
i'm a programmer you know there's a
slash character on the keyboard it's
easy to type
then it's not used you know let's just
use that
that's the you know lots of the design
stories of the unix and c
idiots they have no design that's why
despite
unix in c okay so that's one of the
uh so that's one the slash in backslash
so
about which one should it be okay i have
actually quite a lot
articles related you know naming you
know allowed characters in file
names on unix and why
and on apple okay let's skip that so
so we have written this code on emacs
you know we just really
created the command actually we need
another command we need
another command to replace backslash
two slash
okay and actually we need two more
commands okay let me show you okay let
me let me explain
you you all know why okay so
okay so we have one command we need two
more commands okay so let me
write write down okay
so slash to double backslash we also
need that why do you need that because
then we also need a double backslash two
slash okay
uh
yeah we also need do these two commands
double backslash two slash
why because on windows
okay let me explain okay so so
so um um
you know basically in emacs you when you
have
a backslash okay so let me show you okay
so here is a slash
uh let's make it backslash so okay so
you have a file path
that's uh backslash so this works in
powershell for example
so let's go to for example let's copy
that
let's switch to powershell that's cd
to you know backslash backslash okay
let's cd to that directory
it works okay let's okay let's let's cd
to some other directory first
then cd to the directory we want with a
backslash okay it works but however if
you are coding
in emac list if you are for example you
want to launch
you know you are coding a command to
launch [ __ ]
okay or whatever you need you know you
need file path
but in emacs string this doesn't work
you see because english you know emacly
string
backslash is a escape character so to
represent this
you know backslash path
if you want to pass if you want to pass
this path into powershell
you actually need double backslash
so you need like that
okay so what the you see that
you see the syntax coloring is already
[ __ ] up you see
so you need to so you know this actually
[ __ ] up synthetic screen
for the whole shell for for the whole
buffer you see because that's
because you know when you have one
single backslash that's mean
means escape it [ __ ] it up so you
actually need this
okay so so that is that is why
you need these uh two more commands
okay let's just write it quickly okay so
copy it
paste it delete that let's uh
post it here shrink okay and show the
pink window
then shrink a little bit so we have a
new command so this is a slash to
double backslash okay so now we need to
slash two double backslash so double
backslash is now
eight backslashes
[Laughter]
you see the toothpick syndrome
this is called truth peak syndrome by
the hackers okay
so i have an article on that so it can
get quite uh dramatic you know so
so we are seeing you know in a practical
you know
we are seeing eight backslashes but
there's
situations where you need more there's a
record
you know so you can see here you have 10
back slashes okay
then on this file this file is part of
emacs okay this file you can go
you know check it out this one is got 17
backslashes
hey you know so okay so the
e magnus toothpick syndrome now
hackers call this toothpick syndrome but
the millennial generations you guys
don't know
okay let me write it down so that's
another thing we talked about
toothpick syndrome okay showing browser
there it is okay
close that close that so we just created
this command
let's test if this works okay so we're
gonna
evaluate the buffer so we have uh so we
eval the buffer
and we paste uh
you know we okay open a new buffer we
paste it here
magnify then we call the command let's
see if it works
so slash
two double backslash do it fantastic
okay
it worked okay close that then
we also need another command let's copy
it
we also need that another command that's
a double back
backstash two stash okay
okay so double backslash two slash so
we gonna so we're gonna modify
here that's double backslash
okay and here slash okay
uh we don't need that let's purify the
code
okay let's so we have one command
two command
then three command okay evaluate the
buffer
then so this is double backslash two
slash
okay now open a new buffer magnify
so first of all we call slash two double
slash
okay fantastic now we call
double slash
two backslash i mean double backslash
two slash let's see
do it fantastic so
now we have written three commands
delete it and copy it and back to
star talk show open it and
paste it here showing browser back to
emacs
clarify it showing browser fantastic
three commands complete okay
anything else
looks like that's it for today
so we talked for one hour
yes we talked for one hour uh
and anything else okay
okay so if you like my stuff go by
go buy my emacs tutorial okay so you
have
so you can go here and you can find
you go to e-max this tutorial and you
click to buy paypal patreon me
patreon me amazon keep called me or buy
my
tutorial okay
okay that's it let's see what else so we
talked about an hour what else
now
okay uh that's it for today i guess
uh
is there something other
do you use layers on your keyboard no i
don't use
layers well actually i do you know
so so my keyboard
uh not really so
so okay so let me is keyboard time so
again let me show you so this is my
keyboard
so this is kinesis advantage 2
with silent cherry
red switches okay linear
light this is ultimate hacking keyboard
i showed you many times
it's using using it as a keyboard macro
uh marker pad okay so
so do i use layers uh basically no
because i talked about i hate you know
never
you know you never have like coded keys
control alt method you know crap
you want to avoid that as much as
possible
if if if you already have repetitive
strain injury
you know your hand pan i talked about or
if you type a lot and what do you mean
by a lot you know if you're a programmer
you might think oh i type a lot
no you don't because you have to key
lock okay
so let's so let me talk about um
i'll go keyboard so that's my uh so
this is so that's my review you can go
read
and or buy on amazon for my link
please and uh
and yeah so basically i don't have any
layers
except actually i do except when i hold
down the
end key so let me show you okay so let's
let's start vs code okay so for example
so showing browser emacs keyboard block
back to this page back to emacs now
yes code open vs code do it
so we are looking at the same page close
that
so this is my keyboard blog in vs code
so
actually i can type something here uh
you know i don't use vs code actually so
let's types here so let's
for example so if i want to type numbers
you know numbers usually you use the
number row on top
but however on the kinesis i can hold
down the
end key
hold down the end key which is
which is the thumb key here so hold down
the end key and my right hand becomes
number pad so one two three
four five six actually so actually so
let me show you
so can you see
okay so okay so i need to show this
window
so you can look at number there and you
see
so i hold down this end key you cannot
see but it's right on the left side so i
hold it down so
i can type one two three four five six
seven eight nine so that's about the
only layer i use
and this is actually pretty convenient
this is more convenient
than the the number row on top
okay that's it thank you guys for
watching
bye have a good day until next time
back to emacs
now back to uh back to emacs so you see
on the vs code now did i save
uh no i didn't save so let's save it
so once you save it you can see it's
updated in emacs because you have
revert buffer mod on something like that
okay but we don't need that delete that
back to your esco you see
vs code also automatically update
so okay close vs code so yeah i know
you know you don't using its code
control control q
for exit right no
wait file oh
these states they don't you know
normally the standard key
to quit is control cue
but these days they don't do that
sometimes you know beginning with google
chrome
they made it so that it becomes
ctrl shift q and
in vs code they removed that
shortcut entirely you don't have control
q so you just
you know exit
yeah okay bye