hello welcome to another episode of song
talk show
so today we are going to cover wufang
language this is a tutorial from the
ground up on wolfram language or
mathematica this is a continuation from
yesterday
from yesterday's um
live stream
so video check audio check so good
morning clatterland
talent talent kegma okay so
wufang language from the ground up for
programmers so it would be great if you
have some experience with programming
with python php javascript golan go
golan or any any other
so if you have some experience for
programming this is for you this is uh
but you never used language before and
you never used mathematica before so
this is for you i'm not going to cover
not
calculus derivative equations
differential equations you know linear
algebra number theory those are things
used by scientists often mathematician
scientists engineers who use wolfram
language mathematica the most often
that's those things but that's not what
i'm going to teach you i'm going to
teach you the programming aspect okay so
if you're a programmer especially you
industrial programmers working with you
know web
web dev or you know
drivers linux you know that this is for
you because wufang language is very
different
from all the industrial languages ufam
language is a term rewriting system okay
so this is continuation from yesterday
good morning so
let me first of all tell you repeat you
know you can go to um let me show you
okay so sardi
will friend
land okay so just kasady wu from land
search it you will find it my tutorial
i've done
uh okay so go to the topham language
i've done so many videos in the past you
can see on graphics on
this is
these graphics in particular i'm very
proud of this is a geometry
visualization of a uh
decorative pattern yeah so anyway um
language i've done many videos you know
over 10 before but
today is ground up okay
so um
so first of all download okay so you go
that you go here and you download it
from the wufan developer okay and uh let
me explain again what's the difference
who from engine from script and
mathematica so wolfram engine
you download it free
uh it's a compiler it's basically the
compiler and wolfram script is the uh
user the
con command line interface
so let me demo something different from
yesterday okay uh
this is going to be about an hour 50
minutes or something so
uh
input one uh so let's do something okay
so let's let's say
nest we want a
nester function
f applied to x three times okay
so you know that's that's recursion okay
you don't have this feature in all the
even functional languages i don't think
you even have it in haskell or lisp so
this is how you can do recursion using a
function to do recursion instead of the
function calling itself you know you
simply call the next function
and you can also do
for example next list
which shows you all the history you
create a list of the nesting so
no nesting x then first nesting fx then
ffx then fffx so nest list very useful
so let me show you something very
interesting so you are looking at uh the
wolfram script which is the interface to
the wolfram language so wolfram script
whenever you evaluate something it sends
sensor expression to the wolfram engine
so when you download the oofam engine 3
it comes with script okay so we'll find
script is a command command line
interface so let me show you something
interesting so let's define f
to be a function okay so let me type the
whole thing so actually let me type in
in emacs so because i have wolfram uh
woofer mod which allows me to type
things much simpler much easier so
so let's define a function let's magnify
okay
function
2b
okay completion
x
we want the function to be 1 over
square root of
x
squared plus one okay that's the
expression
so copy that and go back to the wolfram
script paste it here
so we define the function you see it uh
formatted in ascii way so now
let's do the
nest again
three times so you see you get this
kind of like continued fraction you know
and now so this is a this is a demo of
the wolfram script
command line interface okay now let's do
um
now let's go to the wolfram
desktop
i recommend you buy it so now i'm going
to show you the
notebook interface which is a graphical
interface okay we are going to uh do
exactly the same thing uh so
first of all let me copy this here
so that we can
okay so delete that so let's so this is
today's talk show this i'm in emacs
and let's create a wolfram line
code and so here is our code we delete
output
delete the
output okay so
what is this yeah delete output and
delete all this input
so now let's show you in the front end
okay so nesting a function next list
and
now let's do it again just show the
nesting
nest okay a function nested because
recursion three times
and now let's define the function
function equals to one over square root
of x squared plus one okay we define the
function now let's
let's do the nest again so
you see so this is the
you can compare this is the graphical
user interface you got this nice type
setting and compared to these uh
wolfram script
command line interface
now when you when you download wolfram
free okay let's go to download wolfram
free when you download wolfram free you
get the wolfram engine which is the
compiler required for you know either
the notebook or the
or the woofing script you also get
woofen script free which you can use
here but you don't have the notebook
okay you don't have this
you know if you want this graphical user
interface the wolfram notebook you have
to
either buy it or
or buy the buy a raspberry pi it comes
with it wolfen
mathematica come with it free
so
so that's about the wolfram engine which
is the compiler then the
front end the notebook which is a
graphical user interface and you can
also do graphics fantastic okay so
such as we
have shown before you know you can
rotate it and so on interactively
so front end and woofing script okay so
now let's exit wolfram script let me
again show you my uh wolfram uh
xl wolfen mod okay so we can evaluate
this in here
so let's see
you know evaluate it
okay so here is the output you can see
let's see
you can see we defined the function
there it's magnified and then here's the
here here is the output of
uh
wait what
yeah so you see you in in
so you are looking at
some fan mod okay so here's the output
it doesn't do
these
ascii type settings it doesn't do
typesetting it rather it returns the
expression like
you know pure ascii
so this is this is uh someone find mod
okay so let me show you
okay you can see the source code so this
is uh you know the emac this source code
for subwoofer mod and it's about 2050
2500 lines and mostly it's the wolfram
functions you know um let me show you
so lots of code but a lot of it is the
uh you know these are wolfram
language functions there are by default
7 000 of them
so you can see and you can get this for
free here is on github so let's open my
uh website for example mod and you can
download it on
github
okay so
show javascript to turn on javascript so
okay so that's
my mod that allows you to
code ufam language in emacs which is
very convenient so and i'm using stuff
like keys
uh which is you know and the ping window
shows all the command cores i do and the
keystroke i use okay so that's the
wolfram engine the wolfram script the
wolfram notebook you know let's get you
started you can start to uh play with
wufang language now let's continue on
the tutorial the actual starting to
let's continue start to uh teach you
about wuffan language so
everything i talked today is already i
have a tutorial you know i already
written up so if you prefer reading it
you can just follow through you know my
website string okay so let's begin on
wufang language okay any comments and
questions you uh posted here
okay couldn't run raspberry in your
virtual machine
you know if you download the raspberry
version i believe you are limited you
can only run wufang language on the
machine on the raspberry machine you
cannot
you know kind of cheat you know buy a
raspberry pi have the wolfram language
free but then you run it on your pc with
which is much more powerful cpu i don't
think you can do that
um
so anyway so you know i recommend just
buy it because um
you know i've been working with language
since 1993
1993 yes and uh then i got to work at
woofan
uh research in 1995 for half a year uh
anyway
so let's begin okay so uh so so we have
uh demonstrated wolfram language so let
the first of all continue from yesterday
everything when you want the stream
string is uh created by double straight
quote okay nothing else not like python
or you know you cannot use single quote
you cannot use triple quote or whatever
just single double quote okay and if you
want to escape
if you want to create a double quote you
say backslash quote
okay
so that's string and yesterday we
covered everyth
in language everything is a function
okay now now let me show you let me um
everything is a function so
everything you ever wanted to do us uh
to to to
to operate on string is all function so
let's let's show again string
length okay for example here
it gives you the length of string how
many characters in here
okay so
now look at this form okay
everything you ever wanted to do
anything
the entire wolfram language is always
just a function call okay there's no
class concept there's no object concept
there's no reference concept there is no
special
um
no no no object no no abstract class no
no static you know no member member of a
class no uh you know cons no constant
concept nothing okay everything in
language is just expression and the way
you do computation with expression is
you call a function like this so
everything now this is important this is
a
fundamental principle of wufan language
anything everything you want to do is
just f function name something
argument okay and if you have two
arguments separated by a comma okay
anything and everything okay this is all
so this is the main topic today list and
expressions in language okay
so for uh for example you can see
tutorial expression uh list and
expression okay so all this section
list creating a list position in a list
you know like the index of array you
know in other languages you call it
array index position of the list
get elements how do you how do you get
you know extract sublist and things like
that how do you add element append
prepend insert you know in java in
javascript for example you have splice
uh you have various different different
names in python you have you know you
have anyway so
list how do you delete the element how
do you change elements so everything
this is what i'm trying to say
everything in language is always
have the syntax
f something
and arguments okay so
it doesn't matter if you want to work on
string or if you want to work on some
something it's always just a function
it's always have this form okay
okay so that's one thing so this is this
is a
systematic you know a systematic grammar
a systematic syntax so there's no
special you know there's no
you have to create a class then you can
create an object out of that class then
when you define a class then you can
have inheritance you know when you have
a class then you have to define
members private or something or you can
define a method which is
you can only call a method
from the class
but first of all you have to create an
object then you can have code method but
you can also have static method which is
like a function so very complex you know
oop which is the case in java
python javascript at least and and also
ruby
so in and also php in all these
languages
you have these um you know kind of very
complex ideas they have relations to
each other but in wolfen language
there's nothing like that okay
everything is an expression three
is an expression okay a string
is an expression okay those are called
atomic expressions because they are like
you cannot take them apart then
you build other expressions by having a
function like a list okay so wolfen
language is basically mainly derived
from lisp programming language and apl
okay i'm not going to explain apr but
basically like lisp okay so everything
is at least like this but if uh
it uses a different syntax from the this
parenthesis okay so everything is just a
lisp at least like that okay it's called
expression
it's actually called you know so and so
everything is at least
that's uh you know there's no
class in in references or whatever
okay that's one thing so the one of the
advantage of this is that if you know
all the functions
names are fully spelled out so for
example you can you can call this
function names and give a string a while
card so and type string
and that will return
all functions in language
whose name contains the word string
and this is important because anything
everything you want to do with stream
is by calling a function and that
function will contain a word stream so
all you have to do is get you know find
which one function you need you know
including regular expression
pattern matching for for strings uh you
know find the function you need so this
applies to the whole language doesn't
you know so
so in other things like um
so anyway anyway so uh so this is
uh the advantage allows you to find all
the functions easy you don't have to
worry about what's special you know the
the semantics of the language is very
simple just everything is a expression
and you call function on it to change to
get a new value that's how you do
computation
okay so let me get on so let's not let's
get on uh fast okay so they move uh it's
already 20 minutes so
okay so function names everything is
expression then you have you know your
core function to do things then let me
tell you about um
[Music]
shortcut syntax okay why because
when you have everything in the form
you know if everything is just a
function name like that sometimes it's
cumbersome to write it for example in
this
so let's go to wufang language mod okay
for example my source code for wolfram
language mod
so you can see
uh let's go let's go up
you know so you see you have lots of
this nesting that's lisp you know so in
the same way in
exactly the same way in the wolfen
language you're gonna start to have lots
of nesting you know some you know
nesting is not necessarily good because
it's hard to read so movement language
has the concept of
shortcut syntax okay so let me show you
shortcut syntax uh so
shortcut syntax so let me show you where
okay so this is um
this is a principle of fulfillment
language okay so symbols uh not here
syntax okay so i did a video dedicated
to that topic you can uh in particular
in comparison to lisp okay so for
example you can see
you can see this expression
let's magnify okay
let's magnify
so you can see this expression now
one thing to note is that everything is
just nested okay so in in fact we can
evaluate this okay so they copy it let's
go here let's paste it there you know
all you see is the function name for
example the function name here then
followed by
its argument so this compound expression
takes two arguments this is the first
one said something this is the second
one then the first argument is again f
something bracket then it takes several
arguments so the first one is some c
array so this is another argument
coordinate bounds array
then this function takes
two arguments one is the least nested
list and the other one is uh into okay
so you can the point here is that see
the nesting okay you are seeing the
nesting so let's evaluate this
so this
that code returns this thing okay
now there's a shortcut
so
the code we just evaluated is exactly
syntactically equivalent to this
okay so you can see in this form it's
much more easier to read
okay so it's evaluated it returns
exactly the same thing
so you can so you so you are wondering
so what's going on what so
so so remember so let me explain this
quickly so everything remember
everything
is in this form okay however
um
wait oh yeah we defined f we want to
clear f because we defined f before
so now we clear clearly have fabc so
everything is in this form
right but however
because then then your your source code
is going to be lots of this nesting hard
to read so some so many of the commonly
used functions has a shortcut for
example plus
plus 3 4 okay
that's the full syntax called full form
however this for plus for this function
plus there's a shortcut syntax so you
can do three four three plus four okay
same thing with list okay so list
z
y okay that's a list of two items that's
the you know full form
but you but
there's a shortcut for least so you can
write it this way okay that's another
example same thing with multiplication
okay so for example times that's
multiplication
three four
okay 12.
another way to write it is just three
star four okay in fact if
between you can use use a space you can
you know you you can just type a space
for it automatically adds this grayed
out
course
stand for you know it it's trying to
tell you there's an implicit
multiplication okay
so anyway so
the point to remember here is that every
expression is you know function followed
by something however for some of the
functions some of the commonly used
functions such as plus
list
times and many others there are about
maybe maybe 100 of them 50 of them
there's a shortcut syntax corresponding
to the full form so
so that's why
so that's why you see
here you know this
let me let me delete this output
so that's why
this part
is exactly equivalent to that part
now another important thing to know is
that when you evaluate wolfram language
whenever you use the shortcut form for
example here's a here is a nested this
the compiler the first thing the
compiler will do is actually translate
transform this shortcut into the full
form so you are looking at this nested
list you know negative one one negative
one one
the full form is here okay
you see so that's what the compiler do
so it will whatever shortcut you typed
it will first of all translate
internally transform it to the full form
then it does computation so in other
words
unlike many other languages you have
so-called sugar syntax okay meaning that
you can type this way it kind of
equivalent to another way
but in the wolfram language case they
are exactly equal equivalent 100
so this is not just a you know short you
know
syntax sugar it's
equivalent
because the wolfram language transformed
this shortcut into the full form first
so you know in other words
you want when you um program wolfram
language
uh you want to
think of this way so you you want to
think of everything as the full form
because that is the real thing wolfram
computes the shortcut syntax is just for
for visual uh easier understanding and
uh
things like that what actually matters
is the full form this is important
because when you start to get into
advanced programming like pattern
matching it's always done with a full
form okay it's
like when you want to
match your pattern like three times
something
you know and things can be symbolic okay
so for example let me show you
times
x y
you know it just returns x y
that's symbolic you cannot do this with
most languages most other languages it
will tell you oh x is not defined y is
not defined you cannot multiply them but
but in language because it's symbolic
you can now this is also symbolic but
however this doesn't go all the way so
if in this you say x times y
it'll give you an error saying that x is
not defined
you know so that's some technical detail
let me show you okay
so
emac be smart so for example
uh let's magnify so times 3 4 so
evaluate okay so evaluate it so you can
see the output is here 12
right but if you say
evaluate x y
you see error you see debugger entered
error avoid variable x okay
so
uh
okay so but if what if you quote it so
for example let's try this uh let's try
this this way
you still get error you see wrong type
of argument number or marker p
so
so even in the
so even lisp is also symbolic but it
doesn't go all the way so uufam language
can
so let's let me show you talk about
pattern matching a little bit let me i
mean let me show you the power i mean
what what what's the deal
what is the advantage of this you know
symbol thing
so for example let me show you a pattern
matching for example we have done
let's start with script okay
and we have done
let's copy that let's put that to um
okay so
let me go
hold on a second okay
let me uh
get to my let me log to what we talked
about
okay so let me log what we talked about
so today's talk show we talked about um
some of that
and uh
no we i want to demonstrate symbolic
pattern matching the power of pattern
matching okay
so that that uh so
so okay hold on a second
close that uh
we'll find mod okay i want to show you
wolfie mod
close that
page
paste it
here because i will find mod so you can
have a link to it okay so let me
demonstrate symbolic pattern matching
okay so first of all let's um
let's um
copy that okay
and paste it here
paste anyway yeah
so evaluate so you get you get the list
okay so let's do it let's do list
okay so you get the expression next
nested f
uh
and this is a bug i think there's a bug
when you try to copy paste it
things got get screwed up
so exit you type exit to exit net start
again
so copy that
okay magnify
and we want uh
we want to nest it okay
paste it okay we define the function
uh it's still screwed up
okay we let's start a new
um
new terminal
now i wonder if it's because the bug
came from
i wonder if the book came from the
windows terminal or powershell
terminal right now okay so let's switch
to using the powershell terminal
because
the powershell console because i was
using the
okay so let's not get distracted uh okay
okay if you are using the powershell
that you know the windows command exe it
doesn't even you can you cannot even
post yeah okay let's get back to
using the microsoft windows terminal
okay let's start it
copy it
paste it
okay now it's it's correct
now let's nest this function
yeah i don't want that
and paste it anyway
what
i don't want paste lines okay there it
is
i think what happens is that if you
paste something that contains line
return you'll screw up things okay so
now you see we got the expression now
let you know let let's evaluate this in
um
in the
emacs mod i mean
fan mod okay so let's do it again let's
do it again
okay so evaluate it
yeah i need to got too much
um
well it won't let me unless i exit here
so
it's kind of painful i don't want to
exit there because it only allows like
one process if you are using the
terminal
something like that so
i can probably fix it because i i have a
you know
you know the proper wolfram desktop
anyway
so what i want to show is that yeah okay
so anyway so what i want to show is that
i what i want to the same the the power
of symbolic pattern imagine okay so
so right now you see this expression
uh square root two
let's see
nested three times let's say nested four
times
copy yet let's do it over here
okay
copy it
wait so there is only one square root i
want what i want is multiple square
roots
okay so we can fix this
so
let's redefine our function to be
let's redefine our function 2b
plus
2 okay
let's redefine our function to be that
then let's compute that
there it is now we got multiple nested
square roots okay
now suppose you want to um you know you
can look so this is a typesetter format
okay now you can look at this in full
form okay so let's
let's um let's
so you can see the actual
expression you see this is the fully
nested syntax so you got power
plus something
plus 2 plus power
you see power over negative one that's
the inversion one over something the
full form is uh let me show you okay
so one over x
you know this is a normal form but if
you do full form
1 over x
it's 1 over 2.
oh that's rational ah wait
i want to do actually
1 over x
you see so that's power
power x raised to negative 1 power
that's math okay that they are
equivalent
so
so so you got this expression you know
you got this nested
square root expression
and the full form
the full form is this thing
and now let's say you want to replace
all the square root by
let's say square to the third power okay
so we can what we can do is that let me
show you
replace all
takes two arguments the first one is the
expression
whatever you want to replace you know
you do replacement
the second one is a rule
let me use the full form so it's easier
to understand so a rule you want to
replace or square root by
by
uh you want to replace all square root
of anything inside let's name it x
you want to replace it
by let's just say y okay
let's do it
oh god it's replay no this is not
correct
um
let's say this okay
okay so
wait
so
what i want to show uh is you want to
replace all square root by let's say
some function f3
okay so
what
this is
we still have square roots
uh why is that
we want to replace or square root by
yeah what's going on
okay am i still is it interesting any
questions
it comes with uh good morning uh wolf um
i see
you won't work because you are trying to
multiply two symbols yes exactly
that's what i'm saying but in wolfen
language you can do that without you
know it just come out symbols
then
okay anyway so
okay so let me demonstrate this okay
this is easy to demonstrate times x y
okay so you see now if you say x equals
to four okay then you re evaluate time x
y
so now it becomes 4y
and if you say y equals to 3
and then you re-evaluate this you got
12. you see that's
that's the symbols you see if a symbol
doesn't have a value it's going to
compute anyway it's just going to return
the symbolic result
so this part is more
advanced than this this doesn't do that
you know you have to your symbols has to
become a value
otherwise it refused to return it
so anyway so that's so this this is a
good
illustration actually about the term
rewriting system so in wolfram language
everything is symbolic it just
it's just an expression like
you know you can almost think of them as
a string it just manipulate transform
the string that's all it you know the
the
terms
okay so so let me go back to this you
know i want to demonstrate this but it
failed
so i want to actually so i want to
replace you know
so you see we got this this thing
which is full uh form
you know which is this i want to replace
this expression by uh
let me do it the normal way okay
the normal way i'm you know the i'm
familiar with
so
square root replace it by oh first of
all we need to clear x and y
because we defined uh
them before so clear x y
then i want to and by the way here's
another advantage of the
of the
notebook
interface because in notebook interface
you can place
expressions anywhere like you can go
edit here and re-evaluate this part you
can go you know and you can see the
history of the whole thing
you know but not in the com command line
interface which the case which is the
case for python for ruby you know for
javascript deno you know you have you
have to
you know each time you only see one part
and you cannot edit arbitrarily you know
so this is the advantage of a notebook
interface so but anyway let's go back to
here i want to show you
uh i want to show you how do you do this
okay so i want to replace square root
the symbol square root by f3
oh yeah that doesn't
oh that's why it doesn't work i know now
i know you see what you see
uh this is actually tricky this is more
advanced you know so this
so i want to replace or square root by
f3 so i i'm expecting a result where all
this square root is just a function
called f3 f3 will do whatever
but it failed you know so why does it
fail because actually
the the square root does not happen
anywhere
you see
but instead you have the power negative
one so power negative one is like the
the inversion one over something and but
uh you have the rational so what
rational stand for so for example this
rational one two is one over two so the
square root actually doesn't happen
anywhere in output
so
so this is important that's why i
mentioned before
when you do computation especially when
you get advanced into pattern matching
you have to know you have to know what
is the actual full form
not not the shortcut expression you know
not not
the shortcut like one plus two uh where
is it
you know all these are shortcut for
example x equals to 4
the full form is actually let me show
you
so full form you call full form you code
hold so it doesn't evaluate then you
give the expression x equals to 4. it's
gonna be set
square bracket something you see
so
so you see
the full syntax the full form may not be
what it seems so this x equals two four
is very convenient very very intuitive
you know x equals to 4 but actually you
have to know when you get advanced
this is important you know so when you
start to learn language make this
try to make these try to understand this
the syntax shortcut is just the visual
syntax shortcut every the real
computation is always done with the
full form so almost by heart you know
once you code wufang language for a year
you will
you will or you should know
uh all the syntax shortcuts what they
actually are so let me show you where is
it
so ufon language tutorial uh go so go to
my tutorial from language basics then
you go down to the
syntax
so you know there's a full video on that
so you can see here is a list of all
basically essentially all possible
syntax shortcuts using wolfram language
and how they correspond to full form for
example
let me show you an example
um
so for example so so for example uh for
example this one question mark a
so what does that mean so you when you
type question mark let's say full form
you know you want to know what does what
this function does
that's that's how you do it it
spit out a helpful information then you
can click on that
uh then it tells you the full detail and
the examples how to use it what does
this function do everything is
functioning from language
so but however you see that question
mark that question mark something that
that is not the format of f something so
actually there's a full form for that
and that is the information so
so the proper way to do this is actually
like this
information okay so complete
then a string full form
you see that's actually that's not
equivalent actually um
some anyway that the the point is that
you know
everything is
in this you know uh
fully function uh form with square
brackets okay so let me get back to so
so that's why here we failed but let's
we can get it to work
uh
so instead of a square root let's
replace uh let's go here okay let's so
we want to replace all the square root
to something else so
so we say let's see
rational rational
power
of power negative two okay so and now i
get it so
so
so square root so so so here is uh
the way to see
why it is wrong why it's not working so
you can say
full
form
square root
of
x
plus one okay
uh actually you have to
let's say hold it's always good to say
hold but otherwise you'll just evaluate
it okay
and that's that still doesn't work
okay
this is not a good example because it
um it's getting too tricky i mean the
the tricky part is that
how does the square root you see
basically what happens is that square
root becomes
part of it becomes rational something
and part of it becomes power something
the reason for that is anyway let me
quickly just get it to work okay let me
quickly get this to work so let me
because because i know how it does
so i want to replace everything power
p o w
e r
power
two parts
x
numerator and y the demanded denominator
okay i want to replace it by function
f 3
whatever that is
and replace it by
x y okay
do it
fantastic wait what
yeah it doesn't work well it doesn't
work because
uh you have to say replace repeated okay
let's try again
yeah now it works okay so
uh
okay so that's getting a little bit
complex the reason it
you see it does not work before it
because it only
replaces one instance okay so let me let
me explain since we are on this let me
explain okay
so replace
okay let me
explain the whole thing again so we are
doing
replace
the expression
by a rule and this rule is
this rule is
power
okay whenever you see power replace
through takes two arguments okay the
first part is what is the pattern okay
i mean the rule takes two arguments
so replace takes two arguments the first
part is the expression the second part
is a list of rules okay or just a single
rule so right now we are using a single
rule and the rule
has two arguments one the first part is
the left hand side what do you want to
replace what what what pattern you want
to match the second part is the actual
the thing you want to what you want to
become okay so the pattern right now we
want to say a pattern the pattern is
power something uh power
two things okay and one thing inside is
x
underscore okay the other thing is y
underscore underscore means anything so
you want to match anything that's power
anything two things inside and you name
it x and y
you name it so that you can put it in
the replacement so for example in the
replacement we can say
g okay so g x y
okay now if we evaluate that you see you
still get
you still get square root here which is
a power something negative 1.
the reason is that
this replace function only does it one
time so you'll find the pattern you'll
replace it and return the result
so
if we want to replace all the square
roots we have to say replace repeated
okay
so this is uh advanced detail of pattern
matching so let me let's do it again
so you can just call replace repeat it
okay there it is
now you can see
why it you know works so
we got into some rather advanced part of
um pattern matching which is not not
planned today i was just planning to go
over lists
um but i was trying to show you some
some power of panda matching um plan
and
got screwed up
and got more and more into detail and
and
so kind of imagine
you can find my tutorial
on here first of all introduction and
then
uh pattern syntax so let me since we're
talking about this let me tell you what
pattern matching is about so
again remember in language everything is
symbols symbolic okay it can be
numerical but it can be symbolic so if
you have numbers it return numerical
results if you have symbols
uh so whatever symbols it returns
symbolic result you know once you have a
value
you know it it it gives you numerical
result what whatever so
symbols everything the symbols all
expressions are symbolic okay
uh
then
symbols okay so
the because language is a term rewriting
system so what does that mean basically
it just the way it computes is that it
replaces a sequence of symbols by some
other which we have seen
you know like this example we have seen
we replaced all the square root by
um
by f3 so this is uh so here it's easier
to see
here
by the way you know if you are wondering
what what are these slash slash dot and
what is arrow those are just syntactical
shortcuts so
slash slash dot
is a
a synthetic shortcut for
replace repeated okay here and that
and that error symbol is a shortcut for
the rule okay so but if we use these
full syntax it's easier to understand
this is not full syntax yet because we
have the underscore
the full syntax for underscore is blank
something but it gets tedious so i'm not
going to go over that but anyway my
point here is that
we demonstrated
symbolic pattern matching replacement
which is a term rewriting system
everything is a symbols we can just
replace it part of it by a pattern okay
including including deeply nested parts
for example if you are gonna do this in
python in javascript in golan you cannot
okay i mean first of all they they don't
deal with symbols so you can have this
you cannot have this g something
you know because you'll just say g is
undefined x is undefined okay
but even if you give them a number so
suppose we replace our g by
we can do that again for example let's
say
g
becomes three okay so
um let me just use the shortcut syntax
okay so you can
so you can so now it's all symbols or
numbers okay
but anyway
even in python if even if the whole
thing is uh just numbers you still
cannot do this replacement because you
can see deeply nested patterns
you know when you have a in python in
javascript in golan in php when you have
a complicated nested
array or list
you want to replace some part of it you
you know you can't just do a pattern
replacement because they they don't
support pad imaging usually i mean even
in haskell i think i'm i'm pretty sure
in haskell because in haskell you know
camo they have had imaging but they
they
do not allow you to do complicated
nested pattern imagine so but in
language you can you can nest you can
nest it you know the the patterns um in
fairly complex complex ways
so one way to think of this term
rewriting system is to compare it to
a string replacement of regular
expression so imagine if you have a
language that all it does is
do string replacement
with regular expression
you know you call some regular
expression you know using a regular
expression pattern and just repeat
and then
uh
so that's
kind of like how what wufam is language
is doing except you are not dealing with
strings you know strings are just flat
usually so you don't
you don't get to nest you know
you know so
string is hard to work with because you
have to quote you know everything
becomes you cannot take them apart but
if you
so the analogous of string is symbols
symbols you know sequence of symbols
and you replace
them by the pattern becomes
a symbol symbolic
pattern syntax
analogous to a regular expression okay
i think that's it for today
so uh yeah so we talked about for
an hour
and that's it for today
uh so we
we went to some
panel matching
and
that's it for today so we're gonna shut
down in two minutes any any more
questions
so
so so we covered um we covered the
expression quite a bit
and
but i didn't show you every you know all
the other things about these distant
expressions many other functions
so at the end let's show you some
something interesting okay
uh
let's say let's use the table example
so we are going to create massively
nested table okay for example
let's this one
let's see that one
okay
yeah okay let me explain table okay so
first of all let's not
you know let's not do this
massive okay so
so table is a function
that takes two arguments
the first argument is the expression the
second argument is a kind of iteration
spec okay so table is lets you generate
a list or nested list arbitrarily nested
list or you can think of it as a
generate a matrix
of any dimension
or tensor okay so the anag
it it is analogous to python's list
comprehension so let me show you an
example
so let's say x okay so generate remember
it generates a list okay so let's say
x one two five
okay very simple
and you can say x plus y
one two five okay and let's say x
squared
plus y
generate one two five now let's say
one two five but in steps of
one half okay
you see
now remember you see you see these
fractions
these are simplified
rationals
so it will automatically simplify for
example if you have 9 over 3
it simply becomes three but if you have
nine over four it's nine over four so if
you have large number let's say
uh two divided by
over
uh that's another another random number
okay it simplifies for you the fraction
and it doesn't become a float you know
in most languages
most of the time you just get a float
but wufang language remember it's
symbolic so that's why it maintains the
form
so in here we did several table examples
let's
now let's
you know the the function can be
arbitrarily complicated for example
times let's say times our function f x
you know remember we defined f before
so now it becomes
that okay
now
you can have multi-dimensional now let's
say
y go y goes from
one to two
now you are getting a matrix okay so
this is becoming very complex
let's simplify okay so let's simplify
let's not get too complex let's just say
x squared plus y
squared and
x goes from one to three y goes from one
to two so this is easier to understand
wait they got the value we want we don't
want the value clear
x and y
okay
and uh
run that
oh yeah they well
yeah they become a value because
obviously we say one plus we we say um
because they evaluate because x is a
number raised to the second power it
becomes a number but let's say let's say
let's give it a symbol okay
n m
okay so that's
that's the
that's the that's a that's a matrix okay
so
yeah okay so
oh we can do it this way
uh what am i trying to show
let's just say x plus y no let's not
let's just say at least x y okay so this
way it
it gives you yeah that's what it's
supposed to be yeah so for each x you go
uh you know you iterate x equals 1 x
equals to 3 x equals truth
2 to 3 then for each y you repeat
so you can show the result let's say xx
equals to
the
that okay you can say matrix
form
okay so it shows you the matrix form you
can also say treeform
okay so it shows you a tree form so
that's that's what's interesting about
this so now let's do a tree form of this
complex thing
this this complex tree so that's you
know that's the power we can magnify
okay so that's it thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff donate
okay go to my patreon my paypal
[Music]
stuff
bye guys
shutting down in a minute
bye