good morning welcome to another episode
of sontar show today is 2000 19th
October 15th Tuesday 10 o'clock a.m. San
Francisco time
good morning DP so so today I've got
several topics to talk about and if you
have questions or topics just type it
okay and let's begin so one of the
things ok let's let's talk about
schedule and it's talk show some talk
show schedule ok so here is my saw talk
show web website page so we were talking
about what scheduled you know am I going
to do a technical topics like Emacs
tutorial programming to a real the
answer is no because after talking to
some people good morning
Kathi after talking to some people on
this code they told me you know
basically you get the general idea how
much you make if you are a youtuber you
do programming tutorials on YouTube now
even if you are extremely popular you do
not make much okay so for example let's
go to let's go to our blog let me show
you so cuz our talk show go to my
website then go to programming then you
see
so there are some interesting so this
guy apparently very popular he's got
nine hundred ninety seven thousand
subscribers so his name is Derrick
banners and apparently he is a very
famous youtuber and what he do is he
teaches programming for example learn
Java in 30 minutes learn Python in one
video learn C++ learn PHP learn game
programming how to make video games you
know so he teach programming and he is
fairly popular
almost 1 million followers and some of
his videos got 5 million views 4 million
views 1 medium use 4 million views and
he only makes you know there's a
estimate on this website this website is
called social blade ok this website you
can find it you know it's called social
blade which give you static statistics
about youtubers how many followers they
have how many videos they have how many
views and about how much money they make
it's kind of estimated but you know
fairly in the ballpark I would say so
for someone like him 1 million
subscribers he only makes estimated $200
to three thousand dollars a month you
know but if you also at the most you
make maybe three thousand dollars a
month but however if you are a
programmer you walk in you know a Google
Facebook or any of the big companies in
in Bay Area you make 10 to 20,000 a
month so you know if you if if you are
YouTube teaching programming you make
$3,000 a month that's a that's the same
amount of money you would make if you
mop toilets at McDonald's
ok minimum wage if you work for minimum
wage in California that's how much you
make - so so making the videos
on YouTube is not a good option okay so
for example I talked about this the
other day about how much you make if you
are a book writer let's see if I have
that linked up no let me just show you
then good morning in bottle knew this
guy teaches programming 3d graphics so
anyway so if we go through let me show
you I talked about this the other day
search for book okay where is it okay so
book so if you are a book writer if you
write the most popular book in
JavaScript you make $10,000 okay you you
it will take you one year to write it
and you make maybe ten thousand dollars
that is if your book is the most popular
JavaScript book so writing books does
not give you any money at all and doing
programming tutorials on YouTube does
not give you any money at all so forget
about that okay so that is a situation
that is a situation and so what am I
going to do so I was you know people
being asking me to do Emacs emag B's
yeah you know because I'm going to paint
over a double to do those and I'll get
allocated like ten dollars a month well
you know a hundred dollars a month
that's you know that's not enough for a
copy or day a coffee a day so I'm not
going to start to dedicate it to do
tutorials on programming you know so my
youtube channel is going to be so far I
see it's going just to be me talking
random things you know it's like me
masturbating okay it's talking about
myself what
I feel like whatever feels good to me
and eventually I might change you know I
might change into talking about current
events currently in current events in
programming community in hacker culture
in emacs community things like that that
in fact has lots more readers at least
I'm not sure I'm going to make any money
on youtube it's not likely so you know
I'll just go it's just going to be
exhaust diatribe Sarlacc cap like Star
Trek Captain's Log so that is my that's
what I'll do I think and ask for time I
think still I haven't decided for time
you know so right now let's just say 10
o clock every day until I change ok so
again you go through my YouTube YouTube
channel then you go to the you go to my
youtube channel and there's a community
tab I should announce it there and
bathroom you join this code I miss you
join this code so we you know we can
have a lot interesting discussions and
also let me ask you like sometimes you
know discussion you know discussion
often when you talk to people often you
just you are focused you are too busy
just expressing your own opinions so
sometimes you you know it so you you
don't get to ask other people's opinions
so I know so so what is your joining my
Debian server ok ok who is your Debian
server yeah so so yeah so let me ask you
so what what is your objection about
this code other than being not open
source like because because sometimes
you know you might have some like
something happened on this code I didn't
know so if you have that those you know
post post your opinions about
like what why do you not like this code
so much but enjoy it anyway doing it
doing it for me you know it's it's fun
yeah so I learned several of these
things things for example I learned from
panel minutes and from from George about
about how much people make on YouTube
you know they told me about this Tarek
guy and also you learned you also
learned on you you damp you dummy okay
this udemy is one of the popular website
that teaches programming fairly popular
you know it's like Can Can Academy since
about seven years ago there are a lot of
these rising up and they actually make a
lot money you see this is a problem you
see this is why I become I I gradually
become you know the open source
community and free software that they
piss me off you know over the past 20
years you know in the beginning I was of
phonetic of Richard Stallman but anyway
they pass they piss me off but more and
more like in the past several months
I've been talking about the evils of
open source you know but the it's like
the more I talk about it the more things
I discovered the Moi's is just
completely at this point I would even
say it's evil ok it's the open source
and free software foundation why let me
tell you about who'd MIT who Tommy ok
woulda me and can kinds Academy okay and
they are several they are quite a lot
they are there is also some I also
mentioned I know them because some six
years ago I actually interviewed what is
another company guys say it there's
another company that does tutorial very
famous I don't think it's odami it's you
know this begin like 10 about 10 years
ago from Stanford University
you know beginning about Kent Academy
that's that that became very popular
about ten years ago then a lot of
companies started to you know open a
company that teaches programming now
these courses of course they are not
free and they are not open source okay
but however they do make money and
people just flock to them that you know
they go through them and study things
you know you pay of course you pay so
the reason is that you know is one of
the issue the reason is that they you
know in our set they make it clear that
they are not you know this is you know
they make it clear what is their
intention just like Apple or Microsoft
you know you go to an Apple store you
already know from the context you know
this is a Creole context you go there
you buy their stuff that is it you know
you go you don't go to Apple store to
talk about Oh philosophy oh I think you
know which is better for Humanity you
don't do that
okay so it's a store Apple Store Apple
Apple company everything they do they
it's it's clear you know from the
context you know the people at Apple set
it up we our store we sell things you
buy it or you don't buy it that's it you
know it's up to you know you do whatever
but but that's what we do
Apple okay so either you know you go to
Apple so you just buy it or you don't
buy you don't go there to think about
philosophy think about you know issues
in the same way these corporations udemy
you know teaching programming or there
are several others can anyone actually
tell mentioned what's the other name
okay woulda me can Academy they are
quite a few kind of you I've you know no
because actually I interviewed with one
of them it's actually nearby here whose
company is also named use something I
think
okay and so I don't remember the name
udemy online course list is just search
online course online programming course
computer programming edex okay I haven't
heard
EDX MIT is also very popular free course
learn programming Allison oh I guess
Allison is new okay
they are fighting Harvard okay this one
from Harvard
kisara yeah this one kisara
okay so I actually interviewed at
Coursera and it's a very it's kind of a
bad experience everything went well you
know I we okay that's another topic but
any anyway let me go back to what I was
talking about the programming courses so
these companies
kisara udemy okay you know you know they
make it clear this is a company you go
there you learn you know you pay and
take a programming course that is it you
know it's not about open source it's not
about community you know what what you
should be doing or whatever so it's
simple you know so this is critical
because this is this this
I studied SEO I studied marketing I
started I study these kind of things how
to become popular these things so one of
the critical thing is that you want to
make your intention clear and that sets
of your who follows you you know that's
a sub who follows you for example like
me you know so I'm this type of guy kind
of non mainstream and in the open source
community and free software community so
I'm this type of guy you know I don't
dress well I'd you know I just talked
about and also many mainstream ideas so
I you know so you come to my talk show
you follow me we it it it it it attracts
the type of people you know that that's
my audience you guys okay in programming
right but you don't come here to think
so so so now if I say oh you know maybe
you should pay me you know donate very
few people do you know like one
typically the number is 1 in 1,000 okay
1000 people watch your show
one of them will maybe donate something
okay typically that's a common that's a
common number when we're not talking
about Google Ads okay that's another
thing with with YouTube Google Ads
basically for each 1000 view you get
between two to four dollars okay
one thousand view two to four dollars so
anyway and also for donation each one
thousand people who subscribe you
basically one of them will donate so you
don't make money and also let me get
back so about open source because
because my context is about the you know
basically mostly open source people UNIX
people you linux people you know this
type of people open source this this
community it's even more hard to get
this community to pay anything I mean
it's even more hard you know like I've
been writing blogs for 20 years there
are a lot people you know actually there
are quite a few who asked me questions
every every month okay for years and you
just answer them and you know they well
they maybe they paid you for your
tutorial 30 dollars you know but but you
know to answer one question you know you
might think oh he you know someone
emailed me I got email you know I got
emails a lot
I stopped answering emails like two
years ago so I got emails you know it
almost every day then people ask you a
question you think oh you just take five
minutes to answer nah that's not true
you know five minutes here five minutes
there you know there are more than one
people of course once you know once you
are doing become well-known your Emacs
community and it's not just five minutes
because he asks something sometimes you
don't understand what he's saying
because you know up in a while you have
no idea what people are people have all
kind of weird questions so you know
sometimes they don't ask question well
you know they don't you know so and
sometimes you know these so it's in a
wild it so everything goes so they ask
you a question email hey cuz I you know
sigh I you know I saw your this this
website explaining about something but
what about that you know they asked you
a question so I mean so this is a common
attitude mentality in open source
community right because open source free
software foundation I mean the the the
the the the understood community the
mentalities that we help each other we
we share so in so you know they so my
this or my website you know they they
learn something but they have a question
so they email me
hey hey cuz I want you know how do you
do that or how do you do this
so usually I answer you know I don't get
paid but usually I answer you know you
do that for ten years and it's not just
five minutes because once you answer you
know then maybe that's not what they
want they they reply again you you know
you read them you know you go back forth
so each email sometimes becomes half an
hour easy you know is it is extremely
easy and also because of the open source
community the open source mentality then
people will sometimes they will start to
you know like do one upmanship with you
like this happens with you guys as well
I mean I'm not complaining okay but this
is just the way things are you know for
example I talked about some Emacs Oh
UNIX then they say oh yeah thank you for
that but by the way by the way this you
are wrong it should be that way okay
they say that okay then I saw it
you know sometimes okay occasionally
they are correct you know actually
sometimes they helped me correct
something in my tutorial or they gave me
some information that's new for example
today I learned from you know chat is
great you know chess so I learned about
this tarik guy how much he makes you
know how basically the question is how
much youtube who makes programming
tutorials in general how much they make
so now I know you know someone showed me
and some I also told me how much you owe
me cause makes
Maxo Raider Thank You max the Raider so
anyway so so yeah sometimes you've got
email and you get into a fight basically
I start to get into a fight with people
with people who follow me you know so
because they say oh because UNIX you
actually need to do this okay but
sometimes it's helpful but oftentimes
it's not because because you like when
you do have eat blog or You Tube you
have a lot readers right so there's one
of me but you have like thousands I have
at least like few hundred Emacs
followers who follow me you know in the
Emacs community I have few hundred like
three hundred you know the throughout
you know basically in the past 20 years
so anyway so you get emails you answer
them you spend a lot of time for each
one you know they didn't know because
from them their point of view they
didn't know what you know what how much
blogger spends how much use they did
that they don't know okay they don't
think about it they just have a question
they they they in in their mind it's
like I I saw sorry you know he's got
great tutorial so I saw it and I want to
comment you know in the open source
mentality you want to kind of like help
back okay
the real help is money okay nothing it
nothing else is actually help you know
so you want contribute back you know
give feedback something like that so you
they email me then you have to reply so
from their point of view you just you
know they think you just take five
minutes you know and they to them it's
not you spending five minutes for them
to them it's more like we are equal we
are you know friends we are open-source
community we are you know you know
open-source commune with each other so
that's what it looks like to them that's
not true I spent you know every for the
past 15 years you know I stopped doing
that but basically full of past 15 years
beginning in 2005
every day I spend like two hours at
least to answer all the questions
comments on my website emails github you
know this and and then social network
you know everything and Google+ you know
everywhere two hours two hours every day
and what you get you get it at best you
get one cup of coffee a day you know at
best you spend two hours for that not
counting the time you spend to do the
tutorial just counting the time you
spend to answer the comments you know
you have to go github you know github
github is another thing you know
open-source you you know at best you get
like $100 a month that's what you get
and and also also when people donate to
you you know they donate five dollars
you know they think they to them they
think they are doing great you know
actually that is true too because one
person out of 1000 followers actually do
something that actually donate so the
fact that they even donated is is
actually factually they are doing you
know they are they are they are they are
great you know of the open-source
community they are they are great
persons but you know but it's not it's
like you don't survive you cannot
survive you know so so anyway so what I
was saying so so I was saying yeah so
the the point I want to say is about the
open-source context that really sucks
your blood it destroys everything it is
this and and wipe wipes out that's only
one aspect of the you know so I'm
talking about when you open a company
there are so many stories about opening
a company okay if you open a company
even if your code is open source you do
not want to make that the context okay
don't do not get open-source mentality
or open-source community involved okay
don't get I don't do that because if you
do that you have no you go with nowhere
you will die yours coming we were tied
because then everyone who promotes your
company will be this open source type of
people they will do also the things they
the moment they don't like you they will
you and you know they do doooo
nasty things and but to them they don't
know they think this is the best thing
they think they are doing grateful
society you know that that's what
happens so anyway so back to the topic
udemy and Costco Syrah okay they they
succeed you know they they get paid you
know they they have companies they hire
people and the teachers who drag costs
for them they get paid okay you can pay
you can pick you can get paid fairly
well why because these companies when
you go there you don't think about oh
this is part of open-source community
you don't think about that you go there
you just pay pay on you know this is
this is about learning a programming
language or something let's go Leila you
know it's about learning a foreign
language so if you want to learn Python
you go there if the price is right you
pay that's it and they make money you
know that that is you know that's it
that that is why they can make money
meanwhile if you do open source you go
nowhere you know like me you know my
Emacs tutorial and for example my Java
Script tutorial you know I'm kind of
familiar what with these kind of
tutorials what they do they are in
general not not that great okay I mean
if you are a hacker type of programmer
this tutorial tutorials most of the time
they are focused on absolute beginners
who trying to get into programming so
you know it's not great so that's about
that Derrick Munoz yes
whatever happened to nineteen eighties
individualism mentality yeah that
mentality is gone so let me check the
comments and let's see I got several
other topics ok so let's see
where we are 13 people watching okay
we've been talking for 26 minutes okay
that's good so far so good
so let's read comments Bartholomew says
join Debian server ok what Remini says
but what is the problem with programming
ebooks is that there are tons of Indians
that have written so many programming
book clones most of them being for
beginners yeah
the in Indian I don't want to flame
Indian people but I I do have Indian
followers but but it's a fact that lots
of these Indians you know they they you
know they spend you know lots of Indians
they are spamming they are also creating
more you know scam website scam you know
things and also lots of SEO like I get
emails every month for the past five
years 10 years 15 years and this you
know lots of them from India like that
like we are we specialize in SEO oh I
saw your website sorry that info let me
tell you we specialize in SEO so we can
make your website show show us the top
search result result in Google search
you know I got that spam email all the
time and often the these are from India
these are typically one one person or
two person companies you know they are
trying to scam your money and also a lot
Indian programmers they are trying to
you know create teaching materials
things things like that many of them are
not good
of course there are many great Indian
programmers they are a lot Indian
programmers over here you know in
Silicon Valley at Google at the place I
used to work I in for example I work
with you know Anna Tapia at web order
web or dot-com back then year 1999 to
2002 we have
about five or six programmers and three
of them four of them are Indian so you
do not change through live chat Oh live
chat okay it's changed to five chat okay
let's go back to the top Joey my dear
Debian server where's your Debian server
so I'm not such a she'll that I bashed
means without knowing them I have used
disco just when it came out four months
when did they came out like five years
ago or something the longer it existed
the more I questioned myself how do they
make money no ads no nothing they say
many message in their company but okay
but seeing how they grew and grew making
revenue okay so now count one and one
together what do they have from us just
our data they say our data yeah I yeah I
still love how everyone was surprised
that Facebook has illegally selling data
for third party you know yeah so okay so
that is your criticism about this code
okay but that's not much you know Google
Facebook Twitter if they are doing that
all that and and in fact doing much
worse and also Apple you know you
mentioned you don't use phone or
something you know that's impossible I
mean well maybe maybe for you that's
true but you know the four vast majority
of majority of people including
programmers including all the hacker
types including probably all of you
maybe maybe except part okay you use a
form right either Android Google Android
or iPhone if you use a phone there is no
way for you to be careful or not yo I
don't want to use Google you know don't
use face this is no way it's like
building is interconnected even if you
try hard you cannot remove you know
Google phone tracking you it's like
everywhere every website you visit they
have Facebook you know so unless you are
this kind of you know if you are a spy
or you know working for China or if you
are spy working for FBI if you are that
type of person then
you are agent then you have you don't
use the phone you have special phones
you know you you cannot you know unless
you are that type of person you cannot
avoid being tracked you know it's like
you know Google Facebook Google Maps do
you use Google Maps like in USA everyone
drives ok USA you don't have a much
public transit system everyone drives so
when you drive typically everyone use
you know Google Maps or you call uber
uber or you know the company or taxi
it's you are being tracked all the time
you cannot in fact in fact you could say
it's true you cannot live in USA without
being tracked all over like over nothing
you can do even if you don't visit any
website at all you are being tracked by
Google over the place unless you are
abnormal like unless you are a weirdo
like me your helmet you don't go out at
all like you stay hid you live in your
mountains then you are not being tracked
ok then you can say oh I don't use
Google because I never visited you know
things like that you could say oh even
if you don't use computer at all like
Richard Stallman he can if he claims you
know he's not being tracked
I believe him he don't even he's you
know nobody can do like him you know he
he's extremely weird but anyway if you I
mean even if you have a hacker type like
us like me you cannot help you actually
don't have a phone I have a phone but I
don't have a phone number I don't have
that you know I didn't have a phone
number so but I got a phone about two
years ago because I need to go to visit
professor so that's why I got a phone
that's the first time I used the smart
phone in 2000 let's show there's some
pictures the first time I used a
smartphone in let's go to saw keyboard
ok keyboard let's go through
saw desktop some keyboard okay 2017 okay
so I went there I went to this space to
visit professor math professor retired
method prove it math professor friend
Richard palace he taught me a lot math
and he it is he he gave me the iMac you
see here iMac
so I have to go there I saw I need a
phone because these days you cannot you
cannot function almost without a phone
in China is worth because in China you
don't use credit card or checks there's
no checks and you don't use credit card
much everything is phone you just swipe
it so if you don't have a phone you
cannot you know it's like you cannot you
cannot live you know and it's becoming
it's a it's a same way in USA you know
you drive you you Google Maps and all
that so when you say you don't use the
phone right it's hard to I don't know I
don't know your case spot but when you
say yes oh it's not sous-vide even
less yeah unless you are pretty weird
you know you two you two are pretty
weird you know I can believe that
because few people when other people who
follow me everyday we watch you know
spent one hour watching my beauty how
kind of weird so but I mean my point is
you know every you know Google Facebook
is all doing that so if your objection
about using this code is because you
think they sell your data that's that's
too weak kind of too weak a reason I
mean even for me because I mean yes you
know me I'm quite I'm quite picky on
what to use I mean if I know they've
done something they might not use it but
but so far the reason that you know I I
looked into you know I read Wikipedia
about them I haven't seen something
drastic so you know that that so that is
about that so bother me says so now I
can't find one together so I I see you
love however how everyone was surprised
that Facebook has illegally selling data
code or Academy yeah okay code Academy
is another one I guess yeah code Academy
and kisara and you Donny and can Academy
yeah these though these companies they
make money they actually do and also the
authors who make tutorials for them and
over the years I've seen some you know
dramatic stories like some people for
example some you know they are bad guys
over like so some people see that they
will just try to write a tutorial like
they copy websites they they create a
tutorial and they put their tutorial on
one of these websites to make money you
know and so lots of you know it all came
from you know people just trying to make
money so I don't actually find other
many bad okay you need to find the right
teacher and you can actually learn
something if you do every single
practical exercise the teacher tells you
to do okay
so like today you know you app Apple
Google ok Google you know ok Google
controlled my voice in Amazon you know
Amazon dead Amazon echo and ok Google
and Apple Siri and the Microsoft Cortana
it's everywhere and yeah I mean it's
it's going it's it's it's already
becoming a point that is part of no more
society you visit your friend she might
have that device at her house you know
you don't you can you can't go to her
house and say hey I'm sorry but I have
this weird opinion could you turn could
you turn ok Google off you think you're
gonna do that no it's everywhere you
know it's like everywhere it's that is
what happens to society so yeah so yeah
you know like my I have my roommates and
now they have their phone you know my
roommates they are not you know they are
not programmers or technical they don't
know anything about I mean they don't
have a degree they don't you know they
didn't go to college
ok things like that so you know they
don't know nothing about it they don't
even know for example what is Google I
mean while they heard of it but they
know exactly what it is or Facebook ok
they heard of it
so so even my roommates they have phones
you know lying around and they yeah you
know you like it's like you cannot tell
them like you know maybe some of you are
thinking oh you can talk to them or tell
them what is Google no it's impossible
ok isn't it's like think think about
trying to tell tell your mom oh you know
or your grandma ok trying to talk to
your mom or grandma say trying to tell
them what is Emax ok it doesn't happen
you don't even think about it you know
it's it doesn't work you know when you
you can't you cannot even begin the the
topic because they have no idea what
you're talking about
you know after two minutes they tell you
what they thought they think you you
went crazy you know or they think you
want something from them they take it
off you know
you know it's like that so so they they
have their phones lying around and they
they use you know they don't know what
it you know they they don't even know
what is okay Google okay they don't even
know what is CV like they don't know
it's a technology service where you can
answer questions things you know they
ask you know they don't know but however
they see you know they know the buttons
they see the button so sometime they'll
press it and say ok Google they try to
speak to it things like that
so they have their phones lying around
and I you know I'm thinking you know
this probably listening all the time
it's listening all the time what am I
going to do what you know
you know I you know this is nothing you
can do this is you know happening over
you this it's you know it's nothing you
can do you can you I cannot just tell
them to turn it off okay that's you
cannot do that because first of all you
try to talk to them they don't
understand what you're talking about
they don't know what they don't
unless you're gonna start to talk about
it for an hour then then they stopped if
they did they're gonna move out you know
this is like that so but I can you know
just pick the phone and turn it off you
know then they then they may ask what
you know what what are you're doing what
are you doing with my phone they might
ask that you know things like that so
and even if you turn it all off by next
week
it might be on again because they don't
know tech technology okay they'd put
pressed buttons randomly because Google
they designed it so that it's easy to
randomly just turn them back because
every chance they are asked you okay you
know something something okay you know
you just press okay that's that's most
people are like that especially my
roommates you know they don't speak
English
so you press okay okay then then the
Google Voice will go come back they
listen though its listens all the time
so that so what why am I saying this you
know why am I saying this because a lot
of programmers nuts
you don't know like you have no I
you think you know you just you can
convince people to use emacs okay you
know if they don't understand what is
met hockey well you can you can tell
them you know in logical manner ohmmeter
key is this key they are thinking you
can tell your mom to begin to use emacs
this idiots is tech nerds okay so I've
been talking nonstop for 40 minutes now
I got 99 teen people watching so I'm
doing okay
I guess so back to the comments back to
the comments
other amuses my open source mentality
with save your ass when you need your
YouTube archive phone for free okay okay
that's a valid point
piracy is no part of collectivism
culture Kathy says and what happened to
individualism mentality so Barr says I
also don't like about this code is that
everyone takes it for granted
since like two years ago okay so so many
communities are exclusive to this court
Oh
so why not have several options why not
have only yeah so I don't know I didn't
you know I didn't know about that like I
mentioned you know this this code you
know it's like I mean I I think you are
like at least twenty years younger than
me you know as I said I'm getting old I
don't have time to spend on you know
these things and so discord to me is
like oh this is new tech let's look into
you know let's look what they do what
this came up people do so yeah so you
know in your shoe it's like oh it's you
know it's becoming so common and view is
something like that among gamers right I
suppose you know that's yeah but I
haven't been you know I so it's kind of
like new to me
so there is OpenStreetMaps yeah I I'm
not surprised you are the one to say
that open street max maps just like
everything open-source
it sucks donkey ass truly you know I've
tried a few I've tried it a few a few
times in fact you know map is very
useful to me because in my a lot of my
blogs I have links to maps because the
form you know asian asian stories
usually happens somewhere on the map
trojan war for example the greek
mythology so when I talk about Trojan
War quick mythology I like to I like to
see a map you know where is that you
know things like that
Oh goo lavas travel cool Ava's travel he
talks about visiting Japan which is a
not actually Japan but cool of us travel
he talks about and he actually you know
he give names so you can so I went
actually I went why when I notated
Gulliver's travel you know so I actually
look at where where is the location he
is talking about for example let's go to
Gulliver's travel I talked about this
yesterday also or the day before
Arabian Nights Gulliver's Travels
so in one of the chapters you know he
visit you know several fantasy places
but however those these places are
suppose supposedly on earth you know
he's like this is 300 years ago he is
traveling by ship
you know this sailing days exploration
so you know but so anyway he visit
several of these places and and
sometimes they have an actual name so
coordinates so actually one time I
looked okay let me show you a place okay
google maps so I have anyway I got a lot
blocks and often I linked to I want to
look at the maps you
Maps is useful so so I used to link to
Google Maps all over the place and I
stopped you know I stopped a few years
ago after knowing Google becomes so evil
but still I want to you know I want a
replacement it would be great if there's
an open source map you know I can just
link to yeah so so I know about open
maps you know open source I tried it you
know it sucks it sucks donkey ass okay
the just just like every open source
thing you know just like Linux just like
master then it sucks it's the worst of
the worst it see that you don't even
start to compare okay so for example one
of the place school of us travel he
visited is here
okay somewhere here this this in this
this is called alluvia
islands okay so let me show you so this
is here is you see a world map and North
Pole so here is North Pole is here this
is Alaska
you know Alaska here's Canada Alaska you
can now this face is part of Canada you
can name each string okay so you see
USA's here Canada is here almost all
people Canadians they live around here
mostly Vancouver Vancouver Ontario
Toronto Toronto over here Ottawa and
Montreal
so vassman Ike like ninety nine ninety
ninety nine percent of people Canadians
they live here okay
and also the entire population of
Canadians are less than California
California itself has more people than
the entirety of Canada okay and also so
you go up north you know you go up north
it's very cold you know it's almost
everybody code and even in Montreal I
was I lived in Montreal over here
that is 30 degrees Celsius below zero 30
degrees Celsius below zero in the winter
that's Montreal I lived there from 1998
1986 to night 1986 to 1989 three years
in Montreal and half a year in Vancouver
here so anyway here is Yukon Yukon is
one of the story in this story let me
show you Yukon jack London to build a
fire fantastic story Jack London is a
well-known American author it's a short
fiction you can finish it in 20 minutes
or 10 minutes if you read fast fantastic
story so he's talking about a guy over
here in in this you Kong somewhere here
and you know I have actually coordinates
I mean if you read my to be order fire
you know read my page okay not not go to
PDF or some other website the my page
has annotations you know you can so
there it is you come you come a
territory in North Western Canada east
of Alaska so there is Google Maps so you
can click on that and this Wikipedia
link so you know you can click on so I
have a link to Google Google Maps so
they he's talking about someone here
it's a great story okay you come then
you have Alaska which is USA USA parted
from I think from Russia I think anyway
so you know Alaska you have the anyway
what's what's that senator you know who
tried to run as US president Sarah
Palin's Sarah Palin yeah she's she's got
stories you know anyway so Alaska you
know you don't have money many people
here but it's it's interesting you know
the world is so big you know what you
will be interests
to go there and live there and see what
people are like over there but anyway
then you have these islands you see
these islands over here yeah so to me
it's amazing you know what people are
doing you know in fact there is a
YouTube channel showing animals like
woof and ours and egos and that channel
is actually from from one of these face
I forgot well but is it's either one of
of this face of Alaska so she you know
you can watch her video so anyway so
these islands are called a Louisville
and islands okay so you see their
Aleutian Islands okay so in kurukulla
bus travels in one of the chapter he
mentions a place somewhere around here
you know somewhere around here oh yeah I
think it's I think it's it tries to
mention Japan or something anyway it's
incorrect okay it's actually nowhere
nowhere out of nowhere on earth in
Gulliver's Travels so I look you know I
look I looked it up and you know what's
great thing about Google Earth is that
you can drop drop in street view so
let's see if we can drop in street view
okay so you can actually see photo and
people of the face okay so it looks you
know it looks like that nature so you if
you if if you hate technology you go
live here okay if you are tired of
Google and Twitter and and the cellphone
you go live here so yeah so so I want
you know map have you know Matt I'm very
interested in map in fact I can spend
hours just you know using Google Maps to
look around but then I tried you know I
I want to open source one I tried to
open maps it's sucks donkey ass it's
just incredible
you you don't have that for example if
you go to right now if we go to open
source map you go that you know you
let's destroy what we want to do so open
map ok open street map or something you
know it sucks in every aspect
they don't have street you know if you
are trying to look for a street map like
if you are driving like for your daily
needs you know you need to go to buy
some stuff in your town you know sitting
in big city let's say San Francisco you
use Open Street Map it doesn't walk you
know you can find your place or some
road is closed it doesn't show up there
doesn't work or alternatively if you are
like me you know studying history stuff
you know the aluva islands you know you
you you try to find it on opens map you
know like yeah you know you you want to
look at regions you know around the
world you try to use over map it doesn't
work it doesn't work neither in so you
know all in anyway you dies it just
sucked is you know it's this is this is
true for basically all open-source
things like that it's like that so there
we have it so you know let's try to do
what we are trying to do so this region
let's look at okay yeah so you know so
that's so you see what okay there is an
airport and what are these you know you
know it's nowhere this is a far you know
it's no way of comparable to you know
this is nothing what what am I getting
out of this
where is the city like okay so you know
can you see what I'm seeing
do you see what I mean do you believe
this particular criticism about open
source does that make sense
or am I like lying or am i doing
propaganda right yeah at this point you
then then the open source phonetics you
will say where is your code
where
code oh you should contribute that make
that the topic changed to something else
it becomes you should support
open-source not about the quality of
open-source you become something else
you know the reasons like that because
fanatism it becomes ideology once it
becomes ideology people don't think that
you know they don't think about anything
anymore it's just about and look at
these asinine things you know that what
are they trying to draw this this is a
crowd this is what what is is a crowd
around these islands
you know these idiots you know so often
so a street OpenStreetMap yeah it's
great
but one thing we know he's as a fact
okay is that it's that you know it needs
a lot walk you know it's it's just
primitive it doesn't work for for
example suppose you are a open source
proponent you want to try to promote
open source great I support that but
then when you tell your friend oh you
know don't you know you try to tell your
friend don't use a Google map use opens
use open street maps okay you've your
friend you know you he's your friend
you know and you are his friend you know
so he believes you so next day tomorrow
he needs to drive to a friend's house he
needs to drive to your house and he
opened oh yeah he told me your used open
maps you know open Street he tries it it
doesn't work your your house is not
shown on a map
what what is your reaction you know you
just gave extremely bad advice then he
immediately got the impression Oh
something about open source it's really
bad you know because you know that's
that's a fact that's the truth but
however the next day are orders no
traitor you don't hear it oh you hear is
oh we should open support open source
woman show us this great oh this is
better than Microsoft Windows this is
great this is better much
rather than Microsoft Windows this is
ten times better than Microsoft Windows
that's all you hear so dizziness
Disney's says please can you score back
such such grow pasa in the chat and
answer that question of mine okay
I'm especially interested in the plural
versus singular now issue okay who did I
trigger TV says renamed remember
show okay so there is let me answer that
question grow Pass globosa
using Windows app store is easy and
convenient would you use it no I don't
want to use App Store and well you know
the apps stores these app stores are
become another Oh unavoidable it's like
they if you use software at all if you
are average person so anyway where is
the let me search GL OB eh
okay so there is a question please can
you scroll back such well okay so
dizziness says what is your opinion on
Globus ah it is a word LAN because you
speak Chinese and grow pasa don't
normally use poor just like Chinese do
you prefer using floral for nouns as in
English or not as in Chinese okay I get
what you think that is a linguistic
topic and that is also a frequent we
talked about linguistic topic and I have
not heard of globosa
before I suppose is a constructed
language okay let's have a look clovis
ah do they have a Wikipedia entry okay
they do I think let's see I don't think
I have heard of it before
oops this is the wrong article
so globosa a new language for a new
earth is ready I don't like that it's
trying to pitch some kind of you know
the the help the world thing okay girl
globosa is a newly constructed truly
international auxiliary language it has
been designed with the average world
citizen in mind to be as easy as
possible to learn and to use without
sacrificing clarity and degree of
expressiveness okay
that's nothing new after an experiment
after an experimental and developmental
stage of two years only two years
globosa is currently in its almost
growth stage with over 1,000 rude words
including all function words in the
complete core grammar crew bossa is now
ready to be used in put into practice
now now that's their marketing probe now
as far as smart marketing blurb goes
this is lame actually pretty lame
because all constructed languages
languages before this in the past 100
years they are quite a few they are at
least you know five or ten at least they
all say this okay they all say the
exactly the same thing but however they
they they have more than you know they
are already more advanced than globosa
and you know you have Esperanto you have
Lachlan you have lost pal you have you
have interlingua you have kind of quite
a few okay and some of them are new like
within ten years old so grow basa is
only two years old okay it's a
completely new that's why I haven't
heard of it so anyway grow basa is the
work of a linguist yeah
translator an expert in adult language
acquisition and teaching it is design
its design reminiscent of the word quail
a Creole eighth-ranked
it is the result of following in guide
principles yeah all constructed language
is like that you know this in this okay
so this this homepage so far it's rather
limb there is no compelling reason how
it is better than other constructed
languages
so there's guiding principles and okay
so anyway the question is about plural
versus no plural
the English inflection you know the
words morph are morphology you know for
example in English you have plural was a
singular you know if you for example I
have one pen I have one pen then I have
two pens whence more than one you you
have to change the word now there you
have a plural form of the now pens
it's a pain in the ass okay it's a pain
yes awesome so I I forgot what's a
technical did is they are kind of you
know when it comes to being linguistics
like these issues there are many
technical words to describe the you know
inflection you know this they are they
are word for it but I don't remember you
can look up anyway some languages like
Chinese you don't have that okay so one
pain to pain simple you know one finger
to finger three finger okay how do you
know it's more than well you already
said it's three three makes it more than
one don't ya what some that's it's
appointed to change what's the point of
to change changes are now well there are
reasons of course they are there are
reasons in their history historical
reasons because language languages
natural human languages are not
constructed artificial languages like
grow bossa you know like Esperanto like
Lal Qila Lachlan those are constructed
you know superficial they try to make
everything logical and you know simple
we know that but natural languages human
languages are the
evolved you know begin a beginning let's
say one ten ten thousand ago ten
thousand years ago what I do I just like
that okay you understand what I mean
then gradually we have we developed
sound you had particular sound
they then that's language then it
changes because it you know it's very
the history of linguistics is very
detailed
you know the pronunciation changes for
example Chinese change changed over the
past twenty two thousand years English
pronunciation changed in the past you
know one thousand years - and they
change not just they change for many
reasons and part of the reason I know is
that they change because the food you
eat changed then your mouth your your
teeth growth changed then your voice you
have the pronunciation change change
accordingly you know so there's many
interesting details you know you can
study linguistics for years you know 14
years so anyway so so one of the thing
in many language European languages is
is that you have the plural now and
singular part of the I don't I don't
know how its developed and actually I
think nobody knows but anyway maybe
somebody you know maybe this is already
know but anyway the reason you know what
at least one of the advantage we could
say from hints ID is that it it makes
your language less prone to damage for
example you if I say three fingers okay
but but because there's some big noise
you didn't hear three but you heard
fingers then you know I'm saying it's
more than one finger you know things
like that so that that is why you have
inflections you have that but if you ask
for my opinion like if I were to design
complete new constructed language I will
not have that so I don't like that that
is just my opinion I think most
constructed language follow that
principle they did constructed
constructed language tends to do that I
think I think I think in fact I cannot I
don't I don't know one constructed
language that has approval thing okay I
think that's about it so that so does
that is my answer satisfactory dizziness
dizziness where are you from so we got
some comments on discord okay so how
long I been talking okay so maybe we can
end in few minutes so let me just answer
questions then Oh actually today there
are several other topics I want to talk
about so anyway I saw I visited this
professor you know he's he's he's one of
the top mathematicians he's a
differential geometry I talked about him
I mentioned him in my previous videos so
he gave me the Mac that's why I'm on a
Mac so this is 2017 you know math oh
yeah I do math is my thing and in this
guy I think this guy this is another
professor Tasha he not okay not not this
guy here you see you only see part of
him his name is Kasia he is a German
very old they I will retire they are all
peeled so he's a great friend he taught
me he teach me mathematics he is the top
expert
minimal surfaces yeah so back then
back back then I visited the other
professor and he is also visiting him
Richard Paez
so yeah so actually I did I I do have
some other topics but now I've been
already talking too long I think that
that will be it for today so I'm just
going to answer some questions and IOB
it so tomorrow tomorrow 10 o'clock ok
maybe should we - tomorrow be something
like six well ten o clock let's say this
just say tomorrow ten o clock same time
so how do you become how do you
begin to become professional hacker that
depends on what you mean by hacker now
if you now you see your phrase is
ambiguous quite ambiguous because does
the it doesn't make sense to say
professional hacker okay
because hacker has two primary meanings
one is the MIT hacker back in 1980s it's
a culture hacker culture basically it
just means people who love programming
so much and who love programming and
computer hardware so much they they
would do it for free they would just you
know dream about it you know do
programming all day and try to find
clever ways things like that
that's hacker okay that's like for
example Richard Stallman is a
stereotypical hacker you know he used to
say he hit he likes to say happy hacking
you know whenever it's time to say
goodbye he say happy hacking happy
hacking okay happy hacking guys so that
that is one meaning of hacker okay this
is kind of a
subculture programmers a subclass of
programmers that's hackers now another
meaning of hacker which is common in
mainstream media
that means cracker that means kind of
like criminals you go you break you go
to you break CIA smashing you break you
you know you hack into bank banks you
dos attack websites you you know you do
things like that I steal I steal your
password
you know that's hackers that's a
mainstream meaning of hackers okay so
two meanings of hackers in either case
you don't really call it professional
hacker
okay the further subculture hackers they
you know many of them are professional
programmers but they don't call
professional hackers by definition
hacker is not professional okay it's
just it's a subculture and way of life
kind of wait you know kind of community
kind of like UNIX philosophy you know
Linux people they are that like that on
the on the other hand this criminal type
you know sometimes you're not it's not
criminal because the law are not well
defined but anyway the type of people
who break into machines who steal
passwords or who do it for fun these
type of people
well yeah there are also professionals
but they are rather you call them
professional criminals they are you know
you have them in Russia you have them in
China you have American usually you know
you work for CIA you know FBI you know
you government top-secret you create
more where things like that and also you
could be just you know a teenager you
you go online you go to into these
hacker communities then you download
programs to do this to stuff so your
question is your question is how to
become a professional hackers yes what
do you mean
professional hacker so another
interpretation is how to become
professional programmer how to begin to
become a professional programmer okay
okay so now there are three questions
when is how do you how do you join the
hacker code the hacker community how do
you become one of them
well you just you know you start to use
emacs use Emacs
use Linux use vim okay then you follow
me follow you know other people over
here you follow them you know you you
chat with them you make friends then you
become the hacker type of people you
know you you get brainwashed by them
then you will believe every day Oh
Microsoft is evil Oh
open-source is the best thing since
sliced bread okay that's that's how you
become a hacker the other way how to
become the criminal type of hacker kind
of the same way you go to you go to the
dark web you know some people you know
to begin to begin with you go to reddit
you go to hacker news then you pick you
try to pick you know those hacking
articles then you'll begin to find who
are talking about it you as you start to
find links you follow those links then
you will start to find maybe some
communities yeah you dig you know you
follow the rabbit hole then you become
the criminal hacker type now the third
question how do how to become a
professional programmer where you begin
learning programming you can follow my
tutorials in terms of other tutorials we
talked about today then you start to
code you do a lot projects then you
become a professional programmer so
bottom you says the window App Store is
actually more than just a avoidable just
in a word what you can even have window
without any window app store into apps
yeah that's what I do but I know what
you're saying but that's not going
anywhere
the question is again yeah I know I know
and you know we don't need to tell each
other about
how to how to how to set up your windows
so it doesn't track you know that I
already know you know I know but does
your mom know that's the question does
does does my mom know does you know you
can you tell your mom to do that that's
the thing okay so that's I think that's
it for today so you have if you have a
question I think I'm gonna shut down
okay three more minutes maybe if you
have a questions put my name to it okay
make it Orange
so Bob Bob mentioned the Skype you know
I can tell you the history of Skype so
DP says learn Metasploit a ruby based
penetration testing framework and used
forensic oriented distros like kernel
kinetics okay anything else makes so
happy what since you five bucks in
Pompeii ha whoa
I like hearing you talk about stuff
thank you thank you whoo 16200 too
so you once said that you have an
up family yeah that is true
do I want to talk about that no okay
yeah because yeah I don't know I do not
talk about that yeah well my family
maybe another day you know you know the
human interaction is you know one thing
about human relationships is that for
example let's say are you married can I
ask you do you mind to answer that are
you married I'm not married by the way
but let's say someone okay let me just
say you okay whoever you are I mean
you're random person okay because it's
easier to say that to give an example
you know so so so suppose you are
married you know you have a wife now
there is some some you know usually you
always have quarrels like you know even
if you love each other
I mean even if you guys married for 20
years and he's gonna be married forever
but still you sometimes you have
quarrels or fights you know the issue is
about when you if you want to keep a
family the the the main thing is is that
you actually want to keep communication
okay don't don't avoid things when
there's a trouble you want to talk about
it you want to get it soft
you cannot just Oh try not to talk about
it
same thing with doing videos in you know
or if I have a issue with people or
someone you or with your friends for
example if you have a friends if you
want to keep the friendship if there's a
fight you you have to face it you have
to bring it up you have to address it
avoid it doesn't work unless both of you
already know you know you already kind
of understand each other
you know then then it works yeah again
the issue is you know if both of you
have to communicate so anyway if you
have a wife you know you may have a
fight you know usually you don't want to
talk about it and also you know for
example many movie stars
you know they divorced you know after
two years they divorced
you don't go to you know you don't go
online and say oh how is your wife how
is your ex-wife in bed oh you know if
you are the wife you say oh you know
he's got a big or smoke RV you know
you don't do that you know you don't do
that not because you you are trying to
avoid telling the truth but rather there
are issues yeah you know your life you
know it's like there's a some some fact
or truth
it's rather you should not say for
example by my family you know it doesn't
first of all it doesn't do me good when
you talk about it it doesn't you know
when you if you do not talk about your
wife
oh you know the things like that it
doesn't do you good
it doesn't do her good Oh in fact it
makes so angry some you know I mean you
know this is all oh what about your boss
you know suppose you work at Google
there's something something you don't
like when there are people involved
generally you don't want to talk about
it not because you are trying to hide or
because something because there's
reality you know so this is an
interesting issue you know I have
thought about it because there's being
alive the fact that you are alive there
are certain things that already
constraints you okay for example one of
the things being alive is that you have
to eat to survive
now what if what if there is actually a
fact there's a truth the philosophical
something deep truth that if you stop
eating then you're discovered it's
something you know how you know the age
of the universe or something
philosophically there is no way to deny
that maybe possibly is true it is
actually true if you stop eating
something we are you know you are start
to know something is possible but you
just cannot do it because if you don't
eat you die then that's anything you
cannot talk anymore you know so maybe
maybe you talk afterlife or something
but but you cannot tell I cannot tell
you guys what's you know what's the
ultimate truth if I stop eating you know
so in other words all the truth you know
in among human animals there are certain
limitations and constraints for example
one thing is that you have to up your
life you know you have to keep eating
you have to drink water you have to
breath okay then you can talk whatever
and same thing with relationships
certain things about relationship you
can you don't you don't want to talk
about or talk about in your employer for
example one day I was watching this
right-wing the most popular right-wing
new school news anchor who said what's
his name anyone remember say please type
in the most popular right wing news
reporter in USA it's a guy because I
cannot I forgot I forget names all
the time when I'm talking considered the
most he he's on Fox News you know Fox
News he's a let's say Fox News anchor I
can you know I can remember it if I try
to think
it's just such crowd no it's a it's news
anchor not Crowder is a YouTube I'm
talking about the news anchor on Fox
News Alex Jones no Alex Jones is not
it's not a is not an anchor Alex Jones
is a youtuber you know he's a nut job
and Alex Jones he's a he's a nut job
he's crazy nut jobs every everyone knows
you know Fox News the number one guy who
is it's so good I'm sure I will see his
picture took her Carson yes took her
Carson if I don't remember names took
her cows in yeah so Tucker Carlson by
the way when you are on a show like and
when you are off show you are completely
different so he is completely different
when you watch him off show for example
one on YouTube you can go search for
Tucker Carson interviewed by by another
guy sometimes called alright Mac Mac Mac
Mac ins
Vince key what's his name anyway so so
anyway I have what I watched took a
Carson off show is completely different
to a person and very interesting guy
okay so you know the same way
what what's my point why are we talking
about this I forgot
pío all righty Hobie all righty is
another guy he's got he got fired
because of me too or something yeah me
too me too
okay I think that's it today boy I was
talking about oh yeah relationships so
Tucker Carson one day said you know he
you know somewhere I asked him the mug
Mack something you know very right-wing
guy asking something like you know on
your news you know on your show
took a Carson show wait wait why didn't
you answer some questions or something
because he said he said you know he said
you know yeah Fox Fox News is biased but
there's nothing I can do you know he's
my employer he's you know it's very
reasonable he's solid you know it's true
no he's it's my employer you know I
could say you know I could say something
about Fox News but you don't want to go
into detail you know
that's reality you know you work for a
company you but then you don't you know
you don't you cannot start to for
example focus on how bad is your boss
okay
even even though if you had a news
anchor but that's just a fact okay and
that's understood it's not you know is
it's understood you can do that you know
so in the same way you don't talk about
your employee employer so you know your
colleagues things like that you know
good things you can talk about bad
things not so actually I got so that's
it for today so Tucker Carlson lies and
deceives in front of the camera big
surprise
no I wouldn't say that okay but it is
true that on Fox News it's very biased
right wing news but however the left.we
news is far far worse okay it's far
worse but Tucker Carson himself as a
person
I think he's he's he's better than
average you know I actually yeah I think
he's better than an average person when
he is doing news report you know I don't
I don't buy it totally because it's it's
quite twisted towards the the the
concern conservative view but however
the view sometimes he talked about other
things I I just you know took a casa so
anyway that's it for today thank you
guys for watching
PayPal me patron on me and stuff okay
bye guys
one minutes shutdown countdown this
nuclear launch countdown 1 minutes then
I'm gonna shut down and now I'm going to
put my links to my website so good so
globosa I'm gonna probably I'm gonna
look a little bit I don't think it's
interesting and why why are they
creating a new constructed language
isn't there enough already
typically typically this happens is
because this guy some I don't know who
created bit he want to you know he think
he's hotshot you know he's new he's
maybe he's young or something yeah have
a good day guys so close crew basa and
the close that words word map yes
OpenStreetMaps sucks donkey US Open
Street Map open source open source
disease okay so it's disease Google Maps
way Google Maps you say I don't want
Google Maps I don't want this evoke you
know do devious cooperation things I
want open source but I don't want open
source idealogy Mac ideology fun Edison
okay I want society to be I want I
Google who are not doing fax okay that's
what I want and I believe the
open-source fanatism
and free software fanatism today that is
how it got our society to this point
okay I blame parsley okay like 50 30
percent to 50 percent I blame the open
source and free software ideology that
get us to this point today in software
industry that is my belief to build a
fire to be on fire is about the struggle
of human animal versus nature
okay Coursera okay let's copy at cosa
okay I'm done
thank you guys bye guys I don't want to
link to Kosovo hi
one time I had an interview at Kosovo
it's a live video interview to way you
know it's like actually it's via Google
Talk did Google hangout okay they could
they used to call it Google hangout they
shut it down
but anyway Google huh and so it's
one-hour interview everything went well
eventually he asked me to do a live
coding of JavaScript to create a click
event or something so I did that at the
end I have a variable you know I have a
variable like this okay let me show you
for example wait so for example I have a
variable like that right for example
let's say let's say your name handle
okay is something handle okay let's say
box okay then after I wrote it I changed
the name I like ID this is what I did
okay I put a random number there for all
the you know box we did that for my
available and I was not with myself like
now I've done quite a lot videos in
now it's five years where I had a crisis
now I kind of know what I should do I'm
more confident okay I can tell him you
don't know okay I can I can tell
him that and I can actually convince him
and he gonna hire me but back then I
wasn't sure what I had you know I wasn't
you know I was you know you know
financial crisis I'm about to die you
know next day so but then there's this
interview I need to do sides so I just
added these random numbers to do it but
I failed to explain I have my reasons
you know because I can talk about this
why I do that for one hour and and and
half of you will be convinced oh this is
actually this guy knows a lot you know
then you know anyway I have articles
about that about this many way I did
this but I failed I didn't like I didn't
get the chain I didn't you know I was
like no kind you know I'm not with
myself so I was you know nervous you
know doing this and then at the end I
just tried to add this random number one
day number number to all my variables
and I thought you know I thought you
know I have the seed in my mind that you
know I can try to explain and convince
him you know because it's an opportunity
for me to begin a topic but did but Eden
didn't work out that way because I was
too nervous you know and I just you know
you know he added a random number to my
very force then after that it's it's
done I'm done
he when he saw that he I think he
decided okay this is not what we want
Kosar odd you know I so I interviewed
the guy his name I don't remember
let's not mention even in fact remember
but anyway I interviewed the guy at
kisara he interviewed me so after I did
this I think that's a point he said okay
okay this guy
we don't want yeah that's about that