good morning guys
welcome to another episode of talk show
talk show that is right your not talk
about things about Emacs about
technology about the future the future
of humanity and stuff and today we're
gonna let's begin by okay let's begin by
of course I need to update the topic so
let's just type it then that's white
space mod okay global white space mod
turn turn those off so I'll talk talk
show and today state and put it here
good taste
there we are and I'm waiting for fuel to
come in and let's do let's see section
section section at the new section paste
and actually let me turn on sauce start
command log mod so you can see all my
Emacs commands and let me know if I got
echos okay let's see so this looks good
this looks good we got one guy watching
and so what we're gonna do today let's
see
Santos show 31st and so yesterday I did
a talk show that is supposed to be all
Chinese Oh in Chinese someone Shambu
someone but then the Chinese people did
not come but English speakers came so a
switch to English and we talked about
kind of non tech non-technical random
stuff we talked about Jack the CEO of
Twitter and fairly evil guy evil person
and so
today well we're gonna start let me
start let me start by going to my goal
and tutorial : is my favorite language
it's simple it's fast it's and it's
widely used in industry it is so I
recommend it if you want to learn goal
and go to my tutorial sorry : ok and
actually I'm going to do when to almost
can sing ok I'm going to do I have some
notes about some things I want to edit
in my goal and oh actually Zoltan okay
so so actually let's add a unicode page
look I look so majorly stupid you know
you get old there's nothing you can do
you know that the thing about ode you
know being old is that I mean it just
creeps him you wouldn't know until you
are 40 you know so you know you lose
your hair and for me I had I had like
long hair like almost in my in my 20
studies of to 40s I have like hair
that's long to my waist I don't know if
I should show you a photo and actually
let's show it
sar me sorry hair let's see it what
turns up
okay say something here okay say
something let's do let's go to Unicode
okay Golan yeah I don't have anything to
edit let's go to Unicode then so here is
my unicode website and I added these
recently I added these fancy languages
such as Korean and Korean and Arabic
Arabic but I'm going to add so what so
let's go to my keyboard blog I mean my
programming blog so here is a list of
choices of languages I should add Thai
Lao Latin now Latin is the base language
for you know for English Spanish Spanish
French you know most Western languages
and we have this go monkey comma
Ethiopia its Ethiopia you know actually
Thai and Lao and Ethiopia looks kind of
exotic usually exotic ones looks good
you know yeah because they are exotic
that's because we are not for me from
here with them that's why they are
exotic look at this one this is um a
marek language I'm not sure I pronounce
it correctly but hey saga anyhow you've
a are you from so we got a Chinese
people first and cool you know Nene
naughty-naughty like that taro has anger
I said Taiwan so we got this language
should we add this one then let's add
this one shall we yeah so this one I've
been watching your videos these days
cool nickname sensor very good excellent
Sun Sun is a you know sensor so let's
yeah let's have some fun let's go look
up so are you a Emacs user
google map by the way do you hear echoes
yo me llamo Tina waiting Yoruba yogi no
Hamid sucia so let's look at a sentence
sentence one of the big city in China
okay
hey hey Daniel Anglo is hey yeah are we
having fun so you know so the here is
where I live you know let me show you
okay now because people in in China or
in elsewhere don't know us a much you
know because like I wouldn't you know I
wouldn't know some cities in Russia or
big cities you know in in Middle East
for example so anyway so here is USA as
you can see the big cities are New York
over here like New York the you know the
New York on East code so this part is
called East Coast
don't add and this part is the West
Coast the West code the big cities of
San Francisco is here that's where I
live in this area and Los Angeles that's
the Hollywood all the movies game game
totally
so this is samus's so in San Francisco
Google is here Google Facebook PayPal
eBay you know they are all here you see
this area this area is called Silicon
Valley I mean for those of you you know
the outside of USA so you don't you may
not know so this area is a Silicon
Valley all the web companies all the big
ones the facebook facebook is over here
Apple is over here actually you can see
let me drop in and show you and Google
is here Google paper Netscape you know
this case it's right you know it's all
like nearby I walk 30 minutes so let me
show you the Google Play
you probably seen here is a google play
play Google's headquarters so I live I
live here okay
I live here so Google Google
headquarters is just if I walk there
it's gonna be 40 minutes 30 minutes to
40 minutes now let's drop in sound
quality is fine
great thank you so this is Google Empire
the most evil empire in the history of
the world that is actually true you well
it's more or less true you know the most
powerful and very Empire so anyway so
let's go back and you know Apple is also
here Apple you know all the big
companies Apple eBay you know PayPal
uber uber is in San Francisco
oh boy it's over here so anyway let's
fly to Joo let's fry to sentence in
tonight I have never been to China so
I've been to Tokyo visit Tokyo as a
professor back in 2004 to to give a you
know they they they gave me at you know
like a professor tag anyways I was there
to demo some math stuff math
visualization so Shenzhen is over here
Center yeah it's a huge metropolis it's
it's it's like the electronic city of
China or rather the world is like so
unfortunately Google you know they don't
have you know China don't allow street
views I think
in food so this is san-chan
they look at China you know I was I'm
just amazed by other China Development
oh they have google street views now
because back then few years ago as I
know they don't allow it because you
know China has its own you know street
views so anyway since then okay so
that's good so shall we go back to
unicode then or should we talk about you
know usually when we talk about non
technical stuff that's more fun because
technical stuff it's like you know so
let's see how many people are watching
five people yay people say hi strange
say something so let's go back to the
this language okay am i recline with
language actually I am NOT I don't know
what America is let's look
Amharic okay this is how you pronounce
it this is IPA so it's M Herrick Amharic
Amharic is one of the Ethiopian somatic
Semitic languages which are a sub
grouping within the Semitic branch of
the afro-asiatic languages Oh
Ethiopian it is spoken as the first
language by the M help M Harries as a
lingua franca by other population and so
on okay where is it then do they have a
map so where is this language is smoking
it hey no man good to see you good
evening so I'm thinking of doing a
Unicode you know I'm going to add a unit
whole page like you know so this is this
is the writing system for Amharic
language it's interesting because you
know it looks you know exotic and it has
this punctuation symbols it's quite
interesting you see these punctuation
marks now now normally almost in every
language the punctuation well not almost
but you know in most you know popular
languages that are used the punctuation
is basically or or like the English ones
let's do the Unicode okay let's just do
this page then this Amharic language so
you go to Unicode sorry Unicode and such
for oh you have to oh you have to turn
on JavaScript
turn JavaScript
mhm eh
oops
aah so there is no Unicode that contains
the name aah so so usually it's
Ethiopian let's try FeO peon ETH okay so
it's it's using the Ethiopian script you
know the sewing in linguistics you know
in writing systems you have like
so-called script then a given script
like this one Ethiopian script you see
their names Ethiopia syllable Ethiopia
syllable you know what given a script
which is like a writing you know a
system of writing symbols you know given
script then from that you typically
derive alphabets like you have one off a
bit for one thing another alphabet for
example the Cyrillic script so you see
these are Cyrillic script they are
actually I read with you here they are
actually invented they are invented
derived from Latin alphabet for you know
some Empire Russia Russian ethnicity
related you know some you know back then
few hundred years ago oh you know maybe
five hundred years ago so they created
this this is called script Cyrillic
script it's used in these countries you
know the Russia and East Europe and you
know part of Mongolia and you know in
that region then so given the script
then you have many alphabets you know
based on that script you have Russian
Belarusian Ukrainian Bulgarian and and
so on and they are more actually so
so okay so what we're gonna do so we're
gonna add this M Herrick so so I'm
Herrick is from Ethiopia yeah it's such
again ETH yeah so all these characters
let's see okay let's just do that so I'm
going to go to my unicode page so am i
doing good guys say something okay type
when you are quiet
I'm not uncertain okay so let's create a
Unicode so this is my unicode page and
on the left panel you can see all my
Emacs commander I call so I'm going to
go to actually Cyr wait Cyr I okay open
that copy the path close close go
through my programming blog add a new
section pasted here make it into a link
copy it paste it again
then we're gonna say ETH IO thick now
the file name should it be Ethiopia or
Ethiopian well it should be easy o poq
yeah so you know when I'm creating these
pages I have to like do a lot of
so-called research you know read about
them so I can you know when you write
book when you are author of a book you
have you know you will encounter a lot
issues you know about writing book about
the title about paging issues about what
you know choices and formatting
decisions you know lots of these same
thing with when when you create a
website for example right now I'm
creating a new page for the M Herrick
alphabet so first of all I learned it's
part of ethiopia ethiopians script so I
mean the first question is like what
should I name the file
what should the file name be should it
be Ethiopia or Ethiopian or should it be
Ethiopian alphabet you know they are
those are decisions you know you write
website for like 20 years now so I I now
I know the issues I usually know what I
want to how I should name the file you
know the name of the file may not be
important but actually it has some
significance because web search engines
you know depend on it and you know when
you pass a URL to people people also
look at the URL so actually there's some
important also one thing I learned I can
tell you guys is that okay scratch that
because you know it's it's there's no
actually hard decision like exactly
which name is the better but anyway
let's just name let's let's look at
Ethiopian a little bit so Ethiopians
somatic languages so what is so
Ethiopians submit some somatic Ethiopian
somatic is a group of languages spoken
in Ethiopia and Eritrea so where is it
Leo Pia with a small population of
Tigris because incident oh okay so it's
in Middle East and oh my god Middle East
that's that's a sensitive topic you know
in America okay it's over there so good
evening Nick says how to take note of
code block side by side how to take note
of code block side by side like CA CSS
and HTML code embedded in
the two times two table format 2x2 table
format I true I try to find lighter
markup language but I found pure HTML
format is the most powerful okay
do you like are you asked me a question
or is it just an opinion I'm not sure
what do you mean by take note of code
block block side by side yeah you know
if you clarify I answer that so anyway
let's go back to let's just create so we
know what is if you appear Ethiopia
it's okay so the question now is is
there what's the difference between
Ethiopian languages versus Ethiopian
Semitic languages is that just so so
does Ethiopian generally just refer to
Ethiopian somatic or is it is there like
another branch of Ethiopian but for now
let's just name it
Ethiopia so I so I'm going to come and
HTML copy whose size ta me I'll copy
okay
so I'll copy HTML there okay I created
it copy the file open it name the title
correctly and update the date delete
that and D delete and I want to select
that
showing browser empty page Unicode
Ethiopia that's what we want okay now
open the file make a backup then I'm
going to copy all these characters let's
do that
papi
pace it here it takes a while
Emacs is trying to find the font okay so
it's done and the selected save narrow
to region and call space to new like saw
space to new line okay and what are
these this okay they don't have a font
see ryuk later best wait how are they
wireless you read see Reich
okay so that's actually I need to type
the whole thing so ETH I yeah I should
copy these instead so let's copy that
copy select all paste now saw space to
newline now I'm going to record amok
well start mark well move to the right
we have wrap the mock tag then stop
marker and I'm gonna apply it to all
these primal code to region lines okay
now why don't know add a dive tag okay
now showing browser great it's done so
now let's go to each shell and just
upload to my website
Daniel says oak comes with the fast and
intuitive table editor yeah not Kippy
not keep Lee says Ethiopian is probably
Amharic a Semitic language since
wikipedia says that's the language of
government in lingua franca so Ethiopian
so I mean Ethiopian is that a family of
languages or is it just referred to
Amharic you know because sometimes you
know Ethiopian refers to like oh maybe I
I think I know what you mean so it
actually just referred to Amharic I
guess I mean okay I mean most I mean
practically speaking yeah because you
see we are seeing all these Ethiopia
syllables okay so I have uploaded to my
website and you can see now there's one
more thing I need to do I needed to add
it to the panel on the bottom so let's
copy the file path let's copy the file
path and you can see my panel is over
here you see so this you know the for
example the first one is is emoji the
second one is hand like you can see here
hand you know if I show in browser
showing browser you see emoji hand so
I'm going to add it to where I should I
add okay maybe after a rabbit
yeah after the rabbit so let's do that
so first of all paste it here make it
linked then search for a or a B okay a
rabbit is right here but first of all
let's copy this block and call find
replace text paste it here okay because
we are going to replace the whole block
for all files in the directory so now I
just copy this line remove that go to a
rabbit and paste it here so this is the
new the new entry in this you know over
here so it's over here and I knew I need
to choose one of the characters to put
beside it you know like this so it
represents it kinds it kind of give a
visual clue to people you know what you
know visual crew so let's pick let's
pick a letter here now I need someone to
know who knows Ethiopia you know on one
hand I want to pick a letter that's like
the more exotic the better you know
because that's the fun part you know
that's how people identify you know you
know most people don't know they are not
linguistics so when you see your Chinese
you know you have no idea you know they
are you know what what it is you know
usually you you pick for example I don't
know Arabic but when I see this you know
symbol I kind of know you know it's a
rabbit because sometimes I see it you
know you in in photos right same thing
with all the other strange characters
for example he he woke
life you know it's I pick the i-4 hero
guys because that's kind of you know
that's what people recognize and then
you know be you have the deer head so I
need one for Ethiopia so I need to you
know pick one but also the character
must make make sense for those people
who understand you know Amharic or
Ethiopian language because you know for
example if you are doing Chinese and you
pick the you you picked a character you
thought is cool but the characters you
know means bad things you know you don't
want you want to avoid that so in the
same similar way I need to pick
character meanwhile you know it makes
you know it's not something stupid you
know for people who understand the
language so which one should I pick
maybe this one you know it's simple and
it's kind of fun let's do that for now
so okay let's go back here let's put it
here and let's mark it you know add the
mark tag so it appears bigger then ok
here's I'm gonna what I'm gonna do I'm
going to copy these two lines copy and
co-star find replace text so I want to
replace these two lines by by these
three lines including Ethiopia okay so I
pasted it here do it in this directory
yes
HTML files yes right to change yes
fixed case in search yes we face fixed
case in in replacement yes make backup
yes okay it so that each one of these is
a file and the yellow part is the
it's changed so it's all done now
looking browser
okay so except this one we repeated look
at browser you can see here you see we
added there now all we have to do is go
back to my programming blog then add a
to RSS so it's knowing OSS good cuz it
save and go to sync to my web server
okay that's about it you know
Emacs you know that's Emacs that's kind
of boring because I do it every day you
know for the past 20 years I'm doing
like kind of like this every day and for
people you know a lot of people
following me for my Emacs stuff they
it's good to show because you use you
rarely see other people working in Emacs
so now in this page if i refresh it now
this is my website if i refresh it you
can see there's a ethiopia here that's
great so now it's done you see you can
you know so i get you know people are
interested in unicode then okay so and
usually i have to you know now i have to
spend like a few hours reading about
ethiopia reading about you know
ethiopian semitic languages you know i
you know i read them because i am
interested in these kind of things then
after i learned something
then maybe i add some information to my
unicode page so i tell people you know
okay Ethiopia is a it's a language
that's used by you know we're you know
explain you know putting something
interesting for you know the general
public okay that that is it for this
Emacs demo with my
unicode my daily routine so let's see oh
yeah yeah wait you see this let's go
back to this page this is my body
English block you see I forgot to add
you mentioned about this section mark
this very interesting punctuation so I
think they are used in Ethiopian
languages
let's see section mark if you pick
section mark wait I should have it is
not here though a strange he th I
why is it not the Ethiopia ETH IOP I see
wait that's strange so let's search for
section mark section it's here it's here
but however it does not seems to be in
my unicode page let's go back to the my
unicorn page he--they OPIC Emacs is
taking a while to load the font because
you know why it's slow because Emacs
need to search which fund has contains
the ethiopia squid alphabet that is why
so let's search for that yeah so this is
very strange because this character this
character you see here the the Unicode
code point is 496 0 or in hexadecimal 1
3 6 0 and the name is ethiop exception
mark however if I search for Unicode
name ethiop ik apparently this mark does
not appear in my in my JavaScript search
hab eth i/o key IC s
okay I think I know what's going on I
think I may know what's going on because
yeah because I have I put a limit on how
many character it shows you know within
ones search yeah okay I think that's
something I'll fix later so oh so daniel
says nick says i try to insert code blog
in a table in oak mud but i do not know
how maybe it's not appropriate to ask
the question since you are taking notes
in HTML rather than open now I mean that
you know it's good to I don't mind and
you can you know type any questions you
have you know answer them but the thing
is I don't really use oak mod so I don't
know the answer yeah because I just
write in raw HTML and to me it's more
efficient more flexible more powerful
and for me it's faster to do it that way
so I don't use oak mod really you know
so daniel says oh cmon template system
comes with with these predefined easy
template okay
how to insert code in a table yeah I
don't I can I don't know how I'd only I
don't know the answer yeah
because I don't really use old maps oh
yeah I don't know okay so that's that's
the unicode question I mean that's the
unicode page okay what else what else
should we talk about are we talking
about Emacs or should we do a demo of
Golan or do a demo of JavaScript or
let's see let's see what's my talk show
topics san talk show so what how you
guys doing so Danielle so what what do
you being up to Nick so right now it's
let's see what time is it in China 11
o'clock in China
cincin
so that's one topic unicode so let's do
something else other than Emacs cuz you
know change your topic
oh that this one this keyboard is great
now this is a keyboard programmable
keypad so you can buy this keypad for
you know sixty dollars and each key you
can program it you can make it do
copy-paste you know cuts which window
previous tab next tab you know like what
I can do like right now next time next
tab previous tab next type next tab
close it you know or reopen the last
closed you know
like normally when you want to close a
tab you have to use your mouse to aim
for it like aim for the middle cross
site that's not good you want to for
efficiency reasons you want to avoid any
action that makes you like have to look
and check or aim you know using mouse to
aim things you don't want that so if I
want to close this tab I just you you
want things spaced on muscle memory you
know I can close my eyes and press one
key and that tab is good I can close my
eyes and move to previous tag next tab
you know or without you know it's all
muscle memory in a same way I'm using
stuff like he's in Emacs in Emacs it's
all muscle memory like you know I don't
have to like look and stuff it's you
know just by muscle memory so back to
that topic so I was saying so you got
this programmable keypad so you can
program the keys you know it's all one
key press like I can show you here is my
desktop you know right now I'm using you
know it's that's my mouse that's my
once again let's see yeah that's so you
know Mikey Bo so this this is a this is
a numeric keypad keypad but I use it for
programmable pad so I can press the key
and do things for example I'm but back
to browser you know previous had
previous tab next step next tab close to
close the tab reopen the tab you know
new new tab previous tab you know so I
programmed it so but it's best if you
get a programmable keypad so one of the
good choice is this one but let me you
know so you go to let me go go to Harley
keyboard so let's talk about keyboards a
little bit maybe so Nick say is 944 am
Oh am right so how do you sort code Sox
are keyboard blog and here you can see a
section PC keyboards
keypads okay there's a section on
keypads now these are all programmable
keypads I recommend so you can buy any
of any one of them go to my website and
buy it okay and I get a few bucks if you
if you buy it and you know this these
ones I listed here is actually the ones
I I can recommend you know if I don't
recommend your senior CI I have a
comment like for example this one I
think it's out of it's not made anymore
I'm not sure I've you know I think they
yeah yeah so you go back go back
so I have reviews on all these these are
reasonably good but if you you're for
example racer this one is very bad okay
never bad is this one if you read it you
know you'll see my opinions but I can
tell you I can tell you some of them are
good you know this one
they got actually LCD displays this one
and this one so they have LCD displays
that kind of you know that's good if you
have money you know you can buy that but
if you just want practical ki Marcos
programmable keep hands this one is very
good you can buy it and button it's got
lots of keys and this one is good this
one is not bad but kind of expensive but
anyway so you know then it's my website
so Norman says here is a curious looking
ago keyboard for you data hand
oh yeah that's old news you know I've
seen I've seen all of them so data hand
actually have a review of it let's go to
miscellaneous
oh I don't I don't act actually I do not
have a review of data hand but data hand
is one of the funky ones where you put
your hand in this kind of horse you know
each finger goes into a hole then then
your finger you know you can push up or
down or left and right it's kind of I
don't think it's very good you know and
also they being out of you know they
they have not been they've you know
they've been defunct
and it was very expensive I think it is
it sells for $400 or $500 back then but
today you know it is no longer made it's
like they've been defunct for more than
10 years yeah but as far you know so I
study your aspect of keyboards and input
systems so I've studied all kind of for
example economic keyboards those are
efficient I hope and I also have looked
into alternative type systems for
example voice input voice input is very
good okay especially for a common speech
like what I was talking like right now
let's try it let this show
[Music]
let's see view format added speech okay
yes I guess you have to turn it on so
anyway let me do that but let me talk
about it so I studied all the input
systems and there is a steno type and
there's also piano key based systems and
so far okay my conclusion is that if you
need if we are talking about if the
context is physical input systems you
know physical using your fingers okay
the piano based keyboard input systems
is the most efficient that is my current
conclusion so you want the piano bass
input system now stenotype is also good
so but you know but anyway so I'm you
know I mean if you compare piano to the
steno I think piano is still better but
anyway so so actually they they do have
piano based input system like right now
I mean so okay you know there's also bad
keyboard like that the so called coded
keyboard then there is you know that
data in hand I think Dana Han is the
worst then there's this this one is more
like for this epistle both person you
know people who don't have like you have
you don't have fingers or you know you
have problem with your fingers so uh for
a you know healthy person I think the if
you really focus okay full healthy
person and for of all input devices that
involves physical activity like using
your hand the best one the most
efficient efficient one the fastest one
is the piano based system for example
this one that that is my my current
conclusion okay so if you so you could
you know if you really want you know
buy one of these keyboards for example
this one piano text so there are
researchers you know she created a
system that lets you type you know type
anything you know programming code or
paragraph you know using the piano and
she's got a demo you know she has
someone doing a demo here so so in my
opinion yeah the piano bass is the most
efficient so you can actually use it you
know you just buy a keyboard like today
you just go buy a keyboard and you can
actually install it and start to
actually learn it but the thing and you
will be far more efficient than any any
any other way ergo dogs or whatever but
the thing about this is that it's you
know it's unusual yeah you can use it
but you know you're gonna be the only
one using it also you cannot bring it to
work you know if you go to work
you you know it's you know it's kind of
you know appropriate to have a you know
piano keyboard on your desk you know you
can but you know people are gonna ask
you questions and bug you and you know
there's gonna be a lot of eyebrow
eyebrow raising you know so that's the
issue that's a problem I mean that's a
practical kind of problem and everywhere
everywhere you go you have to like carry
your keyboard or things like that yeah
but but if you really are concerned only
about pure efficiency and speed and
ergonomics I you know piano is a way to
go and also of course you have to learn
it I mean you have to spend a lot of
time like two hours every day for the
for the next half a year to to dedicate
yourself you know study this and
practice this but you will be far more
efficient then then then I think then
even steno because you'll be typing like
300 words per minute because you know
one of the reason is because piano
keyboard once you have a key code they
are like huge amount of combinations
but why not for example why not this one
pad keyboard this is also code based you
know you press several keys at the same
time to enter later why not this one
this one is not good because first of
all if you look at just the physical
field you know it's based on keyboard
keys meanwhile if you compare to piano
now the piano are huge keys you know
they are designed so that you can easily
press multiple keys at the same time
same time and you can move to a
different place and it will be another
whole different entire different
combination you know so that's a reason
that's that's what that's the main
reason the piano hero is much more
efficient okay so any anything else what
else we should talk about I mean I'm
kind of you know so like if you guys
don't type anything then I'm like out of
topic okay no one says I remember the
space herb from years ago it is on your
website never used one oh yeah yeah I
never I never used one neither because
you know I'm just you know doing my
research and found these all these weird
things and I study how they work you
know how they operate
like what what sort of input so this one
is related to Mouse and actually this
this herb thing has a long history I
mean like thirty years back they are the
father of these eventually they become
this this space navigator which is
fairly popular today you can still buy
it
I think it's 100 something hundred
dollars there's a video review okay so
yeah so we this is the like the the
father you know the this is from year
2000 from 3d connections
I think they originated from NASA
actually or NASA was like you know the
space navigation they actually you see
space you know ships but essentially you
know but my my opinion on this device
the space of or this one is not very
high because what this thing does this
and these are basically the same thing
they are just in different shape so this
one the space oh you know it's a ball
but it's just you change the shape and
it becomes this so what what they are
you know they it is actually just like a
joystick a joystick but you can also
twist it and you can also pull it or
push it down so it's just that's that's
all it's just like more advanced you
know joystick and it's not really good
in theory because you know for example a
joystick they do not allow you to have
Bo time variable acceleration for
example if you are using a mouse or if
you are using a trackball you can go in
any direction and change speed like like
when you drive a car you can change
change your speed instantaneously like
you can press you know the gas pedal you
know more or less you know so you can so
the the speed changes you know smoothly
and continuously you can gradually go
faster you can gradually slow down or
you can slow down a bit and suddenly go
very fast like like the way I move the
mouse you know in any direction quickly
or slowly you know and continuous
changing speed that's that's a keyboard
but joystick you cannot do that a
joystick is a constant very you know
they are they cannot change speed
basically essentially they cannot change
change speed you know you know in gaming
devices they
but actually they cannot what they are
doing is actually software based speed
changing meaning that you know if you
push in one direction more then it's
faster yeah you know it's kind of like
that so why don't I design my own
keyboard and do the business that's
that's easier said than done
you know yeah it was yeah so you know
I'm not the business person you you know
Yoda I can design sure I can
like you know also I'm not a physical
I'm not much of a chronic engineer I can
design things but I'm not you know I
don't know actually
electronics much but anyway suppose I
want to you know I can't study
electronics and and create 3d models and
make you know make a prototype you know
by 3d printers and make a prototype
that's one thing you know I'm not I that
I can possibly do but after that you
know that's that's not the main thing
the main thing is actually go to many
manufacturers you need you need people
to market it you know you need to you
know find a you need people who can talk
to manufacturers you know you need a
business plan you need you know you know
money you know did venture capitalist or
whatever you know oh you know kickstart
you know sort of you know it's it's not
easy you know you have to then you have
to talk to people you have to have the
ability to you know negotiate you know
and you know have dates you know it's
you know that's that's not my thing
hey Nicholas good morning nickers okay
good evening
actually I think we kind of talked along
and one hour so we any what's what what
else
maybe we call it a day
so I wanted to do a Chinese video yeah
so maybe that's it for today unless you
guys have questions
just type it type it or else that I mean
you know I'm kind of kind of topic today
so I'm gonna talk to China in Chinese a
bit as some sounds oh I got some
wondered so in the 10 hi this is
Michelle watch I'm Trina got peedee
peedee peedee wanna go son knowing good
didn't I say on the Hollywood and cut
this is the unknown 10 had Ahad how
y'all so G ha machine a me oh so G so
yeah Shane Shane Oh Angus oh gee I'm am
was also so so I think that's it then so
I I'll see you guys I'll see you guys
next time
thanks for coming