Hello guys, good morning everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Sound Talk
Show. We are going to do wuam language
graphics programming uh mathematical
artwork. So we we're going to do a
density plots of trick expressions. So
here are some
examples. Uh so this is done like 30
years ago and I'm going to update it. So
you're going to learn some wam language
or also known as mathematica coding and
some uh tech techniques of creating
mathematical art or generative
art. So these are some examples of all
these are called density plots or also
known as heat map and uh of
trigonometric
uh functions. Okay. So it's fascinating
and
beautiful. Okay. So for those of you
coders or into science and mathematics
and students if you are watching offline
play at 1.5 speed because I ramble and I
talk slowly more composed that way. So
you can play at 1.5 or 1.7
uh speed and uh skip
around. And my keyboards glove at
fantastic. I'm a keyboard obsessive
keyboard um uh expert you might say a
official. This is uh Gravity ultimate
hacking keyboard Nulia Track Logitech
405 I think
502. And the most fantastic device is
this one. Uh this one is called SWAL
board. S V A L B O A R D with magnetic
uh device. Uh so magnetic switches.
Okay. So for each one of these keyboard
I talked about I have a video review.
Just search for YouTube or search for
kasari.info for all these
devices. Okay. So play at 1.5 speed. If
you are here say hi. Love to see your
comments.
Okay, pop out chat and put it here. So,
let's see. Concurrent viewers zero.
Fantastic. Okay, so let's begin wam
language coding. Okay, let's Okay,
so increase that size. Increase that
size. And can you see my screen? Yes.
And let's go to the top. This
is BW curtain. This artwork I would name
it. I actually I just created this an
hour ago. Uh so 30 years ago it looks
like that but I you know I did a little
bit. I changed the expression range. So
I created that. So usually so when you
create artwork you have to give it a
name. So what would this be? Uh, right
now it's PW curtain, black and white
curtain because it looks
like curtain. Okay, so maybe you should
call it sinosoid curtain or uh
something. Anyway, so let's begin
coding. So let's Oh, yeah. So uh I need
to get my Emacs over
here. Okay. And start wam language.
begin. And if you don't know, Wufam
language is free since about like six
years ago. So if you don't know already,
so let's uh go to talk show uh go to
today's talk show and uh there is my
wuam language tutorial
on.info. Just search for it. You'll find
uh the location, the link to download
free. Uh and if you want to do graphics,
you need if you need uh graphics, you
need uh to install Jupiter notebook or
there's also one called uh wolf
JavaScript front end. Okay, so here is
Jupyter notebook. So you can code wra
language in um with
graphics. Okay, so this is Wuam
language. Let's magnify. Let's say three
shift enter to get it start the kernel.
Um you know the wuam the way wam
language works is that you have the
so-called kernel which is the wuam
engine. It does all the computation.
Then you have something called front end
which is like this one notebook is the
front end or editor. It can be emac it
can be vs codes you know. So, so the
front end is where you type stuff.
Whenever you press shift enter, it sends
the expression to the woofam engine via
a protocol. So, you have the kernel, you
have the front end. Front end is your
editor or you know VS code, Emacs,
notebook, whatever. So, whatever you
type, it sends the information to the
kernel which is wam engine. Then the
kernel send it back. So it it does
things in a like a server protocol way
since like
198689. So anyway, so so if you if you
want graphics, you need to install the
Wam language kernel for Jupiter
notebook. Okay. So there's another one
also. You might check out this one.
What's the difference between wam
language, Mathematica, Wuam Engine, Wuam
script? Seems confusing for newbies.
Okay. So, today's talk show, let me put
the links here. So, let's say show
today's talk show link. And uh let's put
the link here so people can see it
later. So, we talked about Jupiter
notebook. That's what you want to get.
And go back to wam language tutorial on
sardi.infos. Just search for it. You'll
find it. Wam language in depth from the
ground up. Okay. uh but what we want is
like the alternative or clones. So there
are many tools other people created. So
one of them is Wuham language JavaScript
notebook. Okay, I have a friend Huang
who told me that this is actually better
than Jupiter notebook. So you might try
this one
instead. Uh I don't use them because I
have wam language you know. Uh they sent
it to me. I bought it like I bought it
in
1992. So I became kind of acquaintance
with uh Stefan Wuen. So anyway, so Wuen
language. Yeah. So let's go back to
start to code. Okay. So let me just post
that here. So link go to it. Okay. So
today we're going to do trick density
plots of trick expressions. Okay. These
are for artistic purposes artwork. you
know if you are a Zoomer generation if
you are a young guy you might know it as
like generative art but that's no good
so yesterday or two days ago we did a
talk show on algorithmic mathematical
art you might check that one out uh
where I tell you all the techniques in
creating mathematical artwork and uh
what is the difference between
generative art and uh mathematical art
with a structure. So all these are
mathematical art with a structure. It's
not random. Okay. So anyway, so let's
get to it. Um if you are here, say hi.
Okay. So let's go to trick um trick
expressions. Um so this one. Okay. So
this one is uh here is the code. Okay.
So let's go to where the code is. Okay.
Save. uh make a backup and pop this out.
So this is the
expression and uh copy it. Go to wam
language. You can plot it. There it is.
There it is how it looks like. And uh
you see it's kind of fuzzy. You see 30
years ago it supposed to look like
that. Uh so how do you do that? Well, I
can show you. So you need a color
function. Okay, copy it. And uh you need
to
say so here this is the expression and
this is the range x from uh wait x from
-10 pi to 10 pi okay so actually let's
just okay then you want to say color
function color function that's how you
want to control what color to use. So by
the way what is density plot? Okay so
that is a plot of a function and this
function takes two arguments XY and it
returns one thing Z one number. Okay so
it takes two numbers and returns one
number. So the returned value is like
the height. So for example you can plot
this one. So well let's um uh let let
okay wait. Uh so we got multiple things
going on. Let's let's do one thing at a
time. Okay. So let's talk about
uh plot 3D.
Okay. So normally you plot 3D. Suppose
you plot a function. So this is uh your
function form looks like that. Okay. So
um so it's function of two variables.
Okay. So let's say
sine x
y. Okay, that's two variables. Okay,
fantastic. And uh and from let's say 3
pi to 3 pi. Okay, so same thing here. 3
pi to 3 pi. And we don't want color
function. So
that okay. So it's like uh very you know
uh rough that's
not okay that's
um so you want to increase the plot
points plot points okay let's say 30 on
each side do it so now it's like more
dense and you can you see but it's not
it's still not very smooth because this
function so happens it goes up up and
down very fast. So if you want to
increase the smoothness, you have to say
um max recursion let's say
four. Uh so that's getting a bit
technical. That's about that's about um
because whenever you plot something when
the function's value changes a lot in a
short
distance the wolf language will try to
plot more points you know in that short
region so it becomes more smooth
uh and that basically how much how many
how how many levels that goes is
controlled by max recursion so let's try
that okay do
So basically the plot you see now it's
much better. You see very much more fine
grain and I don't like the color. So
let's change the color. So anyway
so plot points and max recursion. These
two are uh the fundamental way to
control how fine you want the graphics.
So let's paste that there. There. So we
got a new expression. Uh, delete that.
Okay. So, uh, yeah. So, that that and
what else we want? Let's change the
color of the plot. Okay. Because I don't
like this yellowish. That was a new
color default color scheme since about
like uh 15 years
ago. So, color. Well, there are so many
options to control color. So, I don't
remember. Uh so you look up the
documentation for plot 3D and turn on
JavaScript and uh okay
magnify. Okay. So you have like lots of
options. Call out blah blah blah out 3D
options axis box ratio clipping style
color function. Uh that's not what we
want. Uh well color
function okay let's try color function
black and white
okay so color function you so right now
I'm using kas emac
uh kasawa wuam mod which allows me to
code wam language in emacs but you can
directly type it here of course I like
to use emac because I have I'm using
softly keys. If you you know this is for
you Emacs users so keys allows me to
edit expressions uh much more
efficiently. Uh like Vim's model key
binding but much more efficient. So you
can watch a video there. This is for you
Emacs
users. Uh you can use VS Code too of
course. I think there's a VS Code plugin
for Wam language.
Yeah. So for but for Emacs users you
might check out SFly keys. So you don't
have to press hold on control hold on
alt hold meta then press then meta
something you know. So so that's keys.
Okay. And I'm using
um wan mod. So you can see kasawa mod
here. It's free. uh about 3,000 lines of
code. This is the website. Search for
it. Kasawa woofer mod Emacs. You will
find it. It's on GitHub and Softly Keys
is also on GitHub. Okay. So, copy that.
Close that. Close that. Go to today's
talk show. In fact, do I have uh not
here? So, to go to today's talk show.
So, you can see like keys there mod.
Okay.
So now we uh we go back to work on this
expression. Okay. So what what uh what I
wanted to do color function. Okay. Now
uh arrow then gray level. Gray level
basically is a function that returns
black levels of black and white. So this
will just make it black and white.
Check. Double check. That's good. Paste
it. Run it.
Ching Hank, thank you so much, Hank.
Thank you so much. And thank you for the
PayPal donation and thank you for uh
giving me a free game. I have not yet to
I have to look it into, you know, I
haven't seen it yet, you know, because
I'm lazy, you know, my emails piled up,
so I'm gonna check it out. Hello. Hello,
Mars. So, thank you, Hank.
So, so, so yeah. So, now we got this
much better. Okay. So, you see this like
thousands tens of thousands of points.
So, it's um you know, so so let's let's
let's change it again. Let's change it
so that we don't plot that much uh pi.
Let's just say pi. Okay, let's not plot
so many. So there. Now paste uh where
did you paste and let's go here. Paste.
Run
it. Fantastic. And beautiful. Now this
is more beautiful. Okay. So you can see
now it's black and white. Okay. So right
now we are plotting a function of two
variables. Okay. And the function output
a single number that is the height.
Okay. So for any such function you can
also do density plot. Okay. So let me
show you cut paste. Uh let's uh let's I
don't want that. Okay. Copy that. Paste
it here. Make a breaker. Then here you
say
density plot. Okay. Instead instead of
plot 3D. So what that will do it will
instead of creating a 3D image it will
just give you a density plot. You see
that's what density plot means or you
know sometimes you call it um heat map.
Okay. So that's what this density plot
is about. Let's go back to our you see
so all these are like density plot.
Okay.
Beautiful. Okay. So now we explained you
know what is density plot and plot you
know so then now what we do yeah we
wanted to originally
uh yeah originally we were plotting
let's go back to the beginning this one
we want to make it more beautiful I
don't like this one currently is like
fuzzy so what you want to do is so
okay so Let's uh make a color function.
Let's again use uh another thing you can
do is you can use hue. Hue is a function
that returns all different colors. It's
uh hue, saturation, and
uh brightness. Okay, that's a color
model. So if you say hue, it's going to
get you a rainbow color. Okay, so we can
try it. Okay, so let's try it here.
Uh yeah, paste
it. This is much more beautiful. Yeah, I
like it.
Fantastic. Okay, so let's save this uh
save this untitled. Okay, so now what we
want to do uh but this is not dense
enough. So yeah, so let's let's do
another improve it. We don't want 10.
So, so you see trig functions s cosine
tangent so on they have a peri periodicy
of 2
pi and
uh so so right now what what how many
cycle are there like one two three so we
have 10 so let's just make it 2 pi okay
so replace 10 by two do do okay because
we then we get the finer um like we can
see uh more of the detail.
So, okay, paste it
there. Okay, so you see now we started
to see the
uh small area of it. And now we can like
before we can increase the resolution
because now it's like fuzzy. Okay, now
we want to increase the resolution.
That's this two.
Copy it and paste it here. Okay. So
wait. So we can paste it here. So plot
point is the initial number of points to
evaluate on each side X and Y. And max
recursion four. Okay. Let's do
that. Okay. So now we are getting
improvements. Paste it there. Run
it. Okay. So that's not so you know it's
not so it's it's a bit better but not so
much. So plot points
um let's say 40 will it become better?
Not really. Let's say max recursion
five.
Okay. Max recursion
seven. Okay. It's not so good.
I mean you can you still see this kind
of it's not so smooth. Why is that? And
uh and you can for example you can make
it plot 3D just to see what this thing
looks like in
3D. Okay. Yeah, it looks like that.
Okay. not not too interesting.
Okay. So this is now about artistic
design. You see our
goal, you know, if you are a
mathematician or engineer, you need to
know what this function looks like and
that's how you do it. Sometimes you need
this, you know, heat map form for for
reasons, you know. So you better
understand, you know, heat map or
whatever. heat flow or
whatever. But for for for for us, we are
doing this like an artwork. So now it's
time
to, you
know, we we want to be able to like we
want it to be beautiful. So it's it's
about creativity, our taste, you know,
what kind of color we want to use it. So
for example another color we can use is
um red. Okay. So if you say hue uh let's
say
um hue takes three things. The first
element is hue. So zero means red. Hue
basically that's a rainbow color. red,
red, orange, yellow,
green, blue, violet, you know, things
like that. So zero is so the the color
value range from zero to one. So zero is
red and one is red too. So
uh and saturation saturation will be a
function. Okay. Uh and brightness let's
say zero. So we want this to be a
function. So let's write a function.
Okay. So that Okay. So you can
see this expression is a function that
takes one number and returns a color.
And this color will arrange from
basically uh shades of red. Okay. So
copy
it and go back here and paste
it. Okay. We got it incorrect. Something
is wrong. So this hue is not returning
the correct
value.
Um color
function hue red
saturation. Oh, okay. So that's uh wait.
That's a saturation. Why is it all
black? I don't understand. Okay, hold on
a second. my alarm
clock.
[Music]
Uh that is my alarm clock telling me to
get up and walk to prevent ass
rot from sitting too
long. Okay. Comments. Renato says, Weld
says, Weld says, "Hello, thank you for
your talk show. It's very instructive."
Thank you. I can see you got a math, you
know, you got a 3D geometry, 3D space,
uh, special geometry manifold,
threedimensional
manifold profile photo. So,
fantastic. Uh, Reinato says, "I'm a
mathematician." Wow, that works with
numerical methods for differential
equations and most of the time I use
Python
uh or parallel C++ that's
fantastic you know mathematicians and
engineers they are great
uh and of Hank says uh hey numpy yeah
Python yeah Python is hugely popular um
but for you Python is like very super
popular you know and it's free too
um but um anyway so let's you know so so
so I want to find out what is wrong here
so
um why is that not color function why is
that not
working so maybe okay so let's try this
okay zero X. So that will be from black
to red. Uh,
no. Oh. Oh, right. That's something I
forgot. Zero means black. No saturation.
So you need to say one. One is the
brightest there. That's what we want. So
you see so now it's a matter of creativ
artistic vision creativity and taste you
know to see you know how you like you
know do you want something like that or
do you want
um you know something like that I I like
this one you know I like this one red
bloody okay so that's about you know
that's basically how all these uh images
work Okay. So, this one is created 30
years ago. Uh, you know, so and I need
to update it. So, let's for now let's
just use this one. Okay. Let's, you
know, let me show you my like my
workflow. How do I create this uh, you
know, website
page? So, now we know we want this one.
Okay. So, let's um make it easier to
read.
Okay. So, we want this one. And uh what
is the previous one? Uh wait, there too
many confusing. Okay. Go to top. Delete
that. Delete that. Delete that. Delete
that. This is what we want. And this is
a PL 3D version. Okay, that's good. And
this. Delete that. New paste. Go back
here. Put it back. color syntax color
show it here. Okay, so here's a
code and this image dust wave. I don't
like it. Delete it. Okay. And now we
want uh this kind of red
bloody. Yeah. So I like this one. So
let's use this one. Okay. So,
let's do a
screenshot. You can you can also export
it, but I usually just prefer
screenshot. Okay, screenshot. And then
some Emacs magic to move the screenshot
here. Open it. Fantastic. And uh let's
say what kind of name you know if you
are artist you create an image usually
you want to name it for easy reference.
So
uh blood tinge something like
that. Okay. You could also say red tinge
but red tinge is
not is is is
is worse name because red just color
name. It's not like too meaningful. But
if you say blood everyone understand
from millions years ago even before we
have the word
because our blood is red. So I name this
let's just say blood tinge for now.
Okay. So that's
fantastic. Okay. And here's a code.
Okay. So we finished one of them and and
the rest of them is kind of similar.
Okay. So you know you just you just do
experiment um about these artistic
things. Okay. So now four to make it a
new
section. Paste it. For example, that
one. Oh, that one will take a
minute. Uh because this one turn, you
know, this black white curtain turns out
is
very I'll show you. Okay, I'll show you
a 3D version of this because the because
because just like
um you know just like this one it goes
up and down and the closer you know so
there are many there are infinite number
of places it goes up and
down in in infinite more more and more
frequency. So it's going to so you know
this is going to take forever. It take
two minutes
maybe. So numpy sci torch matt plot
live. Yeah those are you know today's
popular python
stuff. Yeah. Uh you know so yeah. So
let's see.
Um maybe that's it for today. So you
know that's you know we you know the
rest of it I can just like try to do it
myself. Uh but you get to know you know
how to do it
basically. Uh let's wait for this to
finish maybe. Um
well this is okay.
So maybe that's it for today. So what
else? So the other thing interesting. So
this so this is about artistic creation
of mathematical art. So but you see I've
manually created you know some of these
very interesting uh
images but you see but but what are the
how many possibilities are there? You
know, by the way, look at this one. I
don't know if you can see it well
because via video sometimes, you know,
the fine details you don't see, but this
one you can see there's a pattern. Okay,
there's a cross pattern. Subtle, very
subtle. And uh let's let's let's open
it. Okay, so if you
magnify, you can see very subtle details
this
one. Uh and
uh Okay.
So, okay, let's stop
that. Yeah. So, so how many
possibilities are there? Basically,
infinite because you have you can have
infinite number of of functions. But
what about if you limit the function
just to the combination of trigonomic
trigonometric expression s
cosine tangent or squared of them or
square root of them or their product
there some stuff like that. How many
possibilities? Of course infinite.
So you want to be able to create a
random expression involving sin cosine
power sin cosine power and uh also their
sum their product. So you want to get a
random possible combination of
them that's very interesting. So you
know so you can generate a random
expression then you can plot it and
see you know like like the image you
never thought of before because
otherwise manually you know you could
only came up with a few expressions. So
so you want this random sign uh trick
function. Okay. So that is what this
code did does. Uh but this is this code
you know it it it generate a list of 10
or more you know by whatever you want um
random trick expressions combination of
trick expressions
uh so but I wrote this code 10 years ago
so today it won't run because this this
package discrete
combinator is gone it's now building uh
so you need to I need to find about you
know what is a
new way to do it but
uh but I tried to do it it's not trivial
okay so hold on a second let me let me
let's clean up this okay uh
let's function of
two
parameters return one value okay So this
is like explanation of what this plot
and density plot. Okay. So
cut close it. Let's uh put in talk show
today.
So today's talk show. So let's put the
code
here. Color it show. Okay. That's the
explanation of the density plot.
Uh okay so but now I wanted to show uh
let's
see talk show density plot okay talk
show what what is it uh oh it came up so
it's done you see so now it's done
uh what I want to show yeah so I want to
talk about you know so so this
expression is very
um let me yeah so let me talk about
that. So paste it here and
uh make it saw wa mod. Okay. So that's a
code. So what this does is given
s
cosine at a list of
functions. Okay.
Write a function that returns a random
combination of them that
returns a
expression that
is random combination of them. Okay. So
that that is what this code does. Okay.
Like you you want to make it all
possible
subset. Uh but but this code I wrote is
like 30 years ago using kind of advanced
syntax. So you know it's
incomprehensible. So in order to rework
this first of
all I need to you know this package
combinatoria is gun uh but it's built
in. So you need to find
like you know you need to find the
building uh alternative and but first
job is to find out what exactly how my
code works. That way you can rewrite it.
Okay. But this is this is going to take
me like two hours
because fairly complicated code. So
here's a chart challenge. Okay. So for
you know if you like to try this is an
interesting uh coding
problem in Python or
whatever in Python or whatever your
favorite programming
language write a
function search that uh search
that. So let's give the function a name.
So
um
expression
random okay random expression takes
uh takes
uh takes a list two arguments. Okay. n.
Okay. Now the takes two arguments a
function list and uh a integer positive
integer.
Okay. Now function
list is a list of
functions such as
uh let's see such as
sine sine cosine
um inverse inverse is like 1 /x okay
like you know flip it inverse then and
the power and uh plus and uh plus is
called addition
Um addition. So what's what is the name
for the function of addition? Usually
it's called plus. Okay. Plus and
multiply. So multiply. What's the name
for the process of multiplication?
That's usually called times.
Okay. Okay. So function list is a list
of such
functions. Uh but there's a difference.
Okay. So you see sign takes one
argument, cosine takes argument, inverse
takes one argument, power
takes power takes two arguments. So plus
also takes two or more arguments.
Anyway, you can refine the details. So a
list of functions n is a
integer for example three. Okay.
uh it says how
many expressions
to return. Now return value return a
list of
random
combination
of fun
list. Okay, that is the problem. So this
is a programming challenge.
for you coders out
there. Okay. And here is all the wam
language solution. That's that's not
working. So I I have to work on it.
Okay. So but let's put this back. Okay.
Cut it. Let's put that in today's talk
show. Paste it.
syntax color. Show
it. Okay. So, I think that's it. Thank
you guys for watching. Uh yeah. Is there
anything else? I think that's it. Thank
you guys for
watching. Uh you if you like my stuff,
post my
YouTube to your Twitter, to your social
network, to your Instagram, to your blog
or whatever. to tell your friends and
you can sponsor me. Thank you to today's
sponsor that is
you. Okay, go
to.info all the way bottom to the
bottom. You can PayPal me, Patreon me,
Amazon gift card me. Okay, $100 one shot
would be
appreciated. Anything else? Okay, maybe
that's it. I think that's it. Um, we
closed down. I
think in five minutes in three
minutes if there's no more
questions. Okay, so we we did this.
Yeah, we did this. Um, fantastic. Oh,
yeah. So, one more thing, let's show
let's show what does this thing actually
looks like. Okay, so it's very
um complicated. So it's going to be plot
3D. So you can easily see now plot
points. Let's say um 10 because it's
going to take forever. Okay. So
let's do
it. Okay. So you can you can kind of see
how complicated that thing is. You
see? Now let's say plot point
Wow. You know this going to be very
Okay. Power point 20.
Okay. Okay. So, you can see you got this
like very weird thing. Okay. And you see
you see this this
this
grove you know they are like a hole but
inside the hole as you get near near to
the center there's more fluctuation the
more near to the center of the hole
there's more flu fluctuation so it's
like black hole you know that that's
where chaos you know happens but you see
they They don't go much. They don't go
up very very big but you know but it's
inside there. So that is why when you
plot the density plot or heat map it
looks like that. You see this you you
see this inside. Let's magnify.
Okay. Let's
see. You see they just go you know like
inside there's like lots of things going
on.
Okay, thank you guys for watching. Bye.