Hello guys, good evening. Fantastic.
Welcome to another episode of S talk
show. Another episode of S talk show. We
are going to do coding of Emac Bisp. Now
if you came here because of this girl,
that girl is generated by Guac AI. Okay?
So you would be disappointed. It's
generated. It's a AI image. Okay? And I
got nothing to do in this video. We are
just going to talk about coding. Very
boring. Nothing to do with this hard
stuff. But she but it's amazing. You see
artificial intelligence machine can
generate this and and guac also
generated a video. So uh let me show
you. So magnify.
Okay. So you can see it's actually a
video. So quite amazing.
Okay. But what we what we going to do is
just coding. Okay. This this coding
makes the artificial intelligence
possible. That's what we doing. Okay. So
if you are here, say hi. Love to see
your comments. And if you are not here,
play at 1.5 speed. Okay. So we are doing
Emacs Lisp. If you don't know what is
Emac this, well, I don't need to
explain. This video is probably not for
you. Okay, so I'm not going to explain.
Okay, Emacis. So, we're going to do some
UU ID. Uh, some quite interesting thing
about UU ID. So, let me tell you what it
is. Okay, now UUID um is a um let me
explain what is UID. EU ID is a it's
called universal
well it's easier if we just look up
Wikipedia okay so universal
identification okay universally um
unique identifier that's what it means
okay
uh that's
it you know that's what it means so let
me show you let's generate a UID so cool
UI ID generate UU ID. Do it. Uh actually
um you need to um
uh insert UU ID. So I have a command
insert random UU ID. Do it.
Okay, you see that's a UU ID. Now can
you see it? Can you guys see it? Does
that make sense? Okay, that's a U ID. So
do it again cuz I insert random UID. Do
it. So press press TU. Do it again.
uh press press TU that's my key for that
that's those are UU ids so it's
basically
uh
128 bits but written as sequence of
hexadimals.
So you got this um you you got let's see
uh 128 divided by 4 let's see 128. So
it's uh let's invoke our calculator.
Okay. So you got 128
128 divided by 4. That's how many
hexadimals you have. But we can let's
try to do this in in the brain. Even
though I'm 30% drunk.
I'm 30% drunk because I'm drinking red
wine
for at this time of the day to soothe my
soul.
Okay. So you see arithmetics uh 128
divided by four that would be uh four
answer that's three. So third so so
third uh 43 382 so 32 so that will be 32
characters of hexadimal so let's run it
run this
what 512 what oh divide not times okay
run it you see 32 is the answer okay so
128 binary digits equals to 32 hexad
decimal because one hexadimal is
represents four
bits binary number four digits okay so
you see you know I've been in my coding
life in the first like 20 years I don't
know much about these things because I'm
not interested in bits and bit diddling
and bit shift and [ __ ] okay
uh because I'm interested in mathematics
geometry, differential geometry,
calculus, uh you know the the graph
theory, lots of very deep complex
problems and computability.
Well, but after 20 years, you started to
know some of the low-level stuff like
bits and hexadimals. So, so what I'm
saying is that if you are the type of
people who code in C programming
language, actually most vast majority
majority of industrial coders you guys
are like you code in C or C++ you know
or Goland or Rust then you are you would
be familiar with these uh bits like um
let's uh wait let's reopen again. So
that's a bit d bit bit ddling okay 128
bits binary digits 128 means 128 um what
I'm saying is that binary digits so you
have you have 128
digits of binary numbers zero and one
and they correspond so to correspond to
32 heximal digits okay so 188 binary
digit can be represented by represented
by um 32 hexadimals. So how many are
there? So you do count words. So you can
see there are 36 characters
not 32. Why? So because there's one
dash, two dash, three dash, four dash.
They added four dashes to make it easier
to see. So it's actually so you actually
get 32 hexadimals. Anyway, so what I'm
saying is this these are called UU ID.
Okay, so UUID is a standard
that is meant to be a universal
universally unique identifier. Okay, so
uh sample of UU ID. Okay, so let's show
in browser. So
beautiful Chinese, you know, ch well,
you know, I'm not sure she's my type,
but this this is hot hard picture
generated by artificial intelligence.
You see, in order to understand
artificial intelligence like guac and
all that, we need to know all these UU
ID and stuff and binary digits and
hexadimal.
You see like today we are in an AI age
because in an AI era. So let me talk
random a little bit. Okay. So we are in
an AI era like you know like average
person like like what what do you do?
What do you do every day
you know they there are there are
millions of uh streamers you know live
streamers right? Why why do you watch
me? Like what why do you watch any one
of them? Like today if you want to learn
coding you can ask AI AI will actually
answer your question and even write code
for you. So this a AI era is like
fascinating and actually we so what will
happen I mean my question the question
that interests me is that what will
happen to humanity what you know will
your society change in some way or will
it change even drastically in some like
unknown way or perh perhaps in a crisis
situation you know like the AI takeover
for example in science fictions. So
there's lots of these questions. So
anyway, so I've been okay, I digressed
over, but anyway, what what I'm saying
here is that you see with all these AI,
you know, like there's lots of scams and
random idiotic opinions, scammers, they
tell you about, oh, AGI is going to do
this, therefore if you are coder, you
must do this in order, you know, to be
safe or whatever. idiots like huge
amount of scam about AI on on Twitter,
on like Reddit, on everywhere. Okay,
they going to tell you something. But
anyway,
but you see but but you see what
actually um
you see however AI is advanced. I think
it's important to know that we somebody
has to know all this code. Okay,
somebody needs to understand binary
digits. Human, animals, some human.
Okay. Needs to understand binary digits,
hexodimal
digits, computer science, sign, cosine,
mathematics, topology, you know, all the
branches of group theory, algebraic,
uh, algebra, you know, all the branches
of mathematics and computer science like
some some human animals, some, you know,
you still to need to learn it like all
the young people like you think about
the younger generation. Hello uh Neimar
you think about all the young uh people
you know who are born every minute right
the next generation do you think they
you know so they can just like oh they
don't know they don't have to know
anything because AI
well not really actually some some some
people they actually we humans you know
at least part of us they need to know we
need to know so this teaching about you
know programming the hardcore like very
you know hardcore uh binary digits
hexadimal digits or mathematics computer
science theoretical computer science
formal languages term rewriting system
like wam language and mathematics
mathematics cycle like we need to know
that
and but you might say well um you know
anyway so I'm kind of like digressing
ing all over. But but I think you know
amidst all these random scams about the
people like tell you about AI especially
I'm talking to you guys young people
like those of you who are let's say aged
around 20 let's say below 25 okay I'm
talking about you guys you guys are my
audience at this moment okay I'm I'm
directly addressing you guys those below
age 20. So you guys, you know, you guys
don't know what's going on. You know,
you guys were like all of a sudden in
the past 3 years encountered this AI age
while all your life is in in the Zoomer
life, the Zuma situation where every
post is fake news, dramatic, you know,
like so I'm I'm addressing you guys.
Okay. So, and you guys are talking about
like Bitcoin. Oh, you know, Bitcoin or
crypto this or that or the blockchain
technology, you know, or or what's the
current situation or the white men or
whatever racial issues and the other,
you know, I'm talking about. So, I'm
talking I'm addressing you guys
uh
well in particular like usually
typically white Americans in USA, okay?
uh below age 25 but in general below age
25 I'm addressing you guys cheers. So
what I'm saying so you guys you know you
you you you you got bombarded you you
know all of a sudden you got this chat
GPT in the past three years and you are
young you know you are just like 20some
right you you don't
well you wouldn't know but unless like
when when you know usually when you
reach 50 then you you can kind of see
you know at least I have like 20 20 or
30 more years like 30 more years
experience than you. But anyway, what
I'm saying is that so you guys you know
being bombarded with all these uh AI and
so you may not know what to do you know
what what to make of it. So I'm telling
you guys
first of all like almost everything you
see about AI like artificial
intelligence like you you go to Twitter
like that's all half of it is like what
you see about artificial intelligence
like oh Jesus all kind of drama and [ __ ]
and and today lots of it is AI generated
stuff right like like you know almost
like all of this is a AI generated stuff
so anyway I'm telling you guys Like a
lot of people will say AGI first of all
is going to fire programmers. That's not
true. Okay. Well, they're going to fire
the first batch of people out of job are
the idiotic programmers like you. Okay.
Like you zoomers like 20s something. You
like you you never actually learned real
coding like the binary digits or
whatever. I'm like the stuff usually I'm
talking about.
Well, of course, because you don't know
code, of course, you're going to go
because AI take over your job because
you don't you you are a no nothinger.
Okay, you are a no nothinger.
Of course, AI is going to take your job
first because you actually don't know
anything. Okay, that's a that's you
zoomer people. Okay, the the first the
first thing AI going to read of is is
you Zuma people like don't know nothing.
Uh, bra I'm 28. That's great. Okay. So,
so anyway, so, so anyway, what I'm
saying is that you know, you see this
AI.
So, what will actually happen? Actually,
nobody knows. That's what that's the one
of the important thing to know because
typically you you human animals, we like
to see more dramatic and confident
answers. We like to know like if if
somebody says oh AI going to do this for
sure AGI is going to arrive in 5 years
or 3 years you know like you know they
they they sound so confident you know so
they they are more dramatic and
attractive so they get like millions of
millions of views but the truth you know
usually the truth is like boring truth
is boring nobody like want to hear it so
I'm going to tell you what will actually
what actually will happen to AI actually
nobody knows okay like you you you can
survey you can look you know you you
take several days to look into all the
greatest mathematicians or AI engineers
you know they created scientists who
created AI artificial intelligence and
neuronet networks and how they work new
you know then you you you see that like
nobody actually know as human animals we
don't actually know
like nobody really actually know what
will happen you know like we we are we
are a you know artificial intelligence
AGI creates like some kind of soul some
kind of selfawwareness some kind of
consciousness you know like like that's
a people that's a thing people talk
about right but
so what will happen actually so I'm
telling you. So I'm telling you as a
kind of experienced um elder [laughter]
outer if you will. Nobody actually
knows. So we don't know. We are in a
situation of society of like
uncertainty. We we don't know actually.
Nobody really knows. So
yeah. So it's kind of boring answer but
that is actually true. Okay. I digressed
all over. So um let's you know actually
let me do what I need to do. Okay. So
this just random chat. Cheers.
So ACP hello to good to see you again.
ACP says how many glasses of wine have
you had tonight? [laughter]
Not much actually. 20 milliters. 20
milliliters is what I usually have for a
day.
red wine. Okay. Like you you know max
max 400 ml.
How can we use AI to learn instead of
using AI as crutch? Well, I use AI every
day. I just ask it ask it questions.
Okay, you just ask it questions.
And today AI can actually also help you
code. So, but I I actually I don't uh I
don't use AI for that much. I ask, you
know, it's quite amazing because I
usually ask a lot questions about
programming about like esoteric
questions like the vast majority of
industrial coders. My questions they
will never ask in their life. They never
thought of. So, I usually ask all these
kind of questions. I talk about it on
Twitter. But then you know before AI it
usually means like several hours web
search and read Wikipedia.
But with AI so let me show you the uh I
just posted about it. Okay.
So actually today we are supposed to
talk about UU ID. Okay UI ID is like
fascinating. Let me magnify again.
So we are we are I was going to talk
about UU ID. We'll do it okay in a bit.
But anyway, so I was talking about uh
doctors, collectors, textures or
confusing which is relevant. So AI
answer that question which is relevant
to know for food health which is what in
what food? you know fructose, glutus,
glucose, dextrous you know that those
are sugars and
this is the state we are in. We live in
a society. Okay. [snorts] Anyway, so um
so I was talking about AI amazing. Okay.
So AI I heavily use it daily typically
esoteric computer programming questions
like all sort of questions about not
just programming but about computers and
some about very advanced mathematics
such as the foundation of mathematics.
So very esoteric since I do research and
want to answer specific super rare
questions like typically the question I
ask is not you know like the vast
majority of programmers they never they
are not interested they never thought of
in their life.
So but before AI it takes like few hours
web research and Wikipedia reading and
and sometimes you just you know the re
you you don't find the answer because
nobody talked about it but but with AI
in the past three years I you know I ask
AI lots of questions usually I get the
answer in five minutes it's quite
amazing okay so that's the state of AI
so so so u and Scott He's a great guy.
He's a professional, you know, CPU
designer, GPU, CPU kind of C and C++
coder. He's a very professional um
knowledgeable guy. Anyway, so yeah, so
I'm talking about AI. So you know, so um
recent conversation [laughter]
anyway. So let's see, you know, so I
asked AI, you know, all um like
questions and one of the well,
you know, you guys are probably looking
at this. This this is like when you you
know so this this is about
when you ask guac on Twitter the Twitter
versions version of guac when you ask it
to generate a picture it generates a
lame picture you know like this very
lame compared to for example com uh you
know but if you ask but if you go to the
real real uh guac.com
Then you get uh then you get this this
like [laughter]
really good picture, you know. So my
prompt is just draw a draw a hot China
girl wearing a top that says lisp.
That's it, you know. I didn't ask it to
show, you know, to show half naked or
big boobs or whatever. It just show
shows it. And this is what human animals
we want, you know, based on this
question. And that's what means you know
when if you ask the question if any
human animal ask this question this is
the wounded result
not this [ __ ] you know this.
So anyway that this this is kind of
another aspect of AI. So you can see
like why would AI
like some part of it generate this
picture and the other part generate
this. you know you can obviously tell
which is the answer that people expected
you know or the correct answer you can
even say right but then
so you know there's a lot like so this
about AI there is this um censorship
issues you see this result is a result
of they they added something you see
this is this is not the natural result
of neuronet networks
engineering. You see that's you know
what this AI image generation they are
all done by neuronet network technology.
So but this result is actually they they
try to prevent you to get the real
answer. They did something to it. Okay
that's that's why you get this. Okay. So
the AI is very interesting, fascinating
and they relate to society to to even
you know to to non techchnical questions
you know about for example here about
girls about how hot they are or how sexy
they are nontechnical. So anyway so we
digressed a lot uh actually so I think
my wife is back. I need to uh go uh
pretty soon. But let me let's finish
doing the UI UU ID today today's topic.
Okay. So, hold on a second. Hold on a
second. Uh be right back in one minute.
Just one minute.
Hello, I'm back. So, let's do the UYU ID
today. Okay. So, let's talk about
today's topic. That's what we want to
do. U universal like the universal
unique identifier. So let me let me read
a comment.
Uh
you get quick overview too long didn't
read on a topic like the five like the
50 ft view. Once you have the idea of a
topic you go and search for good sources
because
AI chatbots can give you false info with
some truth. That's correct. S you
mentioned previously that you have
studied adult content for many years. Is
there a connection between this and your
interest in mathematics? No, I don't
think so. So you so so you are talking
about porn you know porn pornography
pornography. So what is it? It's
basically pretty girls hot girls you
know doing sex tits and ass. Okay,
that's that's what pornography is about.
So I'm interested in pornography. That's
true. First of all, all men, all males,
they are interested in hot girls. Okay.
Uh so basically
I think it is universally
true
all male human animals are interested in
pornography.
Okay. But they will not admit it you
know because well due to religious or
social reasons. So when they grew up
there are certain constraints
constraints or forced upon their
thoughts that tells them no if you look
at hot girls you know the pictures the
tits you know hot girls like you see
every day today like in America the
white men's society you know the the
girls showing their tits and ass you see
it every day so their society social pre
pressure education they tell you no
That's not that's not right. You cannot
do that. Okay. So these people
those people who say they are you know
they are not in into pornography mostly
is because of this religious or social
pressure
uh which includes not just the white men
of Christian people but also Islamic
people
and include certain I I think also
includes parts of uh Asia regions. Okay.
So, but anyway, society tells you no
because you
some of it for good reasons. Okay. very
good reasons because you don't want
because this sexual issue
because
because this you know this is a
fundamental biology you know because
females they attract males
via
evolution. Okay. Because if you don't
get attracted you die you you extinct.
You go extinct. Okay. Only those people
who who who get attracted by female tits
and ass they survive. They get children.
Okay. That's a fundamental human animal
biology.
Nobody like no force can ignore it.
Okay. So, but meanwhile
it's so strong with you know this this
force is so strong and powerful
sometimes it creates problems. For
example, in a society, it creates rape.
It create, you know, when you see a
girl, you want, you just want to, you
know, grab it and [ __ ] her. It creates
rape problems,
creates um lots of issues like for it
confuses men, you know, when a man sees
a girl, attractive girl, like what does
attractive mean? Typically, it just
means young girl who are able to get
pregnant with your child. Okay, that's
that's the essence what of what it
means. Okay. Attractiveness.
So when you you see so men gets you know
get confused because of this biological
urgency.
So they get confused and sometimes
that's not good when you have too much
of it you know when when you have too
much of these in society. That's why for
example in Islamic countries they
to some degree they forbid girls showing
their body you know like you know they
forbid girls showing their hair because
there's just biological biologically too
much problem for men
confuses men like it it entirely eats
your brain the girls okay that's what
I'm talking about every one of you like
you don't you don't you don't want to
try like many of the white white
American Christians they pretend that
they are above it you know they pretend
oh these thoughts I don't care you know
actually they pretend but it's so much
it's affected them so much so you know
so anyway so so some religion
uh forbided and same thing with
Christianity they forbid to some degree.
So this is uh
and well so it's you know it's biology.
Um
so so well so this this this pornography
and what what does pornography mean?
Pornography means just just means
expanded version of girls showing their
body. That's what pornography is. Okay.
So, but so anyway, your question is does
it have to do with mathematics? Well,
not really. Okay. So, I don't think so.
Um I don't think so.
So, how to get solid information in this
era of AI which uh with lots of noise?
Um,
so what can you do in in this era? Well,
there's no magic trick. Okay, so how do
you get solid information in in this era
of AI with lots of noise? There's no
there's really no ma magic trick. You
just have to
trust
people who you can trust, you know?
There's no I mean you can even say what
they are like most of the time it's your
family but
in America for example there's lots of
dysfunctional families due to lots of
polit political problems. So we have
dysfunctional families. So you can't
even trust your mom and dad sometimes
because like depending on like who they
are like you know because lots of
problems
so USA is in a bad situation so
you can trust your friends and peers
that's what most people do but they do
not always provide good answer you know
they they do not always provide good
answer and since you are following me.
So I'm kind of someone you might choose
to trust. Okay. So
yeah. So you know who can you trust?
There's no good answer. You know you
like you can't say
used to be in good times you can trust
authority.
For example, your parents, your teacher,
the government,
you can trust authority. But not today,
not in USA, for example. Not not here.
Um,
in fact, in USA, you you cannot trust
the government. Almost the opposite.
Whatever the government say is the worst
thing. So anyway, anyway, that's an
eternal question.
So you said that this Chinese girls
isn't really your type. What is your
type then? Well, it's hard to say. Okay.
So, she is
it's hard to describe like like
any anyway that's just a random comment.
But anyway, I don't I don't find her to
be like super
hot.
She's hot because well because you know
big tits and and you know she looks fine
but
I don't think she's my type exactly.
So for example well I can show you uh by
example. Okay. So by example if you go
to for example this the other AI image
generated before
uh let's see Emacs Emacs packages
miscellaneous Emacs miscellaneous Emacs
fun. So we I used guac
three years ago to generate some AI
images and that was when guac was using
the flux
image generation engine flux f lux.
Okay. So this image you see it's
generated by AI by GU about in in 2024
when guac was using on Twitter the guac
on Twitter was using the flux engine. So
this picture I find this girl very
attractive for example compared to for
example
you know it's like
yeah I mean it's even hard to describe
the facial features or not it's hard to
describe and here's another one
generated by Gawk on Twitter in 2024 so
those are done by the flux AI engine
okay here's another one. And here's kind
of another one. This this is more of a
like uh a white girl, I suppose. Uh
here's another one, Chinese girl.
Anyway, so that's some of the other
pictures that those are generated in
2024 by Guork on Twitter. Okay, so it's
important to distinguish. You see this
is guac.com. You see today right now we
generated this image and animation a
video it's from gawk.com
but not from but if you if you ask um if
you ask gu on Twitter to generate an
image it generates this this like this
[ __ ]
funny okay I think we digressed we we
haven't talked about the UU ID but I
wanted to talk about UU ID so let let
Let me quickly do that. Let's see if we
can finish in 10 minutes. Okay. Explain
UyU ID. We did that's a universal
uh identification
uh basically uh random number based mo
mostly explain why UU ID is badly
designed and show treat. Okay. So I
talked so I've been so UU ID is very
badly designed. I I posted a tweet about
it. So let's let's check it. Okay. So,
UU ID. So, there there. Okay. So, let me
copy it. Hold on a second. So, go to
Emacs.
So, uh here
UID is uh wait UID is badly designed.
Okay. So, that's a trait. Why is it
badly designed? It's a facted standard
because you either you specify entire
thing as random numbers or part of it as
time stamp part of it as random string.
You don't embed a version number in it.
Extremely complex industrial coding fox
error inducing complex [ __ ] Okay, let
me explain. So what is it mean? What it
means is that in UU ID so UU ID is this
um
uh what
um version and variant. Okay. So UU ID
um UU ID is this 128 bits number but you
must format it in in in sequence of like
in sequence of hexodimals. You must
represent it that way. So every four
bits of binary number is repres sended
by one hexadimal. Okay. And and you must
format your 32 hexadimals in this format
separated by dash by hyphen. Okay. So
the so the first part is like um
let's see eight characters. So eight
digits of hexadimal then a dash then
followed by four digits of hexadimal
then dash then followed by four decimal
hexad four digits of hexadimal digits
then dash then another four digits of
hexadimal numbers then dash then
followed by uh how many is this um god
then followed by 12 digits bits of
hexadisimal. Okay, so in total there are
32 hexadimals. Each one represent four
bits. Okay, so that's how it represents
128 bits. Um and so this is called UU
ID. So this this this this string is
called UU ID. It's mean to be unique
universally unique identifier. That
means anyone any time you can generate
hundreds of them. And the idea is that
no two of them will be identical. Okay,
they don't collide. No two of them will
be identical. So the basic idea of U ID
is just random number. Okay. So, as long
as you have 128 random like random, you
know, like a a number that's 128 bits in
length meaning that two raised to
128 power. Okay. So, what what number is
that? How how large that how large is
that? This we can try to compute it. 2
raised to uh 1
2 8. Okay. Uh let's see. 8. Yeah. So
let's print it. So that's this number.
So that's a number. How many digits?
That's a number 3 4 028 something
something. That's a number
three followed by 39 by three followed
by 30 zeros. Okay, basically that's a
number. It's three followed by 38
zero basically. Okay, so this is like
mega you know. So this is a median. This
is a billion. This is a trillion. This
is then you know mega cha cha cha
something something trillion trillion
trillion. Three followed by 38
zero. That's how big this number is.
128 bits. Okay. So, so what the UU ID
ideally is trying to do is that is that
when you generate a 128 bits number,
they are going to be unique. Doesn't
matter if every person on earth generate
generates one of them every second, they
are still likely to be unique. The
[snorts] chances of them having the same
number so-called collision is like less
than you know a co cosmic ray hit hit
your RAM chip and corrupted your
computer and your computer crashed.
Okay,
the you know theoretically
the chance of two random 128 bits number
is the same is less than you hit by a
lighting. Okay, and you die. Okay, so
that that is ideal. That's the
situation. But why why why is it sucks?
Why why is the [ __ ] idiotic? Why do
why do I say you know like my claim?
Let's go back to my claim the the
[ __ ] idiotic industrial standard
because in UID in UU ID by specification
not every one of these digits are
random. Okay. So in fact in one sum you
know so you have 128 bits meaning 128
number binary digits. Okay now they are
actually
uh about eight of them eight bits they
are fixed they indicate version number
like the version number of the UU ID and
the the like the version and variant
[ __ ] idiocy. Okay. So let me show you
the the the AI. So I asked AI AI helped
me to understand so you can go see it.
So 120 uh let's say uh UID special bits.
Okay. So you got so in UID it looks like
that. But however
you can't just generate all of them
random. If you actually do that you got
a problem. Okay. So by the UID
specification you must
um the the bits version and let's see
the bits version um the bits
position 45 48 to 51 must be have
special meaning okay it cannot be random
and the bits number for uh 64 to 65
two bits they have special meaning
cannot be random. Okay. So basically
what the UUID standard
according to the standard if you if you
are a god if you are able you know let's
say you are god you can purely generate
perfectly random
uh 128 bits random number okay
as a UID right then you are going to run
into collision
because this [ __ ] idiotic like
embedding a version number into the UU
ID into the random sequence of digits.
You see this [ __ ] idiocy by this
industrial you know we are the standard
we are the professional coders the
[ __ ] idiocy that's what Uyu ID is
okay so my post says the special bits in
UID means even if you have a god random
machine
you know random number is always like um
very mysterious because it's very
difficult to define in fact almost
impossible to define what it really
means random but even if you have a god
random machine you will [ __ ] up with
collision with so-called UU ID like if
you are god you create random number but
if you put you know if you put in a UU
ID form you are going to your pro your
your code is no longer random because
you got a problem because in UID some
bits are not rand meant to be random You
know, so the UID is a truly a insult to
random number based ID. You know, it's
like a [ __ ] insult by the industry,
you know. You like like most people
don't know it. Like most programmers,
they never actually they don't think,
you know, they they they they never
thought of it this way. And for sure
they will never attack it attack it like
the way I do like this. are just [ __ ]
insult [ __ ] [ __ ] like like a
pure [ __ ] that's what UID like the
industrial standard that's you know RFC
that's what they are okay that's what
I'm telling you guys okay you guys you
know you don't you don't have to believe
me
but since you are watching me
you might keep that in mind you know to
judge for yourself you know this so so
we are we live in the world you know
even We don't talk about politics. Let's
ignore politic politics for the moment.
The war, the killings of thousands of
people, but let's stick with the
computing industry, you know,
technicality stuff. But we got this UID,
which is like a one what one [ __ ] up
[ __ ] Okay, it's like one [ __ ] up [ __ ]
in the in the in the standard.
But rarely like almost never you like
rarely you hear people complain rarely
that okay that is my claim
okay so solution just just don't use UID
okay like but most people don't know
because most people like like you people
young people you know you got
brainwashed by Python you know Python oh
my god Python the most popular I I want
to use the most popular language because
I can make money right So you learn
Python, you learn the machine learning,
you know that's the solution Python, you
need to do it in Python or Rust whatever
is the current or C++ right then you
tell they tell you oh UID you need to
use UID because it's RFC standard
request for comment you know it's all
open source it's all great for humanity
and you got [ __ ] by this this this
insulting [ __ ] that's your situation
okay that's what I'm saying that's
that's my like my special perspective.
Okay, that's that's my complaint about
UU ID. Okay, so
um I think that's it. you know I so I
got a you know so I got a this code um
actually we uh you know I so you know if
you want it you can search for insert
random UI ID there's a code there like
since like 2011 um 14 years ago
what was it 14 years ago like yeah 14
years ago so I wrote this code that
generates UU ID in Emacs Lisp Okay. And
some people also help helped me improve
it. In particular, this uh Christopher
Wellins very accomplished I would say
very uh advanced this coder. So I
highly highly respect this guy. Okay.
So but I I don't you know I haven't read
other people's um blog that much. Uh so
it would be interesting to see what he
is saying these days. Um
okay so anyway so so he helped and al
also another guy uh hi tech
uh you know from websites that's deleted
things like that. Okay. So
anyway, so some other people helped and
also Yuri Kong and I. So anyway, and the
code um
there's something to improve. For
example, this command insert random UU
ID. It allows you to insert a random UU
ID, right? So I can call it.
You see this command? Do it. do it, you
know, but um but it would be better if
you create a command that just return a
UU ID string because in EMAC list in
lots of programs, you just need a
string. You don't necessarily want to
insert to the current buffer. Okay, so
it would be better if you have a
separate command that returns a UU ID
string. Okay. The other things to look
into is that um you see today of course
you you got the operating system they
all have uh software to generate UUID.
So one of the thing I want to look at is
you know PowerShell got a command to
generate UU ID and the Mac also UID gen
that's a command
uh UUID
gen. Now on the Mac and Linux are they
the same command or not? I think they
are the same command. Okay. UID gen is a
command line utility used to generate
universal universally unique identifiers
called UUIDs on Unix like systems
including Linux and Mac OS OS. Okay. So
they are the same program on on their
operating system. Okay. So anyway, so
you got those. Um so
but I was going to do so what you want
to do is you want to look into do they
generate you see because UID
as we learned um okay so as we learned
uh as you learned there are several uh
versions of it okay so I mean they like
do we have the Wikipedia article yes
there the so Wikipedia article will
explain they embed a version number and
like a specific variant into the into
the random digits. Okay. So,
so you can also ask AI for it. So, it
particular you know bits sequence they
they they they are not random. They
means like they they indicate what
version is this is this UU ID is it
based on time stamp like if it's a
particular version it's based on time
stamp like the first you know several
bits must be came from time you know
they are they they means time stamp then
the rest is random so you see if the
version number is some number then it
means you know it's their hardware is
your hardware ID code from your
hardware. So very bad. It's nasty. You
shouldn't have that.
So anyway, I was going to look into all
these details, but let's you know, but
since I already ran it for an hour, I
think that's it for today.
And I was gonna right so I was also
gonna improve my code my emac this code
for the UID but I guess no.
Okay that's it for today. Okay so for
those of you just want the code you can
search for this page Emacs insert random
UID and you'll find it. Okay I think
that's it.
Okay. No comments. Okay. Am I like
talking to myself
almost? Okay. So, I think that's it. Uh,
any other questions or comments? I we
shut down. Let's see. I talked for 54
minutes. Okay. I think we shut down now.
Is there something like I really need to
do or tell you guys before I shut down?
Let's see. Not really because I can do
all this by myself. Oh, the other thing
related is about the atom uh
web feed. Okay, atom web feed. Now,
where is it? Let's see.
Uh
yeah, atom web feed. I wrote this
article
20 years ago. Okay. Atom web feed RSS.
So, it's interesting because UID is part
of it. In fact, that's how I got started
to look into. Anyway, I'm not going to
talk about this.
Okay, I think that's it. Cheers, guys.
Bye, guys. I think that's it.
UU ID rant and hot girls and fascinating
and beautiful you know AI you know the
fascinating AI and girls and [laughter]
you know what what we going to be
like what you know very interesting
because you guys here you know a handful
of you five or six people
here and watching me Right. And you
know, so what we going to be in five
years or in 10 years?
That's a good question. Like maybe are
we just going to die? Is it is it is it
a possibility?
Because
realistic realistically speaking, USA is
right now like trying to go to war with
Iran.
And then of course there's also Russia
and China around and you know there's
nuclear weapons
that exist
right so so in five five years what
would happen you know is it possible
that we just going to be dead
like the end of humanity
you know be due to nuclear weapons war
that's one
Well, the other thing is well what's
going to happen with AI? So I mean in
science fiction of course we are aware
that
in many of the dystopia so-called
science fiction we the AI is going to
take over. They're going to wipe us out.
Is it? So is that
is that going to happen? Right? That's
you know then if you know then you you
actually you might see a lot of people
say that then there's also opinions no
that's not never going to happen AI is
just not you know never going to become
like human and what does intelligence
what does having a soul what what does
self consciousness mean actually nobody
knows that's the thing you ask the
greatest mathematician you know like
they
they have conflicting, they have
arguments, they don't know.
Then you got, you know, then then you
got so you got all these kind of things.
So,
so that's um
kind of interesting and worome. Okay,
that's that's kind of that's um that's
what
kind of that that's what bothers me as
well.
Okay, bye guys.
Uh, what is your uh do you see this
Chinese girl? Okay, so uh well, if you
guys like my stuff, okay, if you guys
like my stuff, you can you donate to me.
Okay, so you know, donate to me. Go
to.info.
Go to the bottom and there is Patreon,
Amazon gift card, PayPal me. Okay. Okay,
that's it. Bye, guys.
We shut down in one minute. Okay,
let's see.
Yeah, some things I need to do for my
website, but it's not
anyway.
Yeah.