good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of
talk show uh today is 2020
august 7th friday 12 30 p.m san
francisco time
and today we are going to talk about
emacs and emacs lisp
i'm going to do a live coding of a
emacs command and then
we are going to uh after that we we
might talk random about
emacs related stuff emacs
community or whatever or a demo of stuff
like keys
a live demo or let's use stuff like this
to do
a vim golf we haven't done that for a
while
and all we go to talk about keyboards
you know my my keyboard blog uh lots of
interesting things to talk about
and you guys okay you guys type in the
comments okay
questions or chat uh type in the
comments
good morning uh renato uh trying out
stuff like he's right now fantastic any
questions
comments just uh post it okay so here is
my
emacs window showing browser so here is
today's
uh kind of talk show page go back to
emacs
and on the right window you can see the
pink window is all my emacs commands
as i move cursor you can see the
commands call
you can see the command name and the
keystroke i'm using i'm using
soft light keys of course and i'm i'm
using vorack keyboard layout
so if you if there's any command you
don't know you can look up the command
name
on the right window then you can look up
on the web most likely it's on my web
with the source code okay so let me show
you what we're gonna
do today okay so we're gonna do a
youtube
uh command let's go to youtube
uh youtube emacs okay let's go to let's
search youtube emacs let's see what we
find
okay emacs tutorial i don't know who
that is let's see
oh actually let's go to um
abraham okay let me show you this okay
there there is this guy i know
who is a e-max and e-max this expert
uh so i i like to show his video
wait wait is my voice coming through
fine
right i'm doing fine i'm alive alive and
kicking
right good morning allen good morning
sansa
okay so yeah okay so let's go to let's
find
um okay i need to show this allen stuff
so so uh
alan allen drew this picture this is
uh this is reaper
folding table with moving casters you
know why
because you know my favorite uh computer
desk
is actually a folding table like that
that's that is actually my folding
my favorite computer desk why because
that is the borg style you know the star
trek book
uh technology you know the the most pure
functionality without no decorations no
no nothing
pure functionality study you know this
is the
latest research i mean that this is the
fruit
of science you know the most study and
easy to make and durable and uh
and you know you can you can lie
you can you can sit on this desk
and it's affordable and it's you know
it's
fantastic it's the most function
functional stuff
my style so anyway that's my favorite
desk and
of course there's also standing desk
actually i never used
uh rather i never had the opportunity to
use but that's something i would like to
use
uh if i have you know maybe a setup
possibly i don't know you know set up a
standing desk
and if you use standing desk there is
this thing
called wobble board which is fantastic
do you know why
because when i was a teenager from 16 to
18 i was working in a bagel shop you
know bagels
making bread and you rode the door you
stand there through the door all day for
10 hours a day eight hours 10 hours a
day that's
truly the most laborers uh job
and you know i was doing that as a
illegal immigrant in canada
and taking some minimal amount of money
but the the problem is that you stand
there you know you stand there for eight
hours stay your note
you'll notice after a while your legs
get tired it's not just your legs get
tired there's a posture thing
it's just like sitting if you sit for
too long for hours for three hours four
hours a day
you'll notice back problems also the
problems so
so you want standing desk but but
even i mean if you stand for too long
you also have problems you know so
you usually you when you do a standing
you want to
prop uh one of your legs you know on
on a foot box or something like that you
usually
like you know the bar stool the bar
stool you know you go to a bar
where there's a you know a bar
underneath
for your to for you to put your foot on
that that is a good thing because you
want to do that and you want to
you want to move around shift around so
there is this
wobble board you can buy on amazon okay
so you go you you guys go there buy it
now it's excellent let's demonstrate my
the power of my emacs operation
you go by and help the economy
paste okay the best computer desk
so alan says skeletor's skeletor sliding
indeed if you sit too long you'll be
a bird hurt exactly
okay so that's computer desk so let's
let's begin let's let's start to do
the the
uh okay hold on a second let me
let me put that in my in my talk show
page okay
go to talk show show in browser go back
magnify and uh talk
talk talk okay today's talk show
magnify show in browser good
magnify switch back to emacs or single
key operations
okay let's put the link here so that's
that's today's topic then showing
browser
so uh best computer desk we talked about
that let's get on to emacs and emac
these
modify xr html youtube linkify okay let
me show you what's going on we talked
about that a little bit yesterday
i was thinking about building my own
desk table with adjustable height
by manually spinning a wheel
yeah that's that's a good hey good
morning emily
uh like a help you know another
interesting thing
is that let me let me ramble a little
bit
you know the touch screen
the touch screen is the band of user
interface
the touchscreen popularized by steve
jobs of apple
but steve jobs however is a genius uh
genius at marketing he know
he know what to do but however uh touch
screen is not uh
a great user interface you want physical
knobs
and wheels and sliders okay you want you
know like like
like i can show you lots of uh
things uh but but anyway so look so this
is us
navy warships you see you see the
you see it's uh got the touch screen
and with this user interface they got
into an
accident you know it's a merchant ship
ran into them because because of the
touchscreen uh
so after this accident the u.s navy
did research and they realized you know
the touch screen is no good so they went
back they
decreed all ships must use the you know
the back
good old physical controls 1 000 knobs
and wheels you know
like a cockpit you know like a space
shuttle
and then then you see you see this
uh this this thing this nasa thing
i mean not nasa the spacex they started
to use
touch screen user interface which is
disaster
in the waiting
and shut up you know the astronaut is
actually saying when you use the old
wheel and you know when you look at the
cockpit
of a space shuttle you see a thousand
knobs and wheels that is actually good
because you know
you you want to control something you
can you know
exactly where it is and you can touch it
you know uh
muscle memory but with touch screen
you have to think you have to look at
the screen oh you know press this button
change the screen to
this control and press and touch that
you know it's no good
so he actually the astronaut actually
says
tells you that with touch screen you
have to uh
it's more you have to it's you have to
think
so it's accident in the waiting okay uh
so imagine the future you know like a
star trek you know in star trek you it's
all touch swing you see
because we imagine that's the best
but so imagine let's say
let's say 10 or 20 years from now our
space shuttle spaceships
what will they actually use uh
touch screen user interface as primary i
doubt it okay
i doubt it because it is no good
so anyway that's about touch screen uh
i can show you actually a lot of photos
about
you know the physical control let's get
back to emacs okay
comments in questions posted
so touchscreen with adjustable hate
okay so let's get back to emacs and
let's talk about how do you what what
are we going to do
emacs this coding okay
so what are we going to do now yeah so
let's go to
um this this guy okay
before we do that let's go to keyboard
uh block okay uh wait uh
keyboard block go there and
go to ergo keyboards okay fantastic
keyboards then we go to the foot pedal
kinesis foot pedal which i have down
there i i did a video on that
then there is this guy
uh by by this
emacs expert okay
uh i think i have a link there it is
howard
abraham abraham okay
he wrote a review on that he is a emacs
expert
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
youtube search
emacs howard abraham because he's
he's done great uh
emacs tutorials so let's go to his
youtube channel
okay let's see introduction to isha okay
let's see intro okay so let's
introduction to isiah
okay so he's he you know he is his
youtube video tutorial on emacs asia
okay
now i am a blogger so i want to embed
his video in my blog so what i do i
press a key to copy the url
switch back to emacs okay switch back to
emacs anyway
okay then i post it here let's go to my
uh
talk show page okay you see now the link
is here
is there now i want to okay
showing browser
you see that's a link that's no good you
want the embed code so i press a key
actually i can press a key then show in
browser
there it is okay back to emacs
undo undo so here it is okay so
so what the command i just called is
youtube
linkify okay html youtube linkify
that will turn a youtube link into this
uh my format of uh you know
iframe this is the
heart of it okay but i also have figure
and figure caption so i can say
for example this is a great tutorial
on e-shell e-max issue
by harward okay so showing browser
that's fantastic now you so if you are
like me a blogger you want to uh
you need to do these orphans often so
you can just copy a url any url
copy it and just do it here you know in
your blog
press the key and it becomes that
okay so let me show you what's the other
thing okay so
when you copy a url you see the url
it's of this format but when you uh
change it to
embedded youtube video it's actually
iframe
and the iframe uses this url
which is different from the other let me
magnify okay so
you see this is original and this is the
embed
url so what i want to do
is i want my command to be
able to work on this embed url as well
if i do it now it won't work let me show
you okay
so for example this is stupid emacs bug
okay for example this is original url i
press a key
it becomes that which is good now this
is the embed url i press a key
it doesn't work well it becomes a link
let me show you
okay um
you see it becomes a link here that's
not what we want
so go back undo undo
so i want my command to be able to work
on this embed url
code so that's what i want to modify
today
so before before we do that let's let's
show let's um
let's show you the command let me go
over the command how it works okay so
because this is going to be a emac list
tutorial
so you go to the source code html mod
and oops so
here is the source code okay it's not
too long let's
let's cut it's um
okay so okay so here's the line
uh wait so here's a code
it's not too long okay so but let's copy
it let's
copy it create a new buffer paste it
save it xx let's save it as
the command name save it that
and today's state and dot e-l okay
they magnify so here's the code
so it says the line can be so here's the
documentation so
it says the line can be any of
this is a normal youtube url
and it can also be the url i mean the
youtube id
for youtube every video has id which is
part of the
url uh here you see that's the id
and then it also can be this format you
know why
youtube changes every every year so you
know normally when you want to do in
embed you click on this share button
annoying uh user interface then you can
share to facebook you know
you click on facebook it goes to
facebook it
shares you know this social networking
crap anyway so this is the
so if you just click here
it gives you this url which is different
from the url of the original
uh website for example let me paste it
here
let's undo okay
so you see so this is original url
and this is the url if you click on the
share
and this is the url if you click on if
you uh
you want to embed it like for example
you click share
then you click on embed
you see saying then youtube gives you
this crap
this bunch of let me show you okay
that's what youtube gives you
you know uh
frame board frame border is you know
old html so allow accelerometer
auto play encrypted media gyroscope
picture in picture crap
anyway so i just want standard
you know html no nothing fancy so
this is what i want so in order to write
this command
you know first of all you study all
these youtube formats
but let's let's go to our code
so anyway so here's our code so you it
turns
you know any one of these ui out into
this uh
iframe and figure stuff
okay so i think i guess i let me explain
the code uh
i guess either i explain the code i
start oh i start to code and modify it
okay so let's look at the comments
uh what do you guys think so uh paul
says
never uh
have been looking into kneeling chair
oh kneading chair no good okay uh i can
tell you about
kneeling chairs paul edward
let's digress a little bit okay the
stagnation is more fun
uh exactly
needing chair because i'm very much into
these
strange chairs ergonomic chairs but
knitting chairs is no good okay but
because
uh well
okay it's it's on one of my page uh
it's on saudi.org i'm not sure i want to
show it
but anyway anyway there's this
knitting chair okay i which i actually
bought
in 2000 in 1996 okay these are
knitting chairs okay i got them
around 1997 and i used it for a year
you know so i thought this is a great
you know
ergonomic science chair uh
after using it for a year it's not that
good
when you sit on this chair you have the
issue of your
you know it is it's you know it's this
knitting chairs this california thing
bare feet and stuff
so but but when you sit on it a normal
chair you have this
back support okay so you can lie on it
uh wait so you can you see i can
there's the you know you can you can lie
on it
but with kneeling chair you don't have
that so you have it's like a tree you
have this
issue of like you constantly have to
unconsciously you know it's it's not so
good
also also you know when i sit on it i
remember
you you have you have the feel of
falling down like you know
tree topples a normal chair you don't
have to worry about that but but
but with this knee lean chair because
your feet
your legs is all tied up you know it's
kind of
tied up with that the way you sit so you
cannot
readily move your legs out
to either stand up or something you know
you so
you have the you won't actually
fall down but you kind of feel like like
that
because you you know it's like your your
feed is bound and
and you have the top uh moving
so i didn't like it so much the idea
seems good but
um i didn't like it so that's about
kneading chair
okay so
uh so
emmanuel torre says if you
right click on the video you can you can
press
copy embed code okay in the context menu
i noticed that there
are more options okay
uh do you not put them in ten you know
yeah you can do that but it's not good
you know if you are a blogger if you are
using emacs of course you can get the
embed code right click
you know copy video url copy uil
uh copy embed code you can do like that
or you can
click on the share but it's too much
mouse clicks you don't want that
so what you want is you just use the
standard shortcut keys
uh control l to move your cursor to the
url field and ctrl c
then you have it copied then switch to
emax
then you can paste it you see close undo
or i have a shortcut you know i just
press a single key you know
one single key it's already copied i go
back to emacs and i can copy it
so once you have it in emacs you know
you you have it in emacs it's magnified
then you just press a key it becomes you
know what you want
then you can start to type you know so
that's more efficient
that's the advantage of emacs
okay so so let's look at the code okay
let's
let's start to look at the code and um
what should we do we want to let me go
over the code then okay
let me go over the code
so the code you know what actually what
the code will do
is that let me go back to uh you see
the code basically what the code will
need to do is that you
will grab the text under the cursor you
know the user put the cursor somewhere
in the url grab the text under cursor
so you actually get the input that's the
input you want to transform
so you want to grab that text under
cruiser then
you want to kind of pass the text for
example you want to find out which part
is the video id which is this part
you know once you got the video id
everything is easy then you want to
then you just want to insert you know
you you want to insert
iframe tag you know iframe
uh oops let's just do this iframe
you know you insert the iframe tag then
source equals to
source equals to something you know
so once you pass and get the id
everything is easier you just insert
what whatever you want
okay so that's uh that's the core of
this command that's what this command
needs to do so let's look at look at
what the command actually does okay so
so youtube linkify so that's a command
and okay so let a bunch of
uh we declare
a bunch of variables okay p1
p2 is position one and position two
that's the beginning and end of the url
okay
the input string is the url that you
grab
okay and this id is the youtube video id
okay uh youtube
link charts okay so
so these are the characters in the
youtube url link
that you want to skip something like
that
okay skip char let's go over quickly
skip charts backward
so you are skipping so you are moving
the cruiser and skipping these
characters
then uh okay
so first of all what are we doing here
is actually we are trying to find out
the
the beginning and end position of the
of the of the youtube url
so that's what this code does
so we skipped character backward in the
url
okay and uh and what
and this part actually we can ignore you
know the skip chart backward let me
explain what it does okay so you can do
describe function to look to read the
documentation of of this skip chart
backward command
so escape chart backward it takes a
string uh basically
so just like that you know here over
here it takes a string and
what the string is the string function
as a
regular expression
so you are telling you are telling emacs
to skip character to move the
cruiser backward uh and skip all these
characters
so you skip the dash underscore question
mark period
colon slash and equal sign
and ampersand ampersand sign and you
also skip
capital a to z lowercase a to z
and zero to nine you see these
are kind of regular expression uh
uh syntax so it's kind of a mixture of
regular expression syntax
you know it's like the regular
expression square brackets inside it
so you skip those characters so
basically what what we want is
go to the beginning of um
you know actually another way simpler
way to
do this is just call the thing at point
command you know we can do this thing at
point file name but
we explained thing at point yesterday
so anyway so let's let's go with this
okay skip
so you move the cursor backward to the
beginning basically beginning of the url
then you set it to p1 position one okay
then you
move character forward again then you
set the point to p2 so you got the
beginning and end position of the
of the url the url by the way is
by the way could be inside the sentence
could be
inside a sentence okay like that
and something usually is not
so that's py and p2 then you
um you use buffer string no properties
and give two positions that grabs the
text underneath it
then you save it to input string then
okay so the input string is the actual
url
then you try to extract the id from the
input string
okay that's how you do it so you try to
extract id
by condition okay the condition
so let me show you the id okay so
for example
um
okay so for example this is the url
right this is the original url
and let's put it here so you can see
so given a url like that you want to
extract the id which is the v equals to
something
so so we can see if if string match
v equals to 11 characters
so if you actually found a pattern like
that
then then those 11 characters are the id
so so you see then match
string equals two so we captured it you
know so
so that's the id but otherwise
otherwise we do this a second test
so if the string is actually youtube.b
okay that's the other let me go back to
the you see
this is the second you possible url from
youtube
so let's switch back
let's paste it here okay so let's paste
it
to kind of document document so
if the url is like that
then we do that okay so but if the url
is like that
then we do that we get the id the id is
right after
right after the domain name okay
then otherwise when you use condition in
emac this
condition you know you usually want to
give the last condition which is true
that is always true that means if it
doesn't match any of the above then just
do this so it just says error cannot
find the youtube video
so we want to actually modify this part
so because uh you see here is the
alternative url so let's copy that
go back to the list code so we want to
add another condition
okay and
stream match okay
so if the stream match let's copy that
if the stream match that embed
okay um
actually let's copy this part okay so
because it's similar
so if the string match
that okay this is fantastic if the
string match it contains an
embed then whatever the id
characters 11 characters then
then what we do is if the stream match
then we do
just like that here match stream
okay pretty fine so you see
so here is our code so if the stream
match embeds something then
we get the id okay then
otherwise error okay cannot find the
youtube video id
in url okay so once you get the id of
the url of the youtube
video then you delete region okay
then you insert then you start to insert
you know
your your iframe uh you know thing
here okay i think that's it that's what
we want to do we
yeah you you know this here is easy to
understand you just
insert insert a bunch of things and the
id
is right here the youtube id you see
here
you see the id is right there the
youtube video id
okay so now we run the code so eval
buffer
eval buffer we have our code and go back
to
uh go back to our html we're gonna try
on this url before it doesn't work now
it should work okay
core meta x because youtube linkify
oops cannot find your youtube video id
in url what the
what what what is going on let's go back
to the code
eval buffer let's make sure we give our
buffer again
okay if i prefer
11 characters right
oh okay so uh wait
uh
let's just do so
you see we are trying to match the
pattern a to z
capital lowercase and zero to nine but
however
you see the the id actually sometimes
contain underscore
so that's not what we want we want we
want to delete this part
and just say a character
okay any character 11 one of 11 of them
and actually this part is also wrong so
let's just
copy that put a dot okay if our buffer
go back to our code let's try it on here
let's try it
meta x html youtube linkify
yeah fantastic
uh you have to escape the dot you don't
have to escape the dot because
because a dot in regular expression
means
any character okay any character if you
escape it
then that means a literal dot you know
we we don't want that so actually it
works
that's actually what we want to do so so
let's
uh you see it works on that url works on
that url and
you know it all works so show in browser
you can see we have several copies of
the same thing
that's all good so we done with our job
today let's
let's show it delete it show it you know
okay so you might go out check out
howard abraham's tutorial on e-show i'm
pretty sure it's a fantastic if you
haven't used isha
isha is fantastic okay i use it i
started you know i started to use emacs
since 1998 basically i lived in emacs
beginning in 1998 and for the first 10
years about
yeah more than 10 years i use i don't
use e shell i use
uh i i
i use the i use this
shell this you know this inferior shell
they call it you know for example let's
do ls
you can see and he and on the top it's
issue
ls you know so what's the difference you
know i have an
article so you go to my emacs tutorial
i'm going to i'm going to my emacs blog
okay uh hold on a second okay so here's
my emacs blog showing browser
you go to my emacs tutorial
and go down on the left you will see
shell okay let's search for it shell
okay
so then shell in e-max wide one shell in
e-max i explain
you know some people they do things in
terminal
so for example uh wait i don't want to
do ls
oops let's let's cd
okay so in terminal let's see magnify
magnify
so here is your standard terminal and
some people
say let's say web
ergo emacs you know i mean my emacs
directory and
go to emacs okay
then we can do ls you know a bunch of
big
ls you know a bunch of
but emacs is superior okay
you you most of the time you want to do
shell commands in emacs because you have
much more control
and then but but then
and emacs have
multiple uh
uh variations on shell okay let me show
you where is it
article shell wait
shell okay so you have one shell emacs
that's an introduction why even shell in
imax okay
and e shell that's another option and
xiao versus turn versus each
versus isho emax has you know three
shells
more than three four but actually two of
them becomes
are merged together anyway so
xiao is much much more uh better okay
so you have xiao you have isha and and
isha is great okay i started to
to use eshow around 2000
uh 2014 or something like that so i've
been using the the
traditional shelf for more than 10 years
then i switched to esha basically
and there's also term term emulator you
know term emulate you know if you
meta x term that gets you nc term
okay so here are different you know
several different
shells you can run in emacs so i explain
the differences
and in fact if you run term that means
inside emacs you can run vim you can run
vi
you can run ssh you can run you can
start nano okay
actually someone let's go back
let's go to my emacs blog let me show
you these interesting things
somewhat in e-max
let me show a copy uh so this guy
is who is who is this guy this guy is
uh dxlr88r
okay so view image this guy
uses emacs stuff like keys and runs
term terminal okay emacs terminal
emulator
then he start started nano nano text
editor
so
so in fact you can in inside emacs issue
term you can start another emacs
instance
and you can start term again and start
another emacs
instance i've done that i've done that
like 20 years ago
so anyway isha so you know you might to
check out isha isho
you know the difference the y-ish issue
is a shell
that's written entirely in emac lisp
yeah so each out the advantage of each
one of the
advantage is written entirely in imax
this
and it's faster okay it's faster on the
other hand if you run term
or the uh shell meta x shell
they they actually start a shell a bash
and interface that with emacs
yeah but so so one of the great
useful uh situation for issue is that
when you are on windows
you don't have bash but you are used to
bash you know you want to run ls and
unix commands so you can just run eshell
each
has built-in um emulators for those
commands
so close kill it yes okay
uh key it kill it showing browser
star talk show so you might check out
abraham's
uh tutorial on asia
okay that's that's the main thing for
today then we
talk about random depends on what you
guys want to
talk about let's so let me see how long
have i been talking
and let me read the comments
oh we already been talking for 40 mi 45
minutes
okay that's uh so we might shut down
soon
so let's see the comments and let's chat
asking about not putting extra options
like picture in picture
oh okay so okay uh scott hey good
morning scott
scott is the expert on c and uh
low level programming on cpu and gpu
so scott says are you using dollar sign
for variable names in
imac list yes interesting
almost feels like a formal former pearl
guy writing images
yeah i get that question often
but let me tell you okay let me copy the
code let me show you this uh let me demo
this
uh feature i have in size html mod
okay so here's our today's code i copy
it
in fact
uh okay so wait what i want to do okay i
want to
modify the comments to um
okay because we added a feature so copy
that
go back to comment so add add a feature
okay but this command actually
okay let's modify it so it works on the
id
i think i had the code that works on
that but but i
i think i deleted a while back so
so okay let me show you okay so let's
copy the id
now i don't know what youtube url is
that i hope it's
open in chrome okay
let's see what what video is this hope
that
something okay
that's uh that's a youtube that's a
youtube comedian that's
a very funny guy and his name is
fat francis he has a very
touching an interesting history
uh if you go watch that youtube url okay
very sad kind of sad history
uh anyway so let's let's change your url
to something
let's change the apple hem let's use
this ui okay
so let's modify this
copy okay so
so that's the url name
i'm modifying the inline dock
so now it's more relevant because we are
using a
emacs video as a as a example
so so if we copy the id
go back to my html page
paste id let's call our commands to see
if it works
html linkify it doesn't work
because i think i removed the code so
but we want to make it work
so let's go back to our code let's make
it work
let's make it work on that just the id
so condition we're going to need to add
another condition to check this
copy the code okay
so the condition so this time the
condition will be
length okay so if the length
of
if the length of input string is equals
to
three and three let's run it yeah okay
so let's paste it here
11. so if the length of the input string
is 11 characters exactly then that is
the id
okay so then then we say
then we just return the input stream
we return that then we set it here right
so okay evaluate the buffer go back to
the html let's try our code on it
fantastic works okay now go back to the
code
now scott was saying you know my my i'm
using a dollar sign
that's just for my personal reasons you
don't have to okay you can remove the
dollar sign
but if you use a dollar sign you have
the advantage
they become green uh colored
because i'm using sar emac this mod
my own emac this mod so you don't have
to use the
dollar sign okay but i have a great you
know i have a great history about
why i use dollar sign and let's talk
about that okay
you go to emacs blog uh and
it's you know you go to let me show you
yeah it's it's one of the frequently
answered you know asked
question and it's a huge controversy
you know because for for like five years
i have been using
not actually just dollar sign i've been
using i've been using greek symbols
okay let me show you you know that is
like one
one of my weird things right and people
complain you know
these emacs these phonetics you know
these
some of them don't like me because i'm
too weird okay so
so for example i what i've been doing
uh wait okay so magnify i have i
i used to use the greek sign okay like v
okay let me show you okay so
so instead of dollar id i would say fee
id
okay and that
confuses a lot of people but why do i
use this weird thing
thing you know so on all my website all
my code i was using i was doing that
because i was because i believe that is
actually superior
that is you know for source code you
know for as a programmer
you want to you know we have concerns
about how to code what's the
you know what's the best way to code
something the elegance
or efficiency or shortest number of code
you know
all the naming of things you know naming
of things is a
great big giant controversy should you
use
underscore or should you use dash or
should
you you know camera case versus you know
this or that underscore
snake case python people no big
controversy but
and so i studied that issue i've read
this
all articles there is and research
articles on that
in fact we you know i have so many
articles
sally snake
case okay let's let me let me show you
okay
snake case versus camel case okay you go
search that you call a command and
you'll search
google uh actually not google but
duckduckgo okay so i have an article on
that
camera case versus snake case which is
better you know
you know what do you mean by better you
know there's so many so much details
which languages
uses which uh you know the naming their
naming style
or idiom or you know the style which
recommend which
which one is better what do you mean by
better and
you know you measure by statistics how
many codes
what they use and why is it better you
know there's so much details
and also you study the character
frequency
you know if you dive deep into this
you will start need wait
what what the it's not working
oh yeah you have to say uh yeah okay so
okay if you start to study
this issue in depth
and one of the thing you
want to know is the frequency
of the various symbols
used in programming languages
such as the dollar sign comma
semicolon percentage sign
dash underscore and so on
so so actually i wrote this javascript
to compute that and i've done statistics
on you know all languages
what characters they use the most often
so anyway that's one of the things you
want to study let's go back to
um let's let's copy some
some of my urls so i let's go to the
talk show so i can put it there
digressions
uh interesting things
uh talk show okay so let's put some of
the
here so
and uh oh wait wait
what's the
oh like did i did i close it
camo case versus anyway
i forgot where that is
okay here's the url copy back to emacs
paste it thinkify
so back in my talk show page showing
browser so you have
so i have a reference to it so i can put
in the youtube description
for the topic talked today so
so yeah so i was studying this issue and
i decided that
you want to use the greek characters as
a sigil
now the technical the the technical term
to call that symbol is called sijo
cjo is in the term is invented by pearl
people you know pearl people is always
colorful they
they you know their language
you know they use that then they started
to go after a few years after
about five years they they created a
name for that sigil
and i have a great story so let's go
back to my emacs
uh page okay let me tell you so you go
to my emacs
blog you go to the then
you go to the emacs miscellaneous
okay i have some uh past videos on
uh uh how to um
why emac this sucks okay then you just
search for cj
s-i-g-i-l the sigils
wall uh i so you know
so in for five or more than five years i
was using the greek characters and
that's how my
uh buffer looks you know the greek the
variable names are highlighted what so
so the question is why do i want that
why do i want that
sigil well the reason is
okay there are many ways to explain it
what the reason is that
you want to be able to be able to
distinguish
local variables and and
parameters of the function okay that's a
primary reason i want to do that
i want to be able to quickly discern
them
and okay further more advanced reason
for that
is is that this gets deeper okay
this you know so anyway this article i
just i talked about sigil wall
then i have a lot of articles about
my complete reasons why i want to use
the sigil okay you know for example
sigil for function parameter names okay
then there's another article i have you
know quite a few articles
here this one why i want to use sigil
variable naming english words considered
harmful uh okay so it's a big topic i
can go on one hour about it
you know so i have several articles this
is you know
in this article i explained why do you
want sigils okay why do you want cjos
then in this article i explain one of
the primary reasons why i want
to distinguish function functions
parameter names
from variable local variable names
biograms
okay then the more advanced question
is that you know this gets deeper
because you know when you when you talk
to haskell people
those functional programming uh nerds
you know
the phonetics they they keep they they
it's very fashionable they keep wanting
to talk about
static analysis you know if you know
what i mean static analysis
where where a source code you can
analyze what the source code do
without actually running it so there is
huge number of
advantages for that property and usually
it's this is associated with static
types
the main goal is to reduce programming
errors so you know
imagine you don't have to run your
program but however you can just run
another program to check on it and you
can know all
possible errors you know without
actually running your program
theoretically that's actually impossible
due to
um this you know that's impossible
there's a name for that it's called
uh what's the name you know you they're
tuned
chewing something you basically
you want to basically it's impossible to
check if a program will stop running
there's a name for that i forgot some of
you probably know type it okay
type it we are about to end let me
finish the rambo
so anyway it becomes it gets into
theoretical questions okay but
so it's impossible to have 100 static
typing i mean static analysis to be able
to find all your
errors but however haskell
you know those strongly typed languages
they they have those features mp
complete
uh well yeah not that's
mp complete that's that's the whole team
problem okay
yeah whole thing problem is the term i
was looking for you know
if you you may already know but if you
look up wikipedia you'll know what i'm
talking about holding problem
so it's theoretically impossible
actually to
have a static analysis to have a
programming language
such that you can run a static analyzer
such that you
you can know all possible errors without
actually running the program it's
impossible
and there's a theory to back up that
which is holding problem
so anyway but but still a lot of errors
you can find out by
uh static static analysis you know
that's why
the strongly typed languages they love
that they love that haskell people
okay so haskar people love that so
so in order to do that you have to have
strong
strongly typed languages but if you go
one step further you have
you know why not you know why not
let me let me tell you the story okay
about this naming issue
why not create
enforce a situation in your language so
that
all local variables must start with a
dollar sign let's say
okay by the way dollar sign is used in
perl it's
also used in ruby okay and in fact
ruby is more strict ruby if your
variable starts with a dollar sign then
it is absolutely of a local variable
cannot be otherwise okay
so there's a enforcement in ruby ruby
has a bunch of
a few other conventions so you see this
this has to do with static
static analysis you know it helps so
when you whenever you see a
variable name start with a dollar sign
then you know it's a
local variable and your static analyzer
also know that and then your compiler
will also know that
it helps a lot and but also as a
programmer when you code that you see
your dollar sign there you right away
you know
what that that's a local variable okay
that's you know that's one of the
advantage
and ruby has ruby and scheme this has
other
um advantage for example if a function
ends with a question mark
in ruby and in in in skim lisp
if a function name ends with a question
mark then you know for sure
that function will always return a
boolean okay
true or false for sure that because
that's
uh i don't think that's actually
enforced in ruby or
or or scheme but anyway they have that
convention okay
so first of all you have a convention
there's another issue whether the
language
actually enforce it okay so
so there are these issues about naming
okay so if you actually enforce it in
your language there are certain
advantages you know the
the compiler the static static analyzer
we all know
and will help your program and also as a
programmer it's you know you
you you can tell by a glance lots of
properties of your code
so what i want so that that's where my
cgo idea coming i want you know i want
sigils okay i
you know 20 years ago when i was a pro
programmer
you know i was i was the expert of a
pearl you know i coded
you know not like today you know back
then i worked in a
in a company for four years writing the
one of the first
uh back end uh
easter online store you know this is
to 2002 you know newtopia i worked you
know the
one of the first uh
the backbone the the engine of online
web store
that's sold to verizon and others
then they run the web store so merchant
can open a web store like yahoo store
like amazon okay so i was working in
industry
coding that i was you know a
top pearl expert back then
so so back then when i saw per person
you know i hated pearl
and the siege was but anyway but
but but a few years ago i started to
realize cjo is actually a good thing so
i want
i want all my code you know so when you
see a variable with a dollar sign then
you know
that you must enforce that to be a local
variable
and similarly you also i want also
a a cgo for the parameter of a functions
variable
so when you see that you know it's
absolutely a functions variable and you
cannot
change it you know a language you know
let's say a new language you should you
you could enforce that so that you know
a function's parameter is not
uh mutable and most of us of a seizure
so that
so all this has to do with uh static
uh analyzer and you know if your
philosophy
uh approves that you know if you think
this is a way to go
so apparently a lot of people do like
you know the haskar people uh
so that is the reason reason for this
for for my use of sigils
then there's a question about which
character you want to use for sigil you
know
for example you can use dollar sign
percent sign or the
pound sign or the add sign you know a
number of choices
ascii but then but today we have unicode
make let's make use of unicode let's be
progressive
okay in in the design of things let's go
let's use unicode you could have you
know have
20 100 000 characters so i choose you
know after the careful study i choose
the
greek this fee character
there are lots of reasons in choosing
them but
but i'm not going to go over them yeah
some of these are detailed some some of
some of the reasons okay
so that is why i use sigil so for five
years or my emacs code i have sigils
then
the emacs community you know the
traditional emacs gnu e-max their emac
this
coders they don't like that okay because
sadie guy
this is a weird nut job he don't conform
to our tradition you know he doesn't
conform to the emacs
idioms you know the the glue gospel so
a lot of people don't like me they and
they some of them will say oh this guy
don't know how to code
anyway after five years with cjos i
i stopped it you know because
yeah i'm being i'm being very
progressive you know i use these greek
characters but
the fact is in america usa you know
uh english-speaking countries this is
just too weird
uh people cannot accept it i mean my
readers you know some people see my code
they see this and they'll say okay what
what is that they get confused
then you have to explain you know you
get a lot of questions why are you
using that then i have it i have to
explain
then but when i would explain i have to
go you know i just explained for 20
minutes about all these
you know the static analyzing you know
too much explanation to do
then of course some of them most of them
speaking english you know
there's a problem with english only
language speakers because
when you use a character that's not
ascii they
they go nuts they go nutty because they
they just not used to it
on the other hand japanese people
chinese people you know you have
a big 1 billion coders you know they're
you know
not one billion but anyway other
language
and basically other you know languages
they they are they have no problem with
seizures with great characters because
in chinese and japanese
every captain you know you have ten
thousand characters you have to type
you know but with the
english in mostly american audience this
is just too weird you
i have a lot you know i have to answer a
lot of questions and stuff so
so eventually i decided that let's
i decided to stop you know stop using
the greek
characters procedure then
[Music]
then there's a question which ascii
character i want to use
you know if you use sc characters for
cgl then
then there's another set of problems
because for example
right now i'm using dollar sign then
people will have a question oh
is that part of uh emac list because you
know
for example in perl in php in
in ruby they all use dollar sign you
know as a convention
so then when when people are new to emac
these they are they'll think oh
um oh okay you have to use dollar sign
which is not true
uh there's still explanation to do
right yeah but i still so it's a
question you know so
are you going to use seizure or not i so
right now i'm still using sigils because
i think it's a good thing but
anyway that's a digression about sigils
which is very
interesting topic by the way
so i think that's it for today so let's
i think that's it for today so let's see
any other questions i didn't answer
uh i've been talking for one hour and 10
minutes
okay there's so let me answer the
questions and that'll be it for today
uh got a problem with the ansi term when
running some batch programs it doesn't
fit screen correctly
yeah yeah
snake case for variable in function
names okay compilers guys
love static analysis yes
scott would know a lot about compilers i
i you know so i'm trying to learn more
about compilers
so scott says like you i was writing a
lot more pearl
20 years ago so i'm used to c gels yeah
now i write now now that i write more c
and c plus first i'm not sure how
seizures would be accepted
by my peers yeah exactly yeah they'll
flame you to death
your code will not be accepted and
yeah you'll have a hard time to explain
your boss
you know your company what cg are doing
in clc
plus first so you know convention and
tradition they have a
huge force on how things will go yeah
uh so torrei says i use sigils in c
plus plus okay
okay i think that's it for today uh okay
thank you guys for coming thank you guys
for
coming um if you are new
if you like my stuff buy my emacs
tutorial okay buy my emacs tutorial
thank you guys see you next time bye
bye