good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi oh good I'm alive so
today we're gonna talk about geometric
inversion let's see let's see what we're
gonna talk about today I'm kind of late
I'm eight minutes late okay so today we
gonna talk about okay optional function
parameters in computer language
documentation this is one idiocy of the
hacker type of programmers I mean the
programmer ins the industry in general
so let's let's let's start talking about
that then we wait for people to come on
line
hey good morning Isaak how are you
so we're gonna talk about this the
option of functional parameter in
computer languages you know I don't have
a set of topic today yet so we're gonna
just see hey good morning web dog
haven't seen you for awhile so this in
computer documentation you see these
these documentation syntax notation for
functions optional parameters for
example this one is from Python Python 3
documentation same thing with Python -
okay so you have a function bisect
bisect left ok then you have several
arguments now some some are required
some are optional right so the first
argument is a list coma that that is
required then it says item item ok so
that's a second argument which is also
required then it puts a square bracket
then inside the square bracket you have
a coma then something you know so what
that means is that you know that means
this argument the
argument and so on is optional and the
the way the notation the commonly used
in programming industry in PHP in lots
of places is using the square bracket
for optional parameters now that's one
of the most idiotic thing you know so
this is part of my complaint this is
part of my complaint about programmers
and the programming in such industry and
the hacker types and all those basically
you know those people and all those
subjects they talk about the programmer
industry talk about that I think are
just utterly stupid now what why is it
stupid you know look at so so for
example this option of parameters so so
that example is from Python you can see
here and then we have another example
here is an example from PHP
documentation so you have this p IE g
grade okay now that's a function it the
first argument is a stream the second
argument is a array then the third
argument is flags and that's optional so
the way they indicate the you know the
third argument is that they put a square
bracket and inside it you start with a
coma you know so why this why is this
idiotic because you know this is
confusing because if you you know
because the square bracket is a valid
syntax in PHP and also in python
basically in all these languages so this
is confusing because you put a square
bracket you don't know I mean is it is
it does that mean for example in Python
when you put a square bracket after a
variable name that means usually means
you are extract
extracting an index of a string or a ray
or you know of a list or something like
that you know you put a square bracket
after some some variable name then
inside the square bracket maybe a number
like 2 you know that means you want to
get the second index item of that array
or string so so they use this square
bracket to indicate optional parameters
and then inside you you have a comma
this is very extremely stupid okay and
we also have another example this
example is from JavaScript documentation
on the Mozilla website the Firefox
website so I showed several examples you
know - I want to indicate you know so
this is very common you know it's it's
very common among programming
communities doesn't almost in every
language you have this kind of notation
to indicate optional parameters
I'm gonna check I'm gonna look at the
comment am I still alive yes okay so so
so the optional parameters yeah the the
square bracket you know that's very
idiotic you know just this thing this
has this this notation to indicate
option of members has been going on
since at least I would say this 1990s
you know nineteen nineties is basically
when I started to do programming so I
don't know if this happens earlier but
but you know it's very common and I have
never ever seen a complaint about this
notation you know I have never seen you
know programmer like programmers
complain about things all the time they
about programming languages about
you know problem of design you know
elegance of a language or something they
like they like this language they don't
like like that language you know they
like Lisp oh you know they you know they
they may have opinion like like turns
over but opinions on everything however
I have
never seen one single criticism of this
this this very extremely obvious and
apparent idiocy of this notation to you
to indicate optional parameters in a
function so you know so this is one
example where I I find you know this
industry program as they did in
especially especially those elite
hackers like like they are hacker news
like they're post you know their blogs
are we treated reposted by everyone
everyone you know one through you know
they want to tell you how you should
format formatting styles of programming
languages about you know also the things
and in patterns and how you know
functional programming or
object-oriented programming you know but
never I've never seen one one criticism
you know bitching about this so so to me
you know these programmers are just
completely ETA idiotic very okay I mean
what I want to say something I want to
bring out this this issue so you know so
the question is what what is going on I
mean so first of all do you agree or not
agree this is confusing you know do you
do you do you see this is a very stupid
problem and why so if first of all do
you agree you know we we ask all the
programmers you know you you you post
this to your friends you ask them do you
find this kind of stupid it's kind of
you know not correct then you ask them
okay suppose I mean first of all whether
it's stupid and at what degree and this
is like you know a score of night
stability or instability or not really
you know like it's actually good then
you say you put a score of one you know
five is you know unsure or it's okay you
know something like so you use a
in a school you know how utterly stupid
it is now if if if your friends most if
if most of them majority of them agree
that that this is a stupid notation okay
then the next question to ask is why why
is it that in the in the past twenty
thirty years no programmers ever talked
about this you know you asked them that
I mean first of all we we have to make
sure is it true they are that there are
no programmers ever mentioned this
problem you you know you do a study like
we can put it scientifically like likes
you survey let's say ten thousand
programmers ask them if they ever heard
of someone who complained about this
issue okay so we get the statistics so I
would say you know for my experience no
you know you we are not you know very
like almost nobody ever mentioned this
problem okay so that's another thing
then the next question we want to ask is
why is it that nobody ever know
programmers ever talk talked about this
problem now is it because programmers in
general do not complain obviously not
they can pay about all kind of things
like the end they talk they tell you
what you should be doing what is the
correct correct way you know they have
like we see it all the time language
flame war and so on right so then okay
so they do it express their opinions
then why then why is that nobody
mentioned this so this this issue you
know this is one of the one of the issue
I you know I I have lots of issues you
know I so so why am I talking about this
because what I might what I am doing now
is I want to express okay I want to tell
you well it's particular to me okay I
want to tell you that these frustrations
I mean because a lot of programmers call
me autre where whenever I talk about
programming stuff you know many
they think me as a troll but but this is
one example like you know when I say you
know UNIX philosophy I eat you know they
are Voodoo's okay so of course a lot of
people to disagree and you guys you know
probably a lot of you guys do not agree
and so I have this bunch of opinions
also you know the the wrapping of lying
like programmers are accustomed and
accustomed like people are told that
that you should have a hard wrap of a
lie every 80 characters or 70 characters
also so so you have so so so you have
all these issues okay issues on my plate
I have I have all these issues and today
this optional parameter notation of a
function is one of the issue I want to
bring out to address I want to you know
so this is one of my complaints that I
feel somehow the the industry of
programmers are just like you know like
a bunch of people on a truck like they
never actually think they never they are
not thinkers they do not think just like
just like outside of programming like
like religion followers like you know
like like the mob like average normal
people in other aspects of society
that's what I think okay that yeah
perhaps that perhaps that is why but
anyway so I'm talking about this
particular issue about optional
parameters in functional parameters
notation as one of the example and I
like you guys to think about it you know
I mean of you guys who are watching old
you know those people are watching so
why is this happening so to me I mean
like yesterday we talked about
JavaScript string problems which is
another extreme idiocy you know they are
a lot like that
so so anyway so that is the context I
just want to show an example okay of the
issue of you know this is a you know
concrete example it's not like it's not
like I'm bullshitting I mean everything
I say about here you can verify you can
see you know there's a screenshot and
you can ask people ask your friend or
ask yourself what do you think of this
situation is it good or bad why you
never seen programmers complain
okay so at this point if if you agree up
to this point then the question is why
two programmers what do you think you
know what's happening to the programmers
in the programming industry I mean why
are programmers never see this as one of
the problem you want to ask that you
know as a philosopher you know you you
you spend you know like today you know
you spent one hour to think about this I
mean in a serious way that's that's what
philosophy is about you know you think
about things you keep thinking about it
so you think about this you know let's
say for example for half an hour today
why programmers do not you know it seems
like they don't care or is it because
they didn't see the problem or is it
because like they are blind or I mean
what is going on oh is it because this
is really not an issue you know this is
actually a good notation you know maybe
that's is why do so you think about it
you know you you think about it for half
an hour today tomorrow you think about
it for another half hour you keep
thinking about it every day see this
this is what for us for philosophy and
philosophers - ok you you want to
seriously think about this problem for
like four months for a year you know and
and you want to write a report ok in
fact like you have to come into a
conclusion like like like this you know
you know suppose this is the issue like
about the size of the universe or about
some important
think about the nature of science so you
know that's what philosophers do you
know this is just the example you know
typically when people think of
philosophy they think of Oh Greeks or
something something or about the
universal meaning of life that's
actually not the essence of philosophy
okay those are the main subjects that
happens to be as a consequence is
somehow I mean it happens to be the main
subjects of philosophy but that that is
not the essence of loss philosophy
philosophy is you this is me you know
there are many ways to define many
things you can ask what is philosophy
then you know books about economy you
know their economies we'll talk about
what is the economy you know each
different book will have different like
definitions about and there are also
lots of books tons of books about math
and and mathematicians we often talk
about you know have a chapter or preface
like what is math or what is geometry
and they are you know that because there
are so many ways to see this to give you
a sense what it is about you know and
they so so so this is one of the example
what philosophy is doing I'm trying to
show you okay so philosophy so for us so
you think about this problem and in a
serious way
okay this concrete example about this
programming documentation notation and
you have to come into a conclusion I
mean that is important too I mean
philosophy is not about oh you just
think about things like you play video
games and bye-bye tomorrow you forgot
all about it no you have to like this is
some serious issue you come you you have
to come up a conclusion I mean it's like
like how deep you go depends on what
knowledge you have I mean you can go
into like anthropology I mean so is this
is this situation this because because
of certain neurons in your brain you
know
you know those who study brain
scientists you know is that because of
that or is it because certain psychology
because being a programmer you have
certain psychology you know the way you
perceive things therefore you don't see
these notation problems or is it because
you know that it's like the the
conclusion is totally free okay I mean
your way of thinking is is free you want
to think about it whatever you are your
style your background your your the way
you go up whatever comes to you so if I
mean if you are serious about things
okay about every everyday things maybe
politics you know you come you you think
about this every day for full now you
make you you have to make a you know a
see if you are writing you have to
eventually write a report like for
example a government when there's some
disaster or pilot politicians was some
accident accidents you know heavy
accidents or some political intrigue you
know some you know then then the
government says created some
organization that invest investigate you
know create an invest investigation you
know with you know ten thousand hundred
thousand dollars you know put into
emails okay what just exactly what's
going on who is at fault you know or
something like that so on this problem
as a philosopher okay you want to think
and you want to make a report because
you know as if it's a critical critical
like like if you did it wrong or if your
report is unfair or if your report is
you know shoddy or you know if you
didn't actually you know too lazy didn't
actually think about it and just random
glided up you you'll be blamed you all
have problems okay or people will suffer
okay so think of this as a really
serious problem you inquire you know
inquire into it
so that that is about this situation and
the other thing you want to think about
I mean when you think about things okay
this is one example and this applies to
many examples this is this is kind of
what I tend to do okay I mean not that
it's necessarily a good thing to do
because first of all if you are going to
be a philosopher you are now going to
have money to live okay you know you can
think about this problem for 10 years
and you are not it's it's not something
that bring you money you want you know
you know you want something to bring
your money you go to Europe you mop the
floor toilet at McDonald's that that
gives you immediate money or you go work
for Google to write programming and
debug that give you money anyway but
still philosophy you know once it wants
you think about this particular issue in
this example about notations you I mean
depending on how deep you go you can
spend one hour every day if you keep
doing you can spend you know two hours
and four for ten years it gets deeper
and deeper because this notation no
issue let me give you an example what
how is it possible it becomes deeper
this is a notation issue then you start
to research into notations you know
there is a subject of history of
mathematical notations then there's also
the subject I mean I mean the history of
math notations you can study for a full
year okay then you study the so then
maybe you get into history of math
notations then you start to wonder ok
maybe only mathematicians to certain
things this way maybe musicians maybe
because musicians and mathematicians are
different some musicians may not you
know maybe fall into this trap or
something so you maybe you start to
research our musical notations and
history of music notations and you start
to research writing systems
this is written this is not you know the
notation for functional parameters is
not verbal it's not a speech it's at
Wheaton so useless maybe you start go to
into linguistics you know writing
systems of the world oh you know what
what what is possible then you may be
going to maybe you know maybe you have
computer programming background so you
start to focus on you know the syntax of
programming languages so and maybe you
know you are thinking is that the
programmer whatever programming language
they are familiar with they tend to use
that programming languages syntax to
document the the features of you know
the programming language maybe that's
what you think okay so so so you start
to research into the syntax of
programming languages and that subject
you know as you know by itself is very
broad you can spend several years into
it full time you know what what are the
possible syntax is then you know so all
these superb I'm giving you examples
what what what it means
philosophy okay what what does it mean
what what does philosophies philosophers
do and so you so you the goal here is
you want to write a thesis you know so
let's say code let's cover cities so it
can be you know ten pages it can be
hundred pages depending on how how much
research you you can't go into this okay
you write a thesis and you you know the
topic can be becomes you know the
direction of future notations for
documentation you know it can be so many
so many ways and it actually again
depends on which aspect you you know you
are inclined to go to maybe you are
bored maybe you are you know you have an
eye for very specific narrow perspex
perspective you can go Verity
to that for example this can you can it
became you can became related to for
more languages you know which is a very
deep topic in theoretical computer
science so anyway you know you won't
think about this and you write a report
so ok so what is my point about talking
about these so first of all so I wanted
to show you yeah ok so the first issue
is something personal ok I want to show
you some of other things I'm doing about
programming languages that it seems to
me you know the most programmers in the
industry they are not just they don't
think about it for some reason
that's that's one that's first issue you
know and the second thing is that I
talked about
what does philosophy mean okay you know
the kind like what one perspective you
know there are so many perspectives I'm
giving you a 1% perspective of what the
essence of philosophy is about yeah I
guess that's that's it about that and of
course obviously this is interesting to
programmers because if you're most of
you are programmers right and you you
have to you know documentation you have
to read every day and you know bad
documentation is no good to you you know
you waste your time
good documentation is good so you want
to know how to document and what
documentation which kind of notation is
good you know so that's you know I
suppose that's interesting you know
that's actually actually the most
practical aspect of this subject and ok
so about this you know thing so what are
the so there are two things I wanted two
more things I want to talk about so this
notation is bad in my opinion what is a
good notation to express you know
optional parameters that's one thing
the other thing is then we the other
question is why do programmers actually
you know write it this way I mean white
so I have some opinions about that first
of all the okay so my opinion about why
programmers actually write the optional
parameters in this stupid notation is
because this notation is the
conventional notation from from the
conventional notation of passes okay
because you know let me show you the
passes okay let's go to yeah let me I'm
gonna answer the question real soon so
let me go into the sorry pauses because
I'm gonna show you
I'm gonna show you so what what I'm
saying is that this notation for
optional parameters with the square Brad
bracket it came from the traditional the
conventional notation for expressing
grammar okay for me language grammar
okay let me show you maybe I have a
example here syntax Ram abacus yeah
Backus no no form PNF that notation the
square bracket the use of square bracket
to indicate something that optional in a
syntax came from the convention the
convention of the conventional notation
of expressing grammar and this notation
is called Backus no form in P and F P
and F okay that's abbreviation so do I
have an example yes I do have an example
let me show you okay here I have an
article here this article is I looked I
studied about this in depth in you know
I spent several week also study this so
this article is about what is the
difference between P and F EP and f AP
and F now if you don't know the P and F
is a brief abacus no no form but what it
is is basically it's a syntax to express
programming language grammar and you
know most most programmers don't know
nothing about this unless you unless you
are someone who start to work on passes
passes of all compilers now if you write
if you have done any study of a
compilers maybe it's a homework at
college you'll know okay so this P and F
is a syntax to express a programming
language grammar now now there are
several variations you know
EMF EB and F AP and yep okay there are
these three are the major variations so
anyway in this syntax in in this grammar
the bracket notation let's see if we can
see your example here the square bracket
is used to indicate optional optional
sequence of symbols okay so anyway so
this is why okay so this is my reason
actually I think it's true it's a fact
this is the reason that programmers you
know it's it's have it's is adopted the
convention of using square brackets to
indicate optional parameters for
functions optional parameters in their
documentation okay now remember take
take notice that these two are different
things I mean one thing is about the
documentation of functions in you know
you know documentation the notation for
functions for function in your
documentation on the other hand this P
and F thing is is a syntax for grammar
grammar specification okay they are come
well they are they are related subject
of course but but you know it's actually
different in why why is the
documentation notation so anyway so so
that's about what why I think program
are doing it that way now the other
question I mean so is it so given not
now that we know why programmer do it
you know what the reason that
programmers are using this this notation
is it good no still I don't think he's
good because it's confusing you know
because first of all vast majority of
programmers like 99.99% you know what
one in 10,000 only one in 10,000
possibly no have experience about PMF
okay most are not I mean as a programmer
daily you know your job daily job is
program
emag baseball this pool you know front
and back and whatever you know of gaming
or you are not concerned about about
passing you know it's not a actually
typical daily programming problem you
know you
so anyway anyway this notation is is bad
okay so the other thing is then what
what is the what is a better notation a
better way when you talk him document a
function to indicate optional parameters
now I have a pinyin of that and I show
example here this this is a good example
this example is from Wolfram research on
the language will move from language or
also known as Mathematica so you can see
now this may be this is too small let me
magnify a little bit so let me let me
just show this okay so here is here is a
example of how you document of the
notation to document functions
parameters you know and optional
parameters so in first you know so here
we have a table function table is a
function
oops so table is a function in a Wolfram
language so you have first of all you
have you know table table takes two
arguments so you just you know by the
way the square bracket in the
mathematical language is is like is full
function you know it's like parenthesis
in in convention in you know in Python
or Java or JavaScript and so on so a
table takes two arguments expression and
n okay it will generate a list so so so
actually you know by the way table is
actually like a what what's called a
least comprehension in Python other
languages or Haskell but but in
Mathematica is actually of function it
it comes in a function form okay
but anyway table takes two arguments the
second argument can actually be a list
so you have these you know syntax then
the list can actually have three items
and actually can have four items as well
so you see you begin to see you know the
optional arguments are basically each
optional argument you you you repeat the
whole notation for the whole function so
it's clear you can clear clearly see
that table has these one two three four
five six you know six variations of
parameters you know and and the last one
we can see table takes more than you
know infinite infinite number of
arguments but anyway so this is a
notation I think it's a way way better
because you can clearly see all the
variations and you can say and there's
no confusion because you know when you
back to the Python example when you use
the square bracket in here there's a
confusion because square bracket is
actually a valid syntax in Python the
language so when you have a square
bracket maybe it means you know the
taking the index of an array or string
or it can also mean had was it hash
table or was it but anyway you know you
know what I mean you know it means
something in a programming language so
so it's very confusing but okay so let's
go back to Mathematica so anyway so this
is a good example in my opinion it's how
you should document functions and
functional and functions optional
parameters now so so I write a lot
programming
which tutorials right so this issue is
also you know so it's important to me
because I have I write so many
programming language you know tutorials
and often I need to indicate you know
functions parameters specification so
that when whenever there's a optional
parameter I also I follow basically I
use you know the Wolfram language is
notation to indicate a function of
parameters I have some examples here but
we can skip that so okay so so that that
concludes about this topic about
optional functional parameters
in computer language dogs okay let me
read the comments so that was so there
was a rather focused discussion so that
was 40 minutes about that topic so break
the loop says hi question from from
yesterday's topic about Unicode in
JavaScript what is ideal solution to you
make Unicode 32 the expected standard no
so the ideal solution is so yeah the
ideal solution is to introduce a pragma
okay so for example let me open a new
buffer magnify switch to a javascript
mod and so the ideal solution is to
introduce something like this okay use
2019 then then you do whatever
for example console.log one first one
okay let's run it oh I have to save it
xx star Jas okay let's run it so you
know we Saudis to so what does this mean
so the this this is a string okay when
you have a string and you know it just
does nothing so you put this string I
mean in so he Emacs I mean in JavaScript
you or
have you already have these okay so
actually you
it's just use that oops they said so so
you have this use strict it's called I
think it's called pragma let's just it's
just go to a website so people can
understand what it is what it is about
we don't want to go to you Street
so JavaScript has this new strict thing
I mean it's created so that you know
it's part of the language SPECT so when
you have this basically the the compiler
will look at your code in you know will
assume that it is following a new spec
so this is what I recommend a trick I
you know I think the ideal solution is
to introduce a new you know use 2019 so
that will means you know in 2019 we
introduce we change all the behaviors of
the string methods behavior you know we
change those as a 2019 spec so when so
people you know so when you when your
source code you can add you know use
2019 then all the functions methods will
have the behavior specified you know in
the year 2019 so it's kind of like like
the way to go into a new language
meanwhile it will be backward compatible
because you know you just don't you know
you just write code normally without
that use you know 2019 string then you
just you know be the old behavior so I
think that's a elegant solution I
mentioned this yesterday but the
JavaScript standard you know they they
people they they decided that they are
not going to introduce any new you
strict kind of thing because I think
they the reason is that they think it
going to create more complexity which I
don't agree but you know but what can
you do so so does so I am I like am I
still alive let's see five people
watching okay I'm still alive so break
the loop that that is a question that is
he you know what I think
so normal says I do agree the bracket
notation for optional arguments is
irritating and confusing yeah so Norman
says in erland documentation they show
complete form of all possible ways of
coding a function yet so that is similar
to the way Mathematica is doing things
you know I I really like the
mathematical language you know that's
language it happens to be the language
it happens to be my first language and
but in a mathematical language like I
mean let's not even talking talk about I
mean it's not just about language
because for example the way they
document things
there's no jargon and and look at this
notation issue it's just good it just
could what let me explain why is it good
because we found the wolf and Stefan
wolf I'm the guy okay he created the
language he is a well he professionally
well he was a physicist okay he's a you
know he's his quantum physics you know
he's a like like he's got a degree you
know when he was like a king and he
won't MacArthur Genius award so
literally he's a certified genius
then he you know so he published physics
physics you know papers when he was like
you know king or twenties in in you know
professional physicists journals
you know then he abandon academia he
went to create his own business so he's
you know he's really like a true genius
not just academic genius but he's you
know he he he run his you know company
and now that that company is muffin
research is you know very successful and
also by the way it's not a public
company it's not like a Google Facebook
like IPO you know it's not public traded
why because he wanted that way because
you know if you know anything about you
know the corporations in USA public
companies means you basically well
essentially means you know the public
you know all the n anyone have who has
money controls it controls the direction
that you get like how it will go what
direction you become that's what it
means
you know so he doesn't want he wants a
full control like he's so he's kind of a
weird guy you know so I mean so he
wanted full control on every aspect of
his creations Mathematica you know the
language the programming language how it
should move forward you know and he's
doing his stuff you know research on
physics or such oh you know he's he's
very into a cellular automata you know
new he is at a book called a new kind of
science actually I I read it I read it
like three times cover to cover a new
kind of science
he sent me in the book he kind of we
kind of you know we kind of are
acquainted you know he's actually sent
me an email last year
anyway so Wolfram language let's see so
he got this book and he brought this
book supposedly it's like 20 years of
his research he's very much into this
it's it's basically that the subject
matter is a cellular automata we should
talk about that because that's an
incredible fascinating topic okay
cellular automata and yeah you can we
you can look up Wikipedia by the way you
know you know you it will have articles
and by the way it also relates to
automata and theoretical computer
science and the regular expression and
you know it's actually all related form
and formal languages yeah that's a big
topic to go into but anyway so he's very
into that guy is very much into this so
yeah he controlled you know he has a
vision you know he you know and very
successful so yeah so so yeah back to
the previous topic so I I was saying the
reason Mathematica is such a it's rather
okay let's say one of the most coherent
and actually elegant language it's
because because you you when you think
about things you want to think like a
mathematician that's okay it's that does
not actually capture the whole essence
but anyway what I'm saying is that when
you think about things you want to think
in a mathematicians way and by that I
mean you want to eliminate you want to
eliminate eliminate anything that's
irrelevant
meaning that you you whatever you say oh
the result only captures only it
represents the essence of things in
that's one view of math you know so what
is mathematics mathematics is when
doesn't matter what what were saying
anything any topic politics or economy
or personal or how to how to you know
make you know how did how do we
influence people how to make friends how
to get a girlfriend you know any topic
when you eliminate anything else you
will irrelevant and when you do that
successfully that that that is
mathematics that's one way to view it
okay that is also why when you see math
you know you know real professional math
it's all like it's all abstract like you
have you know symbols it's like what is
this like it's unlike physics or you
know black hole at least you know like
black hole physics physics study you
know and this you can you know you can
imagine oh it's a black hole you know
because star you know what's a star you
know it collapse you become say oh ho
you know in its back but math it's not
something you can appreciate because it
eliminates all all all the things you
can perceive but it leaves only the core
which is kind of the ideas of the
relations and logic how they relate how
they how things relate that is what math
is about the Bo math okay not calculus
you study in school but because for
example in calculus you can still see
all speed oh you know the change of
speed is you know that all derivative is
because you want to get the
instantaneous speed you know you you
still have the concept of moving and
speed and so that so also uh but once
you take the Bo mathematicians version
of calculus which is which is called
analysis okay
in USA analysis you don't have that
anymore but the subject is pretty much
the same it's calculus but the way you
talk about it is with
you know speed or movement or cars or
you know directions it's nothing like
that it's all just kind of like symbols
and ideas ideas represented by symbols
and how they relate so that's so I guess
what I'm explaining is the one of the
aspects of perspective about math in it
the nature of mathematics okay so back
to the so so what I'm saying is that it
is because this way because of the
eliminate necessarily things this way of
perceiving or viewing or creating
languages that is what why I think
Mathematica is very elegant and and
including the documentation it's it just
it just makes sense it but by the way he
is probably not the first guy who to
created this notation for you know
optional parameters he's I'm pretty sure
he's not the first one to do this you
know but you know for example we also
see it in Ireland and I don't know if
Earl and you know the guy who I'm strong
you know who created a line who just
died two days ago few days ago he he has
seen the Mathematica documentation
probably not know oh let me speak
actually before Mathematica okay so what
is the alternative notation I just
covered that so are you guys still with
me
so keep the comments going okay so what
few more comments is C so Norman says I
think many and most programmers use IDE
that allows function auto completion
arguments are filled in they don't be
sold to documentation as much yet that's
true but no but you still need to do
documentation but because how how do you
know what arguments are you know what
they mean
so we're dogs
I like the typescript probably probably
some other languages too way so I so
dogs
web dog says I like the typescript way
of expressing optional parameters with
question marks in the identifier yeah
that's yeah I suppose that's that's I
think I think that without using your
question mark is definitely better than
using a square bracket
but although I still prefer the you know
the way of listening everything up but
by the way the way of listing every out
is actually not optimal because because
if you go back to think about the the
BNF notation you see if you go back to
the BNF notation
you cannot well you can actually but but
you know listing out all the possible
forms actually is impractical in the
context of creating a syntax for grammar
of a language okay so yeah anyway so so
by the way using a question mark is also
kind of common it's also a conventional
practice to indicate optional parameters
I think they put a question mark in
front of the the name right I thought so
small groups of single people like
Wolfram can exert control over a
language maintains conceptual integrity
yeah
listening every listing every
permutation of the argument could get
exhaustive yeah
well different event on what do you mean
exhaustive they are ambiguities here
because one what meaning is that it gets
tiresome
you know people cannot possibly list all
permutations of you know optional
arguments that's one sense you know
people get tired of it so it's not
practical the other sense is that
exhaustive is like comprehensive you
know it's complete so obviously if you
did every permutation then it's actually
complete so so normal says if the
language supports keyword arguments or
taste takes a map argument then you can
have a table listing those those instead
of all permutations yeah but that's true
I mean but but that would be a different
thing right I mean because then you are
changing the functions arguments so
that's actually a different issue you
know so I guess that's about yeah that's
about the maybe that's about it today
that's the main topic you know I didn't
know what topic to talk about today
every time I start to do a talk Sal
talks showed like I was you know I don't
know what to talk about not because I
don't have topics but because you know I
have so many I mean I do have so many
topics but you know and it's like I have
to decide then you know but usually like
I just randomly picked a topic and that
insert
like almost an hour okay so that's one
topic about optional function so normal
normal says so stories about my me
working at whooping I don't have much
stories but actually I can tell you some
yeah some experiences but actually also
let me see
so sorry programming experience okay
let's let's try to search that sorry for
memory you experience because I have
written an article about that so I have
an article that's my impression of Lisp
from Mathematica okay then I have
another article okay anyway whoops wait
wait
by the way this page by the way Jang
bays is a great quantum mechanics
physics and he's also a great
mathematician I learned tremendous math
from him in the past in a Google first
days so I learned tremendous math from
him in a span of three years and Google
first shut down and he is now on Twitter
so if you are on Twitter you can follow
Jang pace okay and he is also category
theorist he's he's very much into
category theory and in fact he talked
about it he talked about it all the time
and he actually teaches it you know he
has been teaching it for you know maybe
10 over 10 years maybe and yeah I mean
he's not he's not a programmer though
he's not a programmer so he doesn't know
he doesn't really have any you know much
about anything about programming but
however so he if you are into category
theory you know follow him we'll check
out his stuff okay so I have article
here my impressions of Lisp from
Mathematica because I programmed
Mathematica for 10 years then in 1990s
then I start to learn Lisp around 1991
or 1998
okay so Mathematica is actually Lisp
okay you know you could say that so you
know so this this article this is
written in 2008 actually I think is
written much earlier than that but
anyway so you can see some of my
histories about my impressions of Lisp
basically it sucks compared to
Mathematica it's like you know yeah it's
true you know it's like back in 2008 you
know I might when I have the
for example why the you know I'm a think
okay I don't actually know this that
well so maybe my impression of Lisp from
my experience of Mathematica is may be
biased and also back then I don't know
much I don't know that much about
programming or computer science you know
as compared to now for example at after
all it's after twenty years so you know
so even though I have some opinions and
some of them are strong opinions but you
know I'm thinking maybe actually I could
be you know my my impression is wrong
because I don't really know many of the
topics about programming languages or
design or you know stuff but now today
for example today my opinion back then
is absolutely correct
okay like III I do not change my opinion
in fact it's 10 times more solid
Mathematica compared to all that list
doesn't matter what list of
list common list skinless racket they
are in relation when you compare those
lisps to Mathematica all those lists are
this is like ten times war was okay
no in every aspect in syntax in
semantics in how powerful it is in
express ability in in how short you know
you can express it in how flexible the
syntax can change you know in every
aspect and and and in practicality they
are much more inferior than Mathematica
okay I you know this idea becomes
stronger and stronger over the years as
I learn more languages you know and
understand more you know different areas
of programming and computation but there
is one issue about Mathematica because
its proprietary you know so all of you
open source fast you can forget it
immediately now you have a choice okay
you have a choice
when is that stick with your open source
the fantasy okay stick with your open
source philosophy stick with the open
source mindset you know you are not ever
going to touch anything that's
proprietary so Mathematica is
proprietary you close your toilet you
know like don't look at you like you
don't care
think it doesn't matter what it is you
don't want to hear it okay that's one of
the choice you can make the other choice
is then you have to like oh my god
Mathematica Casali says you know
Mathematica is this in that maybe you
know I should look at it you know maybe
I should you know even though it's
proprietary but so you have a dilemma
now okay method so Mathematica and so
what I want to yeah I want to I was
going to show you an article where I
talked about some experiences where I
was at Wolfram and that and you can find
that Arco by I don't remember what
keyword to search but but I think I can
find an article by going to okay here's
the keyword to search sorry Peter Novick
Peter Novick is one of the Lisp God okay
it's it's considerable by you know
programmers as Lisp and AI God
he wrote a idiotic essay that is widely
spread Amanda he did hacker schools you
know so I want to find my article sorry
Peter Novick
okay so let me try this sorry
learn programming in ten years
oh no Vic Vig right
yeah
there it is the Arco is named the
condition of Industry of programmers
learn Lisp in ten days okay
now I wrote this in 2006 now this this
essay is a reaction to the Peter Novak's
article is a very popular article okay
it was hugely widely spread it's called
the title of that Arco is teach yourself
programming in ten years it's written in
2001 by Peter Novick okay the guy so you
can see I have a link to his article and
his and he has translated translated to
many languages you know Chinese
Bulgarian you know this idiot
well he's not an idiot but he's but this
concept in his essay is idiot okay and
it's widely embraced by the elite
hackers idiot in the programming
community the the UNIX philosophy people
the least people the common lisp
fanatics you know the the hate and so of
Haskell people you know they spread this
every day you know learn list so so what
what is this essay saying teach yourself
programming ten years by Peter Novick
you know what what is he saying
basically he is saying that you know how
common is in the industry where you have
books like learn something XYZ in ten
days or in one hour or in one month you
know learn master C++ in a week you know
master HTTP in one week you know those
books are extremely popular
so his essay you know it's basically an
attack on on those on those you know
learn something in ten days you know
because so what he is saying is that you
know programming you should actually you
should really take your time to master
master it you know so he's saying you
know in ten
years that's kind of exaggeration but
he's saying you really should take your
time to master a programming language
you know and he gave his reasons
okay so and programmers love this this
idea so every every idiotic idiot hacker
types spread this essay so so what is
wrong with this essay what what is wrong
with this concept so in my opinion okay
so I wrote a reaction piece so this this
is my reaction my the condition of
industrial programmers learn Lisp in ten
days so that's my title of my essay so
what I am saying is that the Peter
Novick guy okay he says eh I mean as a
guy he's you know I think he's a good
guy and he's a great expert in Common
Lisp and also he's a great expert in
artificial intelligence of the classic
era okay anyway
so what's wrong with his essay with his
idea of you know how programmers should
you know take years to really master
language my okay so so I think it's
stupid because this kind of idea is
basically unrealistic I mean it's a it's
a idealists notion of really it's like
ignore reality you know and it does not
address the heart of the problem what is
a problem the phenomenon of you know
learn something in one day learn
something in five hours those books are
very popular in fact everyone is doing
that you know you when you want to find
a job you want to you know study a
foreign language you want to get the
book that's a that teaches you you know
suddenly something for dummies you know
learn something in one week that's what
you want everyone you know for every one
of you you are not going to oh I need to
actually I need to do this you know I
need to take my time and I you know
envision I'm going to learn it in tennis
nobody is doing that you need the job
like next month you you're gonna spend
this much
you know study this subject and get a
job you know so you can feed yourself
you can be alive you can you know feed
your family and whatever that's reality
okay so it's it's a fact of life you
have to you know that's a reality so but
he's sa this Peter Novick you know he
says hey he's like okay let's you know
yeah we ideally you know he forgot the
word ideally you know so he so he's
saying ideally we should you know or
take our time there's no rush you know
the word you know we should just relax
and learn language for 10 years
hideously you that that's that's that's
that's ignoring reality okay that's not
not looking at reality like you close
your eyes you know you live in a cave
you know you pretend you know you don't
have to worry about job you don't have
to like all the young people they don't
have like they have ten years sitting at
their home and doing learning foreign
language you know so this is Edie
idiotic concept so I wrote you know
essay to you know to say my opinions but
but in this essay I also mentioned some
some of my experience at Wolfram
research yeah so anyway so so what is my
experience at Wolf and research actually
I only worked there for half a year okay
in 1995 I was there originally I was
supposed to be there as a summer intern
for four months I think yeah a summer
intern you know for a month 1995 then I
was going to UC Berkeley you know after
the intern so I went there 1995 and I
end up staying there for like half a
year you know and not coming back to
California you know I went to you roof
and researches at Champaign Illinois
okay kabaah Marsh
champagne you know that's a city name
you
no it says it is a small college town
okay anyway so in 1995 and when there
was an intern in a beginning then I kind
of just stayed for you know I kind of
just stayed working for them for half a
year eventually I came back because you
eventually I decided you know I should
go back to UC Berkeley but I never went
you know that's kind of my life story no
decision you know dude wandering around
no go and just you know do whatever I do
you know it so happens to be kind of
like my personality my style you know
it's just aimlessly emili´s you know
dreaming wondering stuff so anyway so I
was there for an intern but you know he
he we i ID so I talked to him he kind he
liked he liked me okay and he wanted me
to stay and so what so what I do there I
basically so by the way so I was
arranging her intern but anyway so what
I do there I actually there is no
assigned task for me to do like you have
to you know you have you have a manager
you you have to do this you know by this
week or by whatever you know it's like
you have to this actually nothing like
that actually I it happens to be that I
just I was there and just do my things I
you know it was I was you know I was you
know I was one of the guy you know I'm
so much into math and into programming
like even today you know I Sydney from a
computer I just have to I have to study
passes or whatever you know philosophy
about computer science so automata
theory you know I you know I just have
to it's like I have to do this so it's
the same back then you know so I just
I'm very into and back then I was like
programming Mathematica you know all day
everyday you know I read you know the
mystic book you know three three times
cover to cover the Mathematica manual so
I was there so you know so obviously you
can
see that they they can see that you are
going to do whatever you do because
that's you had you know say anyway so
they they didn't I just I was there to
do this I'm just doing whatever I was
doing and I was doing this visual
dictionary of special plane curves okay
that is the project basically this is a
result of my of my walking there
you got several mathematical packages
the this entire website I didn't create
a website when I was there but after I
came back to California in 1996 1997 I
created this website and this is one of
the most popular website back then up to
up to late 2000s up to let's say 2007
it's the most popular one the let's say
top 100 most popular website on top 100
most popular website whose subject is
mathematics yeah especially you know
earlier days let's say around 2000 it's
it would be top 10 something like that
so this website you have animations
basically it's a it's kind of a visual
dictionary of special plane curves ok so
you know yeah and it's got animations
it's got Mathematica packages and it's
got interactive geogebra so that that's
what I did ok sorry this is the project
I did study math study math you know
calculus you know playing curves this
quick geometry you know the you know
there's lots of things in you know so
that's what I was doing so a Wolfram
research I just I was just writing
mathematical code on on these kind of
visualization things I you know wrote a
lot of them
yeah so for half a year that's that's
that's why what I was doing had a
Wolfram research so I think that let me
read a comment and that would be it for
today yeah so let's see
next video of mathematica live coding
actually I have encoded that Mathematica
for over 10 years and in fact I don't
have it I don't have it on my Mac you
know I really what I need to do is to
get a job because I'm like I don't have
money to eat and I probably there's one
possibility I can go work for Wolfram
research I don't know
so Norman says also curious why you seem
to dislike Nelson Talib yeah he can be
abrasive but yeah I think he's a
crackpot you know I can't be I can't say
for sure but from what I've seen so far
I think he's a crackpot he if he has
many of the symptoms symptoms or
properties or what you say
characteristics of crackpot of you know
the code leader for example one of the
characteristic characteristics of coat
is jargons you always have lots of
jargons and also the other thing is like
see crucian like cut you away from any
outside thinking like you know for
example he he he likes to pan people
like like i didn't mix like Heep and me
okay yeah it's not even is it's not like
I even really attacked him he just spent
me on Twitter so I mean anyway that's
the topic we can go into detail but
probably not today today is kind of the
end of it and also he kind of attract
people like he forms a coat okay
his followers kind of you know it's the
type that forms a coat now actually you
can say that you can say the same about
me because my father's tends to be you
know the net the mainstream the main the
the non mainstream people and usually
you know kind of niche and by anyway
yeah so we can maybe talk about
yeah actually I don't have that much to
talk about him so that's probably it
the nessam Talib you know and also I you
know so one of the things he do is
jargons he likes to create joggins okay
let me I have checked out his book I
mean I'm look I have spent you know a
few hours to look look up what this guy
is about what has he done you know he's
he said he has written books you know
what are those books about you know and
you know the nature of those you know I
have looked he likes to one of the thing
he likes he likes to create jargons okay
like opaque joggers which which is one
of the hallmark of the code creators you
know that those kind of people like the
purl people Larry Walker and other
crackpot sing in programming community
so he liked to create jargons for
example one of the jargon he created is
these anti fracture is that correct
something like that anti fracture and
and then he liked to pen people you know
he likes to then like he he wants to
create a thought to to all his followers
so that so that you forms a sense kind
of kind of us and them you know whoever
don't whoever are not smart they are
stupid we we want to cut off ties with
them so he likes to form these this this
kind of a war between you know he and
his followers in the outside so that
that's another characteristics of code
okay I mean if you study code which I
have you know because I'm upset it's one
of the topic and I spent you know I'm
very interested in my whole life in the
past 30 years Scientology religion you
know sects different you know google of
them how they from how they form what's
their tactics and related to marketing
brainwashing propaganda how they related
what they do
you know what what's their formation you
know how they work you know I'm very
interested in this kind of topic it's
all related so so one of the thing he
does is like yeah chugging chugging is
one of them usually a coat or sect kind
of or even a gangster they have their
like a systematic way of talking about
things it's all jargons like different
from normal usage of the word so he's
he's into Chagas this nessam guy one of
the jogging is anti fragile you know
like he you know he swallows will just
start to say oh this is anti fat fragile
pattern it's like the programming
the programming community you
have patterns oh this is a factory
pattern or you know they create a
chargon that you know anyway jeongeun's
okay that's one of the his thing I found
and he'd you know so I noticed and and
and yesterday you know a few days ago I
have a friend or followers okay who when
I was commenting on the pianist Glenn
could okay I made some comment you know
Glenn could is a very weird guy it's
well known it's a fact that he's very
weird and he has some kind of
personality psychology issue it's a it's
a fact okay then suddenly this my friend
this my acquaintance I would say my
followers he's from Russia by the by the
way is that Quint egg I'm not sure it's
possible anyway he over sudden he made a
comment like you are wrong like like you
are wrong then but I don't know what I
mean what do you mean by I'm wrong I
mean he said you know green code is well
known you know he's well known for his
weird like he has to have a specific
chair it's kind of like you know a
pianist a piano player usually use it on
a kind of a pinch you know a piano bench
but that guy he needs must
it's a requirement he sit on a
no mod wooden chair his dad made for him
it's not a piano chair it's like a just
a wooden a very strange
I actually I have picture actually it's
just such for Glenn could you know
Wikipedia and you will see it you know
so he's a very real guy we all know okay
it's a fact but then suddenly my you
know my acquaintance did you know
kindness of my he say he says you are
wrong
hey I don't know what's going on you
know so what what do you mean I'm good
wrong like do you have what what is the
reason I think I have no idea what what
is going on because I thought it's a
common well-known fact you know this guy
is weird
then he started to say you know like you
know it turns out you know he say
something like psychology like the
almost like the entire branch of
psychology is so after we made
several exchanges because I was trying
to find out what do you what do you mean
I'm wrong
I mean it's like I'm shocked other blue
he says I'm wrong and this is from one
of my followers you know I usually I
have some sense you know who is
following me you know who you know so
yeah I was surprised you know what do
you mean I mean he's a you know he's a
friend you know suddenly he says you
know you are wrong so what do you mean
so after several exchanges it has it
seems like he's saying that he's got the
sense that all psychology is the whole
the whole you know field of psychology
is though eventually it turns
out you know that that idea came from
this nascent guide is this this this you
know this guy we were talking about the
the anti fragile guy so he showed me you
know healing to a Twitter post by this
nessam guy basically says the entire you
know psychology is is idiotic you know
so another characteristic
characteristics of this NASM guy is like
he liked to make
traversée okay he liked to make
statements that are wild and he's like
the ho the like he says literally like
like paraphrase like something like the
whole entire psychology field is is
idiotic is stupid you know he made a
statement so that's another reason
that's another trait I think I find this
guy to be questionable crackpot because
that's one of the it's that's one of the
technique to to make yourself famous you
know that you know when you make wild
you know creams and then you form you
firm kind of like you versus versus name
situation like he also made a statement
apparently I learned from high
acquaintance that that that something
like don't follow
IDI Arctic people you know like the the
idea is that the assumption is that in a
world that you know most people are
idiot when you see those people
immediately you know make a war like cut
them out don't don't ever listen it
seems to suggest that you know I don't
know where that came from but apparently
it's from that that nasan guy so all
these reasons so by the way I think it's
actually true most majority of people in
a world in majority of let's say let's
put this way majority of opinions you
see online or in real life are stupid
that is actually true because you know
because nobody has the time to study
everything there are millions of subject
matters may be social or Sciences of
philosophy or how to do things so the
way of life how to think you know what
decisions to make you know all
literature what books to read you know
what programming language to learn you
know like obediently an infinite number
of questions about life and nobody
really can possibly be well-versed in
all the
you know this infinite number of things
so most of us you know maybe we are a
little bit smart or maybe not you know
you don't have to be smart but the fact
is doesn't matter how smart you are
you cannot know you know you only know
very tiny almost instantly insignificant
amount of things even about life you
know about maybe you are the greatest
mathematician but when it comes to real
life you know what what you for example
how you how politics works
you don't know no idea how to run a
business or what should start up to you
know you know idea maybe the most stupid
actually so that's a situation you know
so so most opinions actually it's
actually true most opinions doesn't
matter in online or real life is
actually stupid you know so when you
hear other opinions including my you you
know you you you want to think about it
is this guy its opinion in this subject
is this really good you know that's a
good question question to ask so that's
what that's what I think about that guy
the nasiha thats why I think he and so I
get you know I haven't released as you
know spend day so you know to research
what that guy is but I feel that he's a
crackpot let's see okay I think that's
that's it
90 minutes okay curious what you seem to
dislike yeah Nassim Taleb is that how
you pronounce his name
Nassim Taleb yeah and he also blocked me
you know very early on actually I was
like I was because I have friends you
know suggesting I follow him you know
and so I did and but I didn't
immediately get any you know I I didn't
find his it's wisdom or something
you know and one day I made a you know
kind of questionable I mean a question
he's coming I forgot you can search
traitor you can probably find it I'm
pretty sure we can find it you know
because because I did not did I did not
delete it you know so then he just
blocked me it's like so okay that's it
for today thank you guys for watching if
you like my stuff support me you know I
got you know just go to any of my
website you can see you know my patron
my Amazon gift PayPal put your money
there or Bitcoin okay so thank you guys
for coming by
until next time