everyone welcome to another episode of
kasan talk show we are going to code
wolam language Mathematica today on
mathematics geometry plain curves
hyperbola and uh I'm going to show you
how to create
animations uh uh animations in wolam
language there are two kinds one is
interactive that is for example you can
create a polom a curve then you can
create several sliders you adjust the
sliders and you see the graph change
interactively as you move the
slider that's interactive animation okay
or interactive Graphics of course then
you can rotate you can create a surface
3D surface or 3D object rotate it change
parameters in real time and see a change
the other thing uh is creating an
animation so let me show you an
animation so yesterday we did uh
yesterday we
did Unicode math symbols in programming
languages in emac we talked about this
guy uh uh so check out yesterday and uh
so today but today we back to wolam
language uh in the past two weeks I've
done several wam language so we did
Parabola we did this one see the optical
properties beautiful but okay so but let
me go to today what we want to what we
want to do okay so you can see this
beautiful uh 3D surfaces okay we did
this one live this is hyperboloid of one
sheet okay H this is called hyperboloid
one sheet why one sheet because there's
only one sheet because there is also
hyperbola hyper hyperboloid of two
sheets okay so this is hyper the one
sheet we did this Live on YouTube about
3 years ago is that beautiful you know
this so you can
see take out go to your kitchen in your
kitchen cupboard take out a bunch of
spaghetti you know long noodles you put
them in a
jar you know to it a little bit then you
get this this they you know the
spaghetti fall into these old chopsticks
and they form a surface they form a
surface that is hyperbola of Revolution
so you take a
hyperbola you take a hyperbola like like
this you know just just a curve PL curve
you rotate it around the center axis
then you get that um hyperboloid of one
sheet beautiful okay so so you have to
see each one of these
glorious beautiful math mathematics now
as we talked about mathematics beauty of
mathematics there are two parts one is
just the sheer visual Beauty like this
one hyperboloid one sheet so you can see
one of the property immediately came out
is that this surface is actually made of
straight lines every point on the
surface is is is is a line so is a line
on the surface okay so this surface is
actually made of of straight lines and
and then it is also a hyp hyperbola of
Revolution you know you rotate it so
there's so many interesting fascinating
beautiful properties and this picture
you see this is in Second
Life Second Life we I you know I lived
in Second Life for like three four years
second is another interesting topic okay
so you can play chess you can have this
uh fireworks in Second Life it's
immersive you know when you are in
Second Life like you can walk around and
turn your head and then you see this
um uh immersive you get immersive
experience so but today you got 3D
goggles okay so but anyway where's that
chess indoor games that chess I wanted
to to show this one
so a a mouse character is playing chess
so you can play chess in Second Life you
know you can move those uh chess pieces
so it's I had tremendous fun uh around
2007 to
20111 basically I spend like five hours
a day in Second Life you can also play
all sort of games okay Al second live is
a interesting thing but let's go back um
let's go back um because that's not
today you know we were talking about
hyperbola okay so
hyperbola so I was saying by the way if
you roll a dice a cube you know you spin
it that shape the silate formed on the
side is a hyperbola why because
obviously just like this rotation of a
bar you know so so the seway of a
rotating cube is a hyperboloid okay
hyperbola okay so you know and and this
this uh is also intriguing you you can
see uh can you play it
Loop you see intriguing It seems
impossible you see but it demonstrate
how the hyperboloid surface is
actually a surface made of a a single
line called ruled surface okay any
surface that can be made by just moving
a line those surfaces are called ruled
surfaces
okay and then you hyperbola is you can
see a lot of hyperboloid of one sheet or
two sheets in
architecture uh in
planetariums in uh in Towers this one is
Tokyo Tower spectacular Tokyo uh Koto is
it Tokyo or Koto cob okay cob C Kobe or
cob in Japan okay then you have the gear
so I need to update this gear picture so
that it's actual actually a photo so
this gear allows you
to have two axess in a a configuration
so you want to for example car
transmission system you see but with the
car transmission it's orthogonal you
know but you you want it to be able to
if they are not orthogonal so you got
this hyperboloid gear okay so I need so
if you know if you guys in the
mechanical engineering department you
know any photo of the real hyperboloid
gear uh show me I need to update it this
uh drawing because this drawing is not
very well made you can tell this drawing
is from the book Penrose styles to trap
door
ciphers it's not very good uh
3D draft okay so back in the days 20
years ago you don't have computer AED
design system you don't have computer
Graphics like that so you draw it
manually but this one is not well done
because you can kind of see it's it's
not very well done okay so I was saying
now back to previous topic I was saying
in mathematics there's two kind of
beauty one is the sheer visual Beauty
like so far we've talked about sheer
visual Beauty but the other beauty is
intrinsic that's that's these equations
you know that takes you know so like
that's this this is what gets
mathematician excited because when you
understand the formula the cature you
know then you see the properties then
it's sheer abstract beauty without you
know
without any pictures geometry okay so
this is hyperboloid of one sheet now so
what is hyperboloid of two sheet that's
like that okay so you again rotate
hyperbola but you rotate this
time uh this time you rotate around
the horizontal axis okay that's called
transverse axis then you get
this hyperboloid of two sheet okay um
okay so anyway so what we going to do
today so am I is the introduction good
I'm going to start to code okay say hi
if you are here say hi love to see your
comments if you're are not here skip
around play at 1.5 speed
uh so we're going to do animation okay
let me finish the hyperboloid um yeah so
hyperboloid of one sheet hyperboloid of
of um two
sheets one sheet and two sheets and then
we were talking about hyperbola and we
were talking about the beauty of
mathematics of two aspects one is purely
visual the other one is intrinsic the
abstract you know you know the group
Theory uh field Theory ring Theory
abstract algebra those are or topology
or complex analysis or analysis you know
that the sheer abstract
Beauty okay so but what is it we're
going to do today so you can see this
animation this animation illustrates one
of the
properties to gener generate a hyper
blood or to draw a hyper blood in other
words this is a way to construct that's
how they say construct a hypera okay you
so you can by this mechanical
means create a h hyperbola but okay so
those are animation I created 30 years
ago today we're going to do this real
time okay am I good check video check
audio check I think I'm good so say hi
okay say hi say
hi okay so let's start to code okay show
in browser this is today talk show and
go to hyperbola so this move this to the
top hypera okay let's go there open the
page showing browser okay now there's a
notebook go back to here notebook make a
backup open it so this is Wolf
Mathematica wam language you can
download for free uh all you have to do
is check out my website okay S Talk Show
wam Language tutorial about the author
wam language in depth download you know
you can download for
free okay so here is my old notebook so
there's one last thing remain to do so
this is 30 years old notebook or I have
all I want to do is just convert these
animations update it put a code on my
website then basically delete this
notebook
okay so let's begin okay so close this
uh showing browser so we want to go to
the
section where go down go down go down go
down go down go down rectangular hyper
okay this is x * y = 1 very simple so
this is a hyperbola rotated you know uh
45 degrees and uh and they they are they
are rectangular hyperbola meaning that
there asymptot asymptotes forms a
orthogonal forms across okay so
rectangular hyperbola there pointwise
construction Okay so this method is
derived from the parametric formula for
hyperbola secant and tangent x equal to
secant t y equal to tangent t Okay where
AB are radius is of the concentric
Circle okay if a equals to B then the
curve traced is a rectangular hyperbola
okay
so
um so we can do this let me show you
another thing thing that's G algebra
okay so this is G algebra you can
see we I constructed you know like over
100 of this in the past 20 years so you
can adjust
the so the way you do this is that it's
magnify okay so the way you do this you
start with two fixed circles A and B so
you see A and B two fixed circles okay
then you draw dra a
line let's see then you draw two
lines touching that's tangent to the
circle so you got the circle a you draw
a vertical line tangent to it okay then
you have another Circle you do the same
thing you have a line tangent to it so
you got two
lines okay two vertical lines parallel
to each
other then what you do then you draw a
line from the center of the circle okay
to to any point on on the on the circle
B
okay then so let's see if we can magnify
this yes we can okay so let me just do
this CLE can you guys
see so two circles A and B and two
vertical lines here and here then you
draw a ray from the center of the circle
okay then let's see how it works so you
see visual mathematics is such that you
can just look at this graph and see how
how this works so you can see this blue
curve is a
hyperbola so but how is it formed let's
see um so you draw a
aray okay so the ray will intersect
these two vertical lines at Point A1 and
B1 you can see A1 and B1 so they in so
this
Ray this Ray will intersect these two
vertical lines at Point A1 and B1
okay
now now take the inner vertical line
draw a circle you got this you got this
this green circle can you
see you see they okay so let's start
moving so take the in you
know you draw a circle passing the A1
okay you form this curve I mean this
circle then then you draw another ver
vertical line tangent to to the New
Circle okay then you draw a horizontal
line passing the
B1 then the intersection of these two
new lines is a point on
hyperbola okay there so you can see as
you change this this direction of the
aray they trace out different points so
for example right at here you
got okay can you see you got oh wait you
got uh
so you got this
line and this okay so you canot use the
pen
uh you got this circle you got this
vertical green line then you got this
horizontal line their Cross Point is the
point on
hyperbola now if you change this Ray
let's say is smaller let's say same
thing
okay same thing you know exactly the
same rule apply then then you got a
point uh here you see you see the the
point for the hyperbola is the two green
lines okay so let's go
slowly look at the two green lines can
you guys see it okay we losing user stop
the philosophical zombies I love wam
okay
so I'm not sure actually you guys can
see this because the lines are too thin
okay maybe I wasted time but
anyway um okay let's go back here so I
want to this code is in my package okay
so let's go to the
package so here's a Cod code search
for hyperbola generator so there it is
so you can
see here is a code and the code is
about 50 lines okay so in fact there's a
lot of tabs okay I want to remove
that okay uh show I space let let me do
that hold on a second
so
replace tab by space okay do it do it do
it do
it okay we we kind of done it so let's
see let me just copy it here okay so go
back to wam language open a new one
paste it so now it might look better
here so let's
magnify so here's a code to generate
this this
animation and uh let's make
it shift control
n so that they
are
formatted type set okay so you can see
the square root there okay so let's look
at the code so I believe that's it this
is a independent code okay
yeah okay so this is actual this this
part actual CA the function so let's try
that
copy uh so go down here go down there
paste control shift n to make it typ
set now go
up now let's
see where does this
begin okay so split
and uh I want to hold on a second copy
that go to the
top
clear clear this symbol so that's the
only symbol we are defining okay so this
defines the option for the parameter for
for this
so hyperbola generator given a radius
least so you need the radius you need
two circles
okay
okay can you guys see can you guys see
the pictures
well can can you guys see this picture
well let me know is a is the line too
thin to see is it visible at all
so anyway so you need so this function
takes two radius that's radius of two
given
circles then you take a range list okay
range that's 0er to 2 pi that's how how
much you want to sweep okay if you Adit
it then it's going to be 0 to 1.4 okay
that's the default value okay then then
whatever come after that is just the
option which is number of frames okay
now I know how to use this
function um the function has a usage
documentation which is here so we can
let's might as well paste it there
okay so that's a documentation for this
function okay but I already know how to
use it so here so here is two radius two
and one then from 0 to 2.1
25 so that would
be uh about less than half pi so Pi is 1
Point Pi is 3.14 something half pi is
1.56 something so 1.25 is a little bit
less than half
pi so that you know basically 80°
something
okay so last frame only true okay let's
evolve the whole thing let's just eval
evaluated shift enter
fantastic fantastic you see it generates
array
fantastic now there is some uh minor
issue here so option unknown option last
frame
only okay I think I remove that option
let's see yeah I remove that option so
so delete that let's do it again okay so
you can see can you actually see it
yeah okay so now we want to make this
animation okay so let's do
that all you have to do in wam language
is to say
animate Okay add that expression shift
enter uh no so anime is actually
we let's see the
documentation animate expression
something
something okay so that's not the command
we
want this is the animate okay so let me
show you this so you
see so if you have a sign you want to
plus sign x + a where X is a variable
and a is a constant but you want to
change a you know you see what happens
then you can plot it then you can say
anime okay but what we want here is not
this and also you can do it
interactively so for example so that's
the power of wolam language let me copy
it so let me show
you stop stop
play parameter change parameter a stop
play change parameter B so you can drag
the slider and you can see how a
parameter to a function changes the
graph so this is really tremendous okay
this is tremendous technology if you are
studying mathematics this is
tremendous so UAM language is free just
down load it okay I recommend
it uh so but that's not what I want what
I want is the least anime because we
already have like one bunch of Graphics
okay so what we do is
just this animate okay shift
enter
fantastic can you see
that the generation of a hyperbola okay
the construction of
hyperbola so you can let's play it
backward and
forward
beautiful uh so I wrote this like 30
years ago okay when I was young 30 years
ago and the code is just here the code
is um you know this about 100 lines okay
this
um this is a body
okay okay what to do
next
uh what to do next
well I mean for me I just need to update
these
Graphics uh so I can export it to uh
this animation I can export it to an
animation so let's
try right
click convert two from canvas get
coordinates uh make graphics print code
Graphics save graphicss
as uh no I believe there is
a animation I forgot what what's a
command to create an animation so hold
on a second let's see
[Music]
uh
edit I forgot what's the command you
know how do you uh you so let's see okay
so go back talk show today's talk show
wam Language
tutorial go down you see number ping
list expression atom head just like lisp
variables how to how to declare
variables conditionals Loop and
iteration function pattern matching data
structure getting advanced advanced
symbol principles full form then there's
Graphics programming that's what we
want there it is at the bottom animation
okay okay so this uh section is still
working progress so here is how you do
animation but my question now is how do
you
save oh I
forgot uh so we already got the
animation here we just want to save it
what what is a
save export something okay get
coordinate make standard size save
Graphics as let's try that again
PDF HTML BMP EPS that's postcript
give okay I don't want to give I want
the movie format
okay wait
how I have notes somewhere but
uh but I forgot what is the um
okay let's finish that and that's it for
today okay I forgot what is the command
to export to animation let's see the
documentation so this anime okay that's
not what we
care okay manipulate
so this a bunch of animations and uh oh
moon
phase so let's shrink this a little bit
resize I forgot let's
say export and animation let's see
search importing exporting
video okay it's try
that okay so again you can import MP4
video you can import audio part of it
you can import
MP4 uh as a list of
images you can in import
MP4 as a uh a duration no you can like
import just the how long is the
video uh export okay so export there it
is export so export there it there it is
now I remember I have a notes about you
see so hold on a second let me show you
okay let's go back here and uh let's
save this to a variable
so x x x
animation
x movie equals to okay and
uh don't produce output shift enter
then now all you have to do is just say
this animate x
movie okay there you have the movie then
what we want to do now is to say
export okay export
then uh so export of that okay so but
first of all you need a name so what is
the name you want it to will
be X Test movie
okay
dot um let's
try give
first okay then this part will be
that okay do
it let's see how long it it shouldn't be
take to
long it's okay thank you
Thiago fantastic Thiago are you in
Brazil I forgot are you the guys in
Brazil it's done fantastic guys so let's
go to desktop I believe it's save in
desktop uh no wait what is
This Test movie where is it
saved uh documents
okay there it
is there it is okay now let's open the
gift let's see there it is fantastic can
you guys see
it
beautiful now the final size is eight
800 kilobytes okay now let's try it
again but now instead of gi gi is not
good okay let's try
MP4 shift
enter processing expression for video
export remaining time 20 seconds 19
seconds 16
seconds beautiful wo F language that's
why I'm telling you guys wam language is
magnitude
beyond anything you've seen hascal or
whatever closure hasal
rust okay it's done
refresh there it
is MP4 90 kilobytes open
it fantastic this is even more beautiful
okay can can you like uh
what
yeah oh stupid this VC player
stupid idiotic from the open source
Linux like every every time you like
after it plays it becomes this thing you
can just play uh click play again you
see the Linux
idiots and Unix idiots they are
incapable of creating any sort software
that involves a user
interface let me explain this one okay
because this is Extreme idiotic to the
extreme degree typical very typical
example of the Unix Linux situation
including the C idiots okay so you see
you got a movie right so if you play
this in let's say in Microsoft um you
know any player on the Mac go you know
let's say uh Windows Media Player okay I
don't like Windows Media Player but um
you know actually I don't you know I
don't want
to yeah I don't I don't even want to try
but anyway if you open in the VC you
know V vcl player which is the open
source Linux so you get that
but
once wait click finish you know like
once it finishes it becomes this index
page which video player does that you
know what incredible ID idiy
idiocy this brainless look you know you
play a video when it finish okay it for
some reason it's stops um but continue
oh it's the
end you know like you extremely idiotic
this is like the you you user interface
aspect of the Unix and Linux thing okay
but anyway our video are successful so
let's just copy it let's copy both of
them you can also try um you can also
try to export mov uh let's try okay
actually I want to see I did this
before I want to see which one produces
the maximum quality with the least file
size so now it's a do movie
file okay done so now refresh now we got
three files so so the mov is
actually okay 300 megabyte MP4 is the
best okay but anyway copy the file path
close close close close go to the
hyperbola Page open then go to the
construction Point Wise Construction
let's just paste them there okay now
make make it into a embedded
GIF uh make it a make you know so it's
so fast you don't know what's going on
so but let's change let's move the file
into the current directory okay so if
you show it in browser now go down go
down go down go down go down go down go
down go down down you see there we have
it so the first one is
um the first one is GIF okay now the
second one
is do move it won't play in the browser
so S6 doesn't play in Firefox the third
one is
MP4 click
Play Beautiful okay now let's show this
page in in in a Chrome browser okay
so but before we do that let's change
you know let's change the file path into
the current directory because this is my
website you know you don't want it to
link to the your document directory so I
have a easy command press press press
okay let's just say I okay done so it's
automatic press press press
I okay so press press press I
so they moved into the
current directory there so you see there
there there okay so the command I just
called is isar HTML move source file
path you know that's part of my own
command you can get it if you want to
you know pay me $30 $40 go to Kar emac
website search for Kar emac HTML mod you
know pay me PayPal me I'll send it to
you you know the uh so okay so we got so
wait what are we doing so you got you
got these files now show this file in a
Chrome browser you see right now here
it's
Firefox but let's show close that V VLC
idiotic let's go to the this is a brave
browser okay Brave browser so
press press press
press there it is in bra browser now go
down go down go down down down down down
down down down down down there it is
give okay this is the move file mov it
doesn't play okay so okay movie file is
not good MP3 is good
play that's that's it for today thank
you guys for
watching uh okay if you enjoy my stuff
just pay me okay just go to PayPal go to
go toad. info. info and
the.info the the the is the site is
called SAR code then SC all the way down
you got all these tutorials for
programming languages all the way down
just PayPal me okay PayPal Amazon gift
card
$100 bye
guys my VLC Player on Linux is normal I
think it's just uh Windows okay yeah
maybe you are right but
VLC I've been using VLC on Linux lots of
problems bye
guys so we talked for like yeah 5050
minutes that's good