good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show today is September
2nd Monday San Francisco time 1 o clock
p.m. okay hold on second again one
second
that is my surface book it is on and
it's actually repeating what I said so
you you know there is a the world record
of people who can speak the fastest you
know for example let's read out let's
see I I don't do well on that one of the
oldest known religious texts is cash
temple time by Asian summer a set of
inscribed clay tablets which scholars
typically date around 2600 BC you know
so if you go to YouTube you can watch
such for you know the words fastest
speaker that is amazing that's some kind
of you know we are things so many things
you know in a word you don't know well
and I don't know so today so we were
talking about FF c/e FF c is foreign
function interface I don't like that
because that is low level stuff you know
the only thing I know like when you code
in industry every language like Perl
Ruby Python PHP almost every language
you know you I you know I work in the
web industry right at least you know
company before every time there's a that
is a problem you know the you know like
if you learn Python you can code you
know things in Python but when you need
to connect to database usually you
cannot because you know so you need you
need this module that talks to database
and that is typically almost always
written in C or C++ so that is as far as
I know foreign function interface that's
essentially the almost the only use for
me of that foreign function interface
thing so I don't you know I that's not
my thing I don't like it at all but that
is very typical that that is typical of
the industrial coding that's
seneschal it's almost like necessary
thing it's it's like Linux drivers you
know you have to write drivers for Linux
to connect to your mouse and keyboard
and stuff so let me give you the
comments and let's see what is the topic
today ok so guys comment we got a lot of
people that's fantastic and let's begin
so sabatham say it's like using an
extremely optimized c library in your
project yes indeed that's what it is but
you see the thing is if your language is
good you don't need it I mean I mean
ideally you have a programming language
right every each person says oh my
language is the best Haskell people say
my language is the best Python say we
are computer science you know so well
then you need to connect to database
that's real wood then oh then then then
the Haskell say oh oh well well we we
need to use C or C++ so you see that's a
that's like a paradox you know that's
that's no good so you know what is good
goal and you know goal and I read
recently last month something like that
Rob Pike who was it was it Rob Pike or
some other goal and guy okay he said so
I I think it is Rob Pike oh yeah he he's
giving a talk on YouTube I don't
remember the title but anyway Rob Rob
Pike on : the Tarot is something like 10
you know 10 10 like those are kind of
things you know these UNIX people like
you say some something like Kane
principles of : ok you know it's like a
motor a jargon you know that kind of
thing you know 10 10 10 commandments of
goal and something like something like
that ok so Rob Pike is talking about
that on YouTube you can you can find it
it's pretty recent I think in the last
couple of years or something and he says
so : has foreign function interface you
know so if you need to talk to C or C I
think
see you can but he says he never use it
because what why because first of all go
line is designed go line is the low
level language you know designed to
compete you know it was originally
designed to replace zippers first so why
do you need you know to write something
in C first first you actually don't you
don't really need to unless you have
legacy code you know that's in C first
person a new talked you need to talk to
see purpose so you know that's kind of
my point of view so you know you feel
language is good you are not supposed to
need foreign function interface you you
see what you see what I mean so let's
see so Julia Bartholomew is in armored
with Julia
but Panther has not learned it yet I
guess Julia has foreign function
interface is for c4 transceivers purse
Python from the Judea website yeah you
know Julia so you know if your language
is fast as Julia claims to be what do
you need those well I mean there are
practical reasons because you know you
know you don't invent the language and
everything is new you know you have lots
of legacy code libraries you cannot
rewrite them because they are you know 1
million lines you just need to talk to
them things like that but but yeah but
it's not ideal thing it's the you know
if you are you know if you've for
example my followers and me mostly we
are you know a lot of us are interested
in elegance you know things like that
you know the best language you know one
generic language for all so you in that
regard you know ideally you don't need
you don't want not not not necessarily
need but you don't want this you know
the foreign function interface so are
there reasons that you don't agree
that you know what so what I mean the
question is why do you need foreign
function interface you know so say it
okay because that's something I don't
know I you know I don't that's you know
that's an area I never looked into
because I'm not really interested in
those you know I'm interested in
symbolic computing proof systems formal
languages you know proper coding stuff
like that and yeah so that's I'm you say
it's not yes you're doing my own thing
but maybe end of this year or beginning
of the next year we I will jump to Judea
that would be great and if you learn
Judea you can teach me okay you know I
always wanted you know I always wanted
to learn you know like once life is very
limited they are they are literally like
million things you can never learn but
you know as technology progresses and
they are so they are exponentially more
stuff for example the banks one good
example everyone knows is today's phone
end web phone and every year there's no
there's new frameworks you know entire
new frameworks or new protocols you have
to learn every year they changes like
today you learnt this for example
react.js fantastic everyone saying oh
react.js you know change is the future
then after two years oh we are chess is
deprecated yeah there is something new
that's what's happening in front-end so
exponential growth I mean that this is
real I mean this is you know we have
entered aih everything you know not just
programming but science is material
science you know chemistry physics see
they are growing exponentially
engineering and all that and and
technology after science technology you
know come with it you know then it so we
are this you know I think it's really
tremendous you know there's many great
opportunities unforeseen that you'd like
you don't know it like you don't know
what will happen in five years in five
you know the new generation they do have
some new AI you know new what happened
you know I pretty and this humanity
collapse you know otherwise it's gonna
happen you know you there'll be some
things you never know Engineering and
Technology so what was my point
so yeah so I was saying so exponential
growth in sciences and technology and
but there is something that so humans
humans we made a meat are not catching
up because we cannot because there are
million things going on in parallel and
they are growing exponentially in a
sense in many ways but humans you only
leave this a hundred years you know 80
years today and you don't you know what
after you pass 50 okay your brains cut
my brain is like it's not like when you
were younger
okay so that's a you know so so it's a
very limited you know you becomes very
limited so what do you need well
according to ellen musk his solution his
idea is that we are going to invent now
hold on a second let me copy the paste
here only thing okay so let me read the
comments so I can catch up so Ellen must
let me let me go back let me talk about
Ella Musk
let me save these text okay so so
today's talk
so Elemis his solution to AI is that you
know we are going to also progress on
the computer and machine interface so in
other words we could have some chips in
our brain and so that you know the AI
becomes so fantastic or amiko you know
and but but we have you know chips in
our brain that helps us so we can see
like super humans you know we can have
infrared vision wink we can we can have
you know echo you know echo
motion you know the sonic systems
whatever you know we can enhance
ourselves with you know in a sense we
became bog yeah cyborgs bog so that's
his that's what Ella musk want to do you
know that's his solution his answer to
whether AI is going to be to be a threat
to humanity you know so we you know put
chips on your brain but but that's far
in the future we don't know that's no no
that's science fiction so far so so so
right now we have the problem where each
of us only you can learn slowly you know
we actually learn things so slow you
know like you know you learn new
language you know yeah you know if you
are a hotshot you if you're a young guy
you know you think you know everything
then you see you know typically
programmers will say oh yeah you just
you you just learned Ruby Ruby on Rails
you know it takes a week programmers
like to say that you know over the face
oh oh oh just learn you know yeah you
know let me tell you pick up eMac B's
you know you learn two days you know in
my tutorial and you know you make this
but actually that's not that easy you
know practically speaking with respect
to reality that's not the case it takes
one month okay to actually learn a new
language to get a basic idea you know
how it works you know you can actually
code you learned you know one month to
begin with it takes actually you know
half a year at least half a year to
actually be comfortable and you know
doing big projects you know half a year
to a year actually yes that is true you
you then you know then some some hackers
would I say would like to say that it
takes ten years to learn a language
that's that's kind of seedy but really
but it does take you know half a year to
a year to to be comfortable in your
language you know to be your project so
you know and they are like one hunt went
when you language every half year now
you know
and you know like I talked about this
many times there's so many languages
functional otherwise they are not just
nish I mean many of these has you know
million followers million uses you know
you need by different companies so so
one problem today we have is that you
know the expansion exponential growth of
everything technology but we humans are
limited we cannot learn fast you know in
Japanese comics there is a very popular
toria okay dorri me doremi mom let me
show you the way me mom do you guys know
it if you know tablet okay but this is
this is a you but ubiquitous comics I
mean it's such it images no that's not
it
this this comics is as popular as Disney
you know Mickey Mouse in the West but in
Japan this is like everyone knows okay
so that that is not it but let me try to
find it let me type Chinese then because
I know the Chinese name
okay that that is the one this one this
cat okay
this cat is very popular Tora ammonia
let me take them in this is the name use
in China in Taiwan we have a different
name and let me show you what's the
English name the Raima yes thank you
then hey then I know you on Twitter so
three months so that's that's the thing
you can look up Wikipedia they give you
details about the character what the
what's the story and so on so in
Doraemon you know let me talk let me
tell you okay anyway so the story is
that this cat this is a cat he came from
outer universe God they he came from
outer universe okay it's a comedy kind
of cartoon okay so the the background
that this comedy this anime Magne is
kind of like same symptoms they portray
everyday life you know it's like
Simpsons okay but anyway this family you
they got this cat this cat is actually
an alien from other you know other
universe and this cat has same as it has
this magic pocket you know this pocket
so the story is that this family you
know you got a teenager you know
basically 13 the the the main character
is a teenager in a family and his
stories with his schoolmates his
neighbors you know bullies and bullies
don't you know so anyway he he got his
cat as his friend and you know and the
cat has this magic pocket and this and
often you know now and then the cat will
take out something magical you know to
help the protagonist to fight the
bullies or cheat in exams you know to
help the protagonist it's very funny
okay so one day he took out bread you
know
like toaster slice of bread you know
where you take the bread in any book you
know like calculus or trigonometry you
know any book you just put the bread on
the book and it'll make a copy on the
bread then you just eat it then you will
memorize that thing
yes so so this is a technique that that
that speeds up human learning g m'm Bao
Oh Kathy you know that Kathy thanks for
the paypal thank you
yeah so so wait so Kathy you did you
grew up in China quit like where are you
from City so anyway so so so I remember
that episode when you know I read it
when I was a like 10 10 years or
something like that in Taiwan that scene
18 1980 early 1980 80 or 1981 something
like that around there in Taiwan so you
got this spread you eat it and you
memorize sort of things on the bread you
know so so this is a one way to speed up
learning so and so ok back to the topic
topic the learning problem you know we
have you know technology grows and we
humans have this learning problem we
cannot keep up so besides you know a
chip in our brain or this magical bread
what we're gonna do not much you know
there are some there are some you know
technology does help us learning like
today for example YouTube or my channel
for example they are you know millions
of videos you can learn you can learn
artificial intelligence you can learn
neural networks you know you know I have
some meat for example there is this
channel that's great you know there
there are a lot of chant channels that's
great that teaches you physics or
sciences or chemistry and things like
that but anyway so that kind of helped
you know because you don't have to like
go to that library or you're a professor
but you can
just you know sit at home and read it
but that still slow and and and back to
the topic you know one thing I wanted to
say is that I always wanted to have
someone you know some of you guys oh you
know or any-any people that who are
expert in something then he can teach me
something like interacting like on video
like we can talk via video that's
technology that's helping helping us you
know iPhone or whatever so for example I
I know a Maxwell email is so that that
thing I know where I know JavaScript
well I can teach you so if you don't
know I can because in one hour I can
teach you whatever you learn in one
month
that's almost literally true you know
you spend one hour a day in one month
that's 30 hours but I if you talk to
someone you who is expert on that
subject one to one you literally learn
you know whatever he says in one hour
you know it's better than you learn it
yourself for thirty hours because why
because there's because for someone who
knows the subject he can he can guide
you you know direction like having a
parents you know your parents guide you
some top-level direction that eliminates
a huge amount of inefficiency because
otherwise you you are exploring and
probing you know you went this way oh
that's a dead end
oh that that doesn't work you know
things like that so you need if you have
an expert that teach you something
one-on-one on video that's tremendous
help you know like teacher usually you
go to a college that's you know
professor he doesn't care about you and
you and he's got hundred students you
know but professor is still very good
you know but but if you have one-on-one
with a so for example I wish you know
for example I want to learn proof
systems you know homotopy type theory
you know all these subjects there are
people of course you know they are they
are let's say at least you know ten
thousand people
mathematicians who are experts on the
subject wouldn't it be great you know if
I can have them just teach me how you
know dad I truly just I'll just pick up
you know the thing like eating a piece
of cake you know I'll just learn it in
one month I have like almost one year
learning experience of that subject when
you have someone teach you that and for
another example I don't know game
programming you know I always wanted to
get into game programming like but I
have no idea how you know there's so
many things to learn about game
programming first of all there's a
practical aspect for example I want to
start to write a game how do I begin you
know I just want to start to do that how
do I begin I need someone to teach me oh
you know Oh more more theoretical aspect
for example what what does skin
programming like what what 3d engines
okay how they how they walk I mean what
are the technical details like what what
level is the pipeline
you know how exactly they work and then
it comes down to the graphics GPU you
know how they hunt a Kinect how they
what languages you know what exactly you
know so there so they ask tremendous
things to learn in game programming for
example you can program me I know they
are game engines okay there are several
game engines some are open-source you
know like 20 years old game engine they
release it as open source help humanity
because they have no commercial value
anymore and yeah but how do I begin I
mean games game Jing as far as I know
it's extremely yeah ok 3d game engine is
a extremely complicated in diva it's
it's you know it's it's kind of you can
say it represents the technology of
humanity you know a piece of game engine
and also today you have physics engine
you know sometimes you can see on the on
YouTube they have physics engine either
2d or 3d for example in second life you
have
this what's called harvard physics
engine where you know you see 3d stuff
you can drop something box or a stone or
a pen for example you drop a pin and
you're just 4,000 pounds around you know
the simulate reality that's physics
engine so you got all these things but I
don't know nothing about them like how
do I begin to write - for example - for
example to write a game to use that you
know so does it involve
does it involve for example that FF FF
is I'd like that at all because game
programming is an entire different area
than say web programming I have some
experience in Second Life which is kind
of very silly but anyway it's entirely
entirely different like in web
programming you deal with tcp/ip you
deal with HTTP protocol then you deal
with JavaScript Tom you know dumb you
know all these things you and you deal
with database or no SQL database you
know that I know yeah that you know I've
been doing that you know since long ago
that I know but kimchi is not like that
it's not like that at all well you still
have databases and stuff but the you
know for example physics engine you know
in web programming you don't have you
don't deal with physics changing like
what the [ __ ] oh oh you know 3d
rendering engine so so in game engine
how do you how do you do that you know
how first of all how do you start to
read again talking to those engines so
how do you or how are those game engines
written like how did that that is really
complex how are those physics engine
written you know so so many things to
learn so back to the topic I was
thinking you know you'd be great if I
can have someone you guys know something
I don't know I'm sure you know so you
can teach me and I can teach you but you
know survived I kind of tried over the
years with the hacker type of people
like you guys okay like my friends on
the web you know I usually they don't
they don't get idea like like this
hacker types they don't like everytime I
you know like my friends I mean they're
my friends I talk to them they say oh
I'll just you know on Twitter I'll just
you know I'll teach you you know the for
example there's a Russian guy who knows
math okay he knows topology now I don't
know topology okay so I like to learn
I would like to have someone to teach me
they'll be fantastic so I say you know
let's scale on YouTube or you know face
to face they don't they don't want to
typically all all these nerds [ __ ]
nuts idiots they their idea is like like
oh I'll just write you an email and you
do this exercise for [ __ ] idiots
you know you if I want to learn topology
I can go with Wikipedia far more
efficient than whatever you tell me
textually like idiots okay the same
thing happens with programmers you know
my friends you know like every time I
bring this up they don't they don't they
don't get for some reason you know they
don't think that way they don't get idea
like they did they are just going to
insist like oh no I don't you know I
don't want first of all they don't want
to go on video they don't want to
anything they want an animal
another nimnim you know that's that's a
big thing among the hacker types they
don't want that although that's kind of
changing because YouTube now everyone is
on YouTube even all those hacker types
then they now start suit come on YouTube
anyway so they don't get the idea they
don't like then because then sometimes I
convinced you no come on do it because I
explain what what I just explained it's
really efficient you we have to do that
you know in order to do for this to no
need to happen they don't get it
did they just insist oh oh you know like
they live in this texture what they
think you know oh oh commodities you're
just gonna all read it you know they're
just gonna type something and they think
they conveyed everything so that's that
so that's that's about that topic
so let me write that down
today's topic so exponential exp Oh any
ntil growth okay and let's move this
somewhere here and smoothies exponential
growth human learning can catch up
whoops idea of one-to-one video learning
exchange okay and also we talked about
firing function interface okay so if you
have questions to me pause it now with
my name you know orange how I'm gonna
let first of all go over the questions
to me good morning iris Kashia eros
Katya wait we from what country and cool
for school says do you provide advance
notice in case of time change change no
that's a problem with me so no I don't
have a schedule but right now for
typically it's last week it's around
noon and this week it's around 1 o clock
p.m. and because my ski sleeping
schedule like psycho is over over the
page so so what what is our schedule for
let's say this week maybe 1 p.m. maybe
just let's just continue but because if
you know after a few days you'll
probably be 2 p.m. or something I don't
know actually
every time this this is a hard problem
for me but actually I've been thinking
the best time you know i when you post
on Twitter or social networks tip and
and there's a question like what
is the time that is the best globally
for example if you just consider locally
for example I mean San Francisco area
Bay Area you know in California USA so
the local time well the local time is
usually you know maybe in USA
maybe noon or afternoon that's that's
the best time because Americans habit
they use the internet most often noon
yeah that is true because I've looked
statistically America but if you are in
New York for example the best you know
New York New York is 3 hours faster so
the best time is still new but around
New York but however in China their
habit of using internet is that the the
most busy time when they go on to
internet to you know is at night is
basically something like 7 p.m. to 10
p.m. you know that's a China habit now
in Europe that's so different ok I've
looked in I've looked into so all these
different habits but but still you have
a global time right GMT so what what is
the time period where most people you
know you you pick a time period that
most people are on the internet you know
they want to look at watch your video
and stuff and that turns out ok here's a
summary
now this is a theory ok not theory but
this is the answer I looked for for
several years you know kind of casually
I looked it for several years the answer
is a simple way to put it is follow the
time of the New Yorkers follow New York
time so New York time from 8 o clock to
12 o clock that period is the most busy
New York time 8 o clock in the morning
to know ok especially 8 o clock
8 the 9 is necklace changeless ok that
period of time that v real time
maximizes the global audience so for
example New York time 8 o clock in the
morning
is California time six o clock in the
morning which you don't have that many
people because six o clock people are
still sleeping but but anyway we are
talking about globally so you know
better would be maybe 10 o clock new New
York time in the morning but anyway but
if you go by 10 o clock new New York
time then most people is too late in
China you know China has got a lot of
people so so the best time is actually
actually 8 o clock a.m. yeah so actually
I have a graph of that let me show you
that okay so let's go to JavaScript
let's see
internet ok internet usage so I have
this website this page copy the path go
to the browser new tab paste enter so
there it is global internet usage our
pattern now this is a you can see now
the light the light lights up red is
busy blue is is no busy ok now as time
goes by you can see how they change so
by studying this image you can you can
you know you can learn when is its
busiest for example you see now the
China right now China is all red
you know the USA is kind of sleeping the
China is all red so what time is that in
China right now so you can see this Sun
sunlight so that this is when basically
like 6:00 p.m. you know evening when Sun
is setting you can see so and and so you
can see China becomes busiest when Sun
is setting but now if you look at USA so
right now it's this is midnight
okay midnight something like that oh
wait that's a wait so here is midnight
midnight then you can see a Sun start to
rise the USA becomes red the USA becomes
the most red when it's new then it dies
off you see so that's the traffic usage
pattern global internet usage pattern
now this graph is actually from some
kind of hacker they probe they have the
botnet yeah
they have botnet that probe all Internet
devices it gives you some idea anyway so
that's that's how and this is all this
is like 2014 so that's and so I don't
have schedule now you know so this is a
one way to look at my schedule is just
always to go to my sorry
YouTube YouTube sorry usually I try to
schedule the next day so you go to my
channel you will see you know upcoming
upcoming stream oh then you click the
community I try to post my schedule
there this one is from last week so you
know maybe maybe check out there so cool
for school says okay if sorry changes
time to 6:00 6:00 a.m. Pacific hold on a
second so that's my roommate he he
cooked lunch for me so this proof who
for school says change if saw changed
the time to 6:00 a.m. Pacific it'll be 2
a.m. your time which means you might be
a walk missed the live session
iris Kashia Oh iris kasha is from spin
okay so let's see so New York time six o
clock what time is spin New York Times
6:00 a.m. that will be 3 o clock p.m.
right so in span so Aries Kashia
so in span when do people use Internet
answer that please
so let's see if we you know if we
according to these let's see Spain spins
around here
yeah see so yeah in afternoon Oh busy
busy busy
so four clock 3 o clock p.m. very busy
so you see so New York time always go by
New York time new yeah New York time 8 8
o clock a.m. is is Spain new New York
time 8 o clock a.m. this around is like
like 3 o clock p.m. spent something like
that and that's also when Spain is the
most busy am I correct
so okay let me catch up on that on the
comments all the comments addressed to
me so works folks sorry so so I have
been thinking of switching my time to
those hours but but that's it that's
just thoughts because my sleeping
schedule changes all that all the time
so Seema's says learning a programming
language is all about practice you need
to give the students a lot of
opportunity to practice yes
so SEMA says so you don't want to be
giving lessons you want to have specific
questions asked no I do I'd know well I
do want I do do some essence sometimes
yeah I do some I do two lessons then you
know you know like sometimes I focus on
teaching emag B's I did that a few times
in the past sometimes I focus on
teaching JavaScript oh yeah you know you
know the whole hour dedicated to or
sometimes leave coding in JavaScript or
other languages but again you know like
like I mentioned there's this thing with
YouTube because when you talk about
random things especially non-technical
then it becomes more popular than people
you know it's fun people get interested
but if you if I teach for example eMac
please please you know you don't was
depends sometimes sometimes you get out
people but sometimes not but anyway that
I also do that so the issue I have is
that is that I'm I'm I I do not have a
plan and I don't have schedule so
oftentimes the problem is actually
picking a topic you know so you know the
easy the most easy way for me to do
YouTube video is just like right now you
know I just I just wake up go to YouTube
I have a bunch of things you know people
can pick whatever I want to talk about
those are easy to talk about you know
those are easy like this internet thing
I can just talk you know pick up website
go to Wikipedia and talk about my
experiences that's easygoing you know no
no no no work for me but usually if you
focus on focus on a technique or topic
JavaScript technical details or eMac B's
that usually it's more pressure and
being fire less people watching because
that's because then you have to do it
correctly if you you know you have to
also you have to follow you know far
Oh ders you know from easy to difficult
then yeah there's usually those are much
more more work but I tend to go you know
I just I tend just to go informal you
know usually I do better that way
informal so so that's why I'm asking you
guys every time you know to give me a
topic you know if you have a question
like if you have a question about eMac
please even if it is technical very
technical I can answer it because I see
the question very specific I know the
answer I can tell I can start to talk
about it turn you know answer that
question fully that's why I that's why I
like to have questions you know because
otherwise if I just going to start to
teach eMac B's you know first of all
what what topic okay I already did
introduction to eMac this fee you know I
really did you know another thing with
YouTube is like when you do a video chat
it's ephemeral like whatever you do to
like what yesterday or past month it's
like history nobody watch them every day
is the first day it's like Twitter it's
like all this you know micro social
networks already door hacker news you
know you just focus on today whatever
great information people have done you
know great comments from you know expert
programmers greatest you know it's good
you know like people don't care that
that's a that's actually a problem you
know we have this situation because of
these companies they want busy websites
so the one way to get that is just focus
you know they want to make people to
post every day like new things today
what's going on Oh new library Oh new
JavaScript oh this is like a new Google
released new new version of a I you know
library [ __ ] so we get so the whole
entire population get into the situation
you just you know then click paid comes
into you know you just focus on whatever
is today's thing so for example eMac
this I did a talk few months ago you
know that's
feet very good you know reasonably you
know coverage of teaching you eMac this
and other things I've you know math and
you know I've you know I'm not great
teacher of math you know I need more
experience but anyway so you see the
problem with YouTube is that once you
know people don't look at all things
switched you know that that's actually
that's a that's a problem that's
actually a big social problem so you
know oh this rather what do you want
instead is something like Wikipedia the
format for example Wikipedia where you
focus on subject and whatever you wrote
in the past you know you accumulate into
a coherent permanent you know subject
matter that that that is good that and
that is also why Wikipedia is so
successful because you have you
categorize things into topic now this is
by the way this is very very different
from blogging I mean even if you are the
greatest plug that doesn't work because
when you plug you know you write you
know today's you have your how you feel
what you come into that doesn't work so
I also write blogs but I do try you know
at for example my Emacs my entire Emacs
this tutorial in the beginning it's all
blogs like today oh I learned the new
way to find out what's a character
Unicode you know something I posted you
know and that's no good because I have
for example you got if you go to my
Emacs blog they are archives for example
Emacs blog archive they go back to 2009
and that's not the beginning because
before 2009 it was on my sorry dolly oh
this is you know
because in 2009 I separated Emacs stuff
into a dedicated blog just for Emacs I
did that because I was trying to you
know the popularity is
you know the youth the Google ads you
know they say hey you know you want to
make money you know those [ __ ] so I did
that it's actually I would say it's not
something I want to do so anyway back in
2009 I separated Emax into it into its
blog then later on or at that time I
also separated you know you know put
different things in different blogs so I
have a web blog you know programming
blog I have you know the English
literature blog you know things like
that
that's not actually what I want to do I
want you know I my idea is that everyone
whatever you say it's you it's it's a
coherent you know we are human animals
humanity human animals you don't you
don't you don't pedal you don't separate
things just so that you know those
people who want Emax they only learn
about Emacs then those people who wants
to learn gold and a wet web dev they
only just you know learn goal and you
know what that what that does is that
it's good for you you make more money
you grow you make more money because you
you focus on teaching and things and
they they also like it because they just
want they just want to learn your Emacs
stuff they don't care about whatever
there's philosophy or whatever so and
that's good for Google you know Google
you know YouTube you know Google make
money and so on but that's not good for
the whole humanity as a whole because
what happens with this this being
happening you know that what happened is
that everyone becomes you know narrow
specialized you know liking what just
you know exactly what you like you you
you don't know how to cook you don't
know anything else you becomes this
dummy you becomes a peg in the social
machinery know that's what happens every
day including you know today is like
today's average people or including all
the educated college degree and
programmers including all programmers
you watch TV TV died instead now you
have social networks you have iPhone
you become addicted in many ways I think
it actually was you know before it's TV
controls your thought you know you use
sit down and just watch TV it controls
you your thought now internet social
network but now iPhone in your phone
whatever phone same thing you it's
actually I think it's I think in it may
be worse than TV the effect this was
then you got people for example this
block you know social net micro so
called micro blocks the Twitter Facebook
you just focus on today you know was
everything you said after one hour is
history nobody ever read it it's that
way because oh this company make money
more and more money that way they made
it that way they don't you know it's
never it's they never say oh we prefer
this way because we make money they
don't say it rather they just create
ways to make money more money and
therefore it becomes this way and
meanwhile what they say is oh we are
here to help humanity we have we are you
know pushing you know helped humanity
help the poor help women help society
help poverty [ __ ] they are scumbags you
know Facebook Twitter Google you know
and and also yeah back to what I was
saying every program including all the
open-source phonetics there actually
becomes you know their thought is kind
of like in in that direction of flow
although they may not agree here and
there oh they hate Twitter they hate
Facebook but in general their their
worldview is kind of like following
following those directions because
that's what they see every day you go to
Reddit you go to trader you go to
Facebook you Instagram whatever new you
know the the stripe the chat you know
whatever the inter telegram whatever
technology that's what you see every day
that's what you touch so your thought
your thought you know kind of just go
that way
you didn't you do you don't have new
thoughts you don't you don't you don't
see
you don't get it that is why so who I am
talking jokes is very very strange guy
you don't want quietly back off from
this guy and he is his coat is the worst
in the universe anyway so iris says you
are right about spam most busy time
completely matches your theory great
great to get confirmation
so CMOS ace know from before no phone
before I was me
III was meaning when you were talking
about getting tutoring from people on
the internet they offer you lessons but
it seems you want to be able to ask
expert questions oh oh I know what Oh
see I see what you mean oh yeah no I I
do want lessons actually I prefer
lessons for example if you know
something I mean okay also this this is
hard okay the question is I want to get
people so we can have one on one video
to tutorial where for example today I
teach you eMac this tomorrow you did you
know and and while I learn you every day
tomorrow you you teach me one hour about
something let's say game programming for
example and you know we do that you know
everyday
alternative you know this say phone for
week for one week or even a month you
know then we I can learn tremendously I
can you know in one month I out actually
know a lot of game for me so this this
is what I want this and this is not
happening
and also what one problem with this is
that besides getting programmer to agree
on this they don't get idea typically I
try to put this out they don't they
don't want to they don't get it they
don't you know they don't see this as a
good thing but the other problem is that
once you post this publicly there's a
issue like okay so suppose I want to
learn game programming they are a lot
game programmers okay out there but
usually they may not
to be able to teach like I mean this is
getting a bit you know touchy you know
because you don't want to say I don't
want to scream you know you have to know
okay you actually have to know you have
you have to I like to say okay you have
to have this says three years working
your company professionally doing kamdev
then I would say you know game
programming then you can teach me
but not everyone like this like that
because most my followers are tends to
be not mainstream okay they are not
mainstream so and it's very diverse you
know like me you know living with a
we're living with your mom okay so you
don't know what they can actually teach
you yeah I mean often my followers they
have weird ideas from 4chan from
underground you know they tell you oh
you need to do this you know this is the
new distributed thing that's not I want
you know for example for game
programming I want the mainstream that's
what I want
I don't want special new ideas
philosophy about them in programming
that's not want I want the mainstream
game programming you know if you walked
in you know you know company in game dev
for three years or two or just two years
you can teach me okay that's what I want
I don't want strange new philosophies
great open-source ideas that's not I
want for example that's the music so
there is also a shoe of conveying this
because if you say oh you have to have a
minimum of two years of something people
get turned off for the [ __ ] are you you
see that's a problem so you have that's
also that's a problem and this one
saying you know yeah and also you can't
have you know so it you see I don't you
know this is not about any anyone you
know if you worked if you worked in a
company you know professionally doing
game dev for two years then you can do
you know you can teach you will know a
lot info I don't know and you will be
fruitful let's say you know you teach me
they for one week that's that would be
tremendous tremendously helpful the
other that skim program programming for
example they are also people expert in
for example networking stuff I mean I
know I don't know that much about
networking networking is a thing bad for
example every time I let's go to sorry
max I don't want to go to excite you max
Krause wait we open close open open that
page internet gossip go to my home
directory sock code go to programming
blog go to tcp/ip okay I have a tutorial
actually on that HTTP protocol okay and
this VIP for beginners tcp/ip you have
the packets the swarm of packets like
every time I type something a million
swarm packets flows you know they go all
directions into the internet that's how
in the internet works you know every
time I read it you know you can you can
learn you know you can learn it and but
but but if you don't actually do this
everyday you forgot like you don't know
what's you don't really understand it
you need someone who is you know who is
a network programming who works on
networks in Internet infrastructure they
can teach you know I would be great if
they can you know if I know such a
person then they teach me on our day
they'll be fantastic you know all these
internet protocols
so that's network programming this game
programming game program is very big
there's many you know game engines and
there's also there's also small things
and you for example you write it writing
a 3d game that's different from writing
a smaller game you know two-dimensional
thing and lots of other topics in math
you know and other programming or Judea
you know Oh Haskell oh yeah a lot of you
I know it no has cow
it would be you know you you guys can
teach me about that so that's that's my
idea so I don't know I just saw if you
guys are interested you know we could do
that the other thing is you know maybe
you know if I talk to you guys sometimes
you don't get you don't connect like
some people I don't know for sure like I
don't understand what you're saying
you know sometimes that so you have to
know people kind of like like typically
like sometimes I need English is not my
native language although I've been
living in u.s. and I speak and you know
read well but I didn't grew up as a team
in US or you know in u.s. household so
often when you are you for example I go
out sometimes I meet people my friends
okay I go out Chad have a coffee they
say things I don't get you know I can
for example I can listen to the news CIN
I understand everything they say but
info in informal context sometimes they
say things quickly I don't get it like
sometimes we go to a restaurant they say
oh just you know do that this I say what
what do you mean what can you repeat
that that's kind of awkward because yeah
sometimes I get that because then they
have to slow down oh you know I mean you
know just get the hamburger and then I
say oh you know then if that happens a
few times it becomes so good because
they they after they know me they they
know that they have to when they say
informal things they have to kind of
slow down you know like especially this
happens like when you have a group of
people who are all Native Americans for
example white people then they did they
talk to each other that he they have a
jokes they they find it funny I am like
I don't get it I'm not I don't
understand
so Bethany says I fully agree with your
view our online magazines beginner
tutorials and click-click Bates
okay Sima says CMAs where you form I
forgot CMAs Similac says the news is
evil and it creates a socially
acceptable history of for people its
history on the news not new things to
know its history on the news not new
things to know okay bathroom you say is
also fully agree on the idea of human
being a certain type of holistic in its
own right
Simon Says Simon Says the big media
coves are the aliens here to steal all
of Earth water just in sky fee domani
says can we do math with Emacs cannot
homotopy type theory okay I don't know
nothing about that actually so that's
something I really want to learn
hopefully you next five years because
after five years I'll be 56 your brain
is going away you know from A to B type
theory so I don't I cannot teach that
what about math with Emacs actually
there's not much math within Emacs you
know if you do Emacs is just Emacs
if you do math they are actually you
know you will be hard-pressed to kind of
trying to connect them together you know
well you know Emacs you have kaak kaak
kaak mod calculator mod okay but that's
I mentioned that before that's actually
you know it's like absolute and the
deprecated it's out of the question it's
like you know some people if you are
Emacs Pam you will probably wonder why
why do you say that you know like you
find it strange but but that's that's
true I talked about this like a few days
ago
Emacs kaak kaak mod I would recommend
never use it
it's like it
it's obsolete for ten years better
immune says so Justin yeah so there's
nothing in max to do with math actually
I would say if you want to learn math
you know go into Julia actually if you
want to learn math I mean I I did I did
several videos on math okay you can just
search my website go to my youtube if
you want to get into math you you you
you one thing you can say is forget
about programming okay I mean that's
another typical thing programmers like
to think you know that's what you like
to think oh I like to learn math but I
would prefer to have something with it
related to programming so that I can
meanwhile you know I can you know
because I like programming I already
know a lot so I can you know do
programming and learn math well it's
kind of chewy enforce but if you know
let's let's pop the balloon let me pop
the balloon okay let me pop the bubble
if you really want to get into math stop
thinking about you know programming okay
like just learn math math programming in
general they are like two different
things although in some aspect you know
you can say Oh proof systems you know
they are they are related you know when
you get when you have AB well AB they
are related after you spend four years
every day studying math yes they are
related but otherwise you know don't get
into the fantasy that you will learn oh
if I just learn Haskell
I will learn a lot math to know Haskell
is nothing to do with math they also
have nothing or little you know you
could say nothing with computers
theoretical computer science you know
because when you go into competi
computer science you don't code okay you
don't code when you must you start to
write programs has cow that's not
theoretical computer science so if you
really want to understand theoretical
computer science automata stuff you know
that you
go into that you know as for example
news you know the news Donald knows that
the guy you guys like you know he's his
idol man hacker type of people
Guth said What did he say you know one
of those Maxim's the pi3 quote you know
those hacker types like to code all the
time
[ __ ] idiots so he made a quote something
like oh I just proved it but I didn't
write any code something like that yesin
you know you have to put it in a way
that tickles people's ideas anyone
remember that quote Ruth something like
you know something like I only proved it
but I didn't you know it's like there's
no code just something like that tor
that affect anyone let's see
check if I'm still alive I'm still alive
and I've been talking for over an hour
Guth quote I only proved something like
that I only proved it wikiquote okay top
25 quotes by goose you see this kind of
web site those are the money making web
site those are scam you know they are
typically created you know by
programmers by the way oh yeah by
programmers this you know by day they
are open-source fanatics they are all we
are helping fanatic humanity by night
they are creating you know they tell
nobody they create these old coats 25
top coats because those are things that
makes money people got you know and then
did you have this brainy quote then you
have this quote up net they are all by
programmers who else programmers create
websites these [ __ ]
yeah by by by by day they are helping
humanity open source we have you know
free software foundation by night they
are the scammers more where's whatever
you have it you know then there you have
you have this quote inspirational calm
you have this quote fancy calm you know
you go there there's 1 million ads
Google ads so good news so these are
things programmers like to quote like
beware books in above code I have only
proved it correct I not tried it this
one okay beware of the bugs in the above
code I've have only proved it correct
had not tried it exactly if you want to
learn computers like theoretical
computer science all those things to
enjoy machines you're not okay forget
about coding you are not coding you
rather want to focus on those okay okay
anything else okay I got no comments so
that means my talking is no good
something like that comments okay so
maybe that's it for today let's see what
comments I have before
so magnify the comments maximize and I
want to Magnus Magnum eyes a lot more so
let's see some fees you know you know I
know you know know you that's you know
that's the one that means from for
chance since ten years ago
know you you know that that actually
captures the captures the humanity
captures the human animals that this
generation the millennial generation you
know know you that captures the online
interaction because you see when we are
online we argue all the time you know on
Twitter on Facebook you know when we
argue on reddit and also improve in
cameras you know gamers gaming know you
that captures the essence of what we
want to say yeah the this generation
essentially because today's society
where everything is independent you know
you know you don't really care about all
the people you know online because today
to determine if tomorrow I'm going
doesn't matter to you actually you know
practically speaking doesn't really
matter to you you know ten thousand you
know youtubers are there and me in you
know same way if you guys disappeared
you know my followers you guys I know
you know some of you I know you somewhat
it doesn't matter to me because that's
that's that's reality because you know I
just noticed oh maybe maybe after two
months I noticed those you know bathroom
you you haven't being on my show for a
while but it doesn't do anything to me
that's modern society that's not my
fault that's not your fault that's
that's just what happens so online you
argue with people you don't really care
you don't care about nothing so when we
argue doesn't matter is political
parties or programming languages
ultimately ultimately what you really
want to say is know you you know it's
like that captures the essence whatever
you say no that's not true one way
whatever no you are
you know shooting in the back like no
you that that is that's that's where we
are that's what we are today
oh they submitted into usage yeah I
would so so who to blame I would blame I
would blame Google Twitter Facebook
these companies and it's not like they
they they plan to be this evil rather
it's you know the commercialization
drove them to become that way because
that way they make the most money and
this is the situation they created and
so they are they are to blame I also
blame the programmers and the people and
most mostly programmers because we
created them we created all this
including Stack Overflow [ __ ] Stack
Overflow you know we are we are helping
fluent humanity they they are the first
company that create the created the so
codes it's no it's the proper term for
this is called gaming system
gamification gamification you know like
the like buttons the badge when you are
on Stack Overflow
you answered 1000 questions you get a
badge you know brown you are a brown
middle east because you help the
humanity yeah you you you help the
humanity to you know the programmers to
go something then you got a bronze medal
the the silver medal things like that
Stack Overflow [ __ ] scum meanwhile
they are peddling you know they are
peddling to the open source group the
free software oh yeah well part of it
okay they are saying oh yeah we are
helping humanity or stuff is open source
and stuff like that you know but anyway
they are the first that creates the
gamification ok system meaning that you
create a website with other you know
points score that psychologically make
you want to come back you know addictive
in the sense psychologically make you
want to come back because once you
learned no points okay then you can
start to brag maybe you know some people
I know some of my friends are like
to have stun that and you know you want
one so you become for example Python you
answered ten thousand ten million
questions you become you know top Python
expert then you can sing your ex in your
resume you know Luke stock over overflow
I'm the top top ten Python answer
answers you know that is so that you put
on your resume you know that's part of
the way stack overflow girls skim a
vocation because without that it's it
becomes you know that that's very
significant
because with that they grows
tremendously without that they're not
really because you know so you use sex
psychology to prepare to benefit
yourself that's what it is a
gamification Stack Overflow then
everyone else picked it up you know good
intentions now Pope Pope granham so he
he has a vision he sees the future you
know there's tremendous you know
exponential growth so there's a
tremendous potential which is true
technology can help humanity you know we
need startups you know and he's helping
these nuts you guys okay all these nuts
you know trying to educate you how to
actually run a company social issues
which you don't know nothing about so
program but you know a stock over first
you know startups but what happens
actually you know over years he said
stock over I mean the Y Combinator
basically it's about making money
okay making money yeah because he if you
don't make money you don't your startup
dies you don't let you know you don't
have a company you die goodbye you don't
change society nothing you no money no
nothing okay money so you wanna go open
source that doesn't work ok nobody can
succeed you know except maybe open to
that's you know do open to we're going
to Red Hat the two companies all three
that's basically it and this day they
become evil also because they ingest
make no money they cannot survive then
they try to do or devious things we went
to for example for example they tried to
they try to have crowds but nobody buys
it then they okay after a year they are
now so we cannot cross car then you know
open to that that's you guys need
expense that you made it happen anyway
so open source
no money no you know not you can you
cannot grow and donation-based doesn't
work unless you'd go hardware like I am
going to create a new keyboard that you
know I'm you know you go to you know the
kick kick starters in others website you
do that hardware maybe you have some
benefit so anyway so the Y Combinator or
the startups
you know they what they want is money
but open-source okay they they all the
people know once you join the stop you
know once you actually instead of
sitting at your home and you know
armchair philosopher oh we want
open-source this necessary because this
and that but once you your life you live
the hood your family your children
depends on money that came from
open-source then everything becomes
reality then you you you you know what
what is true what is not true because
once you start oh you know is you start
a company then you know what what is
good what is bad
Boban sauce out of the door right away
then what do you do
crowds its to crowds because crowd is a
service the open source philosophy does
not you know go against nice that so
this do this go to crowd slack telegram
you know cow that's why everything's
crowd the [ __ ] the open source and free
software foundation [ __ ] okay maybe
that's that's it today so today I end up
you know banking again is open source
again then so I was saying you know as I
was saying the Y Combinator's you know
so all these top startups you know you
you can you can look at them up you can
try to stop you know
start your own company you know try to
try to spread the great idea of open
source in freeware start a company you
know try to it try to do it do you you
would know then you will see what is
true what is not true
so Seema says what makes a computer
language symbolic I did what whole
one-hour talk on that last week two
weeks ago not by now it's two weeks ago
I guess you know you go to you go to and
and that's one of my better videos I
would say okay you go to my videos there
is one 90 minutes talk on sing on what
does symbolic programming language means
so I don't know if you are there Seema's
slack so what makes a computer language
symbolic okay that question yeah so that
question I have 19 minutes talk on that
this one this one okay this one's a talk
show 2019 July 18th Lisp Mathematica tum
rewriting system and what does the
symbolic programming mean you know so
watch that so similar says if we go away
online relationships are very trans
transient what do you mean how many
relationships so anyway that's it for
today
kog'maw pronunciation [ __ ] mod
pronunciation calc calculus calculator
calc
I guess calc is a proper more proper way
of English pronunciation you need so
bathroom bathroom uses you need to
practice your English mod targeted at
success and more efficiently this way
will improve your quality of life
I will not sure about improving my
quality of my life but my youtube may be
a little bit just a little bit that's
that's an interesting topic about
English pronounced pronunciation and
yeah because worthy let's go to worthy
worthy English wor DUI English because I
have 1000 essays on that not 1000
exactly I have like 10 essays about that
let's see English accents very
interesting topics somewhat interesting
so I looked at civil you know certain
American accent new old New Orleans
Orleans New Orleans accent French
English French as their accent and also
Chinese and British accents you have
several British accents Canadian
Scottish Irish in Chinese accents so do
what do I does my English has a lot
Chinese accents I cannot tell but I
kinda have some idea but I guess but you
you guys can judge properly maybe yeah
so you can you can tell what how at what
level how much is my English good or bad
probably pretty bad
because processing of this natural
language will take less time and
computation power what do you mean what
are you talking about bathroom you so
about improving um you know I'm like I'm
too old
pretty much I'm you know 51 you know
what do what is what what let's see I
forgot how how do I normally say it what
what okay what okay so I can actually
try to be Chinese accent because because
I know because I can think about how
Chinese you know the syllabus what what
sounds are available in Chinese and I
can speak it that way well I cannot
really big well what is like yes so the
typical Chinese the Steve your typical
Chinese phonetic pronunciation would be
what what what what yeah something like
that so I guess I have you know I try to
get away because I try to I I really
tried when I was younger to have a like
English speaking English in a way that
is imposed indistinguishable from a
English native English speaker I really
try that because it really annoys me to
great degree that when when when when
people do not but when does the simple
idea where I have Chinese accent that
annoys me that that actually it's a big
problem for me I had that problem so I I
really tried to speak in English in a
later on I learned what what do you call
that is a which is American accent from
from somewhere in a somewhere in
Illinois okay they have a name for that
radio radio English or something does
anyone know remember like around you
know is region so they that's kind of a
standard American I mean broadcasting
kind of thing
you you want that so I tried to anyway
later on I later on I learned you know
so actually so you have New York
essence you have California then you
have the California Gurls
you know when you girls love a tea talk
stuff and then you have you have certain
you know American certain that's very
distinguishable and also you have black
people they their English is also quite
different okay they drop all the Earth's
us and sibilants you know as blacking
English is in many ways the black
English way of pronunciation is very
logical because they drop all those
ordered he well you know kind of
irrelevant
you know consonants or you know
decorative you know things like that
anyway but then I learned you know my
English is pretty bad I mean the the the
pronunciation died later on I you know
you don't know that because like there's
a psychology theory or principle they
say that usually you think you are good
at something but in reality you you are
pretty bad like with other people look
at you Outsiders they you are pretty bad
but you tends to think you are pretty
good so one other thing I guess that
happened to me is the pronunciation the
English speak English because I always
thought because I tried hard I always
thought I was pretty good so that's one
thing but another thing is that I
learned since I don't I started to do
video I learned that my talking you know
speech or articulation skills the you
know the quality is very bad not just in
pronunciation but in a way I like you
don't notice it yourself but I for
example I repeat you know you know a lot
of times and and usually I tends to
jumbo around you know you you don't make
cojiro
the expression the the best guy who is
doing that is Peter jordison okay that
guy he is the expert at articulation he
is capable to condense extreme extremely
complicated ideas and in into a few
sentence sentences with clarity but also
he's kind of extreme though for example
another scholar I admire which is
Camille Paglia if you watch Camille
Paglia you know as YouTube
she has an entirely different style than
children Pete Jordan Peterson okay
Camille of hack both of them they
express ideas they give you you know
they talk about some complex topics they
they they teach you some things very
well okay but however Jordan Peterson he
sometimes go overboard you know Jordan
Peterson style is very precise and you
know he can contains complex ideas you
know into sentences but when you listen
to Camille Paglia she's talking nonstop
all over the place like over the pace
like me but however however she does
communicate she does teach you
tremendous information like when she
talks it's like a machine gun and then
stop very fast and then stop oh yeah and
it's like a hot shock over the pace okay
almost you know incoherent but however
there's tremendous information he does
teach you things anyway that's a that's
about that's about accents articulation
speech kind of thing interesting things
and this also machine you know must
machine speech you know how you say that
for example Mac has it machine voice in
you know and anyway that's the
interesting interesting topic and today
you actually have on the
a real time machine translation such
that for example at if I speak in
Chinese it will translate in English in
real time with my voice my intonation
there's a video that Microsoft is trying
to demonstrate that
let's see somewhere here yeah real time
yeah here so Microsoft is trying to
demonstrate that and this is back in
2012 real time speech translation with
same voice English to Chinese by machine
oh yeah English to Chinese yeah so
that's one of the technology so you know
as far as speech accents this kind of
things cause there's a lot a I very
interesting topics anyway you need
linguistics and so on
and a human expression and how do you
anyway
okay so that's it for today great to see
you Cathy again okay I do have Chinese
accent okay yeah I try to improve that
but I think usually okay typically when
you are younger like before 16 if you
learn English before 16 then you'll be
good if you like like if you come to USA
at age 15 Oh before you you go to us you
know high schools you go up there then
it's good you you have good no act no
accent so so just you know kind of no
accent but let's say well I I didn't
start but after let's say 20 when you
are 20 if it becomes harder and harder I
guess you can still do some people have
they have talent for that like online on
YouTube you can go to see YouTube there
are some people who are you know just 16
or 19 you know young people who can
speak like 10 languages anyway there are
a lot videos on that kind of topic as
accents or you know speaking different
languages
okay thank you guys for coming that's it
for today I yeah my today is a great
talk
I mean in a sense that a lot topics
going on
oh 19 minutes my god 90 minutes