welcome to another episode of sun talk
show
so today we are going to do emaclis
coding
and
the first
30 minutes i'm going to do emac this
coding
so
then after that i'm going to give you
some updates
on what's going on with my
life my websites
um
wufang language stuff like keys news
some news about star flight keys my
package
and wufam language
my favorite language
okay i'm doing gums um
so the first 30 minutes or so i'm going
to do emac this coding so we are going
to write a command
that um delete emacs trash files for
example let's go to emacs init
so you can see this is my emacs init
directory so let me turn on the
highlight uh current line so you can see
where is my cursor so you see this this
is my emacs init directory and in your
emacs init directory you have several
trash files not trash files but emacs
state for example
uh you have the bookmarks file which is
important uh you know your bookmarks
then you have the emacs desktop file
this file records um
which buffers are open which files are
open and their cruiser position so that
when you restart emacs they will it will
open you know all your
uh open files in previous session and
also when you open a file
it will place the cursor on your last
cruiser position when you close the file
excuse me
so i'm chewing gum let me speed it up
so
you know then there's i do
you know i do is a mod um so it records
you know several information states of
your emacs
uh they are convenient um
features
and recent
f
which records
recently opened files
and you know so sometimes when you you
you want to remove all those files or
these trash files so i'm going to we are
going to write a command from scratch
that you can call the command
and also give it a key so you press a
few keys and it will delete certain you
know these trash files
so you know for
privacy purposes or whatever
and this is also great if you are
learning emaclis so you can write this
you know you can copy what i'm doing and
you can
so the command your command will delete
certain files
uh your whatever your files your um
files you want to delete now you just
you can do it just by pressing a key
so let's do that you know so i have been
sick in the past week
uh
code basically code uh it's not covet
it's so code so
yeah so i've been sick and uh we and i
haven't done a um
you know wufang language for a long time
so i want to also get back to wufang
language
you know i've updated you know i
recently i did a lot of things um
you know i have updated my wolfram
language tutorial from language basics
sufam language you know strings
list of functions how do you find the
documentation of a function
so all you have to do is just search for
example from language tutorials
excuse me
oh hi so
truly through on discord uh i believe i
talked to you on voice last time great
to see you great to see you
so wufang language is fantastic okay so
uh
i'm going to get back to working on that
and if you haven't already you know you
can download it for free i did like over
10 videos in the past you know in the
recent half a year and you know check
out you know great
language
uh
in my opinion you know the best language
the most high level by bio magnitude you
know programming language on earth
no nothing comes close not haskell not
closure not overland whatever you know
nothing comes close the highest level so
i did several videos uh in the past
about that so you uh go check them out
so let's begin today's uh main thing
yeah so i've been sick yeah i talked
about that yeah so movement language
okay so
um
yeah so let's do today
let's start to code emaclis okay if you
have questions comments post it okay i'd
love to see your questions and comments
and donate to me okay if you like my
stuff if you enjoy what i do
you know
buy me a drink you know five dollars or
whatever
paypal or patreon you know
you know where to find the my website
it's on my website
so okay so let's begin to do today's
thing um
so so emacs has all these you know
random files littered let's you know so
we are going to write a command to clean
them up to delete those files
uh there are a lot of design decisions
for example when you call the command
should it just delete it or should it
make a backup first
uh
well i don't know so let's you know
let's go through it and see so first of
all which command you want to
do so let's see
so in your emacs directory
um okay let's close this so in a pink
window is all my emacs command cores and
their keystroke you can see any any uh
anything i type you can see it's
reflected in a pink window so i press a
key
i press a key for example delete that
block and you can see
that command is that and the key is e
and i'm using a vora keyboard and i'm
using soft light keys
okay so it undo so
so now let's work on the emac this light
coding so
so first of all the first question is
what command do we want to do because
there are several let me let me see okay
so let's go to my emacs innate directory
uh and uh
uh what's your favorite font is that a
true question you know i did a lot video
on that
answer okay
if you are not a true answer i did a lot
of video on that
so emacs innate directory so let's see
first of all let's quickly decide which
command so
recent f okay
so let's see recent f
so there's recent f
and this i do uh yeah i do we need to
delete
i do okay so let's let's
okay let's start to do it uh
so let's copy the file path show the
pink window copy the file path paste it
here so i do last is one of the things
we want to delete
and
and places we can safely delete
two without thinking too much
and smacks items yeah we need to delete
that but we don't use that anymore since
emacs 28 in my last video i talked about
that
so
okay so let's let's just let's just
focus on these three okay
so i do last so let's first of all clean
clean up i do okay so i do
you know i do is a is a emax
feature where you
where it pops up you know when you
switch to buffer
you know it pops up the vertical choices
of a selection so it's a convenient
feature
okay that's not do i do because i need
to explain you know
for you emacs new emacs users you made
you know it's get gets complicated let's
let's do the places first okay so let me
show you what that is you go to
search for saudi emacs okay so you
search for saudi emacs there it is saudi
emacs tutorial then you go to the init
section emacs tutorial init so this is
all about how to customize emacs
so
uh you know what is init file uh how do
you make the standard copy cut paste and
do keys
uh font setup you know your question
which what's your favorite font there's
a link here that talks about my favorite
font
uh in fact you know i i did a youtube
video so watch those
so emacs init so one of them is
places okay you know you know emacs
command names is not intuitive like you
know for example let's open the file
places you know
what you know what what these places
what does it mean so
well it means that emacs record your
cruiser position right now you see you
see look at my cruiser position you see
its position there
now i close the buffer
and that we open it the cursor will be
in the same place for example i close it
you know press the key close now i want
to open last closed so i have a macro
open last closed you can see my cursor
is in the same place
but if you want to turn that off you
know we can turn that off so anyway that
that feature is that that command uh
what's the command it's called play it's
places okay so let's find it there okay
you see restore things restore open
files
save user position save command history
so one of them is save cruiser position
and this mod is called
save place okay so emacs name is not
intuitive it's it you know this this mod
is called save place it means save the
cruiser position okay
so and when you have this smart on it
will you know it will create this file
places
that records you know the cruiser
position you can see here is a file and
here that number is the cruiser position
you know basically the 2 264th
character essentially
so
so now
we want to write a command that delete
this file okay so
let's just start to write the command
okay so let's um
emac this okay
uh
you know so i'm using side html mod and
i'm also using emac this mod so for
example i type d
space it becomes different space it
becomes a template for defining a
function in emaclis you can see this is
my command e magnus
ximaxidsmart and xyhtml
mod
you know so if you like my stuff you can
buy them it's not free but it's open
source it's free software
okay so we are going to write a command
delete places so let's start to document
it um
delete the
uh how do you how do you say delete the
temp file not it's not the temp file
it's
um delete the
file for places okay what you know
uh we need to think of uh better writing
for the documentation you know so
so new users can understand exactly what
you mean so yeah let's do that so delete
the file so first of all what's the mod
name save places okay so this file is
called save phrases so in order to write
this documentation we actually need to
start to um
start to look into
emac lisp you know the emac system the
whole system so i'm you know so
meanwhile you are learning emacs this
coding but you are also learning you
know look at watch how i go about
finding information about things so save
places is the file okay so this is the
same places dot el okay that's a file in
the e-magnesis directory but but how do
you um
there it is okay so the mod is called
say place is smart okay
so here is the mod here's a
mod name this is the command you call
to turn this smart on or off okay now
once we got the command so this is the
first thing we need to know once we got
the command name you can call describe
function
then
type save save play smart and it will
show the documentation for the save play
smart then you can jump to the source
code you see save place dot e l so you
can open it you can see this is a source
code for save place you know so there's
a documentation near you know say play
smart
the neo means automatically save place
in each file meaning you know cruiser
position
this means when you visit the file visit
means open you know the e-max idiotic
non-intuitive names they refuse to
change
visit file means open the file okay
so places means who's the position so
this means when you open a file point
goes to the last place where it was
when you previously previously visited
the same file so what is a point point
is the cursor position okay that's the
emax jargon so point is cruiser position
visit file means open the file
and place means crucial position okay
that's uh you know so
you know you wonder why not many you
people use emacs because you know
the tech nerds say oh emacs is the best
thing but meanwhile there's lots of you
know
like learning and frustration this is
one good example
the emacs ground people they should okay
i read you know i
i you know try to you know try to
try to um tell people you know so we we
we we want intuitive names so that once
you have intuitive names people
understand that makes emacs easier to
use you know so
you know so for example change this you
know these
this incomprehensible jargons you know
emacs use these jargons because emacs is
the first almost the first text editor
okay 40 years ago so they
you know they're gonna say the emacs
defend you know the e-max phonetics will
say we are the first you know the you
know cruiser cruiser is not called
cruiser it should be called
point cut you know should be called keo
and paste should be called yank because
we begin you know yeah but things change
you know so
you know use the more intuitive
intuitive names that's better for the
emacs
for the future of emacs so
so anyway so so here is the miner mod
say places mod okay
so you
so what we do so let's close that so
this is the mod so first of all we need
to document um
document our function
and delete the file
used for
safe smart okay that's how that's that's
more um
that's kind of
understandable way of document take
document
documenting this function so now we need
to rename the function
let's name it
delete
[Music]
delete trash file so so how do you
trash file okay how do you you know you
have to name the function property
uh how do you call it should it call
trash file it's not exactly a trash file
it's not a temp file neither it's not a
cache file
so
uh so how do you properly call
this
name this function you can say state
file
delete state file for places and that
doesn't you know like what the is
state file so
okay let's just you know let's um think
about
about it later let's just use this name
delete file for places okay that's not a
very good name but let's do it for now
so delete the file used for say
placesmart okay
so uh version number and okay so now we
evaluate the buffer so you can see
we evaluated buffer and we now we can
call
uh we can call describe function
okay describe function and type start
delete file for places and now we can
you can see the documentation for our
function
ddf delete the file used for save play
smart now you can see that save play
smart is highlighted
it's linked why because we put this
markup you know this uh markup so now
you can actually jump to the file
uh wait yeah you can now you can jump to
the save place command
say play smart command then you can jump
to the
save place source code you know
anyway
let's focus let's get back to focus on
writing this function so dd delete the
file used for save place is smart
now
now we can actually start to delete file
okay so let's delete file
okay
and go back to where is the file located
let's go back to talk show
uh here
okay so
so there is the file path and that will
work okay
that will actually work
okay prettify the code
that will actually work okay evaluate
the buffer
now split the buffer now go to my
init file use my bookmark and
go jump to the diode the directory so
you can see here is my directory so here
is the places file we have that there
now let's i'm going to call the command
it should delete this file okay let's
let's call the command
so copy copy the file the command name
mentax
start delete file for places okay
do it
okay done
now go back to the diode buffer and
press
g for refresh okay
g
you see
that file is gone
so we
complete success fantastic fantastic we
you know we have finished one of our
tasks now but there's uh issues to fix
because you see right now we are hot we
have hard coded the file path that's no
good
because on your machine you are not
exhaust so it won't work so first thing
to fix is to change that to a
you know abbreviation you know that
tioda means the home directory so that
will work okay
but that's not all
because emacs init file
there are several locations depending on
the user depending on your machine
depending how your emacs in it is set up
so for example on windows
um
you know on windows your emacs
directory might be in app data you know
app data local or app data
you know app data local
emacs
or app data local roaming and you know
the in on windows
so
you need to change these hard-coded um
file path
so that it's flexible how do you do that
this this one
you see say place file is a variable
that variable the value of that variable
is the file path
where the save place you know stores the
data so you want to use that variable
okay so copy that get back to emax
so there is a variable now
we want to look at the documentation for
this variable so describe variable okay
describe variable
yes save place file okay so you can see
the documentation for the variable so
save place file is a variable defined in
say place dot e l okay its value is that
okay that's fantastic
so now all we have to do is just to uh
yeah so
so instead of you know delete file so
let's just copy that here
there so
there
so that's the that's the thing we want
we don't want this one anymore now
prettify the code
uh pretty fine okay
that should be it
okay now let's save the file
evaluate the code show the ping window
evaluate the buffer now emacs know the
updated version of this command now
let's go back to my init file again jump
to the directory
check for the places file no it's gone
so now we need to recreate the places
file okay that's how do you do that so
we can do that by
call say play smart let's turn it on and
off maybe it will create the places file
again okay so call it say play smart do
it
uh no match okay i got a space okay do
it now it's disabled you can see in the
mini buffer it says disabled okay
now let's
call it again
enable it okay mini buffer says save
place mod enabled okay now refresh
do diode
see places no
okay maybe we need to close some file
and reopen it so close this file reopen
it back to the diode buffer
refresh
uh do we have the places file place no
okay
okay so uh that's a bit confusing so you
see what we are trying to do now is to
get the save play smart to create its
you know the places file you know one
easy way is just quit emacs if we quit
emacs now and restart
he'll show up
yeah but i'm trying to work around you
know so you know i'm kind of trying to
show you
uh how to
go about look for information and stuff
so right now we can you know one easy
way is just quick emacs restart then
you'll see the places file
other way is to find out
if there's a command in the same place
mod that actually does the save for
example one easy thing we can do is just
try
to meta x
save place
you know there's probably a
command
uh save place
toggle save place globally okay wow
there's quite a few
okay i don't know where it is okay so
let's let's let's
describe function
say play smart
so we can wait uh
turn it on and describe function
say play smart okay now we look at the
documentation of say play smart and go
into the go into the file wait let's
read the documentation
true okay that's the emax jargon again
the neo means just true okay neo means
force
so the neo means automatically say place
in each file say the cursor position
inch file this means when you open a
file point uh you know blah blah blah
okay
this is a minor mod if called
interactively toggle the save place
smart mod
uh if the prefix argument is positive
yeah yeah yeah okay so
so how long have i been talking we've
been talking for 30 minutes let's um
let's get on to let's get on so let's go
into let's jump into the source code
okay jump into the source code expand
window
so first thing i do is uh
call the command list matching lines
okay and type defend
okay that will list all the function
definitions in this file so now we have
other functions
so say place to at least say place uh at
least two file okay that is probably
what
you know the command that actually saved
to the file this function say place a
list to file
okay let's open it let's jump to it
and now let's search the function name
to see where this function is called
okay search okay there it is say place
key or e-max hook
okay
yeah so you see
this function say place key or e-max
hook
is a hook
that is probably added to the e-max quit
hook so when emacs quit
this function is called and what does
this function do this function calls the
command say places 80s to file indeed
you know just as my
you know i'll guess
excuse me i got a code
so you see
so excuse me so emax so the way it works
the same place let's go to my init file
okay you need file i'll go to diet so
when does the save play smart save the
file well
it costs you know when you turn on the
save place
mod
basically it adds this function
say place key or emax hook
to
the
to the emax quit hook okay
and what this function so that means
when emacs quick quit this function will
be called and what this function do it
this function just called
say place eighties to file you save the
file and so we can call it ourself so we
can actually just
evaluate this code okay you see
you see we got a
we got the emac this code here we can
evaluate this code right away
and once we do you'll see a places file
in the in my emacs init directory so
let's do it okay now watch the pink
window you can see the command cool
do it
okay it doesn't well it yeah it did okay
so you see if our last sex
that means
symbolic expression okay so
that means we just code we just evaluate
this this function
and now in this direct buffer in my init
directory
now press g to refresh refresh there it
is
places you see the file reappears you
see fantastic
so now open it you can you can see this
is all my wow lots of places uh in this
section in this
emacs session you know
it restores all the places
okay so you know you see a large file
let's
now let's do a backup okay now i have a
personal command i just press a key it
does a backup on this file so that
command is make backup and save if you
search that command name on the web you
will find the code you can use it okay
so now we made the backup now let's call
our command again
uh let's call our command again to
uh let's go to the emac list okay where
is our emac disk
close that
uh
there so let's you know let's call our
command again
it should delete the places file okay so
delete this file okay so let's call
delete file for places okay do it
now go to diet
type g for refresh refresh fantastic
it's good
so our code is
success in final okay now
maybe some cleanup so we don't need this
part anymore
we don't need the let
so delete the led that's it simple
simple and functional now
pop it back to my html file so you can
see it's here you can see now show in
browser
there it is our code today and let's
syntax color it
you know so let's
my own command html file
html mod showing browser again you can
see now
today that's our fruit
for the past 30 minutes we did it
fantastic
thank you ben
holtzmann
for the money fantastic
fantastic i can buy a drink or a coffee
or something a burger
uh
so now
fantastic
okay so we did one of them now they are
you know safe places so that's
fairly
uh good you know this
complete yeah fairly complete you know
reasonable complete this is the final
version i i don't think there's anything
else to do so that's one thing done
okay that's one thing done now let's go
back to my emacs init directory okay so
you can see there are some others for
example this i do
you know we can write a command to clear
that i do so what does that do is that i
do is like you know it records
when you do switch to buffer command you
know when you code the command switch to
buffer let me show you where okay so
hold on a second
cancel
you see there's a command switch to
buffer very very commonly used command
so i do mod allows you to have a
kind of very convenient interface for
completion
so you know so that's i do mod you know
there are many varieties
uh for example helm you know some of you
use helm some of you use iv
iv something something this this is
quite a lot you know this in recently i
learned this there's a vertical
there's a
margin marching liner you know the new
generation
new generations of emac this coders
so anyway so i do is a building
uh e-max
mod minor mod that has this convenience
you know
so
so why is i do mod record
you know this file what what is this
files for so that when you switch to
buffer
it will remember
you know which buffer you know is
the most recent he used
you know it's very typical in emacs
where you have like a hundred buffers
open that's actually pretty common
you know
after you use emacs for a week you know
sometimes people don't quit emacs i quit
every day i quit every actually every
few hours because if you code emac this
often you want to restart because
you know well i'm not going to explain
but basically when you if you code a lot
emac this
you necessarily okay necessarily you
have to do a lot restart
so i restart my emacs almost
every day every day
you know at least once
but you know i've been using emacs for
20 years for some period for some years
you know early days you know from year
1999 i don't create emacs you know emacs
once open it lasts for days for weeks so
sometimes you have 100 you know
literally over 100 buffers open
so
so when you switch to when you call
switch to buffer you know the i do
feature allows you to it remembers which
buffer you use most often so the choices
shows up on top
you know
so that's why i do mod has this
file
now
i talked about last in my last video
emacs 28
has a new feature fido
so basically i do be became essentially
obsolete you know
basically you don't use i do anymore
emacs 28 is great you know lots of
features
uh i i like to mention especially one of
the feature is
compiled natively compiled emac list
code
that that is that is one of the great
feature
in the past 10 years because that means
now
when you write emacs list code
your code is as
efficient as if you write the same thing
in python or ruby or php or javascript
okay so emacs this now is comparable
uh to to these languages in in terms of
speed
okay native compilation
now that that works great if you are
using on linux but on windows um
it's more complex because
it's hard to compile
emac emacs on windows because you need
the gnu compiler the gnu c combine you
you you need those
and on windows it's usually hard to work
with gnu compilers
so anyway but anyway it's a great
feature okay so sooner or later it's
going to be popular on windows as well
because people you know have
uh
you know they they will provide
precompiled version for for you uh for
windows
so anyway so
emacs 28 is great native compilation of
emac this code so that means your code
your emac this code whatever you do you
know i've i've done a lot of video
of in in the past year you can watch
using emaclis to do text processing
that's the that's the best feature of
emac list
you go through a thousand few thousand
files you want to change something text
processing with e-mag lisp and e-magnets
is
more suitable than any other language
emac this is for text processing tasks
emac disk is more powerful
more powerful more flexible and easier
to use than ruby perl python php
javascript or golan trust me on that
okay
because i've i've done that for 10 years
writing text processing jobs using email
list
but however
there was a major flaw and that flaw is
it's like you know three times slower
than using any of the others
and uh but now that is fixed okay
now that so so so now emac this became
the best language
kind of by bio magnitude the best
language if you if your job is to do
small scale text processing you know
typically processing a few thousand
files ten thousand files no problem
but you if you are gonna text process a
medium files you know if you are at
google
then it's not probably it's you know
then you want gold and
gold golan c
c plus first or java you know
or or meta language you know or camel or
you know
but for a typical practical you know
programmers you know you or
as small companies
uh if you want to do text processing
processing images is truly the best
language why
the fundamental reason is because it
provides the
essentially a data structure called rope
or similar to rope okay basically
essentially what it means is that it
provides a data structure that allows
you to
have a glorified uh string which is
called buffer okay
meaning that you can
you know a buffer
data structure is just like a string
it's like an elaborate string you know
typically in other programming languages
you have the string data type right per
ruby python javascript in golan
java or even see you know you have a
string data structure and typically they
are immutable
and typically you know it's not
efficient when you want to edit modify
the stream because every time you change
the string you take a substring or you
do regular expression
to
you know capture or replace part of the
string
it has to create recreate yes to create
a new string from scratch
and that is very uh computational costly
you know so
but in e-max lips this you have this
kind of a glow of
uh
glorified strings data structure called
buffer okay now technically that's
called uh rope data type okay um
let me see if i can
find you show some wikipedia articles so
here's the rope data structure
now
emac
this is not using buffer it's not using
rope i believe i believe it's not but
it's using something similar
but but essentially the idea is that the
buffer data type allows you to have a
it's like a string but you can have a
cruiser position
you can
delete any part of it you can go to any
other part delete part of it or insert
you know
or go here insert something
so if you do this if you do this a lot
with a typical programming language
string
very
that's very inefficient okay you need
you need a
dedicated data structure for these and
that is in e-max that's e-max buffer so
that is why e-max buffer
you know that's the nature of emacs you
know
that's what emacs is designed for you
know the the
buffer so but with emac base you can
control it programmatically
so that is that's why emacs is a
kind of a magnitude
the most the best
language for text processing beyond
uh pearl python ruby javascript any of
the others or golan
why because it has the
uh the
the the data dedicated uh data structure
for
basically manipulating constantly
manipulating strings okay that's kind of
a large digression um
okay let's undo
yeah okay i don't want to screw up my
page
okay so
i think that's it for today so thank you
a lot for choo choo of lamio thank you
great
fantastic so this is a question
can you serve emac lisp via language
server protocol and emax in demon mod
uh what what do you mean okay so answer
my question okay you are you are still
here right so what do you mean so emacs
gets kind of slow if it is open for too
long i need to learn more garbage
collection techniques
okay so there are two questions one is
about e-max being slow when it's open
for too long
not really
i would say not
not really okay so emacs you can you
know
i wouldn't say so okay so you know you
can have emacs open for several days for
a week
it doesn't really get slow it doesn't
leak memory
um
you know
well arguably it gets slower but you
know so that's why i recommend you know
you know you just restart emacs every
every few days so every day
um that depends on your workflow you
know for you know for me these days i
restart emacs every every few hours
actually
so let's for example so let's see what
what what buffers i have opened so for
example i have um and i'm not going to
restart now so anyway
yeah i would recommend restart emacs and
and also re emacs that doesn't really
get slow
uh as opposed to
many other applications today for
example browser you know browser once
you use few days it really gets slow
because it's
it's actually is far more complex than
emacs
browser today
in terms of lines of code or in terms of
the technology the browser is a
magnitude more complex than entire emacs
these
entire emacs
so but so i would say emacs is not you
know
it doesn't have you know these
leak memory problems yeah there's
garbage collection but it's like
i wouldn't say it's a big deal okay so
that that's my uh answer for that as for
uh emac this
you know there's a emac this language
server protocol
okay that's uh let me answer about that
can i serve you at least two over this
two
years code um
uh
like i don't know what you mean so you
know let me so let me explain okay and
answer you know as i go
you know and and
you know
so so so you have the you know the
language server protocol the language
server protocol is something microsoft
invented it's a protocol it's a
communication protocol
um you know basically your standard
you know protocol meaning like a
standard format
that is used between applications for
example between the emacs
between emacs or any text editor and
some
programming language engine some
compiler for example for example if you
are coding c
or java
for example
so
you know or you know so on one side you
have the editor you know you have emacs
you have veeam you have vs code so we
can open this in vs code for example
open evs code
so let's open this page microsoft
showing vs code so any editor you know
any editor so you have the editor
then the editor editor you know editor
needs to do several things syntax
highlight highlighting for example in my
email xr html mod i can delete the whole
uh
um
group for example we i have a list here
you know
an ordered list i can select it you know
i can
press one key or select the whole
an older list
okay
now how does that do how how does it
how does it know where is the beginning
where's the end well
there are several methods
the way
a traditional emacs this you know emacs
mod do is that
for example let's show
so i press the key
okay
so that's a tab e is the key i press you
know in
in
html mod so the command is html select
element it will select
the previous group of element you know
for example if my cursor is here i press
the key it will select the entire
uh
unloaded list okay so that's a command
then you can jump to the source code
jump to it here is the source code
written in emac list
so you can see let's now go to diet you
can see here is my
you know html mark and here is the
source code so
this is written in emaclis so this emac
this code
it will it will try to find you know
where is the beginning with the end and
make a selection okay
so the editor
has all these tasks that helps you do
editing and including one of the tasks
is is syntax highlighting and another
task is common for example i can press a
key
you know
then i have html comment you know i can
press the key again it toggles the
comment okay for example the delete i
can select the whole comment you see
so how does the editor know where to add
a comment and what character to add well
in this case again it's emac list so we
again we can jump to the code you can
see that here's the code
you know that finds the beginning and
end and and finds
you know
so editor needs to do all sort of tasks
and traditionally the editor does the
job by in in the email case you use the
emac this programming language
in vi
you know you use whatever vi you know c
code basically they implemented you know
and in vs code traditionally you use the
javascript you know vs code is written
in javascript so you use the javascript
to find the location and you do the
thing
including
syntax color
now
about 10 years ago microsoft came up
with
the
language server protocol okay i have an
article on that okay
okay so if you search for xr emacs
search for that
you know so this is my essay language
server protocol kiosk emacs so
10 years ago well 2019 years ago 2006
2005 microsoft
invented the language server protocol
which is a communication protocol used
between
applications
essentially between the editor text
editor vi emacs vs code
visual studio code or whatever you know
the between text editor and the compiler
engine
so
when you when the text editor needs to
do something such as such as a
comment you know comment uncommon code
or syntax screen
the editor
uses the language server protocol it
basically sends a message
to the compiler engine in the case you
know for example i'm working on html so
it sends a
language server protocol message to
some sort of html parser for example it
can send to browser
then the browser gets a message and
reply
sends back to the emacs you know sends
back information to emacs
tells you tells emacs that where is the
beginning where's the end and you should
do you know what you should do to those
positions
that's the purpose of language server
protocol
so
so now the question is why do you need
it you know for example in emacs you
have emac this
why do you need
you know a language server protocol why
do you know why do you need to
now it's more complex because now you
need to use a protocol you need to talk
to some another application
you know in this case html parser or if
you are coding c you know you talk to
the c compiler you know air vm compiler
whatever tools you know the
what they call
these days you know the tooling you know
the tooling
so you use the language server protocol
to talk to dedicated
tools that understand the language
javascript compiler
then you know why do you need to do that
well the reason is that
for many languages for example emacs
for example javascript
javascript you know
or c or c plus first
or java
these languages
the task of passing the languages
today becomes extremely complex
so you can write for example in emac
list
you know for example i have a javascript
uh for example it's you know so you are
looking at such javascript mod okay
so
you know you are looking at javascript
javascript mod so i can
console.log
three plus four
i can evaluate it
i need to save the file so xx dot job
dot js okay i save the file i can run it
you can see the result is seven
so again how do i do that well
let me show you okay
so again i use emac this you know i have
lots of code you know 700 you know 2 000
you know 600
lines of code
to do all these things
but javascript is a you know javascript
or c or any language is fairly complex
these days so so my mod for example
doesn't do lots of things you know
for example variables for example
variables constant okay
let's say constant
v equals to three okay
now let's say i want to
print v
now you see i would like the v to be
highlighted i want all variables to be
highlighted but it's not
why
because in order to write
write that code to
to highlight all variables it's very
difficult you know you you need a
complete javascript parser
you cannot just do it with regular
expression you know in order to properly
highlight or or variables local
variables you need a complete javascript
engine
so that is why
the language server protocols comes in
because there are lots of javascript
dedicated javascript engines written by
you know professionals for 10 years you
know
so you use language server protocol
you know you send the message you know
emacs send the message to them they
reply tell you where are the positions
of the local variables then
your emacs can just highlight them
so in this way
the
task
of dealing with the language in a in the
editor is much simpler
you know you don't you know you
just send a message to the
data dedicated compilers or whatever to
do the job for you
so that's the that's the microsoft
invention language server protocol and
today
you have a lot of emac smart for
javascript for
for for java for c
that uses this so instead of you know
instead of using instead of
for example such javascript mod instead
of writing a
mod you know in emac this or whatever
language you know to do the very complex
you know for example you need to know or
the key word in the language for example
all these are keywords in javascript
it's not it's not it's not really
trivial you have to know that you know
you have to pass the language so now you
just use language server protocol you
know
so that this data dedicated compilers
can do it for you
so that's uh that's the job of language
server protocol so
so mike
i suppose your question is
why don't we use that um
so you know my opinion on this
is no good
uh
it's not a strong opinion i mean it's
very you know
language server protocol
is
extremely useful
and it is truly is actually the proper
way
to do things okay because
you know in editor you have lots of
languages java javascript c plus plus
you know terms of language is haskall
uh so on one hand you can write emac
this code to deal with them on the other
hand you can use dedicated tools you
know dedicated javascript compilers has
got compilers for them
then you use the language server
protocol to talk to them that is
actually the proper way you know proper
engineering
but
this is a there's a critical practical
flaw that is it kills emacs okay
that is my claim that you know that is
my claim it kills emacs
it kills immaculate
you know because after after 10 years
emac this is gonna
it's going to lose
its
major uh characteristic major advantage
the emac this is very powerful today
because because of the emac beast
because we can you know i can write all
these tools to do it
but now but emac this has kind of been
dying
a little you know
well in max 28 we have native comp
compilation with the emac beast so
that's fantastic
but i would push for
more improvement of emac lisp
you know i'm
i would not
you know i'm not too excited about
language server protocol because that
will kill emacs
so i would push for
more improvement of emac disk
and push for you know we have a lot you
know if you read my
uh article
i go into detail and i go into detail i
tell you there are a lot great emacs
compiler experts who are also emac these
experts at least several of them for
example mara jean
have a book
hoverback he is a javascript
expert okay he has written javascript
compilers
in macbeth or in javascript then we have
you know anyway these are people who are
compiler experts of various languages
christopher wellers is a great
deep imac this expert you know
the heart of emac this including c you
know c implementation of images in c so
he knows a lot
and he has has also written you know a
very deep code and uh
emax flightcheck author
uh luna rum you know he's also expert
and phil hagerberg
expert enclosure expert in
uh
in also uh what's the language
uh luna um
anyway so this and stephanie he's a
functional programming professor he's we
do research in functional programming
languages great guy
john wigley
is a c plus plus compiler expert for 10
years steve yag is also a language
researcher at
at google for 10 years he no longer
works at google and last magna
inga prince sen inga
and
okay i don't know how to pronounce this
guy's name you know
and eric lord ludhan he's uh famous for
c that he write javascript
java you know he's expert
you know all these are emac this expert
at least and compiler expert
expert of many different languages james
clark is the top most
expert in xml okay he wrote xml mod in
e-mac this that's better than any any
xml mod in the world
okay so
why am i mentioning these people because
these people
are great emac experts and great
compiler experts
they
they can write if you give them
if you improve emac lisp you know i
don't want i don't want i don't want
language server protocol crap you know i
don't want emacs starting to use
language server protocol and talk to
someone some other tools okay
let's improve emac disk okay let's do
this dmacc needs still needs a lot of
improvements let's improve emac this
and these people
including including me you know i can do
whatever i can
in some higher level kind of code
we we will improve we will make emacs we
will create
language tools emac list
possibly even better than the dedicated
compilers out there okay
now in some languages such as c plus
plus that's impractical because c plus
plus and c
these kind of languages they require you
know they have like 40 years of history
they require very very
complicated compiler optimal
optimizers and so on in passes
so in those languages is kind of
hopeless but still
my position you know i would recommend
i'm doing my talk show so
i'm going you know on a
i'm i'm telling you guys
let's focus on emac this okay
learn emac this like today we've done
and let's improve emacs this let's
put more focus on emac this
not
the language server protocol so i don't
i don't use it myself i never used it
myself
i prefer to
you know i prefer going in the emax
native way
okay that's my question that's my answer
i don't know if i answered your question
so your question about emac this so your
question is about
can you use language server protocol on
emaclis
uh
yes but in that case there's not much
for that because emac this the best tool
the tooling for emac this language
is emac list itself
so in the emac this case you don't you
don't even you don't you know you don't
use language server protocol because you
are
you are using emacs that's the best
tooling so in the imac this case you
don't use language server portal
so i hope i answered that question um
uh an e-max demon mod you know that's
another thing that's great you know um
i don't use myself because
um
e-max demon mod you know i can press a
key it will start another e-max for
example
uh did i do it all right let me show so
for example i press key
you know i'm starting another emacs
instance totally
unconnected
i press the key again
i have another emacs instance
so now i can change the background let's
say set background color okay
say brian background color uh
set background color okay let's say
10 okay
now this one
say background color
let's say
silver okay
uh let's say cone silk
okay so you can see i have now three
emax
instances instances independent of
independent of each other so in this way
i don't have to
wait for something that's stuck you know
for example in this buffer if i'm
learning something that's stuck for a
while isha or whatever you know eshel is
very fast
but anyway you know i can just run
something else over here you know i can
you know i can start to look at my talk
show page you know so that's
so i don't use steamer myself demon is
usually
if you want to emax to start up fast you
know i
you know i can start another emacs
instance you know two seconds three
seconds you know
so i don't i don't use demon so anyway i
hope that answered the question that's
it okay
so
thank you guys for watching so we talked
for 7 70 minutes that's it we we shut
down okay so let's let me close my
emacs instances
okay that's it
uh
so i'm shutting down
uh close that code set
so
e-max language protocol we talked about
that
so
yeah that's it thank you guys for
watching
so let's paste the link here
um
so today we wrote this code fantastic
because i delete file for places
uh who who is watching five people
bye guys
okay so i wanna talk random for for two
minutes or so so i i got sick last week
a code
um
what else
so class software keys is now in emacs i
mean it's in um
let's go to
emacs blog
so xonfly keys is now in gnu alpha
so if you don't know gnu alpha is in uh
el paso so it's
you can get it from
you know
airport is the
e-max repository
hosted by free software foundation
but it's not part of the officially gnu
you know
project
by the way ergo e-max mod is officially
in a gnu e-max gnu
part of the
gnu project
but
you know you know i had to sign paper
and nanganu alpha is
you know so it's e-max
it's free software foundation's
repository for emacs packages but they
are not officially part of the gnu
project
uh so it's like it's like male part okay
so it's like mel so anyway stuff like
keys is there
um
what else um
that's it i'm getting hungry so thank
you guys for watching
uh let's see what else thank you guys
for watching um
what other news um
yeah i'm getting tired so
yeah so next few days i'm gonna start to
do live stream more again
uh maybe every two or three days
and it's been a while we did wufang
language i'm going to do that again
thank you guys bye
oh yeah shut down so
in stream
i'm hungry so
yeah i'm gonna eat so
visual
vs code close
close vs go close