hello guys welcome everyone to another
episode of s talk show today I'm going
to code emac disp I'm going to show you
guys emac disp the best editor with the
embedded programming lisp the artificial
language fantastic let's
go so it's going to be 20 minutes okay
I'm going to try to be shorter and more
frequent okay my keyboard you should you
guys should watch yesterday's live
stream
introducing the SW board data hand yes
yesterday okay I'm not going to talk
about my keyboards today because I
talked about them all the
time so yesterday's live stream okay uh
the stupid YouTube warning the current
bit rate that's incorrect okay so anyway
let's stop that and uh so you can see my
screen yes so let's do today's talk show
so what we going to code we're going to
code emac LP okay so let me explain
write a Emax Lis command to break HTML
headers into sections okay for example
this article famous programmers with
repetitive strain injury you know they
typed especially using emac control meta
[ __ ] up their hands they become a
[ __ ] quite a few of them actually
Richard stowman the founder of free
software Foundation GPL G you know uh
his hand got [ __ ] up at some point
Jimmy zinski very badly damaged his hand
uh uh Ben Wing who who is the uh lead
developer for XX for like five or more
years he's he's the most severe case
you know he crippled he became a he
can't type anymore he he went into art
or whatever and gradually recovered but
all these are long time ago all these
are like 20 years ago in the 1990s okay
and John
ort the creator of TCL TK programming
language he also damaged his hand he's a
VI user though so it's not just for emac
Vi user you know you type type type Okay
so anyway I'm not going to talk about
keyboard because I talked about you know
in the past video so much so today what
we're going to do is that for example
this is one of my website page I want to
okay I want to for example this is a
page okay go back to emac go to the top
so you can see famous programmers with
repetitive stranger so I want to add a
section so let me explain what that
means okay so you see I add added this
this um this block so showing browser
you see that's that section means this
is like a a a section okay so for
example I can say something
something showing browser you see it's
nice to have a section you know normally
you don't have a section normally just
Hader you know H2 Richard strowman F
software Foundation founder then go down
then you have another H2 jimy
zinski okay so but it's nice to group
them you know the the history of HTML
changed in the past 30 years so this uh
change but anyway section is a new tag
okay so this section is actually a new
tag since about 2010 the so-called HTML
5 so section means so that you
can via syntax you can group a section
of the page together so for example
let's remove the something something
okay now the pink window shows all my
command Calles for example I just
removed that uh paragraph that's EXA
smart delete that's part of UHA flag
keys and part of kar HTML mod
so these are the packages I wrote so
showing browser again so you can let me
just just quickly show you okay if you
are here say hi and leave a message and
give me money donate okay I'm going to
answer your questions so post your
questions uh so so uh go to kali. infox
tutorial so you can
see uh SX packages so I have quite a
few okay so what what are we doing yeah
so section okay so this is HTML mod so
that you can you know for example delete
one key remove the whole section and uh
the pink window shows uh all the command
names usually if you just search them
you'll find it with the code okay so for
example so we have this section now
let's move this down down wait uh
wait actually delete the whole thing
okay now let's go here Richard storman
and go down go down go down go down go
down go down you see there and press the
key it adds a section can you see you
see now that command is HTML select
element and HTML insert date section so
it insert a section with the date now
showing browser
now it's nice you see so you can
visually see you know this part is a
section and then we need to do the same
thing for the jimy zinski section then
we need to do another one so it's
tedious I'm going to write command today
so I press a key it does it for the
whole page okay let's begin to do that
now the date I don't need so you see
here the DAT line remove it showing
browser Okay so and in fact since we are
going to write a command to do it we
need to test it so for now let's also
remove this section so you can see jump
to the end of section is this key you
see it jumps to the end of section jump
to the previous
section uh you know jump to the matching
TXS so all these are HTML mod you have
to pay you pay me I give it to you it's
open source
uh you know it's been free for like 10
15 years no nobody pays and I was dying
of
hunger okay so questions morning emac
considered physically
harmful yes that's true in fact out of
all computer software in human
history emac is the one that causes the
most repetitive strain
injury that is
true now well some people say well is
that you know that's you know where is a
proof there's no such proof okay but you
know if you really look into
that's uh that's pretty much
true I uh so Sero says I've also noticed
pain in my hands hands specifically my
thumb
yes uh and it says like bending them yes
now repetitive strange are different
from different people so it's kind of
very complex issue in fact medically
scientifically there's no clear
understanding why it happens you know
because I've read a lot you know in
actually I you know I know about
keyboard since 1990 since 1992 so I read
all you know like all the things anyway
scientifically they we don't really know
exactly what is the course you can go
read um Wikipedia for example we know
for sure it's repetitive stress you know
either repetitive strength or repetitive
stress that means you do something
repeatedly like keyboarding or sometimes
it's called Uh
professional uh eess there's a term it's
not professional eess but anyway like if
you do like some Factory workers they
repeat the action every day or dishwash
washers I I I was a dishwasher for a
couple of years that's very bad so you
know you are you know
anyway let's write the command okay so
now you see this section now let's go to
the end okay go to the beginning line 24
go to the end line 60 go to the
beginning go to the beginning and go to
the beginning uh wrong key go to the
beginning line 24 okay now I want to
delete this tag so press that key press
that key so they it deletes the both
beginning and end of tag and the command
is called HTML remove tag pair
fantastic so why do you want to add a
section so visually it makes it easier
to see you know like sections and
chapters the and and the way they they
added it's a syntactical bracket just
like lisp the language HTML is a fully
nested syntax uh yeah so it's just like
lisp so you can you can syntactically
manipulate
sections um for example for example this
H2 uh let's try to see then okay we are
digressing to so many different things
so for example this paragraph you have
parag graph then you have citation which
keyboard so let's see uh so that that
correspond to this part a citation which
keyboard 2007 by Michael Tian he is the
founder and the main coder of of of um
of sigwing Sig is the most popular
package for
uh for running Unix on
Windows today it becomes less popular
because you have so many virtual
machines or drop box is it called
Dropbox no drop not Dropbox but the uh
Docker Docker and you know virtual
machine
so it became less useful and also
Microsoft introduced the Linux in
Microsoft so you know but Sig wi back
then was the number one most
popular uh you know so so that's guy
that's that's this guy Michel ten tmn
okay so it's correspond to this part so
you can see this whole paragraph I can
press the key remove the whole paragraph
or I go here this citation I press the
key is simply remove that citation you
see as opposed to Mark and uh move move
you know
so this is the power of nested
syntax you don't have that if you code
Java C C++ C Pearl
python the power of nestate syntax okay
but it has flaws too because you because
too much nesting uh any anyway so okay
so we digressed so much we we did a pre
lude or for play of the introduction to
the code so let's start to code oh I
already did 14 minutes no let's code
fast okay let's code fast okay uh let's
do okay so let's actually I want to move
this out uh bracket and uh this are some
examples let's put the code at bottom
shall we uh okay uh not that okay uh em
this
okay show the pink window copy it out
okay and let's define define a function
and this will the what's the command
what do you want to name the command
naming of things one of the difficult
thing because English language and logic
you have to you know naming is critical
because naming is serves naming of
functions and variables they implicitly
serve as 90% of the
documentation I have article on that but
it's very uh crafty art okay so this
name will be
HTML we want to add sections Okay add
sections add section
tag okay let's just say that for now
okay I'm going to rename it later uh
because we doing live stream so we need
to be concerned about time we don't want
to think about this for 10 minutes and
everyone is like you know what what you
doing right right right okay so we got
the framework we got the template uh
this function so what how do you do it
okay so now comes to the hard part uh
this is s close it let's go back here so
now it comes to the hard part how do you
actually where do you insert the section
tag okay uh basically you insert let me
show you okay so let me kind of explain
uh and let's you know we do as we go
let's go back to code so every time you
see a H2 you want to add a let me uh
show you okay okay let me just do
it okay so you got the section you got a
section like that you want to add that
so every time you see H2 you want to
replace it by let me show you what you
want to replace it by you want to
replace it
by that okay
that's that's kind of the first step
then after you do that for the whole
page then you go to the first H to then
you add that then you go to the last
h2/ H2 then you add that okay
that's kind of a step okay so let me
actually write it
out so that uh when you write it out
when you write things out depending on
the person each one has different ways
to learn and think but for me and a lot
people a lot a lot people when you write
things out it gives you a
Clarity okay it gives you a CL logical
Clarity what what is the situation what
you need to do and things like that
okay so
H2 so for H
H2 begin at the top above for each
H2 replace it by
that then
go to the first H2
add
before okay
uh okay uh
before then then go to
the
last slash H2 then
add section after okay now pretty format
fantastic okay now we can now we got the
algorithm this is the algorithm
algorthm
uh did I spell it correctly
check no I spelled it wrong Alor
them oh no wait actually I spelled it
correctly I just got the period there
okay
algorithm okay so we got it algorithm so
now code code is the next serious step
once you have the algorithm in your head
you start to code code is the actual
craft because you you need to know the
language which you know okay so so easy
very easy go to CH go to CH move the
csor to both um to point meme emac
shotgun Point means the me Point MIM
stand for Point
minimum that means move the cser to the
beginning meaning of the buffer the
minimum position integer okay so go to
CH point mean point is a IMX jargon for
position of the cruiser okay they begin
with one so for example what is the what
what is the position of my CER position
you can do describe Char then you'll say
position 381 you see that means at this
point the position is 381 so this is how
you code Max every you know you have
curer position so go to the top then
search for word search for word for um
H2 okay and uh optional bound Neil no
errow no errow true if you cannot find
it don't don't you know stop the word
because some page don't have H2 okay so
you find it you search for what then if
you find it then you go to ch
let's just code this quickly go to CH uh
match beginning
position zero that means the whole that
means move the point move the cruiser to
what location to the match beginning
which is whenever you do a regular
expression search emx will populate some
data match data so the match beginning
means the the last match so so so it
takes argument zero means the whole
match one is the first capture you know
this is regular expression so anyway
basically you go to the beginning of the
front of H2 okay so you move the cursor
there then you insert very easy you
insert a what do you insert uh let's
let's check our
algorithm oh you can just replace match
okay so let's do replace match
then let's do replace match okay let's
not let's to replace this so let me show
you okay so basically so replace match
replace match new text yes the new text
is going to be something like
that okay so replace
match in this thing and optional fix
case yes literal uh F case t for True
literal t for True string it's not a
string we don't care you know okay just
that okay so remove that remove that
okay so
prettyy okay so you replace
match you find that then you replace by
that okay uh and you want to do
this repeatedly
because you know you found the H2 you do
the replacement you f found another H2
you want to do it repeatedly so now we
need a loop
okay so but but now our code is already
working so let let's show the whole code
it's already working so we can try it
you know so save it evaluate the buffer
now go to one of the example page for
example open it okay so now make a
backup okay now we can try our Command
what's the command name okay meta X I
add section tags do
it fantastic you can
see it added
that let's undo let's say our cursor is
here instead let's you know let's say
our cursor is here meta X do it you see
it goes there and
add perfect so far so good but our code
is actually wrong we don't want to add
this here wait how where do we want to
add it oh okay so our algorithm is wrong
so let's go back
to go back to the drawing board actually
we should
um yeah you should add that okay it
should add add that instead okay
so so uh section yeah so
yeah so let's see
H2 okay okay run it go back to the test
page the test page is uh Richard
strowman okay so go here now put Cruiser
somewhere anywhere may I X do
it did it work
yes you see but except that section tag
is wrong okay actually we already 25
minutes so we kind of been slow in the
coding progress but that's okay because
I talked a lot
smoothly now let me see if there's a
question
you mentioned in a earlier stream Jack
Smith says you mentioned in in a earlier
stream that you dislike IDE things which
I didn't quite understand it would be
cool it would be cool if you could do a
stream really deep diving on programming
environment okay so I mentioned I
dislike IDE themes what do you mean so
you need to clarify your question so let
me see let me read on and be diving on
your take on fonts themes really all
things regarding similar topic okay so I
guess your topic topic is regarding
themes color themes for
example we digressed but that's okay
because that's talk show you know I
noticed if I when I do live stream if I
just focus you know like very
technical good boy technical ex
exhibition tutorial on emac this few
people care but if I talk about lots of
things random traumatic things a lot
people more people watch okay so that's
kind of uh that's the situation you know
that's a human nature you know low level
drama stuff more popular uh okay so so
so let's let me answer your question
okay color
themes so color themes for example we
let's let me show you okay So Meta X
custom themes okay go there and you have
many choices so let's pick uh modus
vendi this one is created by uh how how
does he call
himself hi hi hi my name is
patu something something uh let's let's
look at his name not here okay so search
lookup web uh oh God what is this
underwar swing
wear so modus vendi actually means
something is a Latin phrase that means
mod of living way of life oh okay this
guy is a philosopher that's why he named
his stuff that but you know let's put
emx
there yeah
prilo
St hard to pronounce name but he says hi
my name is p something I forgot what is
the shortcut to his name but anyway this
guy kind of a philosopher kind of
guy uh oh Je mendous Page look at his
page
1,000 Pages what is this mod themes
accessible themes for Guru yeah anyway
he created this uh theme okay so press
the
button dark thing dark pretty good I
like it okay so I've been trying this at
night usually when lights the sense down
it became dark the nature dark and you
know like you cannot see your thing
there's no light outside so that's when
your wife is
sleeping that's when and the lights are
off that's when I use dark theme okay
so theme okay so you are talking about
the
theme themes are no good okay you know
before you were saying ID no you are not
talking about ID you are talking about
color
themes color themes themes is a thing is
a thing GUI thing it's a fad beginning
about 10 years ago okay you don't need
it well sometimes you know at night when
when the lights are off for example in
my room wife is sleeping she needs the
lights to be off so when the lights off
the screen is too bright you know you
know she doesn't you know you don't want
to disturb her so that's when I use the
Dark theme so let me show this again go
to the powers shell you see I wrote the
command
Taro do them hey see everything becomes
dog do magnify again go it again right
you see emac doesn't auto adjust but I
think there's some pack pack it doesn't
auto adjust according to your operating
systems
setting so anyway
so you're talking about this so you you
see Twitter Twitter disc Discord and
browser so you can toggle do theme again
do it why is it shrink back to the font
[ __ ] so anyway you you toggle so you see
the browser becomes stock the Discord
becomes stock and Twitter becomes stock
and YouTube also becomes
stock because in this each applications
they set their color theme you can
there's a preference you can set it to
use whatever your Operating System is
using you see fantastic and if youo doc
theme that's a Powershell script I wrote
you can go search it you'll find it and
you can use it otherwise if you are
prefer manual you just press windows I
to go
to you know your Windows settings and
personal
personification how do they call it
personifica
personal
personalization okay you see different
you know this is like related to the
naming of things you can call for
example emx it's called customize
things in Microsoft Microsoft Windows
Microsoft people they think it's better
personalization
click on that then colors you know
Windows is idiotic extreme since about
10 years ago extreme bad by the way
Linux is worse Linux is like two three
times worse than Windows when it comes
to usability
okay so anyway so you know so do theme
dark theme is not good it's it's it's
typically a fat the only use case of
Dark theme is at night when in your room
you have the lights off for various
reasons that's when Dark theme is good
or on the form if you have AED screen
where when the background is black it
doesn't use as much
battery but if you don't have this
specific or lead screen technology it
doesn't matter whether you have the
black uh background or white background
they use the same amount of
battery suck your juice out of your
phone but if you have the latest iPhone
then Dark theme saves the battery you
know some uh yeah so it depends on the
technology of your screen so anyway we
digress so much so your question is why
why is that I don't care about it
because it's it's it's insignificant
okay it's
not essential not essential you know the
Dark theme and the coloring is one of
the bik shade
issue um meaning that it's very popular
everyone it's a topic everyone talks
about because everyone can appreciate
like your skin color you know everyone
will talk about it and sex sex and skin
color men
women they talk about every day
forever same thing with the color theme
everyone understand you know oh yeah
what's your preference oh I prefer this
one no that one is not good I prefer
this one Tango do no that's idiotic it
must have this one oh actually what I do
is I combine them you know they talk
about it and font font font is the same
thing every program of you talk about
font of this font that
font insignificant
okay not
essential so what I prefer you asking my
opinion so my my preference is uh simple
okay I don't need I don't need to adjust
you know this this fun phas or whatever
or lature I I talk about F like in lots
of my videos you know that I've been
doing there are like
seven they are like a thousand videos
okay in the past so I rented about font
quite a lot of my videos so you can
watch them and in fact I talked
about uh I talked about dark themes
dedicated you know several of my talk
shows talked about dark themes so anyway
if you ask my
opinion I think it's no good and also
Dark theme some people will say dark
theme make your eye sooth is your eye
you know it's healthier if you use dark
thing
force force okay if you go by scientific
evidence the evidence points
to light theme white background is
better for your eye less tiring why
because that's natural when you go out
it's
sunlight that's bright theme White theme
It's Not Dark theme
at night there's no sunlight everything
is peach black there's no light light is
artificial stuff okay there's no lamp
flashlight whatever your phone glowy you
know you don't you don't you don't you
know in natural Naturally
Speaking we animals we don't see glories
like that's what Dark theme is you know
everything is black but they you see
light you know this glowy things glowing
you know this that's that's
unnatural okay so of the thousands of
millions of years of evolution we we are
survivors that's why we are here you
know other other din dinosaurs they
died okay
so our eyes is best fit for sunlight
okay white them not dark them but
occasional use you know I mean you know
if you have to turn off your light dark
dark them don't want to disturb people
that's why it can be useful okay that's
my opinion about
that uh do I make
sense okay so there's a lot of questions
uh but uh I think so we are already 37
minutes uh I need to finish our code
because it's not good to just hand it
there
so so here's our code yeah so
actually let me quickly see
some questions
okay how do you auto start esell in its
on window when emac is
opened and that's so simple you just
start start iSell you just all you have
to do is
um okay so let let's see so describe key
I press the key for esell so to launch
the esell the command is just esell the
name Esa so if you want to start esell
when emac begin you go to your emac init
file so let's say for example here my
personal init and you can just
put that okay so that does that answer
your
question programming guide hey Mr Lee
how do you auto start eell in its own
window when emac is open okay that's I
think that's it just put this line in
your emac in it that's that's
it how is the far board okay did you
watch my video yesterday I mean how do I
I just did it yesterday I just got
it so I mean you know anyway
um cous okay uh and theme your favorite
theme uh
supr is solar solarus let me tell you
about about
solarized okay that is the that is the
first [ __ ] that started the them fat
okay uh okay let me digress okay so let
me digress solarized I blame it on
solariz okay you
go oh not solarus okay
so um
okay there is is the article web design
great text on white backgrounds okay
let's let's go back to the White theme
because actually do theme you know
actually when you watch YouTube videos
you'll notice if you if the video
YouTube is using using Dark theme I mean
the actual video you know like I was a
moment ago it actually it's hard to see
you know because I try to use dark theme
every day uh for for about three months
or four you know I I you know I want to
check if it's actually good for you or
what not and it's it uh tires your eye
more so okay so look at you look at this
page web design great text on white
background this is a
phenomenon that began around 2010
all of a sudden you'll notice all these
websites they use a gray text on white
background why because they think it
looks pretty this you know this GUI
design you know U UI ux idiots these
designers you know since about 2010 a
lot of them women and Corporation and
Microsoft you know is is garbage okay so
anyway let me get to the point so they
started to have gray text on white
background why because it it looks Prett
pretty because from a design point of
view it seems you know it's pretty but
it [ __ ] up the web you know you can
read you can't you know for you know so
you know you see start required like the
contrast is too low and even this
virus hit even the scheme the racket
scheme lisp people look at their website
I don't know how it looks now but this
is this is 2016 you see this white thing
gray you can't
read okay it's a injury to the whole web
you see they use templates you know
these JavaScript Frameworks you know
they just have it
there but why does this spread because
this Guru you know this Guru they say
you know I'm a designer this this way is
best this [ __ ] and they and Hacker
News and they all trumpet you know
spread that you know
this okay and then you see this AR
Technica arch.com is a
classic website for nerds for
programmers very usually very technical
detailed they also got the virus you see
orange Young way can you read this
orange thing orange who the [ __ ]
possibly came up with this you see it's
a fat you know you have sometimes
Society you have some bad concept it
just spread and spread nobody actually
look into who who do who who which
people think this is a good thing orange
and
gray and there are worse situation you
see Google scum Google became extremely
evil beginning around
2012 okay it was do no evil after 2012
it's let's do evil and the most extreme
evil
Corporation Empire what's what you know
so Google you know Chrome web dev Chrome
Dev tools overview you see gray on
white I can't read it I'm old I'm
getting old so is this just for young
people you know and there's some extreme
so I can show you
progressively extreme
examples you know these
idiots and this one and and this look at
this one okay can you guys check can you
guys
verify you know but there are tons of it
on the web starting around you know
starting around uh 2010
before 2010 there's no search okay but
after 2010 well in general after
2010 American society became very
severely corrupted for many reasons but
let's not talk about politics because it
you know goes uh then Google is going to
censor me you know strike YouTube strike
and stuff anyway so so you can see
progressively bad look at this
one and this one is written this blog
this one is written by Joe
Armstrong he's a very smart guy he's the
creator of
the um of the Erland programming
language but even his blog you know has
this the most invisible
unreadable gray on Gray
[Laughter]
great text on great background you see
what is he thinking you know he died he
died about five years
ago Joel
Armstrong three years ago five sometimes
around there but anyway so why why does
he do that because I
mean a lot of people they don't even
though they are great uh programming
language creators but they don't
necessarily know HTML or css for example
Linus
tover he does he he don't understand
nothing about JavaScript okay nothing
HTML C he don't know nothing but he
knows the C programming language and
operating systems L lenus toward you
know you ask him about you ask him about
JavaScript you don't you don't know a
thing so when they need write to need to
write a blog they use the framework or
whatever blogger you you know or
WordPress so and they use template you
know is cool so you have this happening
and by the way I noticed later it
changed the color change they fixed it
so where all this began it began
originally uh one big
significant cause is the solarized color
theme okay so around 2010 you have this
guy created this website called
solarise the most Mo most [ __ ]
unreadable
[ __ ] he
claim science he claim science science
science say this color contrast this
color solarize this is the S science
reading [ __ ] okay this scums cing on
earth a lot of them on programming
industry you you know
agile and and intens of
it anyway I I don't know who is this guy
and I don't really can't blame him who
who is this guy solar
solarized uh I haven't looked into okay
but he you know he may not be a good guy
he's not you know he may not be a bad
guy uh he just so happens you know
anyway so this you know solariz began
this
more or less around 2010
solarise you know they they say you know
because science or you know c i c i e l
a b one of the color you know model
whatever lightess relationship then blah
blah and and that became a wild fire in
programming
industry then is you know then you know
they have reasons you know that why you
know why is this color should be this
way that way you know solarize you know
features selective contrast oh selective
contrast one two both sides of the force
oh both sides of the
force [ __ ]
scun okay that is my view I don't know
if you agree with
me okay or if you don't agree with me
that is my view it's like you know the
way I see it is like
patently false bad
thing are trumpeted as a good thing and
they
spread and
then so in 201 2013 I run into another
guy website who share my opinion
contrast Rebellion he created a website
dedicated to this issue tells people
stop using the way on white background
okay so anyway content you know you see
content is not the same content is not
illustration you know or these web
designers they want pretty you know this
great whatever the're
pretty content is not illustration okay
so this guy created this website to
promote you know promote
idea
okay and by now you know all these are
history you know this this website is
you know
2013 10 years ago like you guys don't
know you know it's like a it's you know
the information in history is like the
history of humanity where the newer
generation don't know whatever about the
old generation you know it's a cycle it
happen forever fact so I'm
old and you know the newer generation
knows you know they don't know history
history is such that if you don't if you
didn't live through
it you it's it's very hard to know
what's going on you know you can read
history books like we can read World War
II Oh World War II Germany this you know
or a thousand years ago China something
2,000 years ago Egypt something you know
you can Roman Empire you can read about
it but it's like fuzzy okay then they
there's debate what really you know but
basically you you don't
know but if you lived through it let's
say year 2000 when the do Com when the
website began to spread when internet
came up I was there so I remember it was
yesterday but if you were not born you
know let's say if you were born in
2001 you didn't see it of course younger
people so you you don't you cannot
possibly know even if you want to you
can try to read history of the you know
programing language history or whatever
but you don't you don't really get uh
it's hard to get the exact sense just
like when I was younger I tried to
understand lisp history you know in the
1980s
1970s you know you have list machines
you have you know uh operating systems
you know you have the PD PD
pdp1 you know I try to understand but I
can't it's very hard unless you actually
try to run emulation or something you
know I just read about oh this machine
but you I don't really actually know
about
it so anyway we digress so much and it's
52 minutes so uh and there's huge amount
of comments
now uh like it uh yeah so
so okay so what uh let's let's go back
to code maybe we can finish it quickly
let's see if I can do it in five minutes
okay so let's let me just do it finish
it the code we started and that shall be
it
today okay I've been sitting for too
long 1 hour I need to get up and walk
walk okay so let's fix
this uh let's cck quickly and
see yeah so it added uh this is wrong
actually undo showing browser yeah so
okay let me think
about so every time you find H2 you want
to replace it by that
that that and uh okay so actually I
don't want to I don't want to use
replace match
okay let me show you another way so so
first of all make make a uh
xp1 make
some local variables xp1 position one
position two
[Music]
so set XP position one equals to the
location of the m
beginning okay
the set it to the beginning of H2
okay uh then you want
to so I don't want to use replace match
I want to use insert because insert is
more
flexible so in so I can for example I
can say
here so you move there and oh you need
to do a loop right because we haven't do
a loop yet we only do okay so you need
to do a loop okay so let's do a loop so
in order to do Loop let me show you how
to do it okay so you basically have
these lines let's say okay so we do a
while loop
while okay
while search when you search something
when it's found it returns true so when
you so search
H2 okay so search H2 then then go to CH
match beginning okay then insert don't
do replace Del replace so
insert there okay
so in fact let's delete that delete that
delete that okay
so pretty F so why I'll search forward
H2 when you find it go to the go to the
beginning of H2 then insert the section
uh now what
else so you go here insert section
let's kind of do it okay so evaluate the
buffer show the pink window oh the the
window is no longer pink because we we
changed the background color so let's
make it Pink again so all you have to do
is set background
color uh
Pink okay different Hue of pink Okay so
okay here is our
code uh so okay run it now go to go to S
Talk Show go to the emac page the
repetitive stranger page now move the
CER anywhere now let's just call the
command
again uh that HTML add section tax okay
do
it okay we go we went into to a infinite
Loop oh
yeah we went into a infinite Loop
undo oh good we have undo okay we need
to fix our code we got into a infinite
Loop yeah so once you insert you need to
actually
um yeah you need
to go to next you know go back to the
here so actually you can instead of
search again more efficiently is go to
CH match
beginning uh actually match end that
okay predy with the code run it go back
to this page Cod the command do
it okay the infinite loop again you need
to fix the
code wa
my
uh while search for word go
to CH insert and
uh why is it not work I'm not sure but
one easy way to make it work is search
is that you just say search forward
again
okay I don't know why is this go to
chart not work okay we need to just get
on keep going so not worry too much so
anyway so go back to this page now move
put the CER anywhere Cod the command do
it there it is so you have the section
added then next oh that's
it
wait uh
what section oh yeah so you see we added
so a lot quite a few sections so this is
the first one then you see every every
hed2 we added that every H2 you
see now now if you show in
browser it kind of worked but but your
HTML is not valid because you see it
kind of worked so we added this you know
visual uh distinction a box for each
section but it's it's invalid HTML
because if you go to the first
section uh
wait okay go to the top search for
Section you see if you go to the first
section there is no beginning
section so uh so what you do you what
you need to do is you need to for
example to fix this you need
to um
you need to add that then you need to go
to the bottom and you need to add a
closing section okay okay we can do that
but that's that's that's it for the
video I mean we I'm going to do it
offline the basic idea I mean you get
the basic idea of how to how to code
this it's all here that's all you need
okay and uh let me show you a extra
command so for example in s HTML mod I
can call a command that will validate
the whole page for example the command
is this you see it will check the
matching you know whether it will
validate the HTML tags so if you have a
missing closing tag or missing open tag
or miss or miss you know misordered
it'll tell you so we got error closeing
tag you see let's go to the
arrow uh Arrow closing tag section at
position 796 to a06 does not match last
open tag main you see so we can go to
the position
796 okay copy and uh go to
CH go to ch
796 you'll see it it goes there so it's
saying that this tag is not matching the
last open tag meain you know so this is
um this is part of kar HTML mod actually
one of the best feature let me tell you
what is a
command uh the command okay I called it
by a key so it doesn't show but let me
show you this describe key press press
press so this is command is called HTML
validate XML
buer you know and you can you and the
command is available you can validate
the
entire
directory of 8,000
files okay so that's part of thear HTML
mod so if you like it buy it okay pay me
uh donate so for example let me show you
uh HTML mod there it is actually it's uh
so let me delete the backup okay so it's
S one file two file three
file HTML browser HTML engine HTML mod
three files and uh if you open HTML mod
go to the bottom 5,000 lines actually so
this is actually the most complex
uh package one of my package and you go
here you can show in
browser HTML mod and uh some positive
comment by other people so if you want
it you know donate to me 32 bucks I send
it to
you and featur so one of the best
feature is validate 1,000 or 10 5,000
HTML files I call it every
week since since because I write HTML
manually am I is my stream still doing
good yes okay that's about it for today
so let me read the questions and that
will be it
so how about Rob Pik that programs
without syntax highlighting yeah it's
very interesting I think syntax
highlighting you know syntax
highlighting is a thing before the color
themes so
the you know the the
the
the the coloring of user interface
design in
particular gray on you know gray on
white it began by this solarized kind of
thing who is this guy I haven't looked
into who is this solarized guy what's
his
name okay interesting I did mention I
should look into I should look into
what's his background I mean why is he
creating this it's very damaging you
know he did huge damage so I want to
look into what's his background what
what is his you know
motivation is he a good person or did is
he just like trying to sell something
yeah I don't
know uh interesting I didn't look into
anyway so solarise began around
2010 then uh around 2000 was it 2016 or
2017 you started to have dark theme you
know I think it was first it was first
in Microsoft Windows I believe but Apple
made it popular Dark theme okay by the
way on Apple it's well designed on Apple
everything is just good even Dark theme
on Apple you can turn at night you can
turn you know the another thing about
related to Dark theme
is is the
night light you know on Windows they
call it night light so for example I
turn it on so you see your screen
becomes
this um mild and uh warm warm
color techn technically what happens is
that they turn off the blue color in
your screen so at night it's very
soothing so if you don't want the Dark
theme alternative is that you use the
night light
uh feature okay I have it
on so you you know I so I think this is
better than a dark theme okay at night
if you know you can but window sucks you
know some like I have it on sometimes it
fails fails to turn on when the when the
time when it you know when I set the
time it doesn't turn
on then if you if you go to the uh
window setting then it suddenly turns on
it's like you have to remind windows
turn the [ __ ] thing on on Apple it's
all automatic you know you can set it so
that Sunset you know you'll turn on so
on Apple you can choose Dark theme
versus White theme that's one thing or
you can have the night light so you know
e you and you or you can have them both
so on Apple it's very well designed it's
you know it's just good on window it
sucks so between these two what I can
recommend I I believe the NightLight is
actually good dark them you know so
anyway so before so solarus this gray on
white they it began in 2010 okay now the
syntax
coloring began around
um 19 1990
[Music]
1995 sometimes in the 1990s okay so back
then back then when the syntax
coloring
began okay which is great okay so um let
me let me let me turn turn off
the doc turn off the NightLight so when
the syntax coloring began around 1995 or
I for I I don't know what I forgot I
have to look up I have I have a you know
I have an article on that you know in
fact I have so many articles so you just
look at
um where is the search
page search for XX okay that's
history
uh so XX so I tell you my experience of
xax
so yeah around 199 8
um emac doesn't support syntax coloring
you know 1998 emac doesn't have syntax
coloring imagine
that then sometimes after that emac
around 200 3 2005 emac has syntax cing
but by default it's off okay I'm telling
you guys some history like because you
you know you weren't born there you
don't know so em ma is lagging behind
very ma much compared to XX okay XX is a
entire history by itself so but you get
the sense that back then the emac they
don't have syntax ear then once after
five years delay when everyone else have
it you know Microsoft editors or
whatever emac added syntax cing but they
by default it's off it's typical with
the emx people because they believe you
know they they are you know in other
words they are kind of conservative so
they don't you
know uh anyway so but back in the 1990s
syntax coloring is one of the debate
it's like the bike bike shade problem
everyone will talk about it some will
say it's not good it's not good some
will say uh it's good you know the the
older people will generally think oh
that's Young people's idiots you know
you don't you know focus on code you
don't need syntax coling you know
because partly because
habit but eventually syntax coloring
won't of course like and I but so is it
really good that mean so what about
science what about you know you know
science is kind of a dirty world today
because a lot of abuse by the American
deep State you know because Co this is
science or global warming or
whatever but anyway so what what is the
real uh answer is syntax coling does it
actually help programmers okay that's a
question and the answer to that is yes
absolutely you don't you don't need to
like do research you know it's
absolutely syntax because by a glance
you can tell by color because our eyes
can see color so so we we can quickly
see where is where is what so syntax
coloring absolutely help okay but what
about the old people ra Pike or other
they who
insist let's turn off syntaxing okay
let's just see okay they insist your
code let's go to uh you know let's go to
saf Keys okay you see so you got syntax
cling you know comment and stuff let's
go down okay code you
know so let's turn
off you know some people very rare today
they think this is better no it's not
better it's just their habit yeah they
are great programmers but you
know okay enough for today is it enough
enough okay I'm not going to answer so
many other questions but that's it for
today
oh programming gu says dude I've been
online since before there was www
fantastic you know on you know on live
stream I have no idea who you guys are
you know the background varies uh
extremely Douglas Corf for uh so what
you guys are saying but that's it for
today thank you guys for
watching don't forget to donate okay put
money in my pocket
okay programming guy is old guy I
started on green screens and
monochrom okay great
uh ask
techn okay
uh so good
CS him in douglas douglas cord he
doesn't use color oh I didn't know but
Doug both of them Rob Pike the creator
of gold land and many others and he also
created
utf8 he also did a lot things on Unix
you know and uh and what's the uh
operating system you know he created
he's a great he's one of the greatest
programmer in human history okay
raeg top top one 100 probably or top 200
you know in human history that's that's
my judgment Rik he's one of I respect he
raike Douglas Crawford is also one of
the greatest okay don't listen to the
zumas like today whatever popular you
know the JavaScript popular you know
idiots [ __ ] extreme they very popular
like you know they created you know lots
of you know anyway these two people I
highly respect Douglas cord he's a
Douglas now Rik is they have different
uh nature of course the different
personality Douglas cord is more of a
programming language design
guy actually raw pack is kind of too but
raw pag is more of
a a unique C lowlevel kind of guy but he
also he his scand is one of the greatest
language in my opinion go l in fact it's
because of go language that changed my
opinion about the guy Goan is one of the
best language okay now those of you
going to say rust what about
rust shut the [ __ ] up rust is
[ __ ] now Douglas Crawford is one of also
one of the great greatest programmer
he's Focus he's a creator of Jason of
course and he's
also he he he basically
single-handedly made JavaScript
respectable in the year 2000s okay
because of his book JavaScript the good
parts okay he made JavaScript
respectable and he popularized
functional programming which is in
JavaScript inherent
inherently as opposed to python the
Kido van Ros idiot okay so I respect
raik very much I respect Douglas
Crawford their intellectual press their
ability to code and what they have
actually done their accomplishment these
two I highly
respect G van Rosen no the python guy
okay so uh
next uh
license B Bley mono coded font uh I
don't know what is
that by bye guys thank
you font lock mod I haven't thought you
know I haven't thought of the issue of
no syntax coloring it's forgotten you
know 20 years ago some you guys
mentioned it without syntax coloring
that would be
interesting okay HTML mod close Okay bye