everyone welcome to another episode of
sound talk show today we are going to
code iMac lisp uh iMac this coding and
maybe random something okay if you came
here for the girl that's generated by
artificial intelligence fantastic few
days ago we talked about artificial
intelligence generating images so I'm
not that girl and we are just going to
do emac dis coding so programming so uh
okay so emac L coding so let's um Shall
We Begin so my keyboard
gl8 Ultima hacking keyboard newly ATT
trackable and this fantastic device this
we I have a review for each one of them
this one is swbo SV l b o d so very
fantastic interesting input devices and
keyboard you can check my YouTube and
you can see uh what watch their reviews
if you are watching online say hi hello
stay flat if you are watching offline uh
play at 1.5 speed and Skip around
because I ramble a lot okay IMA G coding
so what is the task we're going to do so
let's begin yeah let's
begin okay remember I ramble a lot so
skip around 1.5 speed so we are going to
code emac this this task okay we are
going to write a command that rename
every file in a web in a website
directory uh you know like thousands of
files 10,000 files rename it retitle it
that is for example you know in a HTML
file you have this title tag and also
the H1 heading tag so you know so so for
example let's go to talk show page let
me show you what is a task for example
showing browser this is today's talk
show S Talk Show 2024 September uh 17th
episode
586 okay let's say I want to rename it
uh you know let's let's show another
example you know I've been blogging for
30 years so I have like literally 10,000
HTML web pages and often times I want to
rename the file so let me show you an
example okay um let's say uh uh let's
say s
commments uh if you are here say hi okay
comments hello hello
hang happy aam uh Chinese aam you know
the moon cake day that is the second
biggest festivity in Asia uh China Japan
Southeast Asia
so we eat moon cakes okay let's go back
to the code so I want to for example
let's say uh I want to rename a file
okay insert dat time so let's say insert
dat time okay so you see so I go I copy
the URL back to emac okay back to emac
open that page showing browser so this
is the page so search for
insert uh so insert dat time so open
that showing browser uh by the way am
using Sly Keys
okay sfly Keys search for it you'll find
it it's a efficient emx keybinding
system more efficient than vim and uh on
the pink window is all my command call
names uh or key strokes on the left as I
type them as I for example delete the
entire
uh you know main block so undo undo
showing browser so here's a page insert
data time so close that so I want to
rename this let's say I want to rename
it to daytime stamp uh stamp okay so
what I need to do is I need to find all
occurrences of this path so for example
let's search for it search in this
directory search orx HTML extension file
name
extension and uh did it is it is it
going yeah okay so so you can see here's
all the occurrences so show all the file
path so you can see you got like 14
files in this case 14 files links to
this page okay so if you want to rename
the title of this page that means you
need you need to rename to each of these
each and every of these occurrence okay
so for example here so you know insert
daytime that needs to be insert daytime
stamp okay actually we need to
uh change here so you see I need to redo
let's do that okay
so you see over here the link is insert
dat time but the um but the file name uh
let's let's do that okay so you see the
title the the title on that page is
insert datetime plus a rocket a rocket
sign means like it's a my own command
it's not part of emac so it's like
enhanced command so anyway so we want to
rename that to that okay so normally
what you do is you copy this file path
copy this part okay and then you just
do uh let me show you so this's this
command I find replace text you can see
in the pink window so you want to find
this text enter and replace string so
what do you want to replace string B so
it will be that
plus the rocket and plus the E you know
says emac in front Okay so say yes and
which directory let's say in this
directory this is my website document
route okay Enter file path regular
expression. HTML extension yes write
changes to file yes okay you can say no
so if you say no it's just testing it'll
generate a
report
um it's taking a while because it's
going over 10,000 20,000 files for the
first time so the dis has to load into
memory but once you do that you know
then it's fast okay so you can see they
are like you know four file uh changed
because only four files that's using
this title that link text okay so now if
you refresh this page refresh you
see so that's changed okay so but what
we want to do so remove that go back
here show in browser so what we want to
do is that in instead of manually doing
this every time I call you know sofine
replace and type and directory name and
file name exential I want to Simply put
my CER here and call the command and
then it will ask me the new name new
title okay the new link text okay and it
will just automatically automatically
change uh through the entire sad. info
directory you know there are over
like 8,000 you know also HTML files plus
some 20 more thousand jpeg or image
files and so on so yeah so that's a
command we canot write okay so uh let's
do that so let's let's go to talk show
okay let's uh put a link there so we
have a record of the links we showed
okay so insert dat time so go there so
also copy that
page okay so we you know those are the
files I
changed or need need to change okay so
let's start emac this okay so hold on
second showing browser close close close
next showing
browser uh okay copy that close back
here close and uh also so paste that
link so that's all my emac commands you
can get them
free okay so they are enhanced emac
commands for your emac users okay so now
let's code let's start to code emac this
okay so you know this is kind of
documentation so oh yeah there I I got a
example there so D for defend I'm using
EAC this mod so you can see in the in
the mod line the status line here iMac
this mod you can buy it pay me you get
it free and you know pay us a donation
and
uh it's open source you know I it was
free for 10 years but I don't get money
okay so Define a function so let's
what's the name so the kasan HTML rename
title
or okay let's just name that uh for now
okay
so
so so this is going to rename HTML title
for all HTML files of the file path of
the current curer is on on current web
rout okay
so uh created date
version dates for documentation purposes
okay uh and
uh title and
H1 and the link text okay so not just so
you have to
rename the pages
title the pages H1 header and
also whatever find that links to the
page the link text okay so that is the
task so go back here
um okay that's a
task so first of all you need to so
given uh so what is this showing browser
okay we don't care about that close that
showing browser so the first thing we
need to do when we want to rename is to
get get the file path you know what what
file which file it refers to exactly so
we need to get the file path so let's
show you so how do you get the file path
um the beginning and end positions of
the file path so you can
do thing at Point uh okay not that
bounds of thing at Point okay that will
return the boundary which is two
positions
integers that the file path begin n so
here we'll just say a file name okay
file name so you can also get the line
get the number get the white all white
spaces and so
on uh and uh if you are new here you
know check out my emac blog I mean s
emac tutorial so there are like 800
Pages tutorial on emac and emac lisp so
emag disp uh practical emag disp so go
there and you got a section on thing at
point so this will teach you all about
how do you grab a current word current
sentence
current uh identifier or current URL or
current file path so it can be you know
word symbol number wi space line or
sentence or page you know so on and you
can also get their boundary so there's
example so my emist tutorial so let's go
back here
uh showing browser go back here go to
talk
show go to talk show so let's paste the
link here so it's a things we talked
about uh so so so that
[Music]
you yeah uh my tutorial okay so you can
you can you can buy it of course you can
you know if you like my stuff sponsor me
just bu by my tutorial you can see here
okay so okay close that now now let's
continue to write this so so we need
declare two local variables X begin X
end that's two positions and the set
sequence uh set this is a new um this
function set sequence sequence set Q is
a
new feature in imag is about by now 10
10 years ago so it allowed you to set a
for example you have a list of two
things a b so you can set them in one
shot you know set them to these two
variables so the the the value we want
is this okay so like that okay so
let's uh okay so we got the boundary of
the final path then we need need
um okay then another new variable file
path okay so
set Q file path then you want to get the
text between those boundaries which are
two positions numbers so what you uh
call is uh get buffer substring no
properties okay
but for substring no properties
okay so X
begin uh X
begin
uh X and
completion I'm using by the way hepp
hepp expand that's a very useful command
that's what I use to com for
completion so you get so
the now x file path is a string of the
file path then once you find the file
path you need to get the full
path x file full path okay so a new
variable we declare local variable here
so you want to set fful path so you
typically you see typically in a file I
use relative links so relative links is
hard to work with you usually when you
work with files you always want the
entire full file path you know the the
the proper name is fully qualified file
name usually I just call it file path
it's more uh uh sensible so anyway so
get full path so how do you turn a
relative name to a full P file path to
do that
what you need is uh you need the current
file
path uh so current file path so so let's
do that so the you know so when you have
a file for example this file s talk show
how do you know what is a current
directory so interactively you can use
di jump you see Di jump so you jump to
the directory the file is in so which is
this file go to the top you can see so
that is a directory you can copy it new
buffer paste it you can
see you know so that is the current
directory but how do you do it
programmatically so that way uh so to do
that you just
say uh default directory
okay now that's a global variable
building Global variable whose value is
the directory of the current
perer or file so for example show it so
we can see the documentation default
default directory is a variable defining
C source code its value is this so This
value is actually the Parent Directory
of this file for example go to di jump
go to the top you can see a check check
check out so this is the Parent
Directory now how do you get the this
current files file full path to do that
you can say uh buffer file name okay
buffer file name is also a local V I
mean it's a global variable it's
building Global variable so you can
describe variable to read the
documentation so file name is a variable
defined in seource code the current
value is that so if you you know call
that you just open the current file so
so we got the current file we got the
parent
Factory uh you want to you want the
relative path okay so relative so let's
rename
this
uh
relative
path okay you want to turn the relative
path to a full path so what you do is
there is a um there's a function called
file name relative file relative name
there it is okay so you need the
directory and you need a file name so
the file name is X relative file okay
path the directory name would
be the Parent Directory of the current
buer current files Parent Directory so
let's not use this let's just use let's
get the Parent Directory of that so to
get the when you have a file path you
want the Parent Directory what you do is
um file name directory okay that's how
you get the Parent Directory so so you
put the a file name here okay that's a
directory so directory will be that okay
so then you set the value to the full
path so that's how you get the file name
full path so for example we can try this
so right now let's just print the file
name full path
okay full path is okay now we evaluate
the entire buffer and uh let's just call
itar HTML rename title all okay run it
uh wrong type of argument integer P
marker NE so we got something wrong here
Dan V hello Dan Dan says I can imagine
having to organize update thousand of
HTML files yeah that's uh you know that
that is kind of like shocking if you are
new to it but because I've been coding
HTML starting manually in in Microsoft
world since 19
1997 so after 30 years you pick up you
know you know what to do I mean so begin
in the beginning mean of course this one
you start with one file then you know
after a few year you have maybe 10 files
or or or 50 or 100 files so over the
years then you started to get into the
problem you know once you have let's say
500 files then you started to oh we you
got a new issue of management or things
or directory organization and things
like that so you know over the years you
just
gradually um
uh uh learn more things or uh fix things
you need to do and or pick up ways to do
them so okay so now we uh it's it says
error so wrong type argument okay
somewhere now when you have a error in
emac this you see it doesn't you know
right now it doesn't tell you where it
came
from I know where it came from because
I've been coding em this for like 15
years at least uh 20 years by now so but
how do you do it so so usually you turn
on uh let's see uh this command okay so
yeah so you just call tarle debug on
errow so let's call it meta X tarle
debug on error okay so do it then
you you call that command again HTML
rename title or then you you see now it
tells you the full detail so where so
where did it go wrong it's because of
this is see NE Neil both of substring no
properties it's supposed to take two
arguments of two integers but we got Neo
so that's
why so uh so so we fix that it's
somewhere here so
this beginning end is not set uh oh yeah
I know why because this is very annoying
because this bound of things at point it
returns a cons pair so it returns
something like this okay
um so you see this B of thing returns a
pair like that cons pair but this set
sequence it doesn't accept a cons pair
accept at least a vector or a string you
know a SE quence but the cons payer is
not a so is not a list is not a sequence
so it's very annoying this this is a
problem this is one of the major problem
of this programming language the cons
okay now if you ask Le people some
disagree in fact if you ask Richard
strowman he says cons is the most
important thing but that's uh that's
kind of Asian thought so cons pay is a
problem so that's why so you so what can
you do you can
um uh yeah so this is TD so let me show
you what you can do with uh by that okay
so what you can do is that
you for example you let X boundaries and
uh okay
so so let X boundary be that then you
then you say here
set begin car X boundary okay then set X
end c x boundary okay K car means the
first part first part of k k means the
second part it's named that way because
of History you know like this PT three
uh 40 years old this P three so it's
weird anyway that basically just means
the first part and second part so if you
do
that let me let me put that here okay so
let's clean up so this this is how you
set the beginning and end position if
you want to use bounds of thing at
point so you see but this but but this
but over here sequence set is much much
better okay okay let's not you know we
can so what we can do is we can can
convert this cons payer to a list
by uh okay so let's just show how to do
that if you want to use the set sequence
because this form is much more simpler
and you know provide Clarity because you
can see this beginning and end they are
positions they come in pairs beginning
end so you T you know usually so you
want to set them together usually and
also
also this block of code tells you right
away you are trying to set variables but
what but if you use this
SP it's more complicated
right and you have to declare another
new local variable
so so anyway so but so what you how if
you want to use this set sequence Set uh
uh sequence set form you can what you
can do is convert this thing into a list
okay how you do that is you just
um
uh well easiest way is just say aend
Okay
aend um yeah it's cons is a problem cons
is tedious let see
yeah cons is
tedious you see it's not even easy to
convert the cons to a list because you
need to get into the second part let's
not worry about it okay let's not worry
about it let's just use this this code
another way is to not is so you don't
you don't use this bounds of thing at
point you know but anyway this this
command of thing at point is Asian like
20 or 30 years old so for example let's
look up documentation describe function
so you can see it's defined in thing at
point so you open that expand the window
go to the top so it began in 1991 so
it's 35 35 years
old uh it's not like likely to change
because of the backward compatibility
so anyway let's just do this okay I have
other ways but of course but let's just
do this so so we get the beginning end
position we get the the relative file
path then you get the full path okay Cod
file relative name relative path file
name direct
um file name directory name buff of file
name okay then you okay now evaluate the
buffer call the command do it
okay so showing browser I mean show the
message path show the message buffer so
it says empty so it's actually empty so
so why is full path
empty uh file name relative file
relative name file name and directory
okay we got the file name we got the
directory so why is it why is this empty
let let's try again eval the buffer call
the command do it
so wait something is wrong
here hello
Zama ham
Hamza uh full
path so why is this uh
got the full path okay full path did we
spell something wrong
no uh and uh we set the boundary we set
the beginning and end and uh relative
path so I don't know let's debug okay
let's debug
okay eval the buffer Cod command do
it there is you see this this is
supposed to be interpreted here but it's
not even getting the value what's going
on
eval call the command do
it okay something is wrong I don't know
what it's printing
this so somehow the value of
333 got set
to the relative
path what that's really
odd
what so somehow you see somehow this
333 got set to this variable how did
that happen
I don't know so let's
print let's say
something okay now this message
uh X begin is X begin okay evaluate the
buffer meta X Cod
command show
so X begin okay there so X begin is
439 oh I got it I I think I know what's
going on yeah so what is going on is
that you see when you call bound of
thing at Point file name and when our
file is over here I mean when our
Cruiser is over here then we call the
file name
then we are basically asking emac to get
this thing as file path that is why it's
printing the wheel thing so the file
path is actually this so what we need to
do is actually go to a actual file path
like here so now we call it okay do it
so now show the message buffer so you
can see now this is
correct relative path full path is still
wrong um
okay but anyway we are getting somewhere
so you see relative path and full path
okay so let's fix that let's remove the
messages okay
so so we got a file
[Music]
name oh yeah the full so relative path
is is that right per substring no
properties yeah then full path is
um file relative
name let's check describe function file
name directory okay
so it should return the full path Okay
so
ER the buffer go to this
here open it close it call the command
do it showing browser I mean show the
message but the the full path is still
incorrect so why is it
incorrect
God this is unexpected so what is
the let's do it again EV the buffer go
here call the command Do It show
the uh message buffer related file so it
didn't
change you see it didn't change
so it didn't change so this full path
has no
effect per file
name uh file name directory both is try
that
yeah annoying so okay let's do some
debugging so let's copy that okay split
and
uh let's just put code
here so if we evaluate this what we get
yeah talk show directory that is
correct now what is relative
path
um uh bound of thing bound of thing we
are taking we are taking a file name
here you can supply a
argument so anyway so let's go so what
is
the so this is correct this part
but uh this part is
correct relative path is also correct
then what then why is this so let's test
test
here so cut that this is the relative
path and now evaluate this this
block okay you see it didn't change
correctly now what is so let's try
again paste now let's
evaluate that part that part is that
okay so this so now let's evaluate
that it didn't
change oh it didn't obviously because we
are requesting a relative name we want
the full name
yeah you are um you know you are you are
onto it so yeah we call the wrong
command that's
basically so let's remove that it's my
it's my you know my error my silly
mistake
obviously it doesn't work because we are
re asking for relative name we should be
asking a full path okay so we want to
turn relative to full path so how do you
do that um
you uh I have to think but we you know
one way to find out go to emac this
tutorial uh go to file path user input
file perer file directory file path so
all functions about file path so you get
file name directory file name nond
directory file name extension file name
sense extension relative path file
relative path expand file name that's
right forgot so expand expand file name
that will return a full path so yeah so
basically you just same argument but
change the
function so that's what we want F so
describe function to look up do
documentation correct okay so now remove
this part pry the code
pry remove the debugging thing we don't
need I'm pretty sure it'll
work evaluate the buffer so this is the
whole code let's let's just
um evaluate the whole buffer go to a
HTML file put a cruiser on a file path
on a link call it do it now showing
browser H we we remov the print
messages idiotic so anyway that should
work okay so that's actually let's just
print
it eval the buffer try again do it do it
okay it
shows you see this is the file full path
for for this this related path okay now
we got the final full path what's the
next step next step is
to oh yeah we need to do rename oh my
God this is going to be 20 more
minutes so far so good ask chat GPT you
know chat GPT won't work you know chat
chat GPT is like give gives you it would
give you an
outline of of what to do you know kind
of and sometimes you just hallucinate
that's what they call so you know it'll
give you a function that doesn't exist
you know things like
that uh
so yeah so you know if you are you know
if you don't know a programming language
let's say I'm learning f shop for
example and I want to code something you
know it's good for learning so if I want
if you know in a new language I don't
know I want to see how do you do find
replace or how do you open a file
you can ask chat gbt that's very uh
helpful but it's not really helpful for
actual coding You know despite you know
that like there's a lot fat idiots they
are saying oh CH gbt Code Pilot you're
going to revolutionize the the coding
IND industry no that's false okay those
are
idiots AI is is almost never going to
replace coding okay never produce actual
valid
code I mean never say never but you know
but it's you know we got a long way to
go so anyway for example we can try how
to open a file in F
shop okay in fop you can open a file
using system.io namespace here are few
ways to do it you know it it kind of
help you so but if I you know for short
short things like that you'll probably
work so anyway so back to emac we got we
got a lot to do so we got the file path
now we want to get the
um let's annotate okay
okay so next thing we want to do is get
link text okay so link text is when you
have a link you know this part is a link
text okay so how do you do that
um
yeah it's a bit
tedious okay so here's the example URL
so you want to get the link text
okay so
okay so we create a mini program block
here so you basically you want to okay
so let's instead of um let's say that
let okay um
beginning and end boundary just like
before so what you how you how do you do
that you
can uh here's how you do okay search
forward search forward for the greater
than sign that will move the closer to
the beginning of the link text okay uh
bounds we
care we don't care about those okay then
set X begin to point point is a current
C position it's a integer okay then
search
forward for
the for
the uh
closing for the beginning of the closing
tag okay so we want to search forward
for l than greater uh less than sign
okay then set X
end to be
match beginning okay so that means the
beginning of the last match position
okay zero is the whole match okay that
means just set the point over there so
then you need need uh another variable
link text okay so let's go to the top
let's say add link text okay that's
the that's the link text okay now you
just set link text
to uh to both of substring no properties
both of substring no properties okay uh
X
begin X end
okay that's fantastic
okay uh let's let's just shorten
this okay so we got we got the
code uh go to the so this is here's the
whole code Okay so now we got the link
text what's the next
step oh my God now we have to start to
do F replays okay
so oh my God this is um actually quite
involved you'll take another 20 minutes
uh hello guys how am I doing am I doing
good how many people 11 not too bad okay
let's continue okay we got the so here's
a whole code for today
okay uh so now we got a link text now
next next step is to uh now
do find
replace for all web rout okay
God so
so so first of all find
string you need to get the find
string then get replace
string create replace string uh then you
need to uh get the the
to get the root okay web
root so to do find replace you need kind
of three things find string replace
string and rot directory and also we
assume uh file name extension assume.
HTML files okay okay so we need to now
do find replace oh God this is tedious
then we need to do backup
okay first of all find string
um yeah find
God so to get the find string you need
to okay so now let's make this program
into a block of
code
um so kind of a mini program so we have
our code organized each algorithmic
unit is you know in a
block so and
uh you need to find string replace
string and root so let's say let okay so
actually so let's just say
let
find
replace and uh root okay so few
variables so how do you get the fine
string so if we look back at this so
usually typically the F string will be
that
okay
uh yeah do you
um typically like this
okay because you want to grab you you
want to grab all links
you know of this
form um for any directory you know you
cannot use full path because
the the relative path will be different
depending on you know which file links
to it for example that in another
directory could be like that in another
directory it could be like that you see
so you need to get all these responsibil
you know so um yeah
so
it's okay
so so you want to okay so
okay so what we have here relative path
full path um
and you need
to so you got a link text you got full
path full path is the the things you
need to
change uh current file path okay so you
need also
curent
file let's just say
that okay so current file path will be
very simple current file path will be
that perer file name that is a current
perer files path okay the relative path
is the path you want to change you um
okay
so okay we getting you know we started
to need to organize our code because
it's getting big so
anyway so it's uh relative
path okay so you got the relative path
which is like
we have a example here yeah which is
like
that okay
so so let's set the fine string
okay
uh the fine string will be
path you need to get the last component
of that
okay
um so let's go back to reference my
reference or file path functions you
need
the you need the file name file name n
directory okay so you need to file name
n directory okay for
example for example that you if you run
it you just get the file name part
that's what you want okay so file name n
directory of the relative path then you
need to add a
add a greater than equal sign then you
for example let's put that here then you
need to add a con concact string okay
then you need to get link text then you
need to add a
ending uh
that ending tag okay
so so this whole thing you need to
concact them okay join string
so there so cut that put it here pry the
code so it's like
that
okay make sure that's correct so you got
relative path
then find string so find string let's
rename
it okay and uh this will be replace
string okay so fine string would be
that and uh and
uh this this can be just one single
line
then you got to find string uh what is a
replace string okay replace
string okay set replace string you need
to ask the user
okay uh okay so how do you prompt user
to uh to for replace
string uh let's say new title okay so
replace string changes to new
title so you need to prompt user so what
you can do is read
string so this will prompt user to type
a new title
so okay
so prompt new title
okay
then
uh let's say we don't care about anyone
with that okay so it will prompt user
for a new title then just okay so you
got a new title then you
you now do find and replace
for for or in rud
okay okay so far so good but let's test
our code you know we can when you code
emac disp you can always
like test as you go so for example right
now we can we can print the F string and
print uh the new title okay okay so
let's do it here so
messages this will be xind
string is that then we also want to
print uh we want to print X new title
okay okay so there it is our whole code
now let's
evaluate the buffer fantastic go to HTML
file let's put um uh what is this this
is uh today's talk show okay let's put
the cruiser here now let's call
it do it okay it asks you new title
XXX okay do
it okay uh
debugger entered void variable X find
string okay we got we forgot
something void variable oh because this
is
yeah yeah because we've we didn't put we
need to you see this is a let block so
those are local variables find string
but we are this needs to go
inside okay cut cut now go you need to
go inside
where yeah
here okay evaluate the buffer go back
here put the cruiser here call the
command wait show the pink window call
the command do it new title let's say y
y y y y enter
okay looks like it worked show messageer
so you can see find
so F string is this this this this this
okay new title is this
fantastic okay so so far so good so next
step is to do the actual fine replace
for you know thousands of files in a
directory okay
drink comments and questions am I doing
good okay let's go back to code hello
Janice yeah let's go back to code now
now do the fine replace
okay oh God tedious tedious and tedious
tedious and
tedium uh yeah if I code by myself then
it's much faster I don't have to explain
I just you
know you know so live stream is is a bit
slower by quite by quite quite a few
times by five or 10 times
because if I just code it then you
wouldn't understand I
mean so why but why don't I just code it
without doing any explanation for a
change because we've been doing this
already an hour so so let's just try to
code you know finish it fast okay okay
so now get the directory get list of
files in rout okay so let me just code
it uh so I don't remember so list of
directories so file path walk directory
yeah so directory files so directory
files recursively directory files
recursively uh actually we have used
um we have uh let's just copy code okay
talk show last talk
show yeah in fact last talk show we just
did it here
so because it's TDS because we need to
uh we need to ignore the G
so yeah so there it is directory yeah
this is what we want yes cut it
close uh close back here so that is what
we want so we need a file list uh
declare a new variable file list where
so
here okay so file list will
be uh clean up the code directory file
recursively uh root
the okay re re just quote so what
rud okay so here is the regular
expression in this case
is
uh
HTML dollar
sign okay OBS got a issue are we back
let's check my status OBS got a
issue uh okay we are
back stream settings stream Health okay
we are
back so we get the root directory of all
HTML files and uh and uh include
directories no NE and pred cut yes that
okay and follow s link links no okay so
this is a file list okay
so go
okay these files in R directory then
next is to open each one
okay okay for each file you open it so
what is the EDM for quickly opening file
so let's
see uh walk directory then go back to
read file okay so read file so this is
how to quickly open file not using find
file okay
so there it is okay so insert file
content X then here is where we
do find replace okay so we open the file
temporary file then we do find replace
so we got the uh find string here yes uh
see oh okay so they are inside there so
all this needs to
move move inside okay so going to move
inside
okay so new
title uh we get a new title we get a
file list in rud directory then we start
to do find replace for each file in the
file list we create a temp buffer we
insert the file content then we do find
replace okay so first of all go to uh CH
Point minimum that's the beginning of
the buffer then search forward search
for word for find string
okay search forward for the F string and
bounce Neo no error true because some
files do not contain the link then if
found
um okay you need to say while okay so
while search forward then replace match
by X
new um Okay so so replace match will
[Music]
be you need to create a string not just
the title okay
so uh
concact okay we need to uh generate the
string okay this is taking longer than
expected so here's the example so
concact so you want to concact
yeah
okay let me just do this quickly
this find
stream
uh so let's ask the new title first okay
as a new title first then you declare a
replace string okay find string and
declare a replace
string okay then
you uh so that's the F string and the
replace string is going to
be replace string is going to be here is
a new title okay so it's basically same
as fine string except the title part
okay so here is our replace string
fantastic now now go back here so now we
do the find replace so replace match by
simply the replace string okay fixed
case yes
literal yes okay uh so that that that
that that prettyy the code
that that that
that that try the code uh I think that's
it so okay so we got map this function
to all files in this directory and uh
for each file we create temp buffer we
insert file content then we do find
replace go to the beginning of buffer
and for each find string we found we
replace it
so so if so if that is true we need to
know if it's actually made any change so
so you can
say so you need to declare okay so let's
declare a new local
variable
so changed
okay so if is found you replace it and
set changed to True okay
then then if okay uh
if changed is true you want to write to
file okay so you say uh write buffer
okay um right region that's how you
write buffer that's how you save
something in buffer to a file okay so
right region from beginning of buffer to
end of the whole content and file name
will be X yeah x x is the file name
append no visit no lock no must reew no
okay that's
it this will just change
all okay we can actually try it be uh
but we must be very very careful because
we are not making any backups because
this is just going to go
through thousands and thousands of files
in
in in in the in my uh web
directory
um you know
so okay but here's a whole code Okay so
here's a whole code
basically let's evalve the buffer let's
make a backup go to the dire jump and go
to the
directory and uh let's compile the code
B compile yes compile successfully why
do I compile because usually when you
buy compile it'll tell you any you know
uh errors like syntactical errors and
such anyway anyway it checked out so I
think this is the code so now we just
need to actually test it
so make a backup pop it back syntax
correct showing browser so here's
today's talk show and here's a
code okay it should
work uh it should work but now we need
to test it okay so let's say
let's say let's you know let's test it
okay let's
say uh let's say thing at Point okay
open that showing Brower so this is
about using thing and point page so copy
the file path and let's go somewhere
okay let's go to my computer programming
block showing browser so you know that's
what I'm working on today and let's just
say add this add a test here
test okay then link this link it showing
browser so you see now let's say I want
to okay copy copy the file path go back
to talk
show and uh and uh put it here okay so
but now this time let's
say
SSS let's say that
okay okay so showing browser so we
created a new
link to to a you know to some page on my
website so we are going to try to run
the command so whenever it sees a link
to this specific file with this specific
link text then it's going to replace it
okay so but okay so but so let's go back
to the other
place to make
sure uh not
here yeah here so showing browser so we
got a link in two different directories
you know one is this program you know
both contain this L
okay so close this page
so now we can try our
Command okay but before we try let's
double check because I always double
check before I run but that should be it
today so you okay let's just try it then
okay so go back here put the curer here
call the
command HTML rename title all yes and
new title let's say y y
y y for y okay
Enter wrong type of argument directory
file name NE okay we got Arrow file name
recursively okay we got Arrow from here
directory file name recursively
okay you can press enter to jump to it
uh no not not here it jump to the you
know um
okay close that so let's go back to our
code this is the problem now directory
file
[Music]
recursively oh we didn't Define root did
we no
okay
yeah well the root it should be the web
root so that depends on you know depends
on each person where is your root for me
let's just hard Cod it
okay uh so root is going to
be that
okay you know because root directory
basically you have to Define there's no
other way there's no automatic way you
have to Define what is the web rout
directory ch ch ch ch ch
okay so now we got a root the EV uh wait
eval buffer go back here let's try it
again okay coder command yes do it new
title let's say y y y y y
enter
enter okay now it's going to search
thousand 10,000 files 20,000 30,000
files
so all Links of this Elis SSS should be
y y why why
now please don't screw up please don't
screw
up this is taking longer than
expected I hope this
n okay let's
exit okay
it
seems what did it do
okay saving file talk show okay
uh C that go back to the code go to the
Pam block did it change
no okay make a backup
this go back to talk show make a backup
go back to the code so we got the root
directory uh
so make sure the last step okay here
file list is the file list
correct I think
so uh but this so this part is like very
questionable I mean it's
this part is the heart of the code and
uh
dangerous so when it's changed in right
region because it can
potentially destroy or erase the
thousands of files so you want to be
careful here
oh okay I know what's wrong so when you
have a 10 buffer you see but here you
are calling right region Point me and
point Max so this part needs to go
inside the temp
buffer
yeah okay so now it should
work eval the
buffer I'm I'm I want to be very very
careful because I don't want erase my
10,000
files so you know should should work
though but
let's let's comment this out for now
okay comment this right file out
out so for now let's just say
message okay
wait so when it's changed let's just say
message
changed
path okay let's just print that
message predy the code you The Bu go to
Backup backup and buy compile no error
good close back to here now let's test
it now programming blog we don't care
close it go back to talk show put the
cruiser here call the
command HTML rename title or do it
new title let's say let's say t uh let's
say m all the way do
it done okay now go to messages
sper why is it
uh no it doesn't seems to have done
anything
okay go back
here okay so
let's
message checking file
X it should print it
okay evaluate the buffer go here test it
again call the
command um
let's double
check so if it's
changed I mean change is local variable
right yeah
so okay so but for now let's change the
root directory so it's not
um so it doesn't go over my roots let's
just work in the talk show directory
okay evaluate the
buffer because now in talk show
directory it's
only four you know 1,000 2,000 files
instead of 10,000 files so we narrow
down the possibility of error so
evaluate the buffer go back here Cod the
command do it new title let's say HH
H fantastic now show message buffer
fantastic so you can
see you know it's going through each one
of
them
okay now but it didn't say when it's
changed so close that go back to the
code
so it didn't say when there's changed
found so it's checking the file 10
buffer to find replace go to the
beginning insert file contents yes go to
the beginning then search
forward for the find
string that's right replace match so
what is fine
string so let's print we have
an yeah so let's print the fine string
let's see what exactly is the F
string did we get the link
text
yes
wait wait the link text is is
wrong wait uh wait the link text should
be
correct
so let's print the F string
okay evaluate the buffer go here put C
here call the command do it new title
entry entry P okay now go to the message
[Music]
buffer now where does it
say the link
stream there it is find string equals to
that
okay
so the fine string is correct
yes the fine string is correct
now now close that go to the code the F
string is correct however
it does not seems to ever found it why
it should
because we got the you know we got the
currence right here in the talk show
directory ah okay this is taking too
long so find string search for what find
string is
why is it never
found H
god let's run this
again see not that
call it do
it do it
show go
here
okay but
apparently the fine stren is correct but
it seems to never actually
found that string in all these
files okay now can we mismatching
lines okay that's
incorrect oh we forgot this double quote
what the
all coding eror okay your the F
string needs to have a double quote
here okay so it needs to
be that and the quote okay yeah so it
needs to have that and same thing for
the replace string you see because you
know that's this double
quote okay now evaluate the
code now let's not print the file names
evaluate the code go back here put the
cruiser on this link call the command do
it new title let's say CCC this time do
it okay it says changed switch to
message buffer so apparently it
worked you see it worked so but it
didn't write to the file so now we need
to write to the file so now write to the
file and now also change the uh the root
directory to the
real info okay evaluate the buffer go
back
here now open Messages buffer clear it
by just close in it put the cruiser here
C the command do it new title let's say
R do
it
fantastic now you see it changed the
current one and now let's go to the
programming block you know we can
actually go to the browser here you see
EXA programming blog there's El SSS now
ref
fresh
fantastic so our job is done so this
command let's put it
back syntax CCT showing browser so this
code HTML rename title all we will go
through you know 10 or 20 thousands of
files in your web directory and just
rename them
all one shot so let's try okay now now
let's do a real
test let's go to uh for example I want
to show you a real test so for example I
have a here a link this is SAR music of
exotic songs you know I have a Blog
about humanity and songs I make analysis
and comments on the song and
lyrics so what I want is for example the
Diva dance song from The Fifth Element
this is a very incredible
song uh because they seen in in a pitch
Beyond human capacity but in this case
this is actually computer generated
scening by a
synthesizer by the way this is very good
you know to watch this because this
is uh you know like
Humanity liberal arts you know the the
the you know singing Human singing
performance Opera but beyond
human capacity of the speed of changing
pitch and also the pitch the high
highness of the pitch but anyway in the
movie they use the computer to actually
generate this is very interesting
because not just the computer generated
sing I mean to write this music in such
a high pitch you know difficult part but
also relates to Opera and the history of
Opera for example such difficult part of
an opera is called mad scene okay that's
a name in in Opera it's called mad scene
where you write a you know section of
the Opera that that tries to demonstrate
that this performance you know sing
singing capabilities usually very
difficult but then we also actually have
a actual human there's a lot human tries
to sing this song you
know as you know as best as as they can
it actually is not possible but they try
so she so far is the best
one uh human performance of the Diva
dance song so anyway that's a digression
so what I want to do is you know is to
um let's go back so
go to My Music blog okay so open it
showing browser so I want to for example
this link I I want to add this musical
symbol so that means whenever you see a
link with the musical symbol at the end
that means that has music in it okay so
I want to rename all links to this file
by now having a symbol okay so let's do
it okay before before we do that we need
to change the code a little bit because
this is in a different directory so
through directory is different so this
is not CA info but CA or okay save it
evaluate it okay now let's do it rename
title rename title
or yes new title okay new title need
going be copy that paste it here unit
code insert
music symbol do it so there it is okay
Enter okay it's doing
it fantastic you see lots of fire are
changing is it done yet
not
yet done okay you
see
refresh there it is and go to the
messages buffer you can see all these
roote wrote wrote that's you know that's
all changed file so let's do this
matching
lines so there are 20 files that changed
for example let's go go to one of them
uh uh let's see Bohemian rapity open it
showing browser so that's another
interesting
song and uh in this file contains the
link to
that there uh wait where is see
the uh
Fifth Element there it is so it changed
fantastic that's it for
today thank you guys for
watching how many people watching now
let's
see six stream settings
analytics 10 fantastic we done thank you
guys for watching uh if you like my
stuff buy my stuff of of course so we
shutting down in 1 minute so you go to S
code
uh go to all the way down you can
patreon me Amazon gift card me or gift
card or PayPal okay and also you can buy
my emac tutorial and together and with
emac disp you can find the link just by
go to my emac
homepage uh table of contents all the
way at the bottom by emx tutorial thank
you
guys that's it
any any
questions oh that's that's uh wow that's
90 minutes of actual actually coding um
so this is a code now put it back syntax
C showing browser so you guys can grab
it and you know study it or actually use
it if you have like a HTML static
website for