hello guys so today I'm going to do a
walk through walk flow kind of I'm gonna
work on my Emacs and I'm gonna show you
my surface book so I have this I have
this surface book I have a I have a PC
laptop and I traded it I traded with my
roommate to get this surface book and
it's got a pen and it's so great it's
wonderful but anyway I'm going to show
you my walk workflow in Emacs okay there
it is
and I the surface book this is surface
book pro for the latest version is
actually six what's going on had an
account no I don't want had no accounts
no nothing so anyway so what I've been
doing is that these days because I sit
in front of computer like like almost 12
hours a day so I I need to walk around
you know otherwise my hands is suffering
you know typing too much and so I've
been like every hour I would take my
surface book and walk around just walk
around read you know every time I need
to read something I put on a surface
book so I walk for half an hour and
actually the pains over there so when I
walk I I take notes I just I just write
it you can write with hands as well but
the pain is much better so I'm I'm
actually very excited about pain
computing you know since I started used
useless service propane so anyway there
are two kinds of okay I wasn't planning
to do to do a service pro review but
they are two kind of pain digital pain
one is like with a tablet you know you
read on the screen and the other kind is
that you use a well it's like a touch
pad and you write on on a touch pad you
know you would think that
of course writing on the screen is
better but actually that's not
necessarily so because I've asked you
know artist friends you know it seems to
me that actually the keys with the pen
you know the pain is great but you don't
necessarily need the screen to write on
because when you write on the screen you
you you don't want to touch your palm on
the screen I mean actually this I mean
this this the issue of touching your
palm on the screen and and if you go to
Amazon Amazon actually they sell this
kind of Grove just covering your edge of
the palm you know that's kind of silly
like and so there's that issue and it
actually I mean technically is supposed
to you know the software you know
supposed to eliminate you know detect
that and to some you know that that
interfere but actually it does when your
palm is touching the surface it's it's a
problem so you know typically you know
anyway the screen tablet is not
necessarily better you want to get pain
tablet and I'm going to buy that you
know the cheap one is like forty dollars
I mean there they are tiny ones you
probably don't want that you want you
know you know you can spend like fifty
dollars or you can buy welcome welcome
it's most famous like they go for like
eighty dollars yeah you know usually in
general I don't trust big brand because
typically what happens is a big brand
they become fat and powerful and they
well just like every company they do all
honest you know by all means necessary
to squeeze money and they they're their
prices is usually double double than the
you know small companies for the same
quality anyway I'm going to work on so I
have here you know
quite a lot notes I've written so I'm
gonna walk through you know basically
he's walking on my website so I'm gonna
show you so I'm gonna read my notes
okay loop through map okay it's like
gold and tutorial so this is my golden
tutorial and I need to go to the map
section map hoping it okay before we do
that it's let's make this and it's turn
keys so there you can see there this key
is this key application is sometimes
stops I haven't I haven't took the time
to look why is some time stops okay it
strike again this application okay this
application sometimes stops it's try it
fast is application sometimes stops
anyway so that's yeah there's my keys
and here let's turn on the key log now
you have you oops and do and do okay
open and do and do open go to Emacs
ALPA yes command log mod yes go to that
yes and eval eval eval
there it is now you can see
every every command I type here show up
here so you can pause and find out what
I'm doing so let's go back to Golan okay
now let's make make this into
perspective this is like tiling Windows
Linux tiling windows yeah the most
efficient okay so what yeah what I need
to do go map okay so on this page goal
and this well colon is my favorite
language now it's amazing it's amazing
in the sense that typically the best
languages you like you know the elegant
and you know beautiful languages they
are academic they are not used in the
industry for example scheme you know you
probably heard of scheme list its scheme
lists and now racket scheme lists this
they change their name you know it was
scheme then Rice University scheme then
you know
well anyway scheme list or racket it's a
lisp and that's was the most concise you
know can say it's considered by hackers
to be the most elegant beautiful
language and it's very popular among
hacker community in 1990s up to let's
say mm but you know it kind because
today there are so many so many
languages it kind of faded faded faded
away but that was these you know
supposed to be the most beautiful
language but anyway so typically the
most elegant or functional programming
languages are not use much in an
industry but but so colon is amazing it
is
well III I like it very much
I consider it to be very minimal and and
an elegant and and the documentation is
beautiful it's perfect you know usually
vast majority majority of programming
languages I mean even if the language is
good the documentation sucks donkey ass
this includes Perl Python the Python
Python stock is the worst okay Perl
Python closure closure dock is well it's
got lots of problem Haskell talk is
incomprehensible but to realize that
it's not incomprehensible because you
you aren't stupid or because you because
it's academic because it's involved
involve its advanced math know the
Haskell documentation and is it sucks
because it sucks it's badly written
period okay don't let you know like
typical programmers you may not know you
think Oh ask how it's so difficult
because you know you read the
documentation you cannot understand it
monad and stuff because well because it
involves advanced mathematics know those
Haskell program was vast majority of
them may know about mathematics
when in general when programmers talk
about math all programmers use math
jargons for example on get people likes
to say Oh get is just the directed graph
directed graph my ass okay they have no
idea what they're talking about now you
now if you don't believe me okay you
want to ask people who are in the math
field and a lot a lot of them are you
know who who have a PhD degree in
mathematics if you if you are in those
communities then you can you know you
know pick up but vast majority of
paramus they are just in the programmer
community just like cameras are they you
know gamers are in a gamer community
like you know if you don't get out of
your community
you really don't see things okay my
alarm clock is going let me turn it off
so my alarm clock is going off every 30
minutes because I need to get up it
tells me to get up so I'm gonna walk
through my okay so the plan has been
sorted a couple of times because I'm
talking I'm talking about multitude of
variety things because well anyway so :
tutorial so I like it the more it's it's
it's a rare beautiful end it the the
great thing is that it's actually used
in the industry
you know like C or C press press so it's
got more users than for example let's
say closure ok closure
I like closure but you know the JVM I
don't want anything to do with Java
closure closure heavily depends on Java
like in fact closure is is like the
language is intertwined with Java and I
was puzzled at first you know what why
would whispers want that it turns out it
actually it's two closures advantage
because you know because Java is the
number one basically the top three most
used language in the industry and
closure is like you know piggyback on
that so therefore you know you you know
mass majority of programmers you know
they you know they are not necessarily
into functional programming like if you
talk about functional programming they
what what the is that you know they
don't know but but closure you know
rights on Java so so you know you have
this massive number of Java programmers
and there it is closure well you know
Java yeah come to closure you know you
know it's based on jvn all the things
you know you know works you know if you
want to so so that's how I think that's
it's one of the main reason
closure haven't been moved off into a
independent programming language well
because the the guy hickey rich Hickey
he's a Java program you know basically
he's a professional and Java programmer
and well in other languages well of
course he's a he's a great expert but
that the thing is that you know the
thing about Java is that you know
different languages typically have a
field they are they are a community or
type of programming they are tied in to
for example scheme this is is basically
academia you know Haskell is well for
the most life history of has cow it's
academia you know language research
similar with scheme you know it's only
in the last five years has car became
somewhat popular you know it's used by
Facebook for example so so anyway so
what I'm saying is yeah typically your
language has a community tied to it so
for Java you know it's it really sucks
because the community community Java
tied to is typically enterprise
programming what does that mean it's the
most boring programming ever you know
enterprise what what does that mean well
it's it's like databases many management
systems
well database is the MU is the most
typical characterization of you know of
enterprise programming you know it's
transactions it's you know it's like
boring so nothing like it's nothing
about computer science I mean if you are
like I was a hacker type you know if you
are like me
you know we tend to like computer
science related things you know
algorithms or implementing compilers so
yeah
or visualization you know things like
that but you know the Java award is
primarily I mean the Java language is
very heavily tied to enterprise like the
word Enterprise kind of programming it
sucks
so anyway map yeah so I love column
language so I would recommend if you
don't have a choice if you don't know
you might try my tutorial you know the
the thing you love the more that you
love something the better your teacher
is so loop through map okay let's go
let's work on I've been talking like
probably 15 minutes already you know I
tend to ramble on you know but that's a
good thing because that's why I'm
running
soft rock show yeah I'm trying to do
videos you know regularly and I wasn't
sure you know what style or what subject
or what kind of things I want to cover
you know should I be very focused you
know specific like you know teaching you
eMac eMac B's or should I you know teach
you Java Script like very focused you
know like oh professional like put put
on a suit and tie or something like
community building you know like that's
most programmers like Emacs programmers
or other programmers like you know on
YouTube you find them you know they talk
where they give you a good presentation
and they show you you know how to do
something about and they and typically
they're also oh we're gonna we let me
help you you know my I'm here to help
you and so on and you know yeah they're
gonna build a better world that's good
but I you know I doesn't fit me you know
that's that's not my style I am NOT a
great present presented you know so
anyway so right now I'm just you know
talk random like you know it's correct
kisara talk show
so go math so what I want to do on this
page okay there are several things I
need to add you see here's the syntax
here's how you the syntax for declaring
the map type and here I don't have I
don't have that syntax I just have the
example so I want to add the syntax as
part of I mean yeah I want to not just
use an example but actually just show
you the syntax by the way if you are
writing tutorial sometimes you know for
example you you will run into this if
you are writing a tutorial that like if
you know especially programmers
programmers you know you tend to just
give example code without any
explanation you know just look at the
code there it is but actually if you
want your tutorial to be popular
you actually want the explanation even
more important than pass it's like
having half I wouldn't say it's more
importantly the examples but actually
just a line a set of sentence it's
significant that's the way things are
you know I'm not going to go into why
you know that but in general that's
that's okay so for example you can look
at you know there are a lot of you know
money is a driver of everything so they
are a lot websites they are they are
kind of like professional I mean they
focus on making tutorials so that
everyone can just read their stuff and
typically they are not very good they
are not very good because they focus on
the mass you know you know there are
millions of people who want to get into
programming but they don't know they are
beginners they they have zero experience
they never studied anything well they
don't you know they may not have you
know they've never studied so so this is
there's a sea of people there and if you
can grab their attention you tend to
make more money because you know that's
like you know a meeting of them they all
want to learn programming so they go to
your website and you show them the most
and you know and they like it and they
tend to be not you know they are
typically not professional programmers
you know they're just beginners they
don't have programming experience or
maybe some but they what they are not is
that they are not like us they are not
like the you know how cool hardcore
hackers you know so-called hackers you
know that that word is gone out of
fashion today but so they so we for
example we are interested in oh we are
excited about algorithms and computer
science and stuff in Emacs and vamo you
know the technical details which is
better so on but for them that's not
their interest because they just want to
learn programming language - they want
to get a job so so for those website
there are a huge number of them you know
they like like if you just type like
learn you know goal and or learn Python
or learn PHP you'll find them like there
are a lot of them you know it's like a
lot of them and typically their quality
is very you know pretty bad but but they
are the you know they are hugely popular
they are like a hundred times popular
than whatever you ever write they they
are more popular than my Python tutorial
for example you know and my goal I'm
tutorial for example day yeah did I show
let's say let's try it you know python
tutorial python tutorial that's the most
Pagani's you know that a lot of people
want to get into so yea tutorial point
is one of them these these you know I
despise them because they are
commercialized commercialization and
they you see this one guru 99 guru 99 my
ass so in seven days and efficient ones
by the way official documentation
usually days they are not good so anyway
let me show you a few yeah this one
like you know they are professional but
by professional I mean they are
dedicated to making money but you
typically they are not they are you know
just a few people I would say so this is
you know tutorial point you know and w3
school you probably already familiar
with and this one guru 99 I haven't seen
this one before
but actually they do have a point you
know for specially you know they do have
a point for example if I want to learn
something I don't know or I forgot for a
long time
for example CSS you know cascading style
sheet in principle it's it's very simple
but every year now they check our new
stuff and if I want to read something I
search the web if I go to the
programmers you know hacker typer blog
you get confused like what they're
talking about they teach you know they
talk about little advanced details like
you know if you are a beginner a
programmers if you are being a
programmer you are not probably not
watching me right now but suppose if you
are some some beginner programmer you
watch me and you get confused what way
is this guy talking about languages and
that that you know you just want to know
you know the basic so if I'm trying to
find something new some new feature in
CSS you know some tag or something the
w3 for example they they they they they
give you the point you read it you
understand what what it is about on the
other hand you go to the you know more
advanced hacker sites like they try to
give you syntax you know the the B&B
Backus known form of the syntax and
whatever an image mention you know lots
of job ins they think they are
technically correct but you know they
don't get that point across anyway so so
there are these tutorials you know they
have fiercely competitive
you know they money money is the thing
that's that's what drives it so anyway
I'm going I was going to work on my
stuff but I probably talked for too long
already
so lemme just let me show you London
meet up this Emax meet up in Mountain
View that's good and I just closed it so
anyway so it's already here so let's do
that create map literal expression okay
is this mice the grassroots style
tutorial you know is instead of using
fancy words you want to write to in a
way that vast majority of people
understand it including those people
whose language first language is not
English so I started to write in this
style instead in recent years so
actually usually I would do key type
okay so this this would be key one
key 1 bar 1 key to 2 so this is the
syntax and and do that do that go here
there it is
to create a map with keys and values
okay this needs a
reload reload video real effort if ff5
okay the key disappeared you see this
this application this application key
cast is not showing anymore
so there must be a key that controls it
and I must have heated some something in
the water does not there it is again I
don't know why I have to look into it
so anyway to create a map with keys and
values to like this
okay so there's still something wrong
remove the tax I need that
there it is so we're here refresh there
it is so red means literal that is those
are the characters you type as is and
the green sea and you know green color
is like variable so map key type
go into be a value type so go back here
remove the HTML so I and had the angle
bracket int so actually is not in turn
its value type had underscore there it
is okay and HTML eyes it add a paragraph
show in browser there it is
so this is my super efficient system and
I need to do this okay so make okay I'm
not I probably I'm not going to continue
with this because you get idea because
we've been talking for for the past like
20 minutes already but you know my plan
was to you know I have actually several
more pages you know let's see this
double check if I have anything bad here
if I can show you so I might I have
several several pages I need to work on
so anyway let's stop today thank you for
watching if you have a comment comment
coming out you know comment on it and
ask me questions about stuff and let's
keep let's keep the conversation going
bye