[Music]
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
today we are going to code emacs lisp
i'm going to teach you
how to write a major mod from the ground
up
so let's begin right away so
it's just going to be uh emac lisp and
let's focus on emacs lisp okay so i'm
using this is kinesis advantage 2
keyboard
and this is ultimate hacking keyboard
this one on top and you can go to
xr keyboard blog
and find my reviews and buy them okay
ultimate hacking kinesis advantage
so now let's start coding emac this so
i'm going to teach you uh how to write
the major mod okay
so uh
so what is this so emac this tutorial
that's right so now let's go to today's
talk show
uh
today's talk show
okay and let's go to topic notes
so we have some notes on what we are
going to do today
emacs go line mod okay so let's copy
that
so this is what we're gonna do
turn on global highline highline mod so
that is what we're gonna do copy split
the window go to today's talk show open
it
and uh paste link here
remove the li
make a new list
and uh
okay let's just start writing a
go landmark okay showing browser you can
see
that's our topic
okay
now why do i want to write the new goal
line mod because i have for example let
me show you my emacs
so my lpa
my library emacs the packages i
installed are
yeah magic delete magic i don't use it
get that
um
anyway so there's the gold line mod okay
that's essentially right now
almost the only one package i use so
let's go to a now and then i code gold
land so let's go to a find replace
script i've written in golan so let's
open it now the problem is whenever you
activate golan mod it will actually
start to spin up your d drive very
annoying so it takes half a second so
for example let's go to
open
bookmark finally replace okay find
replace go enter
now it's um
anyway trust me okay it's uh it's
spinning up the d drive i'm not sure why
but anyway so here is the find replace
script
let's clean up so you so i can i can
type whatever i want find string and
replace string find string and replay
string
they are superior to set or whatever you
are using the unique set so anyway go
lime so i'm going to uh save it okay i'm
going to write golan mod
a golem mod from scratch okay let's
let's just do it let's begin okay
where do i want it so go to
xsa
emacs
exci max okay
here is all my packages now speed window
open new buffer
uh
save it
exa
go land
exactly mod dot e-l okay
okay let's start writing a golan mod
okay uh oh i got the
yeah
open today's talk show
go to notes
and
okay go to sas talk show
so golan
fix print lines okay so this should be
actually emacs let's go see
yeah so this topic okay let's go back to
talk show cut it go back to talk show
paste it here
so that's today's topic now okay now
let's write let's start to write the mod
okay if you have questions comments
related to emacs this coding type it
there okay i'll be you know i'm gonna
answer your question related to what i'm
doing emac this email is only today
so go like mod okay so let's start ready
to go landmark so how do you begin okay
so to write the goal line we're gonna do
it from scratch you go to practical emac
list click on writing a major mod
uh click on syntax early
so these are a collection of tutorials
on writing a major mod so okay anyway
let's let's begin okay
golan mod now i need to um
i need to copy
xr e-max
several of my other packages let's model
it on
um
javascript mod okay
go landmark let's model it on there it's
pretty simple okay it's pretty simple
so
let's let's copy the some of the lines
here and begin
because i'll go line mod okay
major map for editing editing golan
okay and utf coding utf-8 lexico binding
true okay
uh date copyright author
version uh
version let's 1.0 okay 1.008
package requires uh requires 25 let's
see let's put 26 okay
now this package requires you should be
it should mean
the
earliest past package possible earliest
emacs version
that your mod will work the earlier
the better okay so if you for example if
you say emax 19 that means your mod is
gonna be compatible with emacs 1920
whatever so emax 19 is like 1990s
so
26 is three years ago
anyway so the detail anyway so let's go
on so uh tell your friend to buy a copy
if you like it buy my mod okay so and uh
here's the webpage
i'm going to create a web page for it
right now it's empty so let's just leave
that this is not part of gnu emacs
that's a standard um
standard header major mod for editing go
line code okay alpha stage no it's not
alpha
okay so
so remove that line javascript mod
history okay see that
okay
now
first of all
how am i going to do this okay so um
[Music]
yeah so um
where's the code
define derived mod okay how how am i
going to do this um
so i'm going to show you how to write a
major mod from scratch i'm writing a go
land mod um
so i can either follow my tutorial here
if you follow my tutorial you can create
a mod by yourself
uh or
i can just go freely
what do you guys think
comments okay
let's uh check video check audio check
okay so
writing a goal and mod uh yeah right
right the goal i'm how am i going to
begin so
i can follow my tutorials
that way you have the notes and step by
step instruction
or i can just do a free
free form coding while i code on the
flight um
so we want syntax coloring
we want uh font lock which is part of
syntax screen we want to define a face
not necessarily we want to
um
yeah actually that you know the easiest
way is actually just to cut for me to
copy like typically i just copy the
copy one of my exis existing mod for
example html mod or javascript mod you
know just for example
copy the whole thing
then just paste the whole thing here
then start to edit it that's kind of the
easiest way
but let's not do that okay let's do i
mean let's actually do it from scratch
okay so and do yeah let's do it from
scratch
so here is yeah yeah let's do it from
scratch so here is how to write a mod so
you want for example you want to write a
mod that syntax color
certain words like that for example this
is your own language this language is
wufam language by the way but suppose
you are writing a mod for it so here is
your source code
here is your source code and
so how do you write it you you you do it
this way okay so here is the code
so define mod golem mod uh
golem mod okay
based on
phenom mod
fundamental mod okay so
uh i'm gonna explain okay
some put the sum here so first of all
you want to say syntax highlight so
go
land
let's okay let's should i name it go
land mod or sago landmark or go mod
yeah i think it should the official name
is just go
okay let's let's just name it go okay so
rename the file
okay
exactly mod done
now search for
now replace all word golem by just go
do it do it
do it okay exactly mod
okay so first of all we want to syntax
highlight okay so what are the keywords
to syntax highlight for example for
example let's open a um
golden file
and this is too big and it's so
so here is my golan script
so
so some of the key words of golem
for example
bar
stream
okay go ahead go go to uh
go to sago land tutorial okay compile
run okay so some of the keywords are
package
import
fun
main
print ln okay for example that's some of
the keyword for this source code so we
are gonna try that okay so first of all
you want to highlight these words so
what you do
cut that so you're gonna create
the first job we're gonna do is create
the syntax highlighting okay so
function name phase so we're gonna
modify this line
so replace space by
replace space by
backslash backslash
vertical line
this will look like there so do it do it
do it do it do it okay so that's uh
that's our string copy the string
okay so this is our line so remove that
sine cosine stuff and remove the
constant stuff okay so
this is the
keywords we want to highlight okay so
now
now we can this is the main function to
define the mod let me explain okay so
you can look at the documentation
describe function
on define derived mod that's a function
to create a mod a major mod okay so here
is a documentation for define derived
mod and you can you know you can read it
yourself so but i'm just gonna go
quickly so define direct derived mod
take several arguments okay
the first argument is your mod name so
this is the command you call meta x then
type this it will activate the mod okay
then the second argument is what what
mod which mod you want it to be based on
so emacs
major mods has some
some sense of inheritance so you if you
based on c mod it will have basically
all feature features of c mod so in in
our case i'm just going to based on
fundamental mod fundamental mod is a mod
with no features at all nothing
every emacs buffer has to have a major
mod so the no there's no you cannot have
not no mod so
the closest is just fundamental mod it's
a mod without any feature so i want to
base
the
go mod on fundamental mod because we are
going to do it from completely scratch
we don't want to inherit
some features from c lan or whatever
that okay
so we are going to do
from scratch
so first argument
the mod name the command to activate the
mod the second argument the what mod is
based on the third argument
is a string
that that
that is displayed here in the mini
buffer uh status bar the what they call
what's the technical jargon emax jargon
for this spot um
you know typically mod line okay so this
line this great line
in emacs jargon is called mod line
so it shows you like what um what's the
current encoding
uh whether the file has been saved what
is the file name
what is the position of your cursor uh
you know if you go to the you know very
you know it's not intuitive idiotic you
know bot means button if you go to the
top
you know it says so it means all buffer
are shown
and here's the line number and the
column number for example if i move the
column you can see it increases
move the cursor you see so this line
this gray bar is called mod line in imax
jargon
so
and here it shows the mod name
i mean it shows a
so right now i am in xiao emax list mod
so the the short name for emax lisma for
display is
summation elise that's just my style
okay my brand
so
so that on the third line uh the the
third argument is a short name for the
for your major mod the display name for
your major mark it has no technical
significance
you see this name has no technical
significance it just
it's just a name that's displayed in the
um
in the mod line that's all so okay so
i'm just going to say some go
uh following my my personal brand name
then here's the documentation string
okay so major mod for editing go
language code okay then let's put the
date
okay
the date created okay created actually
and that's not to put a date okay so so
that's it
then here is the body
so here now is the body of the function
so when when when user calls meta x this
command when user calls this command
what are you going to do
so you know we're going to add more
lines here so in in this case we define
the variable
uh go highlight circle highlight okay
let's copy that
so we want to we we want to set the
building variable font lock defaults
into
this list okay so that means
that means tells the font lock mod
like whenever whenever user calls
go mod
it will set the font lock defaults to
to this
list okay
okay so that's it that's it that's it
for this um let's shrink so you can see
the whole file is just uh like 10 lines
of code okay
save it
go to diet
press capital l to load it okay load
cycle mod dot yeah yes okay
so it's loaded now open a new buffer
copy this thing
copy
paste okay now
now right now it's in html mod so let's
call circle mod okay it's meta x
x
go
mod okay
do it
fantastic can you see that
so
so that's how easy to write a major mod
at least for syntax curling so we have
you know part of the
you know let's go back so we have you
know we we have it
done
so let's save this
xx let's say xs
xx go
example dot go okay
geo
geo is the uh x file name extension for
gold line code okay open it
close it open it again
okay uh right now it's using the default
go mod so let's remove the default go
mod okay so let's let's do that close
that let's delete
delete the gold land
mod okay delete in fact that i think i'm
gonna delete dash
get
magic
magic transient with editor those all
are installed by magic no no good so i
don't i don't use them these days
delete them all
recursively yes yeah yes yes yes yes yes
yes delete them all so i have no
external packages installed now
so now if i open the
example go file
close it
yeah it's still highlighted because
the goal line mod code is already in
cache i suppose
okay let's restart emacs okay
do it
comments and questions
press one single key to start emax
now
make the font size 16
open a new window
okay now move this now now call
call command to start the command log
mod so you can see what i'm typing so
shrink window
put it back here
i'm gonna read the comments in a bit
okay keep the comments going
so now you can see close this
okay now open the file you can see
it's
not in golem mod anymore so now we are
totally reliant on our own golden mod
okay so let's go back let's go to the
our goal and mod definition
um
okay now we now now let's add
let's add code so that whenever a file
ends in go is is opened it will activate
circle landmark
so how do you do that you go to um
let's go to startup uh emacs tutorial
where is it now
okay go to practical emacs
uh i i can um i can easily find the code
but let's go through my tutorial because
that way you know where to find the
information
of course there are other ways you can
also search for emac list
uh manual anyway let me show you okay so
now
click on write the major mod now i want
to associate a file extension to the
major mod so what is the code
actually the code is not here but it's
in emacs init
okay because sometimes when you set up
your emacs init you can
you can
customize your emacs so that when
certain file is opened it will open in a
major mod you prefer because often there
are several major mods for the same
language so okay where is it um
so uh
what is major mod what is minor mod
customize organize init file by compile
what is hook
above lambda in hook environment
variables in e-max check os version host
name install packages install package
manually
tab space um
okay so where is it file default major
mod okay so you click on that that tells
you
how to um
associate
a file name to to automatically open in
a particular major mod okay let's go
back here
okay actually so here is the code paste
it okay
mod a list okay so now
go
change it to xsa go mod okay so that's
how you do it now the first part is a
regular expression now you might be
wondering what so the dot
is a regular expression for any
character
so
you don't want any character you want
the lead to a dot so you need the
backslash in front of it
okay
but backslash in emac list string is a
meta character meta character it's a
escape character so therefore
when you need a backslash you need to
put another backslash in front
so this part just means a little dot
and
this part is
is a idiosyncrasy to emax
this regular expression
so
that
apostrophe symbol means end of the
end of the
end of this um
end of the line okay it's similar to
regular expressions um
dollar sign normally
yeah is it dollar sign yeah normally
it's dollar sign beginning of the line
is the correct
end of the line is the dollar sign but
in e-magnesis
you also have that anyway that's
technical that's a regular expression
technical detail i have a tutorial
explaining that just search for exactly
emac this
regular expression you'll find but
anyway so here it just means any file
ending in dot go okay
okay so evaluate the buffer now go to
the
diode
open this file
close it open it
wait wait why is it not associated why
is not working
uh
at least
oh okay so okay so this line actually
needs to be outside of it
now evaluate the buffer go to diet
go to this
file open it fantastic you can see
syntax colored and if you look at the
mod line it says some go that you know
so we are using our mod
so essentially that's
that's done
now we just need to elaborate it we need
to
we need to so things to do
things to do okay
make the syntax clearing
to
have to
be more proper okay
list of all function names
list of all
keyword names you know
keyword is in a technical sense in
in compiler in programming language
compiler and password
in programming language grammar means
words like for
if
then
go to or break you know
break
wow that's typically what keyword means
in a programming language then you have
class names you have function names you
have directive names depending on
language you know you have several other
so
act so one of the tasks is to refine the
syntax coloring so that it will support
all these different names by different
color okay and constant
build in constants
variable names you know blah blah blah
and this and and string names and string
and comment okay okay then
make
string and comment
syntax color
syntax color string okay
okay
syntax color string and syntax color
common
then
write a function
to
toggle comment okay comment and comment
so we're gonna do this
and then we need to write
completion okay
what's
then we need to do
keyword completion okay
so we are going to do all these today so
how long have we been talking
uh 30 minutes okay so we're gonna do
this
so what's the comments now um
oh mold line okay that's just my
pronunciation i i i always say mod
i suppose the proper way is mode
but i'm i'm i wonder let's digress a
little bit just tiny bit i wonder
i wonder if if people um
sometimes still pronounce it as
mod instead of mode
possibly it's a alternative
pronunciation just
not as popular
so
mary and webster is a lousy dictionary
it it doesn't give a uh um
the
international standard pronunciation
symbols
okay let's digress a little bit okay let
me show you unicode
punctuation square arrow uh man simple
so
let me show you what i'm talking about
phonetics okay i'm talking about
phonetics english phonetics
international ipa okay it's called in
international phonetic association it's
a
um let's see where is it
korean
um
phonation okay
where is oh there ipa okay so here
um you know we have
a system of
letters to indicate pronunciation and
there are
there are several of such standards
the most popular used internationally is
ipa it's called ipa phonetic symbols
okay so
so but however for americans american
dictionaries they tend to use their
idiosyncratic
creation for example on the left column
you are seeing ipa symbols
in the middle is american heritage
dictionary symbols
corresponding to the ipa symbols
and on the right the third column is
merriam-webster's dictionary so you know
they are
idiosyncratic they are idiotic
so here we have
dark heart park car you know that's ipa
okay so digression
let's go to back to talk show
and let me read the comments and let's
go back to what we are talking about
today i mean so let's go back to um so
anyway yeah mode so let's see ipa um
god
show ipa okay and uh my turn javascript
refresh
show ipa
mode
okay mode
do they have you know do they have i'm
indignant you know do they have to do
they actually give a different
pronunciation for
i mean the question i want to ask is are
there people who say mold or smart
is in some region or in some country
um
regional variation i i don't know so
anyway that's a digression probably not
maybe not
so close that close that close that okay
what we do
what do we have here phonetics spelling
and or no hi
the ed
so so you're talking about diet i always
you know this this e-max feature which
you know let's open in um
let's open in in
windows you know
this is what i call folder viewers okay
now there's a technical jargon for this
for the windows this is called
file explorer okay
file explorer on the mac it's called
finder
on linux it's called file manager the
idiotic jargons you know each one has
their own particular jargons file
manager
file manager is actually the general uh
term
so on windows is called file explorer on
in emacs it's called diet or the ed you
know
i always pronounce it diet it's it's
called diet because it's a directory
editor it showed for directory editor to
add so direct directory editor that's uh
that's a
hacker's 1980s term for
for for file manager okay
so but but what i call it
folder viewer okay
that's that's the the most intuitive
to the point
uh terminology so we are into we you
know we are talking about naming of
things like that's part of the theme in
star talk show i mentioned this many
times it's
fairly important naming of things and
jargons you know because when you have
the wrong jargon when you have a jargon
you know there are many criterias
it affects communication it affects
education broadly speaking and long term
so anyway i just call it a
folder viewer okay because it's an
application it's a viewer that view
folders and files for the folder viewer
okay so open so diode okay so let's
close that let's go back to the coding
image
okay i don't think there's a variability
in the pronunciation of mode okay so i
should call it mode
okay so um yeah and the other word i
pronounced wrong
is
hate
you know not until i did i do talk show
you know in the past two years i learned
that you know
nobody there's like there's no uh region
called pronounce this hate they just
hide it's always height but it's you
know it's not it's not um
it doesn't follow the
what what what's the name alphabetic
principle anyway
so let's go back to emacs holding so
let's not digress too far so let's
go back to emacs coding so we okay so we
have actually um
a few things to do okay so here is the
code
so today we have actually written the
code to do syntax coloring of gomod now
let's see what's the next thing we want
to do let's focus on this guy's
emac this today's topic okay so now what
what's the next thing we should do
okay
color uh stream okay so let me show you
let's go back to emacs um
yeah what this is find go okay
yeah you you see this find go is my
script
you know this is a go lens script you
can see it's a go line script here
and if i open it now it doesn't have
syntax coloring because i delete it
i mean i deleted the go line go mod but
now i close it open again
you can see that some parts are syntax
colored because right right now we are
using sargo mod
but you see is it's not complete okay so
here all these are comments they are not
colored properly
and the strings
strings are already colored properly but
not comments okay let's do them let's
fix them one one thing at a time okay so
let's uh fix them close that yeah
exactly is smart close that
close that
so
add syntax
color common okay so
in order to add comment um let's go back
to how to write the major mark in order
to add a comment we need to here color
comments okay so this page i show you
how but essentially let's do this
quickly let me
[Music]
yeah okay so
i need to explain this um
writing a major mod you know it's a bit
complicated because it involves all
these systems in imax
you know if you read this page you'll
show you how to do it but it involves
the font lock mod for example the font
lock we haven't really explained what
exactly it does
um so what what do i
and you
and that also involves syntax table okay
which is explained here syntax table so
in order to
create
syntax color for comment what we need to
do
is to add a entry for a syntax table
let's just do it directly so i'm not
going to explain the whole
the whole thing um
you know let's just
get this
to work okay yeah
um you know so if you want to get the
details
read all these sections you know spend a
week or you know
spend an hour you can write the uh mod
already then
other details you can read them okay so
now let's add syntax curling for
um
for comments okay so the easiest way is
to open
[Music]
to look at my existing mod okay
because i have code there already
so
so open javascript mod search for syntax
syntax table that's what we need okay
so
just copy it
and paste it here
and we also need to copy that line
paste it here okay then then i'm going
to explain
so define a variable
go mod syntax table okay syntax table
for circle mod okay then
then you need to set the variable
uh set the variable let's let's do it
from scratch okay so let me show you
how this is done
so essentially syntax table is
so here's the code okay we are we are
defining a syntax table so what is
syntax table in e-max every character is
given a class for example you have the
class of
function names function names and
variables variable names in programming
languages the jargon is identifier okay
function names function function names
variable names
um you know they are identified so you
need to define what kind of characters
belong to the identifier for example can
you have question mark in a function
name can you have exclamation the band
in a function name or can you have dash
or can you have low
line you know dash
dash
or
snake
case
you know depending most languages do not
allow you to have a dash in identifier
so anyway so syntax table is in imax it
assigns a character to to each of the
two to to a class
okay so it basically classify all
characters so you have so what classes
are there you have the
letters class letters class like english
letters or chinese or japanese or
russian alphabet you know letter class
you have punctuation class punctuation
class are all these plus sign minus sign
slash question mark colon you know
so let's go there okay so let's see
let's go there and you can see syntax
table
so you have okay so here are the
different classes you have white space
characters you have word which are
basically letters you have symbol
which means
characters that can be used in
identifier
but
that is not a word so for some languages
you can underscore as part of the
identifier
then you have punctuation class you have
string delimiter
then you have brackets left and right
brackets there are several type of
brackets you know square
brackets
and so on and you have
you can also define a class for common
begin and common in
so that's syntax table and syntax table
is used um
okay i'm i'm going to slow so it is is
syntax table is used
for
syntax coloring comments and string okay
so let's just uh code it okay so so in
golan what's a common in golan
uh the golan command is
slash slash okay they support two type
of comments so let's for now let's just
do one of them so how do you add how do
you add the slash slashes comments so
let's go here c
so syntax table now let's go back to um
color common okay
so
i'm just gonna do it quickly okay
copy the code here
so syntax table so what uh
yeah so that that okay see
this is a bit complex actually so
lengthy
so you know we are creating a syntax
table here and we are and by default
they they have a fundamental they have a
default syntax table for all the
200 you know 700 000 characters in
unicode
each character belongs to a class
so
you don't need to define them unless you
want to modify some of the syntax table
and the syntax table in e-max is a
fairly complex so that's why you see all
these cryptic things so let me let me
let me explain one of them for example
for example this line this this means
i want the plus sign the character plus
sign to belongs to the syntax table of
dot what what is a dot dot is a
punctuation class okay so let's go back
to syntax table
so you can see you have these different
classes of syntax
and each syntax are represented by a
short code short code so you can see
dollar sign i mean the
dot is right there that means it's
punctuation so this line
means i want the plus sign to be a
punctuation okay so that's what it means
okay so but for now let's delete the
let's
it's fairly complex okay so right now
it's just like that okay
um
okay define syntax table okay
that this is uh
this
will make slash slash to be the
beginning of common character until
end of line that's the end of comment
and what are what are this part that's
that's again some short code
to
tell emacs
you know the golden comment now anyway
you have to read here it's it's fairly
complex okay so anyway so now we added a
syntax table
uh let's see what else i need to add
color comments syntax table
yeah you need to say you don't you don't
need to say yeah okay so that's it
so now evaluate our code you know we we
just run our code run current file now
let's go back to open the golan
file
open it
now add a comment
okay now slash slash
something common fantastic it's working
now let's go back to the
go line go land
find
you know file script
fantastic all the comments are now
colored you see
so this script is my golan
find script like
comparable to unix script so find
strings in author
can be your list of strings okay
so you can see
comments are not colored
okay now that's one thing fixed now
let's fix another thing so
comments are now colored is string color
the string is also colored correctly
uh what what else okay
syntax color string
done
syntax color comma done write a function
to toggle comment okay now we need to
write a function to toggle comment
for example this sample gold line file
normally by default in emacs you have
the command called
common dream okay
so in emacs by default you have the
command called common dream
uh and the default key is meta
semicolon okay in any mod you can press
that key that will create a comment
but here
let's try it it doesn't work so where is
my meta key
you see it doesn't work
so
so that's why i want to write it so that
when i can i can press a key and you'll
just add
slash slash something and if i my cursor
is already on comment you'll just
uncomment it okay so that's what we are
going to do now so close that closet
uh
so write the function to toggle comment
okay so let's do it
let's say
code begin okay
so our code right now is just
20 lines
so write a command to toggle comment so
i don't remember so i have to look up
look up
my own
tutorial
so common command
very easy by the way
so let's just do okay all you have to do
is this okay copy it
so in the define derived mod in the body
here
let's just add
that okay common start slash slash
common end nothing okay
qualify i mean predefine the code
run the code
go to
the ad
go to the sample file go line go line
file open it
now
press the key
there it is comment
fantastic okay now press the key again
it it will remove the comment line now
you see my cursor is right here now do
it
fantastic now let's try it again do it
do it do it fantastic now if they are
close do it do it do it do it
or you or
or
and do a
select them
you know select the two lines do it
fantastic now we have the common feature
save the file close it close it now back
to the gold line
circle line mod so we are
writing a major mod and we are doing
well it's already uh
you know it's kind of like already
working now what other features i need
let's see um yeah so what what other
then
done
keyword completion okay before we do
keyword completion we need to get all
the keywords
so what are the keyword for gold
landmark
oh god i don't
um
so now
we need to collect all
building words of gold line mod now
that's not i mean that's gonna take 10
minutes or 20 minutes because then
you need
if you are lucky you can find somewhere
online where people have already
collected maybe in vs code or maybe
somewhere
otherwise you have to kind of manually
compile it from you know maybe from
golan grammar okay let's see if we can
so let's go back to my golan tutorial
let's see let's go to the golan spec
okay so this is the gopro language
specification okay so let's see if they
have
i don't think they have a collection of
keywords usually they don't say that in
in
in the programming language spec
you know they do have a collection of
keywords you see
here but these are just
these are technical definition meaning
of keywords they do not include building
function names
which makes them kind of not much useful
so but anyway
so let's see let's uh let's add a
function
define bar
okay go line keywords okay initial value
neo
uh
keywords of golan okay then you have to
the
you have to set okay
set
magnify
so these uh show
those are spaces okay now call command
space to new line okay
now turn wait what
call command start space to new line
but
they don't um
do it again right
do it again
why does it okay select it
call it
open
code okay cut
paste it here okay
hide the space okay so we got the list
of keyword here now each one of them we
need to make a string we want to make it
a
list of strings so
call this command
okay so now they all become string and
we can
so that
okay so that then we can
compact it
make a list
okay uh quote the list okay cut it
paid put it here okay
so we got the golan keywords
now we need to turn these keywords
this a bunch of keywords into a regular
expression like that okay so that so
that we can give it to the font lock
no go doesn't have a go to
okay so
12 32 so we
been talking for how long
one hour okay we've been talking for a
while already so we need to make this
list of keywords to a regular expression
so how do you do that you go back to the
syntax coloring
here i show you how okay
um
so we got keywords then we need to
uh make them into a regular expression
so
what we do is
core
rejects opt
list of keywords okay
remove that okay so this part
then
this is what we need okay so
this line let's uncomment that
delete that
let's move that line down okay
so
now go
okay delete that okay so now we
have golden keywords
copy this
so instead of this
you know instead of that string
delete that string
then put that there okay so
so this rejects ops will take a list of
strings and turn them into a official
regular expression one single string
okay so for example describe function
here is a documentation for rejects up
okay so
okay so go highlights let's see
let's try it okay
now before we try let's go to the sample
code
let's see
okay the sample code doesn't
tell us much let's go to
um
okay this is this is my goal and script
for doing find a grip find text so you
can see
the keyword constant is not colored you
see
constant is not colored and
let's see
so constant is not colored
now do we have constant here
there it is so there is constant so once
we run the code
then
we reopen this file the constant should
be colored okay
let's do it
so
but before we do it let's double check
okay that's good
okay eva buffer
okay now go to the file close it reopen
now the constant is still not colored
close it reopen
so make sure we are using circle mod yes
it is you can see in the mode line
uh so why is it not
oh yeah so um
okay i think
i think i got extra pair of paren maybe
try again evolve the buffer
close this file reopen it
no
yeah okay so let's double check
a list okay
each element so this should be at least
each element is a
yeah okay font lock function name okay
that should be it he round the buffer
rejects opt
okay he round the buffer
go here close it reopen
now it's not cons it's not working let's
restart emacs
do
so let's go back to emacs
go back to the um
cassady keywords
set keywords
rejects up keywords
right that's right
uh and the syntax table okay
eval the buffer
okay open a new buffer
go to the find script
turn the
message buffer to see if there's any
errors here
evolve the buffer go mod
okay
now go to the go line
script
it says fundamental why is it not
loading
okay now manually loaded exa
go
mod okay but
why is it not automatic
because we added this line
anyway so now
now it's now it's okay syntax coding is
broken so we we got something wrong here
syntax curling is broken probably
because our nesting structure is wrong
so let's make sure this is correct
um
yeah maybe yeah yeah
let's see rejects ops describe function
[Music]
circle keywords
okay it's a string
and
i don't think that'll help
but
no
is there any error oh there it is
okay error
during redisplay
gtlog function
signaled invalid function rejects up
why is it in invalid function
oh okay so yeah so we need to actually
we need to evaluate this part
now this
yeah i'm pretty sure that's the problem
let's try it first okay run the code
go to go line script
close it reopen it
still doesn't work
oh yeah because
yeah you then you need
not apostrophe but
but the you need the back tick eval the
buffer
close the golan script reopen it
fantastic now you it color syntax color
you can see
the the mode line
circle mod
and you have syntax coloring then you
have the syntax scaling of the word
constant so our code worked
so
what is the issue
you see
the issue is
disp complexity okay so you can see
there's a backtick there's a comma
those are kind of unusual syntax in lisp
you know you might think normally this
is all parenthesis not true because you
have this special
apostrophe or backtick or sometimes
comma
they what they do is that they
affect the evaluation of the this
expression so for example if you have a
list let me give you a simplest example
okay uh
let's say set okay
emax is smart
set okay set x to three okay evaluate it
and now describe variable
x
it says three right
now
now if you create a list
x
two okay
um
yeah
because this is um for example here is a
list
if you evaluate it that's just x2 x is
not evaluated that's because when that's
because you have the apostrophe which is
actually equivalent to that a part
apostrophe is a shorthand for
for these okay so these two are actually
equivalent
yeah because if i evaluate this
oh okay so this um
yeah how do i explain this um
quote
this
basically when you have an apostrophe in
front that means do not evaluate each
element
now it
and it's equivalent to i'm pretty sure
it's equivalent to this okay can we can
we do a equal let's
this is actually
let's see
new
um
do i explain this
uh
basically when you have a apostrophe in
front it is equivalent to
let's see let's see if i can do this
evaluate neo
uh it's complex because then there is
several
forms of equality
now i don't think i got it right
actually
let's do yeah because then there's a
complexity of cons cons
okay so now you can see these two are
identical okay
this and these these two lines are
identical because if i evaluate it it
returns true
now
so what so so
so that also means let's let's do it
again okay so that also means
these two are also identical okay
you see it says true in the mini buffer
now
so we are getting closer to explain
the
the quote okay so let's um can we get
the quote to actually show
um
anyway so
yeah i'm gonna
so
that's too bad you know i
i wanted to be able to explain this in a
concise and clear manner like off the
bat but i
i get i get confused uh i cannot
so anyway so the problem is with this
okay so how do you how do you
how do you get over it you know um
yeah i mean so if you are actually
coding this so if you are reading my
tutorial you are you're probably
you know
you may you may likely to run into the
same problem so i need to
um
get you know i need to explain it
somewhere
but if you just copy you know if if if
you just copy and paste the code then
you don't have that problem you just
copy and paste the code for my tutorial
okay so
a little bit complexity there and that
that complexity is inherent
in
these languages it's not just um
you know it's not
you know it's part of the this language
complexity so anyway
so so far our code works um let's shrink
let's look at the whole file okay so
that's about
um how many lines of code let's copy it
new buffer paste it
30 lines of code okay 20.
if you shrink the you know string thing
click clean them 20 lines of code so
um
okay so that's our major mod what what
what else um
so now we got
so we got all the keywords
of gold language but that's not enough
okay
so
so we got all the keywords of gold
language but they are also let's see
keywords there's also function method
names we should
ideally
you know syntax coloring is kind of
flexible depending on you know which
editor
and who programmed it
you know
you could say i could say you know the
way it is right now it's done
uh you got common colored you got string
colored you got
keywords you know quote unquote the
specific meaning of keywords colored
that's kind of all you need but
so it depends on you know the editor or
the whoever coded it but for me i i also
wants to code
opioid building packages for example
for example um os is a building package
i mean it's
part of golan
and uh
so i do want
building packages and building methods
you know of that package to be also
colored
uh but
okay i'm i'm i'm now kind of
out of focus uh let's
because there are more things to do
there there are more things to do
that is more valuable
instead of instead uh you know talking
about
this okay so we so so we got keyword
colored what else um
we got keyword colored is there anything
else i want to do at least in this
tutorial about
coloring of words
no i think that's it okay
let's see
can you evaluate individual expression
no
uh you can do that in this you can also
well
that usually so the answer to that
question depends on the language
typically
for functional languages
which means they are usually based on
expressions every expression is a unit
you can do that
so
in this in ufo mathematica
in
maybe haskell too i don't know haskell
so if so you can you can have emacs you
can i can modify my code so that
i can evaluate just that part of
expression because
why does that work because in function
languages you know it's not
it's not intermixed you know like you
have a unit that can be independent by
itself it it makes sense
but in golan
c c plus plus java these kind of
languages it doesn't work
because
because for example
we are looking at golden you know
you have lots of statements you know
statements they are not expressions by
themselves um
so that doesn't make sense you know
like
that that that i think that answer your
question
so it depends on the language
it's not about emac
this oh for e max this yes of course you
can for example uh you know
that's
three plus two
you know let's say three plus let's say
let's say uh x again
so casa e max v smart set q x okay set q
x equals to 2
then
let's say uh message
x okay
now if i
if i run the whole thing
it or print two
but
let's say three okay now if i just run
this code i can just run this code by by
calling
you know c
you see the mini buffer that says three
uh wait why is it three
let's say four okay let's do it again
i just call command you see it's zero
three because i haven't evaluated that
part it's three because we we evaluated
to we set it to three before
so right now i'm just evaluating this
part without evaluating that part but i
can evaluate the whole thing
yeah and what's going on evaluate the
whole thing your own type of argument
stream p neo what the
anyway yeah you can you can easily
evaluate you know if you just go to emac
this this that's very basic
that's a very basic emac this okay you
can evaluate
a region or a buffer or a file or a
function or just the last expression
okay i think i think that's it for today
so
so in summary
so we have written a mod
that essentially
you know actually that's what i need
that does what i wanted
and
we got a syntax coloring
we got comment
function we got common coloring we got
string coloring
then we need completion okay we also
need completion
so back to writing a major amount you
you need uh yeah keyword completion
you need indentation but we don't need
indentation because there is a go format
uh
let me show you okay so for example
let's
let's combine this you see here's a
source code here is a
go source code actual real world source
code make a backup now let's say we
change this block let's just screw it
just like that and let's say we add a
lot of space here you see
now we save it
close it
copy the file name
start e-shell
go
format okay that's a bldn command in
come with golden okay then give the file
do it
yeah
okay i i screwed up the syntax so now
open the file again okay this should be
so if you want to do that you need a
comma okay so let's do it
add a comma to them okay
save it close it
run the go format find dot go do it
okay there's another syntax zero
expected that found that okay open the
file
uh
dot okay let's just do that
save it close it
run the file again do it
ah
line seven
character fifteen nine seven so it's
this part when
nine seven character fifteen
yeah that's a go syntax issue let's go
back to go syntax package import because
there are two
uh syntax oh yeah so not comma you need
the semicolon okay so replace
comma by semicolon
okay now we have the proper syntax save
it close it
now open it again now remember it's one
single line and here we um well they
already
fixed you know here we have a lot big
space here okay close it
run go from what format do it
uh
it didn't change the file because okay
go format you need to say change the
file okay so
go format help
yeah creative file help system cannot
find the file go format dash help okay
there it is
so you want to save the file
uh
say w okay so let's call the command
again
go format dash w
do it
okay
open the file
fantastic you see it changed it it
reformatted your whole file to
a kind of the standard go format file so
you can see our giant space has been
removed so
that is
go format a tool that comes with go
language
so that means
when we are writing a major mod for
golan we do not need to write features
to reformat code such as indentation
for example uh you know we don't have to
because
you know for example you know
you know save it close it
kogo format
reopen it you see it just fix it for you
hold for the whole file
so you have to do is in emacs you just
need to assign a key
to call the shell command go format
which we which i can do but anyway today
is too long and i'm now getting
uh over the face
pay for my haircut okay thank you guys
uh if you like my stuff you know pay me
okay pay me give me a coffee to drink
bye guys
so we shut down in two minutes
so let me just write down what we talked
about and screen up okay
so um
so go language
tutorial that's my tutorial go check it
out okay it's you can learn
i like golem very much i think it's one
of the best language you should learn
golan power xiao wufam language
um
golan powershaw wufang language and
let's say another one maybe python you
know the these are the
except gold acceptable fan language
these are the most practical and you can
get a job for them you know golan is
fantastic simple very simple so check
out my tutorial
and wufang language you might want to
learn it because
for
if you want if you don't just want to be
you know if you don't want just be a
programmer you know if you want to be a
mathematician no physics and engineer
engineering you you want to study
wolfram language
so so check them out check out my
tutorials and buy my script buy my stuff
okay javascript
javascript my javascript tutorial
javascript in depth is the most
hardcore
and most complex of all my tutorials
it's the most complete most technical
detailed most hardcore
tutorial of all my programming language
tutorials
i spent three years writing for it full
time or basically and
but
javascript is not a good language
despite all the
fancy features and becoming the number
of basically it's not the most popular
language it's not
a language i can recommend but however
you need it just because every website
is between javascript
uh and the phone apps you know basically
that means nineteen ninety percent of
all applications ever used by human
animals that's javascript
so gold line is great powershell is the
new
shell that that i'm in my opinion is the
future
potentially you can you know you replace
smash
you know bash is still there because
it's like open source powershell by the
way is also completely open source
but it's resisted resisted by the linux
type of people because it's by microsoft
but technically speaking i mean if we
ignore social issues and focus only on
the technicality the the you know
technical aspects of the language
powershell is a magnitude superior than
bash okay
a magnitude superior and in fact it's
possibly even superior than python and
even beyond the
applicability
i mean as far as what the language can
do for practical uses
i would even claim
it's possible i don't i don't i you know
don't
i'm not 100 sure
but
it's possible powershell technically
speaking
is even more
powerful and has wider applicability
than python why why do i say that
because powershell is
essentially a wrapper of the.net
infrastructure and net is
supremely powerful.net is beyond python
okay very nice get out of the
dot net is like the java jvm okay.net
you have all the essentially the entire
microsoft windows is
running around.net
so powershell is essentially kind of a
shell wrapper to the net you can
call.net functions that's
kind of how it works okay so powershell
and even ignore that powershell the
syntax the documentation
the ease you know the the readability is
just uh it's it's just a magnitude
beyond bash okay a magnitude better than
bash or whatever unix uh bag
so anyway yeah that's it for today thank
you guys bye
okay mo wufang language next time yeah
because i done so many videos on wolfham
language in the past two weeks
so you know
it's you know that's why i'm doing emac
at least today take a break
so of course i'll come back to wufang
language
uh but i probably will not continue from
yesterday doing that javascript because
wolfham language you know this
i want you know i need to get to do more
geometry you know you can see this video
it's a
dynamic geometry or this you know this
hyperbolic uh
polyhedron you know you can do a lot of
dynamic stuff not just shell scripting
okay
so
so i need to uh you know so there's a
lot to come for film language in my talk
show
uh okay that's it for today so bye guys
i'm just gonna shut down
[Music]