hello guys welcome to another episode of
Star Talk show so we are going to code
emac lisp
uh we are going to code a major mod for
python a python major mod from scratch
um if you search the web just search for
Sardi uh emac beasts how to write a
major mod I already have a tutorial here
in fact I did a video last year on
writing a Golan mod from scratch
okay so we are going to follow the
tutorial I'm gonna do it from scratch
and I'm gonna show you how to do it live
but if you want to read you know this
old tutorials about how to write a major
mod okay and
okay so today's talk show writing a
major mod python emac beast and last
time about you know uh 2022 November
10th we we did a video starting to write
it but we didn't write the major mod
but we expand
why do I want to do it so anyway it's
gonna be focused today so
um hope you guys emacs fans will get
used out of this
uh it's pretty easy okay so let's start
okay so let's write a major mod from
scratch
um so let's start a emac beast code
okay so actually uh let's see new file
something save it as XX let's say
um
let's say python Mod Dot El okay so here
is a file uh date okay
let's see so copy it post the link here
link it so you can go through it easily
so a major mod major mod
for python okay if you have common and
questions posted okay love to see your
comments
Crazy Frog I don't know what that means
I definitely made good use of your otmax
major mod tutorial oh great fantastic
okay major mod for python uh on the pink
window you can see all my command cores
as I type or move Cruiser or whatever
you can see all the command names and
the keystroke on the left I'm using a
vorac keyboard layout this is Xposed
expose keyboard you can search and find
it on my website because Audi exposed
Saudi keyboard blog you'll find it one
of my favorite ergonomic keyboard
okay and okay so a major mod so
right so write the major Mark you know I
uh so I don't remember so let's go to
um let's just go to the tutorial so the
to write the major amount the first
thing you want to do is syntax coloring
so uh so for example uh so let's see so
this is the code this is basically all
there is to it
so we want to first of all a mod name
let's say some python mod so change that
to
uh
saw python okay change change okay so
the first thing you want to Define is
highlight now in emac this there is no
package or March there is no namespace
so every function in your package in
your list code must begin with a
prefix so in our case it's a python okay
for this example so some python uh so
I'm gonna explain everything okay so
first of all you define these keywords
that you want to highlight
in writing a major mod to to the first
thing you want to do there are several
things you want to do for a major mod
for programming language syntax current
that's the most most common and basic
feature you need then you
in order to do syntax highlight
highlighting highlighting there
two major ways
vast majority of major mod for
programming languages they use the font
lock mod so font lock Mark mod is kind
of a library that
you can call to to to syntax color
the buffer so if you are writing a
programming language major mod you
usually want to use Font like mod the
other way is to go low level so you
actually so that means for every string
of text you use regular expression to
find that keywords or whatever then you
call then you add a um
you add a string properties text
properties it's called text properties
you can see here okay so you add text
properties basically it means you know
that from position to certain position
you add a text property to that text in
the buffer so that emac supports that
feature so for example like this put
text property begin that's a position or
integer then then you specify your phone
lock phase you specify what color or
background color or underline or both
things like that so again in summary two
ways to do
uh syntax coloring there's another way
actually but there's another another way
is overlay highlight anyway for writing
a major mod for programming language two
primary ways one is
you use the font lock mod which is like
a library okay a vast majority of a
major mod do that or you can go a low
level use text properties which means
you use a regular expression lots of
them to search you know particular word
or phrase then add a coloring property
like font size font to use color
background color for one color Okay so
you know so this is low level not many
people do that so most people just use a
front lock mod
okay so scene so for a major mod the
things you want to do is syntax coloring
that's one primary thing then then you
want to uh color the comments and the
stream okay so for example let's see
let's go to python uh wait let's go to
let's go to a python file okay
I hope I can do this in uh in in 40
minutes uh very
um condensed okay so here is a python
file this is the default Emax python mod
so you can see there are some comments
and you can see here is a string and
here are common so you also need to
color common in string okay so that's
that's part of syntax coloring but in
the emac system you have to do them
separately kind of okay so I'm gonna
explain everything
so then so syntax cutting that's one
thing you want to do then you need
keyword completion of course very
um useful for example in in Python if I
say p Okay so
let's see
control meta I to complete and
wait do I still control meta I
now
completion a point yeah the the default
python mods
they don't have that for some reason but
anyway so keyword completion is is one
of the most useful thing uh you want
you know the default I would say most
building emacs programming language mods
they don't have
a very good keyword completion so you
have to install external packages such
as icomplete and others but anyway if
you code emac this the default emac this
mod has a kind of okay key uh completion
so
keyword completion is something you a
feature you need for your major mod very
useful so you need to write that
okay and the
that is almost that's a that's a
fundamental so if you got the syntax
coloring done and you if you got the
keyword completion done oh and another
thing is that you want a comment command
so for example in Python 2 comment or
uncomment a line that is also very
critical so these three things you need
to do syntax cutting
keywords including string and the
comment that's one thing
common command that's also critical
essential okay then keyword completion
you know completion completing function
names building function names keywords
for each Loop while loop you know things
like that so you can just type while and
you'll complete you know um
and preferably with a template you know
with all the arguments you know so these
three things that's the most important
then there are other things like such as
pressure key to look up the
documentation you can have that in
others okay so let's start you know
let's let's uh let's try to quickly um
get uh things to work
uh what what and what did I just close
the bunch of uh suffering replace it's
gonna replace go okay so so now we start
to write the mod so we are we are going
to use the font lock mod font lock font
lock mod is uh loaded by default so you
don't have to require it
okay so first of all you specify a
variable that says what kind of word you
want to find highlight so for for
example so in the python case
uh let's go to let's see what are some
of the keywords
um
okay so let's let's see so keywords
import you want to color okay uh import
and
import and the dev try except Global
okay let's start with those
so so
the
so you want to Define this variable and
you want to say import and this is a
regular expression okay import
uh Dev
try let's see let's copy that
try except
return so those are all uh important
keywords global
4 in
okay let's just say that and
so okay
so first of all you need to Define this
a variable and this variable needs to be
a list of least like in this format okay
this is so important Okay so
so let's just say for now so
each element first of all the first part
is a it's a conspire
you know I'm not gonna explain just fine
just follow this syntax okay so maybe I
can make this easier to read this way so
this part is a regular expression and we
want to color them with uh this this
uh this face so this this this variable
fun log function name phase is building
it's from the front lock mod so this
variable basically Define a bunch of
colors that is used for function okay
so let's just say that
um so actually many of these are not
functions they are keywords Okay so
yeah so anyway so let's just go with
that for now and this part we want a
constant phase let's just read and it's
just not using okay
so we got a bunch of keywords and here
is the part where you define the major
mod so you can use the function to
define derived mod and give uh you know
you can look up the documentation
describe function then you'll see the
full uh documentation for how do you use
this define derived mod okay
uh but basically here is your mod name
and which mod you want to paste your mod
from so Fender mod fundamental mod is a
mod that's that has no features
so you can base it on fundamental mods
or more typically you want to base it um
uh program mod it's called
let's see
program mod I forgot what's the name
I have explained Nation here so how to
write keywords so if you go to syntax
coloring then you have a fundamental mod
uh there is one called Pro program smart
I forgot I forgot so let's you know one
easy way to find find what it should be
is just go to this swipe function python
mod okay so you can jump to you see
here's a python documentation just jump
to the source code you can see
the source code they also called define
derived mod oh yeah prog mod so they so
the python mod is based on top of the
prog mod the Pio Gmod doesn't do much
anyway
so anyway so you can base your mod close
close you can based mod your mod on uh
um prog mod which is like the basic no
feature mod for programming languages
and here the third argument is a short
stream that is the display string for
your mod for example I'm right now
inside emagly smart but you can see here
over here the mod name is summation
e-lisp so that's a short display string
for your mod so here you can say so
let's say I want to
you know for my personal brand I use the
summation
let's just say that so when I when I met
her x sub python mod this string will
show up in the in the button mod line
okay
so major amount so here's the
documentation major mod for editing uh
Python language code okay and let's put
the version here okay
so that's a string and uh
and let's uh
okay and that's it so right now this mod
is just one single line and this is how
it works so you all you have to do is
set the variable font loud defaults
that's building that's from the front
lock package all you have to do is just
set that value to to this python
highlight you that we have defined here
okay that's it
so this is all for a major mark this is
the most simple you know major amount so
let's evaluate it okay now emacs knows
that now let's open the python uh
code
so let's see let's uh open some pattern
code copy it close close
okay now let's open new buffer
and paste it save it as xxxtest dot py
okay
okay now right now because start p y by
default it loads the python mod you can
see in the mount line here
but we want some pattern mods so what we
do is just met IX now let's call XA
python mod
now look at this uh common you know look
at the color carefully see how they
changes okay do it
done
so you can see you see we don't have the
syntax coloring for comment note we have
syntax coloring for string oh well for
string it already does because we based
on WE based on our mod on fog mod so
park mod by default either it colors you
know the kind of very common
Syntax for Strings so we got the color
info string but we don't have a color
info comment but however you see this
in
you see that's the word in that's got
colored you know several words got
colored
find in
not find but in import
you know and let's say
okay we got string four you see four in
you see we got syntax coloring and
return so that is the most basic okay
very easy very easy to do but we got
some errors look at look at this for
example in coding but part of the word i
n is color blue it's hard to see but you
can maybe see like that
you see and also this input you know
input i n is colored blue that's
incorrect and this format the word
format for is colored so that's
incorrect
Okay so
yeah but we got you know this is almost
like uh 50 of the things we need
comments and questions
okay so let's go on so we got that so
now
uh so now we need to so this is just a
test what we we actually need to do is
now to collect all the keywords of the
Python language and collect all function
names things like that
to color them properly
okay so you know in a typical language
you have variable names colored in one
way variable names function names
keywords keywords are typically part of
the syntax such as for Loop if statement
while loop you know um
so function names variable names
keywords then you typically also
sometimes you have types you know you
have a different color for
type specifications such as string
object class things like that
so we dive into detail to now we next so
now next thing we dive into detail about
so so right now what we need to do is to
find actually find a list of all
Python language
um
functional keyword names okay so there
are many ways to do that
one way is you look up the python
documentation
okay so I have it somewhere here I mean
python on Windows
come with a documentation in the let's
open it
yeah
let's open it
okay so on Windows python documentation
comes with this kind of standard
uh see this is called CM chm format
that's a good tip to know so you don't
have to search the web so the python
documentation you you know you can look
up the language reference and try to
grab you know a list of all the keywords
and building identifiers and function
names that's one way to do it okay you
look up look you look at the language
spect okay the other way is to kind of
cheat
we what we do is we just look at
building python mod for example
describe function python jump to the
source code and let's just start to
search for you know see if they have a
list of word uh
usually but but often
half of the time it's hard to find
because
you know you can code emac this in so so
many ways so sometimes you don't see at
least a
you know words at all and usually
okay here so for example here we see a
list of uh python fun log keywords so
these are so called keywords meaning
that they are words that's part of the
syntax of python but they are not
function names they are not variable
names okay
so keyword usually have a kind of a
special specific meaning to the
in the context of writing a compiler so
these are called keywords
and you also have reserved words
reserved words are like keywords but
that are not currently used currently
defined okay so you got keywords here
then you got uh what is python 3.5 pep
the python Community like they like this
pep they have this pep thing okay so we
got a keywords we got what they what are
these symbols start
okay these are kind of these are just
like function names okay
okay so you know this is gonna be uh
this you know
if you're gonna write the python mod
this is you know tip for any language
this will take an hour or more of or
even few days to gather all the you want
to make them correct you know you you
want to determine just what type of
words are there function keywords you
know depending on a language you know
functional language is Java JavaScript
they all have very different ideas of
what's a keyword what's a you know
function name and things like that so
this step is you know take some research
usually you you have to
find all the different types of keywords
and
and gather them okay so here these are
basically here in the python case this
uh as far as I know these are building
function uh not really
uh
let's see do they have length uh let's
search for length no okay
anyway so you have these words you need
sometimes
okay so then you have these words these
are you know all these are kind of
keywords
in Python 2 standard era okay so okay
that's one way to grab all these names
um
let me just get the basics okay so the
basics yeah so I want this okay
so let's start to code them
so I want this kind of
oh they also have some commentary look
forcing none and through our list listed
as keywords in on Python 3 dark but
since they are also qualified they also
qualify as constants they are Quantified
like that in order to keep found lock
consistent between Python versions
okay whatever
uh python fairly complex okay so let's
for now our goal is just to grab some of
these words okay
don't worry about too much about
anything else
okay so some of these we want and we
also want some of these okay
uh
mad
foreign
okay so we got a bunch of words now
uh
okay so now we need to kind of classify
which uh which which group are which
let's just try to do it quickly without
being correct okay
so some python 2
okay I don't care about python 2.
uh
okay what do you do what to do
um
let's just okay so
so first of all
you got a bunch of let's let's just
classify them into two groups okay so
let's just say one is keywords
okay such as you know these these and
the other one let's say is underscore
words
no I don't know what's the proper name
for this kind of thing import you know
underscore underscore module underscore
uh are they they are constants I believe
uh not really but they are
variable names with a specific meaning
in Python
so for now just for for our purposes
let's just say let's just group them
into low-lying words okay so we have two
so basically now the problem once you
gather the bunch of words and you
classified you know so you want to you
want to generate this regular expression
you don't want to do it manually because
that's you know too much problem so
let's let's do that okay
so first thing is you want
um
okay so let's copy this
so you want let's say
and let's remove that this is empty okay
actually so
okay so here is keywords okay
set Q keywords uh actually
so python keywords okay so let's just
say
God okay so let's just say all of these
okay
so we want to okay so let's look at my
tutorial
because I
okay let's magnify
writing a mod for language that has
hundreds of keywords indeed so what is
the way to do it okay here is already a
template yeah here's how you do it okay
uh
uh yeah okay let's
let's do this
so this thing this whole thing needs to
be a list okay so we got a here we got a
list of keywords okay
cut it
and paste it here
okay and this we don't need okay so we
now we got a list of keywords
each one each element is a string
and now we do the same thing
for a list of
low-lying words
okay
and that will be
this group okay actually that belongs to
keywords basically there
okay so here is a bunch of low-lying
words that's right put it here
syntax clean clean syntax okay
so now we got a bunch of keywords and a
bunch of low-lying words now
our job is to
properly create these
example highlights
to feed it into
the
as the value of unlock defaults okay
so these highlights needs to be a okay
so let's see how we do it
there it is okay
so now the problem is you got the list
of keywords a string you want to turn
them into one single regular expression
you know okay how do you do that that is
done by rejects opt okay let's describe
function look at the documentation
rejects UPS okay here's the syntax
returns a regular expression to match a
string in the least strings okay
so here's the syntax okay
so
we just need to so we need uh here is
the
sound python words okay that's a
variable
I mean that's at least the words and you
have options so uh the the second
argument uh optional parent let's say we
don't care about it okay
you can you can read the dot later but
let's just say for now so rejects up
this will generate a bunch of regular
expression cut we're gonna put it
here
so
so I actually put it
you know replacing these this part okay
put it there it's gonna generate uh wait
okay it's this part is gonna generate a
bunch of uh I mean one regular
expression okay
and now let's let's clean it
okay
then this regular all these words we
want them to be colored with
uh
function name no we don't want function
name we want the keyword name okay so
let's
go to the major amount tutorial
here is when you want to look up font
lock
mod so in order to do syntax coloring we
are using the
hold on a second we are using the build
Library phone lock mod and so we need to
understand
about a little bit about fun like mod
okay so fun lock mod it defines a bunch
of uh building variables okay and also
defines a bunch of face
you can read it and you under you have a
very good understanding so right now we
just want to know what are the building
phase in front lock mod so here they are
fun log mods faces so you they are
building so you can use it so now this
is what we want from our keyword phase
okay
so here instead of founder function name
phase let's just save unlock keyword
face paste that's good
now
by the way this this value is a bit
complicated when you do a major mod you
might get a lot errors because this
the value for the font lock defaults
is a list of a part is a is at least a
particular form
so each element of the list may also
require to be a list
okay and sometimes they needs to be a
function or string there are several
Alternatives so when you when you try to
create this value for the fun log
defaults variable
you might so you you want to be careful
okay either either just follow whatever
I have under my tutorial or you just
want to be careful because it can get
very complex quickly okay
so for example let's see the structure
so
first of all it's at least
then the first element is a pair is a
cost pair so you can see conspire is is
parenthesis with a dot in the middle so
conspire has two things the first part
is a regular expression which this
generates the second part is the
uh the face
the face you want to use okay that's one
thing now
we want to do another one okay so copy
that paste it here delete that so the
second part will be the low-lying words
okay
here
and and the low line words what kind of
uh color you want let's say
uh variable name phase warning phase
let's say building phase okay
now this this one lock faces those are
building variables they you know they
are predefined how how some string looks
color coloring
uh but depending on your language you
know you most languages do not have all
of these for example pre-plus
pre-process surface
regular expression group impact slash
coloring then you have string phase
typeface uh variable name phase warning
phase constant phase you know many
languages don't have constant common
phase and some languages you have
special
thing like class or something or in
Haskell for example you have different
things that's not there so when it's not
there you have to create your own face
so here is how you define your own you
know particular coloring like background
coloring and so on so for now let's just
try find like building phase for the
low-lying words okay so I think that's
it so if we so now let's uh that's it
okay so you see
that's all there it is now let's try it
okay
uh let's try it let's just make them
clean even the buffer is there any error
no it doesn't look like it show message
buffer no Arrow so now let's go to
um
let's go to uh example python code
close this
example python code where is it
uh we
somewhere here yeah here
copy the file path close close
put the final path here so we can open
it easily
okay open it
now we are going to call
let's remove the comments let's remove
the bunch of comments
so that
um
so that we can see the rest of this
easy yeah okay that's it
okay so now we are going to call
some python mod again so it should
refresh and and now check the
um
the coloring changes right now it's in
Python mod you can see here so let's do
it
do it
done Okay so
so you can see
we we don't have the common color we
still need to fix that and actually
nothing is colored so we screwed up
right now only the string is color so we
made some mistake you see nothing is
colored the import should be color but
now it's not now let's look at uh the
message buffers to see yeah there is
some error error during redisplay
cheat for unlock signaled invalid
function so that means
you got some error you know when you try
to you know it's trying to color and it
doesn't work so close it
so what is the area well the arrow is
here
because when you use the apostrophe
for the that means quote okay that's
shortcut for quote that means this list
is not evaluated
so this list you know so this part
rejects up this function is not being
evaluated so
that's not good
you know this part wheel needs to be
become a regular expression so to
evaluate it you just add a
comma in front okay and you also need to
change the apostrophe to a back tick
instead
okay
that okay
evaluate it now let's go back to the
python mod and now
now it's default python mod now let's
Circle
okay
so now you can see the summation sign
there now this is some python mod you
can see import is colored
and the Z part of the command is colored
and you can see and or they are colored
but
kind of incorrect
and string is colored here
C
and yeah so now it's better we we made
the improvements so you can see
yeah so now
now let's do that now let's add
um
let's make it so that when we whenever
we open a DOT py file it will
automatically load XA python mod okay
so let me read the comment the python
community refers to them as Thunder okay
the devil underscore
this thunder
and they are usually magic methods that
gets caught by the language at some
point okay
uh yeah yeah
I I don't like python you know I I think
python really sucks anyway
so now
so actually so now let's change the name
Thunder
like this yeah no lying words let's see
dunda
t-u-n-d-e uh Thunder words okay
just for fun now next now let's
let's make a a
let's set up let's change our code so
that whenever people
use open say dot py file here load
python mod okay how do you do that
uh
so let's see let's go back to my
tutorial uh
yeah so it's not here because that
because so you can just click search
you can just click search type major
and
[Music]
uh
there it is set default major mod okay
this is a generic
question
you know not necessarily just for major
mod writers so that's not that's why
it's not part of the
how to write a major mod
chapter
so this is how do you okay here is what
you need to do
associate major amount by file name
extension okay so all you have to do is
here in the body of your major mod code
let's put that okay
so setup files ending in py to open ink
sub python mode Okay so
Auto mod list is a building variable you
can describe variable and see the
documentation and
current value so you'll find a python
mod there so for example let's search
for python
there it is actually that one I added
myself
search again python
you see
dot p y i w so python mod
so there it is okay
so all you have to do is add a let's say
dot py
and uh
okay now that's one more thing done one
more thing fixed
okay Eva the buffer
open that python file now it's already
opened before so right now it's still
python mod close it
open it again
didn't work okay close it
he wow the buffer
open that file
did not work it's still loading the
default python mod close it what
oh that's right that's right because
yeah
in order for this to take effect user
must call python mod
so you know user must
uh
yeah so you need to load
and no this part actually this part
needs to be done outside of the miner
mod
you see needs to be done here so that
when user loads your mod then this is
set globally you know so okay now let's
eval
first of all let's open the file close
it now eval buffer
okay open the file again you can see
it's in some python mod now fantastic
okay one more thing fixed okay now let's
fix next thing now you see this
this declaration in the beginning
you need that in uh here too
so there's a emacs convention when you
write the major mod the first line must
follow that convention so let's let's go
back to writing on my major mod and
so write the major mod open it go there
and the first thing syntax coloring open
it
okay
and
and here we can copy our kind of
template copy that
so here is the convention okay
so the convention start with three
semicolon and the name of the file so
the name of the file will be that copy
foreign
then
then you wanna say Okay major amount for
editing python code okay then you have
to have that to declare the default
encoding for your file utf-8 is good
okay then you say lexical binding true
okay
so let's let's equal binding t means
true that is a
that is a variable
building Emax that tells emacs to
interpret your code
to use lexical
binding okay that's a bit complex but
you know but in you know just follow
this okay you'll be good
so anyway so here this line you need
have to have this line two
it's not necessary okay but by emacs
convention if you are writing a major
mod you should have this line okay so
add that okay that's one thing fixed
now there's a other emacs convention for
the file header you know so if you
follow my
emacs you know how to write a major Mark
tutorial you know basically you just
copy this template okay which is that's
uh kind of the you know so there are
certain conventional headers because you
know for example author version name
created you know because when you load
your package to
canoe emacs repository alpha or male
part you know the external repository
for IMAX
they require this
these headers because they're gonna pass
you know they're gonna automatically
pass
your version name author and GitHub
location things like that okay
so for now we don't care it's not you
know really necessary for how the code
to work okay so let's just remove that
let's let's just say that remove that
okay remove that okay so now
here is our complete code for python mod
yeah now let's eval again
go to uh now and now open this let's
remove that
Eva now open this file let's fix the
next thing to fix okay next thing we
want the comment to be colored okay
let's fix that
color the comments okay how do you do
that
okay go back to the
to my tutorial
um
color comment okay very easy okay all
you have to do here's the example you
know
wait it's let me make the magnifying
let's
let's magnify my font so you can see
better
magnify for every uh every tab Okay so
yeah so uh
the coloring of
stream and comment okay in the case of
in the way emac Beast works is that
these two comes together okay it's a bit
complex but just read it you'll see how
to do it okay so all we have to do is
um
here is all the code okay let's just
copy it
uh let's see okay so let's see what
so Define VA syntax table Neo oh yeah so
you need a syntax table okay this this
part is a bit complex let me explain
so how long have we been oh God we
already been talking for one hour how is
how am I doing am I doing good should I
like end let's finish the common syntax
and uh
coloring and the strings coloring then
maybe that'll be it
okay is it because your mod was added
later than the default uh yeah so that
question is about
about adding the hook
uh no that's not because of that the
um
when you add you know when you add when
you call add to list
to a variable whose value is at least
the new item then then you you know say
what's a new item the new item will be
added in front of the list okay and when
you when emacs read the list usually
whatever the first item that matches
your uh be used so
so
previously the reason we didn't get this
to work not is not because it already
exists because it already the py regular
expression already exists you know but
it it's in the later part of the list
you you you you could go all the way by
removing the existing py okay uh
if you want to do that search for
Association table I mean Association
list okay so this these Basics then data
structure
um
function data structure
list this data structure then there is
Association list that's what this
variable Auto mod a list
is AED stand for Association list and in
this page you can see how do you remove
items and stuff there okay I'm not gonna
go into
but anyway typically
you know you don't bother with that you
just add in front overrides whatever
exists there okay let's go back to how
to color the
um the string and the comments okay hold
on a second let me read the comments
more
uh everything's good thank you for this
information thank you I'm new to emacs
okay thank you fantastic
so now
Let's uh
uh let's recap okay so we are doing so
let's go back so we are writing a major
mod for Python and first thing
is that we are doing syntax coloring
okay and we already did syntax coloring
for these keywords in special words
then the next thing we want to do is
syntax color
the common end string okay in emac this
the way emacs works is that they are
done separately they are not done by a
regular expression okay so how do you do
that so it's you can see here so we just
follow so the way you do that is that
you need to set up a syntax table okay
now syntax table in emac is part of the
emacs system so it's how emacs do things
so in emac this the language there is a
a concept called syntax table
and only only is specific to emac this
you will not find this concept in other
languages
so you have the concept of syntax table
okay so you can click here and see so a
syntax table is basically emacs as a way
to classify for each and every character
for example double quote English letters
comma or underscore every character or
semicolon punctuation or Unicode any
Unicode character so ten thousand tens
of thousand characters
for every character they e-max this
classified group The each character by
by their type okay so you have a type
called uh words for example
English in English letter characters
they are part of the word
class okay then you have a punctuation
class that's comma semicolon plus minus
PSI you know and things like that and
so punctuation so that's what syntax
table is so it's a way it classifies
each and every character into certain
types okay so you can see
so you have this uh class of uh
syntax okay
you have white space character you have
words typically are English letters or
Chinese letters or Russian you know
you have symbols okay symbols now
symbols in basically means characters
that are allowed in identifiers meaning
that in variable names in the function
names in programming language so
emac this is coding symbols symbol okay
so anyway syntax table is a mechanism to
classify
characters into
type of characters so you have white
space word symbols punctuation string
delimiter
you have brackets left bracket and white
right bracket you have common start
common in and you have Escape character
so
and there's a few more okay this this is
not all but you can look up the
documentation you can do there's few
more
now let me talk a bit about synax table
now syntax table concept is unique in
emac disp nowhere else not it's I don't
think it even exists in other text
editors such as VI or vs code I don't
think so I'm not sure but I don't think
so so it's pretty unique in emacs and
it's
um it's very cryptic okay it's hard to
work with and it's very quick cryptic
however it's it's very fundamental to
emacs emac this so in fact when you use
you know when you move your cursor
backward by word or forward by word or
you know backward by word they all
actually rely on syntax table
because how does the command know when
should it stop you know when is the end
of the world
emacs knows that because of syntax table
okay so every major mod
uh set up its own syntax table you can
you know it's just a kind of a list of
things you can modify for example here's
the code how you change certain
characters
you know for example
um
you know so you can read it for detail
so you can
so every major mod basically has its own
syntax table there's a default one you
can derive from
so every major mod have a different
concept of what kind of character is the
letter what character is a punctuation
okay so for example in emac Beast you
know if you load emac new emac this
mod
then the parent
the parentheses will be part of the
uh they they will belong to the class
left bracket and Red Bracket however
the square bracket
character you know
is not is not part you know the left
square bracket is not part of the class
left bracket in emac list mod Okay so
you know it just so happens that it did
it that way
so the point here is that every major
mod have kind of their own particular
concept of what is a punctuation uh
uh mostly they are the same but you know
they may be different Okay so
so we are talking about syntax table
okay very uh critical concept
Okay so
in order to create color for the common
and string
all you have to do is you have to set up
a syntax table that tells emacs which
character is the beginning of a string
you know the string delimiter and which
character is the beginning of common
okay now this this is actually fairly
complex okay but let's just follow the
template here
you know because syntax table is very
very hard to understand in complex okay
so let's create a syntax table and the
our mod is
let's change our mod is the python mod
so python
example okay change those words
okay first of all we Define a variable
sub python mod
you know instead of defined by you can
just say Define okay
and
in if you are writing a major mod you
use you should use Define VAR
but typically we can just do a set queue
it's simple okay you can look up Define
yourself okay so
so anyway defined by is basically like
set queue Okay just set up a variable so
you set up a variable
uh which allows you to also include a
documentation for for the variable
that's basically what defined by is if
you use set queue then you don't you you
know you cannot have documentation okay
so you set up a variable okay so syntax
table for a python mod then here's the
value okay then you say set Q
uh
so you first of all
you create a
copy you know you make syntax table
which create a default synapse table
then you want to say
so what we want to say here
okay so yeah so this is for python so in
the python case the pound sign is the
start of common okay and the end of
comment is a new line so that's how you
do it
okay
uh okay so let's do the common
part first okay then
then this we don't care so actually just
copy that
you need that okay so hold on a second
let me show you
so copy this so we set up
syntax table
here okay we set up syntax table
let's say scene
okay
let's put some
clarification here
clean them up
so it's more compact
okay and then
syntax table
okay so we set up the character pound
sign and new line to belong to the
comment
character beginning and end of comment
then all we have to do
is
in uh
you know definition of the mod we just
say
we just set the syntax table to
some python mods index table so this
means when plus when when user
loads some python mod it will set up
syntax table to be that
the value of syntax table is above a
specific you know it's above a local
buffer logo so every buffer has its own
syntax table which may be different from
others okay
so when you do that so that's it that's
what you do but syntax table is not a
variable so there's actually no variable
you can there's no variable name it's
just local to each buffer it's kind of
hidden
so anyway so that's it so okay so that's
our code so far let's
um
you know let's let's look at the whole
okay that's it
that's okay now let's eval the buffer
Ivana buffer
open this file
fantastic you can see we got the common
colored now
okay and string is already common now
stream how do you comment string is very
similar you know all you have to do is
you set up you know just this line you
set up a
you know you modify you you make the
strings
beginning and end delimiters to be the
string syntax table okay that's you know
read read my page you'll see okay but
but right now it's already works it
already works because close it because
we based on our mod um programming mod
which which you know already
um set up the syntax table correctly for
the
for the double quote okay so what's the
next thing we want to fix one more okay
let's do one more
one more thing which is the command
command
okay uh yeah we need a way you know we
need to comment and you know for example
comment this out
so right now it doesn't work you know so
so you need a command to do that and
that's very easy okay you click you know
how to write a common uncommon command
for major mod all you have to do
is just set two local variables these
two okay copy it
yeah copy it and close this let's go
here
okay then come and start pound sign okay
common end
uh common and it should be yeah empty
okay that's all you have to do
okay give out the buffer
open the python file now let's try the
common dream
there is a command called common dream
it is common Dash dwim that's building
emacs so now if you call that let's see
for example
dwim okay
uh d d w i m okay do it you see it adds
a comment
you see
so now if you select this line for
example select select let's call it
again
comment down
code select them code again and comment
okay so now comment and uncomment now
works in your major amount okay
close it
uh okay now opening it again
now there's one more uh you know there's
a lot of things we need to do so right
now you see this is incorrect you know
we don't want part of the word
highlighted in other parts
so and also here
so to fix that
you can reorder
you kind of
um
no way to fix that you have to hear this
part generates a regular expression uh
it takes a second argument that that
says
you want the regular expression to match
only when they are at the boundary of a
word so you just say word here okay
so you can look up describe function
rejects up so you can see
the documentation it describes here so
you know
there okay so close that so and let's do
the same thing for uh this okay even the
buffer
open this file
let's go
up let's see does that still happen
still happens okay close it even a
buffer
open it it still happens
this end wait so why is it
okay we don't want word we want symbol
okay
symbol means
um
you know symbol means identifier okay so
let's let's try that
not sure it works but let's try it
anyway Eva the buffer
okay did we actually uh it should work
okay he vowed a buffer open it it worked
you see
you see now if I type end
now it's colored correctly you know and
in Python is like
it's a logical end okay
fantastic
okay I think that's it for today so any
comments and questions
so
we got syntax coloring to work
we got
you know we got color comments in color
stream to work now we have also common
command
that is that is 60 of your major mod so
you are
you know we are pretty good pretty good
so of course you have to you have to
write a lot more syntax color into fi
you know close for example
and the next thing is to write a
completion command that's very useful
but I but that's it for today it's uh 70
minutes yeah so thank you guys for
watching okay so if you like my stuff
you know go you know go to my website
saree.info uh so you can buy
you know you can patreon me you know
patreon me five bucks or give Amazon
gift card you know
20 bucks would be nice or PayPal you
know and you can also buy
my emacs tutorial
so
uh and emac this tutorial so where do I
have the link
by xiaomi Max tutorial you know as a
donation so what you get is the complete
tutorial my emacs and emac this tutorial
so it's you can use it as a reference
it's instantaneous you don't have to go
to website
okay that's it thank you guys for
watching
so let's read the comments and shut down
in three minutes
uh other lines you put in their special
type of comments
which I I'm sorry uh which line
I'm not familiar with emacs in is a more
like syntax highlighting and LSP
features okay liko or high liquor 12.
well for this video you have to be a
Emax user to
to benefit from this at all because if
you are not emacs user this is not
useful to you and
you know you don't have to worry about
it it you know so
you know yeah
because this we are writing a major
amount to color you know syntax color
a programming language
in emacs so you know so different
languages you know I actually I don't
have experience in writing a syntax
coloring package for in Vim in vs code I
don't have experience but I have
put as far as I know they you know each
editor they do it rather completely
differently
you know so ideally you know the ideal
situation is that oh you need doesn't
matter which editor you just need a
grammar specification you know for the
language
some kind of standard grammar
specification put it there and and ban
you'll just color everything and you
also have common and common command you
know ideally but that's not reality so
in emacs editor you have to code emac
this and quite esoteric you know in Vim
you use Vim script or whatever
and neovim you use luaus I suppose but
the mechanism how they think is not over
it's all different as far as I know in
vs code is another way okay so
okay so there's a the lines in major
mode line 35 E major mods so oh that so
that is kind of interesting so you can
learn everything about that just search
emacs tutorial uh just search for
that that
is actually it's a bit complex but
that's that's actually just the
character
Line Feed okay so the form feed okay uh
let's just search for feed
okay here form feed okay so this is the
Emax convention
okay let me explain that and that's it
for today so in order to understand this
thing com you know I'm giving you a
rather in-depth explanation this thing
you are seeing you know it displays a
line it's actually just one single
character that character is the ASCII 12
character it's called form feed
character okay so it is a Emax
convention emac this convention since 40
years ago that you use this character
foreign
sorry
as a section marker you know you can
still see it in for example let's go to
diode
describe function diode okay so let's go
to source code of emacs uh you know
build in emac this
code so if you open any one of them
you'll see it okay so you see
so form V character now typically it
will display in emacs as as the correct
Arrow here just display that way you
will not see this line
but however
you uh there's a packages or you can
search on my site you know if you read
this article you'll know everything
about it you know different ways to
different conventions to insert a
section break in your source code you
know there are
there's no standard you know you
sometimes you see this which is the most
idiotic you'll see that in C Java kind
of you know so anyway in emacs this it's
a convention you use this Single
Character ASCII 12 called form feed to
indicate section break
and it's a convention okay and there is
a way there's a keystroke you can jump
by the form
by this bisection or narrow two section
okay just read the article
and there is there are packages and or
functions is you know you can search on
melpa that will display this form feed
as a line
so that's what you are seeing
so you know so I also have my custom
command for example if I want to add
that
I can just say
um
space look look at look at the Ping
Windows space yeah okay so I have the
command size insert from feed if you
just search for that you'll find
uh you know you'll find my article
display short form feed a slime okay
okay so that's that's about that
you can insert the character in playing
glue emacs you just control Q control L
okay Ctrl Q control L okay that's what
you do you yeah that's how you insert
that character okay bye guys
fantastic bye donate okay thank you guys
don't don't forget that's the most
important
because I get a million thanks that
doesn't do anything to me
you know
by
close
uh