good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
today is 2020
august 11th three o'clock
in the afternoon san francisco time and
you guys
pick a topic in the chat box okay i have
a in the youtube description there
are two topics so pick one tap in the
chat box
and jagen says number two now number two
is let's see what is number two and
let's i'm going so today's topic is
gonna be
uh either emacs list coding in real time
with explanation or javascript coding in
real time with explanation
in either case in both cases you'll see
a lot of my workflow
emacs workflow i'll explain that so if
you are
a emacs user interesting workflow i also
explained that and also any questions
type it okay
you know i'm going to try to do it fast
so there's more information instead of
me rambling on so
after that after the live coding we are
going to
then we are going to talk some random
stuff okay now pick a topic and type in
the chat box okay
and uh jason jason jagen says number two
jagen the scheme list expert says number
two so what is number two
number two is uh write a rotate 13 web
app in javascript okay we can do that
uh in 20 minutes i'm pretty sure you'll
be done
so any other choices emily says number
three there's no
number three uh george good morning
javascript okay javascript just follow
the blood let's do javascript then
first of all let me show you this one uh
double check am i live am i am i am i
good to go so hold on a second so okay
check if i'm alive yes i'm alive stop
that to save
my cpu and go to here
yes i am alive and good okay
i'm going to this is the background
image for today's youtube
uh video you see this uh so this is a
photo of
architecture uh apparently they they
it's uh
abandoned so this is pantheon to the
heroes
in the anti-fascist struggle
that's the name of the sculpture in
bogus
bulgaria 1981
so it's a fantastic sculpture i don't
like you know
it's anti-fascist crap you know
a lot of misinformation but anyway this
is a great
uh sculpture sculpture
and here is another view so apparently
this
phase is abandoned bulgaria
okay so let's start today's talk show
i'm going to do yeah so javascript let's
begin javascript okay
comments questions uh as i talk and you
type it okay so let's do javascript we
are going to do rotate
13. so yesterday we did a we explained
what is rotate 13
basically let me magnify okay so abcd
uh okay something
in the water okay i want to encrypt it
so meta x wrote 13 region
and it becomes that so if you start with
abcd
route 13 then you get nopq
basically you switch you swap each
english letter to the 13th
letter after it so a begins
becomes n b becomes o
c becomes p d becomes q
and you if you do it again it comes back
because 13th
uh letter english has 26 letters
so it's kind of symmetric so that's a
rotate 13 and we are going to write up
a javascript app to to do that okay
so let's go to um where should i put it
uh row 13 let's go to comp okay
go to my computer block magnify shown in
browser so this is my programming blog
and we are just going to create a new
page
add the new hold on a second show
in the pink windows on the pink window
you can see all the emacs command i call
such as moving cursor or whatever
keystroke i call
keystroke i type it'll show on the right
window so
i'm using a variable keyboard layout and
also software keys so you can see
everything is
almost everything in single letter press
so i'm going to start a new section and
start a new page so the new page will be
row 13 okay let's just name that
row 13. um
cipher okay c-i-p-h-e-r rule 13
cipher okay i type that then call
command
xp xnp xmp is a brief for
some new page okay let's let's do
describe function
so you can see xmp is a alias for
site new page so you go into that
magnify exercise new page it just create
a new page so let me show you okay
so on this line i call xmp
meta x xmp enter
magnify so you got that a new page a new
html page and linkified so add a
paragraph
show in browser there it is
and if you open that it's empty
so back to emacs
back to emacs put a cuz on the link
press
enter to open it magnify uh shrink
you see that's a page showing browsers
it's empty so we are going to start to
write the javascript
so wrote 13 so in order to do that you
need the input box
input box where people can type things
right am i doing good
okay so uh yeah let's let's let's let's
keep going
so so you need to
javascript this is storm this is uh you
know javascript you you need to create
an input box
so how do we do that go to let's go to
javascript website you just type sorry
javascript you'll see it
so here is the dom tutorial
and how do you do a input text box
there it is text field
okay this is for name and stuff we we
actually want the big input box
so we go to text area technically this
is called text area
you see you can type type
things here and
you know javascript will get the result
so let's
just copy the code let's be lazy and
copy the code here
copy and paste coding okay close that
back to emacs paste it here okay and
of course you have to know what you're
doing so this is a tag we need
text area text area then id
then row row number of rows to show
here then column 40. okay let's just use
that
so type text here here's a default
default input
input text okay and result
uh result this is a show box so you see
here is a paragraph and basically you
have the span
id so spam with id so
what this part means is that in your
javascript
in so in javascript what you need to do
is you grab
the input then you do the rotate13
then you need to put it back in the html
page
so so this part
the spam id you know this part is where
you can know
you can tell javascript to add to add
the result
into uh under this spam for ex you know
for example right now i select or type
something you can see the result shows
under the
result magnify
you can see the result in real time
okay so let's so this is the basic the
code
then this part is javascript cut it
let's create a javascript
uh link okay so
uh so javascript so copy the file path
hold on a second back to emacs copy the
file path
you can see the command here remember on
the pink window copy the file path
paste it and and change the html to
js javascript okay so we have the
javascript
file name with the same name as html
except the extension so now i want to
link it
so i press the button
html any link if i becomes a javascript
link
let's magnify okay so it becomes a
javascript link
now i can go to the link let's split
split the window
go to the link enter file does not exist
create new
yes okay now we have our javascript uh
code so first of all let's put a date
uh so here we begin to code the
javascript
now remember we could we copied some
before so let's just paste it paste it
paste
paste previous there it is so
so here's our code we start with
constant
uh area text area so let's so text area
constant variable name takes area
and the document.getelement element by
id
takes area id so this text area variable
will hold it will hold
this input box item i mean called
element
html html tags when it's
in javascript it's called element so
this is text area
element so that's that's assigned to
this text area
variable and in the same way the show
box
the show box remember it's a result
let's let me show you okay
so split buffer go back you see this is
the show area so you see
uh this is spam tag show area so
that's that's in this line we just grab
that element
so now we have the both of these
elements that's a user input
input and output you know user interface
elements
now you just want to create a function
update
constant update and the arrow function
so the error function takes no input
uh you know this is the arguments no no
arguments
then the body of the function is this
part
okay so let's let's do that so here's
the body of
the function and what does it do it
show box show box remember show box
is this thing the result box
you know the place to display the result
which is a span
which is uh you know the span
tag there so show box dot
text content you know text content
is one of the property of the of the
span tag i mean not spend
so text content is when you want to add
text
inside the tag
then we say text area dot value so
remember text area is the input box
then dot value means you get the you get
the
whatever is inside okay so that's your
function so this here
this is my function update f update a
function to update it
then what you need to do is you need to
assign
a event handler to the function
what does that mean that means whenever
user types something
whenever user types something
that's an event okay the browser will
fire
fire it but you need to set it up
you need to tell the browser every time
a specific
event happens call your function and
your function will do something to it
in our case our function will just take
the input
and output in this you know added
to the inner attack of this span area
so so far so good so you said oh clear
okay guys is it is it good is it good so
far
uh i need to check if i'm like still
talking okay
sometimes i went on uh
dead okay
so we need to uh let's go back to
browser okay so
so we are almost done actually so text
area
we need to add an event so text area we
want to add an event to the text area
which is this
uh this box text area
dot add event listener okay the event
add
event listener is a function in dom that
takes three arguments so the event will
be
input that means every time user type
something it will fire
fire event okay so the event is name is
the input
then the second argument is a function
name
in our case we do we we say f f update
you know
whenever the event happens f update will
be called
then the third argument don't worry
about it you know you can if you study
javascript dom you can look up
at event listener so
so event is input whenever that happens
we call
f update and what does f update do
remember it just all it does is um
it takes the input from the text area
input
and basically just added to the output
so so that is almost done let's let's
show it okay so let's close my tutorial
if you like my tutorial i have a
complete javascript tutorial
you know um if you like it
buy it okay i spent two years working on
this i'm proud of this
this is my best tutorial
even better than my python or my email
list tutorial
so close my tutorial back to my cipher
our cipher page so javascript
okay now we added the event then at the
end
we call the function why because when
when user goes through the page
you want the result to show right away
without
any event happening so that's why we
call our function
so this is all there it is all we have
to do now is add the rotate13
algorithm in other words we need to
change the f
update a little bit but let's see if it
works okay close it
now back to the page um show in browser
you see we we see a area box
now hold on a second magnify
now i want to add a little space there
so
okay br back to browser okay that's good
uh bi is break now let's see if it works
we go to the browser type something it
works
fantastic
fantastic it works now all we have to do
is
to do the road 13 algorithm so we go
back to the javascript
open it magnify uh
okay so row 13 so
let's see how we do it i can tell you
how okay
so let's call e max first we first of
all we need a table
we need to know so row 13
is that you substitute each english
letter to another different letter
so a will becomes n b will becomes
o and so on so
we are going to i mean let's not think
about efficiency i mean let's not
like try to do the best code you know
the most elegant
the most uh golf whatever let's just get
it
work then we can try to make it better
so
one easy the most easy way is to create
a table
you know which maps to wear so first of
all we need a list of
letters so what we can do is i have
several
so many ways so here is the emacs
workflow okay
so for example i can say i have a
command star insert
letter okay i think no insert
alphabet uh no um
wait wait column yeah so insert column a
z
okay that's the command i wrote actually
so
enter start character a enter
how many 26 okay there it is
so it kind of you see it it added
a column of alphabets but we made a
mistake
that's not we want undo we want to add
much more empty space so it can so go
back here
call the command again insert column a z
a 26 there it is so we have uh
26 alphabets there are so many ways to
do it
let's see maybe there's another easy way
but what we need to do is we need to do
this okay let me show you
map okay javascript constant
letter map okay and
later map is going to be a new map
now a map in javascript is a
new feature since 2015 it is a list of
pairs
uh it's a hash table like python's
dictionary
or ruby's hash table ruby and pearls
hash table
or in java they call it map so
you know this thing has different names
it's new in javascript 2015 map
object so map object so what you want to
do is you want to give it a nested array
okay like that let me show i'm gonna i'm
gonna show you okay
so nested array
okay and the first the each
element has two elements okay
so a will becomes n let's just copy that
b wheel becomes nop okay
q abc abc
c will become q okay that's how we do it
that's the that's the table i need so we
need to do this
abcdefg everything so actually now
seeing this i know a better way so let's
let's do this okay
so this is part of emacs workflow so uh
there it is we just do this uh
copy the whole thing paste paste a few
more
so we can you can see we have a bunch of
these um
empty things so let's copy a few more
times
uh 91 12 that's that should be enough
now we're going to
insert xr insert column a z
do it start from a yes how many 26
yes there we have it so you see
we created this table now same thing
here
let's call it again insert column a z
uh start character n
how many 26 okay there's no 26 let's
just do it
okay so it went on to other ascii code
but let's look at
there's you see n o p q r s t u y there
it is
so let's try it again undo let's try it
again
insert column a z start character
n how many 13.
that's fantastic that's good then we
start from here again
we say a okay so start again
insert column a z start character
a how many 13
there it is so
so there it is now we let's delete the
other things we don't need okay
and let's shrink it so you can see
better you see
so we created this kind of table
that's the transformation table
uh okay that's it that's that's for that
let's
let's go back now
shrink a little bit uh
okay let it be like that so now we have
the
map of the of the transformation table
now what we need to do now remember
remember we are given
a text so basically a string a giant a
huge string
we want to do find and replace for each
letter
we want to transform it according to
this
table actually at this point i think
there's a better way
so the better way is to use ascii code
and uh using modular arithmetic
so okay let me explain so a good a
a simple algorithm is that
you you are given a string now for every
character
you do a loop through each character for
every character
you translate that character
i mean first of all if that character is
within the
let me okay let me simplify so you for
each character
you translate that character into
its code point so it becomes a number
so for example the lowercase a
is in apple the lowercase a becomes 97.
that's the
ascii code for a so you you go through
each letter you you translate that
letter back to
the code point which is a number then
you add 13 to it
you add 13 to it then you
you basically com then then you take
that number you convert
it back to the character so
basically that's the algorithm that's
actually simpler
it's simpler than than what would than
what
we are doing now with the
a map of of of character map
but of course there are pros and cons if
you use character map
then if you want to rotate 14
or rotate three or different kind of
cipher then we can easily
do that actually with the ascii code you
can do that too anyway let's
press on okay let's press on just let's
go on with our way
so we so right now what you what you
want to do you got a string you want to
do uh find and replace for each string
according to this table so let's do that
so uh we have to update our function so
let's
let's update our function so our
function is here
so let's create a constant
input string okay input string
is equals to that
then let's create another constant
result string okay uh it's empty for now
actually yeah let's say empty
uh well actually let's say
result string equals three insert string
okay
begin with the insert string now we are
going to go through result stream
so result stream
uh
let's use so we we right now we want to
do find and replace
let's see am i doing okay so okay
comments great fantastic
how is map better than a plain object
okay that's a good question
let me explain that actually that's a
great question
thank you for asking that okay okay
let's let's digress a little bit
um let's go to javascript my javascript
tutorial
so you go to my javascript tutorial uh
magnify then you go down you or
you search for map okay go down actually
go down here
date map object so you click on map
object
so here is the explanation what is a
different that's a
frequently asked question what's the
difference between object and map
you can read that but i'll just explain
to uh you know the the
so an object you know the javascript
object has multiple purposes
for example object property you it can
it has it can be in innumerable
or not or it can be
you know you have to figure out whether
it's innumerable because
some functions will not show
properties that that is not innumerable
but
but some other time you do want things
that's in
inable so anyway the the javascript
object properties
is not really designed to be used as a
hash table because javascript is created
invented
and implemented in 10 days you know so
it's pretty lousy
so let me just read actually it's easier
so map object
keys can be any type on the other hand
the object
type the keys can either just be string
or
symbols so it can be not it cannot be
arbitrary things
but a map ski can be anything
uh and
then okay so yeah so for another
another example the if you have a real
map object in javascript
you can find out how many uh items you
have how many pairs you have
on the other hand for object you cannot
you have problems because you don't you
do you want to count you know
innumerable ones or you want to count
other
things also if you use the object
it has the uh inheritance thing
so if you are checking if a key exists
it may not exist on object but however
it parents
has it so it's confusing you know you
have to be careful you know
on the other hand if you use the map
object which is new
you don't have those problems it's
simply just a hash table or just like
you know perl ruby's hash table
java map or it's like uh python's
dictionary you don't have to worry about
inheritance and all that so that is why
that's the difference okay so let's go
back let's copy that
back to emacs go to the talk show page
and paste it here so we can we know
we have a log of the topics talked
okay let's back to coding okay let's
back to now we want to do find
replace yeah so
we are given a string we want to do find
replace
so how we gonna do this
so string dot replace
so there's a function a string method
replace
and the first argument should be a
rejects regular expression
so in this case
so the regular expression then replace
string replace string so in our case
we want the regular expression to be
a letter in our map you know so and the
replace string
will be a letter in our map so
that means we're gonna loop through the
map okay so we're gonna
loop through the map so first of all
let's write a loop
uh four of loop okay four of loop
okay uh for let k
of iterable so the iterable will be
later map
which is a iterable object
then let key let k be a key value
key value i believe
you know in javascript it's it's lousy
because sometimes it's key value
sometimes it's value keys
so actually i have to go back to refers
to my javascript
tutorial so you go to map
you go to map object and there's a
iterate over map object there are two
methods you can either use four
four of map which is new in 2015
or you can use uh for each
let's use for each then okay let's let's
use for each
let's do functional programming uh
okay so let's but okay i know i remember
if you do for each then
okay then you have to give a function
error function
then the order is reversed so here you
need to
be a value key that's how you do for
each
okay i know because
that's how javascript is you see you
click on
uh for each map prototype for each you
see the
the the things feed to your function is
value key that's in that order not key
value
so it's kind of you see value key here
if but if you use
four of loop it's it's key value it's
such that's javascript
so and you know it's it it's
inconsistent
and the reason they do that is because
well i'm not going to go into because
for each
because you have well i'm not going to
go into
anyway let's go on with this so
okay so let's use for each instead okay
so letter map
for each key value value key
uh then what you're gonna do so
then you're gonna do find and replace
right
so the regular expression the find
string will be
[Music]
will be the key okay the fine string
will be the key
and the the string replace string will
be the value
okay so then you need to say result
string
equals to result replace
okay so that's essentially what we need
because you know in javascript when you
javascript
script string are immutable that means
every time when you create a string that
string never changes
unlike array you can never change part
of the string
if you change it it's going to create a
new string
so whenever you do string operations it
always returns a new string
so you need to assign it back to the
result
string again so i think that's it so so
that's our function so let's let's see
okay let's double check
uh
okay so um
let's do global so when you do regular
expression replace you want to
replace it globally
yeah so not just the first occurrence so
you need uh you need some sort of map
you need something like that
uh you know the backslas the slash slash
that's a regular expression syntax in
javascript
and the g is a regular expression flag
which tells the javascript to do it to
do
to find all strings and replace them all
but it will not work here because right
now k
you see you see rk is a variable you
need to evaluate
it so what you do you do you go to
um you you use the regular expression
constructor let me show you okay
javascript reference uh
regular expression then you go to
regular expression constructor
so here is the explanation so actually
let me just tell you what to do
let me just type it so instead of that
okay hold on a second instead of that
we need to do
uh
okay that's a constructor then you just
use string okay
k and uh k and uh
g okay wait
g okay so that's what you do you
you call uh rejects that's a you know
that's a function
and the first argument is a string
in our case k k is a string you know
it's a character
it so it turns that into a regular
expression object
the second argument is again a string
which is a flag for global so that's
what we want
so let's this dd that this that's what
we want so
once you have that once you have the
result we you want to update the show
box
okay um so show box
dot text content equals to uh wait
equals to result stream
i think that's it that's our code let's
let's predefine our code a little bit so
um yeah i don't have
no wait that's pretty
prettify uh code
okay
okay so let's prevent our code in the
indentation
and all that crap
that's it i think that's it you know
let's hope
you know one shot coding no trial and
error crap
you code it once it works i think i hope
so let's hope so
show in browser uh showing browser okay
let's try
select all a b c d
crap doesn't work turn on console log
let's see what's going on okay type
error embedded assignment to
constant oh yeah obviously obviously
so this result string should not be
constant
it should be uh let uh
you know because we are changing it okay
close it save it back to the javascript
refresh the browser
now it's not working uh
oh it's working a uh let's see you see
abc what
d e f g not is not working so we're
supposed to have rotated 13 yet
let's see where is it what's wrong
uh why is it not changing let's see okay
let's see the console log
and now it works what wait
a b c d e f g
h i j k l
m n o
o n works o works
p p works q
works so some of it works some of
it not uh but what's what is going on
is our map wrong
okay i think this is actually taking
longer than i expected let's see how
long i've been talking uh
40 minutes already oh wow javascript
[Laughter]
so jason says jason says what about an
alphabet string split
the two chart array make that your key
then yeah that can
we can do that too oh yeah that's
another
good uh method you you change the string
into array of characters
then you just
uh you just shift
the array 13 places but
um i get what you mean but anyway
okay uh ascii would be much better than
iterate that way uh damage nearly
midnight where i'm going to bed okay uh
thank you for the details
i understand now okay okay so yeah so
let's
try to finish this and maybe that's it
for today uh
so the algorithm is incorrect for some
reason where is
so it's working for npq so first of all
let's check
out map a2n b2o
then into a all map seems correct
okay
um for each
value key for each one of them
you want to replace globally
key and value and assign to results
why is that not working debugging
and then show box equals to content
i don't know close that let's try again
okay
close that show in browser uh
you see now it works
or maybe because we didn't refresh
a b c no abc doesn't work
some
okay so a a2m
doesn't work but the rest of it works
n2z works a2
a2m doesn't work so we probably
repeated you know you know we
we probably did the replacement twice
so it made you know it went into a cycle
oh yeah obviously a to n right here we
change
a to n but then
down here somewhere we changed n to a
again
that's that's right so what's going on
okay i know what's going on yeah i know
what happened
now so you see given a text we are
trying to do this
change globally so
that's that's where it is wrong so what
should happen is that once we
we changed our character we don't change
that character anymore
so we progress character by character
yeah that's okay that's tedious so
okay let's just quickly try to get this
to work okay so
let's change algorithm because this this
global find replace is not going to work
we need to do it and don't don't
don't change that character and go on to
the next character okay let's do a
stupid way
for i'm just i'm just going to code it
fast okay so
we we we go through the result stream
so a string is iterable so we go each
character
okay uh let's just say cc okay cc stand
for character
we go through each character for each
character we
uh let's say input string okay so
we go through input string for each
input string a result string will be a
array okay
let's not array
so result will be your array okay
so for each character in input string we
we um
we do replace okay we do replace for
each character in
input string
input string dot replace and not global
okay we don't want a global we just want
wait uh
let's just let me just do it
so we want to go through our map later
map
for each
oh god this is more troublesome than i
thought
for each character okay let's not use
replay string so we are dealing with
characters
so for each character in the map we are
going through the input string for each
character
so for each character if cc
equals to the character if
the character equals through the key of
the map then
push then
result array
push to result array
value okay so that's that's how you do
it so
you see if
if the character equals through the key
in the map
then push it then
then we have to abort we have to exit
the loop
and it's better to um
better to replace okay let's try again
cc
dot replace okay uh string or rejects
not global
okay so
result array
javascript live coding result array push
i think that's it
so result array push cc cc dot replace
uh that
no well our function is very inefficient
because once we find
fine we once we find a character in the
map
we should stop we should stop the loop
but we are not stopping the loop because
we are doing a four each
uh okay so let's use four of for a loop
key value
in later map
okay so
yeah okay let me just do it if
character equals to
key then
then result array push
value else
push value and exit okay exit
now you want to uh break okay so break
exit the loop else
else result array push
cc no change then break okay that's
that's that's the that's
okay that's i think that's um
okay let's magnify okay so i think
that's clean the code that's i think
that's it
i don't i don't want to think too much
let's just let's just see if it works
okay so
result array then
then we say result array
join okay
join empty string that turns array back
into a string okay i don't want to think
too much so i think that's
let's try it
close that close that
go back to opening browser magnify okay
that's enough
um no it is not working
no it's not working let's um
so for cc of input string
okay this this is a big sew-up
allen i'm still highly amused like sauce
indentation
you know what i need to do actually is
just to uh
i need to implement indentation in my
javascript mod
because my javascript mod doesn't have
indentation where i have to
indent each line then you know i cannot
select the whole and indent
i need to code more emac b you know
that's gonna be two three hours three
hours
um that's why every time i want to
indent
i have to switch back to javascript mod
you know the default javascript mod
then then select all indented then
switch back to microsoft javascript mod
you know i have my own javascript mod
because i have you know i want to do my
own things i want to use my own code
but right now i just missing the
indentation feature i need to add but
usually i don't like indentation okay
indentation is
crap indentation is one of the big grant
i have you know but for example
you see you see this code i can press a
key
to shrink it you know you should be able
to
what should happen is auto automated in
formatting okay not the manual you know
80 characters per line then indent
manually oh
you missed the indentation you need to
add one more or you need to use this
this tab or you know the the the command
to predict this crap
it should be all automatic that's why i
have delays in
implement implementing that feature but
anyway
right now i we have a problem to solve
we
we need to get this algorithm to work
right now it's not working
uh for cc of input string
then for the letter map
if that result array dot push v
break
okay now what what is break break break
break breaks the inner loop right or is
it
um
continue
yeah i need to use continue that is why
okay save it close it showing browser
what the
wait i should use break uh
a b c
ah what the and not break
i should be break
um i need to figure this out so okay i'm
stuck
well i'm not really stuck but i'm stuck
that
in a sense i'm doing live stream and i'm
stuck in this thing
result array dot push
why is it not working
no it's not working at all
so does any no anyone know we
should we we stuck
yeah jason that's a good algorithm but
um
we are just trying to push through the
algorithm we already started to use
the else must be outside of the for loop
wait let
kv so if that
push
it should be inside right
and again we can add console.log
console.log to
debug
no not try delete else then that's
that's
you know that's exceptions exceptions
it's no good
you you might be right you know no i'm
under pressure i cannot think i need to
relax
okay so let me how long have you i've
been talking
oh my god javascript i thought we i
thought this is gonna be done in 10
minutes
okay i need to think because that's the
only way that's the best way to for me
to get this
going instead of reading different
opinions
uh going through the characters so we're
going through the characters
for for of loop let cc be
input string okay so we are going
through each and every character in the
input string
and for each character we are going
we are doing another loop through the
map for
every character in our map so
if the character in the input string is
equals to the
the key in the map then we want to
change it
okay so what we do is we push it to the
result array
we push the value in the map to the
result array that is a substitution of
the letter
so okay but otherwise okay
but otherwise you know once we do the
substitution then we break
we break the loop of the of the letter
map
because there's only one character we
already found the key
oh i know why okay wait uh we've
we've no we shouldn't break yeah
okay i i know what's going on wait um
if okay i know i know what's going on
right right we only break when we when
the result is found okay
yeah so this break is incorrect
so when the when the when the character
match the key in the map
that's the we do the substitution then
we exit
we exit of the looping of the map we
start with the next character in the
input stream
okay that's that's that but if it
doesn't match
the letter doesn't match the character
in the map we continue
if it doesn't let if the letter doesn't
match
oh yeah that you are so you are right
the else part should be outside of the
um
outside of the uh
no no i got it got it it should be
outside of the
the map loop right so if it match
if it matches
then break okay if it doesn't match go
on to the next character in the map
i mean next key in the map so when it's
all done
when all this is done
you are right so when when all this is
done when none of it matches
then
um then you need to like um
then you need to do that okay so but but
how do we do this
uh if
oh god this algorithm is getting
more and more cold
and how do you do the how do you do this
so if it matches you you push the result
then you exit the map which is uh good
let's just add a flag a stupid
idiotic flag
okay the the the brainless way to do
things matched okay
matched uh force okay
here's the brainless way to do it i i
can think about better ways later later
on
so if it if it worked um
okay my god we have a lot uh
smart people here giving giving the
correct solutions actually i don't want
to use the
flag is wrong wait let me think okay i
have to think myself
so so if it if
if if if it's correct i mean if it's
equal
you push it
if it's uh otherwise
you push it then you break okay
otherwise well the problem right now is
how do you um know whether
you found a match or not
uh okay so well
oh that's okay i know what what to do so
what we
what we can do is
yeah okay let's do this okay so
so what we can do is um
result char okay let's do a result
character
and result character empty okay
now now
now result character equals to um
let okay let result character we put
here result character equals to cc
okay
right so and
okay hold on a second so we need to do
this
okay now we push
okay here's what we do so
we declare a result character and we go
through the
loop the nested loop and if we found the
match
we set the result character to it
and continue okay then
then we push it to array okay i think
that's
that should be it
oh yeah later map has cc um i mean okay
so many suggestions you guys are
probably right but
i need to put in my brain for it to work
okay it seems to work
a b c d e f g
finally it worked i i guess this is
this is actually real life coding when
you code in a company
also the problems happens of course
given my
given my incompetence
so that's why it's slower but actually
this is real life coding it's like that
especially i mean if you don't have
enough sleep or something
okay anyway that's it for that that's it
for today
uh hope finally it's done
yeah so that's it that's the javascript
code and we already talked for
one hour something so wow
one hour and seven minutes okay that's
it for today
what else was was i going to do so okay
that worked
so that's rotate 13 row 13 cipher
same thing as emacs let's try something
okay this
is row 13 cipher
okay you copy that go here
paste it do it and you got that
copy it back to emacs put it here
magnify okay then you do this row 13
row 13 region exactly exactly the same
identical great so that's success that's
row 13 so
now copy this close it
save it row 13 cipher
yes we have it close it close it
close it back to the talk show page
close it
okay talk open the talk show page
magnify show in browser and
paste paste the link here
showing browser so that's it thank you
guys for watching
today if you like my emacs if you like
my javascript tutorial buy it
okay
i hope to see you next time subscribe
thumbs up
and stuff oh by the way emacs 27 is out
so that's fantastic i'm going to talk
about that maybe next day tomorrow
thank you guys bye-bye
ah