good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today is 2020
January sixth Monday and two o'clock
p.m.
San Francisco time so we have a lot of
things to do today and we are going to
[Music]
this crap website crap crap that that
there was Amazon that's good that's my
Amazon money psyche so we were looking
at Los Angeles regions and look at this
San Fernando okay this is the well-known
city okay that's a city of San Fernando
okay this is so sensuous good morning
Kathy good morning to you Kay and good
morning to you people I haven't I'm not
prepared here so this is San Fernando
okay so that's near Los Angeles over
here and we are we were looking at Los
Angeles and we were we were doing things
so today the main topic is gonna be
Emacs and so you guys talk okay talk and
chat and stuff so how is going Cathy so
have you guys have people been going to
the Emacs meetup so you guys go to Emacs
Meetup okay there's one in UK and okay
so what what is today's topic so let's
gonna go to talk show and actually I'm
not so prepared but
we have a lot of things to talk about
the to do and javascript and unicode and
by my tutorial no it's hot I need to
take off my clothes so today's topic
Emacs mainly okay so what are we going
to focus on Emacs
okay so let's talk then since Allah so
let let us see what is the what we have
in store
so just ingesting are you still here
just in scarf I just
Justine Scott Phi is a mathematician and
we gave an intro about just in few days
ago last week so Justine says tell us
about your computer configuration like
what like what what do you mean like I
have lots of configurations of course so
Kathy says okay computer configuration
sounds good ok my roommate is back let
me close the door
so that's what basically we discussed on
meetup where I get to learn Nick's ax
Nick's OS okay Nick's OS is one of the
new Linux distribution they focus on
function package package they are known
for package manager a functional
programming based package manager so
what about my computer setup okay I was
going to talk about real-life coding of
Emacs
and I was going to I'm so busy like I
have ten thousand things to do to show
you guys see duo keyboard dual-wielding
keyboard so this is my normal Canisius
keyboard and I've been using it for
three or four years everyday and I kind
of get tired of it so now I know and
then I connect to this one but this one
doesn't have enough keys okay
so it doesn't have enough keys and you
know like too few keys for me so I have
like 1,000 things to talk about and ok
so computer setup actually so let me let
me take off the unplug this actually so
that oh yeah so I have a new config for
this keyboard I'm going to show you so
there it is I have a new config for this
keyboard ok I have 1,000 topics to talk
about I'm like going in parallel and we
are going to talk for 2 hours today it's
nonstop so let's let's let's write down
what we gonna talk about ok so computer
key computer configuration ok that's I'm
gonna tell you something about that and
emac beast coding so I'm going to do a
live coding of eMac B's the task is to
write a command so that you can press a
key called
man and it will copy the current buffers
file into several directories I need
that I'm gonna tell you why okay so so
that's about eMac this coding so tell me
which topic you guys want like want me
to talk about because we're gonna do
those thing order and typically the
first you know the last three ones will
not be covered because we don't have
time so some Emacs coding and and random
okay so the spice must flow so bits and
let's start saw start command log mod
okay and this is so on the left window
you can see all my Emacs commands so
such as cut cut and do and do or select
cut for example and do or move kusa all
the commands can i show on the left
window and let's adjust it to the right
size so if you see a command of interest
just search it on the web you'll find
the code so we're gonna do Emacs so
besides Emacs or computer configuration
okay it is eMac this coding and okay and
then JavaScript script then command
frequency okay let me show you some of
the things we're gonna talk about
command frequency Emacs command
frequency my new ultimate hacking
keyboard setup okay so that's that and
JavaScript spread operator okay so
that's a new thing and to do to read so
that's a lot of things actually so let
me show it again
so Emacs coding and Emacs command
frequency and automat hacking keyboard
setup so I have a new layout then then
we can talk about JavaScript
spread operator object on object that's
ACMA script 2019 new new install so as
you know JavaScript they have a new spec
every year so every year they have a new
feature and we I'm gonna talk about that
and actually I'm thinking for my talk
show we're gonna need a like scheduled
topic because otherwise every time I
start to talk about I'm wondering about
random topics so is something like this
okay Monday so let me type in Monday
Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday
Saturday did I spell it correctly
yeah and Sunday okay so you see all
those are lowercase and I just press a
key and they they are all capital case
now you see that command is some title
case region or line and now we press a
key it becomes a list you see and that
command is saw HTML lines to list are
you guys seeing it you guys seeing it I
think so okay so okay so you are missing
part of it
so let's shrink this window more so you
can see it the my video is too big hello
Lion King okay so show and Monday to
Tuesday Friday so I'm thinking something
like this okay so let me show you again
the Emacs works well RA for red arrow so
Monday is going to be Emacs and eMac
this okay
Tuesday let's say JavaScript Thursday
let's say keyboard okay then let's say
goal and okay I have a lot to show you
guys and and Wednesday for : and
Thursday for keyboards okay let's say
Unicode and Unicode stuff fascinating
stuff and Friday is gonna be keyboard
let's say and Saturday Sunday random
something like that
good morning Allen homepage at Sony how
Allen from Northern California so we
have so I'm thinking of something like a
schedule like topic schedule topic so
Monday Emacs emag this Tuesday
JavaScript Wednesday : thursday unicode
and friday keyboard saturday sunday
random something like that and actually
that's missing a lot we miss python we
miss a lot of things so there are tons
of things to talk about so just in
Scotts Phi so Justin wants to know what
is my so let's start with the computer
configuration so you go to sorry Linux
set up okay so this is a bunch of steps
I need to do whenever I create whenever
I start a new Linux machine and similar
on Windows but I don't have a similar on
Windows in Mac but I don't have a page
that discuss that so Linux setup so this
is what I do okay so when you know I got
a new machine or if I'm working so this
is Sally Knox setup so first of all get
the LXDE desktop or rx T or F SC
XFC you know it's been a while I don't
even remember the Linux windows manage
your names so that's the first thing I
want I do
on Linux you get either the lxd or XFC
window manager okay so I have a tutorial
everything you need to know and Ubuntu
sucks we went to sucks donkey ass but -
with their new stupid in interface you
know where ever Apple does something on
user interface it's always good it's
just - what you need you know it just
works
whenever open - is trying to do it
whenever the Linux Peapod is trying to
create a new interface it's such [ __ ]
donkey ass the fact that Linux people
the idiots they they're they're these
nuts they are incapable of thinking they
don't know what they're doing so you you
know Ubuntu as you know if you may not
if you do not know open to about 567
years ago they created a unity interface
which is which is actually a copy of you
know a copy of Microsoft and Apple
typically oppose begins something new
then Microsoft the Windows copy yet
after a few years two years then the
Linux copy it and the and the fact that
Linux [ __ ] the Nerds they don't
know nothing they don't know how to do
interface they'd rivo every day with
their open source and free software
chant so anyway so we went to created
unity and they are in fighting which
with each other you know open to created
unity then they fight with the genome
people they blame each other
crawling each other eyes out you know
big drama every every year so that's a
you but you've opened to unity okay so
this is this happened like this is eight
years ago so anyway so the first thing I
want to I do on Linux is LX D and F X F
see the desktop window manager
okay the simple simplest possible and
so I haven't tried the I haven't tried
the the the Knicks OS you know what what
a fancy name Knicks OS you know it's
just just that they have this package
manager so I think I think it's good
based on functional programming concepts
meaning no side effects so anyway so
that's the first thing I do window
manager then keyboard lots of things
tons of things to do on keyboard so set
the watch keyboard okay if I'm not using
a physical vote layout I mean you see
this keyboard is right now physical work
you know it sends the huaraches directly
so if I'm not using that then you need
to set up the Borak keyboard okay and on
this page of course I have everything a
tutorial if you don't know how to do it
you can just go there and let's place it
here okay so here's a link so look at my
Emacs commands for poor view Emacs
people look at how I operate so cut it
go to here and paste there you have the
link so that's so you set up keyboard
switch to vorak layout and look at this
is how you do on linux every
distribution is gonna be different okay
so you're gonna learn this 1,000 times
linux you know the open source supposed
to be cooperated but in reality they are
just kicking each other that's the basic
human nature you know that's that's why
communism never works the [ __ ]
open-source [ __ ] you know the free
software foundation people they get us
you know they get us Google and Facebook
becomes worse and worse today and you
don't have power if you are programmer
nothing you can do the only thing you
can do is go walking for [ __ ] Google
and they when they
don't like you like if you mentioned me
are not women they they kick you out and
you're gonna be poor so those of you
still you know thinking open source
lease that stop it okay stop it
hey good morning but so of course I
cannot convince you you know I mean
about the open source you know it's a it
has become a powerful this this this
this coat this all-powerful coat you
just chant open source every day so
there's nothing I can do so I can tell
you you can think about it and maybe
you'll stop you know so what what is the
alternative what what what else you
should do there is no magic bullet okay
there is no like one thing I can say oh
then every let's all just follow that
and things will be good nothing like
that you just have to think okay so
everyone you know you just have to think
about things that that is basically this
that's that's that he that is the answer
everyone you have to spend time no pain
no gain to type into things you rather
not spend time with you have to
sacrifice your time for playing games
for dancing or whatever you do movies or
whatever you sacrifice those times to
dig into things you don't like to
believe then think that's what it means
think you know sport Ron Russell said my
favorite author
he made a commentary that thinking is
the thing that people do not want to do
the most you know that you don't want to
but that is that is the answer actually
that if if you want a better society
that's what you have to do there's no
way out so anyway so on Linux I switch
my keyboard setup to work then you do
then I neck quite a few things okay then
I said set up my keyboard repeat rate
okay basically to the fast fastest
possible so here's how you do it in
command line you know you can do on GUI
as well like I said every Linux distro
they are you know window manager [ __ ]
we know manager [ __ ] [ __ ] the Linux view
the window manager so everyone is each
one is different and there is no there
is no like universal way not not like
the the way on Windows or Mac you know
you know like if you are not you might
think oh I'm just going to go with the
raw you know the the fundamental the raw
call way to command line to control the
keyboard and you know set up actually
that doesn't work so anyway so I set up
my keys repeat wait then a disabled or
the bunch of [ __ ] the Concord key keys
like code something they'll control
something all space this modem or and
disavowed all the week workspace [ __ ]
the workspace the you know the the works
switch to workspace like like the by
default you have tens of keys
controlling the your workspace it's all
garbage now if you know if you if you
want to know the most efficient way just
follow my way hey good morning is it
wrong crazy haven't seen you for a long
time so I found sorry once I mentioned
in in a Commack forum oh great okay so
that's where you came from Commack
everyone praised his Emacs economic oh
really you have to show me that link
that will make my day so Kathy says time
if the communism doesn't work what else
can save us from the endless neared
listen
niall ISM that's a another big topic I
talked about that a bit in the past
videos because there is a lot confusing
confusion and misunderstanding what it
means you know - too many people near
listen neol ism is just destruction it's
like the philosophy of destruction like
you don't believe like vandalism
vandalism destruction
you don't believing anything you don't
believe in God you don't believe in
nothing purpose life is meaningful
meaningless so you just destroy you
don't care about nothing that's that's a
lot of people and also a lots of
propaganda they want to make you think
that's what Melissa means and they
usually attack it you know so but
actually near ISM is a great philosophy
nearly some is what you get if you go
into 100% science you know a lot of us
believe in science these days especially
you know some of these atheist people
they think you know they don't believe
in God because science you know science
sensors and some other idiots they all
say Oh science and religion are
compatible no they are not compatible
okay you know including some of the
well-known you know philosophers idiots
okay philosopher frazzling okay that's
another that's a big topic I'm gonna get
into so anyway so what I'm into saying
I'm going to tell you that soneul ism is
is bad-mouth by many people in fact
that's common that's actually what
happens in philosophy in academia
- you know you might think if you don't
know you think oh they are respected
philosophers but actually philosophy in
academia they are just fighting with
each other and philosophy is their their
ground you know they are tufted that's
the ground where they fight anyway let
me tell you about Neil ISM Sony ilysm is
what it is is a inevitable one of the
main category
school of philosophy which is inevitable
that is if you are a scientific person
if you believe in logic all the way
there Niall ism neol ism is the result
so what does that mean so what does new
ariza means new ilysm basically means
there is no meaning in life the ultimate
question about life and the universe is
is is unknown it's impossible to know
okay that's that's that's what that's
the core okay that's the essence that
suggest about neol ism which says the
ultimate meaning purpose of life why are
we here you know what's more at you know
what's a good moral principles what's a
good morality although that is
meaningless or unknowable which as the
step as a follow-up
it basically means it's meaningless
because we are able not able to know it
so that's what I'm telling you that's
that's essential that's the essence
that's a core the the actual meaning of
near listen whatever you hear about
neural ism about oh its destruction
oh it's about you know the vandalism or
whatever that's stupid okay the core
meaning of near ISM is just that the
ultimate question is unknowable like
like kind of like eggnog eggnog
magnetism
I'm not Gnostic agnosticism okay so so
but but one step further because a knock
agnosticism means you know things
whether God exists is such a question
it's you you cannot know we cannot know
but if you follow that then basically
life is unknowable
a meaningless okay that's no reason so
so in fact I actually believe near
reason because
because you really if you really are you
know follow science and follow all the
principles you that's what you get but
it's important to say it is important to
say that that does not mean
okay so let's all just [ __ ] around okay
that that's the you know since since you
know since the universe is you know we
we don't know the you know we cannot
find the ultimate answer so therefore
let's just [ __ ] around that's that's
what not it means okay but so what I'm
trying to say is that from philosophy
point of view you know this you think
you think about everything so near ISM
is a essential and you know basically
inevitable a school of thought okay
about the ultimate question in a
universe so that's no reason so let's
see what the comments check out
different subject why is there some nail
later in swung I just happen to use it
because okay so maybe we can talk about
that later in the strong swung the
foundation of Western society did you
did you look at George good morning
George to Australia did you look at my
web site on on that leader in Swan it's
a I have a collection of artworks um
Leda and the Swan I'm not sure I want to
show it because I show it then Google is
gonna pay me you know that's censorship
today we have and also the social
justice packets with their women
concerns [ __ ] Leda and the Swan let's
see if I can find my site without typing
my name you know it's so today he used
to be my you know if you type letter and
swung my website is gonna be the number
one hit
and today you got a bunch of this you
know commercialization all these [ __ ]
websites they are just you know posting
you know clickbait they have SEO you
know the search engine optimizations
began by Google
you know the [ __ ] Google they led the
movement of the SEO they actually
encourage it so that why because that
benefit them so that you get all this
website compete for the Google's
Google's way of things so that today
when you search anything you just get a
bunch of this this one-track mind
website their only goal is to make money
they don't care nothing else and they
with their garbage information and we
have Reaper who is found of posting them
I'm sorry people so in my opinion you
know you are just posting pure garbage
and but meanwhile you are thinking you
are doing good research research all
these crap websites Leda and Swan okay
but Wikipedia is pretty good so you can
go to Wikipedia the subject of Leda and
the Swan you know it's a big Western
philosophy you know it's a like it's a
core of Western philosophy Leda and the
Swan so you can see all these artworks
okay so let me show you my website then
Leda and the Swan so you have to type
Sally there it is okay so arts leader in
Swan actually it's Kubo going to censor
me if I show it I'm not sure I'm not
sure I want to screw around so anyway
there it is the page okay you can go to
we Leda and swung and I have a lot of
collection of arts and some some of them
are in today's [ __ ] jargon
n s and F NSFW [ __ ] chaga by this
idiotic techno hippies and as f w you
know you guys don't know okay you guys
don't know I mean I mean I have my
followers you know this so today you
have this word this word began about
twenty years ago created by American
white people hippy you know the yuppie
modern yuppies in the programming field
in the tech technical field NS FW not
safe for work not safe for the not safe
for they are [ __ ] ass so let me tell
you the story NSFW this word this jargon
led to today's social justice train okay
that is our engine you know like people
don't know get it let me tell you my
authority of authority of thought you
you you you you watch my YouTube you are
getting the authority of thought this is
what do you think should be thinking
okay anything else deviate from my point
of view is wrong okay so I have
followers who are anti social justice
but however they love this word NSFW
they think this is proper what a [ __ ]
idiot so let me tell you what's going on
with this word this word leads to this
word and the open source and free
software foundation this [ __ ] train of
thought led to impart to today's social
justice movement okay it is because this
this a SFW thought because this thought
okay let me let me just explain them
because otherwise I'm gonna be
half-assed since I talk I'm talking
about
these images you know make a full
complete thought of my thought about
this world why I think that that way so
left of you not safe work you know the
idea is that you know today is beginning
20 years ago year 2000 okay beginning 20
years ago the yuppies you know those who
work at Google when Google was the good
guys okay remember back then 20 years
ago Google was the good guys Google and
many you know companies in California
you know Silicon Valley so these tech
people these tech people back then they
are kind of good guys okay so they
created this world meaning that oh
Internet is getting big so sometimes you
see you know pong or naked girls or
something so they want they created this
world I mean the thinking behind this
word is that oh you should you know if
you are going to post something
sensitive like you know tits girl with
tits showing you should have this
warning so that people who are working
not safe for work okay so the thought is
that also people who are working should
should be aware or you know all certain
places you should have you know do not
allow any SFW so that they you know they
don't post such things so you can you
know at work you can slack off this
[ __ ] is slacking off at work
meanwhile they want NSF will fw so
anyway that so that's a base that's a
basis okay that's the thought you know
so that they are trying to you know they
their intention is good you know they're
half of them being practical okay so
they're they they have this thought
about how you know either you should
have a warning or you know you maybe you
shouldn't some some forums you
you should this this should be not
allowed so that so that when people are
working at these tech companies you
don't pop up some nude pictures or
[ __ ] pictures so that your boss come
around and it doesn't look good
you know these [ __ ] these idiots so
they create they then you see not safe
or for work there is a lot of problem
with that okay first of all not safe for
work look look at dive into the the the
addictions this this modern hippie they
are thinking they are brain not safe for
work you see no you see you see I'm
claiming that this came from I'm
claiming this this is this is one of the
foundation of social justice trend as
you know the movement but you know you
you are beginning perhaps you are
beginning to see the link you see they
have the word safe the [ __ ] safe what
does it mean safe so they want you see
they these people this this white yuppie
for heads in in Silicon Valley who
created the internet for us you know
included including myself so they are
thinking of this is something you know
safe now safe so they want to slack off
at work they want to browse random
things and then they want to you know
they then they created this idea of
thinking that this is not safe safe safe
what does that mean safe what does that
mean safe does designing you're gonna be
stabbed when you browse pong a dead walk
you know if you want safe if you want
safety whatever that means
don't browse the [ __ ] web when you
are walking
okay these [ __ ] heads so they are
browsing you know they are browsing
randoms you know sucking of it walk and
then then they create this this idea
they have this mentality okay that's
just part of their thinking they
they want something they want a warning
label or something you know not safe for
work and for what book what walk so you
[ __ ] you know you you make a
million dollars a year so you your walk
you can walk and you can decide you know
you can have your concept of what is
safe what is not work what is not work
what is not safe hopeful for your walk
your your so-called walk where you can
you know sitting up you know being in
office drink your sip years if your
stock works coffee [ __ ] and then then
you then you hope I've run into a poem
that's not safe so so that your boss you
know it's a poses a danger in case your
boss comes in but a [ __ ] are these
people so they created this concept you
know that's their mentality you know
this this modern yuppies working in tech
companies not-safe-for-work
and and this is what what work you mean
you mean you mean those prostitutes who
have to do their work every day what do
you say for them so anyway so so you
have this not-safe-for-work okay this
your piece you know this rich yuppies
created this concept then it becomes a
brief NSFW and once it becomes on a
brief you have a jargon NSFW people
stopped thinking thinking is cut off is
good you just now now you can just chant
oh this is not a sfw oh you know NSFW
now you have a jargon stops thinking you
just spread that so it becomes a you
know you just spread that ESF left of
you so that that is my thought about
this last fw thing you know today and it
becomes so after 20 years today it
becomes a big become something else it
becomes so deviated you know it becomes
something else as you guys know or may
know our master Dan on Twitter
you know on Twitter even master then
okay when you post anything you have to
now now it's a comment okay let me let
me show you master than this
[ __ ] open source free software
foundation [ __ ] okay master then
it's this go to master then
so master then is supposed to be this
anti Twitter thing you know the reality
is much more complicated than than that
but anyway but my point is that today we
have people ok quite a few okay I'm
gonna I'm not you know gonna say who or
what that's not the thing okay because I
have tons of people that tell me every
day my followers okay not not you know
these are my followers who my friends
okay in other words my friends they
think so anyway our master Dan so today
you see you see this let me show you
this thing this this thing okay CW CW
you see that right you're warning here
so you see that over here is say smart
you wanna hear that so that that CW that
button it means when you post anything
that's perhaps sensitive maybe even food
even [ __ ] food you know I have
someone who mastered a because I posted
it posted some food I forgot what what
food you know we gonna what meat yeah
meat or something and someone say you
know I know I don't know who is they who
is the guy but he says he says like oh
maybe you should put post you know put a
warning so that so that those vegans
don't get freaked out by the pencil so
apparently so that guy is apparently a
social justice type of guy okay and he
he's not following me but however my
point is not about that guy okay that
guy okay well he believed in social
justice he can go his ways but I'm
talking about some of my my followers
which I'm against social justice so are
they okay many okay I'm not
not not these people okay don't focus on
my people I have lots of followers you
know so anyway so so I have my followers
who are not you know social justice who
are in fact mostly again is the social
justice kind of thinking but however
they [ __ ] also love the
not-safe-for-work the warning labels
they think whenever you post anything
including including opinion about
politics anything they think you need is
not safe for work this warning label
[ __ ] these [ __ ] [ __ ] heads dick so
you see so that's about that so my point
is that these people this this people
regardless what what's the political
opinion you see the the thing is they
don't have training they don't have
understanding about humanity they don't
have they they don't have they don't
have a solid understanding of human
animals our history what we what we do
you know what what we came from they
don't have they don't have idea they
they are thought every day doesn't
matter you see the important thing is
does not matter where they are you know
there are political factions where they
where they are in my point is about they
have no basis understanding about human
animals in fact you know when they hear
me say human animals they find me
strange okay but what is this Safa guy
humor animals this this or that human
animals so anyway that is my point okay
so I so that that that is my stripe of
thinking okay that's what I'm telling
you what you should do okay so I'm
against this very idea of
not-safe-for-work [ __ ] if you don't want
to browse random things you
afraid that your boss coming or
something don't do it period okay if you
don't want if you don't want to pose
something that's sensitive okay
sensitive whatever you know today there
are so many sensitive things in a twenty
years ago twenty years ago this not safe
work is basically about poem related
things you know or naked you know naked
showing a girl having kids showing up or
something or today you know everywhere
the Hollywood you know they are on MTV
you know music videos right in the music
video they showing their tits and ass in
every modern song which twenty years ago
would be very not safe for work but
today it's like [ __ ] safe in
Hollywood save these [ __ ] with
they're not safe for work they don't
know they don't know what they are you
know they have no idea they think they
know they think they oh I read oh yeah
you know sometimes you'll get you know
sometimes I talk about this my random
topics and something oh I have a degree
in policy political science oh I have a
degree in philosophy no yeah you have a
degree but you are a idiot okay
they are obedient people who have a
degree in philosophy and you are among
them a idiot so that that is my if you
are watching a talk show that is what it
what is that that is my opinion about
that that is what my talk talk about
that talk show about that
not-safe-for-work so cut that close that
show Emacs and let's create that in
showing browser okay so there is a
mistake we don't want the we don't want
the nested list okay so there is more
mistake
ladies so that's so far today's topic so
back to back to my computer set up my
multitudes of digressions computer setup
and I'm going to read comments ok later
in the swamp
so we talked about computer
configuration which we began but haven't
finished yet
then we talked about yeah my Linux setup
then leader in the swamp then not safe
for walk ok and and I guess I so my
computer setup so there are so many
other steps ok and this page is written
this page is written back in 2012 so so
2012 it's what is this 7 years old ok so
you see this girl is talking this ad she
is telling us to go daddy.com fish from
florence this ad adds well my roommate
is back so I didn't fan you know they
are back so I should get off
so let's see the comments okay so I'm
gonna so this is my Linux setup then
there is a mouse setup auto race swap
mouse button so so this is 77 years old
some of the things I probably would
change and there's Firefox set mouse
core your speed
Firefox I wouldn't do that today because
I have I have infinite scroll mouse I
showed that many times spin spin wheel
so set Firefox custom hotkeys I don't do
that neither because now I have I'd
rather use a firmware programmable
keypad instead of you know diddling with
each application about setting keys but
anyway if you don't have a programmable
keyboard then you know you might you
might do something like that I show you
how to so for example Firefox add change
keyboard shortcuts and also Firefox you
know the browser has been changing and
changing so I'm not sure even you can do
that today yeah so you install this
plug-in you can change your Firefox keys
this is back in 2013 but they have
changed you know there they are platform
you know the Firefox their plug-in
system have changed you know they went
through revamped several times so back
here so anyway so that's about and
infante about you know then you have to
install found then you have to I have to
install software these are the essential
software I have to install so you have
to install pure essential apt-get then
install vim the full vim because by
default the Ubuntu comes with a
stripped-down wim
then you have to install SSH you have to
install Tmax you have to install git you
have to install subversion which is some
still sometimes used you have to install
curl unison each table and I have a
tutorial for each one of them then you
have to install Python 3 on open - I
think you I think you still have to on
some Linux distro distro python 3 is now
default but not montano and then you
have to install not jazz for JavaScript
then you have to install a bunch of
things Perl PHP image magic ft PNG for
compressing PNG files then tree for
viewing directory or so tree you know a
bunch of programs so that you know let
me show you the directory tree command
so this is a Linux command that shows
directory as a tree which is very
convenient when you dive into a project
you know you want to get a understanding
of the directory structure using usually
so usually there are lots of directories
and subdirectories so this tree the
utility is a quick way to know to see
the directory structure I used to do
this a lot because every time I get into
a new project I have to know you know
not not to you guys probably you know
modern people you don't you don't care
you you just follow the good money since
you just follow the steps you know the
react or whatever but for me I have to
know the structure and I have to know
every directory what is what is it for I
have to know every file I have to know
where you know when this react or
whatever crap they tell you to install a
command just run this command install a
bunch of things I have to know where do
they go what
they go what structure they created and
what are each file their purpose that's
what I have to know my roommates so so
tree is a useful command to to to do
that and if you want to do things like
the way I do you have to spend a lot of
time you know how us and usually these
days they don't even explain you are on
your own they don't explain what's the
directory structure you see why am i
doing that you know so my mindset this
mindset came from like you have to know
everything on your system like I know
everything like every directory every
fire on my system so when I run a
command I have to know exactly what it
does you know today since 10 years ago
the starting with a ruby [ __ ] a
ruby community they tell you to run the
command you know like you paste a
command to your terminal shell as a
single shell line then you just down
over the shell scripting runners shell
script it's a [ __ ] idiocy okay so
like so beginning with that you don't
even know like it it began the mindset
where you you don't know what's going on
when you run out command you don't know
that's that's a man site
mindset today you just you just go to
whatever new library fancy with your
fancy website you know or the fancy
beautiful website they tell you to run
this command just just type this in your
terminal and you type it in a bunch of
things going on you don't know what's
going on
that's a today's situation and and this
began 15 years ago 17 year around 2008
or so so the way I do things I need to
know everything you know I need to know
when you run this command what exactly
well it create firewood you know what it
does do exactly you have to know you
know so so and it takes a lot of time
for me to learn a new thing today
so anyway so that's about my Linux setup
I don't know if that completes that if H
s so what is f H s so I'm going to read
comments and and let's see how long have
I been talking Carson hi Carson oh my
god I got 20 people watching oh my god
not 20 he's a lot so I've been talking
for almost an hour so maybe so f H s
what is it guys spell things out stop
these abbreviations so I get Far East
High School guys stop these
abbreviations type the full thing out so
let me be the comments see what people
are saying
so Kathy says if the communism doesn't
work what else can save us from the
endless near listen Kathy they're there
we began down the rabbit hole
Zee Tron crazy experiment check out
different subjects George says why is
them now they die in the swamp Allen
says Linux config is opiate for the
Nerds indeed you're gonna spend
configured teetering it every day
forever in this then you're gonna talk
to people I go I then we have on the on
the you know on discord and elsewhere on
reddit then we have a forum dedicated to
show your configs Vokoun welcome welcome
is the leader of that de volcán is
welcome here everyday you're gonna just
you're gonna show your configs
and so a a sink a so so Aaron says use
mainstream OS and let your mind be free
from config a SS I think aesthetics
mostly prevents near listen so so what
I'm saying so you see a a your usage of
Newell ISM is in the negative side you
see that's what I'm criticizing kneel
ISM is a fundamental core philosophy
that's not it's just a philosophy I mean
and necessary inevitably so when if you
follow rationale you know rationalism
you know to the core or not agnosticism
if you follow those two a call you still
have you know then you have several
schools and nearly some is one of the
result and it's not net it's not
necessarily negative okay it's not like
it doesn't mean destruction that's what
you know
a lot of misunderstanding is about they
say oh you know just near ISM is just
destruction no it's not it's just
science you know you won't have to
follow science near reason that's what
you have so so a says I think aesthetics
mostly prevents near reason
yeah I know what you mean so you are
saying so aesthetic that that that is
some that is true you know these some
philosophers believe in that you know so
you you have nearly 'some which is which
is nothing means anything anymore so
what do you what can you do once you
have that where are we you you can have
several things such as beauty beauty is
important beauty you know we strive for
beauty yeah it's true you know in some
sense logically we don't know why are we
here so that but that doesn't mean we
just you know [ __ ] around every day like
this for charm people in the on one hand
you have the social justice people they
are you know they just [ __ ] around on
the other side is the social you know is
a 4chan people they just [ __ ] around
with the law and everything law no you
do know you that's what I did because
they have those they have they become
you know they have they had they are the
kind of the loser of society you know
they have nothing else to lose anymore
so and many of you young people's so
they become this law they just know
everything they don't have no meaning no
nothing and there's nothing they can do
they they became this fortune style type
of people you know the that's what they
became maybe the the the the the loser
of society the fringe that's what they
became so and you know and meanwhile on
one one side you have the social justice
who says is this aesthetic is no good
we must embrace fat people you know they
destroy or you know the classic beauty
and structure they destroy you know
there they are into you know the social
justice that's what they do they destroy
they don't want you know they are
degenerate nudism they are they are you
know you might say they are you know one
branch of new reason they do generate
they destroy anything then nothing means
anything anymore so they have this
post-modernism okay that's one side on
the other side you have the chance for
lack of better term to to categorize
these people these chan people they also
lost they've also become lost you know
on one hand they are anti social justice
but but they have no power
they've meanwhile you know everything is
open source so if you are a programmer
nothing you can do because everything
you do it is already open so sponsored
by Google you cannot leave you know the
only way out is to work for Google and
Facebook these open-source [ __ ] but
they don't know they still they think
they are they are Cham people they are
we are the fighters they are trying to
if they think they are fighting the
social disease and they type into all
sort of weird things but they they are
the loser
they are the fringe and lose of society
that's what they are ok that's that is
my opinion this is you know the if
you're watching a talk show that's what
I'm talking that's that's me I'm talking
so these fortune people and they think
you know that the thing is the thing is
they think they think they are the
cheetah or something they think they are
you know trying to swat the society
thought the powers no they are they are
just actually just losers they are loser
at the bottom of society nothing they
can do maybe yet in the day time they
work for some companies they work for
Google they need the data at night they
go to fortune or reddit or hacker news
they they they spew out this law and
kick all this you know they kept the fog
they think they are doing
Ellucian these [ __ ] and and with
the based based based [ __ ] based I'm
based guys
these people know nothing about society
and everyone in modern society everyone
you lost nearly Sam that's a philosophy
but also in reality in modern society
especially in the past ten years
Dredd by you know these social networks
this Twitter and Facebook they create
you know they have driven you into
garbage like you don't know what's going
on anymore and they they make money
so what I am saying so so you know I I
should try to say okay so what I'm
trying what I'm saying I'm what I
recommend is that you guys okay you guys
go out make contact with other people
okay make meaningful contact not hiding
in some online forum and do and post
your political opinions or kick or blow
or whatever [ __ ] okay
does it doesn't work okay we have
already that you know you make contact
show you face show your ID okay say what
you believe in and if you have to go to
jail for that so be it that's meaningful
okay don't you know that that's that is
my opinion okay that that is that is my
opinion on how things should be how we
make a change to society okay I don't
know if that's gonna walk okay maybe
that we are not walk but you know I
because you know these things nobody you
know I think nobody knows the answer but
but if you ask my opinion some of you do
then my opinion is that how do i how do
we fix this well we fix this by you know
to stop listening to the Twitter social
networks and say things you believe in
with your face okay with your ID like
this is my idea this is my idea okay and
I believe this should be this way and
and if you if if there is something you
think it's too controversial that you
shouldn't say that you only say when you
are anonymous then don't say it okay
then don't say it stop [ __ ] saying it
if you you know that's what I believe if
you think oh no if I if you're gonna say
it you're gonna be fired then don't say
it okay then shut the [ __ ] up and
believe whatever you your company wants
you to believe just just you know put
put put money where your mouth is okay
don't don't do this
fake news or whatever this tends to
happen okay my my roommate is back I
don't feel I should go off I should
that's that should be it for today
because you know my roommate is hearing
me swearing out and all that you might
not want to others to see you seeing
this
other few times I agree 100% with you
opinion about a SFW okay but but help to
call stuff they are true name George
says well put a trigger warning on that
yeah trigger warning that's a
consequence that's a that's that's you
know that's what I believe you know the
a where does they came from you know in
part it came from this NSFW mentality in
particular because once you had a jargon
okay it is not safe for work this this
very concept not safe for walk okay my
roommate yeah I got my roommates
knocking I gotta go okay
trigger warning recursion one in idiot
he had intellectual Talib taps okay
that's it for today and thank you guys
for watching
Cathy how do you know of my how do you
know about the spider thing I think I
talked about it before he was a long
time ago thank in 1995 okay bye guys
so one more minutes let's see what did I
miss
I got a lot of things to talk about so
it's like if I don't do a video you know
I've been missing I haven't been doing
video in the past four days you know
doing video takes a lot of time and but
once I do a video I have like tons of
things to talk about and non-stop so
it's gonna be one hour and more so
anyway that's it for today thank you
guys for watching bye guys