good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's show good morning
Emily good morning Bart today's 2019
December 3rd
Tuesday 10 o clock in the morning San
Francisco time and what is the topic
guys so if there is no topic then I'm
just going to start to talk random
random stuff today actually we did talk
about random random indeed about the
topic of random the other day with
special guest
well prompted by Emily that is random
what is random what is pseudo-random the
math definition of random so we talked
about that two days ago
big noises outside so so that is random
that you know we talked about that then
yesterday ok
two days ago we did what is metadata
metadata and the secret embedded in
metadata images and then yesterday we
were talking about the fascinating
subject of matrix the math of matrix and
vectors and what I mean and it turns out
we had a great discovery that about the
etymology of matrix that is the origin
of the name matrix hey but I had a topic
you for that ok that's great
so Emily says super computers ok so
again talk about super computers and
justin hays morning ok so we don't have
a we don't really have a topic today so
just post random ok keep posting stuff
you post I talk if I got nothing to say
about that you keep posting ok that's
that's the way it goes so matrix it
turns out you know
yesterday so arranged on the arrangement
of the meaning of the word matrix is
womp uterus so that is why we have the
matrix the movie you know the movie
matrix because you know I always thought
the matrix just means a grid I thought
that was the origin because because I'm
math biased so I thought matrix just
means a grid and so the wind when the
matrix movie came out it's kind of
annoying they named it matrix because I
don't want it to be named matrix you
know I want make sure matrix just be
math matrix not some science science
fiction red pea or brute EOP or whatever
but but then it turns out so we look at
the etymology of matrix so that means
whomp uterus so that movie title is
appropriate because they are talking
about you know the artificial farm
artificial womb and by the way that will
solve the men versus women problem yes
indeed when you have artificial
whomp-whomp
you know when you eliminate sex entirely
by biology so you no longer there is no
longer sex not even chromosome whatever
you limit there's no difference
whatsoever
that is when we have total equality
you don't want movie about math well no
no I'd want movie about math but I want
I don't want movie about math
but however the point is that the Matrix
movie it is not about math it's about
some science fiction pop science fiction
okay popular pop science fiction and I
don't want math to has anything to do
with that that is the thing but you know
so but but then I discovered matrix
actually means womp okay so that is
actually appropriate for that movie but
anyway when when movies you know the
hard
would or whatever then when they talk
about math usually it's no good
usually it's just no good okay they can
you know sometimes snow and then you
have movies about mathematicians such as
a beautiful mind okay then I watch it
it's enjoyable but usually it's all just
okay because you know why
because math is a subject the nature of
math is the austerity and coldness that
is a beauty the immense beauty of
mathematics that is code Ness and
austerity you don't you don't like oh
let's do math and let's have fun you
know that that that throws away the
entire essence of mathematics so that's
not going to work you know in modern
society we have you know like in Silicon
Valley you know the people take people
or stem you know women let's get women
into technology you know they trying to
oh let's make math math fun let's make
you know let's do collaborative things
it's you know player game method that's
not going to work okay the the heart of
mathematics is the code nosov it there's
nothing with the you know the pop and
make it attractive things you know if
you find if you if you get into math via
that you are not going to get far
usually your take okay I'm talking about
that's my opinion because because what
you think of a map of mathematics is a
trap you know that is what what not
lesson that that is not what mathematics
really is because when you really start
to get into math then you realize that's
not that's not what you thought it is
you know it's not gonna be fun the way
you think it's going to be the way these
people this you know help society help
whatever you know they trying to make it
to be however you see math is a subject
is such a image
Beauty it does not need you Petty
corporations or you petty government to
try to help people to get into math you
don't did you know math don't don't need
you guys
math don't need it big and and there are
geniuses you know who is a great mind
they type into math all their life you
know they they they they they live in
poverty and they just dive into they
type they living in a math you know like
Emacs but farm also and they did they do
not need this this these traps of
appearances or what what not so that is
math okay well at least that's my
opinion of math okay so Daniel say is hi
hi hi Daniel
so it's Justin so Emily mentioned about
supercomputers okay let's talk about
supercomputers I don't know much about
but it's you know in Smith's just talk
about supercomputers so Emily posted
this message about this supercomputer
that's K computer also crash hacker is
in Bangkok Airport one night in Bangkok
we will reach tomorrow so this
supercomputer I don't know nothing about
K computer oh okay this is me this is a
phone version of Wikipedia I don't want
phone versions I want the real versions
by the way is there any difference like
is there any difference in content
between the phone version of Wikipedia
and the web version the desktop version
so anyway this is the desk supercomputer
we cannot look into but yesterday I was
you know I was trying to pronounce the
pronunciation part of the English so I
was trying to distinguish a ball and a
ball okay
so we have a ball ballpark you know you
we have football soccer we have food
football it's supposed to be bah-bah
football football game ballgame ballgame
not ball game
whoa versus Paul and I was also trying
to pronounce the you know the Kinesis
keyboard which is a ball-shaped keyboard
like a rice ball rice ball so Bob versus
Paul
okay chat comments chat guys comments
let me know what you think okay so we
let's see three we got three people
watching what a paucity we have a
paucity of population and unless you're
going yes I am so Kay computers what
what is about the Kay computers so the K
computers let's just read okay super
computers K computer the K computer
named for the Japanese word numero Chi
meaning 10 quadrillion 10 to the 16th
power is a supercomputer manufactured by
Fujitsu country installed at Rankine
advanced Institute for computational
science campus in copy anyway in Tokyo I
mean not in Tokyo Kobe Kobe his kind of
a city of JSON to Tokyo kind of so he's
seen so in Japan and the K computer is
based on a distributed memory
architecture ok with over 80,000
computer nots 80,000 ok it is used for a
variety of applications including
climate research disaster prevention and
medical research ok
the k computer's operating system is
based on the Linux kernel and additional
drivers designed to make use of
computers hardware additional drivers
designed to make use of the computers
hardware ok in June
Kobe beef hi Nabi good morning Abby
so in June 2011 top 500 ranked Cade the
world's fastest computer this okay so
that's 2011 that's you know a bit old
ten years ago nine years ago with a
computational speed of over eight
petaflop petaflops and in november 2011
k became the first computer to top top
ten petaflops okay
however suspended superseded okay so
okay so it was the world's fastest
supercomputer back in 2011 but those
rankings they change about every two
years because i've been looking at them
the top 500 or 100 supercomputers
they're the ranking you know which is a
top 10 they change about every two years
right now the the fastest supercomputer
is made by American I think last time
like this year I checked and for the
past three years also it's China
it's made from China so let's look at so
Emilee anything interesting about this k
computer so as of November 2018 okay
computer holds the third place for the
HPC G benchmark it held the first race
until June 2018
oh so the case of a computer was a was
decommissioned Oh in 2019 in Japan the K
computer will be succeeded by Fuuka
Fuuka ku expected to be ten hundred
expected to be hundred times faster
scheduled to be operational in 2021
so part says how do you know the lyrics
of
cassia's who how do I know I don't know
how do you know do I know I don't know
at the who is Tommy cash Emily says it's
it's networking uses a six Taurus
architecture sixty Taurus architecture
so six dimensional Taurus
okay so so you have a surface that's six
dimensional Taurus now I don't quite
understand that so basically it's
normally your Taurus surface is
two-dimensional so now you have a 6
dimensional Taurus architecture so Emily
says it's networking uses a 60
architecture okay so so what does I mean
I mean okay so one thing is that what
does it you know I don't understand I
don't think we understand what does a
six dimensional Taurus means I mean we
kind of know what it means but what what
is its properties and why is there
special things like that so that's one
thing the math aspect of six dimensional
Taurus okay
the other aspect is what does it mean
when you have a 60 Taurus
architecture for networking in a
specification section
okay so performance specification not
architecture network file system power
consumption you know these kind of
things you have to actually know you
have to you know to and to really
appreciate like I can just read them off
but it just fly by I I wouldn't get a
thing so to understand to appreciate
this spec
details you really need to be someone
who is very interested in hardware I
mean a lot of you guys are you know
Linux nuts Linux FreeBSD people you know
you guys know these things I don't
really know them because I'm usually not
interested in in the you know in a
hardware but also besides that as far as
I know supercomputers their architecture
is entirely different from you know your
home PC architecture so totally
different so so that's something else to
learn so anyway the not architecture
network file system so let's read the
art not architecture so the K computer
comprises comprises eighty eight
thousand to jjigae Hertz eight core
sparc64
eight FX processors contained oh you
know interesting they are still using
spark spark CPU I thought it's dead okay
but well this is 19th this is 2011 right
it's a bit confusing I mean is it 2011
or 2019 how is it the new generation or
something well anyway so he says it says
you know it uses eighty eight thousand
of to jjigae hertz eight core sparc64
something-something processor contained
in 864 cabinets for a total of something
something for a total of seven hundred
course seven hundred thousand course
manufactured by Fujitsu with 45
nanometer CMOS technology each cabinet
contains 96 96 computing arts in
addition to six io knots each computing
not contains a single processor and 16
gigabyte memory
the computers water cooling system is
designed to minimize failure rate in
power consumption okay Oh your network
Emily is talking about so Network let's
see the knots are interconnected by Fuji
Zeus proprietary Taurus fusion
interconnect okay the knots so nards
means what does not smiie not means okay
each computing not contains a single
processor okay basically a nod means a
single processor okay so the network the
knots are interconnected by Fuji Zeus
proprietary Taurus fusion interconnect
Taurus has a six dimensional mesh
tourists apology oh okay that that makes
sense now okay so what a second I need
to
Taurus tofu has a six dimensional mesh
tourists apology six dimensional mesh
tourists apology so and see if I can
kind of get a sense of it six
dimensional tourists apology okay a
scalability of over 100,000 knots food
to flex links that have a peak bandwidth
of something something each knot is
connected to its own interconnect
controller chip which contains photo for
interfaces okay those are just going
over my head so Baba because you know if
you are not familiar with these things
you know actually most programmers even
hacker nerds
I don't think yes I don't suppose you
understand I mean you are not because to
appreciate them you really to appreciate
this SPECT you really have to be
familiar with basically all all the
supercomputers like you know you know
just by memory what's the other super
computers SPECT then you can see oh wow
this is much more something like that
so tofu 60 mention of mesh tourist
apologies abstracted by software to
appear as a three-dimensional torus okay
this is getting confusing okay and these
supers and is supported by tofu
optimized version of the open source
open MPI message passing interface
library users can create application
programs adopted to either one two or
three-dimensional torus Network so I
don't understand what it says so Emily
do you understand what it says like what
is like basically what why is it so
great why is six to mention of mesh
tourists apology
no I didn't thought hyper Damaris
coughing okay hyperdimensional donut
yeah you know they are several confusing
things here okay first of all I you know
I like to mention when when programmers
okay when these computing stuff okay
when they talk about math jargons when
they use math Chagas they are either
using it as analogy or a little bit of
marketing like jargon you know buzzwords
they are not really using math job ins
correctly because so Emily says but also
a hyperdimensional exit form in topology
is cool so hyper dimensional tech exit
yeah I don't understand what do you mean
exit so exit is at a specific jargon in
hardware architecture or something
everyone who bought it
so I'm highly interested in higher
dimensional stuffs okay so you know my
own comment well I just make some random
fat okay I'm gonna just do some soffit
so first of all when computer when the
engineers or you know computer people
when they use smart math jargons it's
partly marketing is partly you know
coolness it's partly something else it's
part of your analogy so so in many cases
they just don't use the math term
wrongly or incorrectly so so when so
here they say exit for me equals student
walking Oh
exit forming equals through networking
oh okay a typo so
Weiwei is a shame what did she say so
hyperdimensional networking topology is
cool
okay so Emily says hyper you know
higher-dimensional networking topology
is cool I don't yeah you know I don't
really understand what it means okay now
when you talk about networking
networking so you know suppose that
means you have bunch of knots and you
have lines connected to each knots you
know so you form a graph and when you
say so what does that mean when you say
they are hyper dimensional like higher
dimension like in math okay in math you
have one dimensional two dimensional
three dimensional then beyond three
typically use a higher dimension so
higher dimension means four five six or
more dimensions that's the convention in
math so you can just say higher
dimension now now hyper dimension now I
don't think hyper dimension is a term
using math okay and I'm just throwing
out my random thoughts okay how about
this hyper dimension I don't think
that's term using math you you know if
if you want to pick bones maybe you'll
find an article oh there's a hyper
dimensional something something but
typically it's not it's not mainstream
math okay let's just say so you we don't
use the word hyper dimension but we do
have higher dimension means four five
six seven so anyway back to the
networking so networking so they are
talking about networking topology okay
now when you have a computer network you
have more basically you consider each
not connected to other knots now there
are several type of connections now I
can come a little bit for me with that
being a sis at me and you know so let's
see net walking topology so networking
topology just means the structure
of how knots are connected basically you
see a graph okay like that okay so you
have this type of networking topology
you have a ring which means basically
each computer is connected like that
like like a ring you know like a ring oh
you have a line or you have a tree or
you have a star topology which is some
sometimes popular then you have fully
connected meaning every knot is
connected to any every other so that's
fully connected let's click it let's
make it big okay
so fully connected topology networking
topology then you have this bus topology
okay so so networking topology basically
means is it means how the nodes are
connected the it's important because the
reason they are connected has
consequences for example if you have a
lie then suppose one of them is down one
of the computer is down then you don't
then your network becomes separated you
know these three computers cannot talk
to the other because you know they are
connected in such a way on the other
hand if you have a star system do you
have one advantage here because then you
have a central hub so that hub can send
our information to all the other nodes
kind of like a central hook so but if
that one dies then then your you know
basically your your network is dead but
but it it does have the advantage where
you have the central hub you know send
out all information on the other hand if
you have a lie if you have a hub that's
most important and when it sends out
information it has to pass to each and
every other one by one so it's kind of
so you have different properties you
know that's why this networking topology
are important so you have mesh mesh is
kind of just random like like
there's a new foam protocol like code
mesh something where are you anyway
mesh is kind of just random like so
anyway so you have this these are
typical you know conventional
traditional networking topologies and
each of the dot you can either think of
it as a computer or in a case of super
computers they are talking about each
not is a CPU basically now I don't know
the I don't know about super computers
but what I try to read them now and then
so one so one of the important thing
about super computer is that they are
not simply just massive number of CPUs
working together okay it's not you won't
walk so if you let's say you if you have
billions of money billions of dollars
you just gonna buy you know 1 billion
Linux you know the Intel C Linux machine
and you just connect them via via the
ethernet and you think you gonna get a
supercomputer no you don't ok so
apparently the the the gist about these
supercomputers is is about how the CPUs
are connected you know the CPU needs to
be connected to talk to each other to
that's that's what makes them special
that's what makes them super powerful
fast you need to have a special way or
design or whatever to get the CPUs to
talk to each other so I suppose I don't
know for sure I suppose that's why they
have a section about the network
topology here they are using you know
six dimensional mesh tourists apology or
whatever so anyway so back to the
network networking topology topology so
you have you know these these are the
topologies then we look at this one the
supercomputer K computer so they are
saying they are using Sixth Amendment or
astrology so my question I mean I don't
understand so Bank my question is what
what does it mean when you have like
higher dimensional topology like what
what what does it mean okay we can
actually look so if you don't understand
something you click and look now they
have explanations so first of all they
have mesh network okay this I kind of
understand basically just means random
okay the advantage or the situation
about mesh networking is that random so
why so basically usually this occurs
when you have the knots that can come on
and off at any time
unpredictably you know not not plan so
so imagine all the cell phones in the
world they can form a Nash mesh
networking because each cell phone can
suddenly come on or come off so anyway
that's I think that's the gist of mesh
network okay so okay so now here they
explain tourist connection let's see so
a torus interconnect is a switch less
network topology for connecting
processing nodes in a parallel computer
system oh okay
so does that make sense
that's what you are saying right Emily
Ola Gabriel
Gabe Gabriel so ok torus interconnect is
a switch less network topology for
connecting processing not seeing a
parallel computer system so we have to
we you know you have to think about
these a little bit to see what it means
so let's see let's magnify ok well first
of all so let's read the description
first so it says three-dimensional torus
network this topology is often used by
high-performance computing systems okay
so three-dimensional torus Network okay
let's have a look so now we see one two
three four five six seven eight one two
three four five six eight knots
basically the corner of a cube so you
have eight knots and they are connected
let's see let's look at the red lines
first okay so this these two these two
from Sissoko these two Hunziker this to
form a circle oh okay so now I see the
pattern so you see so these two form a
circle then then the green is workers
these two form a circle this to form a
circle these to form a circle these to
form a circle so so what does that mean
so let's look at this one does this one
ever connect to the opposite corner no
not directly you see this one on one
corner of a cube does it connect to the
other opposite corner of the cube the
answer is not directly so for this one
to talk to this one it needs to for
example pass through here then pass
through here then pass down here
something like that okay or go through
the other ways okay so did you read more
hot edge OTG no I don't know what is
h.t.t.h OTG the rain seems superfluous
yeah right you know I don't understand
it so you know you you kind of have to
specialize in these to know what they
are saying exactly so anyway that's
that's some idea of the tauros tauros
interconnect okay let's read an
introduction in geometry or torus is
created by revolving a circle around
axis this is the general definition in
geometry the topological properties of
this type of shape described innate and
networked
ecology in the sense okay okay
illustration of 3d tourists okay I kind
of get what they are saying yeah
so with - yeah but with more each tours
can be many knots long right I'll see
I'll see you right like like the picture
they show here so you have like imagine
imagine okay in one dimension you just
have a grid I mean your line a line of
computers like like this picture okay
one dimension in two dimension you have
a plane okay it's like a grid you know a
rectangular grid then each knot
basically each knot connects - yeah
each knot connects through the neighbors
basically so yeah maybe explain this
thing okay so in a two-dimensional torus
this is analogous to math so imagine a
plane agreed
then each not just connects to its
neighbors right neighbor left neighbor
top neighbor down neighbor but however
at the age H at the edge edge of the the
plane the top one will connect to the
bottom one so so this kind of thing
connection it's called a torus because
if you look at the donut that's exactly
if you kind of unwrap a doughnut that's
why it looks like so if this is the
torus and three-dimensional torus it's
easy to understand once you understand
two-dimensional tourists so instead of
in so you know you begin with a 2d torus
you and you just extend it you know so
you have now you have a grid in three
space and each each knot is connected to
the right neighbor left neighbor top
neighbor down neighbor
and folk front neighbor and backward
neighbor you know it's all connected
like that and on the edge you know on
the face of the cube you know the the
rightmost one is connected connected to
the leftmost one and vice versa for top
down and the other side so that is 3d
Taurus so now we understand you know
two-dimensional torus and
three-dimensional torus so for example
this picture this picture is trying to
show us a 3d torus now I understand why
why you have this loopback they are
trying to show ya they yeah they are
trying to show ya its redundant in this
case when you have just two of them the
the loopback is kind of redundant
redundant but anyway when you have when
you have lots of them like that then
it's not redundant because because this
one needs to connect this one needs to
connect all the way back to 2 2 2 2 2
here I think but you need to find this
too many arrows on to see but yeah but
you know I get idea so so this is an
example of 3d tourists ok so far so good
but the next question is what is a 6
dimensional torus ok ok so from 3d
tourists then you you kind of go by
analogy you got a four detours then you
got five detours then you got 60 tours
so what does it mean though I don't
quite know anyway so we can kind of at
least we have some idea hold on a second
ok wait wait so what so that's now let's
look at these connections from a one
single CPU one single now
perspective so let's look at this from
one single node perspective so this one
this is this one is using a 2d tourist
topology okay so this single knot will
be connected to one two three four
oh now I see what it means you see so if
you have a bunch of knots let's say one
thousands of them and if you connect
them in a 2d fashion like a 2d torus
then every CPU every knot will be
connected to four and only four other
knots okay let me say that again so if
you have let's say 1,000 CPUs or
whatever whatever 1000 knots and if you
connect them in this 2d torus
architecture then that means every knot
will be connected to four other CPUs
right so this is what it means but
however if you connect them in a 3d
tours fashion then each knot will be
connected to one two three four five six
six other CPUs that is if you put them
you know into a into this 3d torus
configuration okay that that now makes
better sense so you do want you do want
the 3d torus connection because that
means your CPU can talk to more other
CPUs in you know in one shot without
going through other many other CPUs okay
so so now I think you know now we I
think we have some idea about these
connections now it says it mentions 60
tourist product performance
okay Fujitsu limited developed a sixty
tours computer model in their model
sixty tourists can achieve 100 gigabytes
per second of chip
with 12 times higher scalability than 3d
tours and high fault tolerance okay they
didn't go into detail how exactly it's
done but we kind of get idea we learned
from this from 2d to 3d example we
learned we you know basically just means
each CPU now connects to much more other
CPUs directly okay yeah so that yeah
good you know we are making progress
some focus missionary working okay
anything else interesting Emily about
this so anyway so it says okay so now it
says now we can kind of appreciate it
more so it says this torus in torus
fusion or also known as tofu connection
has a six dimensional mesh towards
topology okay that means you know it
basically means each CPU is connected to
how many I don't know I you know 10 or
more 12 other CPUs and also it mentions
its mesh you see it mentions its mesh
that means probably it means you know
some CPU can be offline or disconnected
without this swap disrupting the whole
that's idea so so a scalability of over
100,000 knots and voila
okay so yeah it's it's like better and
bigger and better so so tofu's six to
mention of mesh topology is abstracted
by software okay
this part is critical you see it says
it's abstracted by software
to appear as a three-dimensional torus
oh why
I don't know okay so yeah so anyway so
okay so that's that's the that's and and
how it could be implemented okay I don't
know what I don't know about this I
don't even know I don't even know how
CPU one single CPU works really I mean
do you like do you are you like do you
study CPUs likes like CPU architectures
Emily you know but it's a big it's a big
black hole to go into you have to be
specialized into it so now let's look at
the photos now this looks like the
matrix this one array of things yeah so
you know a human is about this tall
maybe so you walk into them one full
array of things so okay and because
programmers can easily think in 3d oh
that's why Oh rather than trying to
program his CD so I was okay so yeah so
okay so Emily says okay that's
interesting so Emily says the reason
they are using software to emulate it
into a 3d tours network is because that
way programmers can easily understand it
better so therefore you know write
programs for it easier something like
that because otherwise six dimensional
torus will be hard to understand yeah
because I was wondering because I was
surprised when I read that because you
begin with us
60 mention of tourist apology then why
do you why do you reduce it down to a
three-dimensional thing you know I was
wondering my neighbor I mean my my book
mate is telling me to eat breakfast or
something so anyway so that's ok that's
super computers I think that's about it
you know maybe I should talk to my
roommate I don't know what is mesh
networking so anything else interesting
let's see how long I've been talking for
46 minutes so top500 you know I've been
looking at the supercomputers of the you
know I checked this article now and then
like every two years or so also just for
interesting things and so the top one
today one and two is us a again okay
that's good to know the top one and two
is us a by IBM Summit and Sierra so what
processor are they using power nine
power night okay I don't know what they
are
interconnect InfiniBand okay and you
know for a while for several years it's
all China this King who are light okay
so the in Japan right now is eighth
place by the way this most of these are
just marketing they don't I mean they
don't mean that much they means
something though but you know it doesn't
mean too much but anyways it's okay so
anyway I think anything else interesting
I'm thinking shutting down I think I
should talk to my roommate for a minute
hold on a second okay one be right back
in one minute
and probably we shut down and unless you
guys have interesting saying things say
it okay
my roommates I have I have like three
roommates okay actually four so they are
they are husband and wife and the son of
the husband and another guy they are
pretty old okay except the son which is
30 something the others are you know 50
60 or something okay Emily what else so
let's see what what other interesting
things so super computers you know today
it looks quiet
does it appear to you guys quiet or is
it just me
it looks quite today is today is
December 3rd and Tuesday Tuesday usually
is not quiet I don't think so so but
what's up but so Emily why are you
interested I mean what for example why
why do you why are you interested in
this one and why are you interested in
the 6th dimension of topology the tour
astrology because for example this one
is not currently not the most powerful
today it is not the most powerful so how
come you stood suddenly mention this one
in particular I'm walking and listening
Oh
so just in do you kodak do you code a
hostile work
so this morning I had a donut you know
my you made the Sun now the the roommate
the younger one he is driving interstate
driving 18 wheelers now in UK it's
called lorry you UK has this funny term
for 18-wheelers they call it lorry right
Emily right right and just Justin in
Canada what do they call it did you call
it in a lorry or one and also you know
you know how I learned the term Laurie
because arethe mix ok let me show you
now cuz some music now we need to go
into the realm of art and music so
justing works with Scala in Java
oh that's still that's still pretty cool
because you code in Scala Scala is a
functional programming language as far
as I know you know it's not pure and it
has lots of ways to do things
Oh Justine says we call Lori a semi but
I am from UK before I came to Canada
oh so mulling drug muling Rouge
now is a pronounced moon in Russia or
Rock Russia I think so there is a tongue
twister try to say red lorry yellow
lorry yet red lorry yellow lorry did I
get anything wrong so Amy says it was
recently decommissioned and the 60
tourists apology was unique oh that's I
see that's why that's interesting so you
know super computers yeah this is this I
don't you know I don't think I'm too
much
interested in that I mean I'm interested
of course like you know like when you
read a pop mechanics or pop science or
pop fiction but you know you have to get
you know this this is kind of a very
specialized thing so Canada is semi semi
a semi is still kind a US would his
lorry so UK is Laurie so there is this
youth mix song okay
sorry music you need to go through I
need to go to Saudi music okay not that
not not they're human animals and their
songs now I have to remember which you
with make song it is that contains the
word lorry
do you guys remember you with mix they
are from they are from UK are they or
are they American hello from Russia
hello ye you are why okay let's let's
talk about this and then they'll be it
so you rythmics they have quite a few
songs let me let me show them the names
okay so you have sisters we are doing
sisters are doing it for themselves
this is kind of for feminism song back
in 1990s okay and then you with mix I
need a man you with mix the day you know
the they are great singers the girl this
this this woman her name is good band
yes and this one I need a man this this
this one is actually funny too so but
I need to think about the the song where
they mentioned the lorry it's kind of a
medal it's kind of mellow so it's not I
need a man and they have a song the king
and queen of America which is kind of
shall we say anti America
okay the king and queen of America and
they have a song let's see next
missionary man now missionary man is
kind of making fun of Christians
okay missionary men and you know so so
let's see and let's see try one more
sweet dreams now sweet dreams is one of
the most popular song sweet dreams are
made of these Who am I to disagree I
travel the world around the seven seas
everybody's looking for something some
of them want to use you some of them
want to get used by you some of them
want to abuse you some of them want to
be abused indeed all the different
people in a world that's their most
famous song okay so actually now the
song that contains the world Laurie is
not the is not their song but however
she did sing it so I remember so let's
go to my some music website and such for
Laurie and we all find it and that will
be here today not there
such again well oh okay what
okay now we need to get out the bigger
gun
I I don't sing well okay so I try to not
to embarrass people so so we need to get
into fish out my goal and script and
type Laurie there you have it okay
that's my so type Laurie in here such
all my websites we shut down in three
minutes or so there it is don't let it
bring you down now you guys know the
song I'm pretty sure some of you too now
let's see if I have it don't let it
bring you down okay actually I don't
have it on my website I just mentioned
it it is in my list of words you know we
have I have English vocabulary I collect
them so you have all these bunch of
words so don't let's bring up that song
and let's say goodbye don't let it bring
you down I need I need JavaScript come
on Prasad of a new taste search
oh so it's a neo young song no I don't
want now there is a version son by the
by the by the Eurythmics girl okay so
you want to listen to that version
that's fantastic I should have I should
have it somewhere but I forgot which
page I wrote about it
but let's show that and that Debbie it
so what is this Neil Young I don't want
Neil Young's version I'm not too
familiar with Neil Young yep that is the
one there it is let's listen the to this
for few seconds okay
bye guys