hey guys so today I'm going to continue
yesterday's yesterday's tightening of
JavaScript to draw math graphics so
yesterday it's part 1 and today now it's
part 2 and we're gonna finish finish
this in 30 minutes so now it's 732 we're
gonna finish in 20 minutes or 30 minutes
we can do it I'm pretty sure so what
we're gonna draw is this it's a math
curve any one of these and it's pretty
easy I'm gonna show you so if you
haven't watched yesterday you can watch
yesterday but we're gonna do it from
scratch so let's begin so what we're
gonna do is first of all create a HTML
file okay save it I'm using Emacs so you
can see oh you can see all my commands
on the upper left window so save this as
just run the name xxx HTML okay
create the HTML template test - let's
say test - so that's our file and create
a JavaScript test has two
link it and the file is empty created
for the date console.log something
something okay and we cannot show this
in Safari because in Firefox I don't
have JavaScript on so but in Safari
I have JavaScript on and you can see
command option I the console.log it says
something that's good
so first of all we're gonna add a dive
element so X X X 80 X X X and add a
style it's not xxx its TTT okay add a
style and let's say border okay
over the read and see we have a border
and now let's say okay so get Helmand by
ID okay
documents constants get element by ID TT
and so what that what does that do is it
grabs it grabs this type elements and
we're gonna create a so then we're gonna
create a SG of an element so I forgot my
G element
I forgot the syntax so let's go to my
JavaScript his SVG reference so create
SG let's see if I can create element
okay
create element namespace yeah that's the
one so document create element namespace
[Music]
well SVG it's SVG is XML and it has a
special it's not just create element it
has created element n yes yes for
namespace it's it's somewhat complicated
but it's just cheat and copy this line
so copy go back here okay there it is
document create create element a yes and
you need this you are hi and so this
line create a SVG element then what
we're gonna do is to attach this element
to to that to here to here so what what
will happen is actually just these wow
let's just coat it and we show the
results so um so X so appendchild yeah X
appendchild a paint child and SPG one so
what this does is to append this element
to this element so that's the code save
it and this foot they said Vardhan we
don't need it really but okay DVD
okay so let's show in Safari okay that
looks good and if you can if you look at
debugger you can see you see we added
the SVG element here
can we enlarge it yes okay you see okay
so we got an SP chairman now let's add
let's add a circle we did this yesterday
so why not just copy the code copy so
create a circle so so this create a new
element circle and add attribute CX CX
is 80 C Y is 80 those are coordinates x
and y in radio study feel read well okay
yeah let's do that so go back to Safari
and reload okay it's not working
oh yeah we need to attach the circle to
the Tuda is SVG so we're gonna do is SVG
one attach circle refresh there there is
our circle now what we want to do is to
actually draw draw these so what's the
plan so these curves are actually a
parametric formula so this is how they
are generated by rolling a circle inside
the circle but we don't care about that
now you know it's fun to do an animation
eventually you're gonna write you can
write a JavaScript to create this
animation but for now we just want to
generate the static graphics like like
one of these and that is done by a
formula you can see your formula okay
plane curves epic rocket have a trunk
are in a hyper tracker so these are
variations they just differ by parameter
so here is a parametric formula copy so
so what we want to do is the ok formula
we creative we create a formula that's
one parameter T and it will create so
we're gonna write this formula first
that's what we're gonna do so what
should it return it should let's let's
have it return a vector of array in
JavaScript so the array is going to be
two parts so the first part is that the
second part is that and but we gotta
need the correct JavaScript syntax for
the formula so a and B are a and B are
parameters are constants so let's define
a and B so hey B let's say I forgot what
the proper value should be but let's
just say a and B equals 1 so now we have
a formula here and
yeah let's forget about efficiency and
everything about that we just want to
quickly get this done let's see if we
can so okay so cosine cosine is in
JavaScript I believe is math cosine
I don't remember it's capitalized or not
but let's see at JavaScript syntax
JavaScript reference math so math power
logs
sine cosine okay it's lowercase trick
methods yeah so it's just lowercase so
math cosine so we're gonna what we're
gonna do is replace cosine by that
okay and replace sine by
don't need that don't need that so
Ava's be math let's add a
so it's easier to see math cosine T of
course this gotta be T sine T and okay
so we're gonna replace all the square
bracket by parenthesis change bracket
square per reign okay
so so that should be it
so let's see if our function compiles so
let's go to Safari and reload looks good
so formula let's change it to FF saves
typing now we got a formula what we want
to do is first of all let's try to put
darts in in yet
what so what what do you mean so for
example if you look at the SVG there are
several elements we can draw a line
square circle so what we're gonna do is
we draw a circle very tiny radius so
it's just one single thought and then we
then we basically so so this is a curve
we just gonna put lots of thoughts on it
then later on we can change it to line
but doing lines is slightly more
complicated let's just two darts first
so if we can do it dots in you know 15
more minutes how you know how code a
success because then it's easy to change
starts to line I mean the idea is just
to show the basic idea of how to do this
so okay so we have the formula and now
we want to create circles circles like
that we have to create huge number of
circles like hundred thousands of
circles on this on a curve so
so we actually need to write a function
so let's let's try to function then
let's it just say create dot and create
that head at X&Y position and also
attach it to element so what so what we
want to do okay create a circle a
seviche element element and attach it to
the Hermant e-l sequoia trees create a
circle SVG element centered on XY with
radius R and attached it to element yeah
so yeah so that's what we wanted to
create out so we're gonna create a
circle so let's copy that whole thing
here so create a circle create a circle
element centered on X Y so this is going
to be X 2 string to string so function
right yeah so here is the same
at y2 string and radios radios let's say
two pixels three three pixels and feel
create read okay let's just try that so
here we are going to so we create
element then we set attributes for those
four for the dot then we attach it to
append child - yeah that's right so here
here we have our function let's see if
we want to I'm using Emacs my own
JavaScript script mod and right now it
doesn't have a nice indentation I
haven't written it yet so anyway so we
do it manually so here is our function
and let's just try it let's make sure
this function works so we're gonna so
we're just gonna create a dot and attach
it to SVG one centered at 0 0 with
radius 3 let's say for example and we
forgot radius here okay we we actually
need
okay so let's see if we got any same cat
syntax error so Safari reload hello it
looks good
oh wait can find variable Y can't fight
oh yeah of course you've got the typo
here
perfect it's so smooth great so now
let's okay so we are successful wait
Howie no we are not successful because
this like this function should added
another circle so for this one let's
comment it out because okay actually you
see that little dot here
that's our circle you see so yeah it's
so there's something radius okay so
let's say radius 30 there it is so the
next step is that we want to now we want
to use this formula to create thousands
of dots let's do that so okay so we want
to map so basically map now JavaScript
function is kind of CV so first of all
we need a range of values so remember
this function is T so T goes from
typically 0 to PI like 0 to 3 point 1 4
or 0 to 2 pi it depends on you know what
parameters a and B are so so that the
curve will be complete
you know they will they will form a
complete loop but yeah so it depends so
but we can just try four values so first
of all we need to create a bunch of
values for T so we're going to generate
a array for example is something like
that you know 1 2 3 so
values so we're gonna generate that now
in JavaScript you don't have you don't
really have a range function like in
Python so how do you do that okay we got
javascript in depth that's my tutorial
so you know check it out I you know I
hope you like it I will I appreciate you
view you know check it out so javascript
in depth so we cannot do array and here
is array how to range function there it
is so okay we're gonna just use that you
know we not gonna do fancy stuff you
know javascript is language that pretty
sucks a lot sucks even with Eggman
script 2015 a commis script 2015 is a
huge improvement however all the wards
you know or the flow flows of JavaScript
is still there because they decided to
be 100% backward compatible basically so
but anyway to this day you don't have a
function to create a range of values but
and and even if you do like like this
code the syntax int it's pretty
incomprehensible so anyway so we have a
range function so here is n what so what
does this to okay it just okay that's
what that's not what we want because we
want not just integers we want zero to
PI you know zero to three point one four
but in increment of for example zero
point one so we actually need this this
function son range you know we can do it
you know we can do it manually and
explain each step each step you know how
we construct this function but that's
that's gonna take too much time you know
so anyway so here's a function of
syringe so here we'll just create T
values for us so so now it's good let's
just do that T values constant T values
equals Lucas our range let's say 0 to 6
in steps of 0.1 0.1 okay that's gonna be
give us a lot T values now we want to
map T values to create a bunch of this
this so T values dot map JavaScript you
know JavaScript you have this object dot
syntax they will you know anyway so
that's so the function is f F and that
should be it actually so points equals
to T values so points should be a bunch
of points knits console.log show it
print it so Safari reload let's see
there it is so great so we didn't it's
very smooth so you see we get our arrays
of arrays of values you know each each
each array is a well my roommate is
calling me but you know what each array
each element in the array is array again
and that's two values that's a
coordinate and so so we got our points
and now we just need to map the points
to we're gonna do another map
so let's do another map so this time
it's gonna be points with Sedona oops
what and so so TT values so we're gonna
map T values points map we're gonna map
the create circle create thought okay
and so we're gonna map create that
attach it to SVG 1 X Y so we need to so
R is going to be 3 for example and X Y
is going to be they need to be actually
vectors so ok ok so what we're gonna do
is we're gonna write an anonymous
function here so let's just let me show
you here so arrow function aramid point
so that's XY array and
[Music]
then here we're gonna so let's see let's
just say P so what we're gonna do oops
pp0 see what so this is what we're gonna
do so here's a function we want to map a
function two points each points each
point is a is a array of two values x
and y so so this is the argument point p
and p 0 is x value py is the y value so
we're just going to map it to you know
create dot we're gonna create a lot of
dots so hope this should work
let's hope it works ok arrow okay cannot
find variable create dot okay so that's
probably your title okay um oh yeah typo
so
so gonna be paste that
okay and let's see we don't need that
anymore
okay that's that's how it works
wait what
okay so the so looks like all our points
is concentrated over here so what
happened is let's change the parameter
let's say 20 let's say 100 200 okay
now I'm not sure where it goes so let's
so what happens is that's okay hold on
let's put these at the top since those
are functions and let's put these also
at the top that's our function and you
know and you know tidy up our code a
little bit so so from here on downwards
that's our real thing
and now yeah increase the parameters and
let's increase the yeah to is no good so
it's at least 10 so we are plotting from
zero to ten T values is zero to 10 so
let's do it again yeah that's no that's
very close now we want to let's say
hundred
okay so there is something so okay so
the t-value so so what happened is that
in order to create these interesting
curves you can see each curve there are
two values on it that's the parameter so
the left is a the right is B so it
depends on what parameters you use you
get different curve so let's let's try
one let's try this one simple so
negative three over seven
it's a is negative three over seven wait
yeah over seven now in JavaScript you
want to make it a float
otherwise it's it may not be it may just
give you the remainder or that you know
the divide and divide the quotient
integer quotient which you don't want
you only want the actual decimal
so okay we should so we are using this
one negative three over seven and B is
negative 4 over 7 so let's refresh ok so
what happens is that they you see these
two values are very small they are you
know they are within one so that's why
all our points are like within one
pixels so so maybe I'm not sure this
will work but let's just try that
actually if you want to do that the
better way I used to multiply the whole
thing by here so we want to multiply the
whole expression
by hundred
so and here we don't want that so this
this is how you scale the curve meaning
that you you make you magnify the whole
the whole curve so let's go to Safari n
yes so good so what you see what happen
is singing a quarter of it because in
SVG zero zero is at this point and X
x-axis goes this way to the right but
the y-axis goes down we can fix that but
before we do let's just so actually the
parameter is wrong you know apparently
that does not look this but that's okay
you know we just we focus on that get
the JavaScript technology going so so
let's fix one more thing and there'll be
it for this video let's try to Center it
like you know so we see the whole thing
okay so that we can what we can do is we
add a you see in SVG you can actually
let's see SVG you can create your own
coordinate and so we have viewports view
box view box is the way to create your
own coordinate and the syntax looks like
this so you see SVG with in hate then
you add a view box so let's try the view
box then append attribute so
so SVG one set attribute view box what
do you want to set it to so let's say so
what what does the value mean first of
all we want to know what does the value
means so X mean Y mean hexamine Y mean X
with Y with okay so x wing is the
coordinate coordinate of the top left
corner so x mean is let's say 100 and y
mean Y mean you remember SVG the y axis
is reversed from the normal math
Convention Y axis goes down it increases
down so why me will be negative 100
okay so and X with Y weight let's say
five hundred let's you're gonna do it in
several tries and let's say 200
great this is great okay so we got so
now we let's say reduce it a little bit
seventy don't magnify so much so great
okay so I'm gonna go eat I'm glad this
worked out and I hope you learned
something I hope you like it so if you
like to see you know let me know what
you think and let me know what you like
to see next
Thanks thank you for watching bye