good morning good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
shop today is October 3rd 2019 Thursday
9 o'clock a.m. San Francisco time in
sunny California
welcome welcome all welcome to the feast
so what is today's topic
so no topic I'm just going to start
talking random
so let's check let's check out what I
don't have a topic in my in mind and
let's check out what's going on oh yeah
so I have this keyboard I want to tell
you about guys this is a new keyboard
for Microsoft
Microsoft just came out with a new
keyboard so let me tell you about that
but before
before that let me go about and see what
are other topics ok so let's go to my
keyboard programming let's see what's
interesting the rise and fall of XML
that's the talk two days ago and
the morning Matt
so Matt you are from Germany right
do you have any topic
so three days ago we were talking about
the rise and fall of XML and it turns
out there is this article from
this article
this article is from I
TF ok it's like it's kind of like I have
see the organization that creates RFC so
they actually have have a article
article that titles that the title is
the harmful consequences of posters
Maxim
now the abstract is ace John post OHS
famous statement in RFC one one to two
of
the liberal in what you accept be
conservative in what you sent is a
principle that has long guided the
design of internet protocols and
implementations of those protocols the
past the posture this statement
advocates might promote interoperability
in the short term but that short-term
advantage is out weighted by by negative
consequences that affect the long-term
maintenance of a protocol and its
ecosystem
yeah that's you know that's what this
article was saying and totally so that
was about so I talked about that for our
video talk show the rise and fall of XML
in fact the realization of the hum of
that Maxim is
is is the reason that XML became so
popular you know like like back then
this is around 2002 everyone understand
it you know they you know before that
everyone was for that Maxim but after
that around 2002 everyone is against you
you know although programmer hacker
types so that was significant
but today you know after the talk show
two days ago I I posted to Twitter and
you got people I put it those I posted
to Twitter and and master Dan and you
have people telling me you know people
they don't believe it they think that's
a good that's a great Maxim you know
people
so this is like people forgetting
history you know so I don't know if they
are there you know they are you know
they are my followers so I ask them were
you there like did they didn't watch the
video of course I post a video and and
they didn't watch it and but they wanted
to they wanted to say immediately know
that's a great maximum you know it's
that's a situation and
so what what can you do it's you know
that's a problem you know i I've been
you know talking about this topic for
like for twenty years you know and
you know I wrote several articles about
it you know it's it's very uh it's kind
of painful to to see it to see these
happen because you know for ten years in
1990s people are quoting the Maxim Maxim
you know be conservative in what you
send believing what you accept
you know people were calling that for
ten years but then then the hacker types
the programmers you know who are talking
on a on the Internet they realized this
is completely wrong so they so this
began the movement the rise of XML you
know for you know for like for for 14
years
so I so so that they realized this
mistake you know this this mistake in
believing this this mantra this Maxim
but now after you know and after another
10 years I make a video about this story
I posted and nobody nobody know a thing
in fact immediately I got two people one
well when one person from from Twitter
and one person from Macedon saying that
you know saying that they like that
Maxim you know this is the
how to say you know it's hurtful to see
that
so good morning
so matt says let's talk about Microsoft
keyboard yeah let's do that I'm
currently debating with myself I'm
buying a mechanical keyboard or oboe
keyboard okay good morning Quinn tech
morning male cat I am as I did nothing
wrong even the Paris City was
consequential good morning just haven't
seen you before
zucchini somebody
greetings greetings good morning
bathroom bottom you
meow cat don't post controversial stuff
okay don't you know those words you see
these words here
you know don't post controversial stuff
because that's you know Google is bad
you know this this word and this word
you know you know what I'm saying right
so okay let's talk about the keyboard
okay so so let's go to keyboard and so
Microsoft they created they they
released a new keyboard they invented
you know they made a new keyboard this
is not on sale yet this is gonna be on
sale available on October 15th and
while writing this alko I realize it
seems October is the time they release
their keyboards like whenever they have
a keyboard they it appears to me because
because the other keyboards from
Microsoft I realized for example this
one this one the Microsoft Surface
ergonomic keyboard also was released in
October 2016 so
they must have done you know market
research that October is the best time
to to sell keyboards you know like maybe
yeah you know these companies like the
date you release a hardware or software
they are all very calculated so they
maximize money this market research
so anyway so
bottom you says can you explain how
controversial words we are was in the
publicity of your channel with citations
with citations
I can kinda I can tell you my experience
you know in the past 20 years about that
but
so the Microsoft you know came up with
this new keyboard
now this one is wired this is not
wireless okay so this is actually
designed for desktop use you know so
there there won't be keyloggers bundled
with it
sorry to disappoint you okay so anyway
so this keyboard and they are quite this
is quite interesting in design there are
several
significant design changes for example
now you look at the left side look at
the column the key columns q a z w sx
did you do you notice anything different
this is significant type it okay so so
that's significant and
so with so apparently they you know like
a traditional keyboard even this one for
example you see the qaz it's like rather
slanted you know they you know the
keyboard fans a staggered layout you
know q is to the right upper left of a
is to the upper left of z so you see
there's this side let me show you a
actually a more traditional keyboard and
see
yeah so you see q is about half to the
left of a and a is about half to the
left of Z
so that's traditional keyboard
but on this micro so this new Microsoft
keyboard you know that that got
straightened straightened out
significantly
so this is a major step this is a major
step towards
you know what we call the auto linear
layout so the for example like this one
you see the columns are straight like a
vertical line w
sx or q AZ you know it's a vertical
straight line
you know when you make a keyboard
ergonomic keyboard you have the choice
you know make either make it you know
vertical align like they you know we
call it great like this you usually
called a great layout or for example for
example this one is most easy to see you
see it's a grid or matrix
but however when you make a keyboard
like that and same thing you know like
this one and all basically all of these
for example this
keyboard IO they have a vertical grid
layout
basically when you make a keyboard like
that your users your potential buyers
will be significantly less
like almost 10 times less you know so
you don't make you know you your buyers
will be ten times less why because
people don't do not like to change habit
that's the thing I mean even something
bad people don't like to change habit
people you know like if you get our
average people to use this keyboard they
will say this sucks okay they were just
they will literally say that including
programmers because first of all they
don't type that much you know they they
don't want to change habit that's it
this you know that's for my experience
experience of studying many things
including programming languages like if
you have a new programming language
that's that's not using C syntax people
don't like it people you know even great
programmers still say oh this language
sucks because it's not using the syntax
the C syntax they are used to this is
true the habit is a such a strong part
of human
behavior but so anyways but Microsoft
did it you see they just went ahead and
they created is this still some some
slant but not that much
so you know and and there is a
precedence to this ok let me show you
another Microsoft innovation you know
we're in talks to when it comes to
Microsoft the UNIX hacker types or the
Linux types they say Microsoft has no
innovation right that's that's force
and you know they don't see it so so
this is this is rather significant okay
from a major keyboard you know maker
that that deviates from the habit you
know that that's a major innovation but
however Microsoft has in another
keyboard that that kind of pushed for
these let me show you okay so
we would go to
design keyboard design then we go to
laptop keyboards history of laptop
keyboards okay
then this page is evolution of laptop
keyboards you can see the evolution of
keys where they go and how they
disappear things like that so them so if
we go down
this is IBM ThinkPad keyboard this is
meows meow cat's favorite keyboard
so let's go down let's go down go down
and go down to the Microsoft Surface
keyboard this one okay this this is the
Microsoft Surface book
keyboard
now you can see the number key okay so
you see the number key one above the Q
it's about one it's about one third to
the left of Q but however if you look at
a normal keyboard it's about half to the
left of Q so Microsoft you know shift
the number rows shifted the number row
to the right and
that's a great change you know that's an
innovation
so that's about that and also look at
the Q I think the Q
yeah Microsoft you see the the
Q above a key this is a this is this one
is a traditional tail tail keyboard Q
above a look at how much distance it's
about one third one third
q is one-third to the left of a
but however if you look at Microsoft is
much less you see so Microsoft has been
in the past few years five five oh yeah
but in the past few years they have been
pushing for
gradually you know by this methodology
of gradually changing the key column
arrangement to a straight line so that's
a great in in omission so that's one of
them there is another great innovation
that is
that is look at look at the odd key okay
you see the old key position is is
between the keys C and V so it's
slightly to the right of C key ABC C key
you see the old odd key is slightly to
the right of C key but that's not the
case this this is again another kind of
major I would say innovation they they
tailor to do that
but you know if we look at the previous
version of Microsoft keyboard you see
the old keys to the left of C key it's
between X and C
similarly for this one
you see it's between X and C and also we
can look at this one you see the old key
is between X and C
so I'm gonna tell you that the old key
so so anyway so this is Microsoft so the
latest version they move the old key
even more to the right that's good okay
if you look at the traditional keyboard
let's see let's go through a tour let's
go to a traditional keyboard PC keyboard
traditional keyboard it sucks you see
the odd keys to it even to the left of X
the old keys between Z and X you see so
we if you want if you need to press the
old key you have to
pay turned inwards so much
so Microsoft made a
improvement in their economic keyboards
they made the odd key between X and C
but now the latest version is even
better it's actually to the right of
seats between C and V so that's quite
amazing so these are the two great
things about this keyboard
then then I also noticed a few things I
don't really like okay for example the
spacebar it becomes one giant key again
but however it's not the case you know
they in a previous version this sculpt
ergonomic keyboard they have they split
the spacebar this is much better
but you know they made it into one space
you know one space spa again this may be
a problem I don't know for sure because
on this keyboard on the map on the
Microsoft natural economic
it has a major problem with the spacebar
its well-known like if you go to Amazon
and you look at negative reviews like
one-star reviews most of them will say
you know the spacebar is too stiff it's
so stiff in fact I used this keyboard
for like three years
eventually I throw it away the spacebar
is too stiff it's impossible like if you
don't have if you don't type that much
you know if you are average person maybe
that's fine but if you type a lot like I
I had several cases of repetitive strain
injury every every
three four four years it come up
so eventually I cannot use a safe space
bar I try to fix it you know I try to I
take it out I try to maybe
you know break the state stabilizer or
something it doesn't work so eventually
I throw it away I went back to the
and went back to this one this this this
is even earlier version it has one
single space bar but it doesn't have the
problem of to steal
but the Microsoft 4000 have that problem
so I don't know if they fix that they
they must have because it's a well known
problem but anyway they they went back
to one single space bar so
so that's about it that's what I have to
say that's my analysis of these key this
keyboard
so so Matt do you have any questions
about the keyboard
so let me read the comments bartholomew
says i just want to know because you
seem super particular about
controversies even though my experiences
are there are a lot of controversial
channels
but um you say is that are super
offensive and they keep going and going
which is good yeah i know what you're
saying yeah i yeah i totally understand
what you're saying
the case of with me is i guess i'm a bit
more paranoid
yeah I'm a bit more paranoid that's one
reason and also the other reason is
because you know I don't have money and
right now I depend on Google ads like I
I'm depending on Google ads for survival
so I don't want
you know so so you have more fear you
know that's that's the thing you know if
you
are financially secure you know
you don't have that problem I mean
if there is some you know that's the
thing about human about fear okay let me
talk about this this is a very
interesting
topic fear you know fear is a human
emotion
so so you know I
mentioned this before because you know
I'm a schizoid personality right I I did
a video on personality disorders
you know on YouTube you can search it
just for just such folks Oddie
personality disorder so I'm a schizoid
which means you know I'm a loner type of
personality I do everything alone at in
general I don't make friends like in my
life I don't make friends
well I have friends but they are like
you guys we are kind you know what no
more people say platonic friends you
know we it's so you know I I get the
situation most people know me friends
you know but they we become formal like
yeah we like that when they talk to me
they become formal like thank you very
much and you know polite
that's the way I am okay it's not
nothing is not like trying to be that
way or something so anyway so I'm a
schizoid personality I'm kind of formal
I'm kind of almost that is you know like
robotic like you know in some way it's
like mr. data in in science-fiction Star
Trek or
or Spock you know the Vulcan Spock you
know the logic guy so in some way I'm
kind of like that I don't get emotions
okay I don't want you know again it's
not I want or not it's just that I
happen to be that way it's not like oh I
you know I I decide that I don't want to
something it's not like I it just
happened to be that way so so as a
schizoid you know I ain't and also
because my back well my my my parents
and my the way I grew up in things like
that I I always wanted to be I always
thought that I want to train myself to
be a robot you know like you know like
mr. data well mr. Spock you know I
I'm not just owned naturally that way
but I also want to be that way like 100
percent I want to be a machine I want to
be like hundred percent in control like
exactly everything is go by logic you
know everything has to go through logic
so I trained myself to be kind of like
that as at least when I was younger okay
I don't kind of I don't really try to do
that for the past ten years but at least
you know in my 20s in my thirties I've
been trying to do that
like everything I trained for simple
food you know like when it comes to food
you eat you know what like whatever you
like maybe you like you don't like
broccoli right usually you don't like
broccoli you don't like healthy food you
just like spaghetti or pasta or whatever
junk food
but to me so-so I mean you like things
that are delicious so I I but I have the
thought you know in my younger years I
always have the thought I want to Train
like I want to eliminate I
want to eliminate the human desire of
tasting something that's good you know
when you eat something that tastes good
you want it more you like right yeah I
want to eat this food because this is
tasty that is not tasting you know just
spread just spread in try bread and cup
of milk that's not tasty I don't want
that you know most people they want
something delicious Chinese food or
Italian or you know curving Indian
whatever you know that's cooked in
restaurant Kume you know
but to me because I'm this you know I
have this
rationality logic kind of obsession so
to me and when I look at this situation
I am thinking okay I should be what I
should you know what I should want is
that I want only something as healthy I
don't know I should not care about
anything else I should like hundred
percent eliminate it eliminate the
inherent human desire for going for
something that tasty so I have so I have
that such kind of thing going on with me
this way I was younger so that's the
thing so
so why are we talking about this the
reason we are so
back to the
the censorship thing
I've
I forgot that moment why are we why did
I start to talk about that but anyway so
there's a reason but I went to elaborate
and so I forgot the connection so we
were talking about yeah we were talking
about why am I so it seems I'm I'm
sensitive about Google censorship you
know I don't want to be banned no fear
okay back to the topic fear yeah let me
so limit so we were talking about why am
i sensitive about you know swimming or
talking about controversial stuff on
youtube because I'm so much it seems
there's
too much fear of Google Google censoring
me so from that I wanted to talk about
the fear the concept you know the
concept of fear human which is one of
the fundamental human emotion fear so so
I have this skis or personality and have
this kind of obsession towards logic to
towards being a machine because I used
to think human is just you should be you
you should be able to train yourself to
become like just like a machine without
emotion what else whatsoever it turns
out I'm totally wrong about that you
know humans are not machines and it's
impossible it is you know impossible
Church two dozen up doesn't matter how
you how hard you try human are just not
machines you cannot train yourself to be
a machine in other words when it comes
to emotion it is it is impossible okay
it is impossible to train yourself
to such a state that you eliminate all
emotion that is impossible unless you
have some brain damage you know so so it
it ties to your brain your neurons you
know that it you know it is impossible
to eliminate emotion unless you know you
have a doctor take out part of your
brain or something like that
so so when it comes to fear I always
have these thoughts you know I want to
be someone who
are able to not do not not not any fear
at all like I said you know goes by
logic like mr. Spock you know mr. data
no emotion whatever it doesn't affect me
like you can swear at me you can do
whatever you know as so much as you
don't punch me physically I think you
know I don't care that's what I you know
that's my idea like that's kind of what
I was thinking but it turns out
impossible you know you can see of these
some of these
characteristics showing in movies for
example well
mr. data in and in mr. Spock are two
examples in sci-fi you know why do they
show that because this aspect being a
human without emotion is very
interesting you know that's that's why a
lot of people you know nerds was like
you know like mr. data or mr. Spock or
you know there's a movie dr. Hannibal
Lecter you guys know that movie right
the Red Dragon Silence of the lamp so
there's this you know character dr.
Lecter Hannibal Hannibal Lecter okay he
so he is this
serial killer
you know very very talented very
knowledgeable and he and he doesn't he
he is in full control of his emotions
you know even if he is you know his
something like his heartbeat heartbeat
do not go up okay that's that's movie
that's fiction but when I see that
that's something you know I thought
that's something I would like to have
you know I would like to have that
anyway that's one example that's another
example so we have mr. data we have mr.
Spock we have talked a Hannibal Lecter
that's what another example in movies
there is more there is another movie I
don't remember the name well anyway I
think you get a point there are quite a
few movies where the there's there's
this character who don't have emotions
who and because of that they are able to
this is this is critical like if you are
you right of course you guys we are all
humans if you can eliminate emotion that
that in some sense that gives you
tremendous power
tremendous power because you can you can
lie you can you don't have fear I mean
just this app aspect when you do not
have fear just this aspect alone when
you do not have fear you have us
you have significant power
but also meanwhile I think there's also
it's possible I mean in reality if you
truly have a human
animal who does not have fear I think
there are also a lot it may have a
life-threatening
disadvantages okay that's what I think
you know because when we think about
fantasies we don't usually think about
the negative consequences
we only think of the positive
consequences
so we have fantasy about you know a
person who do not have emotions at all
but it is my guess okay I haven't really
thought about it this it is my guess
that when you
actually you know if you actually do not
have emotions at all then it's possible
that might be a life-threatening
issue you know it affects your survival
it parts possibly I don't know for sure
paying it anyway so anyway that's some
of the characters in fantasy in science
in movies where you have a character who
don't have emotion so I always wanted to
do that fear and what I learned is that
it's impossible okay why is it
impossible for example let's say you go
to gamble
you know you go you go to a casino you
know in in California in Nevada you know
in some places in USA in Hong Kong in
other countries you can gamble right now
suppose you are a person yes me okay I
have tried this okay to me you know you
know there are a lot of movies that
plays blackjack okay was it blackjack or
some kind of other card game where you
know in James Bond James Bond movies you
see that in James Bond movies what what
is that game called anyone type it
bottom you you know where again you have
to rely heavily on the ability to have a
poker face poker yeah I guess it's a
code poker
so this game you know the card game
poker where the key to winning winning a
game is the ability to lie the ability
to lie and and not let your opponent
know it okay so you know even if you
have the worst card at your hand you can
you know you can
how they say fake or brag or you know
you know you pretend you are this is the
winning hand you put all your money down
such that you you scare off the opponent
then you win you know so this game
relies on the ability of no emotions
it's kind of like that so when you have
no fear when you have no fear you will
you can win this game so
so
so but I well I realized that you know
when when when a stick when there are
more stakes then the more fear you will
have just like a normal person I realize
that you know when when the snake is
slow for example if you are betting for
$10 that doesn't matter okay you can you
can pretend you know you can pretend
that you can do well pretending you have
you know you can do well lying but
however if the stake is all your life's
savings then you immediately I can you
III know this because I am trying this
is what I'm I have been trying to do you
know him half of my life I realized that
when the stakes are high you the fear
becomes proportionally high you cannot
you know you cannot pretend you are just
a machine or something it is kind of
inherent inheritance in heaven inherent
okay
so okay that's about fear so the reason
I'm talking about fear is about my you
know my my kind of worry about Google
censoring me because I'm not relying on
you know their Google ads but you are
right you know you are right I think you
know and and there are other people who
told me by the way part of me are you on
Twitter or how do i how do I like
contact you I know you send me an email
so I get I think that's you but
so you do you have a Twitter I can talk
to you or something so anyways there are
people who told me you know yeah I'm I'm
too paranoid you know because I know
they are quite a few youtubers they are
famous for doing controversial stuff
like anti social justice in fact that's
how they thrive you know the in fact
that's how they thrive you know they
become you know have nothing if I should
do that you know from now I'm good I'm
just going to focus on the social
justice things and then you know it's
possible you'll get a lot followers but
these people most of them are idiots
okay to me yeah okay this is my
this is my deviation about for example
you know I I know a lot of these people
they have no substance okay they are
like they are kind of like just trash
this millennial typically millennial
generation they are just trash they are
you know for example let me show this is
you know let's so let's talk about
YouTube today we talk about none
technical stuff let's talk about YouTube
for example there's this girl shoe on
head
she's focus is anti social justice
that's that's what she's been doing for
10 years and she's kind she's actually
funny you know I enjoy some of her
videos I like I like any YouTube channel
that's anti social justice okay I
support it but however you know on a
different aspect these people the
teenager typically there are young
people they they're video like they they
have no substance whatsoever like they
they have no substance
let me try to find it find them okay
so Milo
Milo is this guy who is meadow is very
smart okay very quick but again no
substance no substance
he's just flashy flashy and be able to
talk talk fast unlike me okay talk fast
use the right words and talk talk very
fast and respond very fast that's a
that's a key like you know like anchors
news anchors or in this type of people
you one of the skill that's required is
for you to respond to you know questions
or
debate you know a tad respond to attacks
in a smooth way and fast
okay I'm trying to find some of the
accounts God
team cast and team pool has become so so
bad team casts has become this who you
know who is trying to use drama to make
money every day you know he's Tim Pincus
no
Tim cast is someone I respect because he
is he's fairly reasonable okay he's he
has two accounts on YouTube actually
more than two he also have another
account called subvert subversion okay
so Tim cast his name is you know Tim
pool he has another account called Tim
cast very confusing you totally
confusing and he what he do is he talked
about he's a commentator about news and
typically and for the first year food he
was a independent independent journalist
but for the past thing for the past one
year what he do every day is he talk
about drama you know like me okay I mean
sitting in front of computer like me but
then he pull up hit some news articles
and he just talk about that for ten
minutes and he's beginning to make five
videos a day every day five minutes five
videos so he just pull up articles you
know before that before before this year
before you know the past year he used to
go out
actual to journalism you know go out to
the street could fly to another other
another country you know film protesters
things like that then he talked he make
a video the you know be in from 2016 to
2018 okay he's doing that that so that's
how I learned I learned about team pool
from in the from
2016 or 2017 so I gradually I gradually
started to watch his videos almost every
day but in the past year he began what
keep he stopped doing that he stopped he
stopped doing actual journalism what he
do is that everyday he just pull up you
know news articles and he read about it
and he is he's unschooled idiot okay
he's a he's kind of a brainless idiot
why do I say that I mean first of all he
is unschooled meaning that he doesn't
have a degree he doesn't have a college
degree he does not even have a high
school degree I mean he talked about
that often
not having a degree is fine I don't have
a degree neither I don't have a college
degree all I have is a GED which is kind
of an exam you take USA so that once you
pass the exam GED that means you have
equivalent to a high school degree you
know I saw I did that in back into the
in in 1991 I passed in 1990s on and 1990
or 91 I passed GG so I have you know
kind of a high school degree so anyway
Tim cast you know you don't have degree
that's fine you know a lot genius they
don't have a degree you know like
college dropout and you know Bill Gates
Steve Jobs and you know a lot
programmers also a lot of programmers
you don't have a degree as fine but
however Tim for Tim Kass is someone
he don't have a degree that that's fine
okay but also he's kind of he's he's
Jewish you know he's he's he's you know
the opposite of intellectual
so he don't know nothing he don't know
about philosophy about history you don't
know but that's ok that's ok too but he
is such a person that he don't he don't
learn he don't care like he he don't
learn anything about those topics like
it doesn't interest him
yeah yeah I guess because judging from
you know what he's been doing you know
from all the talks I talked about you
know I saw him he's not interested so he
so so basically he's
unlearned a knowledgeable not
knowledgeable you know like very poor
knowledge and
and also idiot idiot that kind of like
idiot and not but I mean so what what is
positive part you know so but he is
obviously he's someone who is very
capable at
talking to people you know you know as a
normal person you know not not in
academia for example but outside of
academia doing doing journalist
journalism for example he's he's great
okay but
we but when you talk about news you know
sometimes you have to talk about
sometimes you have to know history right
especially US politics you have to know
is like you know if you really want to
go into that direction I mean oh you can
just do journalism like just report okay
shut up you know don't give don't give
opinions you know just if you out you
know just to news okay that's all fine
just talk about news but he's not like
that he he doesn't know nothing
he's like idiotic but every day in his
videos he he waxing he's like his own
philosophy for
for half of the video
I get so annoyed because he you know
he's churning out 5yi
videos a day reporting on the like
almost sometimes any important drama you
know like social justice who is doing
what to whom for the past year every day
but every time he do that he that he
doesn't just report the news I mean if
he just report Oh today you know louis
c.k is something and tomorrow trump
Ukraine's scandal okay he just reported
that's fine and you know I don't mind I
watched for five minutes or ten minutes
video I don't mind but in you know every
day in every of his video he makes you
know the reporting with his opinions
like he repetitively like oh I I you
know III I'm essentially
this is the thing what he does he like
to insist he's essentialist or didn't
like
Jesus he's a idiot okay so I get very
annoyed about the ting Kass and also
starting this year starting starting
about half a year half a year ago in
ever every of his video he's trying to
you know oh please donate to me you know
every every video for you know one
minute
you know he's Kim poo is not the
teamcast tempo is not a greedy guy I can
okay I know okay he's very reasonable
however you know he is one of the
YouTube stars he's God you know he's God
among his channels he's got 1 million
more than 1 million subscribers so you
you make you make write a lot money Tim
fo okay shut shut the [ __ ] up about yo
YouTube is censoring me therefore and
therefore I'm making five videos a day
you know shut the [ __ ] up and every time
he do a live show like like right now
I'm doing life you know you see his chat
fly by you know like so many people
typing chats you you you can even read
them and every minute June June there's
like $5 donation every minute every
minute don't $20 donation and not after
three minutes tone $50 donation
the [ __ ] so but he think you know he
think he's you know some you know
you know not making money you know
you know he's making too much money and
too many followers and he's like
complaining and repeating so so so
anyway so I'm starting to have rather
you know- you about Tim Kass you know he
should shut the [ __ ] up you know III
support in Thimphu teamcast because he
is fighting the social just just this
can I mean he's doing things that that I
consider reasonable because you know the
social because he became very fun very
popular now you know more than one
medium followers and also so allows the
social justice
extremists you know the antiva they are
attacking Tim PO you know they are
trying to diss disrupt or you know
Taksim things like that so I I do
support Tim poor but he's but the way
he's you know doing his videos this
becomes
you know he has become hehe always you
know what one of his theme in his video
talk is that you know he criticized
those
those mainstream media most of them are
you know left left his mainstream media
they just chunk out fake news or quick
baits or dramatic stuff to make money
you know they click rates you know add
money in fact that's exactly what Tim PO
is doing in the past one year okay in
the past one year that's exactly what
what he's doing he chung out you know
these dramatic videos and he act you
know he kept repeating you know he's
this centralist fair a person you know
repeating it you know nothing new and
knows no substance you know this young
people anyway that's about my my take of
Tim Tim cast okay I support him but he
but I got completely turned off by him
his video in past year so since about
about four months ago I kind of stopped
watching any of his video because I
cannot tolerate it you know I'm still
subscribed so every day I see you know
whenever he posts a video I see it you
know like you know there you go tempo
cry fired for making okay signing photo
was playing soccer game accused of hate
symbol you know he's frying drama for
money you know just like the mainstream
media he's criticizing you know Tim Pugh
I
get turned off okay but I was going to
talk about this YouTube stars millennial
generation typically they are all
millennial generation you know my low
Tim pool and
Chiron had let's look at their
let's just quickly open their channel
okay there are a few people I want to
show you a mess your life guys
okay oh yeah so many comments let me I
need to get
to I watch any gaming channels not
really because you need to play games
all you need to be able I can't I don't
have money to buy games so I don't have
computers so
but I think I am still alive okay that's
good I
want to show you and let me let me get
this something I want to finish talking
where is shoe on head when you need her
shoe on head is also another very
popular
anti social justice channel
there it is you know Google
God okay and let me show you another one
called roaming Millennials Lauren Chen
is another idiot okay I kind of started
to really I find them
Laura and Chen okay let's go buy
alphabet okay let me just talk about
this to person okay King Iverson this
squirrel this woman I respect you should
watch her
okay let me show you some of this person
okay now sure ahead is a very is a
YouTube star edge is the earliest
YouTube star back in 2000 and in many of
these are YouTube stars they up they are
so she's got 1.2 million followers okay
she's a you know millennial generation
young young people basically they don't
you know so they become YouTube stars
they make a lot of money like a median
you know something like that year or
more so but so but she's pretty funny
okay by the way first of all I like them
all you know they keep many of them are
anti social justice I liked him and me
you know but but in general I find them
for example I find them have no
substance okay so anyway she won't had I
like her okay but and she's quite funny
i watch her sometimes like once once a
month or once every two months eyes you
know I watched her videos but they they
have no substance like when they talk
about okay she won't had she talked
about she's basically anti social
justice you know these feminism stuff
you know those kind of thing and some of
the her stuff is very funny but no it's
the substance that's what I'm that's my
point you so I'm kind of into
intellectual of philosophic or history
you know things like that you have some
substance I want to understand why it
happens you know things like that on the
on the other hand you know this young
people they talk about you know they
don't have things you know they just
like they don't have things
they don't have you know substance and
okay and okay Lauren let me talk about
this girl Lauren Chen apparently you
know she's pretty first of all she's
hot she's hot
okay and
she is a new YouTube star okay she only
have four thousand
four hundred thousand followers not even
okay three hundred seventy nine thousand
followers she she rose up in the past
one year or two and her channel is
basically is about anti social justice
you know basically again is the you know
extreme left ideas like you know
feminism and stuff you know the LGBTQ
trans stuff
and you know these days you can you can
become a youtube star by talking about
this actually maybe I should do that you
know make Timmy ten minute video a day I
could do that I could I could you know I
can see myself become a YouTube YouTube
star doing that with with and in my
channel will be with some substance at
least okay not like the but anyway so so
yeah you are talking about anti social
justice Lauren Chen apparently she's a
Chinese
skin I mean shine Chen Chinese blood
okay she has you know some
Asian I think he's China I'd I looked up
I forgot where but I think I forgot
anyway she so she she's a half Chinese
or something but she has no substance
you know she this is like a idiot okay
you listen to her talk about you know
she's so she's like kind of like Tim PO
you know frying drama like whatever is
on the news today for example in two
days ago you have this great hot girl
you know great had another idiot on the
news so you talk about it you know you
give your opinions
but no substance like this fever this is
a name Alania [ __ ] something with you
know something wrong with millennial
generation truly
so on one hand you have the social
justice on the other side is the 4chan
people memes
memes in the chump fog you know every
day is a good cons means no substance
what the [ __ ] is millenials something
went wrong with the millennial
generation too much internet and gaming
okay
yeah exactly one you know one of the
reason people you know for women on the
youtubes you being pretty significant
reason you become popular it's very
significant actually that applies to
guys as well if you are you know
handsome you like the Canadian Justin
Trudeau Justin Trudeau you that's an
asset that's a very significant you know
I talked about this a few times if you
study psychology you know that's a
significant
asset to be a kind of a leader or you
know the star court leader
for example the you know similar cult
leaders they are also you know
good-looking also also several priests
who become very popular you know make
your scans you know they are priests for
Christian Church you know for certain
designation you know who you usually you
you if you are handsome you can cheat a
lot money you know do
anyway especially for girls you know if
you are pretty and young you become very
popular
so anyway so Lauren Chen I watched you
know her stuff you know it's simple I
watched you know mini
she has no substance like
like weight like like you know you shut
the [ __ ] up you know this is this
millennial generation stars they are
quite a few examples let me talk about
another one okay lost see Queen
Rossi Queen okay now you guys may know
her because she is one of the early
YouTube stars la see green is kind of
the same generation as shoe on head they
became popular back you know back in
2000 when YouTube began
so let me pull up her video
oh I didn't I'm not so I wasn't
subscribed to her so anyway lossy green
okay our brown blonde baby the beast she
is another
this this girl only 130 followers she's
another kind of talking about the social
justice issues she she's actually she's
not not bad okay she's you know she give
her honest opinions
unlike you know another thing about
these YouTube stars like
hold on
another thing about this
you know like Dora and Chen what they do
like especially about Laura and Chen
what they do is that first of all they
have no substance right but however they
they are here they are on YouTube not
really because they have you know they
they feel in just you know they want
better society they talk about social
justice issues that's not that's not
like that they are they the reason they
are on YouTube is to make money these
[ __ ] people they you know they are
here to you know you know one way you
can tell just look at by look at the way
her videos like every one every one of
her video is got clickbait is got very
customized icon you see the clowns you
know the you know its clickbait you know
it designed so that you make more money
you know you get people to click watch
it subscribe every video she will say
subscribe me subscribe me and make sure
you click that subscribe and bail button
and they are helping out you know they
have a way to say it is smoothly just
like the [ __ ] Google okay like the
[ __ ] Google always have nice you know
whenever there's some issue of from
their blog you know we always care about
our customers we are our goal is to help
humanity
to spread information for everyone
so it is the same thing the way she do
it you know you know please subscribe
you know
things like that
so anyway you know no substance that's
that's how I that that's that's the
that's all or my criticism about her not
okay it's not about I don't you know
she's I think she's good
person and I think nothing wrong with
making money and I support her channel
even I don't you know I find it bad but
I support her because she's anti social
justice can okay because I think the the
social justice can the my my judgment of
them is that they are kind of they are
like criminals okay they must be
you know they are criminals so whoever
are anti social justice I support them
so anyway that's my opinion about law
and Chen the other one I want to show
you is lossy Green okay I wasn't
subscribed to lossy green but but you
can go to her channel uni and many of
you know her okay she
she's again you know she's an early
YouTube star beginning in 2000 when when
YouTube began and what she talked about
she's got one point four million
subscribers
her channel is about sex education okay
you know she talks about the female you
know
you know
okay I'm not going to talk about what
she talks about but anyway six rated
stuff sex education your body female
body old sometimes mail or dildos you
know she talks about that how do you use
it things like that
you know I so I know her since you know
since maybe 2008 something like you know
now in there I saw her videos and let me
tell you what you know if you had you
know she has got no substance okay this
millennial generations you know YouTube
stars they have no substance yeah you
talk about six you know education stuff
your body but
these people you know like they don't
actually then you know they are not
doctors they don't know the history for
example she cannot for example on the on
the topic of six sexual education
you know if you are academic scholar
okay you should be able to tell for
example I want to know I want to know
the six sexual knowledge throughout
humanity I want to know the American
Indian history what of their sexual
education so back in let's say 1700 or
1500 American Indians what do they know
about six-six what is their safe sex
life like I want to know China let's say
in year one thousand what do Chinese
people do about sex what do they know
what is their sexual education like
that's what I want to know I want to
know let's say Africa let's say your you
know the 1300 what do they do there oh
let's change your topic okay do two - so
I want you know keep you know in five
minutes you know in your ten minutes
video can you tell me I want to know
case ok homosexuals can you give me a
survey like in 10 minutes you know great
video give me a survey of gay in which
part of a country you know of the earth
on earth from two thousand years ago to
today can you give me a survey where our
case you know homosexual allowed or
tolerated or or thriving where it's not
thriving and over the past two thousand
years I want to know so what happens
which you know maybe you can draw a map
or something you know people do videos
right that's good so tell me that [ __ ]
she has nothing like that okay no
substance like
go [ __ ] yourself this millennial
generation
what she talked about you can read on
Wikipedia okay you know beginning around
2000 you know you started to add more
and more sexual stuff on internet like
her she's you know you could say she is
leader a pioneer of talking about sex on
internet but she doesn't know nothing
you know take like what she know is like
she just read the internet you know you
read the internet and and and rephrase
and summarize it for you know and okay
so let's see let's say I want to know
another topic I want to talk to know
human anatomy okay now don't don't just
just tell me how women's body works okay
how they looks like oh how what parts
you know you know human female okay oh
me okay I know how it looks like okay I
know what are the parts I can go to the
Internet okay I want to know for example
how they walk how does the blood flow
what you know nerve systems how they you
know like
be a physiologist bite be a biology so
you know study for years biology and
tell me something about that with
respect to sex or with the lens of
sexual kind of thing
she can't you know so she does nothing
like that so that's why I say that's why
I say you know all these youtube stars
they have like no substance substance
like these people millennial generation
you know go shut up shut the [ __ ] up you
know this millennial generation and then
Bartholomew asked me have I watched you
know gamers no I haven't actually I
don't play games you know I like to but
I don't do to my you know financial you
know my life my life reasons I don't
have games I don't haven't I haven't
been praying but I'm interested in
gaming because I'm the type of I'm a
gamer I'm a classic Emma I'm the type of
person who would play a game without
eating or sleep until I finished the
game so I would play you know it's 16
hours 20 hours a day sleep wake up
immediately go back to the game play do
that for 16 hours sleep immediately go
back until I finish the level or the
whole game right you know this happened
with me often whenever I start to play a
game this will happen okay so I'm that
type I'm very much the Kemah type far
more then
they know a lot of you today's game us
but I haven't played today's games you
know the 3d games I'd really like to buy
anyway so I've checked out you know I've
kind of I want to know what's going on
YouTube so I have happened to look into
some of the game modes stars they are
quite a few today gaming YouTube gamer
stars they they just talk about games
all day oh yeah and then the most famous
one who what's the what's his name
the most famous YouTube with a most
number of subscribers what's his name
that guy in Switzerland Switzerland oh
by the way admit measuring okay what's
that guy's name
who is basically the he's got like 10
million subscribers or was a hundred
media and the most number of followers
pew pew pew pew pi pi okay that the C's
name another thing about these
Millennials they got these names new
idiots okay pew pi okay he's in enough
top-1 actually he's easy is lemme I can
talk about him okay he Sweden from
Sweden yes so he's one of them he's the
most popular okay Tim ten thousand ten
million owed or was it hundred million
subscribers and also they are quite a
few others I've seen you know they have
become their they have you know pew pipe
is a
I'm not sure Expedia no not PD on yet
but he makes you know ten tens of
millions i he make a medium one medium
one month my god these people you know
this you become you can become so rich 1
million one month you can so anyway
pupae by you and also other gamers and
also nasi green around year
2018 or mm mm 17 she met a YouTube star
another YouTube star you know millennial
a young guy who is a gamer also a
youtuber you know he does games his name
is Reagan something rake okay [ __ ]
idiot names this millennial ideas Reagan
so I watched you know Reagan you know
because I'm I'm curious I am the type
you know I want to survey what's going
on YouTube what kind of thing people are
doing right you know with respect to
humanity like what like in this year
2018 in this era what does you know
young people are doing there's this
thing technology called YouTube what do
human animals to on this on this
technology you know that's that's my
that's kind of my direction my
perspective so I looked into you know
the preview hi I looked into what YP he
become famous and Reagan you know the
lossy green
boyfriend so I look into they have
nothing like it this you know for
example preview pipe that's a you know
we can look into for example
PewDiePie second nothing this this is
[ __ ] idiots this millennial idiots
like are nothing neither the memes memes
yeah oh yeah means [ __ ] memes they
just talk about mini and then then make
funny gestures and [ __ ] yeah girl you
know you kill yourself the idiots and
they they become popular you know they
become popular because well that means
they have you know millions of followers
so who follow them of course Millennials
so so the millennial generation for some
reason they become there is something
wrong I absolutely think that they you
know they don't care about nothing
anymore they don't care about knowledge
they don't care about they don't have
aspiration they don't care you know like
life to them it has no meaning it's like
you just sit if you play games you laugh
a bit means so yeah you want to know
what's the memes and then you play games
then you you follow PewDiePie every day
is like
idiots no substance
this millennial generation and they
ended them so half of a half of them are
Millennials I mean half of them becomes
the social justice can they are angry
about everything Oh women we are we you
know women got wrong you know the half
of them is like that the other half is
the memes the gamers the pew pew the pew
pipe I whatever with that what the [ __ ]
you guys wouldn't you know
sorry probably many of you you know
gamer so young you know I'm so in anyway
that's my opinion okay so in some sense
okay from another perspective you could
say you could say actually this is how
humanity human animal the culture moves
so I'm kind of old so I'm kind of just
so that you could say so it's a
generation gap
so it's not necessarily true that the
Millennials are idiots okay so in other
words you know I'm just old that's you
know that's another way so this
millennial generation they just move in
adoration then maybe maybe that's how
how the future of humanity you know it's
that way most people young people are
like it's a fact you know most young
people today 20-something or teenagers
in USA or white nations for example you
believe a lot of the you know the social
justice these things and
you are majority so you know I'm
minority you know that you know so you
could say that so anyway so my so I you
know these people like no substance I
get video and I'm
pew
pie-pie okay and I get really annoyed
pissed me off I watched a few
pupae by videos it's really the most
intolerable possible I don't want to
spend like a minute I've watched many
you know as let's say it's ten I watched
at this 10 of his video not actually not
10 5 I was thinkin of it so everyone is
like that it's no substance he doesn't I
mean oh maybe he can show you again from
start to finish you know he prayed well
something like that is but it's not like
that he's just guys these guys are just
like means in fact what what not so
I don't get you know I don't get this
money no this mind said that's not for
me okay at least you know that's not for
me okay
this millennial idiots they are just
truly theirs they're just idiots this
pipe and they and they become you know
what a hundred 100 million subscribers
so who are they you know 100 million so
so you have 100 millions
people who are kind of you know who find
it fun and also so I have actually
looked into by the way okay Kim Iverson
she this woman she report news and
actually she she is what she's a
journalist okay she's a good journalist
she reported news about us us news I
like her okay so she's like
like Tim poor wench when Tim who was
with doing good you know she actually
report actually she doesn't travel
around but no actually she does research
a lot research okay so I recommend her
she actually
kind of commentary and analysis on news
current events so I like Kim Kim Iverson
she's she's not Millennials though she
is like it may be thirty something
anyway
and so I looked into a lot of YouTube
stars you know for example another one
h3h3 productions
is another example okay h3h3 productions
here's another YouTube star okay very
popular 1 million views to media I think
she's he's got you know 1.4 million
subscribers then he's got another
channel
that's
6 7 million 7 million subscribers very
popular
so this guy h3h3 III started to know him
about three years ago when I run into a
when I run into his interview
when I run into his interview of
boogie you know this there's another guy
boogie fat Poogie Poogie Poogie is 13
something's your number boogie you're a
fat guy you guys know right what's his
name boogie
anyway boogies got an interesting story
boogie 2988 okay I like that guy so
anyway
the first time I learned about h3h3
productions is back in like in 2017 2017
also when he is interviewing
this guy this very fat guy he's with
this guy I respect he's got very
interesting story this guy this is what
he looks like six years ago okay eighty
years ago
and then
the boogie guy is talking about this
feminist okay which is a scammer which
is a criminal okay
anyway so so so because I'm paying
attention to this truly social justice
phenomenon I'm kind of studying them you
know I'm trying to studying them so
that's the first time so so boogie
talked about this feminist and and very
good I liked very much so I started to
that's the first time I learned about
the h3 h3 guy he's got a eyebrow problem
you know like you know how they call
that some this is something called
what's the name of that
it's a Yeon se you know you cannot
control it you know sometimes you he's
got a problems raising his eyebrow
what's the name guys say it
and some people treat their mouse or
something you know if they cannot oh
sometimes like you have to joke around
that's let's say
you know he anyway he's got that problem
so h3h3 then but so so I learned about
him three years ago then I started
gradually like I
started to learn more about him now I
know kind of what he does again it's
kind of like no substance okay these
people they you know it's kind of like
maybe you classify it as comedy you know
there's no substance the way they you
know then he did you know
this year there there is a girl who
become extremely popular this thought
what do you call thought you know this
these teenagers Millennials you have
jargons you know you have thought you
have the oldest jargons okay so there's
this girl from UK an English girl who
becomes widely popular okay so let's go
to let's go here
let's see if we can find it okay so you
have to click on videos
highlights
so anyway I think I've been talking too
long I think they'd stop
what's the what what's them what is that
girl you know called thought that became
the the the most popular who is selling
her bath waters two month ago
I'm sure I'm sure some of you know
so anyway that's my opinion about
Millennials like no substance I get I
get you know I like this so I mean does
a person tell ya pay or Delfin to pay or
Delfin thank you she's become actually
let's look at it would be fun to I mean
since I'm doing video I mean you see
when you do video you start to learn you
know something you learn something like
you should do to you know it's better so
people it's better for your audience you
know doesn't matter what you do so so
when you talk about something it's good
to show what it looks like because there
are people who don't know
ok so as long as it's safe for work so
this girl you know she
you know yeah Millennials they they are
kind of degenerate okay they are
degenerate and also a lot of them are
doing poem also a lot of the social
justice
females they are they are doing phone
directly they are doing the most
degenerate poem like BDSM or whatever
they they are doing actually you know by
day they are singing the songs of Oh
women you know this me too or whatever
by night they are actually doing home
because I I
studied them you know I and I know the
you know the fact you know I'm not doing
a video about it so otherwise I would
show you you know this person or that
person you know they did you know
so Millennials yeah to me Millennials
they got problems they they've got they
lost they kind of become this so I don't
know what maybe that's that is the
future
okay that's I think that's about it so
maybe I'm going to just answer questions
you know when it comes through YouTube
there's almost like infinite topic
because there are so many things you
know right now I just focused on my my
opinion about many millennial generation
and and the YouTube stars you know but
there are so many things we use you know
go to youtube there's so many things you
can talk about
like you know so we can talk about
another day so you know the boogie guy
very interesting guy and he has changed
he's kind of changed stop stop okay
wait oh it went to another I don't know
who is that
so YouTube actually YouTube kind of
today YouTube is so popular YouTube you
can see it gives you you can see all
sort of persons and they many of them
are really experts about something
they like they I mean like before
YouTube if you want to talk to an expert
maybe you go to university you talk to
professor's but now they are on YouTube
so you have also people not necessarily
you know not necessarily professors but
they you know they don't necessarily
have a degree but they are you know
nerds or something else they know a lot
about something you can you know all of
us you know all kind of topics in a
world that's on YouTube
so okay let me just I hope I can spend
five minutes three minutes five minutes
read the comments answer them and that's
it for today
so not many comments okay bathroom Ian
says
you feel punched by youth by eunuchs yes
no okay yeah okay the context is about
so I was talking about me being a
schizoid no emotions but the question
seems to be
so why do you get emotional about
eunuchs it's a show okay let me tell you
bother me you know as a person
you are seeing me like this way that's
not you know that's like 1% of me you
know
and you in fact if you go if you do if
you start to do YouTube you are know it
to people can only see like 1% of you
okay you I can I can act you know in any
way I want about my emotion you know
sometimes you see me get emotional like
[ __ ] the UNIX people that I mean like I
said before that's kind of controlled I
mean on one hand is it's not it's not
cheating neither it's not like I'm
trying to
prepare the script so that I will
suddenly act you know
emotional when it comes to UNIX it's not
like that either but however it's
it's it's you know it's it's YouTube you
know you for example I can stop swearing
if I want to
you know I just means it's kind of part
of your control and in fact this is true
for the the TV stars you know I mean the
the the movie stars you see them or the
anchors you see every day on news like
if you watch news on TV you know there
are certain anchors there are
personalities you become familiar with
them it's all controlled okay like you
know it like the give you do if you do
video every day you start to have you
know a certain personality and it's it's
within your control it's not
it's different okay it's different from
its kind of okay it's no so it's not
fake okay I'm not saying it's fake okay
but it's kind of its kind of just a
window to one part of you that's that's
that's it that's that's it
the difference between hannibal and we
or serial killers is that nobody is in
reality is as intelligent as Hannibal
yeah well yeah because it's a fiction
you know it they made it that way so
it's
banksters yeah they are truly creatures
from without micro gram of emotion
yeah well
yeah I I have comments about that
mr. robot shows the true face of bankers
very accurately
yeah you know right you know
um you know we have to talk about that
in detail right because they are details
are missing so bottom is is one of my
favorite parts is where they show how
those creatures have wives only to show
them off
like some expensive watch or something
no feeling involved at all just in
reality
what is that about
did you watch a mean game channels you
should open your own University
tim is smart enough to know what you
just have to talk about controversial
topics
yeah that's a lot of people doing that
you know I you know I I can do that
you know the YouTube you know YouTube
Google is actually driving part of it
you know Google like I talked about this
in my last week or so you know Google if
you go to Google they have all the
metrics like they tell me how many
people subscribed because you did that
you know your you need to and then you
need to add cards to your videos like
when you watch a video when me at the
end you pop up several things you know
boxes you can quick things like that you
know all these you know for example all
these people they are for money you know
then well maybe not our internally but
anyway look at this you know h2 you know
all the you have to prepare you have to
Gen you know you have to prepare these
icons you know so that so that you get
more clicks that's what you have to do
so nimble says problem with being a
machines as a human is that you need to
be conscious of exactly how the mind
works to be able to modify its behavior
you can change a PC without knowing its
behavior okay we can talk about that
that's about well that's about
philosophy of AI or conscious
next time
bottom you say it's one of my favorite
parties where they show how how those
creatures okay we talked about that
gaming channels okay
centralism is was extermination so many
attention to for a guy who is idiots to
ladies of your of hard time prime time
let's do eMac this okay next day
still alive okay
please stop with lossy green what she
does is that the exact opposite of
Education my was more virulent traffic
than RC Rossi is a good person you know
at least she okay she began she became
she began to be become hated by the
leftist social justice yeah the social
justice people are so evil because Darcy
green must Rossi green the person she
has always been
this kind of nice
kind of gentle girl
help people you know kind of leftist you
know this mentality help people you know
but then she became
she kind of became the target of the the
the extreme left they started to attack
her because
you know so so of course I I do support
ah see yet you know I don't just you
know I I do support her
so var Lord says could you please
summarize what why you decide to talk
about all these people today it just it
just happened but because bathroom you
asked me a question
so bother me says cat watching video for
cats nice such there yeah I
did
did you just mention at all a blue
because I noticed that there's a
kind of watching media forecast yeah
there they are
you know they are certain you know cats
for TV
no mori cats they don't care about our
TV you know whatever you show on TV cats
are not interesting but there are some
things they will start to watch they
will start to watch that he all the time
basically when you have a video of birds
you know birds then cats will watch it
like like you like we watch TV you know
the cats will be attracted to it and
watch TV all the time that's you know
and there are people doing that you know
cats TV if you such that you'll come up
ok that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
subscribe okay
click the bail button
whatever you know if you like my stuff
you know subscribe and stuff in you know
paper me okay so that's it for today
today is about YouTube people YouTube
stars in Millennials my my opinions
about YouTube millennial stars on the
other hand we haven't talked about Peter
jordison and some of the other people I
mean as a contrast those are very
interesting who's got substance
I have you know I have a
weight I have a list of those people you
know who you know people I consider
who's got substance
and also they are also you know people
who doing math channels and physics very
good channels you know yeah YouTube the
infinite number of things to talk about
my guys money interesting bye