oh okay so actually I've been stupid
anyway so this is my weblog I mean the
SVG tutorial so I was talking about
these and I'm thinking of writing my
application doing a live coding demo to
write an application so that you have
input boxes and change values and you
CDs okay so okay this is still bad I'm
so bad at making videos anyway let's see
and I'm going to answer some questions
from my previous videos okay so let me
go ask answer some questions so I got I
got a lot of things to talk about
actually so so that is one question and
there is another question so this guy
says like sigh I became aware of you a
year ago when you wrote a hot water call
for an Emacs rep oh I created which one
is that I don't remember what what that
is this from full bar and he says it's
pressure to finally see you speak in the
West we suffer too much from fashion and
political correctness it is nice to hear
from someone who does not subscribe who
does not okay subscribe okay thank you
so but I don't remember which what is
the ripple you are referring referring
to anyway so that's that's not that's
actually not a question okay okay
so but there is this guy from from China
I know kind of we are acquaintances for
a couple couple of years but he says he
says sound talk sing says I like that
hold on a second let me actually get my
chat
so that so that I can see so if you have
a question comment opinions anything say
it okay
and actually I need to fix this as well
let's just say it's a live stream okay
type your comment and whatever and also
let me actually talk let me put this
here
so okay so that's a list of topics you
can't you can ask me any questions about
it so I'm thinking I'm going to yeah
let's go back to answering the question
so there's a question sound Thaksin says
I like that this topic covers psychology
a little bit I never thought about how
video was more natural than reading and
writing but it makes sense another topic
I would like to see in the future is
learning like learning how to learn new
things well autodidact ism and pedagogy
you talked a bit about how some people
prefer to learn Python through to
through videos I would be interested in
hearing you talk about various methods
of learning things and what you think is
best
okay this also this topic that he so
he's asking about some my opinions or
techniques of teaching myself like
learning stuff you know and yeah so let
me begin with that then that's that's a
topic interesting topic let's see let me
go back to so this this video was
yesterday it's about YouTube society and
millennial generation and text versus
video of human communication anyway so
that's from yesterday and today we're
gonna talk about yeah let me answer that
question then so okay so let me answer
that question
[Music]
teaching okay well learning the self
learning you know I for the whole of my
life I don't have a degree actually I
don't even have a high school degree my
story is kind of strange and complicated
as
you might know you know you can see for
my personality from the things I write
from my opinion so I'm kind of weird and
that is probably part of the reason why
you are watching my videos because I'm
you know not usual so I never had a
degree and in fact in high school when I
was you know in middle school I did not
even graduate middle school instead you
know I get a certificate that says that
I completed not graduate but completed
middle school like let's see so in USA
you know you have high school basically
the school systems of different
countries are different so in USA
typically goes you have great school
which is which is up to grade 6 1 to 6
like you start with kena kindergarten
then great school 1 to 6 then then you
have what's called high school ok maybe
they / junior high school and the senior
high school but basically the whole high
school is like 3 years 3 or 4 years
something like that so after high school
then you have what's called college or
you know University which is 44 years so
after the four years you get a degree
typically bachelor degree so that's the
u.s. system but in Taiwan I grew up in
Taiwan which is the system is kind of
similar so after middle school you have
you have after grade school okay after
grade school yeah you know six years a
great grade school then you have middle
school which is you know same thing like
us then you have high school you know
high school and middle school they
sometimes they are separates and
sometimes they are together but
altogether they they are like four years
something like three or four years so
yeah in Taiwan I was in middle school
but I didn't graduate and then I left my
country when I was four
years old and I never got any degree
that's kind of sad because I actually
was not able to go to school because
yeah well then you know then I then at
age 20 or 21
I got a GED which is general education
diploma you know which you know which is
a US examination you can take that if
you pass it it means basically you have
equivalent of high school you know
learnings knowledge so I got GED yeah
and then I went to Community College
over here at Foothill College and the
answer College this is from 1991 to
about 1993 or 1994 but I never got any
degree but and ever since that I
basically just learned things on my own
I mean I always learn things on my own I
learned English on my own yeah so I
learned a lot math in programming on my
own so so I'm very much into autodidact
ISM you know like that that's the word
that means teaching myself you know
learned learning stuff yourself I'm very
much into that and I have been like that
because well actually most of the reason
is just because personality I mean that
really has a lot to do with personality
of those of you who are you know reading
my channel you are probably also into
self learning and that is also probably
I would say you know due to you know it
is because your personality not you know
it's really it's it's mostly I think
it's mostly it has a lot to do with
personality you know if you are the
loner type
you are a social if you are a nerd type
you tend to learn things by yourself
good good evening Isaac so Isaac says
yeah let me interrupt Isaac says English
on your own
did you just practice with other people
in your daily life no because I you know
I let Taiwan when I was 14 then I went
to Paraguay with my family you know it's
a very complicated troublesome story and
family so I would we went to Paraguay
South America and we lived there for a
year then we need went to Canada well
you know after Paraguay we went to
Central America what Guatemala and
Salvador we lived in Central America for
half a year then we went to Canada and I
lived in Canada for like three or four
years so I learned English you know
mostly on my own when you know when I
was in Canada but basically but I by the
way I talked about in the past videos
I've talked about how I learned English
I learn English just by reading
dictionaries like I ignored anything
else so there was a video like a month
like I don't know when a month ago you
know I talked about the detail the
differences between okay how to learn a
natural language there's two major
differences speaking and writing I mean
speaking and listening that's that's one
skill reading and writing that's another
skill and these two are completely
totally 100% different they are actually
separate things and I talked about that
a little bit so you might be interested
checking that out oh by the way let me
ask you I have a question to ask you so
anyway so I learned English you know
when I was in Canada but mostly because
I'm not a very social person you know I
like I get nervous when you know I'm
me introvert okay and so you know I'm a
ski so so I don't I don't really I mean
I don't go out talking to people I mean
when I was younger
actually I do
but anyway so in general I don't you
know I don't I'm not an extrovert you
know just go out and talk and then you
know how how do you speak you know how
do you say something something you know
yeah I don't do that but instead I'm
mostly I'm a nerd type you know so I
just read dictionaries I literally read
dictionaries like a few hundred times a
day every day and I've been doing that
for like over ten years in the past as I
co2 today you know every other day
you're looking up dictionaries but you
know looking up dictionaries is become
my obsessive habit yeah I talked about
that a lot because in the past video in
fact I have several dictionary reviews I
showed I showed my wit my websites and
stuff anyway so so I learned English
when I was in Canada so and we all get
back to the autodidact ism because I
need to remind myself where were we we
would I were talking about oh yeah I was
talking about why you know teaching
yourself you know learning things
yourself and first of all I was talking
about me and I think most people the
reason they are they they are so much
into that is really because it's it's
actually part of the personality you
know for most people a lot of people
learning is something when yourself is
actually that's not the way they learn
they don't learn you know they they
cannot tolerate you know just being
oneself and read the book you know the
whole day they cannot do that they need
social interaction most people need the
social interaction the require the the
need you know the the interaction with
people you learn things together or
there's maybe a goal you know account
you know something
so that's just the extra thing I want to
comment about these self-learning and
that guy who asked the question I know
him a little bit
we are acquaintances hi and and so I'm
you know from what he post I can tell
totally he's absolutely a loner - a
loner type you know we are a lot of us
into programming language design you
know the elegance of languages things
like that you know lots of nerds are
loner types so so but I I'm going to
talk about some tips I might have about
teaching yourself but it's no I mean I
don't really let me talk about that but
well let me ask you a question a
question Isaac so did you so yeah so
yesterday you asked about the open
source did you watch that video I don't
think that was the video where I
actually talked a lot more because I
remember there's another video which I
went more into about me and my hope you
know my my thought about open source so
did you watch that was it good bad were
you something let me know
hi Zack so let's get back to the self
teaching you know self learning so so
yeah so so learning so for me for myself
I learned you know most things on my own
you know because you know I'm a nerd I
just read all sort of things and and you
know mostly you know programming and
mathematics and in terms of philosophy
psychology and well any kind of things
you know I'm kind of free I'm a free man
okay so you know I I do things
everything I touch I start to study it
you know it's like everything you know
you said maybe programming related
software user interface or the the way I
see people talk what are they saying
their their intonation their
pronunciation and then there's a issue
about speech your vocal cords and that's
a physiology and you know that's that's
how that's one way okay let's let me put
that way put put it into the perspective
of today's topic the tips about learning
things so one tip is that you you know
you live you know you have eyes right
you know your eyes are open
take technically is that it
statistically about 2/3 of the of the
time you are alive so your eyes are open
like my eyes are open right now so I'm
seeing things you know you go out all
you have dinner with friends or you go
to a bar or whatever or you go to work
or you take you drive to work you you
know whatever you do are you doing
things with your girlfriend or boyfriend
or whatever
okay your eyes are open you are seeing
things any of those things you can learn
learn for me yeah I mean if you have the
mind you if you have the right mindset
okay and you have in the right mood you
know so you know like for example when
you are something happened some some
depressing things happened you know you
are not in the mood you you cannot at
that time you cannot oh I'm going to
start to research like research into
depression you do that you know but but
anyway so so one of the way you learn
you you have to read certain curiosity
of mind well and again this oh these
these tips only you know kind of only
are suitable and applicable to the nerd
type of people because I don't I don't
think you know I think vast majority you
know but majority of people they are not
they don't have the they don't have
those you know the mind said the
psychology like nerds you know they
don't you know they want to talk to
people they have you know
they derive pressure when interacting
with people and that is that is also how
they learn
you know they talk to people you know I
pat your back or whatever we go to work
out together you know you know gym or
whatever you know that's how they learn
- okay so anyway so but altogether one
way to learn is that you just learn
things from everyday you have the
mindset to curious about everything you
know everything you see every detail you
developed you can if you want to oh you
know you know you you you have the
mindset like you can see things and
start to dig into them everything you
know almost everything then then it
became it can become deep okay
so that's one of the thing about
teaching things yourself that's just a
tip you know that's that's just one of
the tip that's not a solution by the way
because because you cannot because then
you get chaotic you like this so many
things you need some kind of guide as
well so anyway so okay so let me talk
about that so one thing is you observe
everything but but the problem I mean
you cannot totally rely on that because
you are directionless you know they are
but billion literally infinite things in
life you don't know where to go like
what is worth studying you know for
example I see my screen as a white color
then he said well you know is it what
should I start to study all the words
about coloring English oh should I go
into you know why is it white you know
maybe you know maybe the screen should
be black so he's white on black widdow
black on white better oh maybe we're I
went into philosophy you know for a
service question what is color what is
white in fact Bertrand Russell discussed
that to some detail you know we'll so
what would is the
what does then there's a there's a
science aspect of color color is a
basically magnetic magnetic magnetic
wave you know it's it's it's what they
call radio wave you know it's a wave of
certain links okay and then there's also
the aspect of human eye perception
physiology and also new rounds you know
the the neurology you know the people
scientists study brains how you perceive
you know you have the mechanism first of
all you have a mechanism of visual
perception you know you have rods in
your irons and how you perceive colors
and so and how it's the how it is
different from dogs or birds you know so
if you just observe things you know they
are it can be random especially if you
are younger you you don't have your
colors so so one of the way if you are
if you are into learning things yourself
is you look you go to you know you go to
high school you go to college you know
you go to universities you look at what
they are teaching you know for example
let's say you if you are interested in
math okay hey good morning fubar crater
see use electro magnetic wave yes by the
way what map oh did I contribute to I
don't remember what were you in China or
were you in America so back to the topic
so I was saying yeah so one way to give
you a Kyla guy lying about what to learn
what to teach yourself if you are the
type you know learning things yourself
you don't go to college you know so one
way is you go to college you know you
just go there and see okay suppose you
are interested in math you look at their
math courses
you know like first year college second
year college third year college fourth
year college you look at you know their
courses and you look at their textbooks
you know now that is one way the
is a very good way in fact to give you a
guideline you know of how to study I
mean the direction where to study I mean
first of all like I mean suppose you are
you know you have some sense that you
are interested in mathematics so this is
a very good method you know you go
through you know you see what colleges
are teaching you you have to actually
you know write down
you know the courses you know you can
you can check different colleges you
know Stanford University MIT or whatever
you know write down what the courses
they are teaching and what textbooks
they are teaching then you can follow
that that is one way a good very good
guide to put yourself learning that
subject matter
same thing with physics or whatever
psychology you know that's one way to do
that so so this way you have actually a
guide into you know step by step you
know like we what what what are the
basic things you must know I mean then
what what are the other things you can
learn because if you don't have this
guide a guide a guide like this major
steps what you know courses or what kind
of subject matter to study is actually
critical okay because if you do not have
this guide it makes a huge difference if
you do not have this guide you just
start to you know reach random math
books that's that's almost like self
destruction okay because they are
infinite number of things out there you
know you really the guide is important
it is like having a good appearance okay
now some people some some of us do not
have parents or we had well parent
there's no guidance from our parents you
know that's kind of a sad thing Oh
orphans you know orphans so so you grow
up you don't have a guide but as a you
know everything you're supposed to if
you have a good parents family they they
you know yo-yo your mom
that I mean even if they are not
teaching teaching you I mean even there
if they are I mean it's it's not about
homeschooling but rather your parents
you know just by the way of talking and
interaction they give you guide every
day you know and you can do so a guide
is actually quite important they direct
your focus or direction because without
without a guide you will eventually pick
up you know the proper direction and the
proper you know which which level which
things to study to go to go up you will
eventually have that but it will it is
from ancient engineer as points of view
point of view it's extremely inefficient
okay that's how I that's the way I
learned English I just by by brute force
reading you know looking up dictionaries
I don't care about nothing else I don't
care about introduction to English you
know I just start to pick up any novels
or newspapers so you know American
whatever American you know Native
American you know the white American is
doing I just you know go word by word
and if a word I don't understand I look
up a dictionary that is turns out I I as
I know now it's very efficient you it's
like you are wasting 90% of your time so
don't do that you need you need to
follow kind of guide of course being
being a nerd type you can you you can
always have your opinions I mean as a
nerd a lot of programmers like us you
know we always want to have like you
know we have the urge to say oh no but I
want to be different you know I yeah
okay you say there's a guy then I'm
trying to do something else that's
that's good but don't do that too much
you know you need to like and you know
know a guide not know what what should
be the right thing to study okay let me
see the comments
it's the repo rhythms with Emacs
anywhere but the ripple rhymes with
Emacs anywhere
rhymes with Emacs anywhere I I'm not
sure what that is of hand-eye but okay
it's you know you have you guys you know
I know this this is one of my rant about
programmers and nerds you know you know
I'm very much a nerd and I very much
concerned about privacy as you know and
you know I don't want cookies I don't
want JavaScript you know that I don't
want tracking but however you know it so
happens I'm you know I've used my full
name like like my life story is a open
book you know you can read about just
about everything and and also including
things normal people do not tell about
myself my life you know
on the other hand I have a big rant
about you guys programmers use you see
you and and many who follows me okay no
types you know the hacker types they
don't like you know they don't want to
it's like no privacy and this and that
yeah but also they you know they don't
want to use the real name they hide like
each social network they have different
names then you know and they I don't
think it's a good thing okay I think you
guys really should just you know start
with your real name okay
say whatever you believe in you know
they don't worry about things you know
privacy is important but that's
different you know like okay what I'm
saying is a especially American you know
the American programmers hacker types do
you you have this it's like all day they
are brain is just about privacy and this
is that you know it's it has become very
bad to society and to yourself I mean it
has done huge damage to yourself why
because you know you know for example
let me give you an example
let me sidetrack okay from teaching
oneself a little bit let me give you
exam
you go to read it okay oh oh you go to
YouTube
oh you know yes or even Twitter okay
let's say reddit and YouTube you go
there you you see you watch any you know
YouTube video and you see a huge bunch
of comments right let's just go to a
YouTube let's see you know let's say
what the hell let's go to YouTube it's
just let's show some examples so what's
going on youtube.com yay
the wonders of videos of the billions of
people around the world and what are
they doing and the wondrous technology
that can show it to us
oh ok lots of these things let's pick
something that's ok funny clips let's
pick this one Rick and Morty evil Morty
wings it's so I'm doing a video I guess
it's kind of stuff so am I so talking
I'm talking that's good ok so so there
it is a YouTube let's go back here hey
green deck Oh green deck I want to ask
you a question that Twitter guy is that
you who we had argument a little bit
about about what is the subject about
psychology he's at you
so anyways so let me get back to the
topic so look at so here we have a
YouTube video ok now you have 177
comments ok now look at you know look at
this comment this one JJJ be ok this one
tomahawk play you know ok in this video
this one solve it Soviet Nuggets you go
to any video YouTube video you see most
of the majority of the comments
anonymous okay and act but you know
forgetful forget for a moment about the
names just look at their comments it's
all crap it's like it's all 90% of the
comment it's Brenna's crap including on
reddit okay well did any any topic
doesn't matter what topic doesn't matter
it's a political topic it's technology
about keyboards about programming any
typing you go you read read the comments
90 percent is like pure crap I mean it's
the people do not even try it has become
a point where everyone just go there is
a you know this that you know the and
sometimes just post things to wing to
wing the thump up or vote up you know
society has become that you know with
comment is suppose you you know each
person you discussed your thoughts or
whatever opinions on you know but today
it's not like that at all the comments
comment on the websites has become they
are not you know opinions about them
something they are the nature you know
the nature of today's come and they are
become they are like you know half of it
is I each person posting some soundbite
and you know some fight like memes so
some pie dough dreamboat so you know
tree vote so you know you know things
like that
you know it this it has to be removed
from any humanity I mean it's not about
a person you know whoever you are you
are thinking your opinions or your your
applause you know your recommendation of
this content or whatever it's or you
agree or you just disagree it's not
about that anymore you see it's like
meme so you know crabs or you know who
is more funnier you know it has become
that when a part of the reason is the I
would say okay part of the reason is
this anonymous anonymous [ __ ] okay
because you know somehow the Western
society especially you know let's just
say America okay because I live you I
know he ride
I know I do not know much that much
about Europe or Australia okay but this
so let me just limit to America in
Canada you know because I was living in
Canada for three years so America you
know Americans mentality the programmers
they have being they you know everyday
yeah yeah privacy and so on you know we
have like the privates the concern about
privacy has been going on for 20 years
you know since 1990s since since
Netscape invented cookies you know we
shall require about it every day for 20
years because III I was there you know
we cry about privacy cookies you know
how to remove queasy and so long and
every day
for 20 years we do that daily and look
at what has happened today today is far
worse far worse to a degree you cannot
possibly even prevent you know there's a
phone as you know smartphones if you you
know you you have you today as it has
become a situation you have to have a
smartphone to live okay
you gotta have a smartphone to have a
normal life to to pay stuff to you know
that even you know what I mean
you know you it's like to travel took
away anywhere to almost to anything if
you don't have a smartphone that's kind
of you become art you know you are the
fringe of society so you need a
smartphone almost to do anything
especially even especially if you open a
business and something more important
then you need a smartphone and these
days you even need a smartphone to open
website accounts you know they don't let
you if you don't have a phone number so
you have a smartphone and the
smartphones you cannot even if you are a
programmer like us you know tech nerds
you cannot control like this apps
they're they know everything about you
it's even it's it's almost like
impossible to prevent that if you use a
phone okay and we are not even talking
about at the FBI and they have you know
they they have more advanced things so
it has happened you know it has become
that be good because good you know so
and you are still I
you know the hacker type the open-source
everyday is that we need privacy
oh this that time for twenty years we've
been saying that but the privacy
concerned that the the the the the whale
wellness of programmers the privacy or
every citizen has become a magnitude was
you know of compared to twenty years ago
and and this and wake up guys you know
these geeks you know you guys you know
programmers you know wake up it's you
know you are being brainwashed that's
what you are because the corporation's
they want you you know you you little
geeks you know little niche groups they
want you to cry about
you know privacy because actually that
doesn't matter you know there has no
consequence instead what actually
happens is that the Google Facebook they
become more and more and more powerful
you little you know fringe groups new
hackers who think oh we are concerned
about privacy open-source you know you
become fringe and fringe and you are
censored like right now they are doing
censorship on YouTube on Facebook
everywhere you can have you become
nothing and you and you still chant like
every day you chant about so open source
so we need open source what does open
source to open source what it does is
rap new any power you have it wrapped
you totally eroded away because open
source they benefit they benefit Google
yeah Facebook you have nothing you to
open source because the programmers half
of you okay and what you know a day you
know you chant about open source but in
the day time you go work for Google
which is Peyton Reed and they have
thousand patents you know with hundred
lawyers although your pack Apple you
know Microsoft Google Facebook yeah you
work for them and it at night using open
source all we we love open source and
you you spend your time to contribute to
github and you wrap my any live live the
hood who do not work for open source you
you wraps Richard Stallman's live the
hood because
you you you [ __ ] walk forward you
know this evil company you make a lot
money well you know $10,000 a month
$20,000 a month you make a lot money
your life is comfortable
you drive Tesla or whatever you talk
about Apple's latest toy so I phone how
I like this iPhone no I don't think that
iPhone or Apple you know help of you
know MacBook or whatever you know stuff
then at night you to open-source oh yeah
yeah we should all open so what are you
doing you know you are robbing you know
look you know you forget about opinions
just look at what happens in the past 20
years the the power of individuals the
power of each you know little person
like like you and me it's good you have
no power you just no matter how good
programmers are you what you're gonna do
you know yeah you you're a great
programmer you go work for Google you
know that's what you do what you have no
other choice you what do you think
you're gonna do a open-source you go to
github write a great program open source
you get no money you think you know all
of you open source people say oh we
don't add we don't like ads but you know
however we'd love to donate don't in my
ass you know I've seen guy I know what
happens donate that you don't get
nothing no money you put ads on your
website you get hundred times more the
intonation from the open-source Fox
because I've been in my email site I
know in at the moment you put ads on
your website all the open source people
distance from you that's what that's
what I've gone through hunger you know I
want one day I want to but I'm hungry I
want I need I need to buy a banana 25
cents a quarter for banana I don't have
I don't have 25 cents to buy a banana
because I'm hungry I've happened this
has happened you know most of you guys
know happen in 2013 you know that so
what that is the situation's of open
source
you know the nd has become a ideology so
so you know stuff you know they try to
think about you know I think we have
done open source for 20 years there's
and their stories you know open source
they try to make you know once in a
while you know like one in a million
open-source people you know they get a
lot of donations and you know all the
website is singing songs about it oh you
know I got you know I got donations
thanks thanks to you guys a lot people
you know $7,000 backing you know five
years ago also you know 2012 or 2013 but
you know that's not comparable you know
you work at Google you get $10,000 a
month okay
that's a lot of you open-source guys
$10,000 a month now for the random you
know open-source car does this just say
me okay
how much how much I get in 10 years I
got $10,000 well well you open-source
[ __ ] you know working for Google and
seeing OpenSocial songs yeah you get
$10,000 a month I don't work for Google
I don't work for Facebook I don't work
for no companies I get $10,000 in ten
years so what is this you know yeah so
you know anyway I digress
so and this is kind of also related to
the you know the the the anonymous you
know it's not the the thing about these
things is is that you know open-source
the idea or the free software philosophy
I mean it's not it's a good idea you
help people and so on but but by you
know pride by by these little deviations
because corporations they have lots of
late they control your thought you don't
even know it
by these little twists and turns it has
become you know what what is a great
open source company today that's
Microsoft you know Microsoft today you
know it's said and you know our hacker
news you know they they actually are the
in terms of you know contribution they
did they have the great the largest
number of open source contributions and
now they are doing Linux in in Microsoft
Windows
so whatever what you know what
you know what what is going on you know
what okay let me make a final kind of
conclusion okay so the open source
you know let's remember what is the why
do we want open source I mean what is it
about open source that we must love it I
mean what is the pin benefit what is the
code here's what I say okay the open
source the ultimate benefit you know
it's of course there's two camps the the
free software foundation camp this open
source camp they are and enemies okay if
you don't know history look it up they
are still enemies so but to me okay let
me just say the ultimate core of the
open source of free software foundation
is that it gives individual us the power
okay to you know to share programs well
that's not what they say okay the free
software their philosophy is that I mean
ultimately they they are saying open
source
I mean free software is that you can
share that's a point share up shared you
know the pleasure of sharing programs on
the other hand the open source camp they
automate they say the Ottoman called the
the autumn and the benefit the goodness
of our open source is that the code is
open so everyone can look okay but let
me let me say you know the but they are
all related to this thing about what I
want is the power to the individual not
the corporations like did like today we
have the giant Google Facebook evil
empire there is nothing you can do you
know this like they they are so powerful
so anyway so we had 20 years of open
sourcing it's not doing any individually
good okay and look at society it has
gone bad and and while you know you guys
such you know people these programmers
are changing about open source what what
what is it still good about it
you can look at source code okay
well you know so you know Google most
Google these companies Emma
they went to cloud what are you gonna do
you know today's society is like Oh
crowd why did they we go to crowd
because of open source do you know you
know do you rather wish everything you
have control on your computer or do you
like the crowd thing
why did where did they go to crowd why
did the whole society becomes becomes
cloud base you know so-called crowd [ __ ]
you feminine you know that's just that
basically means their server they
control everything crowd what white
white society becomes car because it's
inevitable or something you know what it
is because part part of the reason is
because open source because when you
have open source they cannot make money
but meanwhile the open source chant is
everywhere it's unstoppable
so the only solution for them to survive
to make money is they let's go to crowd
we are a service we are open source but
we are a service that's how they make
money
so that's everything went to crowd
that's what happens with you know this
open source anyway so you know think
think about that ok so you know so let's
let's see the comments ok ok green deck
ok I see what you're saying
foo bar says I agree with your take on
open source and contributing to these
corporations
my dad says good evening good evening
you are a few years tonight and I can
tell ya well I'm furious you know you
know like you know it's just a rant
about open source because I was you know
like I talked about these in previous
videos I was a I was a fan you know of
Richard Stallman but anyway this this as
you know this is a controversial issue
but let me emphasize you know this issue
is controversial and we you know I don't
know how old are you guys ok you know
but you know if if you know my age
people my age ok I'm 50 you know I we
lived through it we fight we talked
about open source
every day you know there was no hecka
news then there was slashed on this
other you know online forums we've been
going through this this happening you
know is 20 years so I mean it's a
controversial I mean it's like since
every day 20 years you know people talk
about discuss there's every every year
there is a different kind of big drum
drama
you know today to talk about name is
like history you know nobody cares do
you care about history like you don't
care yeah you don't even know what's
going on ten years ago you just care
about today's o Google released
something new that's open source oh yay
great for open source that's that's what
you do you know that's that's you know
that's good Google want you to do too
because they that's anyway that then you
know this been going on for twenty years
what you gonna do you know and and you
know and so each year there's a some
major drama you know one day it's a
witch's storm and versus someone you
open saw some big guys okay
witches storm and we versus leanest
towards you know the guy who created
Linux you know they had they have a
fallout on GPL three you know GPR three
itself some so many controversies you
know issues this this DVR three is about
like eight years ago
oh you know it's ten years ago of thing
you know time gate gets good pass fast
you know everything every year there's
the issues but it then it becomes
history and we have today so what what
are you know you guys you know think you
know think about it what you guys
singing open-source songs for I don't
think it's good you know it's not good
for society it's not good it because it
has become easy either ideology and the
nature the whole thing has been changed
and also let me mention okay since we
are on this topic let that be today's
topic then you know you know today you
have code of conduct it's incredible
evil the code of conduct today thing
okay on github and you know github by
the way it's a centralized power
structure
it's dejected it's like you know we you
know we are concerned our partners we
are concerned about open source or
privacy we don't want centralize things
but that's all there is
so anyway so kit is also code of conduct
you know the thing about code of conduct
is like when you have a open source
project okay you you know each of us we
may contribute contribute meaning you
can say ha ha ha ha I you made ask me to
eat so so so contribution okay so github
you know we you know when you have some
open source on project on github we you
know you may you like it a lot you write
code to you contribute you actually
contribute your time you know your time
and energy to the project in in hope of
you know it was kind of a gesture to -
you know you contribute you use a good
gesture but the you know but the code of
conduct it's such an evil scheme okay it
it kind of reverse this situation so so
code of conduct it's like so so they are
saying that they are you know they are
trying to help minorities or weak people
to contribute you know it's kind of very
strange because if you really want to
help the minorities or so-called
minorities or people of color or you
know me people of color okay or the poor
the poor saps you know is that II mean
for example and you know you want to
help them you know that if you really
want to help them you want to tell them
to hey you know go start your own
project that's how you really help them
not [ __ ] tell them to contribute to
the to the centralized giant
huge repository then you know that they
tends to be you know centralized
powerful these you know you just got
these few things you know so that is the
nature the evil nature of the code of
conduct you know on the surface they say
they are helping something but actually
they they are that's you know that's
part of the brainwashing at work you
know they reverse the whole situation
they kind of implicitly reverse the
whole situation about who is helping who
when you contribute you are spending
[ __ ] your time and you know you are
spending your time days to put your code
to them you are helping them but but the
code of conduct kind of they give you an
impression they reverse that they are
saying I am helping you guys to help you
to help me
so you contribute your code to me
because I'm helping you with the code of
conduct you know this is a fact that why
does that happen because new open-source
flux you open-source [ __ ] you know
open source every day because the Oh
missiles not in the beginning okay it's
a good movement it but it has become
ideology and all corrupted it's like oh
bad you know what why do you think code
conduct happens you know what what do
you think it happens try you know think
think about that issue from an hour
every day for you know for a month you
know try to think no pain no gain so
from today I'll spend one hour whatever
that hour is pressure to you watching
movies be with your family or eat go to
a restaurant whatever don't do that stop
doing that spend that hour to think
about why code of conduct happens why
open source you know why these things
happens then you you start to learn
something about it in the nature you
know what what is open source maybe
maybe in yeah after you know do that
spend one hour about open source I think
just think about this like a philosophy
after one month maybe you you you are
more you even think you are right open
source you should go away to support it
that's good then that's good
I have no you know then tell me what you
think you know then tell me I'll learn
something okay that that should conclude
the rent I I hope so fubar says the
philosopher Nietzche II I don't know how
to pronounce his name has a good
explanation of what the motives of
groups and individuals are the desire to
gain power he also has a good
explanation for the psychology of the
extreme left yeah you know I'm I'm like
I'm kind of old
okay I'm 15 not too old but to me I'm
kind of I'm you know few more years I'll
be done for so about these people I mean
when when when I'm you know I'm doing
videos and I really appreciate you guys
watching it you know to hear what I say
but you know many comments like I've
been there I'm old you know nitin issues
I've heard it many times since 10 years
ago 20 years ago you know so what you
gonna do I mean that's kind of like
that's kind of like how life goes on you
know you you get born then you are young
then you want to make something out of
yourself you learn things you maybe
argue you you know to some things you
then you have a family you get old then
you die so so for now I you know I don't
have like a lot of the questions or
opinions or challenges like what yeah
you know like maybe some people say oh
let's you love Emacs let's compare let's
see who's more efficient oh my you know
with VI you know I have been there like
for 20 years I lost you know there's not
much excitement of those kind of things
for me anymore because I'm saying it I
mean I've been there I've been doing it
I've been arguing I've been called a
truffle for like over 20 you know ten
years so he calls the morality of the
extreme left Slayer
yeah slave morality I agree Fugazi is
the code of conduct is a manifest
manifestation of state morality which is
a Christian morality divorced from God
the Jews created Christianity to
overthrow the Roman Empire by making
them sympathetic that's interesting yeah
you know I read a little bit about that
you know save morality about ten years
ago that you know so this kind of topic
so on the surface you know a lot of
people suggested you know niche this guy
Aeneas I so many of his ideas I kind of
I agree I would even say I agree
strongly you know eyes I see many of his
the me my point of view of philosophy
you know I like his ideas and viewpoints
so yeah so let's see what else
green deck haven't seen you for a while
good so good evening what is it in
Russia a good morning in Russia so let's
see is it six o'clock in the morning so
fubar Zachery Emacs anywhere he acts in
good
Emax anywhere I have to look you know I
have to look up so so well yeah great to
see you fubar so that's is that about it
what else to talk about so I was talking
about the topic was about like
autodidact ism you know some tips about
learning things oneself you know you can
learn things oneself and yeah that's I
don't know what you know I don't really
have some rent or something about that
thing so I always you know it would be
great you know I always thought it would
be magical to have you know in Japanese
comics there's a famous store come is
called doremi
I think it's called ome anime okay let's
let's see because they show you let's
see so you need to wait I need to go to
images oh yeah that's that's not the
right name this told me oh yeah Dori me
no that's not that no not that
Doraemon I think does anyone know say is
saying oh yeah there there
so this is extremely popular Japanese
cartoon you know animation back in 1970s
and to this state's extremely popular
it's so popular to the degree that this
is it's like you can compare to Mickey
Mouse in a Western societies you know
everyone knows Mickey Mouse but in Japan
and also in Taiwan and in China I think
I'm not sure about China but at least in
Taiwan Japan this character this
animation is everyone knows into this
stage you know there's something you go
to a you go to a supermarket there's
lots of food you know made in this
characters shape yeah so I watch this
when I was in Taiwan you know back in
1980s you know so so this thing so these
characters so what so yeah yeah so in
this in this cartoon in one of the
comics you know episode 1 of the they
have this story where they have you know
this story mom is a cat from from the
future okay he's and he's he's got this
pocket this pocket is a magical pocket
you can he always have things from the
pocket and you know magical things for
example in one episode he so he pick up
from the pocket there's a sandwich okay
this is a sandwich but you know like a
bread sandwich where you you you open a
book and you take the sandwich you can
you can press the sandwich on a book so
that you know whatever text on the book
is on the sandwich will be printed onto
the sandwich then you eat a sandwich
then you you you you memorize that page
everything about that you know so that
was a quick I was thinking you know
there was a great well that was a great
way great invention to learn you know
for example if you are a student in
college you know you are doing you know
math exam tomorrow you have math math
exam so you just take this spread and it
get all the formulas on it and eat it
then you can remember that so ya
self-teaching it's it's a great thing
I'm you know personally that's what I
learned and what I want to you know I
won I always hope you know like 30 years
ago when I was younger I hoped I hope
there is some way to speed up the
learning process because I so much I
mean even today I so much you know for
example there's so much mathematics I I
really want to know but learning math is
extremely slow especially also the thing
about self learning is I it's slow it's
it's when you have a teacher it's much
faster much more efficient it's almost
like I don't know I don't want to put a
scale but it's like two times or 10
times more efficient like faster you can
for example let's say you want to learn
group theory okay now I assume we are
programmer let me assume you don't know
what group theory is about abstract
algebra in math you can go to Wikipedia
or find some textbook and try to read it
it's gonna be you know you can learn it
for ten hours you not you will not get
far and it's also boring you know you
don't know what it is talking about even
a suitable book you know you already
know the prerequisite you know you can
read it but however it's the processes
so but however if you have a guide or if
you have a teacher for example I can
teach you the basics of group theory you
know I've done that in previous video I
can teach you that in one hour
you really learn a lot is so it's it's
you because you have a guide you know
why we are doing this you know and you
can ask questions to you know
interactively so you are you you get to
know why we are doing it doing it you
know you get you know you see the facial
explanations when we explain something
you know the because facial explained
facial expressions and intonation the
you know the voices you know they convey
lots of things
don't see in text you know it's not in
text no it's not in a book they convey
lots of informations in three see three
so when you have a teacher or guide
especially one-on-one they teach you
something maybe it's a programming for
example if you are teaching someone
programming let's say maybe your
children maybe your sister or your
brother or maybe your dad okay you teach
them programming they learn because if
as compared to you tell them to read a
book take it it's the efficiency is very
big the difference efficiency is very
big so anyway but still not any one can
always get the teacher or find a teacher
right and yeah you know or otherwise you
have to go to college which is corrupted
and very expensive and have to have the
time your time is spent on driving the
traffic so socializing you know it's not
about learning a lot you know but
university is like that today it's
highly corrupted and and very bad anyway
so so when you don't have a teacher you
you know self learning is still
important so you need the skill of so
you know read the book so so so anyway
let me just summarize a few things about
self learning okay about autodidact is
amol you know so it's a good thing it's
a good always to teach yourself and and
then self learning the thing about self
learning is is I would say related to
personality a lot you know if you are
like most people most people are kind of
more into extrovert okay they are
extrovert they like to socialize they
need to talk to people they cannot sit
home alone for a week they they get sick
okay so most people so so what I'm
saying is that self learning is related
to personality so for most people they
like to have interaction
with people which is great you know they
can learn from each other they can self
help you know teach each other you know
how to do things together you know but
for for you guys nuts you know for us we
can you know well it's related related
to personality that's what I'm saying
okay that's one thing then the other
thing is tip about self Lonnie so what I
want to say is that you want to find
don't blindly you know just try to learn
things you want to find kind of a guide
like step by step like where to learn
which one things to learn and one of the
great thing you can do is you you go to
a college you know you look up their
website and so on find out you know
whatever you are interested in for
example math or physics or what whatever
psychology other things you find out
what courses are for four years of
college you know what what are the
courses you have to study they require
you to take then also you find out the
textbooks they assign to each course
then that gives you okay that's a great
way to find a guide you know which
subject which topic you want to go to
then you can you know you can either buy
the textbooks yourself and read it or
you can go to the library or you can
find similar books because textbooks
today are corrupted they are extremely
expensive
you know I've studied why textbooks
become so expensive you know like
calculus textbook today is like over a
hundred dollars it's it seemed you know
this is City and and also the subject of
calculus you know much of an math they
don't change actually at least for
undergraduate they haven't been changed
for for twenty years at least okay so it
would be as much as good if you read a
calculus textbook from 1990s okay you
can find them like in $2 $1 you know
it's the same it's the same tip that you
know the hundred
over $100 today's textbook on calculus
similarly for physics or chemistry
chemistry this kind of hard sciences you
know so that's that's that's what I have
to say about learning self teaching
things okay okay it's like I guess
that's it so because I've been talking
for like to have 90 minutes let's see
all right anything anything else let me
know
type it type it please you have 10
seconds because this is some kind of
delay when you type something and when I
say something when it reaches you and
when you reply then when I see it
there's this some kind of 10-second
delay so type whatever you have you know
questions or whatever and I'll see if I
have you know my answers of response
then dab it for today for today thank
you guys for coming by
how do we beat the extreme left I don't
know
that's we just have to get everyone to
fight it
that's I hope yeah that that's that's
what I hope for and you know yeah I hope
I hope you know there's a lot of things
these are not things you know this is
like the 4chan coop fortune kind of
people did today today they have the 4
channel 4 channel 4 channel hn you know
kind of people they do means and stuff i
you know that's not my thing i don't so
in general I don't like I don't you know
that's my not my thing so I rather wish
people you know I wish oh you people you
know you know I don't mean to hash out
you know my opinions I I mean I don't
mean to insist my opinions you do
whatever you know is suitable for your
life you know whatever your environment
but what I'm I hope to see is that I
hope people you know the geeks nerds
start to you know use your name and
don't post the mean stuff you know maybe
maybe it's actually working maybe I
don't know but but what I you know for
example I I'm I self tends to be you
know I used to really say whatever I
believe is true you know you have to do
that because when you are when you have
a face and you know you are more
respectable in public when you go and
talk about no I don't disagree I think
you are doing really bad things you know
you have to do you have to do that and
tell other people to do that you know
start to stand as opposed to you know
like this whole video I've been talking
about as opposed to becoming this niche
group you know this niche group in
fortune Oh in whatever programming
language groovy IRC you know you know
become this niche anonymous you know
talking about cryptography and you know
all sort of deviant you know for I mean
techniques to you know pass get away
from whatever things you know yeah
don't you know that I yeah I don't think
that's really helping we've been doing
that for 20 years it's like you know so
I you know this is just my uses just me
okay yeah I would rather hope people to
stand for what you believe is true you
know I think that okay by the way no
worries I mean I don't mean you know I
always tend to get kind of argument with
my followers okay so you know it's not a
concern of you know really okay thank
you guys for watching thank you for
Vaughn I hope to see you guys next time
bye