hello good morning everyone welcome
everyone Thanksgiving Happy Thanksgiving
welcome to another episode of Star Talk
show
so we are going to do emac beasts coding
which we were going to do yesterday but
we
we got distracted I got distracted and
talked random about psychology about
Maya's Maya's break test and so on so
today we are just going to code emac
Beast okay we are going to code emac
beast and this is probably boring for
you okay now if you have not
now if you want to learn this
I'm going to live code lisp okay and
this is gonna be uh the problem is a
little bit esoteric you know and
so if you want to if you don't know you
can go to Psy Max blog and there is this
Basics I did a video on that so that's
inter introduction to emac this so if
you have not yet you can go watch that
if you don't have any emacs experience
uh but today
I'm just going to call something uh
something or more a bit more advanced
okay let me show you what am I going to
code
vocabulary go to study programming blog
if you are here say hi okay say hi
report
you know say hi and any questions you
have
um post it okay so I'm going to write a
command let's see so I'm going to write
a command let me show you on the pink
window you can see all my emacs command
course
and uh
uh the keys keystrokes I'm using
overrack keyboard This is a physical
keyboard This is Xpose
okay let me show you so excited keyboard
blog you can search and find it and you
can go to ergonomic keyboards and this
is all you need to know all you want to
know about ergonomic keyboard and today
I'm using expose night okay it's really
fantastic I recommend it
if you never had ergonomic keyboard I
mean mechanical keyboard before go out
and buy it now okay
you can buy the Xbox night expose uh I
would recommend this one okay hundred
fifty dollars exposed nature
buy that or anything above that okay at
least get the exposed nature because it
has a qmk firmware which is uh very good
but if you are a student you know you
don't have money and you don't you you
want to get your first mechanical
keyboard you can get this exposed light
okay
so exposed so that's my keyboard but I'm
going to code emac baseball Okay so
yeah so it's gonna just be relaxed and
yes in today's Thanksgiving so how are
you guys doing so let's see hey Luis
well hello to Germany and uh Desu bringa
okay this is
okay so emac based coding so let's do
okay let's start so let me show you what
am I going to do what is the problem
what is the problem
let's see video check audio check good
okay so the problem is you know when I
when you write a lot uh when you write a
lot HTML sometimes for example you have
this block of text for example uh this
is my
uh you know this this block of text
corresponds to this text block so
sometimes I want to move these to
somewhere else for example I want to
cut it okay then go to math block and
show in browser so this is another Blog
My mathematics blog so I want to paste
it there okay so I see you see and
showing browser
now you can see I pasted some text here
but now if I click it top file not found
because all the relative links you see
are incorrect now
because of the direct directory
structure so if you move you know if you
copy and paste a block of text
from One Directory
and let's say you know all these links
are in you know within the current
directory so all that those files are
somewhere here if you move to another
page let's say calculators this page and
you paste it there it'll be fine
let's see this is a calculators page
okay but if you move the link to some
other directory let's say I go up one
directory and let's say index.html and I
paste it there all those links will no
longer work because the
those relative links are incorrect okay
so undo undo
close it close it close it
okay so show in browser again so all
these links are incorrect oh that one
still works because that one
let me show you okay so that one is this
one and this one is going up One
Directory you see dot dot slash that's
the Unix
bad tradition but anyway that's go up
one directory then go to the Linux
directory then this file
why tiny Window Manager sucks
so this link still works but all the
others doesn't work anymore Apple Mouse
doesn't work you see
so I want to write a command so let's do
it let me show you okay so let's first
of all
I'm using HTML mod
so I want to copy the whole section I
can press one key copy the whole section
element okay cut it showing browser you
see it's good now close this file
now this is back to my showing browser
back to my keyboard blog okay
uh keyboard blog and go here paste them
here
showing browser keyboard block they are
back you see now you see all this thing
works Mouse history uh yeah let's let's
take a gander let's you know
show some
fun stuff you know Mouse history very
interesting Mouse history back then this
is 1980s I remember using this Optical
Mouse this up Optical Mouse you need a
special
mirror pad
so anyway miles History app and uh oh
this is back in the days this today this
kind of ad is not allowed
but this is back in the day in the 19
1991 when I started to use a computer
you know you have these ads on PC
Magazine you know um there's no internet
yet well there is but you wouldn't know
it's only used by scientists there's no
internet like the web yet so anyway so
this is um you know
this is a mouse history and this is kind
of related because what is one of the uh
kind of very popular game on my machine
so this is 1991.
and then you have Logitech mouse you
know anyway
so
because I I write a lot HTML so
constantly I need to move some block of
text from one page to another so I need
to I need to have a function
that takes the text a string and for
each local Link in the Stream now if
it's links to external link to some URL
HTTP something then there's nothing
needs to be done but if the link if it's
Edge you know if it's a anchor tag this
is one of the idiotic name A4 anchor so
basically just means link you know it
would be better if they say if the tag
is named link so anyway if you have a
link that's that points to a local file
then the emac this command will change
it change just the link okay
so that is the command that is the thing
we need to write you know I've been
needing to do this for a long time for
several years
so let's go back to talk show and let's
begin our journey of writing coding this
emac this different okay different let's
give a name to our function because I
HTML
um
change local link
uh
change your local link
in stream okay let's just name it that
okay so let's just name our function
that or change because I HTML change
local Link in string and now let's
document it document it the more the
most important thing I code I usually
write documentation before I code
as a matter of style coding Style
who else here watching say something
okay and any questions comments uh just
post it okay so this uh so this function
will take three arguments the first
thing is a string
text block the second argument is
current okay then the third argument is
targeted
okay
three arguments
now
what does this command do
um
V10
a string
that is the text block with
all links that is written a string that
is text block HTML
with all links in
or local links in it
changed appropriately you know they
didn't say
[Music]
um
from Canada
to Target the
uh okay this is not the best
documentation but
um you know
we
we have to so now this is the technical
writing you know technical writing is an
art and a skill in itself it takes a few
years to master so you want to be
precise and with Clarity so people read
it once they understand and understand
it exactly unlike in contrast to the
python documentation of the Python
idiots
so here you want to say return string
that is a text block HTML
with all local links in it changed
um
okay this is not the best description
but but you know let it be for now you
understand what I mean and later on
after the video when I put this code
into my you know my my site HTML mod
then I'll just make it better
you know it's uh it's quite an art to
write you know documentation because you
you know
anyway so yeah let's begin so
so okay so let's so let's begin and what
we want to do is we wanna uh by the way
I'm using stuff like keys
so you want to let's go to
[Music]
um
programming blog okay wait let's go to
keyboard blog
because I we already used that example
so when we so we want to look at what uh
the input text looks like so this is
what input text looks like so basically
what the command will do is you
go through
the input string
okay go to the input string
find each and every
link
that is Anchor tag
anchor attack you know the naming is
problematic this anchor attack because
you if you say a tag that's confusing
because a is a article in English you
know you know if you say uh change or a
tag you know that's ambiguous so it's
problematic but if you say anchor
you know so here is another thing that
is another kind of field a subfield that
is the naming of things the naming of
things in programming languages or in
protocols which is very critical very
very extremely critical
because when you have a programming
source code
your function you know even a
programming language you know in
programming language you know you have
things like let that's Define local
variable interactive that's something
special to emacs you have different
that's defining variable some
programming language will say Lambda
some language will say function such as
Java some language will say subroutine
you know Pearl for example uh in Python
you say depth I think DF you know so
that's the naming of things naming a
function naming a variables is quite
significant you know you want to be
um you don't want it to be super long
you know you don't want to say Define
function because then they you know your
code becomes too verbose and that
decreases readability
meanwhile you don't want to be cryptic
like you know for example cryptic like
the closure case you know the closure
lips lips they have I believe the FN
everything kosher is like just two or
three letters
that's not good okay so it's it's kind
of an art so here for example when when
you when whoever invented HTML from sgml
you know you have the when you want to a
have a link how do you call it because
given the the way it is if you say
anchor tag if you say you know anchor
tag you know most people will say what
the [ __ ] is Anchor what what what what
what anchor anchor my ass okay that's an
idiotic name but for reasons you know
maybe back in 30 years ago 40 years ago
it was meant as some sort of anchor you
know I actually I don't know the history
you know but the context maybe it was 40
years ago in 1980s in sgml where HTML
came from you know so back then maybe
that is this this this a thing
is meant uh some kind of anchor okay
anchor meaning
you know fix it
in place something but anyways as far as
We Know It's Just link or hyperlink okay
so today when you say anchor attack you
know people get confused because there's
no such word
in all HTML it's not a keyword in HTML
so you have so so the situation now is a
problem is a problem it's a
manifestation of a problem of a bad
naming okay and we all just suffer from
it you know every day we can't you know
we can say
a you know
if we say a tag that doesn't that's not
too clear if we say tag a that's not too
clear if we say anchor
tag then what the [ __ ] is Anchor or
anchor element you know you know so
that's a problem but if you say link
oh
everyone knows what they what it means
the link you click a link you know oh
hyperlink
but then the link doesn't correspond to
any of the keyword in HTML there is
actually actually there is a tag named
link okay so for example let's do it
link
okay but but you know but it means
something else for example you can see
an example it's DD that go to the top
you can see that is what blink is it's
kind of internal but it you know anyway
that's
so we are kind of going through the
baggage
you know the 30 30 years of baggage of
HTML that troubles us
to this day everyone every programmer
the millions of web dev have to suffer
from this this is just one of the
example there's there's a lot more
so anyway so we want to go through the
input stream and find and each every
link
uh
let's just say tag a okay and find every
link and
if it is
a local link
uh change it so it works with a local
link with respect to so it works with
the
Target though okay so something like
that
so so it is correct with this
with respect to
Target Okay so
that's the that's the task okay now so
now it is coding
emacs so intriguing yes
so so now we're gonna call emac this uh
so we we so you got a text block you
want to go through the link uh what to
do
well
uh you know like I said you are you know
this is you are wasting your time
watching me coding this because this is
rather this is not a simple emac Beast
so I have to do a lot of kind of
thinking and uh
uh how do how do you do this so
a text block that's a string
so you want to
so first let's just let's let's let's
just
push forward let's just code whatever
you know uh because when I'm doing
YouTube live coding it's the best way to
always just push through you know
whatever comes to you know once you know
like when when you think of one way to
do it just do it so instead of thinking
about you know which way is the best and
uh you know so that way
you guys you know can see you know the
activity you know like when you watch a
movie when you watch your movie
involving hackers or cybernetics or
coding you'll see whenever they show
someone programming it's like
and all the key slides up you know
yeah and so we need some music for that
as well so anyway so
so we need to um
so first of all let's create a width
temp buffer okay with
temp buffer now if you have a question
just ask me okay
because it's gonna be kind of boring
anyway you know you you need to know
some images
in order to know what I'm doing so with
temp buffer
uh and insert so with temp buffer
creates a temporary buffer okay and we
just insert text block into it
okay and then
now predefy the code okay with with temp
buffer we create a buffer then we insert
the giant string into it then we go to
the beginning of the buffer go to char
go to char uh the beginning buffer would
be uh point mean okay point mean
that function Returns the position of
the beginning of the buffer okay usually
you can just say go to one the first
character is one okay that's the you
know beginning of above but
but if you have narrowed to region and
things like that then the beginning of
the buffer is not one you know because
because
well I'm not going to explain too much
detail because you know I did so many
emac this videos before so let me just
go on
any quick hint to learn emacs oh yeah
well one thing you can do is just go
through my tutorial okay
okay this and then you know
um you know today we are going to finish
coding this for sure so you can just go
to my tutorial emacs tutorial and each
day read a couple articles like read
three or five each day spend 30 minutes
to read you know download check version
that's a preparation
launch and quit you know every day you
know take take half an hour
on a few articles okay then you have
funds you know the first thing you want
to know is probably how to change font
in emacs here's how you do it and then
one of the first thing you started to
want to know is how to split windows you
see split split split split oh my God
[Laughter]
you know that's that's what you want to
do you eat the power of emacs and you
can have a shell here let's start this
year
uh wait what uh yeah let's start issue
also here's the Issa showed we are in
Powershell so
well among windows but the windows
doesn't well I mean so you have to do LS
in eshow
or we can start Powershell anyway so
this so you know each day just spend a
few you know half an hour to
read one of them okay depending on how
your type of Personality how you like to
learn
uh
but I recommend you know the thing is
persistent okay do not come to emacs
thinking it's a godsend editor you're
gonna Master it in one month then maybe
you have some frustration and after
month you
abandoned it that's no good rather think
of this way e-max is a very classic old
editor and super powerful you know that
for sure because you know either you
have seen me or you have seen many other
people there are many other emacs
tutorials out there you can also watch
them you know so
so you can learn so you know emacs is a
powerful editor but the problem is it
takes some time to learn you know
that that is right if you are impatient
you know your best editor is vs code
uh
but if you are you know you want to you
are thinking about for the next 10 years
or 20 years you are going to be a
programmer for life
or if you are a technical you know you
are a computer operator whatever you do
movie editing or whatever profession
you're gonna need a text editor so
so Matt so emacs or Vim or even Vim is a
good choice or neovim okay so you wanna
slowly you wanna do it every day and you
want to use it in a practical way so
every day whatever you do just use emacs
okay use emacs so one one way to learn
is just each day just read a few
articles then you'll get to um emacs in
it
which is whole lots of things and emacs
keys customizing Keys uh and so on so I
would recommend
you know if you ask me I would recommend
just read my tutorial spend half an hour
a day do that for one or two months okay
start from scratch
you know there are too many options I
can't cover everything of course you
know you might like uh they are doom
emacs there's also space Max
you know you can use them
uh yeah you know but if you ask me
those are also good options but you know
you can also begin uh
from scratch okay that's actually that's
what I actually recommend and of course
Microsoft like Keys you might come to
know eventually uh you know that's what
I'm using
okay back to emacs coding and eventually
you'll learn emac beasts okay so back to
coding so here we want to so we go to
the beginning of the buffer then
then then here is what we do okay
search forward
search for word uh the regular
expression search for word okay that's
what we want we want to search for now
Spirit buffer again we want to search
for
anchor tags we want to search for
text of this form okay so yeah what uh
yeah that so we want to search for
something like that okay so
so okay so you can paste that here okay
and we need in emac this quotes needs to
be escaped so you can do Escape quotes
there better so you want to search for
something of this form h-i-e-f okay
and for now you know sometimes you have
a class here but for now let's just
ignore it you know sometimes you have
class or style or ID
uh in fact if you want to do it properly
you need a passer you know but for for
me that's just you know for this video
Let's you know let's just do the simple
way assume that all links are just a
then h i e f okay
so here is a arbitrary text that needs
to be a regular expression and I have a
brief for that so that regular
expression is going to be
uh
strg regular expression do it that is
the regular expression we want okay so
copy that move to here
paste it okay that is a regular
expression that means Search Everything
any character that is not a double quote
and search the minimal of it until you
reach your double quote actually search
the maximum until you you reach your
double quotes so this will capture this
part will capture the link okay
uh that part will capture for example
this link okay
oh God this is actually a lot of work uh
more than um
yeah actually there's a lot of work
because you know what we need to do then
then we need to check if that's a local
link or not if it's local we need to do
some change uh yeah more than okay let's
keep going now in emac this regular
expression any backslash needs a
backslash so we need a backslash titas
okay but not not the backslash before
the double quote
how do I know well by experience or you
can read you know my emacs tutorial on
regular expression there's article on
that
so so here's a regular expression that
captures the link then what about the
text the text we don't care okay leave
it be so a week here is to capture the
first part okay
uh and once we captured it now why is it
color yeah yeah it's correct
hmm what
HTML so optional optional bound Neo no
Arrow true
uh and count no we don't care okay
so we
find that link now we got the link now
we want to check if that link is local
link as opposed to http okay oh my God
this is gonna be a lot coding you know
uh yeah not coding
so let's see playing emacs sucks
well you have to start somewhere because
if you use you know I know of lamio you
use two emacs that is great
but it's like the cloud that somebody
else is set up you know it's like the
cloud you know it's someone else's
computer
you you know if you want to master Emax
to change emacs to suit your ways your
style then you want to start from
scratch
uh a lot of emac users actually
eventually do it anyway not everyone but
you know you can use emacs for 10 years
and not knowing anything about emac
baseball you need file that's you know
that's fine
uh so different you know different
people for different styles
so let's see what's next so how do you
deal with using emacs in both Mac and
Linux where the super old keys are
switched
that's easy that's trivial you don't
even have to uh because on the Mac for
example
that's a different topic but let me show
you okay let's go to keyboard blog again
showing browser
and you know so you are asking you know
Mac or Windows or Linux they have
different
um modifier key
arrangement
so for that you go to software how to so
you can see how to create keyboard
shortcut so you have a section on
Windows section on Linux it's all about
key mapping KB binding how to create
create your own key shortcuts or
keyboard markers okay then you have a
section on a Mac of course you have a
section on emacs emacs you know
so you go to for example yeah to your
question if you are asking that question
you know how do you switch between well
mostly just for the Mac you just go to
um
you know you just go to the
system preference okay there swap uh
yeah swap modifiers you see
you know on the Mac you just swap the
you know control and opt actually there
are so many ways to do it in emacs for
example okay let me cover let me let me
cover another way okay so again let's go
to emacs okay emacs block you click on
emacs keys and then you go to
uh meta X Okay so
The Meta key
then you can see what is the meta key
some introduction where is The Meta key
on Microsoft Windows by default is alt
on Linux it's also Old Mac it may be
option or command depends on which emacs
distribution you are using in other
words depends depends on where you got
the emacs you know they can and you can
you can change them by the way you know
so anyway so you have to you know if you
want to do that read these articles okay
so you can change it system wide on the
Mac for example you can also change it
in emacs if you prefer that way you know
swap swap the old with the
you know swap the max option and command
key or swap the Windows alt and Windows
key depending on you know and it also
depends on which keyboard you are using
you know because some keyboard they are
designed for the Mac so then if you use
it use it on Mac no problem if you use
on Windows then your Windows key and old
got swapped you know so and depends on
your keyboard
and also depends on if you have a gaming
keyboard or programmable keyboard many
of these for example this one you can
swap them you know sometimes there's a
switch in the back you just switch to
the Mac then the old key and the Windows
key will be swapped okay so that's um
you know that's not
that's a question where you can easily
find the answer so it's not it's not a
big question that's a question where you
can easily find a lot of solutions
different solutions
so let's go back to coding this
oh my God I don't know if we can finish
45 minutes already [ __ ]
uh so actually let's let's focus on this
coding okay we we want to get this to
work
um
uh of lamio just use stuff like Keys
okay don't mix with evil mod you know
they are not compatible and they do not
tolerate each other if you're gonna use
stuff like he's kick kick the Evo mod
out of out you know forget about it
uh it would be I would say Superior than
the you know evil mod but if you prefer
you know you want to be able to use Vim
you know you prefer to be
to be fluent in both emacs and Vim
then Evo mod is a good choice okay
you know you can choose that
uh you know yeah you know you have 10
years using Vim then that's your that's
your thing that's that'll be fine
okay so let's finish coding this so next
next
so we got um we got a link now we need
to check if it's Auto uh check
if the link
is local link got a lot to do man a lot
to code
um
so
so first of all we need the if statement
if you found a link okay if you found
link found the link
wait uh what's going on
wait we got we missed um oh we forgot a
backslash that's why okay so first of
all check
search for a link
if it is found then do your things okay
then we do whatever here
if the link is not found do nothing okay
Neo okay predefined the code good
now so if a link is found such as this
one check if the link is local okay how
we do that
you can do first of all
um
let's let's create a local variable
and let's just say X
h r e f vowel okay that means the value
that means the value of the href
attribute okay
so
so first of all we want to set
these two
match string
okay
you see we captured the link here so we
have we can retrieve it using this
function match string so we say one
means the first capture okay
that's right
so this xhif vowel
is the
link string okay now let's rename the
variable let's use a dollar sign so it's
kind of customary to PHP or Pearl
programmers you know it indicates it's a
variable in emacs you don't need that
but uh I have a convention to do
to you to do that because you can
you can
textually
determine which
token is a variable
by appending by prepending a dollar sign
to it now this has a lot of advantages
this this sort of use of naming variable
is is called um sigio you know it's
popularized by Pearl then PHP
enclosure closure has a ton of it you
know let me show you closure okay
so you just search for oksadi search
then you type closure then you can see
uh there's a lot let's see what is
closure in programming what is oh
closure that's another closure you want
closure with the J okay so closure
I have a tutorial of it of course
then there it is a tutorial The Meta
data
let me show you that one
because this is something of particular
interest to me because when I study
programming languages
the thing I focus the most is the syntax
and the naming a variable or the form of
the variable is one of the critical part
of the syntax so as you can see closure
lisp
you know the language you love
you know like like many list people you
know many lispers when they see me using
the dollar sign they will react the
[ __ ] side idiot you know that's their
reaction a lot of the for example many
of the popular emac this coders when
they see my code with a dollar sign they
will just laugh at it they will laugh
you know there's this this idiot they
don't know you know I don't know this
and you know introducing the pro and PHP
things into him at least
but they but they they don't know they
don't know [ __ ] this these phonetics
okay let me tell you the reason I'm
digressing but let me tell you the
reason why
I use a seizure
and in fact cgo you'll see it in lisp 2.
it's just that they don't really they
don't realize it this list idiot okay
for example
you see that is very common this syntax
you'll see this everywhere you know
apostrophe then parenthesis what if what
is what what the [ __ ] is that apostrophe
that is a seizure my friend
you also see it you know not just there
but for example you can you can have
this Sigel X
what the [ __ ] is that apostrophe that's
a seizure just like just like this
variable with a dollar sign in front
it has a special meaning in this okay
this in this case it's a quote okay and
in this you have other seizures okay
you have other seizures like that a tick
or back tick or it's called um
grave accent
okay the Unicode name is grave accent
accent okay so you then you also have in
common this you have worse you have that
sijo you know those are sijos okay so
they exist in emac this in scheme disk
scheme this has small and they exist in
common lists even more
now in closure at least you got even
more you got 10 times more closure this
CJ
so for example a variable may start with
a
the asterisk sign it may end with the
question mark it may end with the ban it
may end with a
um
a dash or a hyphen the Unicode for this
character the Unicode name is called
hyphen minus okay normally we just call
it a minus sign or Dash or hyphen hyphen
is more most common traditional or the
you know in so enclosure this you a
variable may also speaking with a colon
sign each one had each one of them has a
special meaning enclosure some of the
meaning is by convention
meaning that
you know it's just by convention it
tells you what the purpose of the
variable
is for but it does not have a meaning in
the language okay so that is by
convention but some of them has a
meaning in the language that is if you
see a variable with a particular prefix
then the language interpreted that
variable in certain way okay so some of
them are conventional some of them are
part of the closure language
syntax okay so you have you see you see
all these seizures and the slash by the
way that that doesn't mean division my
friend this this slash is not the vision
this is also this is uh this is a
namespace separator Okay so
so you can see closure has then double
colon then backslash character then a
variable may also be just a underscore
or this character in Unicode is named
low line okay traditionally it's called
underscore okay then you have quite a
lot you have the you know this is
closure okay
uh
you know he normally in a lead in lisp
tradition a function is always usually
spelled out but in closure you have a
lot
weird things like a DOT you know a
period is also a kind of a function
then you have like
a symbol followed by dot then it means
something else two dot means something
else you know
alpha numeric
followed by a dollar sign Then followed
by often from numeric that means
something else okay it means access Java
in a class
kosher is intertwined you know it's like
intertwined with Java they are very
intimate closure
that is why a lot of people include me
in particular do not like closure you
know if closure cut off there is
relation with Java then it's good okay
but closure when you learn you know when
you do closure everything is like going
around Java you know and in fact you
have to know Java to know closure you
have to you cannot go closure without
you know because you see closure
you see all these are just calling Java
methods you know it's like intertwined
it's just
you know
uh so there's much more you know there's
all this syntax this syntax so normally
you would think that lisp is just
parentheses right
not so enclosure lisp enclosure list
your your code is not just parenthesis
you have you have this
special you know correct
braces then you have correct colon
symbol you know it's a shortcut for this
form with meta you know then then you
have the add sign then you have the
pound sign then you have the pound sign
followed by braces it means something
else
here it means a set okay a set
okay that's enough so you get the idea
you know you get the idea about the
seizure the use of seizure enclosure
very very complex
okay so the you know so my point is my
rent against the least phonetics so this
this you know often typical these
phonetics they don't know they don't
know things
you don't know things but they think
lisp is great for uh
for the wrong reasons
just because they you know they like it
I like this because it's functional
programming okay most of all the number
I I read I like this okay
more than say JavaScript
python Ruby
Java and C or C plus plus scrap the
idiocy C and C plus first
those idiotic languages but why why do I
like this more than this other because
the number one reason the predominant
reason over all the reasons is because
list programming is functional
programming
now if you are a Zoomer you you might
say oh this piece not functional because
haskout this or that anyway that's
another story so anyway so let's get
back to this
uh so I'm fine so I found your paid
emacs tutorial is that still a thing or
outdated
uh they might well my emacs tutorial is
all free online okay but if you like my
stuff you can pay and you'll get a
downloadable version which is
exactly the entire my website for the
the emacs section that's what you'll get
so you'll get instant you know instant
page load you know let's go to my email
yeah instant
uh let's see go to emacs tutorial that
you know let's magnify you can get
instant page load and uh you know
you know if you like my stuff if you
think I'm a good guy you want to support
it
pay me okay
we talked for one hour and we barely
begin to code this problem
so
um so let's get back to it God
you need to do this we rambled a lot
by the way a good plug into a
spreadsheet okay
random questions so you guys random do
we have a serious person here who are
really learning emac this is a free
downloadable version for for Google fan
language I talked about that a thousand
times if you watch any one of my video
you know be serious about it not just
random
okay so so so so so let's go back to
code list
um
so now we
we got the link and we want to find we
want to check if it's a local link so if
uh
string match
okay that's how you check
a regular expression against a string so
the string is that
optional start we don't care and the
regular expression is
so let's say HTTP okay so if
so yeah so http
um
s
optional
and followed by colon slash slash okay
so if the string matches that then it's
near okay otherwise it's local okay then
we're gonna do something here so if the
string is local
local link okay so let's predify the
code
so if the string matches HTTP oh yeah we
have to put a correct that means match
from the beginning of the line hey
offamio thank you
thank you
uh
uh so if the string matches
HTTP that's done local do nothing okay
otherwise
otherwise it's a local stream
so when it's local let's quickly finish
this you know Tim I hope to give a basic
form to demonstrate that this code works
okay a very basic form then that's it
for today so you know we showed the
basic way to do this okay
so if string is HTTP ignored otherwise
otherwise we want to get the full path
of the string okay
let's write it out
okay so how do you do that well you can
um
expand file name okay I believe that's
the command you can
you know I know it out of my head
because I've been coding emac this for
15 years but for you
you'll find it by you know learning
basic emac this will find a tutorial
here about practical emac this about how
do you get all the directories
um functions
for example
file and directory path you know so you
can check file exist rename file or copy
or delete file or get get a list of
files names or create directory or
get a directory part of a file or get
the file name extension and so on so
that's how I know
you know I just use it so often so and
that's why I know out of my head okay so
expand file name of this probably a
relative path
then with respect to of with respect to
the related and that part will be
kunda okay so that is how we get the
full file path okay so let's put a
let's just say that there okay so full
path
set full path equals true
okay something like that then
we got the full path then we want to
find the relative path but with respect
to the Target directory okay so so what
we can do is
um
so again we refer to file relative name
you see that one
final relative name
okay now I'm cold I'm a bit cold I think
I need to put on a code because you know
it's winter Halloween Halloween not a
Thanksgiving
how is you guys how's you guys
in our regular expression uh well I can
explain that topic but it's gonna
bring the expression actually there's
nothing you can do I mean yeah regular
expression is hard to read that's true
but ultimately that is the nature of it
there is not much you can you can you
like in other words you cannot
fix the problem you know the
unreadability the hard to read situation
of regular expression you
you can make it better a little bit but
not really because that is the nature of
regular expression
wait that's not correct actually
yeah you get yeah take it back you can
have complete syntax that replaces
regular expression and uh
and make it so much easier to read yeah
there is but I'm not gonna talk about it
for example this wolfam language there's
a there's a syntax called e called
string expression okay in Wolfram
language you have regular expression you
also have string
expression
let me show you okay so Wolfram language
you just search for wufam language then
you go down then you'll see
a regular expression section you can
just search for it there it is pattern
matching pattern syntax okay you click
on that and you can see pattern wait
this is not regular expression you you
need string patterns okay not the
symbolic pattern so there string pattern
okay so you click on string pattern so
we can see regular expression
so that's how you do regular expression
in Wolfram language but you also see
this string expression you see so what
is string expression that is just like
regular expression but allows you to but
it uses a different syntax okay so
string expression is a alternative
syntax to regular expression that's
available in Wolfram language now in
emac based you also have
alternative expression for regular
expression a lisp based Syntax for
example let me show you okay that
package is called RX okay so there it is
okay
so
so here you know so
if you really want to in emac base you
can use this package to do regular
expression this one is called RX okay
the file name is just RX dot El you see
and it's in the you know it's bundled
with every emacs you know in this
directory so you can so you can see you
represent or by parenthesize or
something something you know so this is
a alternative Syntax for regular
expression okay RX package in emac this
or
string expression in Wolfram language so
that's two alternative Syntax for
regular expression
that I'm aware of okay
each one of them is easier to read okay
so let's go back to our code
close that so
so now you want a relative path in the
Target path okay
so you get the related path so now okay
you got that now you need to delete
the link you found Okay so
well oh God this is hard to do so you
actually need
so check
string
so
so if such if you found the link we save
the link to href value now I'm getting
tired my back hurts
so
href value is a link now if you check if
it's a local link if it is a local link
you get the full path and you want to
replace the original link so
you can say delete region
so actually match begin let's let's add
more variable Okay match
begin
let's say position one position two okay
P1
P2 okay so that's two positions integers
position of the cruiser Okay so
so we want to get the region so how do
we know the beginning position of the
link and end position of the link we can
get it by
by this way okay
uh
by this way so set Q
match beginning okay
one okay
so this will be
P1 okay
and here match end okay one one means
the first capture so
now now P1 and P2 is now
the beginning position of the link and
P2 is the end position of the link okay
we got that so now here we once we found
it's a local link
we
get a full path then we get the relative
path new
okay
let's
let's just say that to make everything
clear
okay so new relative path will be set
there okay then delete region then you
need to
yeah so delete region
first of all go to Cha
go to the
region where the beginning of the link
is at go to the position then delete the
link actually yeah they delete the link
then insert the
New Path okay
okay so I think that's that's it for one
link okay we need to do this for other
links this is just the first occurrence
of a link we found okay
but I think that's maybe that's it
let's remove these comments and uh
and let's end this video okay so let's
see um
so here is our code here is essentially
a full code
so this yeah that's it
uh okay check one more time before we
run it
so we search so we we got the text block
and we got a current directory and
Target directory so first of all we
um
we we create a new buffer insert the
text into it go to the beginning of the
buffer search for a link if found if
found to this otherwise do nothing okay
so yeah so if if we found it then get
the link text get the position beginning
and end then check the link is local
okay if it if it is
then we get the full path we get the new
path with with respect to the Target
then we delete the region then we go to
chart
go to chart
um yeah and we insert the new link okay
then
before we are done we need to
um
get the first string perfect string we
we want to return the whole string okay
so buffer string is a function
um
that that returns uh you can say Point
minimum
okay this is how you do it you can grab
the whole buffer content
into a string okay that's what this
returns so
um
so this this should okay let's try this
okay so now we need to evaluate this
function not its test okay
Let's test this function we need to call
it so test function because Okay so
so let's do this quickly I gotta you
know I gotta go take a break and uh so
let's go back to our um keyboard blog
okay uh
uh keyo blog and that's uh yeah so let's
grab the text here
for example that's our text and this is
a text again you need to escape the
escape the chords okay
okay so copy that so here is a string
okay we got the string first argument
text block now the
directory okay so let's go to keyboard
again here is the directory copy the
directory path close it
put the directory path there that's
correct
then we want the target directory let's
say I'm going to move it to sorry info
okay so this is uh sorry info so this is
a different directory copy that
so you see
now we can run this code this block of
course see if it works okay now first of
all
first of all eval the function now
okay
eval
no wait okay this error
you can see the output is here okay so
you can see let's copy it okay so copy
it copy it new buffer paste it so here
is output you can see
the first line has changed you see this
this mouse history it changed but it's
not correct something is wrong so
so we need to fix it
oh yeah we know because you see these
two are supposed to be directories not
file names the you see these two
variables it's supposed to be
directories easy to fix okay we use the
arrow that's actually use error now now
it should work okay let's do it again
control U then give out the buffer that
way your paste the output into where my
cursor is there it is
so
so inexaldi dot info you if you want to
go to the mouse history then you go to
the keyboard section directory then
Mouse correct you see compare you see
that
in that so it's correct so that's it for
today we finished you know what we need
to do uh this command however is not
complete because we need to do not just
that one but the next one next one you
know for every and each link we found we
need to do it and it's easy to fix
so it's easy to fix so let's fix it now
okay so uh search for what yes let's put
a while loop okay while
well
search for word okay there
then
so if it's found while this search
forward is true found a link then we do
our thing
then
you know then
when it all is done we just grab the
whole buffer string okay
there
so let's run it again okay let's run it
then let's run this
evaluate it and go back here delete that
control U Eva last buffer
there it is you can see the second line
Apple Mouse also fixed
you see the third one Neo Geo also fixed
the fourth one also fixed you see so
perfect we
yeah this is complete okay so uh we
could try some other
you know links with more nested
directories to make sure our code is
correct but you get the idea so this is
the result
uh yeah so this is fantastic so now we
pop it back to the HTML page showing
browser's talk show today here is the
fruit of our code today we need to
syntax color it show in browser again
maximize
so that's our fruit today beautiful
fantastic
now you see here this is a function now
in order to make this really useful I
need to write some other wrapper
functions so that I can just copy paste
you know a block of text from one
directory to another and and get all the
links automatically changed okay so
thank you guys for watching
thank you familiar so that's it for
today
um since year 30 thank you codeman code
condemned condemned 77.
uh pass a generated
three-seater is a good parser generator
uh I'm not sure about that you know I
think you showed me on Discord
I think Crazy Frog uh I think you are
you know all these pseudonyms makes
things much more difficult I think you
are someone
who
Crazy Frog I remember
I remember someone showed me the tree
frogs somewhere is is this you Las lies
oh
some somewhere tree frog okay I think um
yeah three-seater okay Salazar is tree
frog I think
so it's a pastor who wrote this and what
language is it written now usually if
it's written in C
or the uh you know then I trust it if
it's written in emac this no
that's just the nature of things even I
despise CNC plus first you know because
I I have tried this you know they not
get
because the easier the language
um you tends to have less knowledgeable
coders so C and C plus plus in Java they
are hard they are rather more harder
language and just too
so
but that also means often most most of
the time statistically speaking
those coders knows more stuff more
computer stuff because it's more
difficult
but it doesn't mean that those languages
I mean it doesn't mean you should you
know stick with low level language
otherwise let's all code assembly you
know there's a reason you need you you
should have higher level languages such
as Golan Golan is pretty very good okay
excellent low level and also Auto manage
goal line is fantastic
so so this this three-seater is written
in Rust as I believe okay so I can trust
it but what does it do you know you know
there are a lot there are tons of passes
okay and also
okay I withhold my opinion because I
don't really I have not written a parser
myself okay
so uh but what do you want about it
three-seater is a good passer generator
yeah but what do you want to do about
with it
uh do you use a website builder for your
no I have used not seen everything is
manual okay
let me show you okay so go back go back
to my top directory Saudi web uh is this
just go to kasari info okay you see now
go start Powershell
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching if you like this video if you
like my videos comment okay you get the
timestamp where you think it's useful or
something you want to come and get a 10
10 stamp post it on YouTube comment or
go post on Twitter or on your blog okay
spread what do you like
and
next step is donate okay patreon PayPal
me okay you know give me some candy
that is a good way put money where your
mouth is you know good way to advance
Society not by drama and clickbaits
okay so
um especially you open source phonetics
okay so now
the
file
because
filter
okay
anything HTML and
pivot 2
measure okay so I have 7 800 and 4 files
on sorry dot info
so you can see you know tense of it and
I also have
how many do I have in on saudi.org so
let's go to it
CD background oh let's magnify okay
let's magnify
CD
org okay and then the same command
measure
000.org seven thousand files close to
eight thousand on Saudi info
yeah I need to see the uh
well there's let's do this again so let
me
okay
so now
the
Sally
hold okay
and now
Sally info
so all together
I have 11 000 files each and every one
of them a manual region manually coded
manually written okay each one of them
uh
yeah just like just like what we did
today you know every tag every character
is manually done with the help of emac
Beast of course and some script in
Python in over the years from Pearl to
python to Golan
um yeah that's it
so that's one of the frequently asked
questions everyone wants to know what do
you what what what
um you know web generator static
generator what do you use I use emacs
manually okay
okay
okay bye guys
naive people
I'm tired I'm tired so I we shut down in
one minute I'm tired I'm gonna I need to
get up and walk
um okay so we did this fantastic
fantastic