Hello, good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Kadan Talk Show. We
are going to do advent of code 2025 day
7 in wam language.
Sorry there's some cough. So wam
language we did this many times. Uh if
you are here say hi love to see your
comments. If you are watching this
offline play at 1.5 speed. Okay show in
browser. So this is today's talk show
page. Now I need to add links to my
previous wam language talk. So for
advant of code. So search for wuam.
There it is. Go to the link URL. Search
for topic.
Copy. Paste. Actually, uh, go back.
Search for Wrame.
Uh, wra search. Search search. Search
search. Okay, that's today episode 741.
And, uh, copy the file link.
And, uh, so this is the topic box. We
just need to add
today's.
So there it is. And update all the topic
boxes. So you can see
we have updated all the topic boxes for
advent of code 2025. Close. Showing
browser. Back to Emacs. Close. Showing
browser. So today episode 741 and we
have the past advent of code topic
boxes.
Okay. Now let's begin. Now problem
number seven is becoming difficult. So
we'll see. I'll try to do it fast. Okay.
Oh, you got a tree. Uh can you see it?
Not really. So uh at the end of code
very annoying. So let's Um move is here
and
day seven
start wra language
and observe the beautiful logo. This is
regular polyhedrin. This is stellated
uh
stellated octahhedron. No not octahedron
doahedron I believe. Okay. Each each one
of them has a special name. So, wam
language version 14. Pop this out and
three shift enter to start the kernel
and magnify
the screen. Okay.
Now, advanc code like I said before is
very lousy website. You see they have
fixed layout so that when your font is
large
they The text went off the window. So
why don't we copy your copy and uh read
it in Emacs.
So
there it is. Okay. Vom code day seven
sponsor Jen Street their sponsor delete.
Okay. Uh now I want to make this to have
a margin.
You see, Emacs does a wrap. So, you can
see the text. It doesn't scroll off to
the right. You don't have to scroll
left, right. However,
I so but however, it still wraps. So, I
wanted to make um let me do this. Okay.
Field column is a variable. Okay. Right
now, it's set to 30. So
uh so you want to set it to let's say 60
uh 6. Okay. Evaluate it. Now describe
variable view colon.
Now you can see the value is 60. Okay.
Now the ping window shows all my command
calls and the keystrokes as I type such
as move down, move back, forward, word,
backward, word. So you can see they are
on the pink window. I'm using Emacs, the
most powerful editor.
Okay. So
code. Okay. So we set this field column
to 60. Now I can, you know, let's say
press a key. Press a key. press press uh
when you need to do Yeah, that's good.
Okay,
that's good. That's good. Or you can do
this alternatively. One sentence per
line. This is another way to format. But
I want it um
let's just Okay. Well, let's make it
that. Make it that. Okay. Now
you thank the Lafo parts for the help
and exit the trash compactor. Something
something something based on a large
sign that says teleporter hub. They seem
to be researching teleportation.
Teleportation. Very interesting topic
because that is the um press press press
press.
Let's go to Wikipedia. So I'm going to
read this like every few years uh I read
these kind of articles. This is
teleportation is an concept from science
fiction and has fascinating
consequences in philosophy in for
example the the meaning of the soul uh
and also physics of course
uh and uh according to quantum mechanics
it seems we cannot do that even in
theory be wait well I I mean, I don't
know much about this topic. So, anyway,
it's interesting. So, suddenly you find
yourself in a familiar unfamiliar room.
The room has no doors. The only way out
is teleporter. Unfortunately, your
teleporter seems to be leaking magic
smoke. Since this is a teleporter lab,
there are lots of spare parts, manuals,
and diagnostic equipments lying around.
After connecting one of the diagnostic
tools, it help for the displays error
code zero H dash N0.
Okay, so let me just uh
read it silently. Tachon manifolds.
There's an issue with one of the tachium
manifolds.
Manifold is just mean a surface in
higher dimension. Okay.
So in two dimensional it's a line mean
in in one dimensional one dimensional
manifold is a curve or line. Two
dimensional it's a surface. Think of a
flag surface or paper.
Uh then you got
three-dimensional manifold
and four dimensional or higher
dimension. Now, Takian is a science
fiction concept.
Potion particle is a hypothetical
particle that always travels faster than
light. Oh
at the end of code. Okay, you quickly
locate a diagram of the tachium
manifold, your personal input. A tachium
beam enters the manifold at a at the
location marked S.
Okay.
Tachium beans always move downward.
Okay. So the S will move downward.
Tachium beam passes freely through empty
space. dot.
However, if a tachium beam encounters a
splitter
correct correct correct symbol, the beam
is stopped. Instead, a new tachium beam
continues from the immediate left and
from the immediate right of the
splitter. Okay,
seems like a fun puzzle problem. So you
got this S that's going to fall down and
the the dots are spaces and whenever
there is a nail
or splitter or the correct
symbol
circumlex accent
character. Okay. Then it became two of
them split.
Okay. So what is the problem? Okay. For
example this. Okay, in this example, the
incoming tachium beam
extends down downward from S until
until it reaches the first splitter.
Okay,
then what happens?
At that point, the original beam stops
and two new beams are emitted from the
splitter. Okay.
Okay. S is the starting position. Okay.
So they split or they may merge. Okay.
This process continues until all of the
tachium beams reach a splitter or exit
the manifold. Okay, too fancy a word
manifold. You shouldn't use it because
uh anyway,
okay, it's split split and okay, to
repair the teleporter, you need you
first need to understand the beam
splitting
properties of the tachon manifold. In
this example, attackum beam is split a
total of 21 times.
Okay, they may split and they may merge.
You don't count the merge, you just
count the split.
Seems like a tough problem. Analyze your
manifold diagram. How many times will
the beam be split to begin? Get your
personal input. Okay.
Oh god, I have no idea. seems like a
non-trivial problem. We need to
study this
diagram quite a bit.
Now let's save this um
so open it. Search for text. I already
got my personal input. So this this is
my personal input. There are
142 lines.
Okay. And each line how many characters?
141 characters. So is that is that
right? 141 characters for each line.
Wait.
Yeah. 141
characters each line. And you got 142.
Oh, the last line is all empty.
Okay. So, make a backup. Go to the
directory and uh let's name this uh
problem.
Okay. Open it. Select all. Delete.
Shrink. Go back to this uh problem.
Cut. Close. Close. Close. Close. Close.
741. Problem. Paste there. Okay.
Input. Close.
Day seven problem. Okay.
Okay.
Oh, okay. So, let's uh actually copy the
problem page. Copy
and
link by
showing browser.
There we have it. Day seven problem
description.
Okay. So, let's see. So,
so we're going to look at this. Uh I
have no no idea how to solve this.
You want to count the number of split.
So you got this grid, you got this
starting position.
So at every line you may have one or
more of these beams.
Okay. So you basically compare the
current beam with the previous beam. In
the beginning you got one beam. So you
have to set up a counter.
Then it may become two or may become
three.
And the two beams might merge. So it may
decrease or increase. Okay.
But is there a possible possibility it
becomes zero? No. Because there is no
because when you decrease that happens
only when you have two beams becoming
one. So you must have two beams at least
in order to reduce it to one to decrease
decrease one number you can't from so
you only have one beam you cannot
decrease to zero.
So you got you got a bing counter. So
they may increase or decrease but never
to one never to zero. And basically you
just want to compare lines previous
line, current line, next line.
Okay. Uh let's think about the
terminology. Current line and next line
or
current line and previous line. Okay.
Well, you have to stick to one else it
become confusing. Okay. Let's say
current one next line. Current line next
line. Okay. Then uh so you compare
current line with the next line
and uh and you also have to keep track
of the current position of the beam
current position of the beam
and if the current position so okay
let's we can start to write a
description of I mean the analysis of
the problem Okay.
Uh uh taking this slowly. Okay. Code
problem analysis.
Uh we can start to write it.
Need to keep a counter of the count of
beams.
It may increase or
decrease
when it merge.
Increase split
but never become zero because
it takes two
beams at least to decrease when they
merge. Okay. Need to keep count counter
of the beams.
Start with one beam.
Okay. And
and uh then
you need to compare
current
line with next line.
And
you need to keep a keep a tracker or
keep track
of
position
of the beams of current
line. Okay.
you and you need to
know the positions
of the splitters
of a line or next line.
Let's say next line. Okay.
So you given each time in each loop
uh in a loop you
compare
current line with next line
compare. So what do you want to compare?
You want to compare the splitter's
position versus the uh I mean the beam
position versus the splitter. If they
are on the same position.
Okay. So if they are on the same
position it becomes split.
But uh meanwhile if they are on these
two
what happens when they merge
also?
Merge will happen only if they are on
the same position. Okay.
much happens when two when the two when
a new when two new beam positions
collide.
Okay, you start I started to know what
to do.
God.
So
go through line by line. Each time check
the next line. Compare the positions of
the beams versus the
correct the speeders.
If they
match then the beam position become two
and uh so they are basically indexes.
Okay.
So you basically just delete duplicate.
So delete duplicate means you can merge
the beans. Okay.
So, go through it. Compare positions.
Now, I I know what to do. Now, go
through it line by line. Compare
neighboring lines. And uh whenever you
see the index of the current beam, you
you keep a track of the current beam
positions when they are so it's
basically a list of indexes.
So when they are the same you um when
they are the same you split the beams.
So so for example if you have beam at
position three then it becomes two
beams. So a list of three becomes two
and four. Okay. Minus one + one.
Okay. Minus one + one. Okay. And so what
happens if you have on the on the edge?
That's interesting.
So does it the problem didn't say
anything about that. But you see my
personal problem do have that situation.
Does it?
You just need to check the first line.
Okay.
toggle truncate lines. Okay. So now
So now you can uh you can kind of you
see now you can kind of Oh god.
So you can see now you can see kind of a
tree shape.
Okay. Does but does it ever occur on the
first um part of the line? Nope.
You see the last the second to last line
is it occur on the position. So it never
happens at boundary. What about at the
end? It never happens at the end. Okay.
Yeah.
Okay. So anyway, so that's a personal
input close.
So you do not have to worry
when it goes off.
For example, if you have a beam here and
you have a splitter here,
it will not happen supposedly.
Since our personal input doesn't have
that situation, we can ignore it. But
that's the lousy
problem because it did not say it does
not happen. Okay, that's the nature of
advancable code under specified.
Okay, so
so you then then what? So you compare
then you each time you adjust your
number of indexes that are the positions
of the beams and then you reach then
then then then that's it that's it.
Okay. So we can start to write um
compare the positions positions of the
beams and the positions
of the splitters.
If they collide
the
adjust the position of
just
that position of the beam into
two new positions
that is first minus
one and plus
one
basic algorithm.
Okay, that's a basic analysis. Okay, now
let's write algorithm.
Turn the X block into a matrix
because matrix is easier to work with.
Yes, absolutely.
Then
write a loop that go
through the lines the rows. Change of
terminology.
Each time compare the current row with
next row.
Turn that into a block of ne matrix.
Start with
a state
which
is a list of indexes
representing
the
beams. Okay. Write a loop that go
through the rows each time compare the
current row.
If the
if the beam
collide
with splitter
change
that beam
position into
minus one And verse one
warning
edge case of
beam and
split
on the edge,
but it
does not
occur
in puzzle
input.
Okay, that's a algorithm
and this in woofer language is just
going to be one single line.
Okay, if you are watching comment. Okay,
in wolfin language this is one single
line. So let's start to code it.
Wolf language.
Okay. Now, but first of all, you need
the input of course
that
wait
copy.
Okay. So, input
is a string
of course
and turn that into matrix. So,
string split x input split by
back space back slash in split by a new
line. Okay, then
you map
this function to
this rows. Okay, character will turn
each
character. This function will turn a
string into a list of each characters.
Okay, now is that character or
characters?
Characters.
Okay, there's s
show uh show the documentation. There it
is. Give gives a list of the characters
in string. Okay.
And we can run it
and you'll see the result.
Fantastic.
Format it. See?
Okay. And uh copy that. And let's do
this in Wufam notebook. Paste
shift enter. Fantastic. And uh percent
for stand for last output
slash slash stand for postfix notation
matrix form.
Okay. So now it shows it nicely.
screenshot that.
Okay. So now,
fantastic.
Now, very easy. So, we want to loop
through these rows and we going to do
functional programming. So there is no
like no loop and update the state. So
but which function we're going to use?
So if so you know if you don't know go
to saw wam language
tutorial website search for it you'll
find it wam language for programmers.
Okay.
Then you go down there is a section. You
got basics, comments, print, string. You
got a section number, boolean, list.
Okay. Then you have a section on list
operations. Okay. This is a guide to to
operations in uh functional programming.
So you you never do like loop.
So what you want? you want you want to
uh basically map
block.
Okay, let me show you. So you can see
uh you don't you don't want to map block
because this is procedural
you know you don't want to map every
neighbor neighboring rows in one shot
because you wouldn't know what happens
here before you process the rows before.
So you can't just map them every two
rows. You have to
so you have to nest you do a you have to
do some kind of recursion.
So each time you basically take two okay
tedious.
So and you need to keep a state. So uh
first of all let's see uh for example
how do you
let's say that's what we have okay uh so
let's see
okay so let let's let's define them x
matrix
equals to so that
so we have a variable to work with shift
enter Now let's say uh take
take
x matrix
and take the first two I first two rows.
So if you begin with that what you're
going to do let's take um
you want to compute so first of all you
need to compute the position
current beam state okay so let's let me
do
So beam state equals to a list of
indexes. So it began with uh that. So
you want to so you know you begin with
that and what you want to do is that you
want to know each one of of them are
strings you want to know.
So you know to make the problem coding
simpler let's turn the dot into zero and
uh and the correct into one so that that
makes easier. So so we do before we
split
we do
string replace.
Okay let's look up the documentation.
string replace. Okay, that's easy.
String replace input
and we want to replace several things
and uh the first thing is dot they
become zero and
correct.
This is what grave accent
circumlex
circumlex accent. Okay. Circumflex
accent
becomes
one because numbers are much easier to
work with more efficient than string.
Okay. In programming languages.
Christian samp I'm watching. Hey, thank
you. Hi.
Okay, we change the string dot to zero
and uh the splitter to one. So, we don't
need that. So,
make it one line.
Copy.
Paste.
Eval. Okay, we got something wrong. Uh,
whoops.
What?
X input.
Yes. So why string replace?
Oh, because zero um
yeah, you got a problem because you
can't replace a string into a number.
So you need to first of all um
okay so you need to do this step later.
Okay. So, so um we have to do it like
first of all you get that then you do
the replace. Okay.
Replace
or
okay you do it here. So let me just copy
the code. Let me show you.
So that's that's our matrix.
Then you replace all that. Okay, that
will do. So copy that. Copy that. Copy
that to verify we are correct. Let's
test it here. You see? Fantastic. And
beautiful. And that S needs something to
do about that. What you going to turn
the S into?
Okay, let's leave it for now. Okay.
Uh,
so let's uh so so this is going to be
okay. That's going to be that line.
Show it again. Paste shift enter.
Fantastic. Okay. Now,
uh what does it return? So now
uh so we can actually copy that.
kind of boring. Okay, but that's what it
is. Okay, so
that's the output.
Now the beam state will be very easy.
You just need to extract position. Okay.
So,
position
X matrix
uh the first element
at
X matrix and you want to find that.
Okay, that will return the index of this
S
eight. Fantastic.
And we know it occurs only once. Okay,
so we know for sure it occur only once.
So we just get the first one. Okay, that
we'll return the list of a single
number.
So that's a state.
Now each time we take two
uh let's say
you see this S is tricky.
I don't like S, you know. Let's change
it to uh two
something like eight. Change it to
eight.
We can it's not necessary but um so that
you know if we change it it's going to
be just all numbers kind of easier to
work with. So capital S equal change it
to eight.
You see
um
which is this is kind of redundant.
Let's not do it.
Okay. Let's just let that be. Okay. So,
and now let's let's remove this.
Okay. So, they are aligned.
Okay. This so that's the current state.
Um then you are given let's say given
then you start to go through them.
In fact, the first row, let's take it
out. Okay, so let me show you
start row. Okay. Start row equals to
first.
Okay. So, let's do this. Okay. Let me
show you.
Start row
and
matrix equals to
Okay. So what this will do it will split
the first um
It will just split into two
H.
This is incorrect.
Yeah. So you forgot to have the argument
here.
Okay, so that's the first result. Wait.
Yeah. So if you say X first row you get
that X matrix you get that okay you
remove that S the starting row because
that's actually special
okay so you so you do that
you know again
can do that. Okay. And this is just um
then we go through the matrix then for
each one you want to
let's see how we want to do this.
Okay. So then
you want to go through the matrix each
time
you want to know the positions. Okay. So
you want to get the positions of the
matrix. Okay. So X matrix
X matrix let's say
first
okay then you want to check the
positions of one okay
then
there are lots of them so let's see what
you It
empty. Are you kidding?
Oh, yeah. Not the first. Well, the
Yeah, the first one is all zero. Okay.
So, you got to check the second. So,
yeah. Annoying. So, let's So, you need
to do this.
two
two and remove the first
that means second.
What?
Oh, not string, my friend. It's not
string anymore. It's just a number.
Okay.
Paste shift enter eight. Exactly.
That is because the first splitter also
occur
position eight. So let's say one, two,
three, four, five, six. Let's get the
sixth
element. Okay.
Uh, no. Oh, you don't want the first.
Okay.
Okay. Not
you don't want the first. You want all
show all. Shift enter. There you have
it. 6 8 10. That is because
this is position six. Let's say 1 2 3 4
5 6
7 8 9 10. Perfect.
Okay. So, what what this let me show
you. Okay. So, this this is the U.
Okay. We don't want the eight. We don't
want first. Okay. Hold on a second.
This is not beam state. This is split
state.
Splitter pers.
Okay, let's try this again. Let me show
you. So let's say if this is six
theme state
eight correct
splitter
state
correct. Now all you have to do is you
want to compare them to see if they
share any
elements.
Okay.
Now why is this a nested?
So matrix six that means
row six
right. So why is that?
Oh yeah. So because position may be a a
nested element. So that's why it always
return a list. You see this is
interesting in normal programming
languages such as Python, JavaScript,
Golan
or just about any programming language.
you the index of a list is a single
integer. Okay.
But in wuam language it returns a list.
Why? Because
because wuam language always work on
trees. So your list may be nested. So
the first index is the first element.
You know the element
then in that element it might be a list
again. So you need another index. So to
refer to arbitrary
element in a nested list you need a list
of indexes
and that is called position
specification. So each one each position
is a list. So that's why you got this
six you know at least even though in our
case the matrix is this you know this
row of matrix is flat. Okay do you see
what I mean? Okay. So anyway, that
explains why you got nested here because
each each thing is like uh supposed to
be several indexes possibly.
Uh almost 100 a.m. Okay, thank you for
watching. Yeah, good luck.
Now 1:00 a.m. That's in United Kingdom
or Germany something
or South Africa.
Okay. Fantastic.
So splitter positions did did we um
Yeah. So copy that.
So this is a sample
sample output.
Then you compare them. Okay. So what do
you do? You compare them by um
let's see.
Want to make sure. Okay. So
you need to know
if they collide.
That means you have the same index in
both. But you also need to know which
one. Okay? Because you need to know
which which one this
beam collide with which
splitter.
Well, basically you need to know which
beam collides. Okay. So you for this for
each of these beam position you need to
know if it occurs here.
Okay.
So what you want to do is that
so we can go back here.
So we these are all list operations
you what do you want to do first? Well
think about it. So for
you want to know so given two lists
each one list of positions.
So you want to know
if the beam state
any element in beam state occurs in that
and you want to know which one of them
occurred.
So one way to do it is do a union. No
not uh intersection.
Okay. So you can easily do intersection.
Of course,
um
you can easily do intersection.
Then we'll just return eight.
See? So
that's right. So you can do that. So
once you got that then you split.
Okay. Then
split.
What do you do is you do a intersection
then for each element. So let's put this
here so that we can see the kind of the
result. Okay.
Then you split. What? What? What do to
do to split? You you
map
the intersection
by a function. Of course, always map is
is should be a function. So function.
Uh so actually let's
modify
my woofam
uh wam language mode
abbreviation
to Um,
yeah, let's not do it. Actually, let's
do it. It's so easy. It's actually quite
easy.
So
map.
Yeah. Here. So all you have to do just
add the function. Okay.
evaluate it.
Close. So now when you say map,
it didn't um
map. There it is. You see? Fantastic.
And saver.
Okay. But you you want to map uh so
So now given eight you a list of eight
then um
that's a position okay then you map
again
Okay.
Okay. You just return a list. Okay. So
uh
-1 One
one
we do.
Okay, we can run this demo.
Are you sure? Yes.
It'll be a list of seven and nine.
Perfect.
Okay. So, there's something we need to
worry about here.
Because
because this needs to go into the
you know this seven and nine each one
should be separate. So,
so let's say the intersection is
something else. Let's say the
intersection is
8 9 8 10
say
and uh so that's the intersection
And what you what happens? Okay, wait.
First of all, a simple case
when you do that,
the result is that. Okay. Now, what
happens when you do that?
The result is that. Okay.
And uh that's not what you want.
Yeah. So you you need
let's check sequence.
Okay. I think that's what you want. Do I
make sense? I think this is
It's getting complicated now
because
okay sequence
C.
No, that's not what you want.
Yeah. So, let's say apply
make it more logical. the syntax avoid
shortcut syntax
so that people understand
okay so that
we'll return what I want 7 91
okay That's
close but not exactly.
Okay, let's not do this complicated
thing.
Let's just say flatten it.
Yeah.
Then do you want to start with the
flattened list or not?
Uh
because they are always
nested. Why don't you always say
flatten?
Flatten. Each row is always just um
okay so one one
let's always work with flattened
you can do that okay
so for example this first row is this
thing.
Okay. So,
so that we can run the code here.
This row that's s
okay.
So
that's going to be just that. Okay.
Then here also you uh just add flatten
and the matrix
row six. Let's say let's see one two
three four five six. Okay. It's that
one. So let's make it
clear.
I mean so that doesn't depend on
variables. Okay. It
okay 6 8 10. Fantastic. So we always
work with flattened list
and the intersection.
Now the intersection of these two is
just uh that
eight.
All right.
Good. And uh then then you Yeah. Then
you um
then you split.
Uh that doesn't work.
Yeah. Of course.
Of course. Now because you reduced uh
nesting, you don't need the position one
anymore.
That's what you get.
Wait, is it still um
Oh, yeah. So you need you need to do
flatt and split.
Okay.
Then
and then you again flatten
it.
Wait,
wait. You don't want again. You don't
want that anymore.
And this is now you work with flattened
list, right?
So
split on a single
on a beam state of a single beam.
That's what it is. Okay. And this one is
split on
on a beam
on a bean state of
two beams. Okay, make it clear.
You see? And this is when a merge
happens. Then you just need to do unique
uh not unique intersection union
intersection um
remove duplicate delete duplicate.
Okay,
fantastic.
In fact, the duplicate only happens
around neighbors. So you you can use
some more efficient um
function because it always happens
around neighbors. Let's never mind.
Okay.
So you see split on a beam state
deal with merge
beam.
So far so good.
What's a fa sith? Hi there. Okay. Wam
language. Okay. So
so fantastic.
new beam state. Okay,
that's it.
So, we just go through this process.
This this this and uh it should
give us result. Okay, here's a sample
code. So, let's put it back. This is a
sample
test case.
Okay. Now let's start to code the real
algorithm.
Now you can't you know you can't do this
get a solution because you need to go
through each you need you need to make
these
uh into like one function then you do a
recursion trivial. Okay.
So let's begin to code it. Okay. So
let's see. Uh you got the first row, you
got matrix. Okay. So and um
so you need to write a function
beam state
and uh
current
beam state and and a row. Okay. So
return
a new
beam state something like that.
You need to write this function.
Given a beam state takes a row returns a
new beam state.
That's right. Then you can call any of
the reduce or whatever. Yeah, reduce
will do.
Mhm.
Because to solve this problem, you have
to
do a loop. You cannot do them in
parallel. Because in order to find out
what happens at bottom, you have to know
the preceding state. You have to like in
order, this is classic example of
uh what Stefan Wuam calls computation.
um principle of
computational irreducibility.
Okay,
principle of computational
irreducibility
because there is no it is not possible
to have some kind of mathematical
formula to find out
what is the final result
without
actually just like do them one by one
step by one step because this is like a
cellular automata basically.
Well kind kind of this is like a special
case of cellular automa. Okay. So anyway
so principle of computational
irreducibility.
Okay. So anyway so let's so
so you need to write these functions.
It's easy. Okay. So let's uh
okay let's just write a functional
style. Okay. Equals to
uh function
functional style. So
wait that that that that that that that
that takes two arguments and what you do
here. Okay. What you do is that you
beam state and row. Okay. So beam state.
So now we need to start. So
takes a beam state. Okay, the beam state
is like uh
you got a beam state and the row.
So you you need this. So let's create a
local variable that's width. Okay.
So local variable
and this part is the row. Okay. Delete.
That's a row. Okay. Position flatten.
You want to find all the positions of
one. That's a splitter.
Okay. Once you got the splitter, then
you need to compare their intersection
which we have the code um
here.
Okay. And delete duplicate. Okay. Split
on. So
you need to do intersect. Okay, you need
to do actually all these.
Okay, let's let's do them. Let's do
them. Put them into a function. So first
of all intersection
of beam state
versus
splitter position. Okay.
Then once you have the intersection you
do
you split them.
That's right. Is that right? Yes. Then
once you split them then you want to uh
Yeah. It's split already. So
yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. Then you delete duplicate.
Mhm. Mhm. Mhm.
That's it. That's our function.
Beautiful.
Very short.
And to solve the solution, to solve it,
all you have to do is
No, we don't need all these. Okay,
that's our code. So, let's remove the
comments. You see how beautiful it is.
Then to solve the solve the problem you
just do
fold the most general purpose powerful
functional programming loop.
So you fold you need to fold on uh uh
you need fold a function
and the initial state. What is the
initial state?
Initial state is the first row.
Yeah. So initial state is you want to
know the position of the first row. So
it's something like that.
position
first row and uh
position first row and you want to find
capital s
that returns the position then you
flatten it okay and what is uh then okay
so you don't want that so that
okay that's the initial state
then the list is just going to be this x
matrix.
Okay, that would be the final solution.
Uh, in fact, we can run this. It should
give us the answer.
I think so. Wait.
Well, this will return a final
state of the beams.
Then all you have to do is you count
them.
In fact, you don't need to duplicate
because this intersection does it. So I
don't think you even need that.
Okay, let's leave it. So
So all you have to do is just length.
I think that's the whole program.
Run it
may not work.
No. Okay. So, you got a issue. So,
what is the problem?
didn't say
actually it's it returns zero which is
incorrect.
Okay. Why does it return zero? Let's see
what is the thing it returns. It returns
a expression
there. See? So search. Oh yeah, of
course we forgot to define our function.
You need to say this function should be
f new state,
run it.
Okay, incorrect because we got a empty
list is not correct.
Now did we the new state the function
new state did we have the argument
like
order correct
just make sure Okay.
It's very simple function
in state split position state.
Be states.
Okay. Very close.
You don't need that width.
Okay.
That should work now. I don't know why
it's not working, but let me just make a
few changes. I don't want this
complicated thing. Let's remove the
first row thing. It's just a matrix.
Okay.
first rest.
Okay,
just do that. Simple. Okay, now I don't
want the first row. So,
so that will be
okay.
And uh this will be rest.
This will be first.
Okay, this will run. Yes, but it's still
incorrect.
Okay, it returns empty.
Now I don't know why
but
we will all know list. Okay, we we all
know did we did the fold? Okay, so here
is it become
you know it start with eight then it
just become zero empty. Did we get the
init initial state function should be
right.
I was just thinking
maybe we got the argument order
incorrect
function initial state list. Okay.
So,
so function first reads. Yeah. So
actually you can drop that
first rest.
Okay. I don't know where it is wrong. So
we need to
debug actually. So copy all
copy all let's go to wam language here
and let's
run it. Now this new state
is a function right?
Okay. Shift enter.
Interesting union.
Yeah. Something wrong here.
So beam state row
print we can like print can we print?
Yes.
do it.
So that's the input that is a function.
This is the first step.
Beam state is eight. row is all zero.
Oh, we have a algorithmic mistake.
Our logic is incorrect. So when they
don't collide, you have to keep them.
Not, you know, when they don't collide,
you have to Yeah. So if the union is
empty,
Yeah. If the union is empty, you just
keep the beam state. return the beam
state. If the union I mean intersection
if the intersection
is empty return the beam state. If they
are not empty then you split. Okay. We
we are
there. Okay. So this is split. Okay.
This this se this part is split.
Okay, let me show you. Easy to fix.
I did
Clash list.
Should it be collide or clash?
Properly it should be collide. But clash
is shorter. Let's just say collide
because to keep with the scientific
jargon. So collide list equals to that.
So now
now
if
length
at collide list equals to zero
then just return
X beam state. Otherwise
you need to
map
you need to split.
Yeah.
Mhm.
Perfect. Perfect.
Oh yeah. So this part is nested
expression. This part needs to go here.
Okay. Does that make sense? Perfect.
Now we can just fold. Let's run the
whole thing.
Okay. Invalid. Invalid.
Comma.
I don't want something invalid.
What? What? Invalid.
Oh, print. Okay. Run it.
Inval invalid syntax. In or before with
Oh,
in or or before width. So
why is this in back? Oh
wait, we got this.
What
we got? We got the parentheses I
think. God.
No, better. Okay, we got Yeah, we we got
put in.
Yeah. Now it's better, right?
Okay. Now, can you guys see?
Just run it.
Superb and beautiful
length at
run it
seven. Is that the right answer? So we
can trace you. You can see we can
actually trace out all the splitter
situation.
Split split split. They become larger.
Of course seven. Is that the right
answer at the end of code?
Let's see.
Scroll down. Scroll down. Scroll down.
21.
Uh to repair the teleporter, you first
need to understand the beam splitting
properties of the tachium manifold. In
this example, attacking beam is split a
total of 21 times.
You see, it only wants to count split.
It doesn't want to know what's the final
number of beams. It just want to know
how many times it been split. And also
it doesn't count about merge. So we
overengineered
problem. We went over we you know we are
trying to we actually that might be in
puzzle two.
So we might have already solved puzzle
two.
If you are here comment okay if you are
watching this find it interesting
comment.
So so well all they want to know is
split. So that's easy to fix.
Uh that's so easy to fix. So the uh
collide list.
So that's just the length of the collide
list. Okay, it's so trivial. Let's just
update a global variable.
Uh
total splits.
Okay. Total split equals to zero. global
variable. I wouldn't have coded that,
but this is just a hack to to make this
work. So,
so
collect list total list equals to
actually you can do equal plus
following the C++ convention. Wat
language actually support it.
But
yeah, I'm pretty sure because for
example
uh x = 5
x=
uh let's say two let's say two
and then x
it will be seven it
uh What
a two.
What?
X = 5 X=
+
uh what?
It should be 7 2. What is it? Was it
plus equal?
Yeah, plus equal. Oh god.
C hack
I'm not going to do that. Okay, let's do
the proper mathematical way. So plus uh
then plus you just plus the what does it
uh wait this part should be zero.
Okay, you need to do it here. So
plus
length at
collide list.
Is that right? So every time they
collide
they split.
Okay. Then then you just need to know
this number. Okay. Now let's put a comma
here so it doesn't print the function
every time.
Okay.
21, please.
No.
Oh, wait.
You got this. This this this should be
that. Yeah. Right.
21. Perfect.
Somehow I got angry,
you know, because I overengineered the
problem. Maybe I solved the day two.
Okay, so there it is. At least the
solution. Wait, let's put the 21 back.
Okay, so there is 21.
Go back here.
20 20 uh copy
21.
Fantastic.
Let's leave it. Leave it like Okay. So
now fantastic.
Uh this cut this belong here. Okay.
Yeah. Put it back syntax color
everything showing browser.
Fantastic problem analysis and the code
and the first time
the first code.
Yeah, we are we are trying to take it
apart to explain how it works each of
the the things we do. Then the second
part is just the final solution. Make
them work. Now
cut paste. Paste again. Pop it out. Now
let's work on our personal solution.
Search for txt
there.
Input. Copy. Close.
Back here. Select or paste. Just run it.
907.
Submit.
That's not the right answer. Your answer
is too low.
What?
This is annoying. So, we didn't solve
the problem.
What is that? 34.
Close.
This is the total number of beams.
That's what not what it want.
It wants to know the total split.
So why is that not correct? Length
collide beast.
Okay, this is becoming painful now. I
don't feel like
I don't feel good about this.
Oh,
when a beam split into two, that counts
as one split, right?
To make sure this
Okay. To repair the teleporter, you
first need to understand the beam
splitting properties of the tachang
manifold. In this example, a takian beam
is split a total of 21 times. Okay. So,
how does it count? So, let's see. That's
one,
two, three.
Oh, five six
7 8
10 11 12 13
17 18 19 20
21.
So every time they collide,
right? Whenever a beam collide with the
correct
splits.
So you want to count is the number of
collisions.
So why a is our code not correct? Beam
state of flen position.
Why is not um
Why is this line not correct? Collide at
least.
Oops.
Maybe is that
minute?
907.
It's 907.
Not correct.
Not the right answer.
Okay.
Wait. But uh if you run it on the test
input, it works
right.
You got 21.
You end up with seven beams. But there
were total of 21 splits. So is that
true? Seven beans. One, two, three,
four, five, six, 7, 8, nine.
Okay, that is even incorrect.
So there lies the problem.
So even on the toy inputs
you got the number of collision correct
the number of time they split. However
we also computed the final number of
beams we have seven which is not
correct. One two three four five six
seven eight nine.
So there is something wrong in our logic
something.
It's okay. So we need to just check.
So what what's with this collision list?
Okay, let's just check. So we got this
function. Fantastic function.
We local variable
it takes two arguments bin state and row
and uh fold new state
position first matrix.
So can you see the position
of the matrix the first
row you want to get X that would be
then you flatten it the rest of the
matrix
then you go through the rest of the
matrix.
Okay.
And uh
so that is the fold
that's the fold algorithm
but the key is this new state our
function new state
so it takes two arguments beam state and
row beam state is a list of indexes
okay
problem.
Okay. Then the important thing is you
find the collision list intersection of
the beam state which you flattened.
Important you flattened it. Then you
also uh flatten the position of the row
that contains one. Okay.
So,
so yeah. So, get all positions of the
one.
If they collide,
that means they have
identical indexes.
That's right.
If they collide, that means they have
have identical indexes.
So therefore, you do a intersection.
What is wrong with that?
You want to know some item that appear
in both.
That's right. Intersection.
I don't see anything wrong with that.
Intersection is a collide list.
and both of the input are already
flattened.
Okay.
So then the length of the collide list
first total splits
should be the answer of total number of
splits.
Okay. I don't see anything wrong with
it.
I cannot see anything wrong with it.
So, how long has this video been going?
two hours.
Uh but
how many people watching? Three
concurrent views. View viewers. Three.
Me plus you and me. Three. Three is a
crowd. Hi guys.
So we are suffering from code which is a
pleasure for computer scientists and
mathematicians.
This is a grand pleasure but however
I need a break really sitting here for
two hours.
Uh we need to debug
but so far I did not identify any
logical problems. Let's run this in wam
language and start a new one. Here's the
code. Look, look how beautiful they are
formatted. Let me demonstrate this
again. You see automatic formatting on
the fly
as you type.
Okay, let's run it. Shift enter.
21.
Okay, so I don't see anything wrong. And
also you see they they formatted with
the mathematical t type set union and
intersection
symbol.
Can you see that there? Fantastic and
beautiful. In fact we can put your
cursor here and control shiftn
to make it mathematically type set.
Oh okay. they also combined that
uh that text input
I mean into the you know backslash n so
anyway so but you can see the union here
so variables become green
and uh you can still do this
automatic formatting on the fly
fantastic
okay now let's copy this and see what we
get state function
Select
copy.
We'll get a formatted version. Okay.
Somewhat better.
Yeah. Somewhat better than now.
You see you can compare this section and
this section.
So
after formatting is a bit better. But
they but what one thing I don't like is
they added you see this intersection
that's that's the symbol that's called
named character for this
math symbol. So wam language doesn't
actually use unic code. It actually
encode any math symbol into its own
programming language.
So you can see
this part you see intersection.
I don't like that if you are doing uh
pure ask code because this this because
this backslash is very nasty in Unix
because they they function as escape
characters. So it will screw up emacs
par matching. You see it doesn't work
anymore.
Uh so I don't like this auto format so I
I like to keep it just just say
intersection the standard you see the
standard
you know function name bracket instead
of this
this um
infix notation with a special
mathematical symbol that
screws screws up your paran matching in
EMAC.
So,
okay, it's I don't want that.
But you can you can undo
then copy
and paste there. That's good. You see
intersection is unchanged. Now, this is
more beautiful. This is formatted more
beautiful than way I have it. So, delete
delete
indented.
Okay.
Yeah, the code is here, but it's wrong.
And uh so far, I haven't figured out
what's wrong. I need a break. Okay. So,
let me take a break.
Why don't we
uh you know the state of code advent of
code we know it's going to take a while
two three hours is common
you know people might think I don't want
to do it because if I do it it's going
to take me few hours looks bad actually
that's normal okay
so uh but
So, be right back.
Be right back. How come I don't have a
brief?
Okay, I lost viewer. Now it's just one
person.
Okay, so
Yeah, I'll be right back in 10 minutes.
Stop my video.
Okay,
I'm back.
So, two hours.
Now at each stage we can actually print
the whole matrix.
Can we not really?
Yeah.
Let's let's see what we get.
Okay. So now
means beam state is row is okay let's
Okay.
Okay, it's cleaning it up.
Okay, now let's
do not
print the function.
Run it.
So at the end there is one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven. But according to
the
end of code,
one 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9.
I got seven, but the result is not. Did
we did we miss the uh the input? Is the
input incorrect?
One uh one, two, three, four, five, six.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
Input should be correct.
Okay. But um
now if we remove that the result should
be same 721
right
because the last row is all empty
now. So where where did we go wrong?
I don't know.
Does any know
is there anyone here? No.
Oh god.
So,
so you need to print
the beam state. Okay. Why don't you just
print out the beam state?
I mean, print out the
diagram of the beam state.
with the current row.
So wait, each time it happens,
you see they they prolonged
they doubled the number of rows. Is that
right?
Oh, it's interspersed with empty rows
presumably to make the problem easier.
You see, they intersperse
the splitters with empty rows.
they intersperse it. So to make it more
efficient, you can remove all the empty
rows actually.
But now I'm tired. I don't want to work
on this
anymore.
The result of that is seven.
Okay.
So when beam states
intersperse with the row let's see
Oh, you need to also
once they collide,
you need to split them.
If they don't collide,
then just return the beam state. If they
collide,
you need to
Oh, yeah. You need to add I forgot.
Ah,
Intersection. Okay.
intersection of the beam state and the
collide list.
That's right, right?
Okay,
that's the Yeah, you forgot.
If they collide, you need to return
their new split position, but you also
need to return
the
beams that did not collide because they
keep going. So, uh, so let's make sure
this part is correct. Okay, so it's not
that. No, it's um,
so hold on a second. So,
so that should be
intersection
of
of the beam state and
this. Okay.
So, let's
there
does that make sense?
Yeah,
if they do not collide, just return the
beam state. Otherwise, you need to
return the original beam state
and the splitted result.
Run it.
It should be nine. No, it wait. God,
now this is wrong.
Okay. But we think I think we know the
problem.
No, not intersection. Okay.
Undo. Undo. Undo. Undo. Undo. Okay. Be
careful. You don't want up here.
Okay.
So if they collide, if they do not
collide,
just return the beam state as is. Now if
they did collide,
you need to
union not intersection.
Okay. Union of the beam state and this
map the split. Okay.
Fantastic and beautiful. I'm sure it is
correct now.
Isn't it? So it should be 921.
Oh 1522.
Now it's incorrect. Now it's like 15 22.
It should be 21. Okay. Almost. Al almost
15. Let's see. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9. Not
15. Okay. So it's not union.
Uh so what is it then?
So if they collide,
if they do not collide, return that.
Oh, you need to flatten it.
720 9:21
1522. No. God,
what's uh something here? Okay,
Union.
Okay.
3 4 let's say
3 4 5
it returns 345 right. So if it does it
does it remove duplicate? Yes I think
so.
Right.
And the order does not matter, right?
Pretty sure,
right? So
almost that it's just a little logic
problem, logistics.
So if they don't collide, just return
the beam state. They flow through. If
they do collide.
Oh, they if they do collide, you need to
split
those
that has collision. You need to split at
those collision points.
But
you also need to remove
the collision points. Okay.
Then you need to add back.
Yeah. So I know what to do here. So
So this line. Okay. If they collide,
you
you compute their split positions
and uh
minus. Okay. Complement
Okay. Complement is like a minus one set
minus the other. Okay. So,
so this is the split.
So,
complement minus the collide list.
Right. So you want that.
Wait, wait.
You want that?
That's the split beams
minus the collide list.
Then you want the union
of
Now, a little bit complicated.
here. A little bit complicated.
that okay I'm pretty sure so this is
incorrect
complement
of
the union
of beam state original beam beam state
plus the splitter
beams
minus the collision list
beam state first the split minus the
collision. So each collision point they
got removed the beam disappeared they
become two new positions. Right? So this
is correct.
So this will give us 921. So let's see.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine. Yeah, these do it.
Correct.
Beautiful.
Two hours done.
Okay, now put it back carefully.
syntax correct show in browser.
So what what what is is we compute it.
So
this part we remove
huge input list. Okay.
So layer 921. Okay. Now go to next. Now
delete that part. Now
refresh. Good. Good.
Okay. Now cut. Paste. Paste one more
time. Copy it out. Go back to the page.
Search for the input.
Copy the input. Close.
Go to the code. Select the this input
list.
Okay, now
run it.
So 87
and uh
and uh 1516. So total split is 1516. Is
that correct?
Submit.
That's the right answer. Finally.
Jesus. Put it back. Syntax color
everything.
Now personal input.
Okay. So that concludes today's talk
show. Uh took two hours and 30 minutes
but we finished.
So the problem we took so long is
because we there's a logic issue in our
algorithm
in our computation of the final beam
positions because we forgot to
remove
the beam position when it became split
and also we forgot
to remain. So let's let's write down why
we spend so long to conclude this video.
Two
logical errors in our AR rhythm.
One, we forgot to keep the beams
that did not collide.
Two,
we uh
remove the beam
that did collide.
Seems these two sentences contradictory.
Yeah, this you know now there's a
logical issue of interpretation of this
sentence.
These two sentence seems contradictory
to each other. One and two. We forgot to
keep. One is keep, one is remove. One is
keep the beams that did not collide.
Collide means run into a splitter. Okay.
And we forgot to remove the beams that
did collide. So
it makes sense to this problem. But for
someone who did not read the problem,
who let's say a alien from Mars, they
just look at these two sentences. Does
that make sense? Keep the beams.
So either they collided or not collide.
So when they did not collide,
keep
right. That makes sense. When when they
did not collide, you keep them. When
they did collide, you need to remove
them. Makes sense. Even when you are an
alien who just read these two sentences
without the problem, without the
context, still makes sense.
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching. Bye, guys.
We got three people watching.
Okay. Take a long time. Take a long
time. So, no request for donation today
because this is not really good.
Almost three hours to solve this thing.
Oh god. Okay. But it's done. Bye.
And we can run this in wra language of
course. Let's run it. Let's uh let's run
it. Copy.
Select or paste.
Shift enter.
9 and 21. That's right.