I'm alive. Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Saw Talk
Show.
And today is what day it is today? Let's
see.
Uh
insert date stamp. Today is 2021,
March 13th. And today we are going to
talk about
mostly I plan to do JavaScript.
I plan to do JavaScript and any
questions you have. And maybe I'll do
Mathematica demo. Okay, Mathematica
coding, the fantastic Wolfram language,
okay?
So, if you have questions, post it there
now, okay? I'm going to read the
questions. And let's go to the talk show
page. And first of all, let me show you
what is this. Okay, not that one.
Uh what is this page? Saw Talk Show,
right?
Okay, I need to go to
the top sections. Okay, on the pink
window is all my Emacs commands. You can
see
uh
Saw Talk Show index.
What? Okay.
So, today's talk show, this page show in
browser. There it is. Uh let me let me
tell you the background
the image, okay? The background image is
a fantastic image. Go to Saw the
keyboard website. But before wait, let
me check if I'm alive. Concurrent users.
Uh it drops. Every time when I start, it
drops.
So, it was 15. So, the DeepMind AI got
90% of 3D shape of a protein, right? How
long until Google became a literal god?
Okay, that's that's a broad question.
How powerful Basically, about how
powerful is Google
or AI of Google is going to be or in
general how powerful is AI going is
going to be. Uh well, you know, nobody
knows actually. You you ask anyone,
including AI experts, they
their predictions are questionable.
Yeah, because it's this this is about
the future, so uh nobody can really say.
But about AI,
uh yeah, the the how powerful is AI
going to become, that nobody really
knows. You know, it's really hard to
say. In 5 years, you know, first of all,
let's say let's give a time frame. Let's
say in 5 years or in 10 years. Let's say
in 10 years, okay? In 10 years, how
you know, what what what is going to
become of AI, you know, how powerful is
going is it going to be in 10 years?
Artificial intelligence, you know, we
have self-driving cars now.
Where and the artificial intelligence
combined with robotics and and of
course, we have quantum computing on the
rise.
Anyway, let let's limit to AI. So, AI
right now,
you know, it can beat closed games such
as Go or chess. You know, Go, for
example, a few years ago Google did it.
Um
and uh now,
you know, Google is of course, it's
already using AI on lots of things, on
filtering your messages, on finding uh
who who are your friends, on predicting
your daily life next year. Uh it
actually knows
you better than you do.
So, but but basically, what will happen
in 10 years? It's hard to say, actually.
I mean, some questions, for example,
will it change society in some major
way? Uh you know, will it change our you
know, will it change the social
structure, you know, turning it into
something completely something else.
Yeah, it's uh it's hard to say. Yeah, uh
I don't know. I don't know. Nobody
knows.
So, today's background picture is this
uh okay, so here's my keyboard blog. You
can see my fantastic keyboard blog. In
fact, they are I'm busy with it. You
know, there are so many entries new
entry for example
let me just show you the pictures. Okay,
anyway, this text is important.
Keyboard layout design versus input
system design.
Uh it's
yeah, you know, it's uh one of my
opinion.
Uh this this article this this short,
you know, this is uh
this is spontaneous reply from
Xah Discord.
Spontaneous reply on Discord. Uh because
people are comparing uh William Gooch
William Gooch
William Gooch the
uh
let me show you
William Gooch's keyboard.
Okay, where is it?
There it is. That's his
uh
oh her keyboard.
So, she
So, she's got this pinky keyboard. So,
he is saying
you know, he you know, he you know, we
are looking into various uh keyboard
letter layouts, you know, for Actually,
that's what I'm going to do today.
Keyboard layout, okay? So, you can see
this is uh So, this is QWERTY and heat
map uh Borak Colemak Colemak DH
um
Okay, I need to uh put on my
patch on
uh for prevention of I have a little bit
cross-eyed. So, Colemak Colemak DH
Workman asset. So, actually today my
plan is to write a JavaScript. There is
some changes I need to do.
So, you know, we are studying keyboard
layouts, you know, which one is better.
In fact, there are quite a few more
uh
than than what I mentioned here in my
article.
Uh so, you know, uh by the way, this is
a new one, Engram layout. This actually
This one just came out this month. And
this one is based on scientific study of
ergonomics. So, of all keyboard layouts,
you know, typically these all these
layouts are created by one single nerd.
You know, one single single nerd write a
program, compare the metrics, you know,
define you know, find the metric define,
then create a layout. But, this one is
actually more scientific. This one
uh he focused on he he, you know, he it
becomes a project uh
You know, I don't know much about this
one yet, but I feel that this one if you
really want to get the extra mile out of
a keyboard layout, which is in
unpractical, by the way. You know,
QWERTY uh uh
Dvorak is good enough. You know, if you
like Colemak Colemak, you know, you can
go Colemak or Workman.
But,
but if you really, really, really want
to say, you know, what's the best best
layout that, you know, 1 0.1
extra point better than all the others,
I feel that this would be the one. This
is Engram layout. Uh I I just found out,
you know, he sent me actually he sent me
sent me a email today
uh announcing his layout. You know, he
wants me to put on me on on my website.
But, anyway, so so this one is a new
layout. So, anyway, I was saying we are
all studying layouts, you know, nerds
you guys nerds studying all the
different layouts, and you want to know
which one is the better. You know,
I talked about this many times.
You know, after Dvorak, you know, then
it becomes rather impractical question
because doesn't matter how better it is
than Dvorak, that little extra yard, you
know, that extra mile, that betterment
you are going to na- never going to uh
realize it in your life if you use
Dvorak. You know, if you use something
better than Dvorak,
um
you know, it's not practical
issue. If you want really want to go one
step beyond keyboard letter layout,
I've talked about this for hours and you
know, several videos I talked about this
topic. If you really want to go beyond
the keyboard letter layout, then you
should
Fi- First of all, you should uh use the
ergonomic keyboard, okay?
You should uh go get a ergonomic
keyboard because that has a far more
impact, far major impact than what uh
letter layout you use. So, this is the
first stop. Get a ergonomic keyboard
with mechanical keys, okay? You you want
mecha- mechanical keys. That's the first
stop. Then, the sec- the second stop
Uh you know, in fact, you can forget
about Dvorak uh or you know, or Colemak.
Th- These are actually not the first or
second uh importance. So, first of all,
get a physical ergonomic ergonomic
well-designed ergonomic keyboard like uh
keyboard, physical keyboard. That's the
most important for ergonomic reasons,
for your hand health, and also for
efficiency reasons so that
so that it's not just healthy. I mean,
they are two separate They're a little
bit separate issues but related. One is
ergonomic hand health. The other one is
efficiency, how fast uh or how uh how
fast you can operate things. They are
kind of they are related because
but they are distinct. For For example,
one example is that function keys, F1,
F2. I talked about this in many of my
videos. You know, function keys. Many
keyboard nerds, they don't like, you
know, they don't want function keys.
They think oh, it's not important. For
example, this ErgoDox,
this Redox, you know, they don't have
function keys. Uh you know, and many of
the others don't have function keys. For
example, Corne Cherry.
So, what they do, they they they press
the control key modifiers and and they
think that's uh
uh they think that's efficient the fast,
okay, fast. On the other hand, if you
have a standard PC keyboard, you can use
the function keys, but you have to move
your hand.
So, for efficiency reasons, you know, we
we are you know, if you want to talk
about ergonomics of efficiency, you
become you you need to become very very
very specific. Like exactly what's your
question. So, right now, let's suppose
um
you don't really type that much, okay?
Let's say you type conti- you know, all
your typing on average for a day over a
year is let's say
So, your daily typing can be can be
typed in actually 20 minutes. Actually,
you don't type much, okay? For some
people, on average, their daily typing
is equivalent to continuous typing for 1
hour. I did that. I thought I typed a
lot, but actually, if you count your you
log your keystrokes and measure it and
and let's say you type only 40 words per
minute, then you'll find out how many
um
if you type continuously for each day,
how much you actually type. For me,
that's just actually 1 hour, no more
than 1 hour. So, I was, you know, at at
that period, I was typing a lot a lot.
For a typical programmer, you know,
let's say for a typical programmer you
work at Google or whatever Facebook, you
if you type continuously, your whole
day's typing can be done in in 5
minutes, in 10 minutes, okay? So, you
don't you don't type much, you know.
So, these are some of the points, you
know, I have a lot of articles, just
read my website. These are some of the
misunderstanding important point. So,
first of all, you need to know just how
much you type, you know, you have
different classes, small men pop
programmer,
uh author, blogger who write, you know,
who writes a novel or novelist, then at
the real extreme is
um
data entry clerk where you go to work,
then you start typing continuously until
you
go to lunch, then you come back, you
type continuously, you know, data entry
clerk.
So, that's the one extreme, on the other
extreme, you know, mom and pop, you
don't use a computer much, maybe answer
email two every day. So, you have to
know so so we have to focus on specific
how much you actually type. Let's say
programmers. So, once if you are a
programmer,
you know, okay, I'm digressing into
several levels hierarchy. So, anyway,
most important is to get a physical uh
keyboard. That's the most important
thing.
Then,
okay, whatever what I was going to say,
I was talking about some points.
Uh
why mechanical keys? I hate the sound.
You know, you can get red silent red,
okay? I know you don't read much. You
are not in a mechanical keyboard
community.
You you want mechanical keyboard. Okay,
I'm not going to talk about it today
because I want to do JavaScript today.
So, but anyway, so you want mechanical
keyboard.
Uh I mean
okay, so yeah, they are loud. So, you
want to get the silent red
version. There's a silent red uh
mechanical switch. I have article on
that. Just click on
uh
design
key switches. Also, this article
introduces you all to all kind of key
switches. But even with silent red, you
you know, it's still louder than rubber
dome.
So, anyway,
uh let me go back to focus on So, yeah.
So, I was talking about ergonomic and
health versus efficiency. I'm I was
talking about they are distinct. They
are related, but actually in details,
they are distinct separate issues. And
one of the example
to illustrate why they are distinct is
that for some people, you uh like I I
mentioned, uh they like, you know, they
like this uh
you know, keyboard without function
keys. On the other hand, you have a
standard PC keyboard with function keys.
Now,
let's say if you press control C for
copy. So, on this keyboard, 30% or 40 40
keys keyboard, you have to, you know,
control your your thumb control and C.
So, that's pretty efficient. Uh but
on the other hand, you can set, you
know, F1, the function key to do uh
copy. So, you just press one key. So,
which one is faster? Okay.
Which one is faster? Now, obviously,
with the modifier, if if you are young,
the modifier, you know, so is faster
because you don't have to move, you
know, move your hand all the way. But
which one is healthier? The function
keys will be healthier long term. So, we
So, getting back to, you know,
So, we when we talk about you know, when
you dive into the science of ergonomic
or keyboard design or efficiency, you
have to be very specific. So, first of
all, ask yourself just what how how you
type. Is it you are you like data entry
clerk? You type continuously for 2 hours
a day? Or are you like a typical
programmer where you can type your whole
day's typing uh in 10 minutes if you
just type continuously. So, this is very
different. So, if you are the programmer
class, you know, you don't type actually
that much, then you know, this 30% is it
works fine, you know, and it's fast, you
know, you don't have to move your hand
all the way to function keys. On the
other hand, if you really type a lot, if
you are novelist, you know, you write
blog or all the time several blogs a
day,
then you want a keyboard with function
keys. So, so you know, so we are getting
into details. So, so one is fast, okay?
On the other hand, the other one is
healthier.
Yeah, so that's why I'm saying they are
related but distinct concept, ergonomic
versus efficiency. So, so
so in general, if you have hand pain or
if you are programmer, you know, you use
keyboard a lot, you want to
um first of all, get a mechanical uh
ergonomic keyboard.
Uh first of all, get a get a mechanical
keyboard, okay? That's the most most
important.
Now, whether you want ergonomic ones,
you know, ergonomic ones usually are um
you know, split, you know,
that depends on whether you touch type,
you know, that's another
complexity, you know, that's another
detail. You know, most people don't
touch type and they don't want to learn
it.
I'm talking about lots of you guys, but
they
you know, so if you don't touch type,
then these these split keyboards are not
much uh
uh
uh is not a good fit for you. So,
you can do fine, you know, you can do
fine with the uh you know, the
normal flat keyboards. So, first of all,
so let me get back to uh the original
topic. The most important thing is to
get a physical
mechanical keyboard with mechanical
keys.
You can pick ergonomic ones or you can
pick these flat ones. That's the most
important thing.
After that, the second most important
thing is that you want to get into the
shortcut
key binding.
You want to consider key binding like
what software do you use? Are you a
programmer? Are you using Emacs? You
know, so I mean even if you
even if you are not using the Emacs or
VI, if you use use VS code, Microsoft VS
code or XCode from Mac, you still need
to have a lot key combinations, compile,
debug, you know, things like that.
Also, if you are a web dev,
a JavaScript coder, then you have lots
of um
uh
you know, JavaScript coder, you you also
have lots of shortcuts you have to do.
On the on the or maybe you are a
professional photo editor, you know,
media professions. You edit Photoshop,
you edit videos. In in fact, today tons
of YouTubers, they have to
edit videos every day using Adobe
Premiere or whatever, you know, I
you know, I never edited video. So,
then you then or if you are a gamer, you
know, so what I'm saying is that lots of
these applications,
uh programming or image editing,
Photoshop, [ __ ] or uh video editing, or
3D modeling, you know, that's also a
very popular
job, you know, media profession. Or you
know, so you many of these applications,
they have, you know, 100 shortcuts and
at least 50 of them are used every day,
you know, in Photoshop, you have to
switch tools and so on. So, when you
So, so these are about keyboard
shortcuts. Now keyboard shortcuts is
also there's a lot to study because you
want you want the shortcut that's more
efficient. So keyboard shortcuts In fact
I've I've I've done statistics. I'm not
going to show you them now. You know
search for ergonomics uh
search for Xah Lee Emacs command
frequency. So I've done studies on that.
So basically
for programmers in fact most of your
keystrokes is actually uh keyboard
shortcuts, okay? It's not
data entry. It's not typing. It's
actually most of your keystrokes
is actually
from keyboard shortcuts, okay? For
programmer even for programmer.
Especially you know
unless you are writing program by
yourself and always writing program
never maintain it.
Especially if you are maintaining a
program or need to do some bug fix then
most of your keystrokes are actually
shortcuts. So
So that is why shortcuts layout, you
know, shortcut efficiency, you know,
there are so many to dive into. This is
the more important. This is more
important than you know, the Dvorak
versus Qwerty versus Colemak, okay?
So first of all get a mechanical
keyboard. Uh preferably ergonomic one.
Secondly, you want to look into uh the
ergonomics of uh the ergonomics of key
bindings. Or in other words, input
systems. You know
and again, you know, that's a lot to
study. For example, do you type a lot of
math? Do you type LaTeX? Do you are you
a engineer or scientist have to type
formulas a lot? Or you work work with
Mathematica? Or um you know, you have to
type or maybe you enjoy emoji. You are
Twitter or Facebook using emoji all the
time. So emoji, how do you enter them?
Again shortcuts.
So you have to So there are many way
there there are then there's input
systems, you know, for typing Japanese,
for typing Chinese.
Um
You know, so they are all related. And
there are dead keys, there are old graph
keys, you know. So, you want to
study keyboard shortcut cut design. But
but in summary, okay, I'll just give you
one advice about keyboard shortcuts.
Basically, if you are using Emacs, do
not ever use the default key
Emacs key binding. Use software keys or
use
VI
Yeah, VI Vim. And also, if you if you
use VI, don't use the escape key. You
know, use
I'm not going to go into detail, but
that's what you want to do, okay? So, or
So, if you are not But if you are not
using Emacs or VI, what do you do if you
are programmer about shortcuts? Well,
you buy a programmable keypad, okay?
So, such as this page. You You get a
programmable keypad. So, each key on
this keypad, for example, let me show
you mine.
Okay, so actually I rambled for like how
long
all about keyboards. I meant to do
JavaScript today. 22 minutes already.
[ __ ]
And I haven't get to today's
background image.
Uh
so, you look at I showed this a thousand
times, okay? So, this is this is
ultimate hacking keyboard. Ultimate
hacking keyboard. That's my key macro
pad, okay? One all everything is one
single press. You see? This is switch
last window.
This is switch to
last window and previous tab.
Next tab.
Close tab. Undo close.
Reload, you see? All single key press.
Uh okay, so what am I
Okay, I actually I spent 20
3 minutes talking about keyboards.
That's
a huge digression.
Okay, okay, let me continue then. So,
first of all, get a mechanical keyboard.
Sec- second, uh
uh second,
buy a buy a programmable keypad, okay?
Or if you are using Emacs or Vim, use
Safely Keys. Or for Vim, you use, you
know, don't press the escape key. You
know, there are several issues you have
to study.
So, that's the two the most important
thing for efficiency and hand health,
ergonomics. Mechanical keyboard and
shortcuts, you know, uh
programmable keypad, okay? That solves
the shortcut problem. You don't have to
control shift alt,
you know, that's one of the most um
cause of repetitive strain injury,
shortcuts, keyboard shortcuts. And never
And also
remember never use a laptop keyboards.
Never. You know, maybe for 1 minute, you
know,
don't use laptop keyboards. Bec-
uh I talked about this many times. It's
a laptop keyboard in 2005 that
uh that gave me RSI in the the first
RSI.
So, let's go back to my uh talk show
page. I mean, let's go back to keyboard.
I was going to show you
um So, I actually I have several things
new here today. I mean, in the past few
days. Uh I was going to show you this
photo, okay? So, this is actually my
keyboard. Actually, now I have a little
collection. Now,
this is truly ergonomic.
This is X Bow. This is fantastic, okay?
I highly recommend it.
This is Google. This is Google Plex,
only 30 keys or something.
Uh and this is Microsoft Sculpt. This is
Kinesis. This is the best. This is
in terms of hand health comfort, this is
the best, okay? And and this is
fantastic. This is going to I haven't
set it up yet. I talked about it
uh about three vi- three videos ago.
This is uh fantastic. It It's got the
thumb pad innovation. Uh the name of
this one is Signum. Signum keyboard.
Okay, so
so that's the background, okay? And uh
one giant digression. So, what about
this article? This article is about so
so we I was I was talking about, you
know, we
we nerds, you know, lots of us, you
know, in my circle who follows me us,
you know, looking at the keyboard letter
layout, okay? This is
insignificant.
All things considered for efficiency of
input and also for hand health ergonomic
of input, this is the
almost the least important thing.
So, next time you hear people say, "Oh,
what is Dvorak better than Colemak? Or
is it Or should you use programmer's
Dvorak? You know, you should use Colemak
DH, you know,
uh minor variation. Or should you use
Workman?"
You know, they they
you know, they they they don't know.
They they don't know what what's going
They you know, they are nerds. They
don't see the big picture. They don't
know what's actually more important. But
they are nerds because, know, this thing
is a ongoing thing for 30 years. So,
they just focus on oh, which which one
is more
efficient.
But, it you know, it's the least
important thing. So, today
today there's a a new one Engram lay-
layout, okay?
Which I think is pretty good good.
Okay, that's about keyboard layouts. Uh
What about Oh, $5. Thank you uh Sid
Addy.
Sid Addy, thank you very much. Do you
have a question?
Thank you.
Uh so,
what do we do next?
Okay, so let me finish one more one last
thing. I was talking about keyboards,
right? I was talking about yeah, we we
nuts are, you know, obsessed about which
letter layout is important, not
important, okay?
Get a mechanical keyboard and study
shortcut layout. Buy a programmable
keypad, okay? That's the That's the
thing.
I mean, I'm just giving you these
these these are the
summary. I mean, these are the two
sentence summary of my
30 years study on input systems on
keyboard layout, letter layout, and
keyboard keyboard firmware, okay? That
That is my 30 years experience I'm
giving you in two sentences. One, buy a
mechanical keyboard, preferably
ergonomic ones.
Two,
uh look into the issues about shortcut
layout, okay? And and and as a solution,
buy a keypad, programmable keypad, okay?
Okay, then after that, then you might
consider layout, okay? Dvorak, you know,
first of all, QWERTY is pretty bad. You
know, it's a good thing you don't use
QWERTY, okay? Switch to Dvorak or
Colemak or some other.
But, between
once you, you know, use Dvorak or or any
others, they are you know, they they
they doesn't differ that much, you know,
you don't get much benefit uh out of it.
Okay, so the first 30 minutes is about
keyboard layout. Yeah, okay,
I again, let me I haven't talked about
my what this article is about. Keyboard
layout design versus input system
design. So,
when we are talking about keyboard
layouts, okay? So, we nerds are talking
about all these keyboard layouts, you
know, which one is better? Oh, by what
metric are you using? What kind of, you
know, how do you measure which one, you
know, is is H better or is it G better?
Or should you avoid lateral finger
movements? Or should you, you know, how
it should be? You know, all lots of
discussions and debates.
So, in this context context, okay? So,
that still makes sense, okay? Among all
these letter layout, although in general
they are not important, but still it
makes some sense to say which one is
actually, you know, scientifically maybe
slightly better than the other, more
efficient.
So, in this context context, then some
people mention, you know, today we have
keyboard firmware, QMK, okay?
Uh how do I summarize this?
Uh
well, basically,
normally normally when we talk about
letter layout, we
assume
that our keyboard is restrained to the
PC keyboard layout. That is, you know,
you look at all these different layout,
they are um
you know, they are physical arrangement
is all the same, you know, you got big
space bar, then you got, you know, three
four rows, then you got, you know, they
are slightly slanted, you know,
staggered, so called staggered,
vertically staggered, you know.
So, we we typically assume all the
people, all the nerds, when they study
this they all assume that the physical
layout is fixed, okay?
Uh but however, gradually because today
that you you have a lot um
do-it-yourself keyboards, for example,
today you have a lot um
you know, do-it-yourself keyboards,
which has very different physical
layouts.
And also, the software, the firmware
used to control these keyboard, they
have a lots of programmability features.
For example, you press one key, you can
program it to
to actually send out control C, then
control B, then alt, then F4 or
something, you know.
And and that
Okay, besides that, you can also make
For example, if you press this key and
release it, then you'll just enter T,
for example. But if you hold press this
key and don't release it and press
another key, and that key becomes a
modifier, you know. So, you know, it
becomes control something. So,
so this this feature, this this ability
is part of the firmware, you know, part
of this
uh you know, this uh keyboard firmware.
For example, there's QMK,
uh which is open source, the most
popular QMK. I've articles on that.
There's also uh for example, there's
also
Let me show you a few, okay? So,
keyboard.io you also has a open source
uh keyboard firmware, and uh it's in
fact it's possibly more is
I I'll just say it's more capable, okay?
It's more capable. It's a better
keyboard firmware, and also open source,
and it's better than QMK, okay? Why am I
saying this? Because lots of these you
you guys nerds, idiots, you know, open
source fanatics, they will say, "Oh,
QMK, why are not you why are you not
using QMK?" You know, QMK QMK ass.
This keyboard.io firmware, look up, you
know, the they are firmware is called
Kaleidoscope, okay?
It's open source and it's more powerful
and it's you know, more powerful and
more quality program than the QMK [ __ ]
okay? Keyboard.io. And also Kinesis
keyboard layout, Kinesis.
Uh where is it?
Uh
Kinesis, this the keyboard I'm using,
the
the the firmware is also open source on
GitHub, okay? Just look for it. And it's
um
I you know, I can't say it's more
powerful or more you know, than QMK, but
it's it's
it's you know, it's up there, okay? It's
for example, I don't know if QMK
supports
on the fly keyboard programming. On the
fly programming means you don't have to
launch a driver to
to program your keys. You just press
key, you know, for example, on my
Kinesis, I just hold down the
Yeah, whether I should show you or not.
You know, I just hold down a key, then I
press another key and then start
programming. So, I can press this key
and press another combination, then
then press the key again, that stops it.
So, after that, when I press the key, it
will just send whatever key sequence I
want. So, without
needing to launch a software or or even
download software. So, it's all you
know, it's all
building in the firmware, okay?
This this this is called on the fly
programming or sometimes driverless
driverless programmable keyboard, okay?
Now, that feature is part of Kinesis
open source. Now, I don't know I I don't
know if that feature is on in QMK, maybe
it is. And another problem with QMK is
that it's very tedious, you know, and
it's
you have to spend hours to study at QMK.
I have article on that somewhere here.
Uh software. Yeah, QMK, you know, so I
have a QMK tutorial.
And it's get it gets complex, okay? You
have to spend, you know, you you need to
be a nerd.
Uh besides that, there's more, okay? Not
not just
not just Keyboard.io Colido software and
not just Kinesis. There's more. There is
uh
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard, okay? Let's
look at this one.
Uh where is it? Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard.
That's what that this one I'm using now,
okay? I showed you a moment ago. This
the software for Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard is also open source. It's on
GitHub. It the name of that is Agent,
okay? You
you
UHK Agent, okay? Open source and
powerful. It's the most I can show you
right now, okay? So
UHK, okay? That's the
This is the software for Ultimate
Hacking Keyboard, okay? Now I can show
you
You see it's all one single key press,
you know, one single key press.
Uh wait, I want to switch to
last app.
Do I still have the key? Yeah.
Uh where is it? Okay.
Okay.
All one single key press. You know,
control alt tab, nothing. So this one,
one single key press to max maximize
window. One key press to move
uh restore.
Uh so this one, for example, this is the
uh keyboard macro I'm using. So you can
see
close window, close tab, previous tab,
next tab, copy URL of the current
window, you know, the
then this is the last window, this is
select all, copy, paste, cut.
This is a new tab.
This is reopen last closed, this is
refresh. This is
a keypad enter. When I use Mathematica
to evaluate, you know, I you need that.
Uh then you know
So, that's my
that's the ultimate hacking keyboard.
So, now I want to close the window.
Uh control W doesn't work. You need to
do alt F4. So, but I don't I don't use
you see one single key press.
You see.
Uh so, that's ultimate hacking keyboard
also open open source. So, you know, the
nerds, you know, the open source [ __ ]
phonetics they every day they dribble.
QMK QMK QMK QMK my ass.
You know, QMK is not bad, but every time
you know, when you when you get you
know, like
William.
You know, you it's great, you know, if
it's great if you are a nerd like a
Linux user, you know, you spend you
know, days to study you know, yeah, it's
great. QMK is fantastic fantastic.
But don't tell me don't tell people that
you know, don't
you know
it becomes bad when you become a fanatic
like most of the QMK open source fanatic
are they know, they tell other people
QMK QMK.
But in fact, they don't know because
they're obsession they fanaticism they
don't know that there are actually
better things than QMK and
also open source. That's the thing.
Uh okay, so that's that's
Okay, so today's whole talk is about
keyboard layout which I I
a thousand times already. It's kind of a
giant digression.
Uh okay, so thank you Sid Edi. Big
loops, what keyboard layout do you use
on your phone? Uh
on my phone it's just QWERTY. Uh yeah.
I don't use my you know, cell phone
much.
Uh okay, let me read the question. So,
today is going to be keyboard then.
22 concurrent viewers, okay, fantastic.
So, Thomas Olson says that uh yeah, so
about AI, the future of AI, nobody
knows. Nobody knows what will happen in
10 years. What to what degree AI, you
know, the power of AI will become. You
know,
this is an interesting topic, so let me
talk about that a bit more.
So, the people who are into AI very
much, you know, nerds
typically, and they have a vision. They
have a vision.
You know, that's a utopia. You know, and
there's a name for that vision. It's
called singularity. Okay, singularity.
That in short, that is when when AI
becomes
uh that you know, there's no exact
definition. When when does that happen?
But, singularity basically means you
know, one of several things. One,
when AI obtains consciousness to some
level. This is probably the highest
level. When AI have consciousness, okay,
self-aware. You know, you know, nobody
can actually define what consciousness
means. You know, if you ask the AI, you
know, nobody knows. AI experts, nobody
can
define it, but
but you you you but you kind of
understand what that means, you know?
So, when when AI got consciousness,
basically they become a sentient being,
you know? They become a
you know, AI animal.
So, they can think for themselves. Or,
then there's the possibility they'll
extinguish humanity. You know, the AI
will take over as as as shown in a lot
of science fictions. So, that's one
you know, one way you can say when we
have singularity, when AI has
consciousness.
Uh or when AI power is beyond humans
brain, you know,
like right now you you know, Google is
using lots of the AI technology. One of
them is a neural
um neural networks, which is kind of
modeled on humans brain. So, I mean,
basically so what
uh people are thinking is that, you
know, computer are becoming faster and
faster and now we have more and more
cores, you know,
the AMD Threadripper,
which Emily has, you know, 20 200 core
what 96 cores.
And that's not even you know, you can
buy today for a thousand or two thousand
dollars, you know, this you know,
best gaming machine you spend three
thousand dollars. Anyway, so
so singularity, another way to say
singularity is when when the number of
transistors or something on the chip is
more than human brain.
So,
so so AI becomes so so you know, greatly
powerful, but um
or another way to say singu- yeah,
singu- basically that's what singularity
means when machines, you know, computers
usually when they becomes more powerful
than human human brain, they will uh
yeah.
So, you know, people people in AI
community are you know, debating or
talking about when will that happen or
um you know,
nobody knows. Nobody actually can say.
And let me give you let me give you few
rants of my own about these, you know,
AI topics or common topics among AI. One
of them is ethics, you know, the ethics
about AI, which is a [ __ ] mother [ __ ]
[ __ ] You know, a lot of people,
including many of many of you guys, you
know,
beginning even 30 years ago in science
fiction. I know a lot a lot of you read
science fiction. You know, so in science
fiction, you know, they they think
ahead, you know, they think ahead. So,
one day AI is going to be very powerful.
They are they're going to be sentient.
So, we should you know, we should think
about ethics, you know, the ethics of
AI, you know, what um
You know, for example, Asimov, you know,
there's a
well-known
science fiction writer uh whose name is
Isaac Asimov, right?
Am I still going Am I live?
Okay, I So, post questions or a comment.
Just comment whatever. I'll get to that,
you know, answer ask me or just say.
I'd like to see that, okay? So, there's
a science fiction writer, very famous,
Asimov something, Isaac Asimov, who
created this um very popular something
called AI Creed or AI something, ethics
of AI.
This nerd, [ __ ] I despise them.
You know, because I don't think, you
know, the almost always you this hacker
type, you know, this this this type of
people I talked a lot a lot, you know,
Unix philosophy, Unix people, Linux
people, this kind of they are tends to
be underground, you know, Emacs users,
VI users.
I'm trying to find a term, you know, he
came up with. Okay, so here is a guy,
Isaac Asimov.
Uh he's a American writer and professor
biochemistry science fiction and popular
science as well, okay.
So, artificial intelligence let's let's
search for wait.
He's known for must be here. Occupation
genre subject popular science history
and golden fiction whatever
field of study.
A
Arthur
uh
search for
artificial intelligence
uh
So, does anyone know what what is the
phrase he used? You know, he has he came
up with a phrase about the ethics of
uh
uh AI.
What? Nobody?
Uh where is my OBS? Okay, I'm still
going 45 minutes.
Three laws of robotic. Thank you,
Camille. Thank you. Good morning to uh
United Kingdom.
Exactly, three laws of robotic. This
[ __ ] these nerds.
Why? Why do I say that? Because I
you know, I just you know, the the the
way I look at things the way that my
thinking is just usually
uh the hackers, you know, contrary to
the hackers. You know, when you know,
these three laws of robotic. This is one
of the thing just like Unix philosophy.
You know, my people in my circle or who
I follow or who follows me, you know,
tends to mention this all the time. Like
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah. Oh,
Three Laws of Robotics. They're just
[ __ ] idiots.
You know, okay, so so when when they
mention this and I look at this, oh,
Three Laws, you know, you know, to me
this is not a good
You know, it's like it's not this is not
a thing I would think. You and I don't
think it's, you know, it's not the way
to go. You know, yeah, I'm also
concerned about, you know, the
you know, I'm also concerned about
Let me put it my way, okay, not the way
typical
uh Western people, you know, typical
Western people will say they are
concerned about ethics, ethics of
robotics, you know. That's not the word
I want to use. I'm concerned about the
possibility, the the the possibility or
non-possibility of the possibility of
coexistence or I don't even I don't want
to use the word coexistence of humans
and machines, okay? You know, I wouldn't
even say coexistence but, you know,
So, I mean, the way how you use words,
diction or phrases reflect your kind of
you know
your view of the world. So, so these
three laws of robotics, that that's a
phrase I despise. What the [ __ ] What
What the [ __ ] law? You know, Western
people, yeah.
I can tell why why they like this kind
of phrase thinking because law law, you
know, to the Western people kind of, you
know, who grew up in Western society,
you know,
most of you guys, white people in short.
You know, they they think because of
law, you know, they they this is the
word this is the word fundamental in
Western
uh philosophy, Western society but not
in Asia, okay? So, to the Western
people, law oh, yeah, good yes. You
know, they they they get excited. So,
they have this term, three laws of
robotic, [ __ ] the law. What the [ __ ]
So, this this is not
So, I I kind of I when I see this and I
I read about it's aversive. I find it
aversive. That's That's not how you do
things, okay? So, I I think about the
possibility, you know, one day AI will
be very powerful and we
there there might be a problem. What if
AI become conscious and they you know,
they take over?
Uh things like that. So,
so
but I wouldn't say, you know, I wouldn't
put, you know,
come up with
ethics or law.
That's not, you know, this just uh
it's hard to explain, okay? So, this is
not the way I I would go.
But, anyway, so all the nerds are you
know, talking mentioned this all the
time. Okay, three laws of robotics.
First law, a robot may not injure a
human being What the [ __ ] What the [ __ ]
is this?
You know, so this Western, you know, you
guys, a lot of you guys, Western people
all you know,
they they they approach, you know, their
view is
like they
you know, first of all, law is they are
fundamental
value of life. They think in terms of
law. So, you have to have a law. In this
case, it's kind of
This is not a natural law. It's a human
created law. So, they they want to stick
with the law idea. Three law laws of
robotic.
You know, your ass.
So, anyway, they you know, then then
they think of in terms of ethics, you
know, like
a robot may not injure a human being or
through inaction allow a human being to
become come to harm. So, in their
you know, attitude, in their viewpoint
is that they
they think of the machine, the human
created machine is kind of an entity,
you know, that like the machine has a
right almost, you know, right, another
obsession with the Western people.
A human has a right. The machine cannot
violate the you right of of of a human
being not to be hurt, you know.
Uh then second law, a robot must obey
the orders given by human being uh blah
blah blah.
Third law, third law, a robot must
protect its own existence, yeah. Crap,
you know.
So,
I don't like it, okay? I This idiotic
[ __ ]
But, you know, so in USA today, you
know, since in in beginning the past 10
years, AI becomes very
uh advanced, you know, it's advancing
very fast all over the place to the
degree that you cannot keep up. You
cannot know what's what's going on.
And especially, you know, when AI is
combined with robotics, it becomes very
powerful, you know. Now, you've seen
those
Boston Dynamics ro- robots, you know,
they
very
Or think of the movie, you know, the the
movie
uh what's the name of the movie? Arnold
Schwarzenegger.
You know, so it's
it's a it's it's a issue. It's an issue,
but um
But, how do I look at it, you know? So,
if I hate, you know, I find this
aversive, the laws of robotics, how how
would I, you know, kind of look at this
thing?
You know, you don't
I, you know, so okay, I
I don't know. I You know, first of all,
I wouldn't come up with some some phrase
that you can plaster over the place.
That like becomes a meme, you know.
Became a meme. Oh, three laws of
robotics.
That's not That's not how you go about,
you know, you don't
You don't create a phrase to to so it
becomes a meme to go over all over the
place. You think, you know,
So, yeah, robots, AI has, you know,
we will probably have a problem, so we
solve it. We, you know, we study it, we
design, and we
uh
spread information about our study, what
what we found, you know, things like
that.
With idea that, you know, we know
you know, we like to you know, we create
more and more powerful machines, which
is beneficial to us,
but we realize there's possible danger
danger of it, so we, you know, just like
everything, you you just study and
if there's something
uh that became dangerous, you prevent
it. You do things to prevent it.
Okay?
But but what the [ __ ] is this three laws
of the, you know, then ethics and
rights, human you know, what the [ __ ]
Okay, that's that's my rant.
Terminator, that's right. Terminator.
And Skynet Skynet is the Google.
And let me mention big big guru. You you
know, there's this guy today, very
popular on YouTube, Lex
What's his name? Lex Fridman, whatever
his name. AI Lex AI, okay? YouTube,
let's just search his name. This this
guy is an idiot.
Okay. Now, I said it I said it, you
know, next time he
If I met him, he you know, that's going
to have a bad impression. Oh, you are
the guy who called me an idiot. But but
but I, you know, okay, so uh what's
what's the guy's name?
Uh let's just go to YouTube. We will we
will find it, okay?
You know, this Lex guy, he's like the
he's like the
the Joe Rogan idiots on AI. You know,
he's you know, he's on YouTube doing all
kind of interviews related to
programming and technology. Now, what
what the [ __ ] is Google showing me?
Artificial intelligence. Okay, if you
search that, you'll find his channel.
Okay, Lex something.
Probably you guys Lex Friedman. Yeah,
this idiot.
Yeah, a very boring guy, you know, and I
don't you know, what the [ __ ] is He's so
he is becoming the next Joe Rogan on on
YouTube. Let's find his name. Okay,
let's find so people can see.
Yeah, this guy.
He's like, you know, he's all over the
place. He's doing interviews like
interview famous people every every
every week. You know, he has interviewed
Stephen Wolfram of Wolfram Research. He
has interviewed, you know, every he has
interviewed
basically everyone in AI field or even
the C++
programmer, you know,
the C++ creator,
you know.
So he interviewed him. You know,
and and the first time I heard of him is
from
is from one one of our Discord friend, a
mathematician from Canada, this weird
guy who
He is posting about Lex
I think he's the first one I learned
about him about Lex Friedman about two
or three years ago. So I watched a few,
you know, at first I was
interested because you know, talking
about AI, yeah, I'm interested, you
know, so I
You know, then he interviews Eric You
know, Weinstein, which I is another guy
I don't like.
You know, let me give you advice, okay?
Are you interested in AI? I know most
many of you are, right? We are the same,
you know, type of people.
Stop watching this channel, okay?
Let me give you advice.
Stop watching YouTube. Not just this
channel. Yeah, stop.
Okay, here's the thing. Instead of
watching YouTube where they chit-chat
about AI, where is it going, you know,
stop doing that. Stop doing that. Are
you interested in AI?
Dive into
AI.
Start to study Go lang seriously. Master
it. You know, don't don't chit-chat and
drama, you know, YouTube. Oh, who said
what AI is going to happen? Oh,
singularity. Oh, Google Google's new
library. Oh, this is all excited. Oh,
JavaScript another new something
framework. [ __ ]
Study one language, you know, maybe Go
lang or something. If you are
interested, you know, master it.
Study mathematics. Study computer
science, you know, if you are into new
neural networks, do that. Genetic
programming, you know.
So, my my point, my message is that you
want to dive into the hard parts, okay?
Stop Stop reading about listening to
these interviews, drama, you know, who
said, you know, what's what's happening
in AI. You you dive into
programming language, mathematics, you
know, the science of AI, you know,
you know.
Basically, they they come down to
mathematics and, you know, lot different
branches and computer science, which is
part of math, okay? Logic, you know.
You do that, okay? Reduce
You know, it's fun. It's fun to watch
this you know, these movies, you know,
these YouTube chit-chats,
but
and depends on what do really want to
do. If you are young,
then maybe take my advice. You know,
it's fun to watch this once in a while,
but you want to spend your time to
actually dive into the
you know, put your hands on on the
serious problem, and it'll be good for
you. Okay, maybe you'll become, you
know, you know, you'll work for Google,
or you'll start your company, or you'll
start to study the real issues. Okay.
The the the actual thing, not just this
chit-chat.
Because why am I saying this came from
experience, okay? On one hand,
all my life I, you know, I I did study
hard. Lots of the hard topic. I I did
study hard, but meanwhile, I also spent
tremendous time
watching this chit-chat drama thing,
because you want to know, like you go to
Hacker News. Before there's Hacker News,
there's Reddit. Before Reddit, there's
uh Slashdot. Slashdot begin which began
in 1999. You know, I used to go every
day. You read what's, you know, Slash
take for nerds, things that matter.
Matter my ass. So, if you do that, if
you are like me, you do that, you you
waste your life. You know, you waste
your life for 10, 20 years. You know,
and also a lot of you guys, which
programming should you learn? Which one
is best? You know, stop reading that.
Stop reading uh whether Rust is better,
or someone some project leader at
Google, he dis- he he he going to
discuss, he tell you their experiences
about Rust versus Go. Stop that. We Lisp
versus uh Haskell. Stop that, okay? Stop
that.
Pick some one language that's, you know,
practical. Even Haskell, even Haskell
can can be it. You know, focus, study
study it, okay? Study things, not listen
to drama. It wastes
it wastes your tremendous um
time in your life if you really want to
go somewhere.
Okay.
So, that's my uh that's my advice.
Uh
about machine learning AI, you know,
when you Okay, deep learning. So, no.
So, Akira Hey Akira. Oh, I know Akira.
No. Akira, you are late.
I know you have a question. You know,
say say say what it you want to say
about the keyboard layout, okay? I know
you uh have uh
something to talk about.
No, this this episode, originally I was
planning to do some JavaScript.
You know, live coding of JavaScript.
Then it be then I started become a
random uh talk. I I talked uh I talked
for
So, so far I talked for 1 hour already.
So, that's about it today. Maybe 5 more
minutes, that's it, okay? Uh
post your last questions, okay?
So, originally it's uh supposed to be uh
JavaScript live coding. Then I started
to talk talk about keyboards, layout,
ergonomic keyboards, all that uh for
like 50 minutes.
So, the last 10 minutes is about AI,
artificial intelligence, you know, just
random.
So, uh So, Akira
Akira is trying your own layout, okay?
So,
yeah. So, Akira actually Akira, you
know, I was going to do today I was
going to do
uh
I was going to write some JavaScript so
that I can
you know, I want to be
able to type in real time and have this
heat map shows up in real time.
Uh that's what we
I was thinking of doing.
But now it's kind of too late. So,
here's the source code.
So, you can see here's the JavaScript
code.
Uh
let's magnify, okay? Let's not not. So
here's the JavaScript. I was going to
modify it so that
so that
um
so that when you type, you can actually
see the heat map as you type.
Uh for example, I have one when you go
to uh layout then you go to
you know, character frequency.
Okay? So for example, as I type you can
see a uh let's magnify, okay? You can
see
a chart of
character frequency is
you see?
So if I type I t d d d d t t t t t t t t
t you can you see? So I want to do that
for the um
for this so you can see. So anyway, it's
too late today. So maybe next time.
So break the loop says
uh "Ksar, when you were younger, did you
enjoy going to the arcade?" Yes, of
course. So I
in 1980s,
1980s, when I was, you know, around 10
years old. That that is the day when the
um
What's What's the first, you know, ping
pong, you know, pong.
Pong began. Pong is kind of the first
that became popular. But But then then
uh the you have the Invaders, right? Is
Invaders, yeah. That's uh basically the
first one. So when that that's when I
was 10 years old. Oh, my I got I was
addicted to to to for a few years, you
know. At that time you have to put a
quarter. I mean, I was in Taiwan. So,
you put um
Oh, I I forgot how much is the uh coin
you put in. But, anyway, something like
a US quarter, okay? So, I put a lot
money.
And
and uh it cost my parents uh problems.
So, yeah, I grew up with arcade. I was,
you know, kind of I played a lot, you
know, addicted to it. Uh
Space Invaders, yes, that's a Then,
Galactica, you know, then I Space Invade
Invaders Space Invaders is not really uh
a great game, you know, it's kind of
boring. But, then Galactica becomes
over, you know, I played a lot a lot a
lot Galactica and other and quite a lot
others.
So, I think that's it for today. Let me
just jump around, see any more
questions. And we're going to shut down
in a minute or two. Uh AI, so we talked
about AI.
I was wondering more about why
mechanical keys, okay, we uh talked
about that.
How do you feel about keyboard layers
like Ergodox? I don't like uh layers,
okay? I talked about that a thousand
times already.
Uh
Don't we have a particular question,
just want to show support. Oh, yeah,
thank you. Uh
Okay, that's it.
A Sanian
It would be more true if AI wasn't a
black box. I
I forgot what's the context. What do you
mean?
The Badisk was awarded to you 15 points.
You talk about layouts.
So, Alan Allen says, "When you talk
about layouts, it's also important
sitting posture. A lot dev looks like
hunchbacks in their mid-20s.
Yeah, that's right. So, again, I this is
the nth time I'm
saying it. You want to get up and walk
for 5 minutes every hour. Every hour or
every 2 hours. You must do that, okay?
Because I have too much experience to
tell you, you know, you
because I've been sitting then oh, you
know,
uh too much. Uh yeah, get up every 2
hours. Walk for 10 minutes and also look
far away. That's important.
Yeah, Centipede, okay? Centipede, I
played a whole lot. In fact, I have a I
have article on that.
I I'm not sure I have uh Centipede, but
uh arcade.
I have article on some of the um
arcade games.
Yeah, so there it is, Space Invaders and
there's YouTube.
You know, there there's people, you
know, who play these, you know, beyond
you know, the record. Uh yeah, [ __ ]
YouTube problem. Oh yeah, and this
Asteroids, I played a whole lot. Yeah,
I'm quite good at it. Asteroid, I played
a whole lot.
Then Defender. Oh my god,
this is a game.
Uh [ __ ] all the videos are gone.
Uh Defenders, you know, that that game I
played a lot. I really love this one.
Uh one of the best game. Defenders, then
Phoenix, that's another one. This is
this one is funky, kind of.
Then oh yeah, 1942, I played a whole
lot.
Uh then, this R-Type
R-Type uh was popular around uh 1987.
No, the
By the time I see it, it's uh 1990s.
But anyway, it was very popular, but I
haven't played much uh with it. Oh yeah,
and the Space Harrier, you know, quite a
lot.
Then, there's maze games, okay? This I
played a lot. Uh
not back then, but uh like 10 years ago,
I played on PC on on, you know, this I
played a whole lot.
Uh Bomberman, also very famous, you
know, and Qix, this is uh
very interesting.
Attax,
you know? Anyway.
Uh video games, arcade games.
Do I plan to do a tutorial on
AutoHotkey? No.
Uh
No, because, okay, this is the last
question, then we're going to shut down.
AutoHotkey, because
10 years ago,
AutoHotkey is fantastic. If you're on
Windows, AutoHotkey, you need
AutoHotkey. But not today, because
today, you know, 10 years ago,
the mechanical keyboards are not yet
popular. Beginning, you know, I have a
history.
I have article on the history of you
know, I'm not going to show it. But
anyway, 10 years ago,
let's say 2010, there's not much
programmable keyboards. There are a few,
like, but they are esoteric, you know?
And let me let me show let me let me let
me tell you, okay? So, 10 years ago,
all this doesn't exist, but however,
this exist. Uh not that. Uh well, this
Okay, and this one this this one is very
old. This this one began in 1990s, okay?
Very expensive. Like if you buy this one
today, only for 16 keys, they sell like
$200. Okay, so they they are old
company.
Okay, but
but today but since but since 10 years
ago, since ErgoDox and truly ergonomic,
then there's a boom of mechanical
keyboards and do-it-yourself and 3D
printers and technology, you know, the
technology growth exponentially.
So, today you have QMK like we talked
about, you know, the the firmware you
know, you just open source, you just
download it, you know, you can So,
keyboard with a programmable firmware is
far far far more robust and better than
a operating system-based
keyboard transformation, you know, such
as AutoHotkey. So, you want
you want to get a programmable keyboard.
Okay, I have
um
you know, you want a programmable
keyboard with on-board memory, okay?
This is important. Not just some gaming
keyboard because they they're not good.
You You know, you want on-board memory.
You don't want cloud. You want You don't
want some, you know, that requires you
to have a Windows software, then it
connects through a cloud, then look up
your database for your key mapping you
know, you want the
keyboard with on-board memory and you
you know, uh
programmable keypad. So,
once you have that, you can program into
the keyboard firmware, you know, it's
far more better than AutoHotkey or or um
Karabiner on a Mac or the X mod map or
the thousand other things on Linux.
Yeah, so but AutoHotkey is still useful.
Like like right now I'm using it, okay?
So, let's see I can show you right now
my AutoHotkey script.
There. Yeah, okay. So, here is my
Here is my AutoHotkey script. Not much.
Uh I have one for uh launch or switch to
Firefox.
Okay. So, then I have a launch or switch
to Emacs. Okay.
Then
and uh toggle maximize window. Okay. So,
this is a key. I press a key uh to
you know, maximize it or restore.
There's no way to do it without
AutoHotkey. So, I have a few. But,
otherwise, you want the
program programmable keyboard first.
Okay, if you are on a laptop laptop,
that's too bad. You know,
nothing you can do, but you know,
try try not to use laptop keyboard. Buy
an external one. Bye, guys.
See you next time.
Okay, I'll give you 30 seconds to say
whatever.
Then, I'm going to click end.
So, I need to yeah.
I need to get my drinks. I'm being
thirsty. Nonstop talking thirsty. Thank
you, Sid.
Bye, all.