welcome to talk show episode 1013
today is June 5th 2019 and today's
episode we are going to do a live coding
of JavaScript in Emacs so this is also a
workflow Emacs workflow demo with stuff
like ease and ok they did let's begin
let's let's show my Firefox browser
and we are going to do a live coding of
a XHTML XML entities so let me make sure
I am alive and everything yes looks like
it
so live coding in Emacs with sapphire
keys live code in JavaScript and we are
going to do the coding the task is HTML
and HTML entities so I have this code
this is a JavaScript JSON format and you
know it's a object and to 2,200 lines
and each object property you have the
entity name called core point and the
characters in JavaScript string format
so first of all what is HTML entities if
you in case you don't know it is in that
HTML you can type for example let's go
to the top of the page for example you
can type helps let's go here and let's
go here so let's let's say X creme name
ampersand sign and let's say pound
semicolon for the paragraph on it
showing browser and you can see a pound
sign
that's what HTML entities are for they
allows you to type a non ASCII character
you know of course you can also type the
pound sign directly if your HTML and is
set to utf-8 for example I type the
pound sign should make a paragraph show
it you see you see a pound sign
so you can use HTML entities for it and
this so this you know HTML entities
begin with the ampersand sign and so
there are a bunch of them there there
used to be about 200 of them but since
html5 they added so they are like 2,000
of them now which is a by the way it's a
bad idea it's very bad I talked about
this my last talk show where I talked
about why HTML entities is very is is a
very bad thing you should avoid using it
don't use it at all so so that's that's
HTML HTML entities it allows you to type
in an ASCII character by a code like
kind of a code coded sequence of letters
now they are act this so so HTML
entities but they are three kind of
entity there are three ways to type a
non ASCII character one way is by by
what's called the code point let me show
you so I type first first of all let's
find out what is the code point for the
pound sign so in Emacs we are going to
code describe char but before we do it
that let me start let me start saw a
command dog mod so you can actually see
it
so start saw start command mod command
mod now that that is my command a
wrapper command to to start the command
log mod you can you can search it may
open and you can find that package but
the package it's not the design is not
so good in my opinion and the
documentation is very bad so it requires
several
and not intuitive commands to start to
use it because I'm you know I already
started so you can see all the Emacs
command icon on the Left panel but I
wrote a command cuz I'll start it
exhaust start command log mod that that
takes care of the starting up you can
find that on my my github Emacs in it
yeah so let's go back to the entities so
we are talking about HTML entities I
said they are you know it's a way to
type know ASCII characters by a coded
stream and and there are three actually
three methods to create a h3 kind of
HTML entities so one of them is you find
out what what is a KO point of the
character you want to type so I so I
call I call describe function
I mean describe cha while kusa is on the
pound sign and what I get is this panel
and you see the name the character name
is pound sign and on the second line you
will see that it says the code point is
163 and in hexadecimal notation is a 3
so anyway so 163 is a KO point so let's
put that here and that's gone out so
let's type pound sign
I mean ampersand and pound sign then
then 163 the code point then coma okay
then make it paragraph and showing
browser you can see that it shows the
pound sign so any character you can use
HTML entities for it when you know the
characters code point so that's one way
to use HTML entity now you can also use
the hexadecimal notation which is 4
pound sign is a three so a three showing
browser oh wait you need X here so pun
so ampersand pound sign X then the
hexadecimal so showing browser so you
can see it's a pound sign so this is a
second way another way the third way is
by what's called named entities so
remember entities or all these we've
talked about those are entities HTML or
XML entities three mates three methods
to use it one is by the code point
- pad hexadecimal the third way is by
what so-called named entities HTML named
entities what that means is that for
certain characters HTML gives it a name
so instead of using code point or
hexadecimal you can just type the name
so for example we have this ampersand
pound semicolon and it shows up you know
it shows up as a pound sign
so why the named entities well named
because so you know it's easier to
remember you know when you need the
pound sign you just say pound when you
need the cent sign you just say
ampersand cent semicolon okay
sure in browser you can see there's a
cent so for all these characters you
have some of them has a name and that
entity is called HTML named entity now
remember it's only only some of these
characters has a name not all for those
characters that doesn't have a name you
can just use the code point or the
hexadecimal okay let me check oh for
people-watching great good morning
so say hi here here you know comment so
we talked we so we covered what is the
entities and three ways to input
entities now so what are some so named
entities as I mentioned before they are
about 200 of them but because of html5
they added now they are like 2,000 to
thousands of them so let let's go to the
let me show you the JavaScript file
actually yeah here so once I can't even
close this window so you can see here
you know two thousand lines of J this is
a JSON file this is a complete list of
named entities in html5 so so what I'm
going to do today is actually you see I
have this web page this is a complete
list before html5 to thousands of them
200 of them what I'm going to do is I'm
going to update this page so it becomes
the complete list of HTML named entities
so what does that involve
that involves you know I got the source
data here this is my source data I'm
going to you know this is JavaScript
code I'm going to convert convert it to
manipulated in some way and eventually
create a web page you know replacing
this page so that's what I'm going to do
today and you know so you cannot see
some demo of my me using Emacs and and
some you know talk about JavaScript and
that's it yeah we already talked about
what is entities so so I'm like okay so
let's do that let's do that so first of
all so what how we gonna do this this is
unscripted so I don't know actually so
let's just figure that out let's see how
long have I been talking okay let's
let's do for another 10 minutes and
let's see how far we go but before that
let me get my energy drink today I have
tomato juice now this is Dollar Tree
store you got one bottle of tomato juice
for $1 it's very good and then add a
pool of the energy drink this is sugar
free energy drink which is basically
concentrated coffee so let's let's get
back to the task at hand we want to
create this turn this JSON file into
HTML page so if you have comments
questions I'd love to see it post it ok
so let's do these so we need to turn
this into a HTML page first of all
there's this problem this this this file
JSON file of the oops of the this JSON
file came from the w3c standard website
and it's done in this funny way because
you see now the key this is a JSON file
and you know which is basically is a
JavaScript object object is a list of
properties key and values now so each
key is this string this string is the is
the syntax for the named entity so if
you type capital a acute it's going to
show capital letter a with a with a
strike on top of the letter so the keys
are the entity name syntax and then then
the value is another object and this
object has two keys one is code point
wines characters the code point is you
know obviously the Unicode code point
which is the ID that identified the
characters
so a acute characteristic 0.91 193 then
the characters key its value is actually
the character so it's been essentially a
string of length 1 but it's written in
this way now that that is a that is
JavaScript syntax to show a character by
the Unicode code point so the syntax is
backward slash u then followed by four
the four digits of hexadecimal this is
not a good thing against sort of escape
mechanism I talked about yesterday so
let's go to my JavaScript blog okay let
me try to do this quickly so that you
know actually we get somewhere but
before so but we need to go to my
JavaScript blog too to show you
javascript in depth you search for
Unicode so you can see here is the
syntax this page explains the syntax of
the java scripts as unicode escape
sequence that's a proper name for it
javascript unicode escape sequence so
actually the syntax the syntax they are
two syntax for it so one of them is
backslash you followed by four
hexadecimal digits
remember only four of them cannot be
more cannot be less must be four digits
of hexadecimal so the other syntax is
backslash you followed by a curly quote
then inside it you put anywhere between
four to six hexadecimals
so you have these two syntax again you
know it's bad design it's confusing so i
you know i show some examples some
examples here so first the first thing
that we want to do we want to go through
the list and change the the Unicode
escape sequence into an actual character
so let's turn you know so we can
actually see you know some of these
characters so okay let's let's begin to
do that so first of all we want to loop
through the object
now this another complexity of
JavaScript because when you live through
object using the for in loop that is
actually a bad bad that's not what you
want because that we are actually looped
through all the parents properties you
know the inherited properties came which
which is the parents or parents or
parents properties that's not what
usually what you want you you only want
to loop through the objects own property
keys so how do we do that there are many
ways so go to JavaScript in-depth
JavaScript properties section then you
have list properties so here are the
several ways we can turn a property into
array then we can do through the array
which gives us which is much more safer
because you don't go into the parents
properties and there are many
complexities in JavaScript because each
property has several attributes one of
them is called a network innumerable one
is called okay
several attribute one of them is in
Irbil in them innumerable also
javascript property keys can have two
possible types data type one is string
one is symbol and symbol keys you know
those properties with key who is type
whose type is symbol is a rarely used
like usually you do not want to loop
through them so that that is why you
have all these complexities you know
whether when
want to call a method to get all the
keys of a object you have to consider
whether you if you only want you know in
number about keys only or do you want
only string keys or you want both string
keys and symbol keys or symbol keys only
so-so this is one of the example of the
extreme complexity of JavaScript so
anyway so these options which we which
one we're gonna use we we do not want
symbols keys we want string keys and
okay get on property names so let's go
let's constant xx let's go down constant
area function wait so we want to object
get on property names get on poverty
names get home poverty news okay so this
is I'm using my own JavaScript so
JavaScript mod and the the abbreviation
template expansion is a bit it's not
inconsistent so anyway I get on property
names we have xx so once we get the
property names constant okay and so we
got our array then we can loop through
the array so for in four of four let's
use a for loop for of loop is new in
2015 what it does it is that it allows
you to go through any iterable object so
for key in array we want
console.log okay let's just say that
okay let's just print it and see what we
get great so we you know you know we are
looking through it and it's spinning all
the keys now we are going to do so for
each key so what we do we want to print
let's just say print key then code point
so that's okay so that's
so key dot cool points that would be the
code point okay then the last part will
be characters so that's easy
okay let's print it undefined that's
incorrect okay
oh okay so what we need to do X X dot k
dot Kol point then xx dot k k let's
print it arrow again coupon code points
is undefined so X X is our object oh
wait so xx
is the object then KK is the key so
perhaps we need to do that because right
because otherwise KK becomes a stream
that now that that is another extreme
complexity of JavaScript because when
you say you know something thoughts
something the second thing big
automatically becomes a stream if you do
not want to it want it to become a
stream you have to use the square
bracket notation to access the property
so anyway so X X dot k k XX is the
object good morning Danielle xx is the
object and we want the key k k that's
correct and then once we have the key we
have the object we want to yes
that's I believe that is correct okay
let's run it unexpected token what
unexpected token oh yeah okay extra
extra period syntax a row okay let's run
it yeah we got it running it and it's
working it's working correctly this is
the power of JavaScript and it is the
power of understanding you know what's
going on what's up Danielle so so okay
so so we gotta train it out so we can
see this is the entity name this is the
code point why do we have a bracket
there we don't want the let's switch
back we don't want the bracket here oh
because a stupid stupid okay you know
what this is very you know this JSON
data file you see this
not 193 that's a cool point but but
however they put a square bracket around
it meaning that it is actually a way so
why do they need an array well usually
it means you know if possibly they are
more than one element indeed you can see
in this line there are two elements so
okay so yeah I understand what they are
doing because for this character this
entity a C capital e now which one what
the is AC capital e oh it is this
one
it's like approximately equal to symbol
okay so - so you they actually created a
named character for for this this
character this is bad this is bad okay
that's another topic that's about
Unicode composition they should not use
that because there is a single character
that is of that you know approximately
equal to let me show you maybe we should
talk about that but if we do then we are
not going to have time to finish this
you know not in ten minutes we okay
we've been yeah let's talk about that
you know after all
so unicode so let's go to unicode let me
tell you what's going on so unicode if
you go to unicode you have this math
section
sorry unicode okay then you can find you
can see the there is a section of all
symbols about equivalence or or
approximately equal to so you you can
see what there are all these symbols so
the symbol you see so there it is you
see this one okay let me let me go to
the let's go to google paste so that you
have JavaScript on so I can show you
better so this is
so let's go to let's magnify the window
and move it here so you can see and the
character we are interested is
this one so the Unicode name is
approximately equal to so you have a
wave then you have an equal sign below
it that is one single character that is
not composition meaning that made of two
characters that is not so basically the
HTML entity let's copy that so HTML
entity they created the entity named a c
then capital e okay and they define that
entity as as i've made of two unicode
code points you know basically they want
this you know approximately equal to
character but they they create that
character by using two unicode code
points it's a composition basically but
yeah let's look at what character they
used so they have a 766 let's see a 766
okay so that is kind of this this symbol
this this inverted lazy-s what I do see
then the second character is 8 1 9 let's
see what that character is so let's
paste it here 8 1 9
so eight one night character eight one
night is this character come the name is
combining the bolo lie so basically it's
like a equal sign so they are creating
this approximately equal to symbol by
using a composition you know one is the
when is rotated s the other one is the
turbo low lying combining oh my god this
is what incredible incompetence my guy
cannot beat possibly believe that I mean
there is is there a reason like you know
sometimes you look at this standard
standards is there a reason that they
use this composition characters then
instead of a single yeah I cannot think
of one I cannot possibly think that is
good
I cannot even you know so why are they
doing it you know the person who wrote
this obviously you know when you write
it you know you know you you know unless
you are drunk like you're on drugs like
you don't know what you are typing they
so they must someone must have seen it
so what is their reason for using a
composition character for this you know
for this scribe of you know a wave above
equal sign because there is a character
like that I don't know so so anyway so
so let's try this character let's just
see let's just try it please
see if that works in browser see see
what it shows what this idiocy you see
it doesn't even show where you see yeah
whenever you use Unicode composition you
know character composition meaning you
create one single character that's made
of two or more characters you often it
does not display well
so the other symbol we are talking about
that a single symbol is let's just you
know put it together in comparison so we
can see so this character is what we
want copy it let's put it here side by
side showing browser you see you see
this incredible you you know the
standard facts so yeah so okay so that
so that's a new discovery today while we
are doing this incredible fuck-you
unicode code point so you know okay so
anyway now we understand why they are
using array here and okay and what okay
what what is the next thing we want to
do we have printed out their values okay
here here's what I want to do let's
create well instead of explaining what
we are going to do it's actually faster
if we just type it you know just do it
okay so let's do it so we are going to
create a Unicode template stream
so let me do these let's say constant SS
equals true Unicode template stream okay
I forgot the syntax
well I think it's dollar sign that's
correct so
so what we gonna do is we want to do
that we want to create a new JSON file
but with a additional additional
property that shows the character
directly instead of using the Unicode
escape syntax because that way then we
can see the character you know we can
see the character so once we have the
new JSON file we can you know use that
to work on you know HTML stuff so let's
this part will be
Oh an issue show you my window so you
can see my commands
cool pants okay and this is an array so
this is an array we need to write
we need to put in array syntax actually
no it's printed then the last part will
be cha ok let's not name let's say
string okay string and
okay then let's just print it now let's
see what happens
oops wait we don't want to print the
first line so comment that out Lynette
oh yeah me we need to print it so
console.log is runnin okay so that seems
correct that seems correct that seems
correct oh okay so now the code point is
not correct because you need you do need
a bracket so
Sokol points is a ray why does it not
train the bracket I don't understand
because when you when you print a array
you when you print a array it usually
prints the bracket so let's
okay this list is too long let me make
it shorter so we can copy save this as
backup okay go back here and let's
remove all that vennett okay now I don't
understand
I should have a array bracket there so
code point I don't understand
yeah you see normally it prints the
array okay so that's interesting when
you have array in a template string
somehow it skips the array brackets is
that true because
so of course you can just print it by by
doing that manually yeah but that's you
know we can solve this problem you know
it's already solved but however usually
you know you should I usually you know
look into why why when you have a
temporary strain that array is not
printed as array for example let's let's
say for example it's common this out
let's let's say console.log printer
array so constant X x equals two one two
three then train X okay but if we say
if we say that
oh this is okay so this is actually
interesting so when you have a array in
a in your template stream then the array
bracket is not printed for some reason
now if you don't know what template
strings are template strings is new in
JavaScript 2015 and basically it allows
you to embed expressions or variables
inside the string you know this is a
popular feature in Python in Ruby in PHP
especially P well yeah especially PHP
it's a popular feature and pearl pearl
began this feature which called
interpolate in interpolation of a
strange stream at you know basically
allows you to embed a variable
expression inside the stream so but when
we use that oh okay I think I know why
now actually I'm not too sure you know
basically when when you have a array in
a string context like when you print a
ray to a string first of all the array
will be turned into the to string method
will be called on it so here the to
string is called and here the to string
is also called but however the to string
method used here is probably different
one from the to string method used here
so so anyway let's let's figure this out
later okay so let's start up show let's
put it here javascript
when a array is inside a template string
it will not print the square brackets
okay that that is the thing okay
let's worry about this later so remove
that uncomment drain it okay that's what
we want
remove that remove that donut yes that's
what we want and what what is the next
thing we need to do
so actually
so actually you add that
yeah so you add a string at the end here
so cool point strain
there is another thing we need to do is
that we need to add the Unicode name you
know right now we have a you know entity
name we have the code point and we have
the actual character but we do not know
the characters Unicode name you know
describe function this character is
Latin capital letter A with acute we
need the Unicode name somewhere here but
however in JavaScript there is no
built-in way to get a unicode characters
name there's it doesn't exist it exists
in Python and in :
you know there's a standard library
building but not in JavaScript so in
order to do that you probably need to
MPN you know fetch some JavaScript
library to get the unicode name but we
are not going to do that because you
know npm is is javascript npm npm is
very bad and javascript libraries are in
general you can you don't want to trust
them so what what we can do we do need
we do need a unicode name because
because the you know on the h my entity
page you want i want i need to say the
name of the unicode character so that
people understand you know a description
for the character so I need a name but
how we gonna do it and we don't want to
use JavaScript because it's not you know
it's not there you have to use the
library so we can either use Python or
we can use Scotland or we can use Emacs
Emacs Lisp the oldest allows me to do
that
now if if I'm going to do this in Python
or Golan what I can do is I since you
know I already have a this is a JSON
string you know so gold Golan and Python
can both read that so I can just you
know I can just start switch to Python I
encoded or Golan now Python I have I
have some experience using the Unicode
package so I can do it faster than :
because in Golan I have not used the
Unicode character package before you
know when you need to know the character
characters for name and if we are going
to do in this in emag list there are two
ways one way is just like Python : you
know you there's also a JSON video you
max list but the other way is to do it
interactivity so we can actually just
interactively start to add add add the
actual character here let me show you
how okay let's do that let me show you
how to do that interactively in Emacs so
once we have a you know we have a
character here character name yeah we
need character name so okay so then
let's do that let's do star tamakwa so
in the beginning let's go to beginning
on line start mark well okay but before
we do that we need to know given a code
point how do we show the character
in such ah okay right in such our does
not take a dismal number you need a
hexadecimal the problem is more
comfortable more complex than I want so
there is a way to to insert a character
using the code point but I forgot so in
order to do that lets go to my Emacs
tutorial so you go to practical Emacs
then you go down there is a Unicode
topic and there is Unicode tutorial so
you go to that page then there is how to
set a key to insert a Unicode character
how to use a brief to insert unicode
character how to insert a yuna character
by its hexadecimal how to insert unicode
character by its decimal value this is
what we want
oh so you just need to type pound sign
or 10 oh okay let's try that so let's
say we want to type the character 193 so
we call in such ah then pound sign 1001
93 enter there it is
great so we got that okay so remember
it's pound sign 10 in such a pound sign
Tina okay let's do that so let's go back
here we're gonna start the macro let me
show you the panel
start amok we'll move to that move to
that move through that and wait
start amok well move move
copy the whole copy then go through the
end go to the end
go back inside not put a comma space
quote name quote colon space
quote
command mod called a command insert cha
ok then homicide 10 are go to insert mod
paste enter
quote that is it now hold on a second
let's stop Marco okay what this Marco
does is that it would just you know add
the character here but we actually want
the name you know we want one the name
of the character buts let's let's hold
hold on on that for a moment let's just
use this macro to to get all the names
so we're gonna select all these nice
okay up to here then let's call apply
macro to regionalize yay we got it
walking so you see now we have the
actual character at the end of each line
now there is a except this this macro
only works for characters that has only
one Unicode code point so it does not
work for this in this case because yeah
because in composition characters that
you actually have two characters so it
doesn't fit into the scheme there's no
one single name you have you know two
characters with two names
so we have to do something special about
the you know the composition characters
it's you know truly stupid anyway so
this email is smoke well we you know
Emacs Marco we just showed Team Aqua
that added the characters for us the
next step step is to replace the
characters to Unicode name so let's do
that so first of all shrink it a bit so
you can see let's record another macro
so start mark well go to the end then
one two three
move backward three times one more time
then that's called describe cha okay now
we have a character information now we
switch pain then search for name
: space okay then we cut the rest of the
line we switch back okay so then we move
coucil right to the coma and let's just
say paste it okay quote paste quote okay
let's do that for now and Marco
okay so let's select these lines and a
primal code to regionalize okay
primal code to regionalize there's an
error of somewhere
okay so I think so this is getting
really long so what I think what we
let's let's this finish this start mark
well go to the end of line one two three
four go back four characters core
describe Chow switch pain search name
colon space enter exit copy the rest of
the line
oh I know what happens because I was
trying to cut when you cut it is an
arrow even though the cut is still
successful but it doesn't delete it so
whenever there's an arrow your key
marker exits you know it so that is why
so let's not do the cut let's just say
copy you know to prevent the arrow which
in turn stops our mark key Marco so
let's start again okay start Rico key
marker go to the end of line backward
one two three four times then call
describe cha switch closer to the next
pin search for name colon space then
enter to exit to search then mark then
go to the end of mark copy okay no arrow
that's good now we switch back actually
we switch back to the panel remove all
the other panels move closer to the
right two times add a comma space quote
quote
okay backspace paste that is what we
want now we exit the key Marco stop team
aqua so we have recorded one key Marco
and now let's apply that chemical to all
these lines okay hop right it makes a
very macro to regionalize superb so you
can see so okay we have just
demonstrated to keyboard markers so you
know you Emacs scheme oppose that that
transform kind of this JSON file
transform interactivity so we have like
2000 lines right remember we had to
thousands of these these you know entity
entities so now we have a way to
interactively change over all of them to
actually show so what is the purpose of
changing them to show the character
itself and also the Unicode name of that
character so this is one of the great
use of Emacs because you know otherwise
you have to you know either use a
JavaScript library from from the wild or
you know start to do this in colon or
Python
you know and Emacs give us this option
just interactively change the you know
the cheerson file and we can also do it
in do it in Emacs lease you know
that's another option so anyway now we
have that so basically what I have to do
right now is just to print it out you
know we have the character name we have
the code point we have the you know the
character itself so all we have to do is
to let's go back to the external page
you know here all we have to do is just
print print it like for example
like this let's magnify HTML mod magnify
what we have to do is add a I had a li
and let's say now let's print it then
why not
so first of all let me show you what
we're gonna print actually let me copy
that just I'm just going to work this
quickly without much explanation name
[Music]
cold point
what we want to do is the HTML syntax
okay
so basically we just want to print lines
like that for each line in the JSON file
we want to print line lines like that
you know I'm simplifying a lots of
things for example we are skipping
skipped in this composition charts
because I don't know how many are there
you know you have to think about how to
deal with them you know remember our
task is to create a HTML page
- that lists all the entities named
entities obviously this page the purpose
is for references purposes and also as a
tutorial so when you have a situation
like these composition characters you
need to kind of explain it you know you
cannot just slap it there you know like
even right now we have difficulties
because you know this this composition
characters it it has to you know because
it's a two characters so it has two
names so it does not fit into our format
here you know where each line is a you
know the entity name then the Unicode
code point but for the case of
composition you have more than one cool
point so we don't know what to do with
that so we are skipping that for now we
don't know how much how many are there
but let me just you know push through
and show you what we're gonna do so for
this composition it's just commented out
and we are just going to print
first of all train days let's let's see
so this magnify this is actually wrong
let's say it's I'm going to make some
modification here but but you can see
that if we do the key mark off the first
time we can do it correctly we I'm just
going to manually add something here so
that is actually what we want
yes
name and for the first one we also need
to do that let's just do it manually
okay that seems it Shannon so we are
making sure that the JSON file syntax is
all correct now what is this one a cute
[Music]
so this is latin small letter with small
letter a with acute now noticed is
something odd here because notice both
this line and this line they have the
same character two to five okay let me
show you two to five code point but
however the the named entities are
different one is without the semicolon
at the end now that that is one of the
problem created by html5 because now
they they have several they created
several about twenty or thirty entities
without the trailing semicolon in the in
other words now that the entity the HTML
entity syntax is now inconsistent
there's no you know it's not regular
anymore because some of the named
entities do not have to not need to end
you know does not ending or same at
semicolon that is actually a problem let
me show you that you can read about on
my on my web blog so you have all these
entities named entities without the
trailing semicolon this this creates a
huge amount of problems when your syntax
becomes irregular because then you have
all kind of special cases it becomes
extremely difficult to pass and
error-prone hey good morning
elusive I cannot see your message and I
don't know when when you typed it so
anyway this video is getting too long
and we are not you know I start to
ramble you know not going anywhere but
let's let's just finish printing this
yeah we are trying to finish printing
this and that'll be it for today I will
say ten more minutes but first of all we
have to make sure every character here
is the JSON file is actually correct
format so you see we are missing that
one huh let's not worry about it let's
just delete it okay it's to save time
but you get a point you know we've gone
through this
so now let's print it it's okay yeah
that's correct
now we need to print we need to print
actually here that's what we want to
print in this format so let's go that's
how do we do it how do we do this copy
that paste it here let's let's just do
that
that's what we need to print so first of
all we need to print the entity but okay
constant entity entity syntax equals to
let's just say that now that is entity
now cool point okay Co point is going to
be this
that is the core point
so we got entities we got cool point
then we got the char name okay
char name will be
name that's right so actually we don't
need these stupid me we don't need this
so that's much simpler code points name
that's right and entity entity is not
string actually we don't need the string
is stupid
so entity is KK and hey base good
morning I'm just going to bed but I look
forward to watching this stream thank
you thank you good night so anyway so
yeah so this is almost done
and we don't need this line anymore make
sure this is correct entity entity
string so entity string that's right
entity disome oh how the that's a that's
a cool point so
then we have entity hex name
hex so how do you get the hex hex is
actually just the
so we need to turn a code point to hex
but before these before all that lets
just trained it just make sure
yep that's that's correct and now it's
to these we are almost done we print
this correctly and we'll be done entity
point okay so not right now the problem
is you need to convert decimal to
hexadecimal so how do we do that we can
do that actually the cool point is
actually we need to do this ampersand
pound you see this is a problem with the
entities entities you could you become
you are seeing a moment why what you
need that m % am P semicolon then here
we need we need ampersand : pound sign X
and here should be a hex hex decimal so
the problem is how do you convert a
decimal number to hexadecimal in
JavaScript wait the dude's to get the
javascript in depth let's search for hex
okay it's not there then it's a number
section
okay eat Robo maybe in a string section
string string above you a string escape
sequence Unicode escape string up to
extreme prototype let's go to object
reference object reference number
prototype let's go to a number object
number object you have a number of wrote
I pass int yes passed int 2 hex that's
right
so hexadecimal string to a number binary
string to number dismal string
okay it converts a string to integer
that's not what we want we want we want
to convert a integer to a string
hexadecimal string string to number
number to string let's see string to
number string string to integer string
to decimal number number to stream so we
want this one yeah that one
so number dot to stream radix okay so
here we will have Cole point Co point is
a number that's right dot actually call
point the first element soco point dot
to strain and radix red X will be 16 for
hexadecimal
okay let's just let's try to do this
okay so we got that it's we don't need
that anymore it's running it again so
that is how results copy it
let's go through the HTML and paste it
and see what we get
you go to order
let's open this page open update the
date and let's paste it here so we need
a ul it's at a ul okay show in browser
so we have a HTML
okay so hexadecimal syntax that's
correct this syntax correct we got it
working well there's some some little
errors we need to fix so you know so
let's let's fix it
console.log okay let's print a ul so
that and then we need to hexadecimal
syntax hex hex is we need a semicolon at
the end semicolon at the end
and also the the entity name should be
that needs to fix we need to fix that
because because the entity name issues
as a character because it is actually
showing the entity name such as you know
such as that but instead what you want
is replace that and put ampersand symbol
bye-bye ampersand a MP semicolon you
know so this this is part of the reason
entities is no good any kind of escape
sequence is no good they increase the
passing and you know complication by a
magnitude and also because that it also
it becomes extremely error-prone so you
know you know often you see a webpage
you see these screwed up characters or
actually there are many reasons for that
but part of the reason is because the
parsing it becomes very complex so
anyway let's fix this so the first
factor needs to be fixed that is not
trivial let me let me do that let me
explain but but also the decimal point
is correct the hexadecimal is fixed okay
let's try to run this again let's run it
named entity syntax let's run it okay
copy switch to the HTML buffer paste
showing browser so named syntax that
dismal syntax that hex syntax that name
is that that is good okay that is what
we set out to do now there is one more
error the last arrow is that the name
entity syntax you know it's it's it's
showing the character directory so
so what we need to do is actually we
need to write a program so that so here
okay so we can do this so so so entity
this is actually the character we need
another one
so what's going on is that we need
another one too for the entity string so
we can do that by we want to remove the
first character so actually so we can do
that by so here is a NP that purse then
substring slice okay slice start with 1
2 n okay
that is the answer okay so
let's do this
ciao so we have the character then we
have named sin tanks then we have
decimal syntax we have hex syntax then
the character name in the end okay let's
run it copy it go through the browser go
to the HTML page paste it showing
browser this is still wrong oh oh
because we didn't there it is
granite copy cross
pase showing browser correct okay I
think so that's it so you know we set
out to do this and it's done it's you
know we got so now all we have to do is
I have to work on the whole 2,000
characters of I'd forgot where it is
entity anyway there are two thousand
lines of the new entities I need to
create that and then I need to deal with
the composition characters you know
figure out how to deal with that so
anyway that's it that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
hey Danielle URL cannot contain spaces
it is actually an example of using
character escape it is it is actually an
example of using character escapes
escapes in markup in CSS yeah that that
so so what are you I think what you are
saying is that you are giving a reason
for for the case of using escape
sequences or entities you know there's
there are some valid reason and you are
saying one of the reason is is that is
that you are URL cannot contain spaces
therefore you know yeah I don't know
what yeah so I know what you are saying
so you are saying that is a or might be
a valid reason for any sort of us escape
sequences or you know entities which I
commented earlier that I don't think
those are good but I think you are right
I think there are some cases of valid
reason so so I think escape sequences
are not entirely bad there are some good
uses so the question to me is you know
are they or some actually could valid
reasons to use it or should it be
entirely banned like no there's no one
single good reason for its existence at
all any sort of escape sequence
characters now I haven't thought about
that you know I've talked about before
if you seen my previous video we are
talking about this because there are a
lot situations where these escape
sequences or entities they actually
cause tremendous tremendous harm you
know they are extremely bad design but
now the question is are they are
actually some yes yeah so they are
absolutely are certain cases where
escape sequences are good design and
valid and one example I know of is that
when you have for example when you for
example invisible characters or caps
control sequence characters in ASCII you
usually you sometimes you want to tell
people you know how to you know the for
example you writing a tutorial
explaining what control sequences are
those are invisible characters but you
need to like identify them you know you
you need to make them visible so you can
explain to users so so for example in
the string you have you have backslash
in that stand for new line which is
invisible characters and a slash t for
tab which is another invisible
characters so when you explain in some
programming languages tab matters so you
need you need some kind of a sequence of
code to indicate these invisible
you know character you cannot just say
tab which becomes invisible so so that
for example is a valid use of a kind of
a escape sequence of kind of a code that
we face is another character now in your
case you are saying about you are not
allowing space which is another good use
of escape sequence I think so I haven't
thought you know obviously you are right
but what I'm saying is that I you know I
tend to have you know this philosophy so
I want I need to think about it for one
hour you know I need to walk take a walk
and do monologue for one hour to to have
a conclusion about whether weathers you
know space in you are not allowed
whether that is a good reason to use
escape sequences or some sort of
encoding but but yeah I think that's a
good reason in anyway so so that's
digression okay so thank you guys for
watching well that's not actually
digression it's related to the topic
because the whole topic today is about
these entities so this this would be
part two of the yesterday's entities
topic if you haven't seen it so go watch
it so anyway have a good day Danielle
and thank you guys for watching bye