morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today is 2019
December 18th
Wednesday 1 o'clock p.m. San Francisco
time morning bots good morning Alan and
what is today's topic today's topic is
going to be random I guess I was
planning to do JavaScript and good
morning then
so what topic you guys to talk about
ok so otherwise I'm just going to do
random ok so today we gonna I'm gonna
show you some stuff ok maths
combinatorial problems Tommy no polio me
no polycube podium and those are
combinatorial problems we are talking
about combinatorial problems because
yesterday we are discussing
combinatorial stuff those trigrams you
see so but we run out of time so we
might talk about that today
combinatorial mathematical problems very
easy to understand but those are
unsolved problems and if you saw them
you gonna be rich and we also have math
folding problems which is another
component of your problem mat folding
problem you guys know about mat folding
problem maybe you don't know if you
don't know let me teach you them so
maths combinatorial problems and dome
gwon dome ok dude good morning the
magpie magpie magpie where you from
and then Morris I I think I asked you
this model 4 times where you from
demo is joint discord don't you want
wait you are d4 right you are in Brazil
in my correcto I anyway so yeah let me
know if i'm correct
the magpie were you from and demo is
Percy oh I think so map folding problems
and combinatorial problems podium you
know and then we're gonna show you stuff
like he's okay mmm stuff like he's
something maybe then we're gonna show
you sake board okay let's begin Sal
keyboard keyboard we talked about many
times there's not much interesting so I
found this women thing this printer this
printer you know it lets you print
something instant mini smartphone
printer and this printer the whole
thing's size is about - looks like girls
are into that you know you go to Amazon
you look at the marketing photo it's
basically girls girls think girls style
girls they need the photos and then you
have this I discovered this portable
monitor the Magpies from Niagara neck
Nicaragua oh that's interesting
well knock knock Aurora where is that so
I discovered this horrible display so
let's go to Saudi keyboard
and I want to get down interesting stuff
so what so Alan says look at small AC
and women products you like what are
those so we go to so I'm very busy
walking but I'll be here as long as I
can
Oh busy walking oh my god poor drought
poor Douro
should have portable monitors like iPad
looks like they have it here but big
screen though why don't you enjoy a
tasty pasteries in your an uptown cafe
where you added a pastor eat tasty
pastor a single uptown cafe oh yeah so
we have this okay woman's printer how do
I know because I these are people bought
for my website I don't know who they are
I just got the information and you look
at the you see so you can see from the
marketing photos they are for women
because you know lipsticks and stuff so
you see you can look at this and you can
understand part of marketing you can see
that when they have a photo like that
they they want to attract women okay and
that is how also you know this product
is mostly for women women like it women
buy buy it and ok so print mod for mod
what is fun mod anyway I don't know I
don't know what it is so should have
portable computers like iPad well they
have you have mini mini portable
computers today they are pretty small
you know just a bit bigger than I I pad
so you have this printer I mean this
this display where apparently you
connect to your phone
let me show
there it is so you connect to your phone
like that and you have a giant screen so
you can watch movies I guess whatever
that is
those are so so okay you go there by it
okay so if you like it you go by it so
what um okay so what are we doing I feel
like I'm wasting time because I'm not I
don't have a topic now here yet and
hello but so what what do you say what
so magpie says being watching your
content for a while now it's quite
interesting fantastic join your
discourse over like a week ago great
fantastic so for those of you haven't
yet joined this code okay so so close
this so you go to my keyboard blog and
you can buy these things
kewal blog and they are quite a kind of
other interesting stuffs we kind of
talked about them before so not keyboard
today and this code here is the score
today's party Thank You Alan okay so I
need to I need to get on something
interesting so you know that is that's
why people come to watch hockey ah okay
let's talk about math then combinatorial
things domine oh okay now you guys know
what is a Tomino right of course you
guys know what is a Tomino but so let's
look at the poly amino now poly amino is
has many combinatorial problems in
mathematics this subject matter belongs
to discrete mathematics okay and this is
also recreational mathematics
recreational mathematics is a branch of
math where the subject matter are mostly
interested by amateurs that's one way to
put it in general their problem are very
interesting and easy to understand we'll
give you I'll give you an example in a
minute
so the problem is very interesting which
is usually visual and very easy to
understand but the solution
may not be so easy the solution you know
some of them takes mathematicians 100
200 years to find but however it's very
attractive
anyone can children can understand so
let me give you an example that is a
polio me know okay so a polio minnow is
a configuration that is created by a
combination of let's say five squares so
we are looking at polyominoes now so you
have five squares and you can create you
know you connect them side by side you
have various shapes so so in this case
you have five squares let's see one two
three one two three four five one two
three are five one two yeah so we how
many of them are total one two three
four five six seven eight nine nine
times through 18 so given five squares
you have 18 possible configurations
counting counting the mirror images and
rotation you know counting symmetry
given five squares
you have 18 possible configurations so
the question is given n squares how many
possible configurations are there so you
guys understand what I mean this is a
unsolved problem okay guys unsolved so
you're gonna solve it and you're named
you are going to be a Emoto
your name will be in dictionary and math
in history so here we are looking at an
example of polyomino with 1 2 3 4 5 6
squares and we can see there are these
many possibilities how many are there 1
2 3 4 5 6 7 1 2 3 4 5 5 times 7
35 so given 6 squares you have total
possible of 35 possibilities of
configuration so we have a function when
the input is 5
you have you have you have 18 when so
then and when the input is is 6 you the
upper is 36 okay so let's write it down
so start command log mod let me show you
my Emacs commands on the left window
okay and okay so we have F 5 equals to
18 and F 6 equals 235 fantastic you see
showing browser you see fi is is that 18
if F 6 is 35 the quite so what is f 7
what is F 8 now daddy that is up to you
to find out but but but are you here are
you are you like you know so here is a
problem that will make you famous
so you see wikipedia as it is very
informative they give you the functions
value so you can see F N 1 2 3 4 5 so FF
5 equals to 18 here that is we don't we
count also the mirror images and we also
count configurations where they have
hosts so you can see Oh a ok actually 12
so anyway so it gives you numbers here 5
is 12 6 is 35 7 is 100 0 8 so it says as
of 2004 I won Jensen has enumerated the
fixed polyominoes up to N equals 256 the
number of fixed polyominoes with 56
cells is approximately oh my god six
point nine one five times ten to the 31
power so that's basic
a number with 31 digits 32 digits
okay free polyominoes have been
enumerated up to n equals 228 so anyway
you see they give you some answers here
but this is a unsolved problem my
background my background is ID he said I
didn't graduate high school and then I
didn't go through high school basically
in Taiwan I have middle school I fell
off to graduate I graduate with a
certificate that says Casali attended
this middle school that's what I got
then he has I didn't go to high school
but I passed GED which is Americans
general education examination if you
pass that that means you have equivalent
of a high school degree then I went to
Community College for two years and I
didn't get any degree but supposedly
that's equivalent to a a degree
associate degree okay so that is that is
it of my formal education and in
community colleges I took all the math
classes including calculus one two three
four and differential equations and and
linear algebra and that's it no abstract
algebra no no nothing no complex numbers
and no analysis so I drop out that's
right
i'ma drop out just like Steve Jobs okay
so and I've never took any computer
programming classes everything I know I
learned on my own you know there is a
famous preface of a book you know
typically when you buy a book there's a
preface there's a dedication okay
dedication or preface or prologue anyway
so so they say you know the thing thanks
to my wife thanks
my colleagues know XYZ and thank you
thank you and usually then especially
academic books by professors they have a
bunch of thank yous like a tenth of
names thank you they need to thank you
people but however there is this guy who
wrote s si s H now I don't know if you
guys know but let me show you okay
should I show my website or should I
just go to general website let's not
show off okay let's just go to their
website not my website s see Sh
this thing skinny shell now as you know
as I get old and most people are younger
you don't know what it is anymore you
haven't heard of this but back then this
thing is big okay
shut up Wikipedia never donate to
Wikipedia okay I did a video on that a
few days ago so SCH SCH that is skin
this show and this show did let's go to
their website okay they don't even they
have a website still this way this show
is basically dead it's been dead for 10
plus years but how however back in 1990s
and early 2000s this is one of the very
popular thing because back then scheme
this is considered the most elegant
language are their skin okay scheme BIP
which is a part of least you know one of
the language in a family of this scheme
BIP so you have SC s H it's basically a
scheme implementation but as a shell so
you can you know like bash however I
don't think they have interactive show
you you know it's not anyways you have
schema okay so scheme Shia was very
popular in the 1990s it's a thing it's a
thing every hacker types talked about
especially among Emacs users you know so
on but it kind of you know nobody
anymore it's kind of been dead which is
in the general situation of scheme disp
and the lists in general so back then so
you have this scheme disp this scheme
shell is written by this guy or Lynch
CEO or Lynn shiva's which is a computer
scientist or Lynn shiva's okay
and I believe originally he is from MIT
let's see where he is now only she was
zoom room 3 1 8 College of computer and
information Sciences wvh okay Oh
Northeastern University so now he is in
Northeastern University Boston so is
this current let's see what what is he
teaching now please get lost you know he
he is a character you see he's a page
that says please get lost
what is his but anyway so the reason I'm
mentioning him and he's got pictures
let's see let's his let's see his great
face ok this handsome guy very handsome
however this picture must be 10 years
old I would say 20 probably 20 years old
so now he's much older
[Laughter]
ok so he's kind of you know a character
ok so and the reason I'm mentioning him
because in one of his book ok that is
the scheme share documentation so let's
go to it download visas resources
documentation let's see ok scheme share
menu is hypertext you know the skeeters
simcha manuals hypertext you know that
those that's the language back in the
days you co a web site hypertext HTML
[Laughter]
there it is guys read this okay this is
this is the mantra for hackers for for
you
nonconformist hackers all in Shiva's
Brian D Castro Martin Gatsby and Mike
spoke okay they wrote the scheme Shou
okay and you have acknowledgments let me
read it to you acknowledgments why
should I thank my so-called colleagues
who laugh at me behind my back
all the while becoming famous on my walk
my worthless graduate students whose
computer skills appear to be limited to
downloading bit maps of the net news my
parents who are still waiting for me to
quit fooling around with computers go to
med school and become a radiologist my
department chairman a manager who gives
one new insight into and sympathy for
disgruntled postal workers my god no one
could blame me no one if I went off the
edge and just lost it completely one day
I couldn't get through the day as it is
without the Prozac and Jack Daniels I
keep on myself on my shelf behind my top
20 J sys manuals okay I started getting
the shakes
real bad around 10:00 a.m. right before
my advisor meeting at 10:00 ten hours
jack and that Jack Daniels and Zac helps
me get through the meeting without one
of my students winding up with his
severed head in a pouting ball back they
look at me funny they think I treat a
lot I am NOT twitching I am controlling
my impulse to snack my nine millimeter
Sig Sauer out from my day pack and make
a few strong points about the quality of
undergraduate education in America
if I thought anyone cared if I thought
anyone would even be reading this I'd
probably make an effort to keep up
appearances until the last possible
moment but no one does and no one will
so I can pretty much say exactly what I
think
oh yes the acknowledgments I think not I
did it I did all by myself okay guys
okay so this is Olli she she she was
Cambridge Cambridge
that's Massachusetts right Cambridge
Massachusetts as I learned is these tiny
states very tiny where Richard Stallman
the coat bidder besides so here are
these in September 1994 so this is a
famous acknowledgement I did it all by
myself
okay so so I learned by myself oh my
gosh I forgot my internet deep hole of
Ernst report this is like Napa okay so
that's it that is interesting and that
is about scheme shell of so of those of
you millennial younglings those you
millennia younglings read and learn
something okay God s see SH scheme share
which is dead dead te ad dead okay of
you these phonetics scheme is dead
oh of those of you who are chanting
about Haskell about Julia about him
these type of people
beware scheme was considered by you guys
hacker type to be the most elegant
language on earth and for thirty years
forty years instead it's where is it
it's your tail recurs recursing on Mars
there there we have a scheme shel
okay that's scheme show and close close
close and scheme shel okay so that's
that's that so what what's the next
topic so let's talk about a
combinatorial thing we haven't finished
that so so you guys learned about these
combinatorial unsolved math problems
right keep that in mind okay remember
these because it is this is a unsolved
problem and I hope I articulated the
problem well now once you understand
this you can try to understand
poley amounts which is also unsolved I
think it's a variation so this in this
thing you arrange triangles and you try
to calm them okay so and do they have
like today say is it solved or not so
okay so the number of free polio amounts
with horse is given by that the number
of free polio amounts with our horse is
given by that the number of fixed polio
mounts is given by that the number of
one-sided polio mounts is given by that
Oh looks like it's all solved let's look
at them so apparently for the polio
mount the combinatorial problem of
arranging them for the total possible of
shapes looks like it's solved problem is
solved do they have a formula that is
the question this website is very old
okay this website is website design 1999
by this guy NJ a strong and yes I have
contact with him
in fact on this the online encyclopedia
of integer sequences I have a entry in
it
so let's see let's see if I can still
find it posted
oh ye is okay then it's such folk sorry
I have an entry in there there it is
wait okay there it is Oh II is a zero
zero one seven one zero let's see so
this sequence is this sequence is one
one one three twelve sixty three sixty
two thousand five hundred twenty then
two zero one six zero and so on and this
sequence our card this suicide is so
hard to read and it's just such fun my
name okay
sabi there it is sorry why is it not
linked God did we move the links so you
cannot even click it so anyway so let's
go to the side sorry
combinatorial loop in endpoints away
that's copy that link paste paste and go
to sock sorry info of course my website
has changed domain in the past 20 years
since this site this website the online
encyclopedia of integer sequences began
around 1997 or so something like that
okay so this website is very old and
this guy NJ is long is a mathematician
and you can see because this side is
work very oh these mathematicians
academics their website is the
formatting is basically 1999 so you know
very hard to read and so on anyway this
this encyclopedia of integer sequences
is is a huge reference it's basically
the reference for mathematicians for
professional mathematicians when you
want to find a sequence you can look
you know in this encyclopedia to see
what what kind of math object or process
generate that sequence so in this
particular sequence I happened to write
a page back in 1997 about the possible
ways to draw a line and pass through
endpoints for example if you have four
points you draw a line what are the
possible configurations so there's one
there's two there's three okay do I
count I guess I don't count rotational
symmetry anyway well I guess I do but I
don't know why you know this is written
like 23 years ago I have to read it in
detail know why I have this to repeat it
for example so anyway this is about the
possible loops with endpoints so when n
is 5 you have 1 2 3 4 12 possibilities
so when when n is 6 you have all these
possibilities why why am I doing this
problem because I was studying Pascal's
theorem okay
and by the way this is written in
Mathematica 20 years ago so Mathematica
it's fantastic ok so I was studying
Pascal's theory that's that's math ok
that's getting a bit more complicated I
have to spend five minutes to explain
this ok let me show you ok dad so this
is conic sections
that's the conic sections ellipses
parabola hyperbola and you have and they
are formed by a shadow of a bow you can
see you can do this at home turn off
your lights in midnight and take out of
a lamp and take out take out a ball and
you can see these shadows this is a lisp
that one this one is
this this one is hyperbola okay so you
have if the light is over here the red
dot you got aleast so if the light is
above the ball you got a lisp
if the light is below the ball like this
blue dot
you got a hyperbola if the light is on
the same plane as the top of the ball
you got a parabola okay that's how
fascinating are these math things math
curves aliefs hyperbola parabola so and
there are many theorems okay I'm not
going to go into I guess actually I
could go into that would be the topic of
the day so I had no idea there was
encyclopedia of online sequences yeah
that website is very big I mean well I
can but I can tell you are not in math
community so if you are a mathematician
and basically if you are any graduates
you know or undergraduate student you
study math you all know this this is the
basically the reference okay this is not
even I mean this is the reference for
for professional mathematicians even and
for amateur mathematicians like me
amateur and okay so what's our what our
a man talking so I'm talking about so
I'm talking about conic sections many
interesting properties then you have
then one of the theorem is projective
geometry okay this is gonna be fantastic
actually
if we're gonna start to talk about this
it's gonna be half an hour one hour but
anyway there is a social signals math
people in group indeed know well the the
math professors the real mathematicians
professors they wouldn't read they
wouldn't watch my video okay that that's
not the thing if I talk about that's not
their thing
I mean I'm not what I'm doing is
math education okay math education to
undergraduate students somewhat okay but
if you talk to mathematician they don't
that's this is not the type of not the
way they talk you gotta use all these
math jargons you you gotta okay so if
you are for example if you see the
mathematicians like professors lecture
or or meetings or conferences what you
hear is space ok spaces space space set
map linear map you know that sets are
you here you don't hear about this you
know one way to easily see the
mathematicians how they talk how they
write online you go to math overflow
okay for you programmers okay you you
know many of you programmers programmers
are generally entirely totally ignorant
of math like they did you know they
think trigonometry and calculus is math
no those are not math okay those are not
math that mathematicians are concerned
about mathematician is also anyway go to
stock stack of math overflow which is
part of stack overflow okay so we are
here you look at what are you talking
about that you have no idea okay the
stupid task our and get you know
graph and your things look at the attack
okay algebraic geometry number theory
fundamental functional analysis
combinatorics okay that programmers know
combinatorics because that's that's
recreational math algebraic topology
group theory I'm trying to get you guys
interested in interested in group theory
because that's very interesting you will
actually I did two videos on that you if
you look back my videos tutorial on
group Theory very interesting
differential geometry representation
Theory you know category Theory hug
probability any
so this website is supposed to be less
professional mathematicians okay so for
example for example let's look at this
one e equal variant Co homology of diffs
s 1 divided by s 1 and virus or oh okay
like you don't know what they talking
about I don't know what they talking
well I have some idea ok but that's
that's kind of typical mathematicians
just talk online questions you know and
we we do have a professional
mathematician in your group and his name
is Sid yesterday he posted a fantastic
lunch dinner at I showed yesterday he is
in Japan doing research on quantum
cryptology
so Sid okay so he is a professional
mathematician and you know he's got this
fantastic sushi dinner going on
yesterday so that that so anyway so
let's go back to conic sections so conic
sections there is a theorem called
Pascal's theorem that means ok Pascal's
theorem should I explain it or not -
Adrian so that is a method ok so
Pascal's theorem came from 1960s ok 19th
I mean 6 1616 40 when he was 16 when
this guy Pascal you know by the way you
know the programming language Pascal
that's named after him or his dad I
forgot which one he and his dad are both
mathematicians and Pascal the Blaise
Pascal guy so he was born in 1623 he is
a devout Christian okay devout
especially remember the time is 1600 so
and he's and and he's a devout God
believer and then he there's quite a lot
Louis interesting Louis Bob's you know
when you talk about math so when for
example he he I think he was it he
proved or something about the existence
of God something I forgot I have to look
I haven't been really in a math
community for 10 plus years anyway so he
Pascal's theorem at 16 he discovered
Pascal's theorem that means let me just
read it ok so Pascal's theorem it says
does okay let me just read it first the
six vertices of a hexagram lie on a
conic if and only if the points of
intersection of the three pairs of
opposite sites lie on one line okay you
you actually have to spend time to
understand that but let me explain what
it is okay so if you have a conic
section okay if you have a lisp it lifts
ellipse a lisp yeah if you have a lisp
or if you have a hyperbola or if you
have a parabola any of these okay in any
shape you this can be in any other shape
so given any any one of these shape a
conic section you can put random these
six points on on the curve okay so we
have a recipe or we can pick any random
six points one two three four five six
for example and in this example we can
put any random six points anywhere on a
curve okay anywhere even if they are
like this you see this hyperbola they
shoot to infinity so it could be very
far away so you put any six points
random points on the curve
then then the theorem says the theorem
says if you connect let's see how it
goes okay I have to think about this a
little bit how to because
one shoe okay so let's see what it says
okay so so right so you put six points
on a curve let's this focus on the least
for now and it also works on a circle so
you can do it on a circle as well
because circle is also it is so you you
draw six points on a circle you number
them the number you have to number them
so one two three four five six okay it
can be any order any order you want but
you do want to number them so it says it
says if you connect the opposite
connection of the three pairs of
opposite sides lie on the line so
right so this is a bit hard to explain
because basically what he's saying is
that if you connect these points then
these points will form intersections you
see this blue line these two blue lines
forms one intersection and this these
two green lines forms intersection and
these three red lines forms one
intersection the theorem says these
three intersections lies on a line
always always
doesn't matter what where is your point
if these points are on a conic section
and if they are not our conic section
this will not work in other words if you
have a situation situation like this
then you know those six points lies on a
conic section now to understand fully is
you you have to understand how the lines
are connected basically basically you
have six numbers one two three five six
one two three five six you want to
connect the opposite the opposite points
I think any way you read it you'll
figure it out okay you you want to
connect the the for example number one
to number three number two to number
five something like that you you can
figure out if you read it this and think
about it carefully oh yeah I have an
example here so so anyway so this
theorem is called Pascal's theorem and
and it's invented in 1640 by him when he
was 16 years old oh yeah so I know I
remember there's something interesting
Pascal's wager it indeed the Mac the Mac
tie knows Pascal's wager that's very
interesting okay so Pascal's wager is
that is the is on the question about
whether you should believe in God now
you can go to Wikipedia and I know it's
there I think I've read it 10 years ago
on Wikipedia but I learned these things
in 1990s before there's which
pedia how do you how do you learn back
then well you you read books and you
talk to other you know you read books
talk on the phone to mathematicians your
friends you know anyways and there's
also online forums of all math so
Pascal's wager is a wager it's like
gambling about whether you should
believe in God so for those of you you
know you don't know whether you should
believe in God here here is a Pascal's
wager that you know he he's got a
theorem that tells you which he has the
better outcome so here his theorem goes
that if God is exist then of course
you better believe him because you know
otherwise God is gonna punish you punish
you you know so if God exists you better
believe but however if God do not exist
you better believe too it's better to
believe for your for your good because
because there is the possibility that
God believes exist because if God
doesn't exist it doesn't matter you know
you're you believe in God is okay it
doesn't affect your daily life so it's
like free you know it's like something
you get something for free so if it if
God doesn't exist yeah you can still be
difficult believe in God no problem
nothing happens to you but in case he
does exists then but if you don't
believe God then you got a problem you
know you gotta be fun you're gonna be
punished
so the Pascal's wager says that the you
have a better outcome if you simply
believe okay
Pascal's wager let's see
Pascal's wager there it is now this is
how Pascal looks like and remember
Pascal is the programming language
Pascal is named after so Pascal's wager
is an argument in philosophy presented
by the 17th century French philosopher
mathematician and physicist plays past
Pascal it passes that humans bet with
their lives that God either exists or
does not pascal argues that a rational
person should live as though God exists
and seek to believe in God if God does
not actually exist such a person will
have only a finite loss some pressure
some luxury okay whereas he stand to
receive infinite gains was represented
by eternity in heaven and avoiding abode
infinite losses so anyway that's so that
there it is Pascal's wager okay so so
let's spit back to Pascal's wager there
we have it okay so let's close that and
we talked about conic sections okay
and why are we talking about conic
sections because and Pascal's theorem
because so anyway that is Pascal's
theorem and by the way there's a duo
there is a duo called Brian Coons
theorem because in project in projective
geometry every theorem has a dual so
here is a duo that means basically means
if you draw six points on conic random
points and you create tangent lines
passing those points and then you create
lines connecting the intersections and
they we are intersecting a point so this
is like the the dual or the opposite of
the Pascal's theorem basically it's one
same theorem because in projective
geometry
every theorem has a dual so anyway so
that that's about so this is about
Pascal's theorem now remember why try to
explain Pascal theorem I was you know
there's a problem about about how do you
connect the points like what what's the
proper order
that is when so I was studying this in
1997 so that is when I decided I want to
know how many possible ways to you know
to create a loop through endpoints so
that is why I wrote this program so with
so if you have five points you have 12
possibilities and if you have six points
you have these many possibilities and it
turns out this sequence this sequence we
have this sequence so it so one point
one possibility three points two points
three possibility three points twelve
possibility something like that okay so
you got a sequence then you know that is
why it showed up on this online
encyclopedia of integer sequences so you
know he just cites
he just cites my my dabbling and I'm
happy I'm happy
you know back then I was going to become
a mathematician oh well so anyway that's
so N and n J Sloan he's got stories okay
he's got stories I'm not sure anyway so
so anyway maybe that's it for today
Oh Paulie ami knows we were talking
about polyominoes and we have not
finished that yet so oh yeah so we were
trying to see if the polio mounts if
they are solved problem or not do they
say
hey you know this this side is a bit
hard to read you have to you know you
have to spend time to read them because
I cannot you know I cannot tell whether
it's totally completely solved or not
because by completely solved I mean
there is a formula for it well typically
they have recursive formulas okay that's
another interesting math topic so you
can usually you can create a sequence by
recurved recursive formula for example
the factorial of a number so if you know
what's the secret what's the number
before you can easily compute the next
number but however it's very difficult
to compute some number of far ahead
like if the input is 1,000 so that's
recursive formula but however some
formulas some sequences you can have
what's called closed form formula which
lets you compute a input directly
without doing recursion so my my my
question is I don't know so you have to
read this so it's kind of so anyway so
the online encyclopedia of integer
sequences they also have oticon
wikipedia you can read about it okay so
close that close close close close close
holy amounts okay polio months they form
a this these are about combinatorial
problem against a recreational math
problem okay and oh hello beautiful
people good morning to Prague Czech
Czech Republic so and so we have the
podium Ino which is also a soft problem
so these are combinatorial problems
that's what I'm talking about that's why
I mentioned them now the problem is not
just enumerate of the possible
figurations that's one of the problem
there are other problems for example you
you must have run into this puzzle okay
let me show you the puzzle so you go to
Saudi math of course sorry
math and today I'm going to read the
comments okay so okay so let me read the
comments okay you go to saw math so this
is my math blog and you go to great math
software so we have a list of great math
software separated by category then you
go to puzzles I used to love these
puzzles you know all these are basically
recreational math problems so in 1990s
what I was a big fan of recreational
math recreational mathematics you know
you study this solution to this by the
way recreational mathematics which is
which is usually discrete math okay so
in all the branches math you have in
general the algebra okay algebra then
you have analysis which is like calculus
then you have geometry that's a
traditional way to group math branches
these top three categories algebra
analysis geometry that's one of the
traditional way then you have a list
button so this is a classic you know so
so they do not for example all the you
know they do not include it you don't
see recreational math there's no X
special branch about recreational math
you don't even see combinatorics you
don't see in general you don't see graph
theory you don't see you don't see
things like you programmers are
interested okay let me tell you about
let me give you an example of why
when I say you know you got you know a
lot of programmers you know including
Haskell people you know they talk about
they idolize math they say oh Hess
coffee you know
category theory everyday or directed
graph graph theory that's okay so
to mathematicians is some almost
like those are fringe they don't did you
know it's like fringe that they don't
they don't study you know in general in
general I'm talking about in general
professional mathematicians they don't
study those kind of things those those
are kind of like fringe okay toy toy
those are toys okay
it's like how you program us we got
Visual Basic okay you know when you are
a programmer you know hacker type you
you talk about difficult things C C++
rust rust everyday rust rust rust this
and that and when someone says oh I
programming in Visual Basic you kind of
want to laugh at them okay in the in
math it's a similar situation the
mathematicians are busy about topology
analysis differential geometry algebra K
theory and song and and geometry okay
when you mentioned Oh company Horrocks
Oh graph theory oh you know the
especially the the elementary type you
know the in in anyway so or recreational
recreational math you know the math -
mathematicians professionals they don't
that's like fringe to them to some
degree okay I mean that's how they
regard it but anyway but it doesn't mean
by the way it doesn't mean these are
trivial problems it's not trivial okay
you know many great many greatest
mathematicians spend their life studying
this recreation of math things the
reason they are kind of fringe to
mathematicians is because it's kind of
because society is how it just how
things work just like why do programmers
why do you guys sneer at visual visual
basic you know why do you guys sneer at
you know Visual Studio code users what
do you do that
he's just it just kind of its kind of
the I was a phenomenon of social
struggle because when you are
professional method when you are a
professional programmer you want to you
kind of want to promote things that are
difficult and you want to laugh at you
know those kind of things that makes you
know something something for dummies you
know learn something for dummies in one
week learn something one week you you
kind of want to laugh at them because as
a professional programmer you want your
topic to be grand you know that's why
that that is why you usually laugh at
you know like for example these ten
years ago the JavaScript coders the PHP
code us you know the visual basic coders
you laugh at them you know you sneer
them in the same way in mathematics the
analysis differential you know the
analysis differential geometry you know
in geometry and the algebra those those
are hard things you have to spend years
to just start to learn things as opposed
to this recreational math or discrete
math kind of things these kind of things
are easy you know any child can begin to
understand okay
so these kind of things are easy so
these mathematicians they don't you know
that's not that's not things they like
to promote this is why okay that is my
explain explanation why mathematicians
in general the profession wise they
don't we don't you know don't regard
this as as you know they don't they
don't they don't you know it's not it's
it's not like they think it's trivial
but rather they just they don't promote
it that's the thing just like how
programmers ignore or you know laugh at
easy programming stuff so anyway
recreational geometry creation or math
so recreational math is part of this
grid math okay
discrete mathematics and in general the
discrete math is what you programmers
are interested mostly most of the time
and so one of the recreational math is
this thing this okay the Penta mint
Pinto Minos puzzle so basically you are
given a bunch of you know pen dominoes
and you want to arrange them so that
they feel a square so that is a problem
and here's the software you can try this
is written by a friend who I worked a
bit with you know four fold so so this
program tries to solve the pentomino
problem so let's see when okay you can
see it runs in real time it used brute
force
I think brute-force algorithm to try to
solve this problem so why am i showing
this because this is one example of
combinatorial problem okay so
combinatorial problem we talked about
you know it's not just in numerator but
this is another example and by the way
when I was in the 1990s I bought a bunch
of these puzzles like physical puzzles
you can let's see if we can find it I
bought a bunch of them I bought a lot of
them I spend you know a few hundred
dollars on these toys you can still buy
today on Amazon but I'm trying to find
it they are like that okay yeah kind of
like that but this one they try to make
it into animal shape that's not so good
okay and here you have a three
dimensional version of a puzzle and
here's someone trying to solve it or
something like that you know things I
bought this okay things like this you
buy this and you try to put them
together and this is great for a
Christmas gift so you guys inspired
on my website okay let's see if we can
find it on my website I think that's
about it
and let me read the comments let's see
what I also I want to talk about polio
me know puzzle okay so they got a bunch
by the way this book George Martin who
wrote is George Martin I've seen this
book okay in this book this book is what
polyominoes moding Japanese edition wait
I want to I don't want books I want the
puzzles anyway you yeah here so
passwords okay so no crosswords are no
good I hate crossword course crosswords
is the worst game possible crosswords so
Allen says topic to what extent can
people choose what they believe in can
you choose to believe or just leave on
those assumptions that something is true
like what do you mean I guess depends on
what what is the thing we're talking
about again I choose to believe can I
choose to believe people do not exist
well in practice no because otherwise I
will be insane but can I choose to
believe that God doesn't exist in
practice yes because a lot of people are
atheist you just live and die it works
fine can I choose to believe you know
like what would you mean exactly what
like what kind of things you can choose
or not to choose to believe okay so
Allen says Allen says there is no need
to believe in integers but you can
assume integers of reason about them oh
well that big
comes philosopher philosophical then
because what do you mean by believe and
see how your model of them maps to
reality
yeah dad yeah I guess yeah you also your
question is like philosophy and in fact
it's about is kind of useless philosophy
okay that's your I think those kind of
topic becomes you know mind and matter
problems or the problem of the mind you
know that's classical philosophy you can
talk you know like the question of
freewheel you know what do you mean by
believe like in philosophy they will
they actually talk about what does
believe means you know they they have a
book on that what does believe means you
know that's usually used that those are
the kind of uses philosophy and those
are kind of philosophy when people think
about philosophy like when people wish
you will consider philosophy useless and
when they think of that because because
those kind of things you know that you
know that's why they think is philosophy
but actually ferocity is fundamental
what right now every one of you whatever
you think doesn't matter you are Asian
white people black people the every
thought is influenced by philosophy of
your culture you know you know for
example in general why do a cm people
Japanese for example you guys seen or
the Japanese websites right
they have different different ethics
about sex you know different ethics
about you know there are anime always
girls with panties showing querying
America that's like no you cannot do
that you know but in Japan it's
everywhere everywhere you know it's like
everywhere you can you gang everywhere
so and Japan have weird you know Japan
they have different culture and in u.s.
you have your culture this is quite
different okay and why I can tell you
why philosophy philosophy shapes your
entire culture the culture the cultural
difference is the major part is
philosophy because
why why white people think different
than Japanese people because white
people they grew up in Western
philosophy Greeks you go you know it's
like it's it's it's not something you
can actually pinpoint but that's the
thing so so don't say don't say
philosophy is only important okay that's
idiot that's idiocy poor granham
actually said that program is idiot in
that regard in fact I have article and
also by the way recently we talked about
the guy Marc tava who created the Qi
language the chilies and the Shen
language Shen disp marked hava
a very weird guy who is a monk lives in
you know in India some he's a certified
monk like he's a like a certificate he's
actually a monk you know of certain
Buddhism I don't know what so he's very
weird so he created Shen language and
and you guys have read some of his
articles and so he he also criticized
program you know this program God you
know the the program celebrity okay why
I attack him not attack okay why I
criticize because why do I call him my
idiot idiot because it's not because
he's a really easy at big but because
once you become a celebrity he's you
know I he's very smart okay intelligent
and great worked great programmer very
smart and also helps has the ability to
start a company and very rich as well so
of course he's far better than me in in
lots of regards but however I call him
an idiot because once you become a
celebrity every fat becomes Gordon like
spread by every idiots the programmers
okay all the hacker types and also he
proclaims oh heck er hacker is like a
painter if you not a painter you are not
a hacker something like that yeah you
know anyway he will wrote a book you
know hackers and painters and over China
or the Chinese people are like idolize
the book you
because Oh programs at least God wrote
it we must meet it
it's idiocy and so he has a lot essays
on his website you know program and one
of the one of essay is about you know he
is claiming philosophy or logic is
useless
okay let's search for poor granham okay
I have a article on that and I must
mention mock Taba concurs okay so here's
article program in program hams
infatuation with the concept of hacker
you know program ham this guy he's got
the he's a hacker type okay he's got a
need to invoke hacker everything is
about hacker hacker this hacker dad oh
you must have company that's made of
hackers otherwise your company won't
succeed that's for God you must have a
programming language the person the best
programming language is the one that
hacker likes that is from poor granham
he create arc language uglies which is
dead and by the way three months ago he
created another article about a new Lisp
which I seen zero value at all
so anyway program because he's white you
well because he's famous like Kim
Kardashian Kim Kardashian among the
girls everything every day the King
capaci em you know they wear some bikini
then all the girls went crazy
same thing with program he just fought
anything then all the idiot followers
medians literally you will go o
program say this that that okay anyway
wait by the way I and I know you
mentioned you mentioned programs recent
article about geniuses you know like
what makes up genius I haven't read that
I skimmed it it could be interesting
no I am just criticizing some some of it
because he's celebrity okay not
I mean I mean you know but he I'm pretty
sure he's you know very smart and you
know these not he's good so anyway
philosophy and program okay that's
another article philosophy
what's philosophy and program ham
Chile's create a mock tava on is
philosophy useful so so program ham one
day he he is found found of writing
essays so one day he were essay that
says is philosophy useful and in my
opinion that essay is idiotic he
basically he concludes philosophy he's
not use he's like you don't know what
he's talking about so I disagree and
mark tava also disagrees okay so that's
some anecdote any Anna Anna any thought
of the programmers law that is the
proper way to put it of what I just
talked about and a a a n ec do t did I
spell it correctly and AG dot yeah
that's right
an anecdote is a brief revealing account
of an individual person or an incident
yeah so I'm giving a anecdote of a of
the hacker law regarding Paul Graham and
his essays hackers in Pentos and hackers
and stuff okay let's copy that and
that's I think that's it for today let's
post the articles here so we need to
post it oh there's another problem
combinatorial problem so let's do that
so that's we since we are talking about
mathematics let's do that okay but
before we do that let me finish posting
my essays
close that close that puzzles okay
polyomino puzzles you can go by I'm
gonna go by polio Nino puzzles on Amazon
I'm gonna put put a link later
so and this puzzle is interesting and
you can find all of them on my sock wait
great math puzzles page and you can buy
this and so christmas is coming so you
guys is you know it's time to buy gifts
for your loved ones and your coworkers
ok and so i have a collection of great
math books and this puzzle by the way
this puzzle is fascinating this this
puzzle is part of the logic puzzle ok
which is the same class as this one but
this one this one by the way the name of
this puzzle is called 15 puzzle and so
there is an entire category of this type
of puzzles ok but the 15 puzzle is
trivial I mean it's really easy but this
one is quite fascinating okay so it's
called cross cross peak it goes by
several names actually if you go to
Wikipedia you can find huge amount of
details and history of this puzzle have
you guys played it let me ask you guys
have you guys played the have you guys
seen the cross key puzzle in fact there
are JavaScript versions I'm pretty sure
you know because back in 1990s I go to
the library
I read all kind of books all these books
that that is a you know there are books
that that you know this is before the
internet era so there's no internet net
so what do you want to do what do you do
if you want to know all the puzzles in
history you go to the library there are
books about like all the puzzles in
history you know
or focus on in one country or things
like that so I read you know I borrowed
quite a few of those books and lucre
looked up their names and stuff so you
have puzzles and you have games for
example you for example you guys must
have heard of Chinese checkers this
thing Chinese checkers you can go they
are by okay let me just paste the link
here okay I messed you um so how long
have I been talking so oh my god 1 hour
and 40 minutes 14 minutes time to
stop okay I think that's it then okay so
let me copy that let me copy what I have
talked about so I need anything else so
copy that and copy Pascal's theorem okay
actually we already did and stack
overflow okay stack overflow is a good
place to look at what mathematicians are
talking about you go there you know you
look if you look at some of them then
you get idea what what the math real
mathematicians professional
mathematicians they are talking about
then you go back to your programmers
fascination about category theory you
can see it's crap okay you promise
because you are in this well you are in
this where you don't and you don't know
what is actually the real math yeah but
you think you think Oh category theory
is the foundation of math it's gonna
solve all things oh because I saw movies
um oh because this is a crap okay okay
and this website I showed okay so
Internet you know online encyclopedia of
online sequences that's great okay
that's it for today and magpie says so
do you ever talk with people on this
code I see a voice channel but I don't
reckon ever seeing anyone on there no
we've been there a few times just on the
you know you can
start one like you if you just if you
feel like chatting you go to the voice
Channel and you say hey I'm gonna be in
voice Channel who wants to talk about
you know something whatever you know so
right now for example I mean voice
Channel living actually closed down that
so there are some people I've talked to
Emily I've talked to hello beautiful
people in fact had a beautiful people
here he did start here quite a few times
he started a conversation like someone
has to start it because if you don't
everyone is like oh you know they are
not going to begin a voice because for a
lot of programmers you feel you nervous
about going on voice things like that so
someone has to say you know like hello
beautiful people did a few times you
know you you say hey I'm gonna be a
voice Channel in its chat or something
or some topic or something so so I
talked to quite a few people they are
you guys okay hello beautiful people and
Emily and Alan and Reaper and and this
morning I talked to this guy DXL he's
from well he's from Scandinavia okay
which is amazing Scandinavia yeah okay
so that's it for today thank you guys
for watching bye
oh yeah so then actually let me see a
few more comments so bar says every
every form of knowledge roots in
philosophy you could say that if culture
is based on philosophy then Japanese for
us so forth then Japanese philosophy
must be much superior to Western
philosophy so why do you prefer idiotic
Western philosophy over Japanese nuts I
you know the culture is not wholly based
on philosophy well yeah you can you
could say it's based on philosophy he's
not but philosophy does not make up the
entire culture in other words culture is
is not
how they say that the constitute you
know the culture is not just philosophy
okay it's kind of some it's a major part
of it is is philosophy then you say okay
so then the Japanese for us we must be
much superior to Western no not really
in my opinion they are kind of different
ways to look at things for example you
look at things Western philosophy let me
give you a summary okay Western
philosophy tends to be logical precise
you know everything must be logic like
for example you know we when we argue
okay what's your reason you know logic
oh you you have this falsity because you
you know young people they just studied
logic they have you know they have a
bunch of jargons that's that means that
leads to for example one of those jargon
is strowman strowman is one of the
fallacy okay fallacy oh these are voice
Western tradition when you argue tends
to very go by precision by logic for
example Jordan Peterson the great
intellectual of our time Jordan Peterson
today he is you know one of his 12 rules
for for for for a good life or something
is like you must learn to articulate
well and 3p precise like him you know
articulate well like him that like the
way he does because he happens to be the
one biggest great guy in articulation
and precision of words
Jordan Pederson guys so he's a great
intellect lecture of our time but he's a
white guy white guy Western philosophy
he's missing the eastern part of it okay
so anyway Western philosophy logic and
precision is is a great part of it and
then you also have justice justice
freedom of speech or individual the
concept of freedom in general justice
freedom and rate okay that is in fact of
one of the core
Western philosophy for example the
seduction of Europa that it that is how
Europe is named you know we I did a
video on that for one hour few months
ago about you know Europa how is Europe
named because the Greek mythology the
seduction of Europe Europa Europe Europe
is a beautiful girl and one day the god
Zeus the Oh omnipotence yours just
grabbed her by becoming a white boy
white beautiful boy look at Europe had
on his bag and just right off so I
talked about that a few months ago so so
that's Western philosophy ok Greek
mythology just is the concept but just
just is freedom and and democracy part
of it okay and you know the in position
and all that now when it comes through
Eastern philosophy you don't have that
okay none none of that none of that
you have Taoism you have a young you
have in young you have Taoism you have
everything is wish she wasn't you
everything is the first okay is the
first it's not logic okay it's it is not
logical it's not it's not the Western
logical it's not precision no precision
in fact everything is firstly was he
think that is that is the art of that is
the kind of that that that is the nature
of Eastern philosophy when we talk about
is mostly I'm talking about Chinese
philosophy because Chinese basically
well I'm Chinese in China based
basically China spread that influence
Japan Koreans and South Asia so Eastern
philosophy okay Taoism Taoism and
Buddhism and Confucianism okay so you
it's kind of fuzzy you go look up you
can't study so it's kind of so that is
why you have like Taoism daodejing
and eating you know book of change and
basically you don't encounter logic or
logical arguments you know things like
that but however I know because
the logic kind of style or the the
philosophy of logic they did exist in
China around year 300 or something
during the warring era there's a era
called warring era okay you look up
Wikipedia Chinese history warring era so
at that time during that time there is
actually one branch one philosophy okay
inch in China that is that is basically
just like the Western philosophy they
focused on logic and linguistics they
analyzed the meaning okay just just like
the you know Western philosophy but
that's cool never that's good is that he
kind of disappeared
that school is got more mogea wait
actually that's interesting let me write
it out so today's topic and we don't
have time to talk about classics off
like he's remove that so I'm talking
about summary of eastern of Western
philosophy and Eastern philosophy okay
and and I'm coming
and then I'm talking about the arrangin
okay the the history of logic or largest
ISM in China that is called more yeah
okay so that means in Chinese it's let
me write it in English first okay so
it's called mope ISM M OPP is M okay I
think I spelled it correctly I hope no
it's not right I have to type in Chinese
okay so let me type in Chinese so let's
switch because one sign I find the
Chinese I can type the I can find the
English okay wait
there it is okay let me copy that so you
guys actually can look up so we have
that word here so now we look up the web
there it is nope this is mope ISM this
school this school of thought is called
mop ISM and let me show you the English
version okay there I'm missing a H
mohism mohism that is a word okay let me
paste it here so that's today's topic we
talked about so what I'm a-saying I'm
saying I'm saying that the mo mohism
is the origin of the logic and precision
school of thought just like Western
philosophy in China and that happened
around 470 BC so this is this is two
hundred two thousand five hundred years
ago in China mohism okay you can read
Wikipedia in detail and this school of
thought
yeah they focus on logic pretty much
like Western philosophy but but this
school did not dominate after the world
roie's period after you know 100 years
or to this school kind of died out so
the that the Confucianism and legalism
and kind of took over so they so in
general Chinese in China they don't
anyway that that's a bit history of that
more she got more yes
okay that's it so so I do not think
Eastern philosophy is better than
Western they are just like different
philosophy you know how you regard the
universe how you regard the question the
ultimate question of what we are why are
we here
you know if you go by Western philosophy
you don't have answers because you could
go to quantum mechanics and you still
don't have answers you know you don't
know you can in fact you cannot you to
this day you don't know you whether God
exists
you have arguments you have great
varieties of arguments but nobody can
say a thing for sure that's Western
philosophy
now Eastern philosophy regarding the
ultimate questions like where are we
here
you know well they they don't have
precise answers they don't seek precise
answers neither okay today you have Ian
Young you have kind of illogical first
scene is philosophy okay you know
different approaches and today I do not
you know I kind of like the Western Way
because when I was young I always
disliked I always hated the eastern
philosophy precisely because they are
fussy I don't like you know like you
don't know what you're talking about
exactly you is open to interpretations I
like I instead I like I'm in love with
the Greek mythology and the Western
philosophy okay precision and all that
logic but now I'm old and you know since
10 years ago I I don't see it that way
anymore so it's just different
philosophies and in fact western
philosophies we got today's problems you
got lots of problems today like the you
know let's not get into like today's
problems okay that's it that's it for vo
bye guys have a good day
and I probably missed questions but but
that there'll be it