Hello everyone. Welcome to another
episode of cell talk show.
Let me heat up my tea and I'll be right
here. So today we are going to
introduction to F sharp programming
language.
Okay, let me
microwave my tea.
Be back in 1 minute.
If you are watching this offline, skip
around and play at 1.5 speed because I
ramble all over.
If you are watching live, say hi. Post
your comment. Hello Louis.
Fantastic topic.
F sharp, okay? Let's begin. So my
keyboard is Glove 80. Fantastic
ergonomic keyboard.
Ultimate hacking keyboard.
No liar track ball.
And this fantastic small board S V A L B
O A R D.
I have a video review for each one of
them on YouTube, okay? So now let's go
to F sharp. So if you don't know yet,
F sharp is the programming language that
is derived from OCaml.
Okay, so let me uh
make clear the lineage, okay? ML is meta
language. Then it became then then
there's a variation SML.
Okay.
For standing for
standard meta language. Then there is
Camel
standing for something something. Then
there is
object
Camel. Okay, so
So that is a lineage. Then there is F
Sharp.
Okay, that is the lineage of the
F Sharp programming language. They are
functional.
Uh very much functional programming
language. So Haskell
is sometimes after OCaml. So Haskell is
very much similar, very very much
similar, but somewhat different. So
Haskell is after OCaml. Now OCaml did I
spell it correctly.
Um
you know
OCaml came from, you know, Camel. So
they added an object. So but how what is
the So you see OCaml is objective Camel.
So this is
uh CAML.
Now what does Camel stand for? Category
something. Okay.
So
categorical abstract machine language.
Okay.
So that's a lineage. So F Sharp began
around 2002. Amazing because, you know,
functional programming is not popular,
but Microsoft
created
uh
you know, like this is So this is the
first
mega corporation sponsored
uh uh,
functional language
.net, okay, like
in fact, F# is uh,
based off .net. So, .net is entirely
open source since about 5 years ago,
something.
So, it's fantastic. Now, you want to
install it, it's
uh, trivial, you know, like in fact, I
installed it by accident
because
so, you can look at my PowerShell
tutorial because I was studying, you
know, I was looking up some
documentation of PowerShell functions, I
think. Now, PowerShell is also based on
.net. .net is this programming language
framework. So, you have .net, then you
have C#, you have F#, you have
PowerShell,
and you have .net Visual Basic, .net
Basic, something.
So, in fact, also Clojure one time was
implemented on
implemented on .net. So, .net is like is
like Java's JVM, so you can implement a
lot languages
on top of it.
It's got its own virtual machine, you
know, cross-platform.
So, and it's open source.
Uh, so, one day
like half a year ago, I was looking at
the PowerShell dot uh, PowerShell uh,
documentation. And then I run into some,
you know, sometimes it has to reference
.net stuff because in PowerShell or C#
or
F#, you can call any of the .net
functions. So, it's entirely super
powerful.
So, I was reading documentation and then
and I I click click, you know, run to
.net and then then I see a download of
F# here, you know, because it's it's
related. Then I click download, install.
So, in 3 minutes, I installed F sharp.
And I try to run it, it run.
This is in contrast to
you know, OCaml, you know, OCaml I try
to install on Windows. Took, you know,
took took me an hour. Like you you have
to install this first of all, which
which runs your machine, 86 or 386,
whatever, babbling. You know, then you
you don't know which one. Then you after
you found one, then oh, but by the way,
if you are doing this, this, you have to
get that from you have to run this, you
know, that [ __ ] [ __ ] up.
That's a typical open source.
Similar is the story for Haskell. Okay,
I tried to learn Haskell for like for
for 10 years since 1990s.
But it never went anywhere. But F sharp
is amazing. F sharp, okay? So, you you
want to install just just search for
install F sharp. You'll install it in 3
minutes, okay?
And then the documentation, oh my god,
the documentation is amazing. First of
all, let me show you running uh
um
uh running F sharp, okay? So, this is my
learning notes. So,
So, copy and paste, run, okay? So,
search for print. So, for example,
print first F sharp. Run it in Emacs.
Fantastic, successful.
Welcome .NET 8.
Uh and where is my output? What is this?
First F sharp.
So,
this is the output.
Okay, close it. Now, let's say print
three.
Hello, love.
Run it.
You see,
when you run the first time, it prints a
bunch of other stuff, copyright or
whatever version. Then then now you just
get it, okay? Now, if I can run this,
okay, I'm going to do that. So, anyway,
so this here is um OCaml, okay? Syntax
color it showing browser.
Fantastic.
So, you get If you want to run this in
command line, then then it's dot net fsi
then um
then the file name.
Okay, so that's kind of the introduction
to F sharp.
Uh it's fantastic. Oh, yeah, the
documentation. The documentation
of F sharp is beautiful, okay? You can
learn it in like you know in
in an hour, in a few days.
So, you know, so everything is
professionally written and clear.
You know, so fantastic. Now, again, in
contrast to the Haskell [ __ ]
or the OCaml [ __ ] this open source.
You know, I love them. I I'm obsessed
about them like since like 20 years ago.
But you try to read their documentation
like
extremely lousy.
Extreme, like to the extreme. Okay, you
know, let me show you some of my old
articles about it.
So, as a
proof
of what I said what I said is true. You
know, so there are few articles. Let me
just randomly show them.
Um
Okay, Haskell basic. There it is,
Haskell basics, you see? So, I started
to actually try to write a tutorial for
Haskell in 2009. So, you can see or see
some vestige of my like defunct
tutorial, 2006.
This began in 2006. You know, I started
to learn Haskell.
Uh in fact, I deleted I think I deleted
most of the, you know, like
You know,
it's this is abandoned project. So, 2000
2005, you see. 2005, you read the
documentation, it's like they got a
bunch of academic documentation written
by professors.
You know, the first chapter is going to
tell you mathematics something
something. Then, the first program you
have to write, "Oh, let's write a
derivative."
Who the [ __ ] do does a derivative?
That's what they do.
You know, for for 20 for 30 years, it
has has Haskell begin began in 1980s, I
think. Okay? Haskell
in in competent incompetent [ __ ]
So, this is the proof that, you know, I
started to learn Haskell in 2005.
And in the 1990s, you know, because I I
began my programming career in 1990s.
And you have like functional programming
frequently asked questions.
They tell you about Haskell, OCaml, ML,
and a quite a few. And a Clean, there's
a language called Clean. There's a
Miranda. Okay? These are the like
popular names back then.
Uh okay, so then let me go one by one.
So, um
So, let's go to talk show again. So, let
me just mention some of the names.
Miranda
Clean
functional programming language, okay?
Let's search it so you can see Clean.
There it is. Clean programming language.
This was in the '90s. This is a It It
was a commercial programming language,
commercial. Then, I think in 2010 or
something, they
released in 2000 um
you know, they released in open source
because the open source virus, you know,
you can't survive if you are not open
source.
So, that So, there is a clean
programming language and Miranda. So,
let's search for You see, they are You
see, influenced by Miranda.
Uh you see, so if you are in a
functional programming community, you
kind of know all these because they are
all
you know, neighbors and
brothers and sisters. So, there's
Miranda, there's SASL, very
familiar name, and Hope.
So, Miranda is another commercial um
functional programming language. You
see, started in 1985.
Okay. Copy the file name.
In fact,
I'm not going to you know, I don't want
to link to Wikipedia these days because
Wikipedia become very corrupt. However,
for technical stuff, Wikipedia can still
be trusted.
So, you see, Miranda. Anyway, so you
know, many old programming language,
functional programming languages. They
are They are all kind of related, just
like C, C++,
C#, Java. They are kind of the same
bunch. You know, doing one thing, you
have similar thing in another.
So,
that's similarly in functional
programming community. So, there is my
Haskell, you know, backing. So, one
thing worth mentioning
uh
this you know, my tutorial is not worth
reading. I mean, there's nothing, you
know, there's only two pages.
But, one thing
uh is interesting is that I created a
um
uh
I created a Haskell logo.
I thought I deleted this page, but I
guess okay. So,
where is it? Yeah, Haskell logo. So,
back in 2005, I created this
this web badge.
Uh back then web badge is somewhat
popular. You can put on your website,
you know, kind of a logo. This website
is made by Java. You know, this this
this website is made by something. This
website is W3 standard approved, you
know, like a bunch of badges.
So, I created um the Haskell logo.
Uh that's very interesting because then
you see the Haskell logo history. This
is Yale Haskell project. This is dead
since 1999.
You got this bullfrog, very interesting.
Then this this is Hugs 98.
Uh this is
this is one of the original Haskell
logo, 2002.
Then in 2003, they improved it upgrade.
So, it becomes like that. You got this
bunch of symbols. I'm I was still am
obsessive I'm fascinated with this
symbology. As you know, I talked about
Unicode. I have a lot of work on Unicode
and math symbols. So, what does this
each one of these represent?
So, I asked the arrow the So, I asked
people. So, actually people
uh in newsgroup, they helped me. They
they told me.
So, the at the right arrow represents
signifies signifies transformation.
The upside down A is
for all.
The double
greater than sign is free from disorder.
Free from disorder.
The doubles
colon means exactitude.
The double arrow means generality.
The lambda means functionality. By the
way, this is kind of a poem I wrote.
I mean, that's not exactly. I mean, I'm
adding a little bit.
Florid this florid description.
That's my alarm clock telling me I need
to get up and walk.
Okay, let me get my tea.
So fantastic Haskell.
Uh you know, so in 2008, about 2007,
2008,
Haskell became somewhat very popular
uh
because that's the era when CPU becomes
multi CPU, you know, multi core
because CPU don't get any faster
anymore. So, around 2008
Haskell suddenly became very
popular used by Facebook and other
corporations. So, these days today if
you do a pure if you code in pure
functional programming languages
you can find a job, okay?
So, they are used by
by by Facebook and and elsewhere.
Is Coke?
Hello German, Wolfram language
programmer.
Hello Michael.
Hi, are you teaching the fun funda
fundamental of functional programming?
No, not really.
But I can do that, you know, that would
be a fun topic. I can do that, but I
wasn't doing I'm not doing that today.
I'm just rambling. I mean, talking about
like functional programming introduction
to F sharp.
F sharp beautiful documentation easy to
understand
you know, language guide literals, you
know, F sharp literals and strings, you
know,
easy to understand. So,
I recommend F sharp.
Now, if you are on Linux, you have a few
choices. You can go with Haskell or
OCaml, okay? OCaml is very good.
And by the way, OCaml also came to
JavaScript. So, there is JavaScript
version of OCaml. So, let me let me let
me
go through my topics one by one, okay?
No rush. Uh
ML script and
So, Facebook, the mega corporation by
the Zuckerberg
scum
the corporation created they they moved
the they created a JavaScript version of
the meta language.
OCaml, okay? So,
so let me try to find the name.
Um
JavaScript type TypeScript, so it would
be much better than TypeScript.
TypeScript is [ __ ]
TypeScript, you know, uh TypeScript is a
superset of JavaScript where they add
you know, like strict types and type
inference to JavaScript. But, however,
it's strictly a superset. So, when you
write JavaScript, whatever JavaScript,
it is also TypeScript because it's
exactly, you know, TypeScript is exactly
a superset.
So, by grafting type system into
JavaScript
that makes it very lousy because
JavaScript the syntax is already [ __ ]
Then you then now you have to add types
to that [ __ ] syntax. So, it becomes more
[ __ ]
Nothing they can do because if you
create a new language, then people is
not going to learn.
That's the major factor for popularity
of language. That is why C++ is so
popular because C was popular. And the
C++ [ __ ] he's thinking, "Oh, I'll
just add a little thing to C.
Then everyone will love it because they
already know it. You know, people don't
want to learn new things like new way.
They don't They know They don't care.
They They They just care, "Oh, I already
know this. I can make money."
You know, that's how C++ became popular.
Uh scum tactics. Lots of the things in
uh software industry is uh scum tactics
scum tactics. Somewhat, okay? Not
exactly. The I I don't think the C++ guy
is a bad guy. His name is um you know,
some uh
hard to pronounce, you know, so I don't
think he's a
bad guy, but however
the way he created C++ and promoted
I don't like it.
You know, it's like [ __ ] Like let's add
a [ __ ] layer on top of another [ __ ] C.
That's what C++ is.
So,
TypeScript, you know, Types Oh, by the
way, the the guy who created TypeScript,
that's one of the great genius, okay?
I respect
the guy who created uh TypeScript from
Microsoft.
By his name is Andy something.
Coke and tea.
Where does it Can you even find the
name? Yeah, God.
Uh so
Okay, let me go through them one by one,
not missing a beat, okay?
Um
O'Caml in JavaScript, let's find what
that uh name is.
Um
JS of O'Caml, no.
Uh
okay, I can find it. Hold on a second.
Uh where is it?
Okay, so hold on a second.
Anders Hejlsberg, yes, that's the guy.
Thank you.
Um
Hold on a second. So, let me I
determined to find it on my blog because
the web is chaotic, so usually if I have
something written down,
I can find it on my blog
and I remember where it is. So, here's a
bunch of languages and uh
um
So, I just have to remember what was the
the article title.
Uh that all the history of this
um
There, proliferation of programming
languages, okay?
So,
Okay, so you got a Lisp, new Lisp, Arc
Lisp, Chi Lisp, Shen Lisp, Closure Lisp,
Scheme Lisp.
You got six SICP
Structure and Interpretation of
Computer Programs, and you got this
lambda in a school.
You got Dylan Dylan Lisp dead from
Apple. You got Meta Language. Then you
got Oh, by the way, so I also wrote a
OCaml tutorial back in 2009.
So, this is I went much further than the
Haskell. You know, so I I actually
learned learned something.
So, you got OCaml, list,
you know, list, array, tuple, record
type, function, pattern matching, uh you
know, types in OCaml. By the way, so my
OCaml tutorial is not worth reading
today.
You know, so it's not good. So, you
actually you can learn
a lot just by asking AI AI chatbot, you
know, just ask Google like,
you know, so
So, I started So, I didn't finish you
know, OCaml tutorial. So, let me make a
copy. So, why not?
And where is my Haskell?
Haskell logo, copy.
Uh I'm going to go over each of these,
okay? So,
So, Haskell logo, great. Um so, now we
want to find the name of that
programming language, which is OCaml,
but in JavaScript syntax from Facebook.
Okay, so you got F sharp, you got
Haskell, you got PHP, you got you know,
Scala,
Groovy, you got a bunch JavaScript,
PowerShell, TCL, very popular popular in
year 2000s. Lua became popular in year
2020.
Linden Scripting Language was massive
number of users back then.
Uh so, what is the uh yeah, so you go
down then Pure is a
uh term rewriting system.
They used to have a um
they used to have a Wikipedia entry, but
it got deleted.
You know, sometimes Wikipedia delete um
entries. Factor, so a bunch of
programming language Go, 2009,
a kind of revolution because Go is a
language that introduced automatic
formatting.
Go format, that revolution
revolutionized the
the programming coding style, [ __ ]
Okay, because now you don't
you know, you don't indent one by line
one line by line, okay? So, and Rust
Rust with you know, okay. Rust is the
one with the hype.
Idiotic. Julia is great. So, Julia is
another kind of functional programming
language
together with Haskell, F sharp, OCaml.
Uh and they became, you know, in 2011,
they came, you know, they supposedly is
a fastest, you know, even as fast as C.
That's what they claim when it when when
it came out. So, Julia, okay?
And I think it's good.
But today, you know, since like 2010,
you just got so many so many languages.
So, even though it's good, but there's a
lot of other good ones, too.
Uh
so,
I was going to learn Julia, but I think
I learned
F sharp instead because F sharp, you
got, you know, Microsoft.net,
which is the powerful engine,
which is also running C sharp and uh
PowerShell.
I already I know PowerShell, so
you know, so I didn't learn Julia. And
And the other thing about Julia is that
So, one day, you know, a few years ago,
5 years ago,
you know, on Twitter,
you know, uh that's back in the social
justice warrior days, you know, social
justice, feminism, patriarchy. All males
are evil. All the bad things in the
world are created uh done by males. If
you are a white male, you are a
[ __ ]
You know, that's that's back then,
social justice warrior days with Black
Lives Matter,
burning buildings, beating people. Then
Then comes trans.
The
trans is the king,
where they can go to women's bathroom,
and they can get pregnant, and then
begin to erase the word women.
You know, they don't say mom, mother.
They Well, they say the person
you know, the person you
something something.
You know, so that's that was the social
justice warrior days.
So, around, you know, a few years ago on
Twitter, I saw the Julia group. Oh, we
we are sponsoring this women group. We
are, you know, like we think it's
important to promote women.
Uh you know, so they are they are they
are
They They
they are pushing the social justice
warriors thing or rather they are a
victim of the deep state.
You know, deep deep state threats you.
You know, do this. If you don't do it,
you're going to be gone.
Okay, then the Julia creator um,
okay. Okay, yes, sir.
That's what they did.
So, that's part of the reason
and I'm not going to learn Julia, but
but anyway, that's not important reason
because this happened in go in golang
in rust very much. You go to their
website, there's a big banner. We
support Black Lives Matters, you know.
Back then.
Uh, this, you know, about 5 years ago.
So, pretty bad, very bad. You live, you
know, you know, if you are a normal
person, you kind of live in fear or
alternatively, you can join them.
You know, I'm you know, put put on your
website, I support Black Lives Matters.
And if you're if you have a good friend
who is not corrupt as you are,
then you can go and beat him up and get
money.
So, a lot of white people actually
started to, you know, do this, join this
movement. You know, you got to be smart.
I got to join whatever is currently
powerful.
[ __ ] ethics. [ __ ] what is, you know,
good or bad. I just care about money.
That's most of the the you some of you
the open source [ __ ] heads.
That's what some of you are doing. Open
source. Open source. You need to you
need to
use Linux.
Okay, slight digression. So, there's
TypeScript.
Originally, this is a TypeScript's logo.
Okay, then they got, you know, kind of
um
Okay, oh meta. So, the language I'm
trying to find
is so many, endless, you know,
so there's Elm, another functional
programming language, kind of niche for
the web and Hax
or Haxe.
A multi-language compile to multiple
legs, something.
Then Hack from Facebook
uh
upgrade from PHP, like improved PHP.
Then Swift, I think this is great from
Apple, 2014,
modern.
Then there's Elixir, also great, based
on Erlang,
but with a better syntax, something like
that.
Then there's Kotlin, a new kid on the
block,
you know, became overnight super
popular, taking over Java
in the Java land.
Okay, which I'm not interested, you
know, I'm not
Anything Java is [ __ ]
Then there's Nim, another niche, like we
have Possum is a fan of Nim. And, you
know, so a lot people is like Nim, Nim,
and Crystal of the Lisp gang.
Then Pirate,
because Scheme nested paren failed
failed. They can't, you know, people
don't like nested paren, so they they
the Scheme the Racket Scheme these
people, uh
maybe we should abandon nested paren.
So, let's create Pirate, Python-based
syntax. That's a root of
Pirate, okay?
Then PureScript was kind of popular
around like
10 years ago.
Another pure functional programming,
Reason, okay?
ReasonML, that's the one I'm looking
for. So, ReasonML is basically OCaml
but in JavaScript clothing.
Okay?
So, that's related to today's topic. I
need to mention that, ReasonML, okay?
ReasonML.
Okay? Took Took like 10 minutes to to
get to this page, Reason. Okay, so
yeah, so we were talking about ReasonML,
so so this is OCaml in JavaScript.
Uh then
Okay, yeah, and then there's Author,
yeah, so let's
um
TypeScript.
Uh you know, so so much history. Then,
you know, so you Then you got
CoffeeScript. So, there is this Anders
Hejlsberg. I think I think he's a
genius, you know, he's one of the
greatest
um programming language compiler creator
and programming language designer, okay?
One of the greatest.
For example, Python, you know, the Guido
van Rossum,
in my opinion, is the most stupid guy
among those who creates language. Most
stupid, and but he think he's smart.
Guido van Rossum of Python, okay?
Now, there's Ruby creator, there's
original Lisp creator, there's Wolfram
language creator, which I respect very
much, Stephen Wolfram. There's Go
language creator, I respect very much,
Rob Pike,
and another guy co-creator and you know
many programming language creators.
So
I you know Anders this guy I think he's
he's one of the great really great.
But I don't know much about him because
you know he's he's working for
Microsoft. So you you know so I'm
usually in a Unix kind of open source
circle so I don't know much about him.
But I can kind of see especially
creating type script you know creating a
language from scratch
is easy especially today because you got
so many tools you know it's compiler
passes and 1,000 books on passing and
compiling and you can ask AI bots.
You know so it's very kind of very easy
to create a
your own language.
But it is very difficult if you are
going to create a language that works on
top of a existing language especially
very popular one like JavaScript. Okay
that makes it incredibly difficult.
Because if you create your own language
you you you can do anything you want.
You can just say oh I designed it that
way.
You know but if you are creating a
language that works on existing language
there's a lot of
constraints you know you know you have
to follow whatever bugs that were there
not just that but you have to be
compatible you have to
then you have to create a new syntax
such that it still works makes it
consistent. Okay this is
super difficult to do that.
And and he he is doing that to make it
you know type script to make it very
strict like like a functional
programming language so that
it's, you know, that's not easy at all.
Okay, so
we kind of rambled over, so let's see.
Um
So, let's see. We talked for 40 minutes.
Uh so, PowerShell, Clean, Miranda,
TypeScript.
Uh then, okay, so So, there is one that
I need to copy. Proliferation of
programming languages, okay?
Copy that article.
Uh
Yeah. Oh, and another very worth
mentioning related to today's topic is
Lean.
Okay, so I have been learning Lean
in the past month or two, so together.
So, I'm learning Lean right now, and I'm
also learning F sharp.
Okay, so Lean Lean, you know, so both
are like functional programming
languages, but Lean is more is it's
primary design is for math, proving
mathematics, type theory, okay? So, it's
dependent type theory.
Uh let me go to X X22.
Search for Lean. So, I have my learning
Lean notes.
Copy the path.
Close that. Paste it here. Make a link.
So, there it is, learning Lean.
So,
so far the the trip is not easy. It is
very easy to learn F sharp for me
because I've been functional programming
since 1992 in Wolfram language. So,
you know, and then I code Emacs Emacs
Lisp in past, you know, 15 years. So,
I'm very familiar with functional
programming
or whatever, you know, how you do it.
So, when reading F sharp, where's the F
sharp?
F sharp, especially when it has a very
nice written documentation. It's It's so
trivial, you know, I can I read this, I
can understand, you know, just read all
strings, literal let bindings and
functions, you know, no side effect, you
know.
So, it's very easy for me to learn
uh F sharp.
But, however, Lean
is entirely different, you know. So,
I've been trying to So, let me show you.
So, I um
very difficult
because this type theory
So, Lean Lean is like two things, okay?
One is that you can use it just like a
pure uh functional programming language,
like Haskell and F sharp.
We, you know, you So, you can use it
just for that purpose.
But, meanwhile, it is primarily designed
is a proof system to prove mathematics,
like topology, you know, like very
complicated, very advanced.
So,
So, you know,
So, I think, you know, let's let you
know, I I can just learn this as a
functional programming language, you
know, I already have like 30 years of
experience.
But, but, but it's not uh so easy
because
well, partly because the the tutorials I
looked into and the official
documentation,
they are not that good, okay? So,
this is Yeah, so, anyway, so, that's my
experience of Lean, but but I'm
persistent, you know, I'm going to learn
Lean because I need it for doing my
mathematics.
Um doing
curves index
You know, I talked about this. I did,
you know, many live streams about
mathematics and and also
surfaces, you know, this is fantastic
Wolfram language. This is uh inversion
of a
array of cubes.
Beautiful, extremely beautiful. So, but
this are visualization of mathematics,
okay? So, but you know, so but there is
also differential geometry,
which
I've been, you know, these are graphs
made by, you know, a professor who
taught me a lot differential geometry.
So, when you do these kind of things,
differential geometry, manifold,
topology,
you need to do proofs. Proofs is the
basically the heart of
advanced mathematics, you know, you you
you just need to do proofs. So,
today with computer, with this, you
know, so new type theory
um
homotopy
type
theory
or uh univalent foundation for
mathematics is like like a new era for
mathematics.
They provide a new foundation for
mathematics, and this new foundation
is is
can be done
by computer. So, today you have a
thriving community, like a new era of
proof systems, you know.
So, I think that in in fact, this is
critical. I think this is a revolution
because like almost like from now on
mathematics
is going to be done with computers,
okay? Not like before.
I mean some you know, the if you ask the
old mathematicians, they they would say,
"No, you know, this computer [ __ ]
that's just for kids." Some Some might
say that, but actually
you know,
like the top some of the top, you know,
let's say the greatest
100 mathematicians alive. In fact, one
of the top few they they are doing these
um
computer proof systems, you know.
So, anyway, this here is to stay. So,
this is what I want to do. Lean, okay?
So
Yeah, so I've been reading, for example,
this book.
You know, I I was reading all of them,
but anyway, but this one this chapter
two, the dependent type theory.
I spend like 10 hours in a week.
Read and reread.
I learned a lot, okay? I learned a lot.
You know, it's it's a bit long. You
know, 20 pages, but I read it like over
a week, like 1 hour a day.
And and and you know, read part of it or
whatever and repeat and you know, so I
read this chapter. It's
it's great.
You see, it's I it's it's great if you
learn a programming language that do
proofs instead of just reading about
the type theory, okay? So, like
before
traditionally the math foundation is
based on set theory, okay? But that's
kind of old and that's not suitable if
you are doing
like computation-based mathematics.
Computation does not necessarily mean
using a computer. It just means like you
are So, in other words, you are doing
constructive
the philosophy of constructivism
of mathematics. So, you need to
construct So, anyway, so
So, the old way is set theory.
Which is, you know, traditional, but now
the new way is we are basically type
theory, okay? So, you can read about
type theory,
but that's not as useful
than if you actually hands-on learn a
proof system based on type theory.
Because when you actually do it,
computer will uh tell you you are wrong.
You know, you read a book type theory,
you think you understand, you know, very
advanced type, you know,
you think you know, but actually you
don't.
But if you learn a programming language
such as um
Lean or another one, Coq.
Okay, so let me let me
Let me just introduce you to you guys.
Is it interesting?
So, uh so Lean, there's another one
called Coq, okay?
From French, okay? Coq proof assistant.
Uh
so, they they they It's very annoying.
They renamed
their language, you see? It was called
Coq, c o q.
For many good reasons, okay? But then
then the you know, the moralists think
that, "Oh, sounds like a penis. That's
offensive."
You know, so they renamed it. It's no
good.
So, I will
So, anyway, so
Coq is another traditional proof system.
They are basically all type type theory
based and
you know, there are many different
branches of type theory. So, anyway.
So, Coq is another one. Okay, so you you
can learn if especially if you are
French because when you are French, you
you know, you probably want to learn,
promote a system
that your countryman, your bloodline
created.
So, if you are French, you can learn
Coq, very popular, okay.
So, anyway, so that's okay, I think
that's that's that's about the you know,
what I have to say.
Uh, so that's so maybe we should down.
So, I've been talking for 50
for 50 minutes.
Is there something I
else I want to say? Um,
yeah, so F sharp is great.
Easy to install, great documentation,
easy to learn. I highly recommend it.
And
based on .NET,
so and
.NET is fully open source since like 5
years ago. And
and F sharp, the entire .NET languages
is fully promoted by Microsoft with VS
Code integration.
Open in VS Code. So, this is a Emacs
command. I can open the current file in
VS Code. VS Code is easy to use,
popular. So, it's fully integrated with
PowerShell, with um,
you know, with PowerShell, you can run a
PowerShell command, but I hardly use it.
So, so let's see. Where do I
Um, so anyway, F sharp, C sharp, it's
all integrated with um
VS code, okay? So
Uh, okay, so let me
let's um
view
explorer, what is this explorer?
Yeah, I don't use
I don't use uh VS code, so
but I know
you can
uh new terminal there, okay?
There, so there is your PowerShell. So,
let's go to CD Kusande.
CD web
Kusande.org,
Kusande.info, go to it. CD
Emacs
Emacs, go to it.
So
So, there it is. This is VS code, so
Yeah, so I recommend F sharp.
Then
if you are into mathematics
uh you can learn Lean.
You know, like I am. I'm struggling with
it, but I'm persistent. That's a key.
Because when you read
you know, like right now, you know, like
I showed you which page? God, so many.
So, for example, Lean, this page.
You I don't, you know, it's like
you know, this paragraph I don't
understand, you know, tomorrow I read it
I still don't understand understand, but
just keep doing it. That's what I do,
okay? Just let whatever the word. So,
like if I don't understand, that's fine.
I will make sure, you know, I'm going to
be like I'm going to memorize each
chapter, like I can recite each chapter,
okay? Even I don't understand, but
actually, when you actually do that, you
will begin to understand.
Okay, that's what I do.
So, right now it's quite difficult, you
know, even though I have
you know, I I I have some you know,
quite quite some experience with
functional programming language and
logic.
Uh you know, the the mathematical logic.
But, I still find this, you know, hard
to
understand, you know, but
I'm persistent. That's That's what I'm
telling you guys. So,
if you want to learn something, you got
to be persistent.
Okay, F# So, if but if you are on Linux,
you know, OCaml or you can learn
Haskell.
Pretty good.
Um
then if you are, you know, you can if
you are a web dev, you can use um
you can use the um
Reason ReasonML, okay?
Okay, that's it. That's it for today.
Let's see.
Let's read the comments, answer the
questions, and that's it.
If you like my stuff, go to xahlee.info
and pay me, okay?
Got to uh
Why is this?
Yes, I'm you I'm I'm just starting to uh
well, I I haven't been using
uh Swab board, but I'm trying to, okay?
So, just wait for me to have something
some news.
Hello, I don't know.
Oh, so Ferrison says, "Hello, I watch
your talk shows, but I never seen see
you use much modern tools like LSP tree
sitter, okay?" That's correct.
So, why is that? Well, the short answer
is because I'm getting old.
So,
LSPP
and tree-sitter, they are two different
topics, okay?
LSP is a language server protocol. So,
if you go to Xah Lee Emacs blog, search
LSP,
you'll see it there.
Language server protocol, LSP, kills
Emacs.
Year 2017.
This is when LSP came out.
So, in my opinion,
we should never
use LSP in Emacs because it kills Emacs.
You know, because you know, once you
have the you know, the idea is not too
bad because you have you know, one
centralized server protocol that deals
with syntax
of all different sort of programming
languages.
So, in each editor, Emacs, VS Code, Vim,
uh Notepad++
or Gedit or whatever, you know, so many
editors.
So, you can all in any editor, you can
all just talk to the server protocol of
that language, maybe Lisp, Golang,
whatever, Python.
You know, so
you you so each editor don't have to
write their own
like syntax parsers and highlighters and
edit, you know, semantic edit, whatever.
So, they can always just talk to So, you
write, you know, so this modularization.
You have, you know, this language server
protocol, which is a protocol, then you
write a program to
to pass the syntax of a language, then
you have editors. So, editor talks to
the parser via this language server
protocol. So, everything is nice,
modularized.
You see? So, if you create a nice parser
for Golang or whatever, Haskell, F
Sharp,
any editor can use it, too,
via the language server protocol. That's
the idea.
Okay, but the consequence of this nice
thing is that it kills Emacs.
Because before this,
Emacs has a unique power that doesn't
exist in any text editor.
Why? Because Emacs Lisp you got Lisp.
In fact, Emacs, the entire Emacs, is a
interface to the Lisp system.
You know, in your init file,
in your init file, that's all Lisp code.
It's not like configuration.
Well, they are configuration and
settings, but this is actually all Lisp
code.
So, Emacs is actually a Lisp programming
language interface.
It makes it extremely powerful.
But now you have a language server
protocol, so
so that kind of
nullify
the power, the advantage of Emacs over
other editors.
Okay, that's that's that's one of the
element.
You know, that's one way to see it.
But why is But you know, the the other
issue is that Emacs Lisp has been
stagnating for like 20 years. I I blame
the GNU
Emacs dev [ __ ] well, half of them.
Because they, led by Richard Stallman,
you know, because they they think they
are God, you know, they They change
nothing.
Unlike Python, PHP, JavaScript, you
know, each one like
every year they have a new compiler,
every 3 years, you know, new compiler
because there's competition. You know,
JavaScript engine from Firefox from
that, you know, I create a faster engine
than you.
Same thing with PHP, you know, same
thing with Python, Python 2, Python 3,
you know, same thing with especially
JavaScript and and you know, so all the
languages are competing and they they
thrive fast. But Emacs like
they stagnate.
You know, if you're going to
if you write a better compiler, you have
to beg, "Please, I I just created this
much faster compiler. Can you Can you
guys God, Richard Stallman, I respect
you so much. Please, can you possibly
think about maybe add my stuff to your
to to the GNU Emacs?"
You know, that's what happens in GNU
Emacs led by the Richard Stallman, [ __ ]
it.
With a bunch of other, you know,
you know, they
Why is it that way? Because they are
like a commune. They are like
communism. You know, they are they
became a commune
where Richard Stallman is the leader,
the head.
You know, you donate, you know, you
should donate money to him.
So, that's part of the story, okay? Of
course, a lot Emacs people are great,
you know, we
you know, I'm using Emacs and Emacs in
the past 5 years there's tremendous
improvements
thanks to the Emacs dev.
Too, right? Also thanks to Richard
Stallman.
You know, so one thing good about
Richard Stallman is not is that he has
not fallen
as a victim or ass kisser
of the men can get pregnant [ __ ] or code
of conduct, [ __ ]
Or the you know, if you are a white man,
you are a evil, [ __ ]
You know, we got Richard Stallman
who defended our rights.
So, that we have to thank Richard
Stallman because he's, you know,
So, Emacs, you know, dev has good and
bad, you know, good and bad and so, but
they but
But, they uh yeah, they you know, some
there's some flaws. So, Emacs this
this you know, actually there's a lot
improvement of Emacs this in past
especially past 5 years.
But, anyway, so my original uh I did
opinion about language server protocol
is and uh
I rather, you know, so you can if if you
read my article, you know, it's
I want Emacs this to improve
because we have so many
incredible, talented people. I list
their names here.
They have written compilers and passes.
Some of them are professional
compiler and parser developers such as
John Wigley
who is I believe who is country
currently the leader of Emacs.
Okay. So, they've been, you know, John
Wigley, for example, working with C++
compiler for 20 years in a professional
manner.
Steve Yegge works for Amazon and Google
for like over 20 years
develop developing
programming languages
tools and stuff. You know, so and and
Lars Magnet, you know, so we have great
number of people, you know, and James
Clark like
You guys don't read stuff. You guys are
zoomers, so you guys know nothing.
But, if you read, you know, my article,
James Clark is
is
he created the XML parser that is in
every or just like almost every XML
parser used in the world.
And he created also the
in Emacs
nXML mode, which is the best editor for
XML, okay?
Okay? So, let me show you his name here.
He's a big open source fanatic, okay?
James Clark.
You know, beginning he I believe he
lives in Philippines. He's a white guy,
okay?
He beginning 2003.
So, he is the the world's top ex- expert
of XML
technology, okay?
So, and we have Flight Flight Check
author, we have Eric Lundem, creator of
C-CEDET. All these are great Emacs Lisp
dev. Xavier well-known. Meet most of
them uh
you probably heard. They are well-known,
okay? Lars Lasse Måge in this this guy
created the EWW browser, okay? So, let
me
let me see.
Entire web browser written in Emacs Lisp
among other things, among GNU's and you
know, so so many.
So, EWW, okay?
Web browser. So, which website you want
to visit? Let's see, xsali.info.
Okay? This is xsali.info
in Emacs. Oh, you got graphics, too.
You see?
xsali.info. Let's Let's full Well, you
can see.
So, you see?
Entire web browser. So, let's look at
source code, EWW, okay? So,
there is a source code. There is a file.
So, this this this, you know, so you got
this like a lot files.
Okay, entire web browser in written
Emacs. So, and then you got John Weekly,
uh
Stefan Monnier, professor in functional
programming language research.
Uh Phil Has Has Hagelberg. He's also,
you know, he's a
commercial programmer, a great
programmer. And Christopher Wellens, I
respect very much. He's, you know,
they they all, you know,
like almost
all of them work for companies or they
are professors, you know.
So, they they have written passes.
So, if Emac Lisp improves,
then
like we don't need like the LSP [ __ ] We
don't need like other people's uh parser
because we all these people are creating
them, you know, as breakfast.
But, what we need is improved Emac Lisp,
okay? We need name space. We need
actual you know, we
you know, there's you know, there's
quite a lot improvements we can ask for.
We need name space. We need uh
keyword arguments. We don't have that
right now. We we kind of have like
borrowing from, you know, common Lisp.
But, but basically we don't have keyword
arguments for functions.
So, anyway,
but anyway, in past 5 years, there's
already tremendous improvements in Emac
Lisp because, for example, today we have
native compilation.
But, however, it's not available on
Windows.
That's too bad.
But, anyway,
so my original opinion of LSP is no
good. Don't use it.
Yeah, but you cannot avoid it once it
became more popular because everyone is
every editor is supporting it.
If your editor Emacs does not support
it, then it's like a flaw, right?
So, you also, you know, so
So, you you also might want to support
it. But, why am I not using it? Because
Well, the short answer is I'm getting
old. I have not taken the time yet to
study this and write my own, you know,
study this protocol in depth. I I
started to a bit, but
I'm old, okay? And I do not want to
like like
install other people's stuff, these
packages.
You know, so you can these packages, you
got a thousands, you know, you got a
thousand packages, like 6,663.
So, you
I can install them, you know, I can
install them, you know, go land mod, F
sharp mod,
but I don't need to because I
been coding Emacs this myself for 20
years almost and uh
I can write my own mod, F sharp mod,
like in in an hour.
Do exactly what I want.
I don't have to read documentation,
search for it if it doesn't exist or
like what what other people's thinking,
why are they designed that way, uh how
do I make it the way I want? I don't
have to.
I create this F sharp mod in
in like 2 hours.
I don't need
another
you know, compiler the server protocol.
I don't need it.
Because and I I'm more efficient, you
know, like I can
Anyway, so that's the reason I'm not
using it because I'm getting old. Same
thing with tree-sitter. Tree-sitter I
believe is much better. Tree I mean both
are good, okay? LSP is
I mean you know, LSP is is is a good
idea. It's good, okay? Tree-sitter is
also good. Tree-sitter is advancement of
parsing
a progress.
But I'm just I don't have
I didn't you know, I don't have time. I
didn't
yet to get to it.
Like right now my time I need to spend
on learning this proof system.
Okay, so that's further delay to the
tree-sitter. This learning this lean
proof system is more important
for me, more critical for me than
than learning about the tree-sitter, you
know, parser mechanism, how they
integrate with Emacs and and that's why.
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching.
Yeah, tree-sitter is good. I mean it's a
good idea. It's uh
You need more adaptive and study fast in
modern world.
Yeah, but but but but but but but you
can only do so much. You see if if you
try to learn a lot fast, you don't have
depth.
Anyway, that's it for today.
Thank you guys for watching. 15 viewers.
Okay.
Yeah, that's it. Bye. I think yeah.
Uh
Close that. Okay, so anyway, bye guys.
Go to xali.info,
okay? xali.info
Go all the way down and pay me Amazon
gift card.