check-check
if I'm alive today is 2019 October 14th
Monday 10 o'clock a.m. and yes I'm alive
that is good and today's topic is I
don't know so good morning guys good
morning but body's going but it's busy
today
good morning TP good morning Matt and
good morning League of noobs and so what
is today's topics and I'm going to get
my tea okay be right back in one minute
well
so I'm back and I have my G now this is
kind of like green tea or alone tea or
whatever cheap teabags you see there you
there we have it teabags fantastic
invention of modern society and
technology imagine just put hot water
and dip in the back and you know we have
to look at the history of the tea you
know it's not no trivial task you know
how you make tea you have to go to the
mountains to cut the leaves then you
have to dry them then you have to bake
them you know it's like rice you know
you guys know about rice like rice you
know you have these tiny pieces now in
Western countries you don't eat rice in
general that's just that's not your your
main main how they call it the main food
how they call that staple staple yeah
that's not your staple that's the wood
okay so in Western society what you eat
you well the main carbohydrate is
play-doh and bread but in China in Asia
it's rice you know the rice he comes in
tiny pieces and where do they come from
well they came from Syria right
you have to it's extremely
labor-intensive and you can't possibly
imagine how people make rice you know
you work with today with technology you
have machines and so on but if you don't
have that it's extremely labor-intensive
to to make rice and people you have to
do it that's that's your food good
morning pausing F of a fasting F where
are you from did I ever discuss Bitcoin
just a little bit I don't really know
much about Bitcoin I think it's a
inevitability you know the question is
not whether Bitcoin or cryptocurrency
will succeed it's it's a matter of time
you know soon because it's a new piece
of technology it will be at some point
you know it may be government-sponsored
or it may be otherwise you know it's I
think in my opinion it's gonna be almost
universal because yes that's what I
think unless unless we are there's a you
know a few percentage of chance if the
word is very unfortunate it becomes you
know hyper dictatorship ruled by you
know big corrupt government then we are
we will not have it but otherwise I
think some form of cryptocurrency is
going to be the main currency sooner or
later maybe in ten years something like
that
noodles are staples everywhere DP DP you
are from Germany right so so far since a
saml evening in Canada born in Iran oh
yeah I remember I remember I asked you
that I remember that answer before okay
so we don't have a topic today and okay
let's see what's the comments let me try
not worth Muslim you don't know any
topic okay four minutes praise praise to
social justice can its praise to the
Lord
noobs Lord of the Flies that's a that's
one of my favorite book Lord of the
Flies fantastic by William Golding
William Golding William coding yes
unfortunately it's still copyrighted
because I was thinking too you know to
put it on my website and
make an annotation of it Lord of the
Flies William codeine I love this book
this is a novel because have you guys
with it
okay comment okay Lord of the Flies I
read it like two or three times in
different years since since 1993 or
something and you know I look I like it
because it shows a fundamental nature of
human animals Lord of the Flies and in
fact today's USA's society the social
justice can we are in a situation that's
pretty much like Lord of the Flies
that is when when your country are
lawless almost lawless so whoever is
powerful if I'm stronger I can punch you
I can do whatever I want that is the
situation of the Lord of the Flies chaos
so Farzin says what do you think of
Sascha
schwa how was your interview with her
did you watch it so that was like six
years ago so she I think she's a great
person she's Filipino I believe by
arrangin she's I think I think okay I
may be room I think she's Filipino or
engine and she's a Canadian so she's
extremely energetic and she is also a
super nice person that is her
personality you know she always you know
not you know not not just positive I
mean she yeah she's a natural
you know I maybe I could say a natural
positive person as opposed to you know
I'm putting this on in contracts too
many of these whites social justice type
of people they are like superficially
positive focus for example they want to
chant like every like on Twitter they
don't every day they want to chant oh we
must say something positive oh you know
we must be positive things like that
that's that's the typical social justice
white people they anyway
so Sascha true I think she's a great
person and she is always helping people
out and in fact she has helped me about
six years ago I have financial problems
you know I was so she actually helped me
financially - that's beside the point
I mean even if she didn't I still think
she's a great person so that's that's my
opinion about Sascha ah now she says
she's a girl of course she's a female
she is busy she she got married a few
years ago and she has a kid and so she's
now busy with her life but still she is
a great Emacs fan she still you know
create Emacs news letters like every
every day or was it every week you can
see her on Twitter she's a prolific
blogger and she she is also technical
but she doesn't show that much you know
you know if you are a guy you show that
you know because you need to show it
otherwise you don't get mates
she doesn't show that much but I think
she's also very technical she's a for
example she's a master of oak mod so if
you like oak mod you can go read her
blog she has tons of stuff about Oakmont
her her entire entire Emacs in it file
she put it into a oak format oak Mart
format so that so that you have you know
the part of the use of oak mod is that
you can embed
like normally in your Emacs init file
you have code that's the main thing then
you have comments but if you use you can
use oak mod so that the comments you
know the human text is primary well the
code is embedded you can use Oakmont for
that I have a tutorial if you just go to
my Emacs website such folks are the
Emacs Oakmont babel you'll find it so
anyway she's an expert at Oakmont so she
has her entire Emacs in in file in oak
mod format and she has a lot of
annotations you know so you can learn a
lot from it so that is my opinion about
her so I wish she would so she she used
to you know like five years ago also she
used to do Emacs interview of people
with famous Emacs people so so you know
five years ago like things changed a lot
of things changed no not today YouTube
is even more common but but even six
years ago it's less common than today I
mean still very common so she is one of
the pioneer who I would say who began to
lead people you know technical nerds
like you know hackers Emacs users to
begin to show their face because she
started to do to interview well-known
kind of mostly yeah she started to
interview Emacs people you know if you
read Emacs if you are in Emacs community
there are some people you know very well
known because they have written packages
or something like that so she interview
people so I watched several I mean in he
so six seven years ago I watched almost
I would say yeah probably like five five
also of her interview that I think
that's that's what she did so you
started to see Emacs users pupils face
you know she also interviews any you
know you do not need to be famous
so popular to you know she just like to
interview she wants you know she her
intention is that so she introduced
Emacs users to the people you know any
any Emacs users yeah but now she's busy
I wish she would come back to YouTube
doing YouTube stuff okay so that's about
that come back it for sure yeah
so what else so you know people has been
asking me to do stuff like he's I I
can't do that so so this week the
schedule for this week I'm not sure me
me you know because for the past week we
have not been doing much technical stuff
like programming and I like to get back
to that but usually live sessions chat
anything goes good morning green deck so
I don't know what what's the plan you
know I don't have a plan maybe I'll do a
separate video every day on technical
topics like sapphire keys and oh yeah so
people you know sapphire keys let me
start start common log start command
lock okay so you can see all my commands
on the left window and stuff like keys
is my most popular package and also
there are a lot of people who asked me
to do Emacs writing a I think it's what
was it you
League of noobs about or was it you mad
or somewhere else about doing more
tutorials on how to write a major mod
but they don't have like I think it's
hard to come up with a specific question
they just want me to talk about it so
yeah okay so I should I can do that yeah
because you know I just I can just stop
talking about that because once you
start talking then they now have a lot
things to say like opinions tutorials
for example you see this for example
okay we are almost beginning like every
time you start to talking about
something then then then we start to
talk for example you see when I move my
mouse to these commands you see the
Emacs in line doc
the string documentation comes up now
that is done by and you can also move it
to the code for example you know you can
move to any code defined derived mod
okay then it pops up the documentation
you move the mouse to set local it pops
up the documentation and this is of
course written in Java Swift you need to
do that
I mean I mean of course because you need
to use JavaScript for that so if we open
the file you see here is the JavaScript
so we open the JavaScript magnify
magnify so you see you have this e list
data okay actually this I should not use
let it should be constant actually we
can edit it right away so okay we can
edit it no it's not so anyway so here is
the data part if you go all the way down
after 2880 lines so that so we have 200
mm I mean okay 2880 email is functions
documentation then after that you have
the code this is JavaScript so that's
that is why
doing JavaScript I'm learning digging
into JavaScript technology in detail
because I do websites that's why you
know this is important to me and this
pop-up is also very interesting because
how is it possible to have a pop-up so
whoo-hoo any of you do JavaScript anyone
of you are coding JavaScript so the
pop-up technology is very interesting
because we have we had that since early
two-thousands let's let's say 2003 and
back then is what is it was a not
popular people don't know how to do it
but anyway so if you go to my JavaScript
tutorial you go to JavaScript in depth
then you go to Dom section in order to
do pop-up you need the Dom basically
anything you do on the website using
javascript is actually the Dom you know
like 80% of your code is about
understanding Dom not JavaScript because
JavaScript it's just well yeah you know
javascript is a language that allows you
you can print a list of numbers you can
sort sort array you can print you know
you think you can write a program to
print prime numbers under 1000 things
like that but if you want to do anything
actual useful like web application you
know 80% of it is about Tom about your
understanding of Dom and that's
basically all these libraries such as
react stuff are yes we need to get into
react you know the the anyway so so
about pop-ups so you go to my Dom
tutorial and near the bottom of the
index you or see WebSocket
websocket okay web scripting example
pop-up new window image rollover this
digital clock stopwatch parks following
squirrel falling snow effect
where is the document right until they
pop up new window image Ryoga so
somewhere here there it is how to create
two tips so this tutorial shows you how
to have this pop-up in fact when you
have this pop-up the content of the
pop-up is HTML its HTML you know snippet
so you could have images and anything
you could have images video animation
you know in anything so this you know
the thing interest so this is how you do
pop-up it's you know only 50 lines but
actually to understand to know how to do
this takes took me years to eventually
and you know actually 15 years I did I
don't know how to how it is done it's
always a puzzle to me because JavaScript
on a web like you know this is not a
typical desktop library like like kinome
GD GD k oh how they call that g TK or gk
something microsoft you have Microsoft
things on Apple you have apples things
you know a library that allows you to
create desktop applications but
javascript is not like that but how do
you they they don't really have like
widgets that you know do pop up so what
you do is that so the way it is done is
actually by creating using CSS to create
layers so you actually you have a layer
then when you you create an event so
that when Mouse Hoover over this thing
then like that layer becomes visible
that is basically how you do it can you
provide a link yeah but yeah of course
but usually you just go to
I okay so so here's a link what is that
whose link I forgot who you think who
think you talking about by anyway so
let's copy that close that close that
close that Emacs two tips JavaScript in
depth let's go back to create a new
window go back to talk show today's talk
show and post the JavaScript to tip okay
then post comments
okay so close that blog Emacs close that
some talk show okay that's today close
that close that reopen last closed okay
so show in browser another new window I
don't want new window I mean yeah I I
want the tab
you had one new new window so anyway how
to create two tips okay that's one thing
close that so Emacs I have two tips and
Emacs major mod how to write a major mod
so that so we I think I I don't know
when we're gonna talk me so I don't have
a schedule I don't know what to do yet
use use prototype Jas together with Ruby
on Rails later jQuery must be bio j.j as
though
okay so let's read a comments then
so NASA's Matt says but seriously did
you make up your mind about the schedule
and splitting the content into talk and
programming technical stuff yeah
good question what should I do
so 10 o clock I also need to switch my
schedule time a little bit maybe on one
hand 10 o clock is a good time for a lot
of people for for people in Europe and
for American people in America but it's
not a good time for people in China
Taiwan Japan Australia
you know because right now it's 3 o
clock in the morning for them so we need
I need to do something about that either
change the time or create another
YouTube stream live stream had another
time so we have to add a or instead
instead of a second live stream we'll
just do technical talk and upload to
YouTube so what what am I going to do
yeah I don't know
so you guys you know so you guys donate
ok put money in my pocket I go to PayPal
go to PayPal you know by my Emax
tutorial there's a link right here by my
JavaScript tutorial or go to go to you
know one of any one of my website go to
the top you gonna see PayPal patreon
Bitcoin links in Amazon giftcards links
so you know you I give you if I get more
money out you know then I can do better
because right now I'm not you know
getting much money for for the 40s
so so like you know so if I want to if
I'm gonna do more technicals made more
time it's you know it's like no money
and it's just me doing stuff and you
know then you get like 50 50 people
watching me my videos per video that's
let's go you know where that's pretty
bad well that's but but that's the
nature of me that's basically what I
have been doing for the past 20 years
and that's kind of the nature of of me
because I don't do things to in a
direction of money because if I really
you know if that is my goal with my
YouTube then there there are a lot of
things I will do differently for example
stop first of all stop the livestream
you know ninety minutes per day that's
you know that's gonna that's killing me
instead to like 15 minutes video you
know and focused on technical topics
Emacs JavaScript oh if I want to do
politics you know go you know you
focused stuff for example anti social
justice I give my opinions about daily
happenings about the social justice or
politics my commentary something like
that then I can see that you know I
start to have viewers you know what one
of the thing is that people you know so
why am i why won't I do that why don't I
do that for example why don't I just
started to do you know focused Emax
tutorials or because I feel you know
it's not it's kind of you know those
people doing that I mean if you're doing
that that's great but
it's not okay Matt says don't
underestimate the time spent into
putting together a 15 minute video yeah
that's true
you know some some of the very popular
youtubers with millions of followers
they spend you know some of them not all
yeah the each person youtubers they have
different style different strategy but
for example the GP there's a guy very
popular few million followers GP gray
something but what's his name anyone
remember you know GP three-letter
abbreviation that's that's he that's how
he's known by GP grey G gray something
GP not GPL but type it anyone remember
but that guy see CGP grey yeah that guy
so one one time I read I watched one of
his his video anyway I've watched out
quite a lot of his videos like tens tens
of them over the past several years five
five or 10 years his video is very short
like three minutes three minutes five
five minutes tops this back then and
very extremely condensed like often I
have to pass I have to pass everything
every ten seconds you know to really
sometimes two to two so to to get what
he's saying and sometimes I have to
think about what he's saying because
he's extremely condensed five minutes
per video but however one day he talked
about how Mahalo does he does it take to
make one video it's like 20 hours 40
hours to make one video so that's so so
that you know that's his style and and
that's one of the good way to create a
video you know the thing about making
video same thing with blog and same
thing with Twitter social social
networks Twitter Facebook things like
that if you want to be popular you
it's so they are you know I because I
write websites for 20 years so I'm very
familiar with the SEO thing like SEO
stands for search engine optimization
you know you want your website to become
popular in Google search engine
SEO is kind of dead for for like five
years today you don't hear people talk
about that much anymore but basically
the gist still exists the gist is about
marketing how do you you know if you are
a Content so-called content creator
maybe YouTube or writing blogging maybe
technical physics math teaching
programming or random chat you know
political commentary stuff like that you
see so so there's a question how do you
do it like what time it should you post
there's so many questions things like
that so so so one of the question is
should you post you know create content
frequently like like every like few you
know two times a day every day every day
or well I'll just get to the bottom of
it you know you should so what you want
to really want to do is it's much better
you want to spend your time to create
one video or one blog okay just one you
know maybe you'll take you one month to
do it that's fine create one and make
that one go viral
make that one just create one make that
one go like a few thousand views or
whatever is your goal median or whatever
you know like go viral
you know make it go very popular you
want to make one to be two for it to be
popular now so that's that's actually I
mean that that is tried and true theory
that that is what you want to do okay
but for however that is not my that's
that's not my style and and that's not
my that's not my style that's not me
because
yeah but podcast is actually like the
opposite extreme podcast or daily you
know radio talk show yeah talk show is
actually the opposite the opposite
extreme so like me talk show you know
then many many other talk shows you know
Howard Howard Stern you know he's a
popular talk show jockey and many others
Joe Rogan for example well Joe Rogan he
does interviews so that's another way to
make yourself very popular because you
see me talking every day you get tired
same old Saudi same opinion you know you
after a while after a month you you know
what I'm thinking you know you know my
style you you want something fresh so so
what another way to become popular is
you do interviews so for example me if
if popularity or money is my goal I
would have to start to get my machine
fixed so that I can interview people for
example Sasha hey Sasha
you know didn't know it's a time for me
to interview you and then people want to
watch it because Sasha you know they are
here to watch Sasha or many other Emacs
people you know there are so many of
them or you know maybe our interview the
JavaScript creator pin print and Ikes
you know I so so I had an issue with him
but but yesterday he kind of apologized
you know two days ago on Twitter so I
feel good about that because I talked
about this there's a video I did a month
or two ago about you know we are we had
some kind of argument and that pissed
pissed me off on Twitter but but
yesterday he said nice nice things so
anyway so for Easter for example one way
another way to become popularized you
interview people so that that is what
Joe Rogan is doing Joe Rogan is kind of
at this idiot okay I don't really like
him at all because yummy his Trudy
idiot hee-hee-hee every time he
interview you know he interviews you
know a lot of people almost every day
you know politicians famous people in
entertainment in you know or walk of
life almost so that's interesting
because you know you will find someone
interesting you won't watch for example
Jordan Pederson you know he interview
hundreds of people so by now so a lot of
people you find interesting so you go
watch his show you know and he makes
money you know not I don't think the
interviewee get paid do they get paid I
don't think they get paid right yeah
today maybe maybe some but but means but
the point my point is that you see when
you do interview like that you make he
makes the money this you know once you
have a million followers you make a lot
money it's something like million a year
or more so so yeah another way so so let
me summarize so I know quite a lot about
these marketing things because part of
the reason is because I'm very
interested in marketing persuasion coat
leaders coat leadership propaganda this
kind of all these related things you
know techniques you know human
psychology things like that so and also
because I'm doing websites for the past
20 years so I you know the SEO or how to
become popular you know that that also
interests me practically speaking you
know and and so what so the few you know
some of the aspects about popularity is
that you want to create you want to
focus take your time to make one post
one content one YouTube video that make
that one extremely popular
you know the likes go viral you know
instead of posting mediocre you know
things every day instead of that that
that
you know like what I'm doing like like
like my blogs you know like little
opinions every day so you want to do
that focus on creating one few good
great content but but however that's you
know that's just one of the style on the
other hand on the other extreme you have
this talk show or podcast they do you
know they they talk every day every day
they at the same time that is also
another way to get you popular you know
totally entirely different style because
with the talks your way you get people
into a habit to watch you every day
especially if I started to talk about
current events you know that that is
that that is one easy way to to make
yourself popular you know because people
want to know current events like today's
news whatever you know today or
something happened or what's your
opinion about this or that every day
there's new things right or what's you
know latest movie Joker
you know Joker becomes a controversy so
a lot of people wants to know what's
going on oh you know so so I could for
example I can tell you know I can
started to do current event events
everyday either with my own opinions or
without you know without opinions then I
just talk about what's happening you
know what people think I spent a few
hours to read about all the articles and
I give you a summary you know what
what's you know people are doing what's
the mainstream news news websites are
saying about this movie oh oh you know
oh I can add my own comments my own
opinions about this movie and I go watch
a movie so anyway so that's another so
the yeah talk show daily talk show is
another way and that's kind of what I
have been doing that's that's kind of
more natural for me you know what one
reason I want to say one reason I don't
follow these I don't want to
I don't follow these create something
you know very condensed and go viral I
don't like that because because just
because of my my own style okay that's
not natural okay that's not natural that
is a extreme form extreme form of kind
of marketing derived situation you know
like capitalism you know the the market
ain't arrived style with without the
capitalism you know consumer reason you
know where everyone is so every every
every person becomes the done consumer
you know back then back back in 1990s
the idea of consumer is very popular
today it's kind of gone away but but the
idea is that everyone becomes none you
know everyone will just watch TV they
just you know you are lazy you become
you brainless basically you just watch
TV whatever is you know you know switch
channels but TV is dead but instead you
have social media and Twitter you know
because it's kind of even worse in some
way I'm not sure which one it was but
Internet when internet began it's
supposed to be the consumer you know
what what what content you see is
supposed to be your own choice you know
hyperlinks you know when it begins but
anyway it's it's it kind of all of that
it's kind of rotted out today so today
people just you know look at their
phones addicted to their phones you know
Twitter its Facebook you know follow
whatever just come to them instead of
being active digesting you know choose
what you see so anyway so so the reason
I'm not into you know creating content
content is that I you know because
that's not me because I think that's
that that that kind of style is a
product of consumerism
because that because when you do that
because most people today we are
thinking everyone is so busy you don't
have time you just want to watch
something you know condensed like you
don't have time anymore even the
technology you know it's it's it's a
slap in our face we have tremendous
technology progress but people becomes
ever ever more busy you know you you
have you become very busy you have to
work 40 hours a day you know they all
this happens you know it's not what is
supposed to be technology we supposed by
today technology is so great we supposed
to like relax you know work 30 hours a
day or less things like that but it's
not happening I actually somewhat become
ass was you know you are busy you
address you have so busy doing
everything every time you see like
today's blog you go there on top you'll
say three minutes reading five minutes
reading it has to tell you how many
minutes of reading this is supposed to
be how extremely idiotic could that
possibly be you know so anyway back to I
want to let me finish my thought so so
the condensed way style of creating
content is is a byproduct of consumer
reason okay
it is not natural so I rather I would
prefer the kind of the talk-show style
because you know this this is more
natural because if you think about 200
years of human history or three or 3,000
you know 2,000 3,000 5,000 years of
human history the tradition of teaching
is by you know daily life you talk to
your children your your kids or as you
know your neighbors your you know your
tribe you teach them you know you you I
you know you're gonna be dead sooner or
later so you talk and teach them oral
tradition that is more natural and when
you do that you don't you don't like
prepare condensed and you know you
prepared 40 hours to condense it into
five minutes then you in it you try to
talk in these five minutes everything
you know that's that's a natural get
it's it's not natural and also when you
in a traditional human manner you don't
you don't focus your talks to just leave
Emacs nothing else okay this this video
is just about Emacs about Emacs how to
use Emacs as if nothing else exists
javascript programming programming
culture you know programming programmers
culture and politics involves in
licensing you know this is the if you
are a programmer
this is issues you touch every day but
when you have a video that's so focused
like Emacs
this is just Emacs it's it's kind of a
natural you know so so that is my kind
of my style that is why I preferred you
know the talk show and you know do it
every day and and and not not focused on
one thing you know whatever things I
know I you know I talk about my
experiences Emacs it's not natural okay
so what what so I think that's which
that basically finished that topic I
mean what that's what I want to say
about about about YouTube yeah about
what about yeah how many hours you put
into making a video of things like that
so so yeah
okay I've talked for 40 minutes 15
minutes 7 people watching anything else
so let me read the comments so about my
schedule I'm not sure yet okay so why
don't we so you go to youtube sorry so
sorry there it is okay let's actually go
through my stream go to my channel you
go to my channel and you will see I'll
post my community I think I'll post the
schedule for this week in a community
section maybe I'll do it today
so okay so go there check you know then
you'll see my schedule for this week
what I decided to do yeah and I opposed
to opposed to discord to king hearing
hearing you know I'm doing a video I
cannot read stuff in detail Nikon took
chord style egg mass script took court
style have you heard about the
JavaScript 1k challenge no what is that
it's about writing clever JavaScript
demos in 1k code of or less okay I don't
like those things that's like golf and
up first occasion things like that I
hated those things I despise those
things
and JavaScript demos in 1k oh I think I
have seen that site they have you know
they have a lot amazing things I think
the JavaScript code golfing competition
yeah I truly despised hate the golfing
concept you know because the essence of
the code golfing is about hack its it's
about abusing the language to the
extreme that is the bottom line you know
and you know part of it because part of
it is about knowing the language very
very well you know you find all kind of
loopholes you find always basically when
we program you know we teach college
students or or in your company I'll go
is that you know we always try to write
the most readable the most arrogant the
most efficient code you know the most
the code that's also the readable
efficient and also extensible you know
so that in modular that's what we want
on the other hand code Kofi is the
extreme opposite you you want the red
code that's the least read about the
least module the least everything you
know that this this [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] code
coughing you know where where does this
came from this came from okay excuse is
excuse my UNIX philosophy event it's
coming up okay any warning you first
where does this came from this came from
the UNIX philosophy the see [ __ ] [ __ ]
heads the seek program of [ __ ] it is
the C language that that began with this
kind of thing that is why I constantly
say you know the UNIX philosophy and the
UNIX see bootstrapping
each other that is the everything that's
wrong in computing industry began with
the UNIX philosophy and
okay that is why my opinion about that
yes I pay $80 a month you know and I
only have like yeah yeah it's well known
that in USA the Internet is very bad
it's well known you know in Korea I
think Korea is the best country for
Internet the fastest you know everyone
is high bandwidth Korea Japan all better
I don't know about Germany I think it's
better in Europe I think too and also
you can you know use your phone to buy
things things like that
in USA it's not so good so nice my my my
internet speed so let's look at Saudi
internet speed so I did a study about
the growth of internet speed over time
so this article how fast does internet
speed grow okay hold on a second there
is another article interesting so how
fast does internet speed grow and the
other article is USA internet speed map
okay so let's look at that so this is
USA internet speed map anyway so my
speed is about any anyway this this map
is not so good so let's go back to my my
so internet speed basically grows
exponentially pretty much like CPU and
hard disk space so you have a table here
from 1990's
so in 1990 you have one point two kilo
bits per second and in 2000 you have 669
kilo bits per second so in 2010 you have
you have 3000 basically four thousand
kilo bits per second so basically it
grows you know the formula is speed
times 1.5 raised to n where n is the
number of years okay starting with 1990s
it's one point two kilo bits per second
being anyway so daddy this is the
theoretical numbers but I also
calculated you know my actual speed from
1991 to 2017 and today we pretty much
have the same speed which is about 26
megabits per second so you know so you
can actually test it today
you go to Google this is my speed 28
megabits per second so let's this go to
Google and it's like I think it's $60 I
mean total is $70 or $80 a month it's
pretty bad so la casa paid $75 for 20
megabits down oh ok so but you are in
where pet Peru right you are in Latin
America I think maybe it's not so good
there so you go to Google you type my
internet speed okay then you give you
the your test let's let's try it okay so
you have to actually to turn on
JavaScript wait let's go so I'm going to
stop talking because you know because
the live-streaming maybe that that we
are so let's do it
okay he says 14 mega mega bits per
second it's half of my usual speed
because I guess because I'm doing live
video but normally yeah it's 28 and it's
been like that for the past ten years
so energy drink necessary so DP how much
do you pay a month and what is your
speed you know about the code golf the
code golf is such that yeah so I don't
like it right yeah but you know so it's
just no good it you know it's it's a
competition about who knows it's it's
kind of like the competition about who
knows the most worthless thing almost
almost like that it encourages bad
language design you know first first of
all if you have a good language okay the
better the language the less golf code
golf you can do with it because you know
that's the goal of a language you want
to program you want to create invent a
language such that writing bad code is
impossible you know there is no hack
there is no loop horse things like that
I mean that's the ideal situation when
you create a language I mean
theoretically it's you know that go is
kind of impossible but anyway that you
know it is impossible to create the
language such that such that is it is
impossible to write bad code you know
you know even mathematically because you
know he's anyway but but the go about
creating languages you he said you want
to so that there is no abuse no horse no
you know bad arrows no incomprehensible
syntax things like that so the coding
cough is actually you know it it
encourages everything like the opposite
of that so so the coding of when people
competing cook coding golf
it's what they are doing is that the
people the people who love this kind of
thing are people who it's basically a
show-off
it's a show off about your your tenacity
and your the your tenacity with digging
hacking programming language basically
and also it you know it requires you to
know the language it requires you to
know the language in-depth however not
for the good aspect of the language
in-depth such as you know how to use
esoteric functional programming in
JavaScript that's not the direction you
go but rather if you do code coughing
competition with JavaScript the the
aspect you dive into is about all the
esoteric things you don't really it's
almost like useless you know you don't
want to almost like you don't want to
know those kind of things you don't you
know that that's what code code coughing
is about and it's somewhat related to
hacking you know hacking us in more
we're creating more we're how to how to
abuse the language things like that okay
so that that's called cough code
coughing it's a worst [ __ ] in your
industry but however I mean it you know
but but on the other hand look at you
know if we take a different perspective
this exists in society you know a
society you have lots of things you have
you know for example you have cancers
you like it like it or not cancerous
exists mafia exists
you know underground society subculture
or you know bad things exist code
coughing so code code coughing is one of
the things that exists and you know it's
it's not exactly criminal so I mean it
just is something people do for example
you also have competitions about who can
who can drink the most water within one
hour you know that
you have record for that who can you
know a couple you can kiss you know a
guy and a girl kiss who can have the
longest marathon kissing you know you
kiss you know without eating or sleeping
for two days you know this it's kind of
sick you know you don't really want to
promote that but those things exist you
know it's part of human society you know
those exist so as you know when it comes
to god coving you know it just exists
and okay so but yeah and some of them
you look at them it's very interesting
you know they do
it's like surprising oh my god you can
do that you know you know it's kind of
surprising so let's look at let's look
at 2014 dragons
prize so how much are they paying wears
a coat God show the code demos okay okay
let's see this one
so am I supposed to play this I suppose
- arrow keys doesn't work away from
Dragon and avoid the missing parts of
the footbridge use a and D to move okay
idiotic fat a and D a and D oh okay what
cool
yeah okay it's stupid
that's it pretty boring this one okay
this one is not so great but I've seen
some amazing things so in general I am
NOT into the that's a dead end
how can that be you know you're supposed
to always have a way to survive right
this is a bad one this is a bad bad
application Dragons it's a form of Arts
well yeah it's like yeah I guess you can
say that you know some odds some odds
you don't like for example you know
yesterday you have a there's a
sub-branch kind of odd they splash paint
onto the wall and they call it art you
know you piss you piss into a wall and
you know the piece the way that they
tripped maybe it's art you have a toilet
you put it in museum that's art you know
it's not odd to me
so anyway that's about that so any so
maybe that's it for today what else we
let's see how long we've been talking an
hour okay
so DP says I pay 25 euros a month for
Theoretical 50 megabits per second Wow
but I hardly ever reach it usually
thirty to thirty to thirty five megabits
okay so 25 euro a month so how much is
that in USP 25 euro 2 USD it's like $40
USD maybe wait you need to go to ok
Oh 27 how Europe went down euro went
down so it's only wow so that's pretty
cheap well yeah so deep he says some art
provokes provocators the dialogue you
know for example you know I could have
done that yeah but you didn't but you
know yes a lot of people I don't like
that you know the like there's this very
famous graffiti artist very popular
especially yeah I guess among some of
the hacker types very popular graffiti
graffiti artists you know I hate those
things
like they they anyway you know like what
would you mean provocative you know like
okay here's the thing about art you know
odd art like poetry and math part is one
of the things that's dramatic okay
people talk about that out of
proportions dramatic art and I got you
know I did a video a few days ago
talking about math how math is dramatic
you know anyway art so art is this
dramatic thing so oftentimes you can
create you know okay so yeah it's true
art is you know art you know part of the
part of the goal or purpose of art is to
provoke thought oh you know yeah this is
some hard part of the purpose of art is
that but however
it it has also become it's kind of
abused you know so it becomes somewhat
like suppose if you are someone you
don't have any talent not you know
nothing at all no skill you didn't take
any time to learn painting or anything
like you are nothing you you know you
don't have any skill your your skill is
very bad right so if you are that guy
but however you are a corrupt you know
you are you are you are just the guy you
you you want to become rich and famous
you know so you are abusive you know you
you you are willing to do anything
possible to to make yourself famous and
what so so one you know one conduit to
that is art right via art so they are
you know they are they they are quite a
few famous you know so-called artists
they are doing that it becomes abusive
so so like you you just you know piss on
a wall and you say it's art and what how
how what is the what is the method that
makes you popular by by emphasizing that
that art is the conduct you know can't
do it to provoke thinking that is your
rationale that I mean that's a method
that's a mechanism you promote yourself
even you don't know if you don't know
nothing about history you don't know
nothing about philosophy you don't know
nothing you don't know how to paint you
don't know how to sculpt you don't know
nothing you know but however you are
this kind of political type mindset you
just want to make yourself popular in
your head
so you abuse you know you you you just
create garbage you know for example I
smash my keyboard you know I take my
keyboard so you know this so that you I
got this keyboard and I just smash it I
make a video and I smash it him a
particular way maybe you know the corner
first you know this is smash it you know
first eyes try to smash it
again it's a spoon for example again
it's the pillow then I smash it again is
the concrete you know for example that's
one way to do it okay so I make a video
of that I try to make it viral you know
it just smash things okay then I say you
know you know you know I say okay this
represent you know a certain political
idea where when you smash things again
it's a pillow it doesn't break because
something something but when you smash
your gayness concrete it breaks because
something something then I try to
connect it with politics you know well
it like you know I try to connect it
with let's say capitalism therefore you
know for example today right there's a
rise of this loss of riot on Tifa Hong
Kong you know so I create this video I
smash it so I try to sell it to them you
know I tell them you know this is how
you know sometimes violence works you
know I can't do that then then oh oh my
god sorry is a great great artist you
know he provoked people's thoughts
that's what I think about those kind of
things this is a idiot okay criminal so
yeah art is not the way yeah that's
right that's that's right there are some
exceptions to to that you know there's
some exception for example there's this
graffiti artist you know that I despise
that guy they are quite a few actually
not you know the it's true in general
you won't say you you won't make money
god but there are quite a few these kind
of type of people they become very
famous and you know they they have a
Wikipedia entry about how they what is
tech lead
okay I think it's a UK graffiti artist
he's got a name Banksy yeah that's right
Banksy I despise that [ __ ] Banksy
it's just such a Banksy okay now he's
supposed to be these artists that that
you know that's provocative and very
popular among especially this Anarchy or
hacker types of you know kind of you
know so you know he put this graffiti
and you know he make it he just to you
know these like this little this is a
little Rios Keo you know he just for
example for example this French painting
did he did he paint that no it's not him
you know he just he just take the right
opportunity the right political you know
opportunity when they are a lot angst
you know among people so when they see
these oh this is great art you know how
how dare he is you know truly a
courageous person who do this on you
know Wars and stuff the [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] idiot this guy
and you know recently about two years
ago Oh last year you know he I think he
did this okay so it's a it's a painting
or something
so it's auction auction in UK then
during the auction once it's sold there
is a machine shredder that shredded the
artwork then oh everyone is talking
about it
this this is exactly the kind of thing
I'm talking about you see so so he
created this odd okay is this a great
painting it does this require you know
the mastery of you know imagination no
it doesn't really okay anyway so he
created this and it's trying action okay
auction it and he sewed for I don't know
medians or something big money then
after it's sold you know he created
machine a shred you know a shredder
embedded in the frame is you know so he
pressed a remote button it shreds the
artwork so how do you what would what do
you think about that you know this this
I think you know what I think I think
this guy is a scum you know because when
he does that it creates you know it
creates if it makes him famous because
oh my god this is crazy oh my god you
know every every website reports it you
know then people say this start started
to think oh this this guy is a
philosopher oh my god this guy is a
philosopher because he provokes people's
thought well and then people start to
maybe make connections with philosophy
or politics so this means you know the
the this signifier is something
something something consumerism or
something you know then then that you
have a bunch of hacker idiots like you
know like programmers in and on a key
type of people then you know most people
vast majority majority of people in
society are not that smart okay they
don't know history they don't know
art history they don't know nothing but
then when a CD so this
I created you know shredding the thing
doing auctioned it's fantastic it's
something it's never done before it's
nothing it's it's nothing it is just
this guy trying to make sing himself
famous that is all there it is
and the way and also the his artwork
you know it's ugly it's ugly is there's
no beauty involved you know like there's
also another famous artwork you run oh
you wanna how do you spare that art okay
something like that
yeah that that that laughing you know
this is this is support this is like
supposedly postmodern art you know you
put this in a museum you know art
exhibition is supposed to be odd so so
so why did this kind of things become
popular because I think part of the
reason you know so anyway this type of
artwork postmodern you know part of you
know this kind of thing they become
popular because it has to do with
society you know people becomes you know
modern people modern society each person
becomes independent we don't care about
each other like I don't really have to
care about you guys you guys don't
really care about me you know you but
you know you well you you like my video
right but tomorrow if I disappear
nothing happens you know as as opposed
to hundred years ago you depend on your
neighbors to survive you depend on you
know you have to know people that's why
you care but modern society each person
becomes independent so I don't really
have to care about any you of you you
don't care about me things like that you
know applies of course you don't care
about any anyone else
it's almost basically you don't care
about Nate your neighbors in fact the
more City the the more money you make
you know if you are a programmer or if
you live in city you don't you don't
even know who is your neighbors like
next door you don't even know who they
are
well you know what they do you don't
even know most you know so that's modern
society Andy and we as human animals we
become more Longley Longley we don't
have you know we need that you know we
don't have to touch with other people
then you know then you have the social
justice then you have the gamers you
know just playing games every day memes
you know then you know people become sad
and then then you started to have these
kind of things it's a it's a phenomenon
of the years of society I would say so
that that is my opinion I think that's
it for today okay I think okay so one
hour forty minutes so let's read the
comments don't smash your keyboard is
your technique so what is technique take
tech lead tech lead so you mean a
general I mean is there a special
meaning to the word tech lead oh so he's
a guy his video always pop-up I don't
know who is he
let's see oh the Chinese guy or the
Google guy what what do I can I say
about him I've seen a few of his videos
I guess he's just a smart guy I have
yeah so I've watched a few of his videos
you know so what what is my comment
about him I guess he's just a smart guy
he's Asian
he worked at Google and you know and he
just created a video he talks about his
experience and he's also I mean he's
smart guy for sure because you know he's
very fairly successful YouTube you have
to gather your thoughts you know to
create a good video and and also he you
know so for example he is he must be
someone who is capable of knowing what
people want to see you know because for
example a lot of his topics a lot of
people wants to get to get into Google
right because Google is this very big
corporation you know and people hurt you
know it's very well-known for Google
pays you a lot and how you have food
free food with chef you know in Google
inside Google and all that good things
so he makes a video catching on that
think so you become popular and you know
and also getting into Google is not easy
so you know he he's a smart guy
obviously and I so I watched a few of
his videos I think he's also pretty
honest he's not someone you know just
[ __ ] yeah
so that that is my opinion about him you
know and he makes you know he each
YouTube video basically if you have 1000
views you make $2 to $4 you know so for
example let's pick one of his you know
for example this one I got fired from
Facebook having a YouTube for having a
YouTube that's a quick paid so let's
look at this one it's hold on a second
let's stop
I got fired from Facebook for having a
YouTube channel okay that's kind of
click bait but maybe it's true actually
so it's got 53 thousand views oh no wait
it's got almost a million views 895
thousand views so 895 you multiply by
three so you got about $1,800 yeah so
wait nine item stream
$2,700 so two thousand seven hundred you
get about rich if you multiply by three
by three or four so if we multiply by
four
you got $3,200 $3,200 just for this
video you know so he's smart guy so he
does that so smart a Salesman or really
smart I think both you know after all
he's a coder at Facebook and Google you
know he's fairly above average I would
say so I feel like he's faking it maybe
you are right you know I watched a few
of his videos I think he's pretty okay
okay so Cody and channa got it okay it's
not coding it's not really coding he
doesn't I don't think he actually do
coding he just talked about the social
issues like how do you how to get into
Google you know how to do Google
interviews oh I got fired from Google I
got fired from Facebook you know there's
drama you know things people want to
watch you know that's kind of thing for
example if I gonna do something like
that I'm gonna create a video why you
should not use Emacs okay a lot people
will click on that well you should not
use Emacs or something like that you
know why you should not use JavaScript
they have to prepare you know I need to
do a good video I need to like dress up
you know something you know like I have
to not just random like right now I'm
just random every day I what I have wake
up whatever you know my my bed have you
know that you have to do a presentation
you have to like do that those things
and so to me those are fake I don't mean
it's not exactly fake but easy you have
to it's it's about you know creating a
product you know you said he's kind kind
of fake you know you have to prepare
things like that okay so that's that's
it for today thank you guys for watching
yep I'm gonna shut down in in one minute
okay last words posted so deep he says
the the self shredding painting has been
an instant instant classic
I respect the Nifty and twisted
connotations or around it yeah that's
that's interesting
oh yeah so he's got now he's got close
to a million way oh yeah five hundred
seventy thousand subscribers yeah I I
saw his video on 4chan you know I'm
surprised people used fortune you know I
didn't know and
some of you guys too so I didn't you
know I always I'm surprised people
actually go to full charge because I
always you know sometimes I you know in
the past years even ten years ago
sometimes I see my name dimension there
and you should usually on 4chan you know
you have tick you know slash or tick or
something and usually it's like in least
they're talking about least you know so
I see my name mention you know I was
thinking who go there who goes to
fortune and talk about programming stuff
like I cannot imagine but apparently
people do go there so what you guys go
there I mean you go there for challenges
like you are like you are anonymous you
go there you post whatever and more than
like 90% of the post is like pure
[ __ ] you know they cause [ __ ]
posting and but but okay she posting but
but you go there to talk about
programming stuff like like sometimes
the omission like typically the topic
will be like this Haskell you know these
kind of dramatic things you know this
Marcus has cow monad scheme tail
recursion you know the tech or CC you
know this fancy jargon kind of thing and
you know but you go there and anonymous
and and after day your posts will be
gone but you go there then what is the
point
I mean you don't learn things there
right yeah I mean I can understand this
[ __ ] posting but I'm programming topics
like what what what do you get out of it
yeah [ __ ] [ __ ] toilet the pant
bank Banksy guy funding to this
tremendous inch interesting thing going
on you know in society
so this Banksy you know I looked into
Wikipedia you know I read he's you know
I read a count what is this guy is about
where he came from who is he you know so
it doesn't interest me you know this
type of people had kind of despised but
anyways he's supposed to be anonymous
but however you know people think he's
anonymous but however you know this kind
of things especially when you become
this popular it is actually impossible
to be anonymous okay so but on the
internet you know you say it's anonymous
actually it's not you know IIM pretty
sure a ton of people know him so the
anonymity is kind of like it become part
of the you know way to to become more
even more popular people try not to say
who he is you know you're not really you
anonymous when you become this popular
it's not it's impossible to be anonymous
yeah okay so that's it for today so
let's see internet speed thank you guys
for watching see you and go to youtube
okay go to so today today or tomorrow
you know today or tomorrow probably post
my decision on my schedule like what
time and things like that
the Lord of the Flies by the way that
phrase came from the Bible you know what
I didn't know until much later the Lord
of the Flies Lord of the Flies basically
refers to bismallah I think if I was in
Pisa ma basically means devil
hey guys