Hello guys. Good morning. Welcome to
another episode of Saw Talk Show.
Today we going to talk about randomish
Emacs stuff, technical stuff,
programming. Okay? Saw Talk Show and uh
welcome aboard. If you are not here,
play at 1.5 speed. If you are here,
say hi. Love to see your comments.
Uh if you are not here, skip around,
okay? Let me show you my keyboards.
Glove80. Fantastic.
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard. Fantastic. No
Lear trackball. Fantastic.
And
not yet. This is Svalboard. s v a l b o
a r d, okay? For each one of them, I
have a review on YouTube and uh
on my website.
So, let's talk about things. Randomish,
okay?
Hello Shrimp. Hello
M23
row. Hey, good evening. Hey from Europe.
So, we going to talk randomish, okay?
Randomish.
Uh
doctype.
Uh we need to go to So, we going to talk
about which key from Emacs version 30
just released 2 weeks ago.
Which key is great?
We going to talk about HTML doctype.
Okay? Uh and we going to write a Emacs
command that insert
h- HTML doctype. You know, you can pick
a choice, like uh HTML5, HTML4.
And we talk about random rant about
Microsoft firewall versus the Linux
firewall. [ __ ] Linux. Unix. Idiot.
Uh then we talk about doc type and uh,
you know, JavaScript coding DOM,
document object model.
Where you have
you know, you have a bunch of jargons,
element node.
You know, I'm going to talk with
something about that. So, you see I have
a comprehensive tutorial
on HTML, CSS, JavaScript in depth.
JavaScript object reference starting
from the global object because
everything is a child of global object.
That's JavaScript. So, and then
DOM.
This is document object model. This is
basically what you do when you use
JavaScript to program the web. So, in
fact, when you do web dev, programming
the website, Google, Amazon,
uh, whatever,
you
most of the time you're working with
DOM. Okay, so JavaScript you you call
DOM methods.
Uh, so comprehensive tutorial and the
SVG tutorial. SVG is very simple, okay?
And there is a SVG clock you can learn
in 10 minutes.
And here's the code, okay? So, the code
is 100 lines.
Um,
so anyway, talk about these things, then
um,
yeah, so I'm I was talking about my web
dev blog. So, there's a lot update on
HTML doc type, HTML,
complete list of tags and uh,
their
um,
their structural example.
Um, wait, not this page,
uh, but somewhere, okay? So, anyway, so
then you have
DOM and JavaScript, lots of things,
Okay, let's begin something somewhere.
Okay. So, Emacs 30. So, if you go to
Emacs blog, just search for xahlee.info
Emacs blog. You can see
there is Emacs 30. Am I doing good?
Okay, comments.
Uh Shrimp started learning Go lang
because of you.
Fantastic. Go lang is much better than
Python. Indeed.
Much simpler,
faster,
and uh much more cross-platform,
and you can compile it into a binary
blob.
Uh so, Go lang is in fact it's much
faster because it's uh actually a system
language. Uh much simpler. So, Python
it's more complex.
The syntax is [ __ ]
It does not support functional like
basic functional programming like the
Python kind of [ __ ] [ __ ] lambda.
You know, you
you can only use lambda for simple like
one you know, simple functions. [ __ ]
lambda
doesn't do much functional programming,
while Go lang allows
you know, you can Go lang does much
better.
And so, Python is just no good. Python
is sucks in every way.
Uh
it became popular because Google, you
know, only because Google. Basically,
only because Google. The Guido van
Rossum is the one of the most low IQ
uh person among programmer among
those who created a programming
language. The Python
uh Guido van Rossum is the most idiotic
brainless idiot.
He's he's he's got a vision about, you
know, he want Python to be the most
friendly uh
tutorial for children, you know. But,
it's a lousy language. It's the most
lousy language. How But, added to that,
he has an attitude. He think he's the
greatest designer.
Guido van Rossum, idiot. Plus, he's, you
know, doing the social justice warrior
era, you know, the Black Lives Matters,
the all white males are criminals, all
all white males all the bad things are
done by
men,
you know, the patriarchy theory, you
know, the Guido van Rossum is sponsoring
it. You know, he's saying, "Oh, I'm
going to start to teach women only."
Like
So, so in that respect, Guido van Rossum
is a minor [ __ ]
He's a skunk.
Uh and created the worst language. Why
But, why is it so popular? For two
reasons.
One is the first time around 2000, year
2000. That's because Google started to
use Python. Before that, year 2000,
Python is unknown.
Uh so, Google, you know, Google is the
beginning, like the big
corporation and good corporation. They
turned into a evil empire, starting
around 2010. Okay, but before that, it's
one of the best company, best code, best
product. Every Google software is the
best. No, you know, privacy privacy
invasion and
do good things for you. That's how
YouTube became very popular.
You know, Google
bought YouTube in the beginning, around
2003 or so.
So, anyway, in the first 10 years,
Google is very good company, and Google
choose Python.
Because
back then, year 2000, the only other
choice you kind of have is Perl, which
is extremely [ __ ] language.
So, Google started to use
Python and all the programmers are like,
"Oh, Google, the great company, the
giant corporation, they are using
Python. I must use Python, too."
So, that's the beginning.
Google introduced Python to the world,
basically, okay?
They And and, you know, and Okay, so,
but then Python is because the language
is not good. It's like, you know, going
downhill.
And then Ruby is a much better language.
Okay? So, you go to xali.info, you can
see my tutorials on
Go lang,
Python,
Ruby,
Perl. Now, Python, Ruby, Perl, they are
kind of similar. They are all scripting
languages. They're basically in the same
category, okay? So, in the first
beginning is the is a Perl, which which
created by Larry Wall, a [ __ ]
He is kind of this um
He is Larry Wall is this kind of um
cult.
So, as a sort of cult, how how shall we
call it?
Uh
cult maverick um
uh snake oil.
Uh charlatan, okay? By the way, all
these are my opinion only. Just my
opinion.
So, in case, you know, they cannot sue
me.
So, Larry Wall, who created Perl around
uh '89, okay? That's the birth of Perl.
So, Perl is But Larry Wall creates lots
of like
He creates a some sort of cult
uh that, you know, saying that computer
science is overrated. Uh we I created
the language Perl. This is the the first
post-modern programming language, okay?
And he's got lots of
jargons and chant phrases which are
recited by almost every programmer
because for Perl for about 15 years is
the most popular programming language,
the most popular scripting programming
language for like 15 years starting
around, let's say, 1995 to 2010.
Then Python and, you know, took over.
So, Perl was the, you know,
and the saying that, you know, he
creates lots of jargons and chant
phrases like Perl is the Swiss Army uh
knife of programming languages. Like
Perl has the TIMTOWTDI [ __ ] you know,
like do what I mean, you know, like
idiots.
You know, he creates creates lots of
jargons and the the the state of the
union, I mean, the state of the onion
and uh
and
apocalisp,
like Perl apocalisp something. And also
lots of, you know, lots of like like
he's known for that, you know, so
Perl
they dismiss computer science and they
there's another phrase okay, so let me
go to my rant mod. So, I have 1,000
articles on Perl, okay? So, laziness is
another
chanting jargon he used. Um
and and theory versus practice, that's
another thing the Perl coder spread
around, you know, saying that in theory
everything should be correct, but in
practice theory is wrong.
You know, things like that.
So, lots of
And here's a piece of history, Python
surpassed Perl in popularity.
So, this is 2008. Exactly 2008, okay?
Um so, we got lots of you know,
historical articles. So, anyway, back to
my topic. Um
Uh so, let me show you a few, okay? So,
Pearl is doing a lot of [ __ ] you know,
in in you know, for 15 years. Back then,
you know, people don't know because
every programmer you talk to, they're
idiots online, like today. Like today,
even today, you know.
Uh but they have different things back
then. So, like every programmer you talk
to, they all say, "Pearl is the greatest
language, you know." And the Larry Wall
says it's a first post-modern
programming language.
So, anyway, then let me get back to
whatever. Okay. Um Pearl Books
survey, year 2002. By the way, I got him
him, Larry Wall, to sign a book.
To Brain Power, Larry Wall. You know,
Brain Power
brainpower.com,
that's a startup company.
Uh
about five of us
worked on That's 1997.
1997, 1998, brainpower.com. So, Larry
Wall signed it.
Um
so, I did, you know, I was a master
Pearl, so I read about six, seven Pearl
books from cover to cover. And here's
the list of them and my review. So, you
know, so they are these books you can
check out. So, this article is Pearl
Books survey, 2020 2002.
So, you got that. You got learning
Pearl, very popular. You got Mac Pearl.
This is before Mac switched to Mac OS X.
Okay, so this Mac Pearl is for Mac OS
classic.
And then this this this one is actually
was my favorite one, advanced Pearl
programming. Okay.
Now
they came out with a newer edition, but
so the 1997 edition is good. But then in
2005 they came out a new edition, but
actually it's written by someone else.
So it's entirely different.
So I cannot recommend that one. But
anyway, these are old books. Okay, so
like
they they are basically obsolete. None
of these,
you know, you should read. They kind of
obsolete.
And then nobody is learning Pearl
anyway. Pearl is kind of obsolete.
So it's you know, so this is one of the
amazing things in history.
Like
Pearl at one time is the most popular.
Like it's the top three most popular
language. C,
C++, Pearl, Java.
Basically maybe not Java, but C, C++,
Pearl.
Okay. And Pearl is said is believed by
most programmers to be like forever, you
know,
like the the the scripting language. If
you want to do scripting language,
Pearl.
And that's basically it, you know,
there's not going to be any more.
You know, so for 15 years programmers
believed that.
And here's Pearl cookbook. So but
but now we know
Pearl died. Okay.
Now of course you newer generation like
you don't know [ __ ] you don't know a
thing.
But
for 15 years, Pearl was the most
popular, like believed to last forever,
like, you know,
um programming language, but it
dead. It died, okay?
So, that's Pearl. Um
So, that's one piece of history that's
kind of uh
kind of important. That's one big
chapter. Another one, for example, is
Google. Google for for the first 10
years is believed the most the best
ethical
corporation.
The one that will save, you know, that
will fight the evils of Microsoft and
others, you know, that
it's a evolution. But But now, Google
turns out it became
one of the most evil empire.
Even more evil than Microsoft. And not
just USA, globally it control everything
and, you know,
lie big time, lie for the government,
create fake news,
uh influence, you know, cheat USA
presidential election, and on and on.
Google.
And uh they do um you know, so Google is
become So, that's
that's one of the things you should
learn because
you know, it turns out back then all the
programmers, we
saw Google is the greatest company. We
supported, you know,
Google is so good. But then, they
they turned, they changed.
So, that's another um interesting thing
to know.
Okay? Uh there there are quite a few
more. And the another one, for example,
is Free Software Foundation and open
source.
You know, in the beginning they are
supposed to mean to be helping the
little programmers, us.
Against the giant huge corporations like
Microsoft,
Apple, Google, Amazon,
you know.
We share code. We are, you know, we are
hackers, programmers, you know, like
ethical, you know, the the the sense of
hacker as a uh
playful programmer, not as a
computer criminal.
Okay, so free software foundation by
Richard Stallman, then open source in
the beginning, which is a branch off
like a
schism from free software foundation.
Um so, we believed, you know, it's a
good thing. So, you know, we
programmers, we don't we are not greedy.
We share our code, you know,
among friends.
We are against the giant huge
corporations who are usually greedy.
Patents, lawyers, you know, 1,000
lawyers among Google, Amazon, Facebook,
you know.
But turns out, now today
today, 99.9%
of all the open source are sponsored by
these
corporations with 1,000 lawyers and 1
million patents.
You know, they say they they sponsor
you. They sponsor Linux, too.
Without these Google, Amazon,
uh you know, especially Google, uh
Microsoft,
without their money, the entire open
source dies overnight.
Uh and also open source fundamentally
got problems. Also free software
foundation. Okay, that's that's another
topic I talked often. So,
let's go back to programming languages.
I kind of digressed already for like
30 minutes.
Um
So, Ruby
you got Ruby
is a much better programming language
than Pearl, okay? Ruby is much better,
created by this Japanese guy. Ruby is
based on Lisp.
In particular, based on Emacs Lisp and
uh
and Pearl, okay? So, the idea of Ruby is
let's you know, Pearl is like, you know,
this
uh
Pearl is like this snake oil thing. Can
we create a language that does what
Pearl do?
But with a much better fixed
syntax.
So, that's how he created Ruby.
So, the syntax is kind of like Pearl,
but much more
uh it doesn't encourage like [ __ ]
around like the Unix [ __ ] The Unix
[ __ ] with their man page, you know,
LS grep, you know, awk, you know, this
little jargon, cat.
They love that, these Unix scums.
So, Ruby doesn't do that. And Pearl
Pearl Pearl is like
hopping onto the Unix philosophy. Pearl
Pearl is like I mean, not um
Pearl and Unix is kind of in the same
community, okay? They They love like
hacking. They love things you cannot
understand right away, you know, they
they love that those little things,
incomprehensible, you know, they think
you need to
learn it.
Uh so-called hackers.
So, Ruby is not like that. Ruby is more
like scientific, like more computer
science and
simple, easy to read syntax and the
semantics of Ruby is based on Lisp,
okay? So, Ruby is actually much better
language. And around 2008, the Ruby on
Rails made Ruby incredibly popular.
Okay, that's Ruby. So, Python is the
same category, but Python is the worst.
Uh Pearl, Python, Ruby.
Python and Pearl
versus Pearl, I'm not sure which is
better, but they are both really bad.
Okay? Pearl is pretty bad by intention.
It's bad because it's intentional
intentionally
embrace
the
hacking and [ __ ] around attitude of
Unix. Cryptic names, everything is
cryptic. You cannot understand it.
But it But it's like convenient and easy
to type. That's what they say. So,
that's Pearl, okay? Intentionally that
way. And with a bunch of uh jargons and
slogans, a coat, just like Unix. For
example, in Unix, you have Unix
philosophy.
You know, so in Pearl, they have like 10
times more jargons.
So, it's like intentionally created
crap. That's Pearl.
Uh and Pearl, the syntax of Pearl is
based on Unix. Basically, bash, shells,
awk,
you know, and all the Unix things like
file
uh file descriptors,
uh you know, like all that. Error error
code.
Um
Go Go lang Go lang by design is supposed
to be more like more computer science.
Like do do things the
There's only one way to do it, you know,
things like that.
But
but it turns out guy Python is actually
the worst language.
Okay, that's about kind of programming
language history.
Oh, yeah. So, Google So, Google in 2000
around year 2000
Google spread the popularity of Python,
okay?
Now, by 2008
Ruby took over
in part because of the Ruby on Rails.
Ruby becomes hugely popular.
And even possibly it Chris eclipsing
Python popularity.
Why? Because Python is really not that
good language.
But, however
starting around year 2010
there arises the concept of big data.
And then data science
and and then AI, okay? Because Google,
they have like huge amount of data. They
need to process it. They Oh, machine
learning, okay? So, big data machine
learning then so-called data science.
You know, they need to process this huge
amount of data to learn something, like
learn
what
what kind of clothing do you like? When
do you go to shop? Where do you shop?
They you know, they need to find the
information.
Uh
so big data, you know? So, so then
machine learning uh then
then it became basically the
AI chop chat bot, you know, like the new
neural networks.
So, Google started to do a lot of
machine learning, big data, and they
they started to churn out lots of
AI libraries, machine learning
libraries, okay? And also chips, you
know, dedicated chips.
So, they produced a lot Python like
code, you know,
uh open source. That is that is why that
is the second time
Python became hugely popular, okay?
So, also because of Google.
Without Google, Python will
you know, go go nowhere.
So, here's an article, why is Python
popular? Okay, let's open it.
And uh then uh why Python sucks.
Uh why Python sucks. So, they are like
20 articles
on the details why Python sucks.
Uh
then you have why Python documentation
sucks. Python documentation is the worst
[ __ ] possible in programming community,
in programming industry, okay?
The number one
the most [ __ ] up scum documentation is
the Unix.
The Unix man pages by the Unix
[ __ ] the Unix scumbags, including
Linux, okay? In this context, counting
all the Linux things and their
community.
The Unix [ __ ] with their man page,
and also the Apache
documentation. They are the worst
possible.
The worst technical writing in human
history.
In human writing history, in the history
of human
writing for technical documentation,
okay? Unix man page, Apache, the the web
server documentation around year 2000,
and Python, okay? So, Python would be
the second or third.
The worst documentation possible.
By the Guido van Rossum, like
pretentious guy. Like he think but he
think he's like very smart, but
and and he turns out to be the worst.
Okay, so here's like 20 articles on why
Python documentation sucks.
So, going back to Yeah, go So, Go lang
is
Go Go lang is created by this
programming genius, Rob Pike,
and another guy, okay? Uh very simple
programming language. It's it's designed
to be like the
uh clean up of C and C++ first, okay?
It's a system language. Uh and very
simple. So,
it So, it began around 2008.
That is when I realized this Rob Pike
guy is super smart, okay? Rob Pike, he's
known for several things, you know, he's
a big uh well-known guy. He's known for
creating UTF-8, the Unicode.
He's known for the Unix
uh
known for Unix propaganda. He's a big
Unix guy, okay? He's uh known for Unix
propaganda. He's also known for, you
know, the the newer generation of Unix,
Inferno, called something and Plan Plan
9.
But those kind of failed. So, Go lang is
successful.
Go lang is very good, simple, okay?
Um
Okay, that is something about the
programming languages. Um
so, I kind of digressed all over. Uh, I
don't think I'm going to talk anything
about today's topic.
Um,
because I already talked for 40 minutes.
So, let's see. So, maybe this talk show
is just going to be
like a rant on programming languages.
Uh.
So, ubiquitous in current type
environment, hype environment. Yeah,
Python is super popular and
Python, the truly the worst language.
So, it's, you know, it's so it's like
amazing.
You see, so this is you can see it as a
as how the good things get buried.
Uh, but the bad things, the worthless
[ __ ] they became all over very popular.
Examples are C,
Unix,
Python,
PHP,
and we might count JavaScript as well.
Haha, okay.
Now,
however, there are a lot good reasons
for it because, you know, if we want to
trace the reason
why these languages, C, C++,
arguably Python,
and PHP, and JavaScript, why are they
popular? Meanwhile, a lot of us would
agree they really
they are quality is not very good. Bad
quality, but
however, they become super popular.
So, why does that happen? You know, we
don't want things like that to happen.
We want
good quality
programming languages or protocols to to
win, to become popular. The bad ones,
the bad technical quality, they fail.
But, that's not how things work. So, we
can So, we don't want to ascribe some
mister season, like the Unix [ __ ] heads.
You know, they will say, "Oh, because
because look at cockroaches.
They are so popular, that's why. Oh,
look, because Windows
Unix is so good, but it's not too
popular, but Windows is
Anyway,
for social issues, such as why certain
programming languages are popular,
that is mostly a social cause. Okay, so
it's a social
causes, not technical. Because
for a programming to be used or
operating system, you know, by people,
by corporations, by industry,
there's a social forces going on. So,
it's not just like
mathematicians reviewing
programming languages, and I think, you
know, we think this is the best one, so
we should all use that one. That's not
how it works.
So, for social causes, we can look into
social causes.
Um
So, there are many.
You know, so there are many social
causes, like um
For example, we talked about why, in my
opinion, why Python become popular.
Because two
Because Google, okay, for two cases. One
in year 2000, Google is a big company,
very loved by programmers, and they
choose to use Python, because the other
choice is what much worse, Pearl. So,
they
So, that made Python popular.
Then, in 2010, because of machine
learning, Google turned out a lot of,
you know, libraries that's written in
Python because that's what they use.
So, that
made Python very popular again.
So, that's valid reasons. Okay, that's
valid reasons. Not because you know,
some mystical or cult reasons or
whatever, you know.
Or earth is flat.
So,
yeah. And why is C popular? Well, for
one thing it's free.
The same thing like most of the Unix
things because it's free. Okay, why is
Linux popular kind of in the server
in the server enterprise sphere? Why is
Linux the most used? Because it's free.
You don't have to pay.
Not because it's open source.
That may be part of the reason, but
mostly because it's free. If you require
corporations to pay just $10 for Linux,
you know, it might die overnight.
So, so so the cause is a popularity.
Okay, so that's that's kind of another
thing to dive into.
Uh I have an article on that.
You know, I have like
I have an article on almost all the
things I talked about. Um
so there's programming language
popularity 2017.
There is um
jargons and why and what determines a
programming language's popularity.
Uh
and Clojure's popularity entangled with
Java.
Uh
and
uh then then then then lots of others.
Uh computer language popularity 1997 to
2006.
So, this is one of my
article back then is very popular, super
popular. Like
Like if you search for popularity of
programming languages, this article is
what you'll find. This is 2006.
Okay? I I wrote it in
what time when did I wrote it?
I think 2006, yeah.
And I included a chart. You know, back
then you don't have Stack Overflow yet.
You don't have GitHub yet.
You might have, you know, maybe they
just started. So,
you don't have this, you know, so you
know, you don't have many What what's
the other website that
TIOBE, you know, that's one of the
circuit's website for
popularity of programming languages.
Today is like the most popular. If you
just search for
you know, programming language
popularity. So, anyway, back then 2006,
this my article is the most popular.
Uh because
you know, I
grabbed
the mentioning of words What is it?
Yeah, new scoop traffic on different
programming languages and I made a chart
with Wolfram language, okay? So,
basically,
you know, basically C, C++, and Java and
JavaScript, okay? So, let's see. So, the
red is Lisp. You see, this red is Lisp.
You know,
So, this Now, remember this is 2006.
I'm a Lisp fan, okay? So, we Lispers
hope that Lisp is finally, you know,
it's going to become popular, but no.
[ __ ] the Lispers.
Because they believe in false
information, that's why they never
become popular.
And they you know, lots of other
reasons. So, the red is Lisp. The blue
that's C.
The green is Perl. You can see C and
Perl is like over.
Uh and the the pink you see there,
that's JavaScript.
Okay, so this is 19
to 2005.
Okay.
And the the other chart is scripting
languages. So, you have Perl,
JavaScript, Python, Ruby, PHP.
So, you can start you can see you know,
anyway.
Uh
So, what we going to
do? So, let's see
um
I wanted to
Well, there are several things I wanted
to talk about, but we
got digress into programming language,
okay? Let me may I think I'll do
some of these. We got
15 more minutes.
Read comments and do some of these.
Oh, we got lots of comments. How many
people watching? 13.
I'm a popular guy.
Is my video audio going good?
You know, sometimes I did entire 1 hour
but my video or audio is off.
Uh
Python, you know, so how long we will
last? We don't know. I mean,
it could die in 10 years, you know, like
it could.
You know, just look at
you know, look at Pearl. Now, remember
back in year, let's say year 2000, every
website, basically almost every 99%
is created by Pearl.
Uh but around year 2002, like also, it
took over PHP PHP took over.
Um
Yes, the Glorious 80 is fantastic
keyboard, okay.
You know, I talked about so many times.
I did so many uh reviews about it.
Okay, so let's see. Let's we going to
talk about next.
Linus Torvalds
Linking description doesn't work. Yes,
that's true because I haven't uploaded
it yet.
You know, that's the page right now we
are talking about I haven't synced to my
website yet.
Is there any reason why you choose um
Wolfram back then? Yeah, I talked about
that before.
I like Linux because I don't like
GUI-based program. That is also a bad
thinking, but you know. So, anyway, so
let me talk about a few things. So,
Wolfram language and um um
Yeah, so why why did I pick Wolfram
because back in 1992,
you know, I'm a math guy. I wanted to be
the greatest one one of the greatest
mathematician.
Back in 1992,
well, I was like 20 years old.
So,
but I'm also into computers. I love
computers. So, I want a you know,
computer algebra tool software that's
the best one.
So, I researched, you know, back then
you don't have internet, not really. Uh
you know,
but then you read books, you talk to
people, there's online forum like
CompuServe. Their opinions, you know,
they say, you know, Wolfram Mathematica
is the best computer algebra system. So,
I bought it. I read the 1,000 pages
documentation cover to cover, word for
word, three times over different years.
So, I become, you know, so I mastered
Mathematica.
So, that's starting around 1992.
And uh my next language is only in 1998,
Perl. Okay?
So, I don't know any C. I have no idea,
you know, I I haven't learned any
like I didn't go to I well, I I went to
college, but I only took math classes.
So, anyway, I learned, you know,
Mathematica just by reading the manual
by myself.
Uh then I started to learn Perl, you
know, the industrial thing. Like, what
the [ __ ] is Unix? What is tar? You know,
I was like back then.
You know, Unix is like this strange
thing. Oh my god, this like seems like
very advanced,
uh you know.
And then tar, you know, like tar so
silly, you know, like what what is tar?
And then I heard this GNU thing, GNU,
and I heard about this Emacs, like so
some kind of weird thing, you know.
So, 1998.
And and I don't know anything else, you
know, I just know Mathematica.
Learned by myself. I didn't go to a
college for like standard programming
course, like introduction to computers,
to programming, to operating systems, to
networking. Uh you know, data
data structures, algorithms, I didn't do
any of that. I just learned
Mathematica.
Today known as Wolfram language, by
myself, by reading the manual, like
1,200 pages.
I have an article on that on my website
with photos and pictures, you know, so I
have like just search for Google Saudi
search, you'll find.
Uh so
So, I don't have the normal, you know,
so that's how I learned Wolfram language
because I'm into mathematics, and
Mathematica is the best software
for doing mathematics. So, I mastered
it.
Then in 1998, I started to learn Unix,
like what what a [ __ ] is Unix? What is
Pearl? What is, you know, what is C? Uh
you know, and Lisp, you know, I heard
Lisp so much because
because Wolfram language is very much a
Lisp, you know, in the same kind of
community for mathematics, for
advanced computer science, for, you
know, theoretical stuff, for
you know, so
So, then then I started to learn other
languages, like the so-called industrial
languages, like today, Python, Java,
Pearl, Ruby, Bash, you know.
And
and it turns out, why are these
languages so [ __ ] up, you know? Like
in Wolfram language,
I don't know anything else. Like to do
this, I just this line. But in in other
languages, in in Pearl, you have to do
like five lines or seven line. Wait.
Why did Why does that happen?
Why are all these other languages and
then C? I don't understand. What What
What is
What is malloc? What What Why do you
have to do like malloc or what what
memory? What memory? What memory?
If I If I want a list, I just say
variable equals to a list of items. What
the [ __ ] is malloc and array and the
pointers? [ __ ]
I started to learn
like the reality, like like this
industrial programmer and file handle.
What the [ __ ] is a file handle? And file
descriptors.
You see?
I'm a mathematician.
A file is a thing on your computer. You
open it, you know, you say open file.
A function.
Then the argument, the file path. File
path allow you to specify, identify a
file. A file is a like computer
you know, item on a computer, you know.
Open file, file path. That's it.
What the [ __ ] is file handler? File
descriptors? Then you have to close the
file and all the bunch of like
error code and whatever whatever, you
know, like and bit mask and octo mask
and the the [ __ ] Unix [ __ ] heads and
[ __ ] C.
And and pointers, you know.
And so,
of course, now I know the answer. It's
quite interesting, of course, because
they
you know,
Wolfram language is a
Turns out, now I know, it's a high
higher level language, a magnitude
higher than all programming languages
even today.
Like
like Python, Ruby,
JavaScript, they are a higher level than
C, C++,
so in Python, you don't have to deal
with like malloc or thing, you know.
But then But then But then Mathematica,
Wolfram language is like a magnitude
higher than Python.
Okay, that's that is what's actually
going on. That's why in Wolfram
language, like, you know, you can do
this but not the you know, that's what's
going on.
So, in lower languages, you have to deal
with memory. You are working Basically,
you have a
programming language that's
that works with the hardware, okay?
So,
that is why.
Um
yeah, so that's how I learned Wolfram
Mathematica because I want to do math.
Uh
about GUI,
you know, that's another big topic.
Like, I have 10,000 articles about that.
Because one of the thing that the Unix
and C and Linux [ __ ]
why are they [ __ ] Because they are
idiotic
when it comes to certain things to a
degree
to a degree so severe
that whatever their opinions on this
topic, they are just like they become
idiotic and create harmful
opinions to society, to the programming
industry.
And that is why today
or back then on Unix, on Linux
everything you do on Linux or Unix, the
the graphical user interface is the most
idiotic, the most unusable.
Why? Because these people
you know, first of all, they don't care
for it. They because their mind has
certain way that you know, they don't
know about GUI. They They don't like it.
They don't you know, they cannot
properly think about GUI. They don't
They don't know.
They the the things these C and Unix
[ __ ]
what they love and what they do the best
is hacking.
Okay? They cannot, you know, for
example, Wolfram language, mathematics
far more advanced than their malloc or
memory.
And far more structured.
But it's too deep. They They don't
understand and they They don't like it
like when mathematics, you know.
They don't know.
They like the hack bit bit diddling.
They They are very good at it. C, Unix.
That is the heart of C and Unix and all
the things these people creates.
Okay? So So one of the relevant issue is
GUI.
Um
GUI, okay? So let's look for GUI.
Uh so I have some
relevant articles about that.
So
you got to go to
um
You got to search for graphical user
interface, okay?
So, let's search for
graphical user interface.
Uh
graphic, okay? User
article, do graphical user interface
make people dumb? Okay, that's that's
one of the popular opinion
from the Unix [ __ ] and from the
Emacs fanatics.
Very common opinion.
You know, they hate Microsoft. They hate
Microsoft words
because they in their belief that any
people, you know, it you make you make
GUI to make software easier, then people
become more dumb.
So, you have to forever create more GUI.
That's their opinion.
The idiotic opinion, okay?
Another article, a graphical user
interface versus command line.
Okay.
So,
and uh
uh Emacs terminal versus graphical user
interface,
uh several articles, okay? So,
so, it's a common attitude among Unix
Linux
lovers is that they hate GUI usually.
They love command line.
Okay, but they but their opinion in
general have lots of flaws. They
they they don't think deep. They don't
know much They don't have much knowledge
about things, about people's behavior,
about perception systems, about the
human brain. They don't know much of
anything. You know, they they they just
like the Unix and C hackers. They just
know bit diddling.
Very technical stuff.
They believe if you are a person who
cannot understand what's a bit, you
shouldn't use a computer.
A lot of them actually believe believe
that. So So they have So they they this
type of people, Unix and C, they created
lots of
bad information, okay? So I'm kind of
like quickly trying to describe it.
Okay, where is it? Uh here, okay? So for
example, there there is this guy, David
Castrop.
In 2010,
he wrote a uh
uh opinion.
David Castrop is one of the well-known
Emacs
developer, okay?
Back then, uh I don't know where he is
today, but back then he's very
he wrote a lot on the newsgroup.
So he wrote, you know, let me just
quickly uh
repeat, you know, recite what he says.
I think the point was that the manual
was not deficient concerning the
information it provides, but
in not making Saudi want to read it.
In a way, it is a losing battle.
People expect software to just work
without reading manuals.
95% of all Microsoft
Microsoft Word users, for example,
create their documents by mostly visual
manipulation of their text without
having a clue about underlying
structures, like references, style
sheets, and so on.
Okay, that's like very common opinion,
and he's trying to analyze the context
is about I think Emacs manuals, I
forgot. But there's a link to the
original on, you know, original post.
Um
you know, here.
So, anyway, so then then I retweeted,
that's called progress, you see?
One of the progress in technology
a general progress is that you do not
require people to know much things in a
in order to use it. Okay? So, today, for
example, your cell phone
it enabled
billions of people
to use a computer
without even knowing what is a website,
what is a browser. Like
most people don't know what's a browser.
They don't know what's a Wi-Fi. They
don't know what's the difference between
cell phone
uh
you know, net networking versus the
Wi-Fi. Like they they they don't know
nothing. They don't know what is a copy
paste. Okay? Like my wife don't know
copy paste.
Okay? But
it enabled a billion of, you know, like
half of people, like more than half of
people on Earth
to be able to talk to their
friends, grandma, parents, whatever
across the globe.
The cell phone.
Thank you, Steve Jobs.
He made it popular. Okay?
That's one example
of
of the of the characteristic
characteristics of uh
uh technological progress.
You do not
require people to understand how it
works in order to benefit from it.
Okay?
Now, if you leave it to the Unix
[ __ ] and the the C [ __ ]
you know, you will never have progress
like that. Like never.
All you get is like the bunch of like
tech nerds, like one in a million
in population, like us. You know, we
talk to each other. We love each other.
Hey what hack did you done? Did you
filter your firewall? Did you install
this or that? You know, like this this
this [ __ ] heads.
Okay, they have no idea how other how
other people how society structure and
so on works.
They just know what they you know, they
are they they they are concerned. You
know, this this nerds.
So, they have opinion on GUI. You know,
like GUI should be banned. You know, we
should all you know
You should be all like me. Okay?
Let's see.
You know, like
turn command line. The this is precise.
This is precise. Look, that's how
precise it is.
[ __ ] the Unix and [ __ ] the C [ __ ] heads.
I'd like to emphasize that because it is
not a troll. Okay? A lot of people say,
"K, you are a troll. You are the biggest
troll." They've been saying that for
like 20 years.
No, I'm not trolling.
I believe the Unix and C people, they
created a damage a huge damage to
computing computing industry
for like 30 years.
Okay? Even today, their damage lasting
even till today. For example, line-based
computation. Like when you do diff,
everything is line-based. Because why?
Because back in 30 40 years ago, Unix
truncate lines. When it's longer than 70
you know, 80 characters, they truncate
it silently, too.
By the Unix [ __ ]
Silent truncation. That's why
all the programming languages habituated
to line-based.
In particular, one of the big example is
Python.
Okay, what why do you have line-based
programming? Because
I mean, what what is a example of the
Unix damage that
we still have today? Python.
The entire language syntax is
line-based. Like you like line-based
then indentation. Okay, that's another
thing, but it first of all, it's like
each line is is a unit. It's kind of
it's part of the, you know, you cannot
have like
you cannot have automatic formatting
like Go from language I showed before.
Automatic typesetting, on-the-fly
formatting, you cannot possibly have
that. First of all, I give you the rule
that everything must be a line.
So, you are
you know, you you you are you are um
cursed to forever format each line like
tab or space like then let's argue about
tab space each each one of each line.
You have to format each each line.
That is the damage by from the Unix
and the C [ __ ]
Okay, they did damage to computing
industry.
Long-lasting.
And one of the damage to this day is the
line-based computation, the diff. Like
you if you join two lines even it's the
same statement, but the diff
will get confused. That's why today you
have like semantic diff,
which is like different, you know, you
know, you have that.
Okay, and counting of lines, line of
code, you know, that's another damage
like
you know, like
counting of lines as a way to measure
the program complex complexity or
program software power, you know.
Or programming effort, you know, very
idiotic. So, all this I attribute to the
Unix and C [ __ ] heads, those people who
spread them.
Okay.
And to this day, lots of like a Git
whatever you commit if your commit
message is longer than 80 characters,
it'll complain.
You know, "Please format your message,
you know, your commit message to
80 characters because otherwise it's
hard to read."
They don't You see, it's hard to read.
You see, they don't understand You see
this You see this?
This auto formatting,
they they forgot about it. When you have
anything code, they they forgot about
auto formatting. They think every time
your line reaches 80 characters, you
must manually cut it. Otherwise, you are
a [ __ ] head. By these Unix and C [ __ ]
heads.
You see, they they don't they don't
they don't understand this any
of this auto formatting.
You see?
You see? You see that?
And this this damage this about the line
truncation I talked about in my live
stream for like
three times in the past, like the whole
hour.
Okay.
And I learned
people don't This Unix people, they
don't get it, you know, they watch the
whole thing and they will still say,
"Oh, but it makes it hard to read."
Okay.
Okay, so let me let me try to explain
that.
You see,
it is true Let me try to explain that
again, okay? One one more time. Why not?
It is true
that lines
longer than 80 characters make it makes
it harder to read, okay? It is true.
However,
we do have the facilities of automatic
formatting so that lines do not go
beyond 80 characters. Okay? And this
automatic formatting of lines
is everywhere.
In your you know, in any text editor,
in your Gmail, in your browser display,
in HTML, in you know, in in in your chat
box,
it's it's like normal.
And it's better. You don't want to force
people to like count number of
characters. Oh, did I reach 80
characters yet? Press return.
Or oh oh, by the way, you need to
install the auto fill so that then you
will automatically insert a carriage
return when you reach 80 characters. You
automatically count for you.
You don't want that.
You want people to simply type and
whatever window size that will
automatically wrap it, okay?
That is the thing.
So that your line is not like 1 million
characters like you have to read from
you know, left to right. That doesn't
happen. It does doesn't happen anywhere.
But the Unix you Unix and C [ __ ]
didn't understand this. They will still
insist, you know,
you know, after this video, they will
you will see in the comment. Oh, but the
but it's harder to read. More than 80
characters it's too long.
You know, you incredible because you see
why I hate the Unix and C so much
because they
they are not just bad. For example,
Windows is bad enough.
But Windows is a commercial entity, you
know, they are bad for a reason.
They are bad because they are just
greedy.
They don't care.
They just want money. Okay, all I want
is money, you know, Bill Gates.
They don't care what actually is good or
bad.
They just care Bill Gates makes a lot of
money and whatever investors.
That's the reason Windows is bad.
Okay.
Part of the reason.
The other reason is because they are
big. They don't, you know, if they
improve it, it doesn't doesn't doesn't
make them more money. They already like
saturated whatever money they can make.
So, Windows is bad. Yeah, sure, there's
good reasons. They I, you know, they are
commercial. But the but the Unix
the Unix [ __ ]
they are bad but they insist they are
good. You see, that's the problem.
This happens with the Unix and C
[ __ ] and the Perl
because they create a cult.
You see what So, that's why all these
bad ideas
are persistent
to this day.
They they have a cult behind them.
You know, Unix is the best thing. And
today, Linux, of course. Linux is like,
"So, why are you not using Linux? Oh,
you you must be stupid because Linux,
everything I can control. Oh, and Linux
command line. Oh, it's so precise. You
know, you you you have to spend one 10
years to learn it, but it's good."
[ __ ] the Linux [ __ ]
Let me repeat.
I'm not trolling.
But I seriously believe
the Unix and C
phonetics
has done great damage to computing
industry for the past 30 years.
And in the past 10 minutes, I just gave
a example
from the line truncation, which
basically began with Unix. The line
truncation and its consequences.
Among them is the designing of the
Python programming language, which
forces you to manually indent each and
every line.
And other things, you know, like like in
Git message commit and in you know, in
lots of other things. In another
example, let me show you another example
of the damage of the line of the Unix
line thinking and also line of lines of
code, you know, I mentioned.
So, another uh damage, let me go to
Yeah, let me just mention that and maybe
that I'll be it.
Um
Okay. Yeah, about user interface, we
haven't finished talking about um
you know,
because we haven't finished talking
about that, but we digressed.
Um but um
Yeah, okay. So, let's let's go to um
yeah, okay. So, let's go to So, search
again.
Nagam, okay. Let's just go to
Death of a Troll. My memory of Eric
Nagam, 1965 to 2009, okay.
So, in this article, I quoted what he
wrote. You can see.
Uh so, you can see here is message he
wrote on newsgroup.
Okay.
So, here. That's um um
Let me Let me magnify.
Okay? You see, it's nicely formatted.
This is from New School. This article is
from Eric Naggum.
You see, he follows
a good boy. He follows the Unix or the
email convention. By the way, the Unix
[ __ ] made it into the
into the email protocol that you must
have a new line at the end of every
characters 80 characters or or or less.
You must have that.
You know, Unix [ __ ] made that into
the email protocol. Okay?
So, anyway, so this message by Eric
Naggum, let's copy it.
So, you can see
he he he he does format his code. So, I
mean
you know, so let's open it.
So, you see you see here.
Can you guys like what you guys are
seeing?
Uh
Yeah, okay. So,
you see, so how many characters are
there? Uh ruler mod.
Okay? So, 80 characters is here. So, his
line each line is less than 80
characters. Perfect.
Following the Unix convention. You see?
But now, the problem the problem is
this, you see?
Now, if your window becomes smaller,
you see, right now it's this nicely
formatted, you know?
But if your window becomes smaller, then
you got this [ __ ]
Okay? You got this [ __ ]
Why does this happen? This Is this what
you want? No, it becomes like [ __ ] up.
But why does this happen? Because
because this 80 characters per line,
this idea
is a type of physical formatting.
So, it's
fixed.
It's hard-coded.
physical
So, it does not adjust or adapt to
different window size.
Your window or viewport must be such
that it must be, you know, like
exactly 80 characters.
If it's longer, that's fine. But if it's
less, you got this [ __ ] up, you know,
wrap. Or all the the rest of lines went
into uh invisibility.
So, that's another that's this is
obviously this is bad.
You see, because the Unix people, they
don't want, you know, they like they
don't they can't think of the, you know,
the automatic wrapping they you know,
the
that's that's beyond them.
You know, they think you must manually
do this.
Okay, that's another damage.
Okay, I think that's it.
So, that's 80 minutes now, I think.
Uh
okay, I think that's it. Let me just 3
more minutes. I read the comments and we
shut down.
Okay, don't forget to pay me. Now, if
you,
you know, uh
like my stuff, just pay me. Go to
ksadi.info.
Uh and go all the way to the bottom,
okay?
Amazon gift card, click that link,
PayPal, and then you have to type my
copy paste my email address. I don't
have the like
nice link
where you just click there and then
directly you just type your credit card.
I kind of don't like that, but you know,
so you have to like you have to be
conscious. Like you actually want to pay
me.
Then you go there to the site, then you
copy paste my email address
and stuff.
Put money where your mouth is.
Um
Is there any reason why you choose Wolf
and yeah, I answered that. So I like
Linux because I don't like GUI. Yeah. So
so so GUI and and the command line
they have different advantages and
disadvantages.
You know, so that's scientific way of
approaching. Let me summarize it
quickly.
So GUI, I mean the terminal
Excuse me.
I smoked too much.
Um the terminal has advantage, the most
being extremely precise
and extremely powerful. Okay. So but
however, the disadvantage is that you
have to take time to learn it.
Now just like Unix and Linux, that's why
you guys love it.
You know, you
for example, what what does it take to
learn shell?
You know, a month. Bash or PowerShell,
let's say bash, you know, in in a Unix
environment. So you once you know it,
you can like I can write a pro-
program, like let's say, I want to open
this in terminal, I press two keys,
that's in
that's a Emacs command, you can see I
wrote it.
Open in terminal, okay? And magnify, so
you can do the
the
and the you can filter out, you know,
the let's see uh CD dot dot, so you go
to the previous the you know, so
it allows you precision, it allows you
power, but the disadvantage is that you
have to take time to learn it.
Okay? Now, if you do not take the time
to learn it, then you have no idea what
is going on. Like what what what do I do
with this? Like what what do I type?
What what commands? What does command
mean?
And okay, command is like oh oh you
explain that what's a command then? How
many commands are there? Like what what
is it?
Like I want to show a photo of my mom,
let's say. How do I do it?
You see?
You have to take time to learn it.
On the GUI, you don't.
And GUI usually takes much more time to
program, okay? Command line, it's much
easier to create
command line interface. But if you want
to create GUI, oh my god, that involves
First of all, it involves the entire 2D
graphical system. You need to be able to
draw. Somebody must be able must have
write that.
Okay? You Unix [ __ ]
You don't do GUI because your brain is
too small. You are incapable.
The this systems back then in 1980s,
they do GUI. They do graphics. They have
raster images and vector graphics.
The Unix [ __ ] and C, no.
Because they
they are simple brains, simple-minded
brain. They like bit fiddling and
commands, but they don't know how to
like mathematics,
uh matrix,
uh linear algebra.
Oh my god, you have to, you know, draw a
window. How do you do that? It's too
complex to fool them.
Okay? So, first of all,
GUI is actually much harder to do.
Even when you have a library, it's much
harder. And even when you have functions
to draw windows and buttons, and
especially like in in HTML,
you know, you can do do that
all in HTML today. Go to the DOM section
and go to, you know, radio buttons. This
is what radio buttons originally meant.
And here is, you know, radio buttons,
bird, bird, dog, cat.
And you can uh
create a buttons, you know, like click
me, click me, click click click click
click, you know. So, all these GUI, even
if you have a library to do it, such as
HTML,
it takes a lot time to design. Like,
where do you want to place these two so
for it to make sense? It takes
far more thinking.
Okay? GUI is far more difficult to
create.
Command line is much simpler.
You advantage is, well,
fast to create a command line,
uh precision and power.
But you have to take the time to learn
it.
GUI, anyone can use. When you if you
spend the time to program the graphical
drawing library to design the interface,
then anyone can use it. Your mom, your
pop, you know, you know, your dad can
use a phone, cell phone. They can use it
to look up Google Maps. They can use it
to browse the web to find what's news,
to find the weather. They can talk to
their grandma or whatever, your friends
phone.
Okay?
So, GUI is much actually much difficult
to create
and advantage is much easier to use.
But, it has a disadvantage, that is it's
less powerful. So, for example, GUI I
want to, you know, get all text here
involving certain word.
You can't, you know, you go find, let's
say, document, okay, one occurrence, one
that, you know, document. You know,
that's that's GUI.
You know, on the other hand, if you are
on
terminal,
you know, there it shows, you know,
everything that you can do it in the
command line, too, but
as an example, right? So,
So, all things said, all things
considered, which one is, let's say,
more important? Both has uses, of
course. For scientists, for programmers,
uh
command line, yeah.
But,
for non-tech people, GUI is much more
useful.
But, all things considered, if you can
have only one, which one is more
important for the entire Earthlings,
humanity? That would be GUI, okay?
Because without GUI, imagine all your
phone, all the phones in the world is
gone.
We are back to like
So,
that means all the collaboration, like
all the thing, much of the things we
know is gone.
Okay.
Diego purchased Mathematica, worth every
penny. Thank you. Yes.
Uh all the Wolfram compiler itself is
written in C. That is true because well,
you have to it's a low-level language.
Um what's this annoying thing?
Uh hey George, the same type of person
who likes Unix and C also likes Doc Mod.
So, that's funny. Is that true? Yeah,
kind of.
Uh yeah, I would a little bit. Things
are not black and white. They are
different requirements and different
people with different experiences. So,
different tools are better for different
tasks. That's kind of true, but that's
not a general theory, okay? Because a
lot of people will say, "Oh,
uh comparing programming languages
doesn't matter because different tools
for different people, different use
case." No.
It it's like saying, "Oh, comparing the
power of a tank and a Toyota car is
false because different tool for
different purpose." No.
Uh sometimes you need to compare which
one is more powerful. Tank is much
obviously more powerful in terms of
running down houses.
So, obviously tank is more powerful
when it comes down to running down a
house compared to Toyota.
But this But this which, you know,
different tool for different
people,
they will say, "Oh, you cannot. No,
that's not true, because different tool
for different purposes." Those are
idiots. Which is common.
I don't mean you. Okay, but it's kind of
common. Whenever people compare or
discuss the merits or the design
advantages of programming languages.
You know, like usually it's heated, you
know, a lot of them just just, you know,
you can argue with reason or a lot of
them is more
arguing because of religion, because
this language I know, I think it's
better than everything.
Right?
But then
they'll pop pop out It will pop up pop
up another group. It will It will say,
"Oh, you guys are silly.
Uh languages, they have different uses.
Therefore, I'm the most superior because
the [ __ ] That's another group I
despise, because that group always
dismiss, you know, if you are a thinker,
if you are talking about think things,
you know, deep analysis,
you know, which what are beneficial, GUI
or command line or or different
languages, their design.
That's the issue, because you have to
design there's good and bad.
For example, bad, let's say every
function name is 50 characters
compared to another system, every
function name is
like 20 characters.
The 50 characters, obviously,
it's like what what for? It's mostly
likely bad, right? So, that's a
technical,
you know, like actual point. You can
say, uh it doesn't matter. It matters.
So, yeah, so so when when you do deep
dive, then then there comes out a guy,
you know, oh
it doesn't matter.
Different people have different likings,
you know, so all you are thinking is
like stupid. It's too much philosophy. I
despise that.
Okay, bye guys.
That's a big rant on programming
languages 90 minutes.
Bye.
Shut down in in 2 minutes, okay? This
time shut down. Shut down for sure.
Show that let's reopen show that close
show that close show that close close
show that I'm just going to put links to
my talk show, okay?
Um
Yeah, so today's talk show we
basically did a rant on programming
languages and we didn't talk about
anything else.
So, yeah, let's copy all the things we
talked about.
Death of a troll. My memory of Eric
Naggum. Eric Naggum is a troll. He's
He's one of the top expert of Emacs of
Emacs and Lisp in general Common Lisp.
He's a fanatic of Common Lisp, which I
despise, but
but I but I like him. Uh so anyways, so
he died.
Um JavaScript in-depth copy.
We close down in 2 minutes, okay?
I'm just going to post link here, so
HTML button when we are talking about
GUI source code. Ubuntu Unity, that
sucks. That's another GUI issue.
Terminal width versus graphical user
interface in Emacs. Uh, you know, like
some people prefer to use Emacs in
terminal only.
Which which has a lot of
disadvantages because that means you
cannot display a image.
Uh, so for example, I have lots of
images here.
Uh, let's not go
let's go to the top.
All these are text.
JPEG.
Okay? You can display images. You cannot
do that in terminal. So, that's one big
advantage of running Emacs in a GUI
environment. You cannot do in um
in a terminal. And lots of other
reasons, okay?
And this article is about Okay, so we
know
that there are advantages and
disadvantages of terminal and GUI. So,
is it possible to have a system that has
the advantages of both?
Okay? That's what I think it is
possible. So, uh, basically you want a
GUI
interface but with with the
with the like
with the key system. Okay? So, for
example, on Windows you have press Alt
and T and you got a key system. So, you
press a sequence of keys,
it will call the command.
So, in this way,
you can have this system would be have
the
accuracy, the precision of the command
line user face, because each key
sequence will always produce
basically just call a command, okay?
Produce the same result. So, you got the
precision, and you got the
uh
ease of use. So, you don't have to learn
it. You can just oh, menu. You know, you
take a you know, 5 minutes to learn
about what menu is. So, you can you
know, you So,
I believe this is a system that has
advantages of both, okay? But, nobody
actually
uh follow this.
In order to actually
use this advantage, you need to be
pervasive. You need to provide all
possible commands as a key sequence and
available on the menu, okay? Like all
possible. Like in in bash, for example,
you have 1,000 commands, and each
command, you know, you have uh options
parameters, right? Optional parameters.
You want to be able to encode that in a
GUI
um
and be able to also provide options a
way, okay?
So, nobody actually do that fully, okay?
So, and but however, there are few
systems that's very close. One is Emacs.
It doesn't exact exactly follow it, but
but you can, for example, by the way,
Emacs 30, you have which keys. So, you
can see
So, you can I press a few keys, you will
call a command.
And and if I press them slowly, the
sequence of keys, you'll also show me
what's the next possible key.
So, this way is kind of the merge of the
advantage of the command interface and
GUI. So, I can
I have pre- precision.
And I have power, too, because then you
can give arguments to any of these
commands by
traditionally pressing control U first.
Okay. So, that's So, Emacs does that,
and the other one is Wolfram language,
okay? So, I'm not going to talk about
that.
Uh
Okay. Bye.