good morning guys
welcome to another episode of our talk
show today to 2020 January 12 Sunday 3 o
clock p.m. San Francisco time and today
we the scheduled topic is supposed to be
random but so random so if you guys do
not have any comments or questions or
topic if you have a topic posted
otherwise I'm going to start to do
random and that means I'm going to start
to work Emacs
I'm going to do live coding of Emacs
Lisp with explanation so and the thing
is in the description youtube
description you can see where we are
what what I just said and ok so I'm
going to just start to do Emacs stuff so
the first thing I want to do is let me
show you my art block ok so that is
actually today's today's image on my
YouTube livestream you can see this
image fantastic image good morning Kathy
so any topics Kathy otherwise I'm just
going to do eMac this live coding so I'm
going to begin so I have this blog blog
some art blog so you can see it's
basically all arts related stuff visual
arts animations and stuff and some of
them are beautiful beautiful to my eyes
and we have a lots of girls because
girls they are the beauty of humanity
and
and so you can see this this art blog
page is getting long so let me show you
how many pages 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 very
long 10 is like 40 40 screens so we have
Russian girls what are what are these
Russians to wardresses then we have
Europa in the book we talked about
several times then we have the white
magazine of least code some 40 years ago
1979 and this is a fantastic article by
the way and this is I mean my essay is a
fantastic essay and I talked about from
Lisp from this byte magazine cover byte
magazine is a old classic magazine for
programmers for amateur programmers
mostly and professional in a in a in an
era of 1980s and 1990s and 1990s and
this by the way this photo is taken by
this guy this has me the Mishnah me see
what how do you pronounce his name
Casimir maturing ok he is in I think he
is either Russian or East European
somewhere there I forgot exactly he's a
friend and he is a common base he's a
disc expert so he studied this and and
comedies and other lisps and in fact he
is also a lisp historian he has actually
written a book in in what language I
forgot what was it Russian or some you
you chronic or III I don't remember the
name ok but you can go to his blog ok so
he's got a blog here so he has written a
book on the history of lisp
so you see this this we what we were
chatting you know he doesn't his last
blog is 2013 I guess so
this guy this expert and you know you
his account of this history is contrary
to the common list [ __ ] you here
you know around the web you know like
like I mentioned many times before if
you have watched my video or watch you
read my blogs
you know this typically you hang around
the hacker news reddit you know they are
these communities to the Emax
communities they what you hear every day
about history about things is all fake
news fake news you know they are pushed
by these fanatics you know people who
really you know they really love these
comment-list they think he's the
greatest thing they think it's a
greatest thing since sliced bread
they think the diss Marco you know they
you know people are like that you know
you have the Emacs coupe you have the
common list group then you also do have
Python group per group goal and you know
trust goof haskell group you know they
or you know there are people phonetics
coat you know this is many of these hack
hacker type of languages have this code
and among this code if you are not
careful if you are not well if you are
not a learned man
you you you learn or everything's you
know not just this particular language
you know so if you are not careful you
will hear mostly fake news you know in
in Python groups in in Linux group in
this group things like that so he wrote
a book on the history of Common Lisp and
and I cannot read it but I chatted with
him so his story of this is not what you
hear is not you know so what I mean by
that so what's the difference
if you are a common Lisa you probably
know a lot stories and basically what
happens is that these people they want
to promote news or history or facts that
that is advantageous that is positive
about the thing that they love
for example commonly Spurs they were
just there their head is filled with all
the things that's positive about
comedies about how common lisp is going
to is the best language ever same thing
with Haskell people you know with their
monad and the whatever scheme people
with their tail recursion and Co CC
stuff like that Python people you know
the same Perl Emacs and bheem
so but anyway so you you read his so so
anyway check you may want to check out
he's this guy you have to look somewhere
you have to he was on Google+ but
unfortunately unfortunately these
[ __ ] corporates comes they spread
fake news you know Google+ and Google
censorship and Facebook and Twitter the
Google+ killed Google+ Google killed
Google+ about a year ago so all the
other posts in writing zarkan anyway he
has published the book so that's a
digression about this essay okay let me
copy it to my website actually I want to
start to do I want to start to code eMac
B's so let's go - so let's post that so
I in this essay I was talking about this
magazine so you look at them you you
know with a curious mind you study and
all the details then you find then you
start to read about a Space Odyssey the
movie not the way you think okay most
people they watch the movie oh this is
movie day and that's it but you hit dive
deeper why why is it made what what's
the background story it's a lot okay
so for example it says anyway I'm not
going to talk about this page anyway it
then is soon involves thus Spoke
Zarathustra and richest rose
you know the richest Rose is a famous
musician and a nice [ __ ] a philosopher
who is known for nearly me reason okay
so it's ready to this walk this this and
music classical music and then you start
to read about thus Spoke Zarathustra the
philosophy and stuff okay so that's
about that so anyway so back to my art
blog so most of them is pretty pictures
and this this creature you know it's not
not it's not just pretty pictures okay
this creature éxito this creature is
known for its regional regenerative
abilities they are quite a few creatures
that have that ability the most
well-known is of course lizards
you know lizards or gecko you cut off
their arms and they will regrow but this
creature is more so and actually there
are also other micro micro organisms
that has such ability and in scientist
stars you know by our biology start
studying it of course to benefit
humanity so anyway but but there's more
than that this creature is from known
for its regenerative abilities but by
the way this creature lives in like miss
Mexico Mexico there's a lake something
like that but this creature is also used
in a science fiction doom okay so have
you guys read iam dune deep fake ok
defect so anyways so this D fake that's
a topic subject
by day Morris actually I don't know
nothing about that I I have not even
seen it deep fake wait deep fake is that
okay I was thinking deep nude deep fake
so what what's deep fake or deep fakies
say AI software that generates fake news
in a believable way right
that's a deep fake so so this creature
is also used in in the fiction
Dhoom and it's used in a very dark way
okay
it's called AK so tank oXXO told tank
you have to look it up I'm not I'm not
going to go into because because then it
it gets into the the topics the topic
that's sensitive to the social justice
scan so anyway so there is this thing
called ax o Thoth ank of doom doom is a
epic epic science fiction you know
recounting the stories of thousands of
years generations with nations and
planets and the universe and different
Maps and what what happens to them Jim
I haven't read the book by the way so
this so back to my art blog art blog so
you have pretty pictures then you have
not just three pictures you know yeah I
love tits here we have a girl naked girl
tits sculpture so you have girls naked
girls and and by the way naked girls you
know like I said before they are the
center of humanity we evolved around
them throughout the edges age throughout
the it you know the edges in Asian you
know in white because they they give
birth girls not
the women girls young girls that's
that's why we are centered around them
men centers around them and girls center
around em - because all you have to
check for that is you look at women's
magazines it's all pretty young girls
women's magazines it's all pretty young
girls and it's on Hollywood everyday you
know the superstars they showing their
tits their ass with their naked dress
you know the ever forever ever more
creative naked dresses showing the you
know the 1,000 ways to show their tits
and ass young girls so here is starter
of neo P and so you know besides besides
being pretty you there is art there is
humanity you know this is a ancient
story of Greek mythology daughter of
Niobe so let me tell you what's the
story so why is that she what what's the
story of her she okay that that's going
to be a big story then you know since if
I gonna start to talk about Greek
mythology because quick mythology is 1
million pages 1 million pages ok let me
tell you the story yes you know summary
so you have this this girl this girl is
the princess
the goddess the Queen of pretty girls
the let me tell you what it is she is
the greatest speech of all times this
this girl her name is autumn as' she you
know she's like a princess you know the
she can do whatever she wants
and she and her brother Apolo killed 12
childrens of now now Niobe
so she she said that's her okay she and
her brother
Apollo killed 12 children of Niobe
why because Niobe boasted that she has
12 children far more then then then
Artemis mom no Artemis mom Artemis her
mom is yeah her parents is yours and
Leto
okay so they have zeros has thousands of
children's with which things are 10,000
women okay so but anyways us and Leto
have two children I think one is Artemis
her who is a goddess of her story varies
some sometimes he said goddess of most
you know but vagina birth oh no I got a
spelling error so I got correct that
vagina [ __ ]
mercy this vagina [ __ ] that's right
Artemis for her vagina beauty and
cruelty Artemis is a merciless vagina
[ __ ] she kills with her brother with
her arrow for petty much for pretty much
gaming that's what she does she so she
killed the 12 all of them 12 children
some of Niobe because Niobe boasted that
she has more children than her parents
so she killed them she and her brother
with an arrow like again you know again
and so that is the story of Niobe so
Niobe became a stone that's wet forever
crying forever
so you know it's interesting sometimes
you have this stone where I was shot
child I I've seen it like you have a
stone you you know you use a water spray
you know what a gun you you put water on
it and the water disappears right away
does anyone know what what what is that
I always wondered about that I don't
think I ever find out what what exactly
what's the name of such stone and what
is the property that makes it do that
does anyone know
like this I think this often happens
with the break as well since some some
break like you put water on it the water
tries to write away like within one
second you disappears right away does
doesn't matter how much you water you
put on it I don't know how does that
happens does anyone know the name of
such strong so anyway Niobe became known
as the you know she became by the Greek
mythology she is perpetually weeping so
that's that's about that
Niobe daughter of Niobe that's that's a
sculpture by what by who who is this guy
by ho t Saarloos kyani in Rome okay five
fifth century BC so this is two hundred
five two thousand five hundred years ago
this sculpture have you ever touched
something that's few thousand years ago
okay so that's about that and that's
about Artemis okay Greek mythology you
know there's tons of stories quick
mythology Artemis so anyway back to my
art blog so many interesting things and
many mathematical beauty for example we
have this hexagonal star roof this is a
architecture architectural beauty this
one is in China you know China in the
past 10 or 20 years has grow and grow
and you have so many things in China and
the Westerners don't know you know those
are the white people they they don't
want to believe it and they are in
darkness they don't know but they
thought what they want to believe is a
China bad you know they you know you
need to bomb them that's what they want
to believe they want mean why are they
they they have a instinct
teve you know it's purely in the brain
or all of us you have an instinctive
theater to filter out anything that you
don't want to believe because if you
believe it it may do harm to you you
know that this is a very interesting
phenomenon in in psychology because you
know you might think logically we want
to know everything that's true because
once we know the truth we can deal with
it better you know we all will fare
better we all have better outcomes for
things you know whatever whoever you are
once you know the truth then you can
make a better decision so that the
outcome will benefit you more but
however that's not the case
you know we our brain has speared in
theater so we actually we filter a
certain fact or truth we don't want to
believe that's why you have coats like
Emacs code Python code Common Lisp code
Haskell code you know some of these
examples codes they believe they believe
things and not not to mention political
codes and religion of course it's even
bigger political things and religion and
nationalism and you know so anyway so so
human animal psychology we it's building
you know by evolution which we so
apparently apparently this is this seems
like a paradox apparently human animals
apparently if we filter out certain
truth in fact that actually have
beneficial outcomes for us I think this
is a bit hard to explain why that is so
you know because well I know partly
because you know your behavior depends
on your because our codes too yeah I'm a
I'm a code I need to be a bigger coat
you know a small code like you know
fifty people watch
video says no codes I need to be vegan
and I need to generate money you know I
need to that's the thing that's the
thing about codes the code
leaders usually often often not not
always but often so anyway so it's a
very interesting phenomenon that about
psychology where you where certain fact
if you feel to it out it actually
benefits you and in part I think it's
because your behavior depends on what
you know and what you think your
behavior you know your decision who you
make friends with what what's your goal
your plan the way you think's depends on
what you know you know your experience
and if you feel to our certain fact
certain you know certain fact it
actually benefits you it's it's I think
it's hard to resolve that in some you
know to explain that completely but but
that's you know that is what what is
going on you know in this this this bias
in other words it's called bias this
bias is Bo Dini in the brain you know so
it's it's not magical you see that
that's the thing you don't you know we
are getting into the forefront of
psychology and neuroscience because if
you really think about it the
neuroscience or the brain or how we make
judgments how we judge things how does
that work exactly we don't know you know
to this day we don't know how that works
exactly yeah we have neuroscience yeah
we have neurons we understand you know
but we don't really understand exactly
how it works and also we don't
understand what is consciousness I mean
what self so you know it's we cannot
find a mathematically precise definition
for what is what is intelligence no can
we define what means you know
intelligence as in you know artificial
intelligence we cannot find a precise
definition no can we define what is a
conscious you know what is conscious
what is self-aware awareness for example
we kill pigs we kill cows and bulls we
kill we kill them because we think they
are brutes
you know we kill them for food you know
ants and insects flies mosquitoes we
kill them without much thought but and
we kill you know cows of course we
killed him and you know you go to
McDonald's you eat you know hamburger
let's have a hamburger that's that's the
meat of some dead cows or you know and
and then sheep and goats land lamb chop
I would like to have a lamb chop fries
so we occurred you kill them no problem
but American to the white people these
idiots these rights human rights animal
rights this and these idiots but they
they have a reservation when it comes to
say dogs or cats you know because who
know now you cannot cure it because dogs
is somehow you know we are we say dogs
are the friends of humans okay but what
about cows you know ma me I mean what
about quotes you know clothes are super
intelligent and we we kill where else
where else you eat them too you know we
the lots of things yeah I mean even I
mean the Chinese they eat even more they
eat everything but we let's limit us to
you know Americans you see ochio a lot
of things so I mean the point is so what
what what what makes a distinction what
animal you can say you kill that's no
problem and why other animals you say
that's all you cannot do that yeah
that's unethical
you know this human rights and I'm
alright this this rights idiotic concept
so
question is what what what what can you
kill what you can you kill what what
what is the definition no mori we say
those we cannot kill or we we do things
to them we think it's cruelty is because
we think okay we intelligence that's the
dividing line normally tradition okay if
you have an animal that's intelligent
then if you do something bad to them
youth you know we think it's not ethical
we have a problem with it you know
especially the white people for example
dolphins dolphins whales horse but
that's not a that's not a consistent
argument because dogs and cats they are
not really smart okay
octopus octopus and octopus and course
they are far more intelligent than dogs
and cats or horse for that matter but we
eat octopuses
you know we eat them but then we don't
you know but host dogs cats we think oh
this is you cannot eat them that [ __ ]
you know white people do you know so
it's not consistent so what you know so
you get into this problem anyway we
digress into that because I was talking
about intelligence you know you by
tradition you should usually use the you
use intelligence as the dividing line of
what animals you can kill and what
animal you cannot do bad things to so
back to so why did we mention about that
intelligence because we are we were
talking about yeah we started to talk
about you know how do you define
intelligence and and artificial
intelligence consciousness yeah
consciousness and the human mind the you
know so what I'm saying is that we don't
to this day we don't understand how it
works we don't really know so these are
kind of the ultimate question in
philosophy and we don't know what what
he says we have no idea so how do we get
into that topic so I was saying because
how did we get into the intelligence
topic because oh biases yeah the
interesting thing about why biases form
which biases actually so as far as I
know biases is building it's a natural
it's part of our brains fundamental you
cannot remove it so if you study this
Steve you know this even this fun this
thing about bias even comes up in
artificial intelligence for example
today we have self-driving cars and
usually you have a dilemma should you
you know you feel some choice you know
car when a bad situation and should you
kill let's say this one person who is a
professor oh this can't homeless person
which one should you kill like like
there's a meme where you have to decide
on a real track you either kill one
person or ten person you know to decide
so that meme came from came from I
suppose some artificial intelligence
research so the question is you want you
you want the self-driving cars or
certain artificial intelligence to make
a decision but the the thing is that how
do you make a decision you know
especially when it comes to ethics so
basically the current state of things is
that we can't we don't know how to read
we don't know exactly how to what is you
know what is more ethical what is not we
cannot make that decision so this is
connected to bias that's what I'm
talking about so I'm here so this is
connected to several things
justice bias artificial intelligence
philosophy ethics you know philosophy of
ethics and you know psychology so what
I'm saying is that this filtering
mechanism fioating filtering out things
you don't you don't like it is part of
us you know it's it's we we have it from
evolution and it seems strange that you
filter out things you don't believe that
actually benefit you and that's the that
is how to explain that's that is what
I'm saying and and so what I'm trying to
say is that we so far we don't
understand how all these things work
because in order to in order to
understand how it works you have to drag
in basically you have to understand what
is what woody you have to know what is
intelligence what is consciousness
what is self-aware awareness and you
know all these you know so we don't know
the answer so far so back to the back to
my art blog so we have a lot of things
and this is David Lee Roth he is a rock
star
you know he's one of the top rock star
in 1980s
you know he's old he's he's a nerdy
character he's on YouTube doing his show
he's doing a show on YouTube you know
but he's now you know 30 years old older
so he's like 60 probably years old and
he's a nerdy guy but but this is one of
his most popular video California Girls
song in 1985 so I'm going to go through
my okay so many interesting things this
is this one is a commercial made by
Motorola and they are making fun of
oppose 1984 commercial so let me show
you this is
this is this is one of the most
commercial ever you know in human
history apples 1984 commercial and this
commercial if you haven't seen it you
know go see it go to my saw arts page
you know go to my page and you can see
it so good so let's go to okay so let's
sync my website and then go back copy
the file path paste it here make a link
copy it close and I go here I paste it
so you can go to that website then you
will find my link to my art blog then
you scroll down then you can get to this
commercial you can watch it okay so this
commercial is very popular weekend and
it's popular in part because it alludes
to George Orwell's 1984 his novel his
dystopian novel which is a big topic by
itself so this is this happened in 1984
but but in 2000 in in what year in 2011
Motorola Motorola made a commercial that
makes fun of Apple you know all these
white hooded people they are Apple
people you know with their white year
Europe year birds like visco so Motorola
made a commercial that's that's that's
taunting Apple and so that's interesting
okay so that's about that so that's my
art blog so I'm going to go down there's
quite many interesting things and some
of the some some of them are internet
history for example this one this guy is
a very funny
very popular around years early year mm
mm - you know things like that very
popular this before YouTube became
popular okay that there's like so many
interesting interesting things on my art
blog and this one this guy who drew this
one Kim Jong gee he is one of the
greatest illustrator on earth okay
probably one of the top five or top
three greatest living illustrator you
know maybe top ten in history of
humanity so he's one of the greatest
illustrator I've seen there are many
YouTube videos of him he draw things
live you know he he can draw this just
well meaning illustrator skin you know
you just start to draw it very fast no
but and also no mistakes I mean if
there's a mistake he just keep going so
he draw this in VO time in terminates
something like that in it's like you
have this in real time without without
having a model or having you know some
photo to copy he just like destroy it
start from scratch without looking at
anything so this guy Kim Jong ji but
however I don't I don't like his hard
work you know when you look at artworks
oh god we got to not-safe-for-work
stuff so when you look at this
when you look at a artwork artwork they
they they within it within the work it
embeds the style of the artist and it
embeds the personality of the artist so
this kingdom a king king jinji guy he's
a great artist but I look at his artwork
i I don't like his artwork that much
because
there is a certain personality certain
perspective of the world
you can see his artwork I don't like
that style I mean he's kind of like he
looked at the world you know you can
look you look at his artworks you know
hundreds of them and you can see the
character of this person in the same way
you can see that in a novelist you know
if you read certain novelists you can
see the character of the guy the author
Stefan clean or you know many science
fiction writers or other novelist but
anyway so I look at this Kingdom his
artwork I see this guy he's he's got a
worldview a perspective of the world
that is some some somewhat a similar
like sloppy and happy-go-lucky you know
like careless you know he doesn't he
doesn't care you know that kind of
attitude so I I didn't really like his
work and biology is another great is a
classic French movie okay so lots of
lots of interesting things and here it's
an interesting thing you have the Hugo
the this is a character in the video
game Street Fighter okay but however you
see what's interesting thing about this
drawing is that they have you know art
works are often exaggerated for the
dramatic effect okay so this is you know
one of the character
so this Hugo so you can but here you see
this girl is super small you see this
car it's pretty girl is so small sits on
his shoulder and this giant guy you know
do the fighting it's interesting and
scientifically this is called sexual
dimorphism
where the male and female of the same
species become very different you know
they differ greatly in some cases they
differ greatly in their size in their
physical size and this is also true for
human animals males are bigger than
females but in other species it it's
very big difference like Mayo is this
big females they speak something like
you know something like that so this is
called sexual dimorphism you study that
when you study biology you know you
study you go deep you know in college
you take intro biology then you take you
know you you learn things okay you learn
cellular biology microbiology you know
you go learn things and here is another
architectural beauty this is again in
China this you see this like they have
hundreds of these like hundred literally
hundreds hundreds of these amazing
architectures in China
well elsewhere elsewhere too but but in
China a lot more you know incredible so
you have this tree tree like building in
China fascinating you know I was so
amazed by these Chinese things you know
like you know how do you find this thing
well you can you can follow some Chinese
on Twitter you know the Chinese some
channels so you see turn of it every day
like the big you know train like they
have the you know pulley trend like 2020
rails in parallel Jesus like 20 wheels
so so then you see the train then you
see these buildings hundreds of them
every day you know there's new then
skyscrapers then bridges you know the
longest bridge you know the beautiful
fantastic you started to see this like
oh I see I started to see it you know
like every day you know and I was just
then you know this is genuine amazement
you know I'm like I'm America American
I've never been to China so I live in
America you know and you know America we
have you know we have San Francisco we
have New York we have you know Chicago
or Los Angeles you know skyscrapers we
have we have skyscrapers we are the
first one to have lots of them
record-breaking but then but you started
to see this this China things they drove
they trough your American Fox okay like
American today you have nothing nothing
new everything is like hundred years old
you don't have anything new you don't
have new skyscrapers you have nothing
meanwhile you see in China and other
places you know in in Dubai you see lots
of these going on the biggest bridge the
biggest I'm the biggest satellite the
biggest biggest radio dish embedded in a
mountain you know things like that so
you don't see that but meanwhile you
talk to typical Americans like I know
you know on my discord see they they
like don't know a [ __ ] okay
meanwhile they have this very strong
American buyers they you know they they
don't in meanwhile they don't know a
[ __ ] they are thinking Oh China is just
corrupt it oh they just evil or they
just whatever you know meanwhile on the
on the news in USA papers every day you
see is like stupid things you know
propaganda China evil basically just
China you go China
Evo this channel you go that but the
real life things like these buildings
you don't you don't see you don't you
know this you don't see so I'm I'm
literally change annually amazed by
these things going on in China then you
have this okay this poster Lolita okay
this this is a classic film which again
the white people
white men okay it's a taboo you know
they don't know how to deal with this
issue when it comes to this thing that
there is a word okay I don't want to
mention because in in the white guy's
mouth every day is like what they have a
few words that they that that that they
chant every day it's in their brain did
they cannot escape it like they are they
they are forced into thinking about
about about five or ten terms every day
so anyway this poster is about the film
classic by Stanley Kubrick okay so I'm
not going to talk about that too much
and in Brazil is another great fantastic
science fiction okay it's it's also
about dystopia Brazil and this girl this
this woman is fantastic is she is
fantastic four zero okay it's a
fantastic movie science fiction you
should go watch it so anyway so I was so
I'm going through my okay then then you
have some of the greatest solar tower
you know thermal energy you know
renewable energy this one is in China
again in China but you also have some
USA ones okay so let me show you some of
some of these this one is in France this
one is in in USA I think yeah I think
this one is not no but wait is it in USA
I forgot where Isis and this one is in
Spain I think your spin you know about
solar panels so I'm very much into so
this is a different style of solar
energy they concentrate light way into
the pipe in the middle
you know a difference so it's very
interesting to study the efficiency of
these different styles of solo energy so
you have massive erase of it I like I
love these kind of things I love it so
you so you can see so you know so I'm
very much interested in these things
here is another style parabolic mirror
they concentrate the sunlight into this
thing in the middle so they heat it up
and here is another one so I'm I'm very
attracted to these things but how you
know and and also the wind turbines let
me show you some of the wind turbines
they are beautiful you know some some
people they think these are I sauce but
I rather I think I think they are
actually beautiful to my eyes I love
seeing him this hot gigantea okay you
see this you see this that that thing
there that's a human is like this tiny
over there you know so this is like 20
stories high 10 stories high no more so
you usually wind turbine is like 120
meters okay so this Archer gantry you
know you have array of them and this one
this one is in Sweden and actually one
of the person his dad works with these
things so his dad goes into one of them
and take a photo and in this guy you
know he seems Swedish he sent me in the
photo about in 2006 so you know he is a
Emacs user so that's how we you know we
know each other he sent me this photo
because he saw me collecting these
photos what's his name and the spark god
yeah and the spa god okay so I wonder
how he is doing so
this is you know this is 14 years ago so
he sent me this photo in Sweden and some
other photos I took oh I I took all my
friends you know my real life friends
sent it to me and this this one I took
so anyway wind turbines okay fascinating
but you know then I learned I learned in
the past few years that wind turbines in
the solo energy they are crap okay we
have been brainwashed especially
California in California here you know
the California the very progressive
state in USA we we have been brainwashed
to believe that these are great things
because I believe them I really I love
them I love how they looks I love how
they works I love the technology you
know and I love how they works you know
that you know so I believed in them for
like 20 years but until the rise of
social justice in studying in 2016 I
started to read you know all the you
know why are they thinking about these
things or that things so I started to
read a lot of things then they I learned
eventually you know two years ago so I
learned the truth that these things this
renewable energy this solar and an wind
turbine they are like do nothing okay
compared to nuclear energy what you want
is nuclear energy that's ten times more
efficient something like that then this
this then these solar panels or wind
panels these are like petty they are
just decorations they are and and partly
they are pop agonda and money they make
money for certain people you know that
that's so we have been brainwashed to
believe in them so anyway so so that's
my some of my interesting photos and
stuff you know usually my collections
are things contrary to your opinions
contrary to your PV
that's the things I like to talk about
why because what's the point if I talk
about things everyone already knows
already believes so I talk about some
other things especially because I'm
American I live in USA so I hear the
news from typically white people and
today the social justice can they are
far worse they are much more worse but
they don't see things they don't they
don't know things okay for example this
this sign okay this sign is one of the
things that's lodged in white people's
mind every day every day they talk they
talk about that they cannot escape like
their brain is like deformed its creeped
out by certain you know bite by certain
thoughts so this so these white people
they don't know they don't see this they
don't know these things and these things
this Buddha it is not some obscure thing
that you have to dig you know in history
in archaeology that's not the case in
Asia Asia Japan China ok Taiwan Hong
Kong in South Asia you have more
population than Europe in America ok
more people being Asia then also
including India ok China India Japan ok
you have more people than you then
Europe in America and Australia combined
ok these white people countries more
people in Asia and every person in a
seer know about this but in America for
example the white people when you show
them this oh they are like hope my god
what is this Jesus this should be banned
you know they they never seen this
before they don't know that's a
situation that is a situation I'm
talking about that is a situation why am
i have contrary opinions I'm showing
this because I because what do you
believe is not truth you you you are
like 1 plus 1 equals 2 3 every day you
know that's that's what's happening so
so that is why
collect these photos and also the photo
by itself you know it's deep okay people
human animals we human animals created
this thing you know this sculpture it's
not it's not something you can just
create try to do it you know try to go
ahead and do make one make this thing
today you will see you cannot do it you
see this this I'm not sure how big is
this you know this is sculpture it takes
a team you know 100 thousands or a city
to build it so it's a human artifact you
know human sometimes somewhere in some
region they created this and of course
this is part of the religion this is
Buddhism it's another big topic just
like for example in Brazil I think st.
Paul or some some large city you have a
giant huge Jesus you know like in this
posture and of course then USA you have
the freedom goddess you know in New York
which is a gift from France so you have
to look and understand things
not from your narrowed you know your
comment you know the idiotic sources you
have to broaden your mind and here here
is a piece of history okay here's a
piece of internet history now look at
this this is back in 2000 what year is
this I have the year
I think it's 2005 or something around
there this is at Google you see that now
today you cannot do that anymore
so this this photo is a it's a piece of
internet history and some are
significant
you can see a cultural shift here and
this guy again that's he this guy is a
piece of history
he's the his this guy his name is Vic
Gundotra I think okay so wait I'm not
sure it's actually him but Vic on Dora
is a guy Indian blood he was the lead
you know some top manager top leader of
Google he was the lead of Google Plus he
tried to push Google Plus to become the
social network you know because of the
threat of Facebook and eventually he
failed and gave up then he quit he quit
Google you know so here is a piece of
Google history and also a piece of
internet history and history of American
culture so you can see back then this is
kind of fun ok and we have lots of it
this is Google
I think it's Google Halloween or
something where Google people have fun
you know engineers back then it was
Google was good this is mm but today
Google is mostly just social justice
lawsuit you know Google you know those
who this feminism lawsuit trans lawsuit
Google suing you know Google firing
people you know then the Google firing
people criticized this or that and
Google firing activists you know some of
the soldiers you know it's a lawsuit
it's a lawsuit lawsuit games those huge
circus and this one is the beginning of
Google+ she is she's kind of actress you
can you can watch a video on Chrome this
video does not show up in Firefox
because Firefox does not support MKV you
know again here is another very
interesting history of ok here now this
is about history of technology as you
know we you know we technique us know a
good morning hello beautiful people
I'm gonna agree the comment singing a
bit okay I already talked up about 57
minutes okay I think I do 10 more
minutes in this thought so internet
history here is a piece of internet
history two aspects one is the history
of Google Plus this is a video of
showing this car scene scene II mean
kind of a song about Google Plus this is
when Google Plus began okay hold on a
second there's a Jesus
be right back
okay I'm going to stop that's about it
for today's talk show and and let's see
my store life so that's about it for
today's talk show I was going to do some
Emacs but we talked and talked
then stop so I was saying I'm going to
read the comments for five minutes okay
so I didn't catch up hello beautiful
people anyway so I'm talking about this
beginning of Google history of Google
but the other aspect is about technology
the history of or the politics of movie
codec movie formats you know video
formats in the past 20 years you see
here's a very interesting thing and and
this this relates to open source the
politics of open source you know as you
know I'm against the typical open source
and free software of phonetics you know
here is an example why you see this
video codec this video is not showing in
Google in in Firefox okay let me show
let me show this video in Google Chrome
so right now I mean Google Chrome and
this video shows up you can play it
[Music]
so that's you know this video was some
sort of meme on Google+ when Google+
began in 2011 okay so this is like nine
years ago so it's a piece of history and
I'm recording it and so the thing I want
to talk about is the video format so the
video format MKV is espoused by all the
open source people they love it because
they say oh it's open source and also
it's technically superior things like
that but mainly because it's open source
but an open source people they usually
often also chant about Firefox you see
right now I mean Firefox you can see but
however in Firefox you cannot play this
MKV video but you can do it in Google
Chrome so this you see this this open
source is seems there's a problem why is
that the question is why is that this
Firefox browser loved by all these open
source fanatics does not support this
video technology that's also open source
and and and loved by this open source
phonetics why is that have you guys
thought about that have you guys why is
that
good morning bond is it open source I
don't know I don't know this MKV but I
know it's a format that open source
phonetics love okay so let me so that's
about it for today let me read the
comments which we we stopped in in in
three minutes five five minutes okay
okay since I started to talk about my
art
Prague I cannot stop because this one is
another great fantastic interesting
thing this guy Richard Williams wrote
this book the animators survival kit
okay this is a classic you know it's a
loved by all anyone who who do
animations or have professions in
animation you know animation is a big
big business today you know movie
Japanese animation or with Disney
animation or not even though commercials
you know you have to have animations and
also illustrators and artists you all
involves animation animation is very
different from from Troy from from anime
or from drawing static cartoons okay
anyway what I'm saying is that this guy
so this book is well known and you know
the it's a classic the best book for
anything related to animation and that's
one thing okay but more than that
animation when you read this book or
look into the details animation involves
you know Emma animation is so such a
fascinating thing like when you watch
Disney Mickey Mouse Mickey Mouse or
other characters you can see you can see
their expressions what they want you
know the who they're even even Mickey
Mouse is not human but you can or
Finding Nemo you know the modern movies
you can see their desires you know just
like another human animal and how do you
get that you see you you you you read
them through the lines through the lines
so not just not just a static image of
their face but you also much of it came
from their motion that is body language
so which you know in fact body language
can't you know it's it's significant in
some cases the maturity of the content
of human communication
and that brings me to the nuts the
[ __ ] nuts okay most programmers you
know nuts we you know we don't want to
go on to video because Oh Todd you know
text is sufficient you know they don't
want to go on video for many reasons but
they are just idiotic they don't know
about all these things body language
okay body language in many cases like
when you watch me okay I conveyed far
more like hundred times more then it's
possible in writing okay so anyway so
let me read the comments and that's it
for today
so I haven't been reading comments and
witness read the comments and that's so
I'll shine says that guy the Lisp expert
is from kosha I think okay so we talked
about this this expert before and he is
in kosha okay so where is it here yeah
wait this guy this guy Casimir Shirin
Casimir maturing okay he's on in
question how do you know so sunshine
so outshine all shined so you know okay
so we got quite a few so I'm gonna read
the comments for for two more minutes
and let's stop pickle this okay so lots
of comments I missed
hello beautiful people I got my Chema's
track today oh my god
Cathy you you bought that Cathy show us
photos you have to show us photos and
you bought that thing amazing Cathy says
I bought in pieces assembled at home
it's 40 dollars cheaper Wow they put my
pieces back to multiple times
okay so Cathy says double Chema's track
not chair mounted brown switch and quote
I am glad I didn't go straight to work
it's a bit harder to get used used to
than I expected yeah hello beautiful
people says every single Rock I touch
was formed millions of years ago yeah I
was car when I was about to mention that
exception no except rocks and trees you
know of course that doesn't help I'm
talking about you have to have you ever
touched something that is human-made and
that's a few thousand years ago then
that's the question very few people have
I mean you you you could go to museums
but usually you are not allowed to touch
you know please don't say we eat
everything then we Chinese don't have
friend Thank You Moscow he was much
longer than the time they say you get
used to it he Mouse okay beautiful
people keys
so geez
so Kathy says I actually actually find
some Chinese sellers manufacturing this
stuff with less than 150 yo hope there
will be more people interested greetings
greetings sparked tired pretty much I'm
gonna go sleep bye send you information
okay Cathy edge asked you to send pics
of your stuff pics of my stuff
she has already seen already seen ok I
think that's it for today guys thank you
for watching and have a good day
I'm gonna shut down