good morning adventor Advent of code
welcome to another episode of EX talk
show today we are going to do Advent of
code in wolam language AA Mathematica
okay let's begin there's a lot to do so
Advent of code so it's going to be
probably 1 hour or even more uh so my
keyboard This is kesis 360 search go to
c. info and search my website kesis 360
I have a review and video review and
this is automate hacking keyboard I use
it as a marro keypad okay so let's go to
let's start aand of code okay I haven't
read the problems yet uh so I want to do
this all fresh uh do I have it open here
somewhere
no okay so we can so I open it here
here so let's uh let's begin okay
Mathematica Advent of code hello Joan
hang hello hang
so day one Tri uh Tri chat now what is
Tre chat okay I don't know what is Tre
chat let's
see uh what is this so S Talk Show yeah
day one Advent of code TR chat so look
up dictionary
uh what is triet a medieval catapult for
hurling heavy stones of an employing a
long
sling
Christian Christian Christianity gets
fancy something wrong with the global
something wrong with global snow
production and you've been selected to
take a
look Global snow production okay the
elves have been given you a map on it
they've used stars to Mark the top 50
locations that are likely to be having
problems you have been doing this long
enough to know that to restore snow
operations you need to check all 50
stars by December
25th collect Stars by solving puzzles
two puzzles will be made available on
each day in the Advent calendar the
second puzzle is unlocked when you
complete the first each puzz grants one
star okay 50
stars
uh two puzz a
day okay something like that you try to
ask why they can just be a weather
machine now there's a link what does it
link to Advent of cod.com 2015 yeah God
Jesus linking to its own history to
promote itself anyway you try to ask why
they can be just weather machine or
weather machine not powerful enough and
where they are even sending you the sky
and why your map looks mostly blank you
sure ask a lot of questions and hang on
did you just say the sky of course where
do you think snow come
from when you realize that the elves are
already loading you into a trible
chat please hold still we need to strap
you in what the idiocy now they now how
do you pronounce this word travor chat
they kept mentioning this word uh elf
and bunch of elfes and stuff so let's
see Tri triet tribia shet probably a
French origin or something
okay so this uh you know all the fluff
things that you don't need to know in
order to solve this puzzle this this
kind of this is a sto storytelling way
of a essay lots of flu like 10% real
content the 90% is just
dressing okay so anyway what is the
problem as they are making the final
adjustments they discover that their
calibration document your personal input
okay has been amended by a very long by
a by a very young elf who was apparently
just excited to show off
her art
skills okay so she made a mistake
probably consequently the elves are
having trouble reading the values on the
document okay now we are getting real
the newly improved calibration document
consists of lines of text okay lines of
text each line originally contain a
specific calibration
value okay each one line contains one
value that the elves now need to recover
okay on each line the calibration value
can be found by combining the first
digit and the last digit in that order
to form a single two-digit number okay
so for example this is the input uh
okay first digit and last digit okay so
what is this so wait can you guys see no
you cannot okay so wait H I need to make
adjustments okay now you can
see so the ad Advent of code
triet how do you tri Tri triet
tribet tribet that doesn't that that's
not a proper English pronunciation
that's that's wrong we need to look of
other dictionaries okay let's do let's
let's let's take it slow and digress
okay look up all
dictionaries okay they even spelled it
wrong
what wait okay capital letters edotic um
you know edotic Wiki W wiary if you have
capitalization wrong they don't show the
result okay so let's see
atmology medieval Stone throwing engine
of War so CA 1300s in Anglo Latin from
early 13th century that means 12 thou
1200s from old French
Treet okay Stone throwing engine and
from the four to the ground over through
11th century from TR Latin trans here
expressing displacement plus old French
Buck trunk bulk from Frankish Buck trunk
of the body from Proto
Germanic used in forming words Loy
associated with
swelling okay a swelling bomb a flying
bomb
basically a medieval flying bomb but
what I wanted to know is the proper
pronunciation so let's tret triet no
that's not good wait ah God okay so
let's look up uh Google
then I don't think that's a good okay
there's a picture so this is what look
at
like
uh britanica I don't want britanica okay
let's go to uh let's use
Google
magnify uh let's see
Wikipedia yeah Wikipedia is the most
smallest font
idiocy
okay they don't give the they don't give
a
pronunciation I want the IPA
pronunciation
fics okay God a little problem takes so
much
work where is
the the worst dictionary the Mariam
Websters are bridged that's huge
marketing everywhere but now when you
need it it's not here
okay
Define now there it
is okay you need to turn on JavaScript
Google wants to know where you
live trebia okay uh edotic word edotic
word used by this when you see when you
see someone's writing this guy Advent of
code of course obvious I mean he's a
Christian you know actually he's a you
he got a YouTube channel talking about
this we did this last year by the way
2022 uh and I stopped at problem six uh
so and join Discord so we have you know
we have a channel discussing this uh
Advent of code 2023 we also did 2022
okay so you know lots of discussion so
join Discord you go to kali. info you'll
find the link the invitation link okay
so this guy you know when you look at
someone's writing you can kind of tell
that he's personality his mentality what
his his environment you know things like
that uh and his style from his style you
can derive you can you know derive
certain uh guesses guess about the
person the character okay so anyway he
you know this elaborate story Tri sh
let's get on to the point okay so for
example this is a input line so the
first digit is and the
last the okay the first digit and the
last digit in that order to form a
single two-digit number okay so in here
we have uh some of these lines doesn't
start with the digit okay oh well okay
so you see is correct because first
digit doesn't mean the first character
so the first digit may be somewhere in
the line okay in this example the
calibration values of these four lines
are 12 check 38 check
15 check okay and 77 check okay adding
This Together produces 142 okay consider
your entire calibration document what is
the sum of all of the calibration values
okay again my criticism you know this so
we are talking about uh writing a puzzle
programming puzzle with a story to go
with it okay like the guy this guy did
uh problem okay uh flaw or imperfection
you see the way he made made up this
story for this
problem uh the the essence of the
problem has not nothing to do with the
story you see the story and the essence
of the problem are are
disjointed why because you see in this
example the calibration values of these
four lines are this this uh and the the
problem is that you want to find the sum
of all the calibration values okay now
what is the sum has anything to do with
the story he has given like so far
according to this page none I mean what
why does the Al needs to needs the sum
of these values right each line is a
calibration value but why do you need
the
sum okay that's that's a a that's
analysis that's a critical theory that's
a of the literature okay that's my take
my judgment okay so we we know the
problem so let's start uh to solve this
problem okay so let's get the
input uh uh text okay input do I have uh
text okay start a text block uh wait
what okay so pop it out so uh you got
this input so what you want to do not
the solution the algorithm is that you
go through each line for every line you
find the first digit and the last digit
okay that you can easily do with regular
expression for the first digit now for
the last digit what do you do uh regular
expression
um how do you find the last digit so can
um I don't know so far so you can
do you know in when when solving a
problem you have many issues you have
efficiency concern you know you have the
algorithmic
speed you know uh complexity
so-called uh from computer science point
of view basically how many
steps algorithmic complexity so you have
that concern you also have a storage uh
efficiency concern and of course then
you have the Elegance of the code
concern so we are just doing this
problem which you know in general
usually people people don't talk about
this this this this hacker you uni see
hacker idiots they don't they don't
actually you you never see you almost
never see they analyze things like this
but anyway so but in general in general
when you want to code you want
um so yeah my usual habit is to analyze
a thing too much let's just get on okay
but right now the problem is how do you
find the last digit okay what way you
can do
it is just to split the lines into a
list then get the last
element you know that's obvious you know
that's uh inefficient but obvious
solution uh
but okay we can't just code we actually
have to think so how do you get the last
digit of a line in a line now let's see
can you use regular expression then um
can you use a regular expression let me
what you guys are saying bu broken good
morning
uh please read chat wam can speak speak
oh yeah we need to try that one okay
yeah wolam language I discovered so
let's uh start a wolam language and
speak okay and the word is triple chat
okay
uh okay so now you know you uh you have
to go to wam language to so we are doing
we did this yesterday let's start a new
one um yeah close it don't save don't
save a new
document okay a new
document paste it and uh magnify
160 okay put here shift enter to
Fantastic
let's let's do this uh 10 times
okay
table okay that and
uh then x
uh yeah this is the problem with the
when you don't have emac X to 10 okay
that's
TR
Tred
Tred okay trbu shed trb shed I don't
like the sound of that word
uh those of you trollers stop that okay
there some kind of
troll okay so Tri your [ __ ] okay so um
okay let's solve the problem so how do
you get the last digit
though let's see regular expression
regular expression
um you can use just use pure regular
expression
and yes yes and
[Music]
no yeah I I I don't know that you know
it's possible I think
uh so the question is can you re use
regular expression in one shot to get
the last digit in a string in one shot
okay not not repeated regular expression
can you do it in one shot now let's
let's think about that okay so regular
expression um
you so you have a pattern of A to
Z you know for example let me just write
so you guys can understand so A2 Z is
one thing then then you have a pattern
of 0 to9 that's a digit and the digit
can be can can it be more than one digit
it didn't say but no I suppose you
cannot I mean you know in the context of
this problem it's just first digit and
last one okay the first occurrence of a
digit that's a first digit the last
occurrence of a digit is that's the last
digit okay so so it's just one single
digit so so you have a pattern of a
digit and um just one occurrence and uh
then so and uh basically the A2 Z can be
zero or more so that is
usually a
star and uh you know the last I mean
right now we are trying to find out if
we can get the last digit in one single
use of regular expression okay that is
our
Focus uh so and so um you know I'm just
exploring uh so then the
last so if you have this pattern then
you know this pattern can
repeat but
uh repeat can you get the
last you know usually depending on the
on the language uh function for regular
expression may find all
occurrences okay then you just take you
know as a array when they return a
object or array but anyway a sequence of
things so you just take the
last oh yeah so why yeah yeah so you can
do that you know when they if they
return all occurrences you just take the
last element yeah that's it
so in fact you can do this in one
regular expression to get both the first
digit and last digit
okay uh
okay so let's let's do Mathematica okay
so okay so now this is the input uh it's
some kind of string so now another
problem with the Advent of code
description is that they are never very
super specific like for example is the
input a
string or can we assume the input is a
fire or can we can we can we directly
assume I mean instead of given a string
we can we we we just assume already that
each line is is a string uh you know so
for
example can we do uh
what
you know as a input and something is
wrong
here you know there we have a list okay
we have a list of things can we use this
already prepass list as a input because
if we do that that that then save you
know one or two lines of code it doesn't
say
so judging from my experience from last
year and a bit looking into I I think
you know either one is acceptable so
let's just go with the easy you know
actually this is very easy to
pass okay let's just do it uh okay
split
string okay so string
split okay string split this is input so
let's just say input equals to that okay
then string split lines equals to that
okay then so now each element is a line
now now does it split by the by the uh
new line by
default well I don't know let's try so
do it run
it you know you can run it in emx too to
so there it is so it works okay now we
got each lines you know in a list now
the next thing so now let's do regular
expression so easy so this is uh string
cases okay string cases and
uh
wait regular expression and what is a
regular expression 0 to 9 a digit okay
and
then then what is the input okay so the
input is just
the lines each element in a line so we
need to map it okay so let's look up the
documentation for string
cases now I'm usinga Wan mod it's on
it's free on GitHub you can search and
find ITA Wan mod that allows you to code
wfam language
in in in
yeah in emac that allows you to type
much faster and stuff and uh as you can
see I can press a key and you'll show
the documentation so string first
pattern seconds okay so uh the string uh
comes
first so you need to map this actually
so uh but let's let's just try
this for test okay so suppose that's a
string regular expression 029 and it
will return a list okay uh ret let's
see there it is three and eight correct
okay so this is so now we got that so
this is heart of the algorithm now you
just need to map it uh oh you need to
take the first and last digit okay
so uh okay so we can actually just do
this first last is negative 1 okay let's
try
it three and eight okay that works now
let's try let's see if there's more
numbers nine okay do
it correct three and nine you see this
is testing the case if there are
multiple digits okay so this is a
solution the hard of the algorithm code
for the hard of the algorithm now we
just need to map to each line okay so
map okay map this function you need a
function okay so I I'm just going to uh
code wam language in the long form so
it's easier to understand as opposed to
using lots of syntactical shortcuts uh
which are cryptic unless you know wam
language but I'm going just to use the
long form okay so function uh variable X
now the string is X then you do the
regular expression and you want to map
it to lines okay
and uh uh and the first level okay so
let's do
it there it
is one two okay now all you have to do
is join the two digits and uh sum them
okay uh okay so
wait okay so you want to join for for
each one of them you want to
join join the two parts okay okay so
uh the first and last so you have a list
of two elements each element is a string
you want to join
them okay let's
see okay there is a function string join
let's see how it
works magnify magnify magnify super mega
magnification
okay so string
join uh so you want to call this
function
on on this thing
okay so then then you want to turn the
string into a number okay then you want
to turn the string into a number so
string to number okay so what is a
function string to number okay there's
no search you need to do in a different
way string to
number let's go to wolam language okay
so Kali wolam Language tutorial now if
you don't know check it out just you
know go to cali. info and then you click
here download for free you can download
the wolam engine and run it like I do uh
you know uh then so but what we want now
is to find the string to
number function yeah turn a string into
an integer now what how how is that done
actually I
know two expression okay you know if I
don't know I can search uh I don't think
I get I'll find it uh I need to but
anyway you you can you know anyway
that's my tutorial from ground up
learning wam uh wolam language okay okay
so and I did like more than 10 video
tutorials on wam language from the
ground up on the graphics on the you
know Basics um I'm programming it and
the best ones are collected on this page
okay so you should uh check it out so
now let's go back to yeah so we want two
expression this is how you turn a string
to a number okay now look up
documentation to expression gives the
expression obtained by in interpreting
strings or boxes as wam language input
exactly okay
so now normally when you call a function
in wam language you have the square
bracket for the arguments but you have
also a prefix syntax so this can be also
written by just add X okay so in fact
that's what we'll do just say add okay
and in fact that's that's also
uh
yeah you see with the add ex with the
add syntax it makes things easier to
understand so you don't have a lot
nesting okay so there it
is that is our thing so let's do it
let's just do it all you have to do and
so now this expression is a sum I mean
is a list of numbers you want to s them
so now you use a postfix notation okay
uh slash slash that's like the Unix
vertical line pipe okay then you just
say
total okay total is a function that sums
a list of numbers okay
evaluate 142 let's
check correct okay cons consider your
entire calibration that what is the Su
okay uh
142 oh oh then okay get your pel input
that's a real pel okay lots of lines
Let's see we going to solve
this okay so the input is now instead of
this you know this this is
um so this the real input is
actually that
okay input this is input test okay now
this is a real input
okay okay wo how many lines of code how
many lines 1,000 of them about 1,000 run
it D it prints a bunch of the input but
the okay the answer is
55386 let's do it again let's put a
semicolon there so it suppresses the
output and run it
again
55386 are you sure I'm sure with my eyes
closed this [ __ ] trivial problem are
you kidding me paste
submit that's the right answer you are
one goat star closer to restoring snow
operations thank thank
you fantastic now let me show you how to
make this wolam Lang language one single
line okay now we are already like one
single line it's like we we are already
one single line so you know just so
lines equals to so we don't even need
that so lines are put here in fact let
me tell you in all the advant of code 24
problems or such each solution in wam
language is one single line like the way
I have it now okay let me show you okay
so right now technically it's two lines
right now because you have the input but
you can just grab the whole input delete
it okay comment out that one and put the
uh whole input here one single line of a
code except the input you know you can
but the input in fact you can make it
you know replace it by back slash n to
make it one single line so any anyway
run it again there it is a solution okay
so uh let's undo that so because that's
not good coding practice you want
different things in different lines okay
so there it is solution okay pop it back
cify it in HTML showing browser there it
is advent of code day one solution part
one
okay now part two now I heard from the
grape vine of s Discord that that the
part two is
problematic let's go to it okay let's
take a break and let me read the
comments how long did we took 36 minutes
not too
bad
okay now let's interrupt this
broadcasting by telling you how much I
love you and uh how much money you need
to give
me thank
you yeah that's a good person
do okay so okay so let's take a break
and let's read the comments
tremendous humongous number of comments
let's see what what the what you guys
are
saying
magnify question which is better
wolfland or EAC disp that there's no
question about that emac lisp is one of
the lousy language okay so when you want
to talk about emac lisp common lisp and
scheme lisp they are both of
them a magnitude better than EAC disp
okay emac disp is basically just for
emac the only exception is that when you
are doing a lot of actual text
processing so if your task is text
processing nothing beats EAC disp okay
but for General programming problems
emac disp is inferior to Common disp and
inferior to schem disp or racket lisp or
closure lisp
okay
now now that puts emac thisp away you
know so wam language wam language is
better than hasar better than closure
better than Java better than uh uh rust
better than better than better than any
any by a magnitude there's no comparison
wfam language as you'll see you know
maybe I'll show you know you uh you know
you can watch my past
videos not just uh anyway so a magnitude
uh high level okay there's no comparison
whatsoever one line of hascal or
whatever is your best language least
Pascal one line one line of wolam
language is 100 or 10,000 lines of
hascal or lisp okay depending on what
kind of function if you consider
mathematical functions such as
solving uh integrals or derivatives or
or or differential equation
one line of mathema or or or pols one
line of
Mathematica is a million lines of C or
Cas hascal or rust or whatever okay now
if we exclude those mathematical
functions because you know you might say
oh that's specialized you know uh you
know that's that's specialized math but
if you exclude those let's say if you
are doing a lot list processing Lis you
know list processor that's what Lis
stand for supposed to be good at let's
say if if we are doing a lot list
processing one line of wam language is
10 lines of lisp okay at minimum at
minimum minimum okay most likely I would
say is more like 20 lines of lisp or
hasar okay one line of
Mathematica okay so let's not not
digress let's go on to the part two
because part two I think it's more
difficult okay Jack Smith please stick
to solving the
puzzles okay focus on coding please okay
yeah sorry
already actually think that's helpful
analysis yeah you know sometimes I think
analysis of the question so you see
other people how they think uh is also
useful uh uh cases like
uh okay okay wolf language is sexy oh
chat use two glasses okay one is my near
sightedness the other one is old age
glasses okay I'm getting old like your
grandma I should get better classes you
know I should uh you know this is kind
of old I need to get the new
prescription
okay let's go on to part two okay say hi
if you are here still let's let's go on
to part two 41 minutes let's see if we
can finish in 20
minutes part two
magnify your calculation isn't quite
right it looks like some of the digits
are actually spelled out with letters oh
God 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 and N9 also count as
valid digits equipped with this new
information you now need to find the
real first and last digit on each line
okay
so okay so you got um okay so you got
basically I suppose regular expression
with this
um Okay
so so these are
your okay now you see let me show you
the pink window shows all my key strokes
and the the command name in emx okay so
now we want to make this into a s uh one
line by itself okay
um okay then remove the
comma okay now now let's put a quote and
the comma
okay what is
this okay
now okay so it's probably going to be
regular expression okay so equip with
new information now find the real first
and last digit okay so here is the
input uh in input equals to A String
okay okay so let's check so two is a
thing wait is it exclusive or
not looks like some of the digits are
actually spelled out with
letters some not all that's a key okay
so in here
two is a digit one is another digit and
nine is a digit okay
uh okay
so so in this example the calibration
values are 29 uh and and on and on and
add this together produce 281 what is
the sum of all the calibration values
okay same problem but with this new
trist okay so let's do
it
start a new block paste it pop it out
okay so now what is this so
you so if we look at our last code let's
copy
it okay
[Music]
so so this regular
expression
so let's see so this is four and two
okay so for
example for example this is this should
be 29 okay this should be
83 This should
be one three this should
be 2
4 this should be
42 this should
be
one
four okay that this one is tricky let's
check what is uh so this one is
7 16 oh
wait it's got a
16 but however it does not say 16 is a
valid okay so 16 is
invalid what wait
what
Jesus found a problem in the description
so this line only have one digit
seven yeah seven oh seven six okay there
it is six ignore the
T three
tricky okay let's
check let's
check so it
says 29 83 13 check 24 check 42 check 14
check 76 check so our understanding is
correct okay our understanding of the
problem is correct okay now so let's not
solve the problem okay so first of all
we need this
uh we need this this thing as part of
regular expression is that right now we
can turn this list into a regular
expression with the
all or we can just manually manually do
it let's just manually do it because
judging on pass experience this aent of
a code they don't actually you know like
I said before they don't specify the
input exactly it's like almost you can
you know as long as you give the correct
answer you you solved it okay so it
doesn't you know let's not take the pen
to like suppose the the input must be
this way or that way but as long as you
solve the problem you solve the problem
okay so let's just do
this there it is okay okay so we have
this is a regular
expression and uh now we basically just
need
to yeah I
think uh the order also matters okay
so in fact the
order also matters okay so actually I
think the
number should be in
front
wait so regular
expression string cases regular
expression so
yeah so you find any one of these and
the result are always ordered by the
string cases function so you don't need
to worry about
that and uh are there cases where one of
these word joins together to form a new
word No 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 no they are
all distinct 16 is outside of it I mean
16 is just part of the six
but okay so I think that's actually
it let's just try let's just run it run
it okay invalid syntax because
we uh
wait why is it invalid syntax let's see
oh yeah because we this you
know let's just run it run
it oh so there's one more step you need
to do you need to transfer each of these
back to a number okay ah God what a pain
what a pain
yes yeah okay so you need to transfer
each one of this into a
um okay so let's just do it replace that
by a new line okay so
now you need a rule okay you need the
let me show you how to do that okay
so double
quote comma okay so let me just show you
okay so repl TR comma
by okay so um you know you're going to
see so we have going to have a list of
rules so one is 2 one two is 2 three ah
this is so another way more efficient
more elegant is that instead of actually
putting a numbers 1 2 3
4 five you can you can have it just go
by the index of the array but let's just
do manually do you know
because let's just solve the
problem okay so that's all kind of the
map usually what they call map or
dictionary
so let's
uh transcode let's just call this trans
code okay equals to this is our
transition I kind of
function so once we do that then okay
once we do
um uh let's clean up let's make this I
need to
actually I need
to
so
you know ju shut
up okay so we need to so once we got a
result so this
result and string join yeah so before we
stram
join this
this this uh what let me just show show
you okay so let's run this so you can
see what is a solution I mean what it
comes
out okay run it oh we we can't have the
total yet run
it okay so this is what it looks like
when you do
that okay so you got a list of list each
list is two numbers but the number may
be you know spelled out so you need to
do a
step by so post fix notation so we apply
a function here to the above expression
this is like Unix pipe so here is a
function the function will
um actually let me just show you wam
language
um uh you don't understand but anyway
this means replacement okay
so so let's rename these
rules okay X
rules
it's okay that's the that's our rules
okay so all we have to do is just
that okay let's run
it there it is you see how fantastic so
let me explain this okay so let me just
run this here so you can see what is
what is going on uh what yeah my my
wolam language mod code is incorrect
here but basically if you run this let's
go back to wolam language you can run it
here
you can see shift
enter uh
what oh yeah you didn't Define rules
here so you need to define the rules
here copy
that
paste shift enter so you got the rules
now you can re-evaluate this
expression Shi enter there it is so you
can
see uh wait why is it not
replaced uh
what let's do it again here x rules okay
that's our rules that's that's correct
paste this here
evaluate why does it not
evaluate
what
oh yes wait
what oh yeah because you forgot the
string these are strings right you see
let me show you okay so this this is a
string you forgot those are strings
okay okay let's do it now it
work there it is okay so that's what
this means okay so now we just put it
here and
uh and uh I mean so we put this here so
to show
that you know to to as a common so
programmers know what is this going on
so anyway here's our
code run it
okay we got the list of pairs of numbers
now we just uncommon that run
it okay something oh you forgot a so
this expression must be evaluated first
so you need to add a peren on this line
okay run
it okay
uh
okay another thing we got wrong because
our rules is actually returning a number
now when you have two numbers you cannot
string join so if we want to keep using
our code like that we need to change the
rule so that they are numbers let's just
do it but this is actually getting more
efficient
we uh
actually because some of the numbers are
still digits so actually this is the
best way okay R
it okay now you forgot the total so now
total okay run
it 281 let's
see what is the sum of all the
calibration values okay are you sure
yeah I'm sure idiotic [ __ ]
submit that's not the right answer
what return to day one day one second
problem what is
the why is
it it's
yeah oh yeah but did I forget to get my
input oh so the input right the input
you need to use the previous humongous
input okay
stupid stupid okay that's a lot so let's
you need to get the previous input which
is this
part okay okay this giant input
now
okay this one is test the real input is
this one okay now run
it okay copy and
paste you
stupid
thing that's not the right answer your
answer is too low
what
wait okay
uh this
input okay so this input
already contains some of
the one you see all the one let me show
you a feature okay
so we can see highlight all ones and
highlight
all2 okay so you can see the numbers
embedded in them in the real input so
why why is
my solution not
correct
now is there any occurrence of for
example this thing
3544 is I supposed to
be that should be 34
right so let's double check where did we
go wrong so the rules is one
two one 1 2 3 4 five 6 7 8
9 okay is your
zero okay zero does not occur
okay so
then so let's try this
again yeah that seems
right okay
then this we don't
care
joet
wait did I
5487 what is the sum of all the
calibration
values okay
so okay let's separate let's maybe debug
okay so basically this is our code now
let's just
debug you know so let's put them apart
and give them a
value uh something like that okay so
this the result of this
is
list
of two nums
okay let's print let's see
what's oh okay now you got the
function yeah you can't move
out could it be a sum of both numerical
and spelled out
numbers
that's what we are doing glad to see you
are highly involved and engaged
throughout the process of problem
solving especially as a software
Dev all rules the rules are strings oh
okay good
finding zero is not an input what about
zero are you you coming out transition
coding
setup I don't know if the word ter has
been coined a new bus word but in it the
industry but can we make a analog for
case folding to block folding now if
this sticks maybe we can have a arrow a
narrow definition for
what okay so we got a problem here
so let's okay let's let's let's become
and solve
this
string cases regular expression so
regular
expression is
that oh maybe our regular expression is
incorrect right
so wait normally a regular expression
you can say right literal right so
whatever you type is
literal uh and
uh so we can actually do
that so let's take the input of the
first element okay the first element of
the
input H
[ __ ] yeah you need to split
string
just
okay right so the that is the first
answer let's
see nine and uh okay in this case that's
also interesting because there's only
one
digit
okay so that's why it's 99 uh and
uh what about the second
one so what is the second one R
it 36 okay let's
check three is the first digit six is
last digit that's also
correct so where is our
problem so once we have list of num
was
we
let's let's see what is the whole
thing oh we got this to go
what
what let's
[Music]
see oh yeah because we got no this
is this should be just X
okay
right so this this is
our
thing but why is it say
incorrect I think the
problem specification is problematic it
should be
5487 548
07 54
a07 submit that's not the right answer
your answer is too low if you are stuck
make sure you are using the full input
data okay there are also some general
tips on the about page or you can ask
for hints on submitted please wait one
minute before trying
again
I think I think you got a
problem Lulu zili okay good night
everyone did you
pinpoint uh s does your code consider a
case with a single
number yes I think so for example a case
with a single number is for example
let's try
it a case of a single number uh you know
let's not let's just say
n okay so Ren
it you know that's 9 right so if you
have a two here let's drop the nine it's
just one number so you got two two
that's the situation with one single
number so single number is
covered now let's just see see the all
the pairs of
numbers
um wait we don't want to
some string join okay so let's not
string
join you see so now we got a list of all
the single numbers okay let's make it
and
let's make it one line
each you know actually we can do it you
know we can copy the whole
thing back to the wolm
notebook paste it here fantastic you see
the formatting and all that so you see
the here is a input huge number of input
and uh then here's our code then let's
Str right shift enter so you see
that's
the pair of numbers then for each pair
you add them you you you join them
together so you get a single number then
you sum them
all I'm I'm getting
frustrated does it handle where I'm
getting frustrated let's
um I think the problem is with the the
question
spec now for the for the input now let's
try the test input okay for the test
input
what let's try the test
oh yeah there's no input so the test
input you remove the
test run
it okay so yeah so let's total
it
h what
oh yeah so you forgot to uncomment
that so the test input is
281 so we got the test input
correctly so this is the problem with
the design of this puel you see I passed
the test input but the real
input it says my answer is
incorrect that shouldn't happen that
means there is a
discrepancy between the test input and
the actual input there is something in
the actual input that's some some
property in the actual input that's not
in the test
input stupid problem
stupid the V of code so so now we need
to solve this is but what is the problem
you know so one way is that we can start
to look at what our Discord s Discord
people have talked about there seems to
be some confusion of the second problem
or we can
continue thinking about this now it's
like 1 hour and 14
minutes so what so so let's think about
it first so what could possibly go wrong
I passed the test input but the actual
input it says I'm
incorrect
now it says the actual input I'm
incorrect what could possibly go wrong
so is there something something
did I maybe did we copy the input
incorrectly because maybe we screwed up
something let's redo the input
then okay let's redo the
input maybe I copied it incorrectly you
get your personal input copy or
copy back here paste it okay
now run
it
same
5487 okay so that is not the
problem 54
now those of you
this problem is this number
correct
[ __ ] ad Advent of code day one solution
let's just see what is
the
um day one solution redit okay let's see
what is the number I mean this is not
cheating
because
uh where does it say it's a Time of the
Year again blah blah
blah rules for posting a solution make a
thread I just want the actual number
what you know to
see is there a browser issue or
what how weird can can format be another
Cod developer to another developer code
it will be weird if more way overlay to
introduce dynamism input validation
what how can we
from oh each person get different input
[ __ ] idiotic
[ __ ] so okay so there is no way
then okay each person get a different
input so let's think about this a little
bit more what could possibly go wrong
if we use the test input we are correct
now let's highlight some more numbers
let's
see
three let's see maybe there's some weird
pattern
for
five so you see here is an interesting
case you see you
have 78 then
51 let's try this number let's see what
is what what is this number come out to
be
okay
so uh so this
string this
string what is this
string 72 okay so this string G gives 72
so seven is the first digit that's
correct and
uh oh there is our error you
see the last digit should be one
but we got
two so we are
incorrect right so there is a issue of
joined
word TW w o n
e okay so in this case the correct
answer is
one but if you use regular expression
you'll get
two yeah we
don't let's see all
the let's
see okay let's try again let's see what
we
get oh okay okay so this regular
expression so let's think about
this
172 overlap wrong okay yeah the problem
is
overlap that's what is what I
said
okay
jacksmith okay so that's a
valid you know it's a tricky part it
didn't explain in the in the first input
but it it
sneaky put that into the real
input okay so how do you solve this so
there's
overlap
okay I need to think about
this
uh the second number so the second the
second
um so the
overlap so when you use a regular
expression you find any one of these
patterns
okay okay so this
is string cases oh God this is going to
be okay let's look at let's just like
stop thinking let's just try to find
easy solutions maybe there is a option
in string
[Laughter]
cases
okay give a list of sub strings in
string that matches the string
expression
pattern right our pattern is this
thing now right hand left hand left hand
side right hand
side we'll do a substitution so in fact
we can do a
substitution okay and
uh then you can have
have n include only the first
n occurrence okay then you have this
give a subring that matches any of the
pattern maybe
that give substring that matches any of
the pattern okay so let's try that
one it's not let's let's try this okay
so instead of
a yeah so instead of this long regular
expression we are going going to give it
a list of regular Expressions okay let
me just do it let me show you how to do
this
okay
uh
so replace that by a new line first of
all
okay so now we
got double
cot comma okay now for each one of
these we need
to just add that okay yeah
so maybe this is silly but
we just we just trying to get the
problem solved my
friend there okay so instead of one
single regular expression you give a
list of regular Expressions this is one
of the kind of the power of wolam
language you know no other language have
this uh in wolam language usually
whenever you have a list it
automatically Maps over the list so you
don't have to manually do a
map uh in fact we can anyway
so so if you do it this way will the
answer be different okay so let's
see do
it no the answer is C2 at the end it
should be
one all right so it should be one so how
do
you so the issue is about
overlap this the result for each of the
S1 the issue is
overlap so no so uh
normally a regular
expression if you found a
pattern it Advanced the
index I
guess wait actually you really need to
think about
this
but I don't think there is a option
here oh there it is with overlap or
multiple substrings that match the same
string expression are all included with
overlap
true only the first sear Master sub
string at given position is
included multiple sub strings that match
the same string expression are all
included with overlap equals to
True only the first search Match uh
matching subring or given position is
included so by default the overlap is
true I
suppose we can find
out
o overlap Force okay by default overlap
is force that's right uh but we want
overlap to
be all or
true we want overlap to be true to be
all
okay so
forget about this we just say overlap
true
okay string cases okay an
option
uh okay let's just run
it fantastic
correct God [ __ ]
fing okay let's just uh let's just get
it done then let's call it the day call
it a day okay overlap true run
it 548
824 are you sure yes I'm
sure paste it
submit that's the right answer you are
one gold star closer to the restoring
snow operations okay thank you thank you
I'm
done yeah so power of wolam language now
let's clean up and that's it for today
thank you guys for watching fantastic I
enjoy the problem so here's the test
input here's a real input 1,000 items
here is our rules to convert string
to uh Arabic number string then we then
uh then here's a example how that works
it shows shows you uh then this is a
test case this is a test situation on
this long stren it's a tricky one
because there's overlap so let's say uh
interesting
overlap situation okay and uh okay
comment it out we don't need it and this
we don't need and here's our full
solution and make it one single line so
our whole code is this also let's make
it single line now you can this this is
X rules now hold on a second copy close
we open so we remove all those coloring
so this rules let's color these rules so
these rules occurs ones here so you can
replace this whole thing by this by by
by the ru uh you know the value of the
rules then you got a single line
solution okay wam
language Mathematica okay I've been
coding since
1992 okay so and okay so let's finish up
now now this um solution can be written
in a m shorter way so let me show you
okay so because there's a lot of brief
syntax okay so let me show you how to
how to write uh this expression in a
much kind of normal simple way you know
if you code wam language a lot that's
what you do so for example
um so what I'll do is uh yeah so I'll
use that and uh uh string cases replace
of the pound sign stand for argument
okay
so so cut that
out so here is a single expression and
the M perent symbol stand for the
function so we don't need the function
thing whole thing anymore so here is our
function here is a like Lambda this is a
Lis Lambda okay now you just want to map
this Lambda to to the split string so so
to instead of using the full for map
bracket something you can just say slash
add okay that's a shortcut syntactical
shortcut for
map okay so you want to map
at map at split string and split string
at input okay so that is that okay then
you the whole thing just total yeah so
you can just put that there so this one
single line solution okay now we can try
it so commment this out run
it there it is so we forgot uh this is
the correct answer so the correct answer
is
actually oh uh yeah
54824 not not not
that uh what yeah so delete that so here
single line solution now uh now let's so
delete that so
um yeah delete
that uh uh let's put it there so you can
kind of compare wait anyway so that's it
put it back color the whole thing
showing browser so that's
today's code 90 minutes uh we solved it
or got the input is long
but here's a woen language
code thank you guys okay if you like my
stuff donate okay uh uh you know go to
Sali
doino and uh at the bottom you'll see my
PayPal PayPal is the preferred or you
can uh pay me Amazon gift card or
patreon
patreon thank you guys
bye that's some work today great workout
and tomorrow I think about the same time
uh we're going to do continue to Advent
of
code two day two and join Discord a lot
a lot of discussions on the you know
some so we have a JavaScript solution
now I know the you know now I did it I
can look at the solutions so there's a
JavaScript Solution by JavaScript expert
George there's a
python there's a c Solution by this hot
dog this a c c solution let's have a
look wait this this one part two will be
interesting so
JavaScript let's see oh my God C
solution 100 lines of code
magnify
you C solution 100 lines of code who who
else got Solutions
um let's
see Advent of code day two zelfa is
getting Advanced he's on to day two
now now who else got solution for day
one guys Post Your solution okay so we
only got JavaScript uh looks like okay
bye