hello guys welcome to another episode of
s talk show The Greatest Show on Earth
of coding and technology and AI okay so
we are going to do Advent of code day
five we're going to continue from
yesterday but you don't have to watch
yesterday so everything will be
independent I'm going to code it in
wolam language
uh and uh wam language so you can learn
a lot about wam language the most
unusual different programming language
from all the other C C++ Java python
Ruby JavaScript goand hascal and so on
the most
powerful so continue
from you know we're going to do day five
advent of code uh okay so let me
introduce my keyboard This is kinesis
360 fantastic keyboard This is Ultimate
hacking keyboard fantastic keyboard okay
uh and let's go back and this mouse is
also fantastic it's got the spin wheel
spins you can it it spin for like 20
seconds uh you can find all that
information on my website so today's
talk show let's go
to search for S keyboard block and
you'll see orgonomic keyboard reviews
Grava is great kesis great great okay so
anyway so that's my keyboard box so you
can find all the information and also
about the
mouse
uh this sping wheel okay so both of
these are great this one is great too
g604
g502 and MX Master 3 or
Logitech okay so that's the mouse and
wolam language let's go back to wolam
language yeah we're going to start
coding and if you don't know about
anything about wolam language you can go
to my search fora wolam Language
tutorial you can download it for free uh
and but I recommend you just buy it okay
so this tutorial is designed so that for
programmers you know wam their own
website has has like 100,000 Pages
literally tutorials and documentation
and all that but my tutorial is kind of
more for programmers if you are already
a programmer you came from python
JavaScript C Java and so on uh you'll
get much out of it the most concrete and
I tell you how the wo FR language works
it's a term rewriting system okay or you
can call it a uh computer algebra system
but it's it's beyond computer algebra
computer algebra system means it it can
solve equations do integrals do
derivatives you know do Matrix solve
Matrix invert Matrix linear algebra and
all that but wam language is is uh you
know it's a programming language it's
symbolic it's kind of like lisp and AP
okay so anyway so let's so let's
download let's begin uh let's begin day
five then uh let me tell you so uh yeah
so let's begin if if you are here
here uh let's see talk show if you are
here say hi okay if you are here
watching say
hi okay so the problem is let's go let's
grab the code from yesterday I'm going
to tell you you know you don't have to
watch yesterday but I'm going to tell
you so the problem is that you got
a oh God I have to repeat the problem
the problem is that you you got uh event
of code let's go to the website okay day
five the problem is that you got a bunch
of
[Music]
um you got a text input like that so
it's it's you know just read here so you
got you got a hey Q intent so you got a
list of numbers called seeds then you
got this bunch of
uh triple numbers okay so you got seed
to so your map which is two
triplets each
triple is three numbers okay so this and
you got two of them C to all your map
then you have so your to fertilize
map again it's a triple and three of
them then fertilizer to water map then
you have water to light map then you
have light to temperature map then you
have temperature to humidity map then
you have humidity to location map those
are your input okay and each of these
map
is uh several
triples okay and each of the triple uh
there three numbers meaning it means
that the second number is the
source the first number is the called
the
destination and the third number two
means there are two range a range of two
so these
are so so this means this means
98 Maps 250 and 99 Maps 2 51 okay and
that's it so you so it's a map it's a
map it's a pairing of things um and
yesterday did we show result okay
uh okay so you can look at this you any
anyway it's a pairing okay it's a map uh
but they specify the map instead of one
number to another number they specify it
in a kind of a range a range of number
way so for example the 50 2 50 48 that
means it's a range The Source start with
the number 50 and they are 48 of them
for the last number is how many items so
starting with at 50 and there are 48 of
them meaning 50 51 52 53 and so on until
like 97
okay so that's the source and the
destination is start with 52 then again
48 of them so 52
50 52
53 54 and so on 48 of them okay so each
of these triplet
numbers they basically creates a map of
mapping one number to another okay so so
this is one map then you have another
map then you have another map you have
like total of seven of them all specify
in this range way so your job is given a
seed number you know you have several
numbers seed called seed so given a
number you want to go go through all
these maps and find out what that number
what is the corresponding number to the
given number so for example
79 you go through the first map how do
you go through it well you see so so
this means you know so this so 58 so
this
line means there's a map starting from
50 50 50 to 50 50 51 52 and so on up to
48 of them so it includes 79 right so
79 then the destination start with 52
then 53 and so on 48 of them so you just
check which number 79 becomes okay so if
79 is in this
map then it becomes another number right
but if it's not the 79 is not in this
range you know of numbers
then uh by the specification you just
return 79 itself okay so the point is
that given a number you go through this
Maps each time the number will becomes
another number then you go to the next
map to see that number is in it if not
if it is itself otherwise it become
another number so each map
either becomes another number or the
number itself So eventually you'll get
the number you know so 79 eventually
after going through all these Maps
you'll get a number am I good say hi
those you watching okay So eventually 79
will become a number it may be itself
okay same thing for 14 same thing for 50
five same thing for 13 each one will
become a number and your job the P the
answer should be pick the number the
corresponding number that's the least
that's a minimal okay that's a smallest
that is a problem okay so yesterday we
did um so we tried to solve this by
yesterday we by we we try to solve this
by turning it into a uh into a
uh let's let's run it okay so let me let
me just show you yesterday's
code okay so this is let me show you
yesterday's code and why we failed
yesterday I failed because it run out of
memory because I was trying to do it in
the most simple way without worrying
about efficiency then I got stunned
because you have to worry about
efficiency because each of these yes
because yesterday I was trying to turn
each of these triplet into a full list
of numbers so for example the this 52 50
48 I I created a array of 48 items you
know 50 51 52 and so on and another
array of 48 items and again for each one
of these triplet I have two arrays okay
for for and that works that works for
this to input but Advent of code you
know they also give you a the real
personal
input you know so the so this this is a
you know the to one is just a example it
shows you the answer so you can check
it's correct so you understand the
problem then they give you the you know
your own
input uh so then when I run my solution
on this
personal
input it crashed you know the mathematic
run out you know it's it used up all my
78 16 gigabyt of memory and crashed my V
live
stream so that's what happened yesterday
then even then I realized look at this
number this so This triplet means that
this has 124 million of items items so
I'm generating hundred of these 100
Millions items so that's that's why uh
16 gigabyte of memory is not enough
control shift Escape let's look at the
uh so you see this is my memory I got 16
gigabyte yeah you know that's
interesting I wonder if there are
someone using a giant computer so you
know
maybe 50 gigabyte 128 gab of memory then
that will solve the problem with this
solution okay so let me show you the
yesterday's code okay so uh okay
actually showing the talking about the
code is now again taking 20
minutes okay but let's do it anyway
since we already started okay so here's
a wam language code so let me show you
the input
uh wam language there so paste it so
here you have the input let's
magnify so you see here the input is a
string okay but we turned it actually we
turned it we manually turned it into
a uh let's paste it here so basically
this is a input okay so each of these
triplet is a is is a map okay so so
that's a input let's run
it okay then our solution let's skip the
uh now solution
is that okay
copy paste it uh wait did we copy
no so wait
what
copy yeah so here is our solution run it
so you see this means the
input 79 14 55 13 becomes 82 43 86 and
35 so you pick the small one so that
would be
35 and uh you know we go back to the
Advent
code uh it says shrink shrink shrink you
see the solution is 35 so it works but
however if you use the real input then
you have problems because the real input
has
this huge 100 million I items so all
together they going to have like a
billion How many how many
total how many total number of arrays we
can find out actually
so let's find out
okay actually so here is the full
input
uh anyway let's not let's not worry
about this because we need to code we
got to finish this code this problem
okay
so yeah but what I want to show is that
what um what we did yesterday is that we
created
a uh a bunch of dictionaries so you can
see for example for the the
input for example the input 52 50
48 a triplet that
becomes that
becomes
this dictionary you see 50 maps to 52 51
maps to
53 and and 52 maps to 54 53 maps to 55
and so on there are a total of 48 of
them so and likewise for the others so
that is why when but when you have a
million you know 100 million items you
got screwed I got screwed okay
so the code we our code actually
generate the hash table the the
dictionary
so so this
approach solves the problem but however
not in practice because out of memory so
you know when you uh program that is a
consideration not theoretical thing so
we need to so in order to redo this we
cannot use this algorithm we cannot like
generate a bunch of uh
so what we do so
let's let's start over Okay so now let
me see what to
do
uh
cut paste okay let's paste again let's
work on this
one okay so let's work on
the uh the toy input first okay so let's
not worry about about the real
input okay so the total input is like
that is is this okay and we want to so
the ultimate ultimately what this
map the functionality of all this map is
that given a number you want another
number comes out of it okay
so so so let's see so let's see so this
is one of the input this is one of the
map that means beginning the
source start with
98 and there are two items so you have
99 hello snit
player uh so source is 98 99 so we have
we have it here you see this one 98 250
50 99 to 51 that's the map that's what
this line means okay
so instead of instead of creating a hash
table like that
we uh let's
see so let me just show let me let me
just code it faster I want to I want to
finish this progr okay Source let me
just write
it
destination okay uh num of items so it's
like that okay so
Source let me think of an algorithm for
this uh Source destination number of
items
so so what we can do is we can what we
want
is source
minus
destination
then then AR
range
wait okay wait
source so
source
to Source plus number of items okay so
this would
be the range of numbers the range of
numbers of input it'll take okay then
this will map
to this will map
to so first of all check if the number
if the given seed number is in this
range it's in
between uh if it is then that number
becomes
then that number becomes let's
see uh Source in destination Source in
destination uh yeah the difference and
see okay then that number becomes input
num
plus that okay something like
that
so we write a function
okay uh let's see okay we write a
function this function we'll take a
number then we'll take
another a range okay so takes two
arguments a number and a range let's say
C okay seed and range then it will
return another number that is the
transformation of the seed number
according to the according according to
this given map okay very supremely
elegant uh so how do you do this well we
already almost got it so the body of the
function is
if okay this range will be
[Music]
actually
let me should see okay so function takes
two arguments the first the first
argument is the bunch of variables the
second argument is the body of the
function
so so X range is a least okay so then
you have yeah I can use module
okay okay let's let's go with a simpler
um let's define a local variable
so let me just write it okay so you can
kind of
understand Source equals to X
range the second one
okay and the destination equals to the
first
one and uh
count count is the third part of the uh
of the range right so we Define local
variables so it's easier to understand
so we got Source destination and count
okay now the expression then uh the
expression is let's see copy that okay
so the the output will be
if the
number if
C
if seed is in
between the source and Destiny I mean
the
source if if seed
is greater than or equals
to H let's put it this way okay
actually mean Max okay if the C is
between minimal and maximum so what is
the minimal the minimal is the
source okay and the maximum is
the
source
plus okay let's rename some variables
okay
so
Source okay so Source
start and
uh
so if the seed
is greater or equals to Source start and
uh less or equals
to source. plus number of items
then then the
solution then the number the seed number
should
become uh the then the seat number
[Music]
become let's see if there's some trick
we can do this uh
tricky so that's my Discord if you
haven't already joined
Discord uh let's close it Discord it's
not not get
distracted so we okay that is my
Twitter okay so we have we yeah let's
focus on this okay so if it is in
between then you do something okay
otherwise then just
seed okay otherwise just just seed
itself
uh and uh but how but so if it is in
between what do you do let's
see so if it is it is in between I'm
going to do a trick instead of uh so if
it is in between then it's going to
[Music]
be
seed
minus Source
start
plus
destination
okay so it's going to be like that so
we forget about that okay so basically
this is now we don't need
this okay so this is kind of a
function
so this
function let's paste it here move from
language paste it now this function can
uh okay syntax Z this missing one oh
yeah we don't
need so this
function now we apply this function
two
arguments this function now we apply
this function at two arguments so let's
try
79 the second argument is let's
that okay
copy so does that make
sense so we have a function
here then we
apply to this argument 79 and uh this
list okay okay that should
return let's see what it should return
79 should return
okay R it
fantastic Supreme algorithm this is the
most
efficient uh actually we we don't want
uh this too
much you know I mean we don't need to
define local constant we can shorten the
code code we can shorten the code a
lot so do you guys know what I'm doing
am I doing good
guys so let's see clean up the code a
little
bit so so function takes a c let's
see okay so
this
happens this happens
twice and number of items just happen
once
okay yeah maybe that makes uh you know
it's a
lot it's more of a boss but however it
makes the code easier to understand
okay okay so remove that remove that so
we got our function and all we have to
do now is to just let's remove
yesterday's
code oh we have to do now and this
explanation we don't need anymore that's
yesterday's code so today's code is just
that so once we have a function all we
have to do now is to apply this function
to this to to this
uh okay let's say
function uh how let's give a function a
name uh and it's not any anyway so apply
this
function let's give it an a
name what is a proper
name the resolution of a
map
you know find the you know the
destination
ID let's just say function
okay
uh okay that's a destination ID function
we name it then we just
map map the destination ID function to
okay we need to map them in sequence we
need to map
this and this then this this this this
this you know we need to do it in
sequence
okay so
um right it's all just
triples
yeah you just map them in sequence okay
so you don't need so
actually so now you
see each of the map they Define the map
by several
triplets now one of the question is what
if this map
overlap we just assume when they overlap
whatever comes later will overwrite the
previous okay so if that is the case
then then you simply you know if you
want to find the number and you if you
want to find the Destin destination of
the SE number you can just pass that
number through each one of these triplet
you don't even have to worry about this
group this grouping you know you simply
pass it to one you know each one of the
triplet okay so you you don't have to
you know the the fact that they are some
of these triplet are grouped together
that's irrelevant okay they are just a
sequence of range okay so you know uh so
therefore we okay we going to map it to
so we defined our Maps
here now this map this map we want to
map the destination function to the maps
Okay but the the maps each one of
them it's a list of list of list okay so
actually you can
just flatten it by one shot
okay let me let me show you am I doing
good okay no
answer
U you know because your answer
determines whether I'm going to explain
full in full detail like what I'm doing
now or should I just like quickly you
know show the
answer okay for example we can do this
flatten let's say flatten by
one yeah that's good we flatten it
we don't need we want to remove one
extra nesting
okay then okay so then actually do we
map it all through no we don't want to
actually map we want to use reduce okay
fold fold is like python JavaScript
reduce okay fold a function and the list
okay the list is going to be this
flatten map and the function is going to
be yeah okay so our
function let's name
it
get destination ID okay so that
function
actually uh let's see so it
takes range okay so actually we're going
to have nested functions you you won't
understand what Ian doing
but okay because right now it's like one
shot solution okay let me just code
it
so we are using fold now we give uh
third we give it a third argument and uh
actually map it
to okay you don't know what I'm doing
but I'll just do it okay since you guys
are not responding to
not saying
anything
uh okay so that that is a function then
within
this so this is a
function and uh within this what you do
is is
you okay I think that's the the answer
so first of all let's define
this okay we Define the function then we
just do this let's double
check
okay
now it already takes two arguments what
doing really takes two
arguments
yeah
that okay let's show a simple
case 79
okay let's try
that
82 so let's check check the advant of
code
answer 82 okay then
43 what do you do what do you get for 43
43 is
wrong 43 should return
wait oh 14 okay 14 let's try
14 14
returns 14 returns
43 we are
wrong okay we are wrong because
we let's see what is seed
number 14 we are we are wrong because
there is
some
calculation issues let's double check
this
Source
start Source start destination
start Source
start number of
items Okay then if the
seed
is
if the seed is
between sour start and
[Music]
destination between sour
starts and the S start plus number of
items let's see if is that right so so
98 to here this means 98 and 99
n okay so you need a minus one you
forgot minus
one you know that's off by one issue
common in
programming because on the edge on the
border of things so you know when
something let's say a fence is on a
border in general you know in real life
let's say a fence between you and your
neighbor but if that yours or your
neighbors you know that's a borderline
issue so off by line off by one
problem uh so you need to minus one
right so then you then you compute seed
minus then you compute
seed minus sour start and plus
destination start you don't need the
par okay let's just try if that works
okay let's define it
again Define our
function okay let's def let's try that
79 is
82 14 is 32
wait
14 is 14 should return
what
uh let's let's run them all let's
see 82
32 86
35 so the second one is
incorrect
14 returns
43 but I got
32 now the second one is 14 right
yeah so 14 I got 32 the correct answer
is
now okay so now what is the
problem 14 are you sure that's 79 14
5513 let's double
check
okay okay clean up our
code
so did we get any number incorrect or
something
so if it is in it then you
do seed minus sour start so when seed is
greater or equals to so
start okay
so seed minus
so
start so if the input is 98 in this
case
it then 98 minus 98 is
zero then 0o plus destination start is
50 so 98 maps to 50 so that algorithm
should be
correct
uh yeah so so why is it
uh
so the first solution is
82 yeah
but but the solution
for
is
but it should be
43 yeah how tedious this
is yeah fairly tedious to verify
this yeah we have to go back
to
now if we
use let's see
did let's see yes yesterday's
solution yeah yesterday's solution is
correct so for the number
14 oh new code got it
wrong
14 uh do we have map three Maps
two maps two map
three so now this is UniFi
right oh okay so I think I know what's
going
on you
cannot you see in our algorithm before
we mention that we
assume we can just go through this each
we can go through each triplet one by
one that's not the case because if you
have a
number now whether you know first of all
there's a question whether they overlap
or
not if they do not
overlap
then if if you know if this grouping
this triplet groups they do not overlap
then you can go through
all of them one by
one but if they
overlap if they overlap you must use the
last
map because otherwise the first map or
the previous ones will trans from your
number so you got
screwed right you don't want the number
to be transformed more than one time in
this in any of this group of
triplet when does it happen when would
it occur for a number to be transformed
more than one time that occurs
when you know that occurs when basically
there's a
overlap okay we have we need to fix it
uh
uh I thought yesterday we
determined there's no
overlap
God okay this is not going so well now
it's already 1
hour uh let's
see
so you
check then the second
one
so there's
yeah
for
then
53 to
60 11 to
52 0 to
6 7 to
10 they do not overlap that's this
one then this
one 18 to
24 25
okay and uh this
one
to 99
45 to
[Music]
64 2
76 right what's going on God so in that
one this is six
69 0 to
68 there it is oh no that's a new one
okay so then this one 56 to 92 93 to 59
they do not
overlap oh that's right even if they do
not overlap but once you pass one of
them it transformed the
number yeah okay so I know what's going
on so in each of this
group you you know in each of
these triplet
group as long as one of them transform
the number you want to
stop that's
right okay okay let's a a little bit
more complicated so that is why
so okay so we have to modify our
function very
easy as long as it's happens in one of
these trip
group then
stop you don't want to loop back and you
know
so
okay
so let's rewrite
this so again the function
takes two items X and uh now this should
be ranged is more than
one okay
uh
okay
so no more coffee let me get something
to drink then why not who is
watching six people okay let me get
something to
do
for
red
wine
cheers
two 2024
amazing and this this is apple
cider
you know to solve the problem really
need to think you can't just can't do
talk
and um you know really just so you're
going to stare at
me not moving that's the that's a on
average that's what you see when you see
uh programmers
coding you really have just to think
cannot just like
trial and error and do okay so the
harder the problem the more thinking you
have to do okay so let me think about it
so of these three of a group of
triplets you just want to you know as
long as one of them
apply now is there a way to
determine uh which they
apply uh this this
range so you got a range but you got a
least of least of
them so if ass soon as one of them
apply stop okay so this will be a re
kind of recursive a loop so our function
is good but we just need to apply them
to several range okay so you need to so
this function is good actually we don't
need to necessar need to change it so
you just got several so if
um
yeah we're going to so there
is there's a question do we worry about
efficiency uh because I
Okay
so
so you got
the set of
triplets a set of triplets as soon as
one of them apply
stop
so you can kind of do a fold fold fold
while
yeah yep that's one of the
way let's look up the
documentation
okay we can do for
Wale
so for qu
takes two or three arguments so first
one is a function fold while is just
like fold or python reduce JavaScript
reduce but each time it checks a
condition if the condition is true it
continue to fold okay
so
so takes a
function then takes
you know like what we have
here not flatten here we don't want
flatten
anymore okay
then d a condition I
guess h
ah
e
so fold fold
function and yeah so this so fold qu so
actually okay something like that
okay so fold
while fold while a
function that function takes one of the
range and uh start with starting with a
seed
number
then then assume and the condition so
the condition will
be we can so so this we can just repeat
this if
statement kind
of
uh so this is a condition the
condition well but how do you get it
um yeah uh okay test is
not
good because we you know here we need
no okay so besides fold W what what
else
Let's see we need some kind of loop okay
let's see what Loop do we
want we need as soon as it's
true
stop so our function as soon as it
transformed
a function a function as soon as it uh
as soon as the
input is changed
stop so we have a function that takes
two
arguments and uh uh this function will
be applied to a bunch of
triplets however ass soon as as one of
the triplet that changed the function
value that is the function returns
something different from then from the
input then stop okay
so this will be some kind of fold
so it will be some kind of fold or it
can
[Music]
be oh four pair gives a result and
maintain a state at each
step okay so you see alha
function you see what what you see our
function takes two things one is a SE
number the other one argument is a
range and uh it simply returns another
number that is a result of the seed you
know with the range you know it simply
return a
number but it does not tell us the state
the state we want to know know is
whether the number changed or not that
is in other words if the number is
between the range if it is then
obviously it may have
changed and even may not anyway so it
doesn't this function doesn't return a
state
uh
so
yeah so this four pair is actually hard
to understand what it's
doing gives the last element of four
pair
least so anyway
so so we want kind of some kind of
loop that is so in functional
programming that's fold or
reduce and the condition to stop the
loop
is that when the
input no longer I mean when the
input when the function when the input
to the
function is
different from form the output actually
not even that because sometimes this map
can be identical Maps so that the input
returns
itself
so what we really want
is basically to check this condition so
start less equals to seed and uh you
know less equals to so start plus number
of items minus one so as soon as this
condition is
true we use that map and stop okay
so
um so how do you use fold while let's
see you know we can use fold
while
fixed Point
list Nest
while okay sequential fold fold while
fold
pair
uh so we probably want fold wire but the
problem with for while is how do
you how do you express this
expression in a functional way you know
because we have this all these variables
came from came from the
arguments
so for while let's see for on 79
Maps as as soon as this is not true okay
so basically we want
not so not is a negation so basically we
want
um you know we can just use the
exclamation as soon as this is not true
but the problem is these are variables
how do you
you know you need to turn this
expression into a
function and uh but most importantly you
need to you see this these variables are
part of this arguments how do you get
that okay let's look at for
file
test okay what does the test so test is
a function but how do you how does it
get the
value let's see for while detail for
while test Returns the last element of
fold while
least if Test X does not y true F while
returns
X
right
so if it's true if it returns true it'll
continue if it is not true it
stops right so test is equivalent to for
while x l
uh a is one a is test
one
so let's look at four while uh so
there's a m supplies the most recent M
results as argument for test at each
step oh that's how you get the that's
how you get the argument to the function
so supplies the most recent end results
as Arguments for
test so this this W language for while
function allows you
to specify how many argument to pass
pass to your test function this one
m so Supply the most recent M results
okay what does that mean
so oh you can actually
okay this is supreme functional
programming even more than
hascal so so anyway back to our problem
what we need is we need
to uh this is a function we need okay
but we right now we have a expression we
need to turn this expression into a
function and the problem with that is
that where does the argument came from
for the
function uh so and here the M kind of
indicate
that example divide by five factorial by
consecutive positive integers until the
result is a non
integer divide by five
factorial until the result is no
integer okay kind of makes
sense
okay I'm slightly
drunk
that's 200 mL of red
[Music]
wine
so what are we doing we are trying
to we are trying to figure out how do
you use fold while and the main problem
is the function where do you get the
argument for the function
so so the test by default red wi food
for s
who is that
juice uh
yeah have drunk slightly I'm not you
know I'm not a
drinker so just 200 mL red wine will get
me a bit
diasy but I can do it for sure this is
Trivial problem Oh God okay so again we
are trying to figure out the function
where does it get arguments so by
default the argument that fed to the
function that feeds the function is the
is whatever this F
returns
okay so in other words in other words
whatever the uh get test get destination
ID function returns is the argument to
this function for fold while okay but
that's not enough we also need the
input so for test for while list
test okay and for while test M supplies
the most
recent M results as Arguments for test
at each step okay that is a key Supply
the most recent M
results
so we want it to be
true so let's let's start to code let's
write this so we want the right now we
want to turn this expression into a
function let me show you how to do it
okay function okay XY to results okay
and then we need to say
two according to the documentation so
two
result then what you want to say is
um you see what you can say is X not
equals to Y
okay so as ass soon as one of this
triplet change the
number that means stop okay but however
however like I mentioned this does not
necessarily this tricky issue
because because some of the map you know
this tricky you know by now I learned
the Advent of code is tricky you'll trip
you you you know in the user input
you'll have something different so
anyway let me summarize again so we are
given a seat number we want to go
through this maps and eventually get
another number that may be itself that
is the answer okay so among so each each
of the input number correspond to
another output number so among this list
of input we got the list of output
number and we want to choose the small
this one that would be the answer for
the for this Advent of code day five
okay for this Advent of code day five
now now when this seed number is fed to
one of these you know group of triplets
in sequence okay now let's suppose the
second group of
triplets if any one of these triplet
apply you need to stop okay you cannot
like you know turn the 79 to one of
these triplet and apply to another
tripet no as soon as as the seed number
fits in one of these tripet you need to
stop okay then you go on to the next map
you know as soon as the number fits into
one of these you stop
okay so but the tricky part is so that's
so this is the this is where we are at
we are trying to find you know this is
where we are
at uh but the tricky part is that so
normally this will work you know you
check the input if the input for example
the input 79 has it
changed so if it changed
obviously you know one of these triplet
applied you know it changed it so we can
stop but however here's a here's a
tricky part that we don't know it happen
or not the tricky part is that this
triplet it may be identical for example
the triplet may be such that for example
this one is 49 53 and 8 okay it is
possible in the user input where you get
a tripet triplet where the first two
number are the
same meaning that meaning that this this
map is like map the number to
itself okay so if that is the
case do we have to treat it in a special
way if that is the case I mean so if if
the number if there's a triplet that
Maps the number to
itself
then the question is it is it possible
that for subsequent triplets in this
group to change that
number yes or no okay that is a tricky
question so if there is a triplet that
Maps the number to
itself that happens when the first two
number of the triplet is is identical
okay if there's a triplet that Maps a
number to
itself then the question is does
subsequent triplet
possibly change that
value
uh so so to answer this question there
are two
cases case one is one of this triplet
overlap with the first one case two is
none of this the following triplet
triplet overlap with the first one okay
so let's go with the no overlap case
first if none of the triplet overlap
with the first you know identical case
then then it doesn't matter so if
there's no trip if if they don't overlap
and the first triplet Returns the number
itself then it doesn't matter you can
you can just stop okay as soon as you
detect
that mapping through this gets you
idental identical number you can stop
wait okay let's think uh I'm not too
sure yet let's think about the overlap
case the overlap case is
that this is tricky so this is
actually indeed tricky overlap or not
overlap so there are two so there's two
tricky aspect one is that whether this
triplet in a group do they overlap is it
possible for them to overlap that's one
thing the other thing is that is it
possible for this triplet to map a
number to
itself in other words is there a triplet
such that the first two numbers are
identical so this is two aspects of
complexity then you have to
consider the cross breeding of these two
so you have four cases you
know identity map EX
exist and the case of overlap
exist that's one case the second case is
ident identity map exist but no overlap
exist Okay the third case is identity
map does not
exist and no overlap exist that's the
simplest then the fourth case is ident
and identity map does not exist but
overlap
exist okay so I have to think God I'm
slightly drunk what is this German
hello shule gun 10
hello okay
so I don't know where I'm
going uh we can just like just do trial
and error and you know but that's no
good oh this trivial
problem and and what how long have I
been 100 minutes
already
ah not so
easy
so you really need to think over this oh
God I think the drink is a
mistake
so how many people are watching four
people three people okay it's just like
one one of you are
watching uh not this one is no good okay
I need more
drink
for
don't drink in cold hello
nightberry Happy New
Year
okay I want to finish this
okay
God
so so if there's identical identity
map so we are doing
this let me try to finish it okay let me
just try to finish it so if there's
a okay here's a issue
okay
okay case
one
case two issue two okay now there's a
combination so a combination of
case
okay even I'm drink I can type
fast
so the combination of
cases
analysis so what we what will happen you
know so that's when we are trying to
figure
out you know I instead of just talking I
write it down so you guys can watch
something as some
show so
this is like reflective analysis like
I'm not even thinking I just
mechanically type
out the
logicality so I'm doing this analysis of
the problem via a mechanical process I'm
not even thinking about it but okay so
there are four cases I mean if I'm
actually thinking about it I don't need
to you know like it out you you you can
just think about it in one minute and
you'll find find out but I'm now have
drink half drunk so I write it
out so yes identity map and yes
overlap so when there is identity map so
you have the this situation
where consider some of these triplet
they overlap and and some of them are
also identity Maps
so what would happen you know what what
what would happen to that those
cases so let's suppose so so let's
suppose the first case there's a
identity map okay so let's say
79 and one of this triplet is 79
something so it applies but it returns
itself okay you know for example one of
these is 79
791 that means you know you 79 return 79
so that applied okay but however let's
in in the case of this overlap so
there's another one of these
triplet that 79 is in between so let's
say let's say
1791 right so in that case 79 becomes
100 right because there's overlap 79
applies you know both of these you know
sequence will apply to 79 so in this
case when there's a when there's
identity map and when there's
overlap it is
possible uh
wait it is possible that after you went
through the identity map the number will
change but what what about order what
what if you what what if the identity
map comes
after when you apply some you know so
this this ad Advent of code like
they don't care about
you see I'm a thinker so I analyze the
problem
so alternative approach which is vast
majority of people do is they just trial
and error right they you know you just
you know you
just you just use this you know if it's
correct you know you just test test with
the user input If it's incorrect then
you think about it
again but what I'm doing here is like
you know just analyze the problem the
possibilities
of okay let's think about
this if there is a overlap now let's
forget about identity map okay let's
just think about the issue of overlap so
when one of these
triplets they
overlap what should you do I mean how
how does it affect
the problem so there are Poss there are
I think two
cases now if they
overlap then it is
possible when you start with a input
number one of this triplet we'll change
it to something
else uh wait so
wait wait okay let me restart so if the
if the
tripletes
overlap one of the possible scenario is
that it depends on which triplet you
apply first so you will apply this
triplate you get one number but you
apply this another triplate first you
get another number
okay so in other words in other words
this map is
inconsistent that's what happens okay so
now I finally you
know thinking about this throughly now I
understand so if the triplet actually do
overlap and if they are not identical
then that means this map is simply
inconsistent
okay so what does that mean to this
problem well you know the thing with
advant of code is
that it doesn't it doesn't guarantee I
mean they don't typically guarantee that
they you know it's cons
consistent so we cannot rule out the
possibility that they are overlap and
inconsistent so for example if the input
is 79 one of this triplet may change it
to 100 but another triplet in the same
group change it to 100 and one so you
got a problem you know which one you
should so I mean so when you are trying
to solve the problem you have a decision
to make is it true that as soon as you
find one of these triplet that apply you
exit this entire group of triplet
or you keep checking if there's another
you
know you know because of the overlap
exist
so you got this so so first of all this
this issue of
overlap okay but so far so far as I know
the to input they don't overlap okay but
you don't know you don't know if the
actual input overlap or not that's a
thing that's the thing about the the of
code you know they
don't it's not very
precise okay but anyway so you do have
this overlap situation let's keep that
in mind okay so so let's summarize the
overlap situation is that when in in one
group of
triplet such
that you have more than one triplet that
can apply to a number okay and they are
not identical triplets so you get so so
the output May depends on whether you
apply the first triplet or the second
triplet okay that's one thing and and if
that happens when you have overlap and
nonone identical that means your map is
not really a map your map is
inconsistent okay so I we can I think we
can kind of assume that doesn't happen
kind of you know we don't we don't know
but let's keep that in mind okay so
that's one thing now let's think about
the other issue of identity map so how
does that affect this scer triplet okay
what what if you have a you know a
triplet that start with the first two
numbers are the same you know for
example 99
991 meaning that if you have the input
is 99 the result is also
99 so when you have that identity map
when you have a identity map in one of
the triplet what
happens so first of assume first
assume there's no overlap okay
so okay that's
simple uh no matter
basically so when you have a identity
map and there's no overlap it doesn't
matter it in the sense that it doesn't
matter if
you basically when there is no overlap
then you can fall through any of these
wait no you
cannot
uh so when you have a so this is not no
matter we don't know so when you have
identity map and there's no
overlap
This is complicated to analyze but
actually I kind of you know I'm going
like philosophical about this but
another way simply is that you simply
check all these triplets okay you just I
mean first of all you just check all the
triplet to
see if there's one of
them you know if there's no overlap then
there's only one of them that applies or
none of them applies then you you then
you just pick that one then then use the
function you know then you get the
number okay so that would be the common
approach instead of me going
philosophical about
it so nber says you look into both
directions when crossing a
one
what oneway street where most AOC
servers only looking One Direction yeah
thank
you okay so the uh so let's go back so
let's continue what how you know
whichever way I was going
so
so so there is the issue of identity Map
There's the issue of over map overlap
and there is also the issue
of of you know of you do not want to go
through them all of them
sequentially like typically when there's
one match you know the input number is
in between you stop
okay I think that's assumed you know
because I'm thinking too
much you know I'm thinking too much like
I'm thinking too much about overlap
about identity but basically I would
say that the standard solution to this
problem is that as soon as there is a
your input number fits into one of these
range you
stop okay so don't worry about this
overlap or identity map okay I think
that's
it uh okay so how do you do that then I
want to finish this problem even drunk
even when I'm drunk I'm going to finish
this problem so okay so how do you do
that then let's just do that so you
given a list of triplets okay you give a
list of
triplets you want to see
ass soon as
um okay basically this
expression you know basically this
expression
okay
no Tri no it's
uh basically that okay
so
oh
God
okay I'm just going to code by myself
then okay
so
so we
want change change so you cannot go
through uh so as soon as do
you so this this is a key expression
actually so this is a key
so you apply
[Music]
to okay so you apply
to an
argument you
map that to a list of
triplets you may have that that to a
list of
triplets
Supply the most recent end resources
Arguments for tests at each step so
supplies the most M results that means
is return
return so actually the issue
is are there identity Maps let actually
a
question the question is are their
identity Maps because that determines
your algorithm I mean that affect your
algorithm if there is no identity map
you see if there is no ident identity
map then then I can then I can simply
use this
test but there if there exist identity
maps in one of this triplet then this
this test will fail that's that's the
thing so that's the thing with the
uh okay but let's get on
so
oh this is not
good
my one so you just map each
one so you
have keep going keep
so this is f qu is actually
appropriate so you want to
determine
if so this is this expression is what we
really
want uh but how do
[Music]
you but the thing is how do
you express this expression let see the
C is the first one
no you
cannot Source start what is a source
start so start with the second
one
true okay basically that means so start
that's how you express
so
start and uh the number of items
is that
okay so that is what we want kind
of first argument second
argument yeah that's kind of what is so
if that is
true
if that is not true stop okay if if that
is if that is
true
stop so if that
is
uh for
while so while this is not true continue
that's right
okay so I think I got it so let me just
read the full while documentation
carefully Supply the most recent end
results as argument for test at each
step okay so here is a function there it
is okay so we are
Supreme you know we are writing this
supremely in fact
it's just trial and error I know you
know this this just trial and
error got tired of this okay we got
something
wrong
uh function slot number
two cannot be
fielded
okay
four fire one two three four five five
arguments four fire one two three four
five yeah so why is it not
working 2 two three so
source oh okay now I understand because
it is it is you know supplies the most
recent end
results so the result is actually just
came from F
not these oh God I need to
fix so what we can do is that in this
get destination ID we can have it
return two
items should we do that get destination
ID no we really
shouldn't uh okay I want
to
so okay so supply all results so far as
argument for test at each
step
okay all results okay for while okay you
got the
results but that's not what we
want uh now this one return the result
after applying F an extra nend times
after this okay that's not what we
want Returns the result after applying F
an extra n times no returns the result
found while F had being applied in fewer
times okay now for qu F test represent
an operator form okay so the for
qu
the design of this for
wire seems is not what we want because
the test the thing is about the test
because the test you know the crit
critical thing is the argument to the
test
function right now in this design for
while of wolf language the argument to
the test function is basically
previous results of
F that is f recursive applied
recursively applied to this X and list
so that's all you get that's that's all
the argument you get for
test
but okay so the the what we
want the test the argument for the test
the the the argument we want is part
part of this
input this list
input so we can make this four Loop for
function adapt to our need needs by
modifying our get destination ID
function by returning two
things you know one is the one is the
output we want then the second thing is
the is the input is is the second
argument to it but that's but but but
that would up the semantics the
ideal semantics of get
ID right the idea of semantic of a get
ID is you just get a SE number and a
range and return
okay you could return another value you
know a list value so the second item
would be
true or false true if it returns true
that means this seed is in between the
range that you know that range
applied okay so you could return another
argument you know so we
could so that would be for the purpose
to indicate the state kind of
so so let me continue uh so this four
while fold
while so let's go on think about the you
know an analysis of the design of this
fold while is it really good or am I
just you know it's just my special case
that doesn't apply so I mean is this the
design of this for
while
uh
function
is it General I mean typically wfam
language design is so if
usually you know in a quick judgment if
I have problem with it that probably
means the problem is me it's not you
know the wolfen
language I kind of know that because you
know because the you know it's things
are very complicated so sometimes you
have to really think a
lot so in this
case it seems to me so far that the
design I mean this doesn't do what we
want because it doesn't pass the
argument we need to this test thing so
how does that so
so what is the problem I mean is the
problem is is it my
problem was I trying to use the wrong
function or is it let's think about okay
so so but looking at the fourth wire
design basically the
test all the test does all the argument
it receives is the previous result of
function so this for while is a form of
blop and the condition is
just it's almost like fixed point you
know it basically just it you know all
the condition the power of this four
condition is
simply the re the return value of the
function you know or how many of it so
so this Contin so this four F
construct is designed such that
essentially it's like a loop right but
it has a it's a functional programing
style of a loop but it allows you to
stop the loop by this test but however
the power of this test is only about the
value of the return value of the
function that's all you can
do yeah kind of like that so so what so
why is this so is this let's see so in
general a loop you have so many you know
in general when you do a loop you have
when uh and you want to stop at a
condition you can express that condition
in so many
ways uh but in functional programming
you need to narrow down that condition
to some kind of function in this case
right test a function test and that in
turn depends on what is argument to the
test to this test function and in this
case is simply the previous values of
this
F and that since significantly n Narrows
the power of
this fold
while is it
true well maybe maybe it's just simply
because this is a function of
programming that's why that's why you
have
restrictions you can have
arbitrary Global variables actually you
can uh so
let's Okay okay so you can use throw to
exit for while before it finished oh
okay and you can use un same Q or go on
applying until the same
result uh Legend what you talking about
Legend okay so this F CH I mean we we
need to solve our problems so we've been
talking a lot about philosophy and
stuff uh so something you know I
get something is not
right
uh so F
while I'm kind of like stuck in this
Loop you know you should you know this
should be simply solved in one hour but
I I got
into stucking in some philosophical hole
okay so how do you
so let's try to just simply solve it
okay so for while
um so the question now is can we use it
or
not the okay the answer to that seems to
be yes we can but if we want to use fold
while we do have to modify our get
destination ID function
for it to return EST State otherwise we
cannot and that reason is due to due to
this identity map issue uh you know
that's another
whole another hole to look
into uh
so but the issue is I don't want to
modify my guest get destination ID I
don't want to be because it's
perfect because that that you know that
really just return so how can you what
can you do
well and you do want to stick to
functional programming right so what can
you do
then okay for while
so for while is it really
true
that I cannot use for while if I do not
want to modify my function it seems that
is
true
okay and
uh sequence fold so this so This fold
while and the sequence
fold
they uh sequence f for following
sequence of previous values okay uh
sequence for this kind of like for
recursive functions that depends on
previous more more than one previous
terms that's what this is a bit hard to
understand too uh and you can use you
can use it to Define
feasi numbers very
elegantly uh but I don't think that's
what we want what we want is not is is
um is some kind of fold or
reduce
but but the test condition the condition
we really want is just the second
argument that is the
range you know that that is if this you
know the source start is less than
equals to se less than Source start plus
number of items
then that is a state okay if that is
true
apply it and stop truly that is a
condition
okay
so I'm trying to come up with the most
proper functional approach to this
problem that is why I'm kind of like
stuck
here uh so you want so
sequential
so fold
qu
uh okay I'm going to go for a cigarette
okay this is getting too long and maybe
2 hours or 3 hours it's already 2 hours
but let's just try Break YouTube let's
see what
happens I never I never did two hours be
I mean I did two hours I did three hours
before but let's see who else is talking
Ang
gr reer
so yeah
Mark so Eng gr is cool they've recently
add some cool features okay I need to go
to the bathroom see what's in a I ODS
okay okay I'm going to go have a
cigarette I'll be
back let's just press on let's see what
happens with this live stream
okay I'm going to have a cigarette I'll
be back in five five
minutes
for
e
okay I'm back I'm back let's keep
working on
this you
know there's no
problem so so right now we stuck on this
functional programming thing I
want you see the thing is I want stick
with functional programming and
uh in some kind
of besides besides sticking with
functional programming I want
certain other
ways that's beyond function programming
that is why I'm stuck
here uh but is there a solution yes of
course so so we got our get destination
ID
function that takes a seed number and
takes a range and returns okay and
returns another number but however it
does not return a
state because if the X range does not
apply it simply return the seed itself
but it doesn't tell you this get
destination ID function doesn't tell you
whether you know this range applied or
not that's the
thing that's that's kind of my own
condition you know I can change this
function so that it Returns the state
then it kind of solve the problem it s
it get me out of the hole I'm stuck in
but I'm kind of stubborn you see
that I'm kind of stubborn that's why I'm
kind of slow in programming and then we
got into this you know then we started
to look at this issue
of of whether there's identity map in
this group of triplets or whether this
this any of these triplet they overlap
you know we got this
situation you know these triplets
triplets triplets whether they overlap
within a
map so we we we went into analyzing that
and we haven't done yet because what
ultimately what you want to know is that
you got these four conditions you know
there's identity map and there's overlap
and there's identity map but no overlap
no identity map but overlap or no
identity map but and no overlap so four
possible cases and uh but what you want
to know what I want to know is how it
affect you know in each one of these
case how it
affect the condition that you you want
keep applying this this uh this
range triplet
okay so so we can continue to an Analyze
This or we can you know try some other
way so that's why I'm stuck uh and uh so
so what to do now is
that let me just
think okay
so so actually the best solution is just
to use fold
while because this is the proper
approach are there other approaches
because I I want the the best functional
programming style the
best um thing the the the best way the
best
pure in some kind of mathematical sense
the purest Sol
solution and the most efficient as well
you know anyway so so right now what to
do are there other approaches of course
there are tons of other approaches you
can simply just write you can you can
just change the function get State get
destination ID so that it returns a
state but okay so the question is it is
that absolutely necessary in order to
maintain my kind of
way
uh so one more look at
this one more look at this so you see
I'm very thorough I want the thorough
understanding of all this you know which
I do mostly but anyway
so the final I mean the the question
here is this fold while we
have analyzed and we have
understood this for while construct
which is a functional approach for a
loop that the test
function the power of this testt
function really depends on the argument
to the test function and uh in this case
it only allows you
to the argument only allows you to be
whatever F
returns so if your F does not return a
state you know you are kind of so
let's make sure that is the
case
yeah it really it really
um it really it really just depends on
what
if
returns yeah this so F
wire is a loop construct in a functional
style but however the condition the
power of this condition is really just
what this F returns you know previous
value or previous previous or previous
previous or next next next you know a
sequence of the return values of
F that is how this fold qu
determines but what we really want what
we really want is we want this you see
this least this second argument to the F
to determine whether to stop or
not so but according to the wolam
documentation you can use abort you can
use throw you see to exit for
while but if you do that that that
that's that's that's not functional
programming that kind it kind of breaks
the functional programming
scheme you know if you do a throw inside
this for
example uh let me let me just tell you
okay so for example let's if we want to
just get this to work
then then you just do a throw here okay
throw
you know then then you just put a throw
there that that kind that will that
should
um because that throw will just
exit the whole fold while
loop yeah that that th we just get exit
the
whole
um and you actually you want to throw
this
value let's look up throw okay startop
evaluation and Returns value as the
value of the nearest enclosing catch
okay so if you want to use a throw you
put a catch and it's not
good that's that's not that's not
functional programming throw is is just
go to okay throw is just go to in kind
of a functional
form but uh it's but that's not
good okay how how do we
so why am I stuck here so let's see this
is
really it's really a trivial
problem so fold
while
map
okay so let's write another
function
see
okay we can we can do this we can we
just write another
function okay so
is so
simple so for qu is just write another
function so for qu
if for if each one of
these
um
takes two
arguments
okay okay so for while this is a
function it's
just okay X and Y so
if
so
if X and Y so this will be
y
to
x
three so let's remove
th so if that is
true the condition so we need a
condition if this that if that is true
then we
simply actually we simply doing
that
that's
this are range so this is why is range
okay this
is
if
if that is
true uh God
fold when you
stop so yeah so functional programming
in a loop you have a lot
complications complexity
uh because all these reduce reduce is
reduce is one of the greatest way
of I mean not greatest but reduce is one
of the way to write a loop in a
functional
language such
that okay so fold then you have Nest you
you have fixed
point you know you have Nest you have
fold then you have sequence fold
sequence
fold depends on like previous end
results then you have fold
pair which I have not looked
into I shouldn't remember maybe F pair
is what I should use f
while maybe four pair is what should I
use then you also have fix Point fix
Point
basically
continues until the result no longer
changes okay that's not what we want
then you have Nest
while you nest the
function which
is no we can if you do if you use Nest
then you need
to the nest if you use if you rewrite
your get destination ID
function to to be used with Nest while
that means the get ID function will
repeatedly call itself
so it will repeatedly call
itself
God start with
expression
test yeah yeah so next next while next
while is if you take the function
itself
again the condition for the
test the power of that is the argument
of the subsequent result of f
so in some way your function needs to
return you know either one of the input
the X range or some kind of
state so we started to look into the
computer science of
things the function needs to return some
kind of State
uh so I'm run running into a problem
because I do not
want and
reconcentrate about how I don't want the
function to return state but
meanwhile the condition requires me to
use one of these you know a condition to
stop
the the kind of recursion or
fold so that is kind of the problem I
run
into so let's analyze my
problem so this seems to be a logical
problem CU I don't want to modify my
function to contain any state but
meanwhile I want to use functional
programming construct of loop I don't
want to use you know the
loop the imperative or depending on
global variable so each time you check a
global variable so if I want don't want
that I want pure function I want pure
function approach I got a problem
because
is you know I should my function needs
to contain some kind of
state because otherwise I'm running into
a contradiction you know your function
don't have a state but then but then
you then you depends on
this then you depends on this uh fold qu
which is requires a
condition
oh take while maybe take
while oh
that
that might be what we want take while
can we use object we say any here not
just
so take
while this list will be a least of the
triplets so when you call take while
each
time
it returns an element of the
least that's it takes take
while
take that's it that's s the
problem let's just do
it take qu let's see let's say for this
you know this take while this list okay
a list of triplet the condition is
that criteria is true so what is the
criteria
criteria is a function now the function
what is the argument to the
function function is one of the least of
course yeah okay that's what we
need functional programming like the
scheme thisp
phonetics if you want to truly remain
functional it actually does require you
to think a lot
more I mean so I mean so we are so here
we is a
digression on the question of is it
true that if you always stick with
functional programming forms of Loop and
map you know any form of iteration
Loop so in functional programming you
use map or you use recursion right
so if you do that so if you avoid any
any type of loop or
iteration and you instead you use the
functional programming style to do them
does that mean in general your
code becomes difficult more difficult to
understand wow
that's uh I always denied it I always
denied it because I you know I'm not fan
of the imperative you
know actually that is true
because if you stick with the purely
purely functional form of any type of
loop or iteration
repetition
then so so it is true that it is
actually conceptually more difficult
more complex so okay okay I think this
is the thing I'm arriving this is a new
Theory the theory the statement of the
theory is
this so if you stick with functional
form of any kind of repetition Loop or
iteration so you know in in a stateful
form in in what's called imperative
programming when you want to repeat
anything you you do the so-called four
loops loops or iteration or enumeration
you know so in each Loop you check you
know what state what condition whether
you should continue okay that's the
imperative programming style okay now
the functional programming
style is that when you do a loop or
iteration you don't check the state of
each trop instead you use a Pure
function so there are two basically two
major ways one is
recursion a function calling itself or
the other way is a map so you give a
sequence of a list and you return you
apply a function to the whole thing or
reduce okay so there are several forms
for the functional
Loop
recursion reduce or fold in UAM language
is called fold in Python in JavaScript
it's called reduce which allows you to
repeat by a given like uh each time you
repeat you take another input from a
list okay so that's reduce and fold or
you can
do um map so right map recursion and
reduce or
fold that is these three major way
um so let me explain so what is the
difference between this two what does it
mean functional programming what does it
mean imperative so imperative means like
your code anytime you can check a state
like a global
variable while if you programing a
functional programming form you are not
not allowed to do
that so why do you want to to do
functional programming form well there
are
advantages the advantage
are each of your unit sematic unit unit
of your algorithm is in captured in a
function so the function really just
care about one thing input and output so
if you do the functional
form of programming so you know your
program become just functional unit each
function is just concern about one thing
as opposed to the imperative form where
any sub routine can do any many any kind
of thing can in can can can involve the
whole state of the
program because the imperative form you
really have lots of variables that means
State you can check you can update the
state and so on
so that is the advantage of the
functional form now when you want to do
a rep repetition so fun in functional
form you typically do
map reduce and fold and or recursion
okay now of course all these are
actually equivalent you can just you can
um yeah all these are equivalent to
another the difference is
that it the difference is that in in the
complexity of your function
right so you know you can actually
translate you know you can you can you
can do a loop or repetition in any one
of these in a map or reduce or recursion
the main difference is how you how does
your functions input and output
are so for example if you want to
convert a map like you you your apply a
function to a list of numbers you know
map a function to a list of number if
you want to turn that into a
recursion of course you can you just
change the your function so that so that
the function takes instead of one
argument now it takes two argument the
second argument is the
least right then the function just call
itself again each time it reduce one of
the least item then call itself again
and reduce one one more item until the
list is empty so that's how you convert
a map of a function to a list to a
function just calling itself and consume
the list in the first core right so
that's how you convert between a
function mapping to a list and function
that just recurs doing the same thing
they exactly return
um yeah they can they can return the
same thing now so this is a conversion
between recursion and uh form a map to
recur recursion you can convert the
other way too and the other form of
using reduce is similar you can also
convert in between map or recursion okay
so anyway that's the functional form of
a repetition okay of some kind of loop
or
repetition so and with are doing that of
course that's because the advantage of
function the function ody you know
because the function is like kind of
just make your code clean the function
just is a semantic unit okay now back to
our problem what we are trying to do in
in order to solve this day four day five
or day was say day five to day
four uh problem is that day five okay
okay is that I'm trying to use a purely
functional form and uh now I need a loop
I need a
repetition and in order to do
that why am I stuck I'm stuck because I
was resisting
from yeah that's kind of stubborn that's
not good I'm stuck because I was re I I
was refusing to change my
function yes that's true turns out that
is my problem I was refusing to change
my
function to kind of re to re to return a
state or or refusing to write a new
function to return a state that a rer
function you
know meanwhile I was trying to stick
with a functional form of
loop so you can't you know you can't
you can say you know I don't want to eat
a cake but cake but I want to eat a cake
that's a
contradiction so if you want to use the
functional programming
form and if you do want to have some
kind of loop or repetition using one of
the map or recursion or or um or reduce
or
fold you do have to
embed the state in your function that's
right you do have to embed your state
some sort of State in your
function that's
right so I think that is a conclusion
that is why I'm stuck I'm refusing to
you know I'm refusing to embed a state
in my function I think that's make that
makes sense
now I think the alcohol effect is kind
of gun so I'm doing great thinking
now so that was my problem I was trying
to stick with pure functional
programming and doing a type of loop or
repetition more
specifically using a fold or or fold
while but I was refusing to embed the
state in my
function that's that's kind of true
that's kind of true but but but
meanwhile it's not purely true though
because the form I'm looking for Wolf
I'm doesn't have it you see the form I'm
looking for
is very exactly you know it's almost
exactly like
the um fold
while however what I want you know I
require the test what I require is that
the test for the condition to
repeat to be able to have a argument
from the second argument of
F that does you know the wolf language
does doesn't have
that right okay so that's that's that's
that's a good great
clarification it's not purely
because you know so is there anything
wrong with my previous
conclusion
that that in order to be purely
functional and do a loop you have to
have stayed in your
function no that's not necessarily true
that's not necessarily true you could
you know we could invent a new fold
while like right now we could invent a
new fold while function or
construct just like just like map is a
construct reduce is a construct or fold
is a construct or
recursion normal normal recursion is not
a construct because Normal recursion is
just a function in the function body it
refers to the function itself that's a
normal recursion but there are forms of
recursion for example the uh
Nest you know the nest function just
recurse the function Itself by n times
so in this form of recursion is a
construct because this Nest function is
a construct you know so wolam language
provided
you this Nest function that allows a
function to recurse on itself
you see so in
short if you want to do some kind of
repetitional loop in a functional
way such that you know meaning that you
have a function that already always just
only care about input and output and
doesn't
use uh doesn't rely on global other
state of Global Information so this is
the meaning of functional programming so
if you want a functional Style to do any
kind of loop or repetition you have many
ways typically classified into map
recursion or
reduce they are interchangeable okay but
now if we go one step further down into
the programming language the programming
language actually have several construct
to allow you to do any one of these for
example another example is parallel map
or in language called map
thread so normally when you map a
function to a list typically the
function takes one element one argument
from each you know from the list but
what if you have a function that takes
two
argument and you have two
lists so each time the function takes
one argument from each list so that that
that is called map thread in W from
language in this is just map okay in
this that's just a more generalized map
I mean that's the way they did
it so this this is also
a a form of loop because you are
applying a function to multiple values
okay
so right so so in this case that's a
example of
a a loop a map but different from the
ordinary map which is for function with
one
argument in this map you may call it
parallel map or map
thread is when you have a function that
takes two argument and you have two list
or the function takes three arguments
and you have three lists they kind of
map in parallel so again this is just
another form of Loop okay but it's a map
but different from the ordinary map
so what I'm trying to say is that this
illustrates another form of map that
kind of belongs to the another form of
loop that kind of belongs to the
map uh category okay so in
short you can do functional programming
and there
are there are many forms of loops and
generally in three categories map reduce
or fold and uh recursion okay in general
in these three categories but there are
nuances and differences so my main point
is back to the uh my my main point is
back to the
um to the uh n
Fold uh my main point is back to the
fold while
construct so wam language provide this
fold while which is a form of fold or a
loop but however that this fold qu is
not what we want what I want you know I
could have re you know I need another
fold qu which which the condition the
test can depends on the input that's
right that's right so that's right
right so back to my original argument
then it is not true it is not true that
my St
stubbornness caused me this problem it
is not true you know I was saying that
because my
stubbornness that I want a
function I want to do program this in a
functional style and I refuse to change
my function to return a state
yet I want to use one of the functional
forms of loop or
repetition and my previous conclusion
was that this is CD this is
contradiction contradiction you cannot
do that and
uh my new conclusion is that that is not
true no I can still do what I want is
just that the wolam language does not
provide me that construct
okay that is a better
conclusion okay so it is true okay so
final analysis it is
true so but however now I discovered
take while take take while we actually
solve my
problem without me having to change my
get destination ID
function so take what we solve my
problem
because let me how how does it solve it
let me show you
okay take while we'll solve the problem
beautifully
actually I wanted to hey Hank of flamio
great to see you Merry Christmas
or happy
quansa do you celebrate qua uh or
Christmas anyway great to see
you uh okay so take while we'll solve my
problem so let's see let's solve let's
try to do
it okay so let's try to do
it
Ching thank you thank you
Hank what take
well
ew
so today is three
hours God do I want to do I insist that
I I finish coding this problem until or
I will not stop the
YouTube It's a that's three what three
viewers okay I'm going to insist
okay if I'm going to insist on that I
better just start to
code think and code okay great great
analysis uh take
why
actually
for
yeah
God God I want to
see
you take a function that uh so you take
that so you
take so you just map
this do you map or
reduce you no you don't want to map you
want to
fold so when you
fold when you fold you need
to
uh take take take take so take take
take take so you want to use some kind
of fold however you you want a condition
to
stop
okay you want some kind of fold but you
want a condition to
stop okay
so
okay the easiest is actually just modify
your function
okay and I don't I don't want to use
throw because I don't like throw that
up the function of form
so so don't use St Okay
so
exceed
range how do you embed the state then in
the function so exit
range and if you do that it's too it's
it's it's uh seed
range okay so you want
to return this state
somewhere okay this
state seed
range
so oh
God so so St seed so
start so you want
to one of the issue with functional
programming in a
loop in recursion or reduce is that if
you're going to include the state in
your
function
which means you have you have your
function is no longer just concerned
about it's whatever it's trying to do
because because now you have a extra
argument that that that means the
state so in a sense it's not pure
anymore uh and if you want to include a
state in your function you also have to
change the input both the input and
output
so but you see if you want to use reduce
or fold the function is limited to two
arguments so you need now you need to Ed
the state in one of these argument it's
not good I don't want I don't want to do
that because right now the the get
destination ID is in a perfect State
okay that's the perfect
function you take a seed number you take
a range then you return the new seed
number you know whatever it's
transformed or not okay the thing about
this you know so it's in actually kind
of perfect but but there's extra thing
kind of a state we want to know is that
did this range actually worked you know
but that's beyond that's beside the
purpose of this function the whether
that range actually worked
out from a functional point of view
that's not the job of this function okay
whether that range worked out is that's
somebody else that's another job that's
another functionality okay separate of
concerns the concerns of this function
is just take a input number take a range
and return a new number okay the you
know because that's what this map that's
what map
means so if you want another
state it will be this okay so let's so
let's go back to take while I think that
that
works
okay
so so this is what we need
so this function takes a seed uh and
uh function of takes takes a
seed it
takes
that's
wait so this is a
function
okay
for
example
right
true take W this is true
take
take take
while
oh it returns them
okay of
them
cases and not really happy with today
took this
long
yeah not really happy because
this
so you can do cases and you can do
uh that
okay now I assume there's no overlap
okay
just uh you know actually my wol
I'm language
not feeling good
today this such a trivial problem and
stuck uh and also stuck in the past two
or three you know
problems hello
Valley okay select um select you can you
can work out select and criteria will be
that
okay and uh yeah and ass soon as you
find one drop out okay and uh if you
didn't find any what you
return select criteria criteria is a
function okay so for example we can run
that
that returns that of course now if you
just
say
what so if you say
what
uh if you say 50 it's going to return
that that one
what
79 yeah if you
say
98 yeah that's
correct take care of
valie so one of the function you can use
is
Select and this would
assume
this this would assume there's no
overlap
Okay
so
so let's try another different
case okay let's try if there's some
giant number that's not there empty okay
so what we can do
is
if
for
there's so many ways to do this now I
know
for old
while
pretty pretty
bad
pretty bad and I want to
sleep
so we are back we are still back on this
how do you approach this functional form
of loop
problem there are so many there are
quite a few
approaches
so you can
select from a list of
triplets now if you do
that that will give
you the first triplet that
match and
uh so if that returns so select if that
returns a empty
list
then then okay then then don't do
anything so you want a function
that
um so
function so a function you can
still reduce or
not map or reduce if you going to use
reduce
then
and same is
should
select so select either select that
triplet all returns and empty list
so
oh
okay I'm going to stop
guys failed okay I'm going to stop
it and I'm going to delete this video
this
failed video too
bad bye guys I'm gonna yeah I'm going to
stop
and it's going selecting all the
triplets matching the condition yes so
have you been watching so far have have
you been watching Lucas have you been
watching my elaborate
analysis on on the problem
so have you have you done this problem
do you know what this problem is
about talk say something so you know
Lucas have you been doing this
problem
uh because if you have done this problem
I mean basically I watched the bit is
this not doable with a reduce accumulate
yes it is but the issue is
that the issue is that you know I've
been I've been trying to do that for two
hours you you
see so reduce in wolam language is
called is called fold okay and then you
have fold while Okay so reduceing wam
language is called fold it's just like
python reduce or
JavaScript
uh but if you want to use
fold you know we you there's a you know
you have
to you have to have a condition for it
to stop because for this Advent of day
problem you have you know I started to
analyze you have the issue of whether
one of these triplet is a identity map
so for example one of the triplet
triplet the first two numbers is the
same let's say
551 so if you have that triplet
5510 that means if you have a seed
number of five it returns five if you
have the seat number of six it returns
six you know and so on up to 10 of them
so meaning that the triplet is a
identity map okay so if you account
encounter one of the triplet that's
identity
map do you continue with the other
triplate or not that's one of the
question or do you just stop because
that that affects the answer if if you
continue then possibly the subsequent
triplet they will also they will overlap
with your identity map so so meaning
that your number will get changed to
something but however if you stopped at
the first identity map which means this
you know this condition fits if you stop
at the first identity map
then then may you you lose the
possibility of overlapping situation so
your answer may be wrong you see that
that's the thing tricky
about event of code it doesn't say you
know sometimes your solution pass the to
problem but it doesn't pass when the
real input because the real input
contains some properties not in the to
input I run that into yesterday because
yesterday I was trying to turn these
numbers
into uh
actual dictionary
but when you run the real input you got
a dictionary of 100 million items and
there are hundred of them so that runs
out of memory the crashes crashes my
OBS so the so so you have the issue of
identity map then the other issue is
overlap you see overlap means one you
know Su of this triplet
overlap so that is also another issue to
be of concern so anyway back to the fold
or reduce so when you use fold or reduce
you need to have a
condition to you know when to stop okay
that's one thing the other thing which
is mostly where I'm stuck is that you
need to change when you use reduce of
fold you need to change your function in
in my case this this get uh get
destination ID function such that it
contains the state in its input and
output so that when you do reduce a fold
you can you can determine when to
stop okay
so because reduce function itself never
has as a condition to
stop you know typically it just go
through all the input so it will go
through all the
triplet which is not good
because because I did that before and
one of the input is
wrong once you found a triplate that
does doeses change change the seed
number you you don't want to go on okay
you don't want to go you you want to
stop because otherwise that number
changed to something else that's not
good because each one of these group of
triplet is supposed to be one single
map right so if you use fold or reduce
you have to have you cannot just go
through all the tribute you have to you
have to change your function so that it
embodies a condition to tell you to
abort literally abort this reduce
operation so that's one of the problem
and if you want to stick with functional
programming pure functional programming
form you do not want to use a board
okay you use fold or reduce only if
there's no such case of abort you don't
want to ever abort you want to go
through the complete list because the
moment you use a board you are not doing
functional programming you kind of you
know you are not exactly doing
functional programming okay
so this kind of issues is where I'm
stuck in the past three hours so I don't
want to abort you know I I you know you
can see do I still have
it I don't want to use a Bo and I don't
want to embody the state in my beautiful
function okay so you cannot use fold
okay but however you can use something
similar which is uh fold while which
wolam language provide but not in Python
not in JavaScript not in hcal okay but
wolam language provide fold wire which
is like reduced but with a extra
condition you can tell it when to
start okay but if you use
this you know but however there's a
limitation in the test function it um it
only the argument to the test function
is just previous results of your
function f
so this is not useful to me I need I
need the text function to be able to
take arguments from this from this
triplet from this you know list of
triplet so when one of these triplet you
know the c number is within that stop
okay so therefore I cannot use this f
file so you get into the situation
consideration of functional programming
purity of functional programming and the
forms the various forms of doing Loop in
functional programming you know I went
into a whole 1 hour analysis of it to
see where why am I stuck with this is it
because my refus so to change my to
embed a condition in my function that
fun
fundamentally creates a contradiction
because meanwhile I also want to use
pure functional form of loop I don't
want you know the imperative Loop of
checking you know lots of variables and
checking
State and it turns out no that's I
didn't create a contradiction
rather it's just because there are so
many there are different there are
various forms of Loop in functional
style and the particular one I
want wam language doesn't have it nor
does any other language you know the
particular form of functional
programming loop I want
is a is
a
is a is a fold while but with a
condition that takes the second and all
the first argument of the function
that's fed to the function in other
words I want the condition to be able to
take these
triplets okay so anyway do I make
sense Lucas do I do I make sense if I if
I actually made some sense to you then
I'm
happy you know because that means I all
this time I'm stuck in my analysis means
something okay so anyway so I mean the
other thing is so it's not you know you
could actually do this finish it on time
but it's just so I'm not happy you know
I'm not really happy with where I'm
doing you know how I'm
doing it shouldn't take that long you
know I'm like just going over all
these shouldn't take that long and there
are so many other ways to write it so if
you don't want to use fold fold or if
you if I for some reason don't want to
use fold or for while there are so many
other ways but I was just not quick
enough to do it okay there's so many
other way ways you know select is one
way take while out is another another
way okay uh but I just failed
to do
it okay so that is that the real end
that's the real end I
think oh yes yes that's a good uh
solution you know so Lucas says I think
so but can you not put this triplet into
a function and use a function with
arguments so in other words writing a
rapper uh which I been I started to do
in the beginning and then I went
somewhere
else you are right you know yeah I'm
pretty sure if you do it if you know
some if someone will probably finish
it uh
sooner I I start Stu on something I just
stuck on
the purity of it so yeah right the
rapper so so what we need to do is that
we we we call
the um you know actually that's what
this take while I was trying to
do so we we kind of still use
um we we we you see we so the problem is
we want a function that goes through
these triplet groups okay as one set
then another triplet group so given one
Triplet a list of tripletes we want a
function that go through
this however we want to be able to stop
somewhere once a condition is met so the
proper solution is some kind of is
either fold or reduce
such that the function contains a
state or you can or you can just have a
function that just recurse that a
function that call itself but in the
beginning the function takes the whole
entire set of the
triplets so each time the function Calla
itself and each time reduce one of the
triplet C it out whenever then when ever
the condition is met the function simply
returns uh without coding
itself you know so many ways the
function can embed you know in the
argument one of the true or false
expression so
recursion or you
can you know so there are so many ways
so you know or I can I'm trying to use
the take file the idea of the take while
is that you know this triplet is a list
of triplet right so you feed this list
of triplet to the take while function
the take while function take a list
which is this triplet and a criteria
which is a function that determines when
to stop taking it Taking it
so so on once the condition is met it
simply return one of the triplet that
what we want that's what we want you
know in instead of you know it just this
function will just return one of the
triplate so we kind of avoid the entire
loop the loop is already within this
take while you know this so once we
found this triplet then we just feed it
to our you know get destination
ID uh but you can uh what
uh but you canot
what but you can you not use a filter on
each group oh yeah so yeah so filter
idea is like this take while or even
better select okay so
that's that's what I'm doing so select
take a list and criteria so the list is
just this list of triplet and it just
return a criteria I mean the I mean the
criteria is another function which is
this
function you
know and uh so that's what I'm getting
on to so anyway so I'm kind of slow so
that's why I'm stuck in uh not good okay
so but I think that's it for it today
I'm not going to
finish um I I going to go to sleep thank
you great um
great uh comments Lucas bye guys I'm not
going to finish I'm going to finish
it I'm going to sleep