Hello guys. Welcome to another episode
of the start talk show. Today we are
going to code Emacs Lisp and JavaScript.
We are going to write a
search engine
search engine for xahlee.info website.
And it's going to be on xahlee.org
as well. So So let's get to it straight.
So this is just uh today is just a live
coding and plus I'm going to explain
while I code and uh
and this is going to be probably 90
minutes, okay? 90 minutes or maybe 2
hours. I hope I can finish in 90
minutes. So it's going to be dense
coding.
Uh so writing a uh
writing a search engine for my website
and you can see the topics uh
here I outlined what we are going to do
today. So today's uh
2022 March 26th. Okay, let's begin.
So write a search engine. Uh okay, so
hello guys. If you have a questions,
comments, uh post it, okay? And pay me
uh super chat and PayPal and Patreon.
Okay, so writing a search engine and I'm
I'm using uh Emacs Lisp, of course. I'm
using Emacs and you can see all my Emacs
uh all my command calls and keystrokes
on the left side
as I as I type.
And uh if you don't know any commands
I'm doing, you can just search for it.
Uh for example, that. Okay, so yeah,
let's begin. Okay, so
writing a search engine. So
So let's see. Um
So first of all, let me tell you
tell you what is the expected result,
okay? So
for example, you can use Google. Why Why
do you need to use um
search engine, you know? You can use
Google. But let me let me tell you
what's the result, okay? So, if you go
to my Unicode search, you can, you know,
just search for Ksana Unicode. You can
go to this page. And for example, I type
water, you know,
watch the
uh screen. w a t
e, you know, as I type, you know, the
result shows.
Uh so so this is what I want.
Uh this is the expected result or the
spec of this job, you know, this task of
writing a search engine. This so so I
I'm going to have a search box just like
that. And as you type, you can show the
result.
Uh water and try something magnify. And
uh you know, uh and uh
l a t i n or Latin letters and so on,
you know.
So, this is what it's going to be like.
And why do I need to write a search
engine? So, I'm So, you know, my website
has 10,000 files. Together it's 10,000
files. So, I need, you know, when you
code JavaScript or Emacs Lisp, let's go
to JavaScript, okay? So, ksana.info
and you go to JavaScript in depth. You
know, if you are a JavaScript coder or
Emacs Lisp coder or any any language,
Golang or whatever, constantly you need
to look up uh documentation for
for functions, for methods, or
variables, you know, you need to know
what they mean.
So, for example, when you are coding
JavaScript, you know, I So, I have
JavaScript in depth. This is my best
tutorial.
Truly, you know, one of the best three
top three um in the world in English
language, I would say. So, if you like
my stuff, support me, okay? You can, you
know, pay me and buy it.
JavaScript in depth. So, when you are
coding JavaScript, for example, I have a
complete reference on JavaScript, you
know, object uh
object array, you know, array for
example, you want to uh
you want to get the slice of array, how
do you do it? You know, there are so
many functions, right? So,
when you code if you are a programmer,
constantly you need to look up, you
know, go around the documentation like a
sea of functions.
Um
So,
so for my JavaScript website, it would
be nice to have a search box just like
just like my um Unicode.
You know, just so so you can type a
function, for example, what's the
method, you know, you might remember,
okay, so how do you call a function? Uh
uh
How do you um
How do you call a method?
That's
You know, uh
uh how do you how do you
how do you delete a element in array?
So, in JavaScript, you can do that with
a delete
operator.
You know, so
so you have to find the page, that's the
issue. So,
because I'm familiar with my own
website, so I so I know exactly where it
is. So, operator, so so you go to
operators
and do you see the delete operator,
equality, bitwise, logic? So, no, it's
not here.
So, that's why you have to search.
So, let's go back to JavaScript in
depth. Let's go to the array section.
Array, so all about arrays,
uh
where here. Array overview, create
arrays, sparse array, array-like object,
array equality, array how to. So,
let's let's see.
So, I don't remember exactly where I
mentioned the delete operator.
So, I mean that's a point. So, when you
code, you know, so if I have a search
box, then I can get it right away. I can
see the variety of ways to delete
element or a bunch of elements in array.
You know, there are several methods. You
know, what's the difference between
them? You know, so that's why a search
engine and especially instantaneous one
is extremely useful. You know, Google
what why don't you use Google search or
DuckDuckGo or anything like that? There
are several reasons not, you know,
that's no good because Google search
they do not index all of my pages. They
index like 90%.
You know, there there are maybe 5%
of my pages they do not even index. So,
and that's one thing. The other thing is
that when you search for JavaScript
array methods, you know, you you'll get
a bunch of spamming websites with lots
of ads, shallow, you know, written by
penny writers, you know, I you know,
like tutorialpoint, W3School. They are
not in-depth and sometimes they are
incorrect.
You know,
lots of spam, you know, they all show on
the first several pages.
And also, you know,
for example, you can use Google to
search a particular website. For
example, I believe the syntax is site
site xahlee.info.
Let's say, then let's say I I want to
delete array element, okay?
Yeah, so, you know, so then you get my
PowerShell you get to it shows my
PowerShell
you know, tutorial about array
uh array.prototype.splice,
that's what you want, okay?
You know, so it would be so
So, and plus a lot of people don't know
this uh
you know, this syntax to search a
particular website uh with Google
search.
Uh
So, they don't index all my web pages
and uh
when you search something, they often
show irrelevant results. So, that's a
problem. The other thing is Google is
becoming a evil empire. So, also you
don't want to rely on third party. So,
Okay.
Let's let's get back to let's start to
write write it, okay?
So, to write a search engine, you need
uh
I don't know what is Algolia, okay?
That's another search engine. Same
problem. Same problem. Okay, so
So, to write a search engine, you need
um
you need two things.
One is that you need you want to index
you want to create a index file.
Kind of like a database. So, for So, the
index file will be just like a hash
table or in other words, key-value
pairs. So, key is a word people search.
Let's say delete array, you know,
keyword. And the value
uh the essence of the value should be
the URL, the page that contains that
word. So, you need to create you need to
go through all your um
content, you know, all your files in a
directory,
you know,
thousands of them. You need to create
this index file, create these key-value
pairs where the key are the words people
type. And you know,
then it's a hash table. It shows the
page it is located.
This is the simplest form of search
engine. Now, if you're going to show the
context, you know, what's the word
before or after the searched word, then
that's gets more complex. But for me,
for now, a simple case will do. So, you
need to create a key value a hash table,
the index file, okay? And for that, we
are going to use Emacs Lisp, okay?
I was thinking maybe use Golang, but
apparently lots of you people says, you
know, you want me to do it with using
Emacs Lisp, so let's do that. So, once
you have a index file,
that's essentially the hash table, you
convert it to the JSON format. Then you
use JavaScript to um
to
you know, use the JavaScript as a front
end as the interface to to query, to
look up the hash table, then show the
result instant instantaneously. So,
that's what
we need to do, okay?
So, let's go to let's start to write it.
Okay, just talking about that takes 10
minutes. Uh
Okay, so today's uh thing we going to
write uh so, first of all,
create a index file
using Edisp, okay? Emacs Lisp. Then
then okay, so I actually already said it
here.
Okay, so first job, let's begin. So,
Emacs Lisp, so we create a Emacs Lisp
file. So, here's a file, and uh let's
put the date, and let's say
go through all the
and uh create a index file of their
content.
Okay, first of all, let's be simple.
Let's create create a hash table.
Keyword being the
title of the page. Wait, so let's see.
So, I'm going to create a title of the
page and the URL file and um keyword.
Key is the
title of the page, let's say.
Value is the
file path, okay?
Now, we need we may need to change that,
but let's go with that for now. So, go
through all all directory, create an
index file of their content, and uh
And for now, let's just focus on the
title of the page. You know, we only
search the title of the page. Let's
forget about the whole content. It gets
more complex.
Um
So, title of the page and value will be
the file path, okay?
So, that's for now.
Then
s- uh
save that hash table as a JSON
file, okay? So, that's the main thing we
need to do. So,
first of all, okay? So, let's see input
the Okay, let's create a
variable.
That's a input directory. So, where
would it be? So, let's see.
So, let's do Java uh let's do Emacs
list, okay? So, go through my Emacs list
tutorial. So, the input directory will
be
my Emacs tutorial
page, that's right. So, okay, so let's
copy that.
Uh so, here's the file path, that's
right. So, the input directory
will be this, okay?
So that So we going to index all files
in that directory, actually.
Actually, this directory has lots of
other things. We do not want to index
the Emacs manual. So
So okay, we immediately we run into
complexities. So you see the Emacs
directory is all is most of my Emacs and
the Emac Lisp tutorial and blogs.
The Emacs manual directory is Emac Lisp
manual and Emacs manual. You know, each
one of them is about 800 pages, 900
pages.
Uh a thousand pages for Emac Lisp
actually. So then there's miscellaneous
directory, which is 150 pages. And this
is about miscellaneous essays. So am I
going to index Okay, for Yeah, for now
let's go simples, you know, because I'm
kind of doing a tutorial and demo, so
after the video I'm going to you know,
make it uh for real life stuff. So for
now let's just um
Yeah, so for now let's just
index that directory.
Okay, that directory
you are looking at, which is 800 pages,
okay? Now let's delete the backup.
Delete the backup, okay?
So this is input directory. And now
go through the the
for each file
get the title string
and file path.
Okay, that's what we going to do. Okay,
so how do we get How How we How do we go
through a directory?
You should write in assembly.
What? What crap? Okay, how do we get
into How do we traverse a directory in
Emacs Lisp? Okay, let's go to my Emacs
Lisp tutorial. I have a tutorial here. I
don't remember offhand.
Um
walk-d. So, this is how you go through
all directories.
All files in a directory, okay? So,
here's a code.
Uh
So, here's a code.
directory-file-recursively,
okay? So, um yeah, so let's
Okay, let's look up the documentation.
Okay, so directory-file-recursively,
that's right.
Yeah, okay. So, we already have a
template. Um
So, we want to go to the d- So, the d-
would be
X input directory, the root directory.
Then regular expression, uh what is the
regular expression for?
Uh
Return list Return list of all files in
the directory and all its subdirectories
that have file names matching regular
expression, okay? So, this regular
expression is the
matching file names. So, we want HTML
files, okay? So, that's the regular
expression.
Then optional include directories. No,
we don't care about directories. We only
want to uh go through the files. So,
here we'll be setq file-list, okay?
Okay?
Pretty fine, okay? So, now we have a
file list
to go through, okay? Now, we just need
to write a function
that
enumerate that go through each one of
the file. So, here is a file list, for
example, let me show you, okay? If I run
it, void variable, okay, yeah, void
variable. So, we have to evaluate this
because Emacs right now doesn't know
what is this. So, evaluate it and now
evaluate that line, so you can see a
bunch of results. Now, let me show you
the result. So, you go to the messages
buffer.
Uh, it doesn't show them all, but let's
copy it, create a new buffer, paste it.
It's, you know,
uh, uh, you know, turn the, you know,
make them into each line, so you can see
lots of files, okay? Let's close it. Let
me, yeah, I'm going to show you, okay?
So,
So, here is a list of files, okay? We
got a file list. Then, we need to write
a function
uh, function that takes a file
uh,
takes a file path
and do something, okay? So, let's say
let's call this function process file.
It will take, it will read a file and
uh,
get the title and uh,
and get the file path and uh, push it
into a hash table, okay? So, so that's
that's the function. Now, let's leave
it.
We're going to come back to it. So, next
thing we're going to
have this function run on each and every
of this file list, okay? So, to do that,
you use the command, the function map C,
okay? So, map C
takes a function then
take a list. So, the list is going to be
X file list, okay? And the function is
going to be
X process file, okay? So, you need a
quote.
So, that
So, essentially that's it. So, for now
let's say what the function do. Let's
just say let's just say print the file
path, okay? For now.
Uh
you know, okay? So, there it is, very
simple. So, we can actually test test
this script.
Okay? So,
So, let's run it. Actually, we can run
it run this now and it should show you
basically a list of all the files.
Yeah, let's run it. Now, make sure
there's no errors, okay? Uh
run it.
Okay, it's done. Now, go to the messages
buffer. You can
Now, you can see all the bunch of files,
you know, we just you know, we kind of
we went through, okay?
So, now So, you know, lots of them.
And now
Now, we need to create a hash table in
you know,
for this function. Each time it you
know, get the title and string and push
it to a hash table.
So,
how do you write a hash table, okay? So,
let's go to Emacs tutorial.
Um
Let's copy the Let Let's put this in my
talk show, so we have a record of what
we talked about.
Uh So, let me
go do that.
Okay, now we need to look for we need to
check uh look for how do you uh create a
hash table in Emacs list, okay? So, hash
table so you go to Emacs Lisp
uh Emacs Emacs Lisp advanced.
Then, you have
cons pair, list, vector, sequence types.
And you have association association
list, you have property list, you have
symbol property list, and then you have
hash table. That's what you want.
Okay, so we're going to create a hash
table. Okay, let's just copy the code.
So, you know,
So, we're going to create a hash table.
Uh let's put the comments here. So,
shrink it a little bit.
So, we're going to create a hash table.
So, yeah, let's say my hash.
And
you can kind of ignore the rest
the rest of it.
This part This argument just means it
tells Emacs
how do you compare? What what what
function to use to
to check if a key exists.
You know, typically if the key is a
string,
then
then you use
string equal. You know, because
different data types,
they have different
um
sense of equality. For example, the
number three integer versus the string
three,
for example,
three
versus three.
You know, so are they equal or not?
Well, you know, conceptually they are
equal. They are just three, but you
know, technically, depending on the
language, this is a integer, this is a
string. When when you compare you know,
they
you know, they don't they are not equal.
So, so when you create a mesh hash table
in Emacs Lisp, this this argument tells
Emacs what function to use to determine
whether key exists or not. What kind of
uh comparison function to use.
So, that's what that part is. So, in
general, just use equal. That's good.
Okay, so the hash table So, let's put a
some documentation
for the hash table. So,
So, we can say
uh define var
my hash in need value in need value,
let's say nil. And documentation
is
key is
a
string title title string, okay?
Key is a string.
The title of the HTML page.
Value is the file path.
Actually, we might need to reverse them.
Uh
Let's not reverse them. I don't Well,
anyway, let's let's do it
this way for now, okay? So, that's my
hash. Okay, right now the hash table is
empty.
Okay, so now
Now, we go we need to modify this
function. Go through each file.
So, first of all, you need to open the
file.
Uh Open the file, get the title string,
then add it to the hash table, okay?
So, how do you open a file?
Okay, we check my tutorial. But first of
all, let's add it add this here, okay?
So, you open the file by Let's go back
to Emacs tutorial.
Practical Emacs Lisp.
Uh you open the file by
read file. Yeah, that's the one you
want.
Yep. I already have it written. This is
the best way to open the file. There are
some There are many ways in Emacs Lisp.
Uh, some of them are not very efficient,
you know, for different purposes. Some
are Some of them are just only for
interactive use.
Uh, typically those are not efficient,
such as find-file, you know, for
example. Find-file is what you use in
Emacs to open a file.
But,
if you are coding Emacs Lisp script,
usually you don't want to use that
because when you call find-file,
it opens the file, it it starts it it
starts to syntax color the file, it
turns on undo, so everything you do
there's, you know, it slows you down
because it has undo information. But, in
our case, we don't need undo, you know.
And we don't need syntax coloring
because, you know, it's going to process
thousands of files every second.
So,
you don't want to use find-file. So,
this way So, you want to use this way,
okay? So,
so which is, um,
did I paste it here? No, yeah, okay,
here it is. So, this is how you want,
um,
to do it, okay? So, let's
What?
Ah, we screwed up a parenthesis
somewhere.
What?
Unbalanced parenthesis. Where did we
Scan error.
Yeah, we missed we missed right
parenthesis, okay? So now here, okay, so
yeah.
So now we have So this is what we want,
okay? So let's let's name it properly.
So name
uh
file path, okay? We don't need this
anymore, okay? So that's what you do
with temp buffer. So you create that
function, create a temporary buffer,
then you insert the file contents, and
uh uh oops.
Yeah, you you call the command insert
file contents and give it a file path.
It will insert the file content into the
buffer, okay? Then do something here.
And what we're going to do, we're going
to First of all, go to um
go to char point minimum. That's the
beginning of the buffer, okay? Then
search forward, search forward for
title, okay?
Search forward for the for the for the
word title.
Uh for example, in a HTML file, for
example, here's a title.
You know, every title is not optional.
Basically, whenever you have HTML page,
you should have a title.
Okay, so we search for the title, you
know, search
to the title, then
optional um bound
We don't care about those options, okay?
So search forward for the title, then
then we want
set
point uh
set P1.
P1 is a position, okay? Let's say set P1
to
match
end.
Okay?
So, we need to declare a variable P1
local variable. So, let's use let
P1 and P2. We need two variables for
storing positions of the
cursor in the buffer. Okay? So,
So, now we can move the whole thing here
inside here.
Okay?
Prettify it.
So,
Okay, so
Okay, so we insert the file contents
into the new buffer we created. We go to
the beginning of the buffer. Then, we
search forward for title. Okay?
Okay, then we
set
P1, the local variable, to be uh
we need P2, too. We set P1, the local
variable, to be the
the end position of the last match. So,
that's going to So, basically, that's
the beginning of the inner text, okay?
Then,
we search forward again. This time, we
search for
the closing tag of the title, okay?
That.
Then, uh we don't care about the
options, okay?
Okay, then we set
position two to be match beginning.
Okay?
Match beginning zero means the you know,
zero means the entire match, you know,
when you don't have, you know, sub
groups.
So, P2 is the position of the entire
match the beginning position. So,
meaning
you know, right before the closing tag.
So, essentially, our P1 and P2
Let me show you. So, our P1 and P2 is
right there.
So, now all we have to do is tell Emacs
to grab the string between these two
positions, okay?
So, now
So, let's declare a new variable uh
title string.
Uh let's let's
let's uh let's do that.
Let's change our variable name, okay?
So,
yeah, this is my new convention.
Okay, so title string title string. So,
we're going to grab the title string.
The title string is going to be
set buffer
substring um
buffer substring no properties, okay?
P1 P2, okay? This going to be set
title string
that, okay? So, now we got the title
string. Now, once we got the title, we
going to
push it to the hash table, my hash,
okay?
Let's change the name my hash to X hash.
Yeah, let's not change it now, okay? I I
uh you know,
bad habit of me of of my of of obsess
obsessing about the variable names and
stuff.
You should write it in assembly. Uh what
a comment. Hello sir. So,
who how many is watching? Only six,
okay. So, we going to So, now
we have the title string. Now, we going
to push it to the hash table, okay?
Yeah. So, how do you push to the hash
table? Let's go back to the Emacs Lisp
read file, okay?
So,
how do you push it to the hash table?
Okay, here is what we talked about hash
table. Yeah, so let's go to hash table
and see
how do you
uh add a key-value pair to the hash
table. There it is, put hash.
Copy it back to Emacs.
Okay, put hash, then X title,
then the value will be
uh file path. Let's Let's write uh
Okay? And put put it into the my hash
table, okay?
Fantastic.
Okay, that's I think that's it.
Now,
now we can actually run the whole file.
So, so right now this file
uh this file
right now this file will go through
every file
in the in this directory
and uh find the title of the page and
push
and push it into the hash table.
And so, at the end, let's print the hash
table to see what it looks like, okay?
Print.
Okay? Now, we going to run this
code, okay? Run it.
Search failed the title. Okay, so
apparently some some some of my HTML
file don't don't have a title. That's
the problem.
So, I don't know which page it is. So,
let's put a print statement here so that
we know which page it is processing.
So, processing that file, okay? Now,
let's run it again. Run it. Okay, search
failed title. Now, let's switch to the
buffer message
to the uh messages buffer. There, okay?
So, this page this
page doesn't have the title. Okay, we
found the error. So, let's open it.
Oh, okay, page moved. Okay. So,
yeah, so that's another complexity, you
know.
Uh
So, because, you know, when when I have
that, for example, sometimes you for
many reasons you change the file name.
So, I have this,
you know, it says, you know, page moved
either merged into another page or
something like that.
So, that's why this page doesn't have a
title and
in fact, you don't want to index this
page, you know,
for search engine. So,
so when you see that,
okay, so what to do? So, basically,
we are going to put a if statement. So,
if you cannot find the title, then skip
that page. Okay? So, we going to put the
if statement. Okay, let's change the
code. Let's put a the statement.
Am I Am I doing okay? Voice check, video
check.
Is this interesting? If it's
interesting, say hi, okay?
Uh
It say, you know,
if it's interesting, say Tiffany Dover.
I learned this from another YouTuber.
So,
if it's not interesting, say no.
Perfect. Fantastic, Louis. Thank you.
So, okay. So, now we're going to we're
going to put a if statement.
If it cannot find the title, then skip
this page. Do nothing, okay? So, let's
do it.
So, if statement
show the pink window. So, if statement
if search forward is true, you know, the
search what forward function returns
either true or false. So, if it is true,
then
we're going to do that.
That that that that that Yeah, we're
going to do this whole thing.
Okay?
There it is, okay? If it's, you know, if
it's
if the title is found, do this. If it's
not found, do nothing. So, let's uh
change this to when, okay? When
when is
basically the same
as if statement. Uh basically the if if
not not found, do nothing, okay? So,
so when search forward is true, you
found that you you found the title,
then,
you know, grab it and put into the hash
table. Otherwise, do nothing, okay?
So, now actually our code is complete
again. We can run the whole thing. So,
let's prettify.
Shrink a little bit.
Uh let's
let's um
let's call
you know, the whole so we can see the
whole. Okay, that's it. So, we're going
to run this again.
Run it.
Ah, search failed title. Okay, same
error. So, you again you run into search
failed. That's because
when you call the function
search-forward,
you have to give it options.
Uh, because otherwise, if it's not
found, it will return an error. So,
let's
describe function search-forward. You
can see
the the first optional argument is
bound.
Bound bound is a position. That means
search up to that position.
And and ignore the rest of the text.
Okay, so do we want it bound? We are
nil, okay? So, the next option is no
error. That's the That's the thing we
need. So, if it's not found, just no
error true, okay?
That means
if it's not found,
don't error out. Don't stop it, okay?
Ignore it. If if no error, no problem,
okay? So, no no error true, okay? That's
what we want.
And the other option come, we don't
care, okay? So, now search-forward for
the title and uh
not bound, you know, search all the way
to the bottom of the file. And uh if
it's not found,
okay, ignore it, okay?
And uh when it's found, it will return
true. Then,
you know, then we do, um,
you know, this, okay? Now, let's run it
again. Run it.
Fantastic. Fantastic. Done. You see?
Now, let's Actually, let's print done.
Let's run again. You see, very fast.
Let's show the message buffer. You see,
done.
Uh now let's look at the message buffer.
You know, you have this whole thing.
That's a hash table, you know, that's a
hash table we generated.
You know, when you have a super long
line, Emacs become very slow. Like right
now I cannot you know, I press page up,
it doesn't move.
Because this this line is
this long line is some eight
some 800 file path. You know, that's a
hash table. So,
we need to do something to it. So, let's
close that because it slows down Emacs.
So, instead of just print hash,
let's say
Now, let's loop through the hash table
and print each each one's
uh title and file path, you know,
per line, okay?
So, let's So, how do you print hash
table? So, how do you loop through a
hash table? Okay, here is how.
Uh
there.
Map hash, okay? Apply a function to each
and every entry in a hash table.
Yeah, that's that's what we're going to
do. So, this is my Emacs Lisp tutorial.
So, instead of print hash, we're going
to map hash.
Okay, so
the hash table is going to be that, and
what is a function? The function is
going to be a lambda.
Okay? Uh lambda.
So,
so for each element in a hash table,
what we're going to do
uh
add entry, remove entry, get keys value,
number of entries, remove all entries,
check key exist, apply a function to all
entries, okay? Apply a function to all
entries in a hash table. The function F
must take two arguments, key and value,
okay? So, the function takes two
elements, key and value, okay?
Okay, key and value.
So, for each key
let's just say message, okay? Key.
Uh let's let's name and them KK and VV,
so it's easier to search.
Okay?
So, for each key, you print it
and uh let's say key
value.
Okay? That's going to print the key and
There it is. There is our function,
print
each element in the hash table, okay?
Now,
let's run it.
Now, let's shrink the whole thing again,
so you can see. Let's run it. Fantastic.
Oh, wait. Invalid function. Invalid
function. Let's see. Let's go to the
message buffer.
Invalid function, lambda something
something.
Okay, why Oh, yeah.
How idiotic I am. You know, I was using
a comma, you know, in JavaScript. In Go
language, you need a comma, but in
Emacs, there's no comma, okay? Let's do
it again.
Uh what?
Uh again, there's a comma. You don't
need the comma, okay? In in this
Okay? Now, let's do it again.
Fantastic.
Let's go to it. You see? There it is. Uh
there it is. Uh hash table the the full
glory.
You know, 800 8,000 file. Now, you see
now it's fast.
Before it's one giant long line, and
Emacs cannot deal with that. So, but now
So, we can see
So, for example, so let's see. So, this
line So, on this file
at this file path you the title is that.
And on this file, you know, title and
file path. Fantastic.
So, essentially now we have the index
file for our search table. So,
I mean, for our search engine basically,
yeah.
So, we got an index file. God, there's
so much There's a lot to do. So, how
long have I been I've been talking for
an hour almost already.
So, essentially now we got an index
file. Now, we need to convert this hash
table into a JSON format, you know,
because JavaScript needs to read the
JSON format.
Then we uh start to code JavaScript. We
almost done.
Uh and I'm been talking for an hour, and
I'm kind of tired. So, let's Let me take
a break, okay? Few minutes. Let's read
the comments.
Uh
So, where is my video? So, yeah.
Let me have a drink.
Energy drink, okay? So, this is my
energy
super energy drink.
Okay, so let's um so I got I got a hash
table.
Now, the next thing I need to do is to
convert this hash table um
into a into a JSON format, okay?
So, let's clear
Yeah, I need a a break.
Uh sitting here for an hour coding this.
Am I doing good?
So, let's clear clarify the
comment a little bit so people can
understand what we doing. So,
uh go through all the and create an
index file
of their contents.
Create a hash table for keys, the
Okay, so the index file is a hash table.
Key is the title of the page, value is
the file path, okay?
Save that hash table as a JSON file,
okay?
Okay, and uh
Yeah, so that's what we are doing. So,
here's the input directory. Here's a
hash table.
Okay.
And uh then here's a file list to go
through. Then here's a function
that takes a file path
and find the title and add to the hash
table.
Then here is the line
that calls the function on each and
every files in that directory.
So, in fact, the file list can be uh can
be placed over here. But anyway, let's
continue, okay? So
So now we have a hash table. Now we
print the hash value, okay? The
print of hash table, okay?
Okay, so so far so good.
So the next
task is to convert the hash table into a
JSON. Now I'm not sure how to do that,
so it's going to be a bit exploration.
So in in Emacs list, you have a
library that does JSON, but I've never
used it. I don't think so. So
anyway, let's see what's the comment.
Really liking it. Fantastic. Fantastic.
Thank you.
I love it. Fantastic. Interesting
indeed. Use when, okay? Great. It is
very interesting. Add a lot to the side
car quality, great.
Don't need programming when that's
that's correct.
Yeah, so you know,
there's little, you know, style issues.
So so when you have a ran when you have
a when, you don't really need
the p r o g n to group them together.
Yeah, but some you know, that's a little
issues because you know, it's because
sometimes when you are working on Emacs
list,
it's convenient because for example, for
some reason later on I decided I don't
want when. I do want to have if.
Now if I'm going to do that,
then if I don't have the program,
you know, this p r o g n, then it's
going to then I have to find out, you
know,
you know, which line I have to put them
together and then put a program. But now
I can just press a key
to
to have the whole group, you know, I can
easily manipulate the whole thing.
You know, so
when you are done with the code at the
end, then maybe then you clean up. You
know, then then okay, this p r g a is
redundant, you remove it like that, then
you prettify the code, you see.
But then,
you know, after a month when you are
maintaining the code, you know, you
always have to maintain the code, you
know, maybe you need to add some more
features, maybe I decided I'm going to
index the whole file content instead of
just the title, you need to edit the
file again.
Then then
then you're going to have Oh my god, uh
tedious, you know, I I need to put a
p r n here because, you know,
so
so in general, I don't fuss about these
um
you know, these tiny issues.
You know, usually
in fact, ideally, you should have always
have
you should
group
your code in a syntactical unit, you
know, like
you should make them so that a any unit
like independent unit of code
semantic unit of the code is also
syntactically a unit. For example, this
this few lines,
they
they are meaning is a independent kind
of independent unit. So, you can make
them into also a Wait.
Make them into also a syntactical unit.
So that you can edit your file,
you know, the syntactic syntactical unit
and semantical unit uh
there's a correspondence and that that
is the beauty of the
nested parenthesis syntax.
For example, here's a function, right?
This is a function.
Now, I can edit the function by just
like remove the whole. You know, I can
go anywhere or to another file and uh
put it here. You know, I don't have to
like if you but this is the beauty of
S-expression, you know, the symbolic
expression.
There's a correspondence between
semantic unit and syntactical unit.
But, if I'm doing this in JavaScript,
then no. Then then you have to you know,
then you have to go line by line to edit
it, you know, basically. So, that's so
you know, that's my minor, you know, uh
kind of tip. That that just that's one
of the advantage of the nested
parenthesis syntax. Of course, there are
many disadvantages as well because, you
know, you got lots of this nesting. If
you are missing one, then it's hell.
Yeah,
if you by some reason if your cat jumped
onto your keyboard, then it's hell. It's
hard to fix, you know, it it you know.
So, anyway.
So, let's So, now So, let's get on to
the next thing.
Um let's get on to the next
thing of converting the hash table to
JSON, you know, there are many way to do
it. You know, one easy one easy way is
just search, you know, Emacs this hash
you know, JSON. Then you'll find the
library, but I'm not going to do that
because
well, because I'm going to show you some
some of my um
my skills, you know, but you know, I'm
doing my talk show. So, let me show you,
okay? So, first of all, you So, right
now we want to convert a hash table to
JSON. The question is how to how to do
that.
Now, I know there's a library. So,
you know, so one way is to just
look into the
the Emacs Lisp
libraries that comes with Emacs. You'll
find it there easily. So, how do I begin
to do it? For example, I just search,
you know, describe function on any
function name. So, so I
am now looking at the
the doc the inline the doc string for
the forward search forward function, you
know. Then, I can jump to the source
code. Okay, this one is in C. So, that
doesn't work.
So, you you actually need something
that's not in C. Okay, so with 10
buffer, there it is. Okay, so describe
function on that. So, you see with 10
buffer is a this marker in this file.
Okay, now jump to that file. Now, we are
at the source code of this function.
Now, you dial jump to the directory. So,
here is the file the directory this
function is defined.
And here is the you arrived at the
the Emacs Lisp libraries that comes with
Emacs. You can see the file path is
there.
So, so let's go up a directory.
In fact, it's here. You know, if I just
search for JSON, let's say this matching
lines JSON.
There it is. You know, we already found
it. Okay, yeah, so let's let's directly
go to it.
So, here is a JSON library.
Let's see. Okay, so open it.
Okay, open it.
Written by
by this guy. I know this guy. It's
actually
a she now.
Any anyway, so
this is written in 2006. Yes.
So,
Okay, so JSON. So, let's see what
what
So, here's some documentation.
Okay, so here's a library for parsing
and generating JSON files, okay?
JavaScript Object Notation. Learn about
JSON here. Use So, what's the
So, this is unexplored territory. I've
never used this before. So, we need So,
this is how
you know, I look up
um
how I do things, how I try to find,
okay? So, the user serviceable entry
points for the parser are the functions
JSON read, JSON read from string.
Uh
the encoder has a single entry point
JSON encode, okay? Since there are
several natural representations of
key-value pair mappings in Emacs Lisp
associative list
property list, hash table
JSON read allows you to specify which
you the prefer, okay? JSON object type,
okay? So, we need to look into that.
JSON object type and JSON array type.
Okay, similarly, since false and null
are distinct in JSON you can distinguish
them by binding JSON false
and JSON null as desired. Binding JSON
false and JSON null. Okay. So, you know,
we don't care about this, but we care
you know, we want to convert a hash
table into JSON.
We could also convert the hash table
into a list
then convert that to JSON, you know,
several ways.
So
um so, let's So, let's just let's look
at Yeah, so we need to read
um,
define the So, this is unexplored
territory for me. So, let's look up, you
know,
this matching lines to see all the
functions in this file, okay?
Let's say if there's a hash word. There
it is. JSON encode hash table.
There it is. So, this seems to be the
function we want. It takes a hash table
and returns a
a JSON string, I think. So, let's have a
look.
Okay, open that.
Okay, hash table encoding JSON encode
hash table. Return JSON representation
of hash table. Okay.
Um,
Okay, wait. Uh, return a JSON
representation of hash table. This That
mean it returns a string.
Because
because a
Yeah, a string is what we want. That's
basically JSON is just a string, a giant
Well, J- JSON itself is not a string,
but however,
however, how do you represent it? You
have to represent it as a string in
Emacs.
I Well, so, I'm I'm not
I'm not too sure what's going on. So,
anyway,
So, here's the function we want, okay?
Let's go back to our code. So, let's uh,
let me show you, okay?
Uh, wait.
Okay, let's put this window over here so
that
so that we can see.
Now, let's go back to our code, okay?
Temp buffer we don't need. We don't need
that. Go back to our here. Here's our
code.
Now, the function we want, let's say,
let's put it here. That's probably the
function we want.
But, before
before we call the function, we need to
load this library, okay?
So, you're going to call
require
and the JSON, okay? So, this is how you
load the library, require JSON, okay?
Now, this function will be available.
So, I don't know what this function
does.
So, the easiest way is to test it first.
So, first of all, you create a hash
table and the call it, see what it
returns, okay?
So, here's a hash table.
Uh
You know, we can create a new buffer and
start a fresh, okay? So, save this
as the date
and dot EL, okay?
Okay, require JSON
and uh
Okay, so let's look at this.
So, now
we load the JSON library.
We create a dummy hash table.
And now we
call the function
JSON encode hash table and give our hash
table variable.
Uh but, what does it return? Let's run
it. Run it.
Fantastic, it runs.
Okay, but what exactly is the result? I
don't know. So,
is it a string? Let's try. Let's see.
String P.
Let's say X result. Okay, so
result, okay.
Then, is it a string?
Run it.
Run it. True. There it is. You see? In
the mini buffer, you can see it's true.
And by the way, I want I want to test
this. Okay, so there is something
You know, when I'm doing a video, so
there's a little digression. Okay, so
when I'm doing a video, I want the mouse
cursor to be big and magnified. Like
Like can you see it?
Yeah, a a little red. So, let's see if I
can turn on
um
control panel. Okay, so you you go to
control panel. You go to the classic
Windows mouse.
You want the trails. Okay, let's see.
Pointer options. There it is.
There it is. Let's see. Do you see the
fantastic?
That shows Yeah, that shows, right? In
my video.
Let's see.
Yep. Fantastic. Okay, let's
let's
let's get back.
It is This is just fun. Okay, so So,
back to um what is this? Close.
Yeah, so now
it shows a string. Okay, but what is the
result? Okay, fantastic. So, this is a
result. This is a JSON.
Um
Okay, so
So
So, this function
This function takes a hash table and
returns a string. This string is a JSON
thing. Okay, but
But, how do you um
Let's switch to the message buffer.
How do you
You you you want to save this into a
file essentially. You don't want You
see, you don't want the
lots of these escape codes.
Wait, so
How do you
So, you So, you So, you got a string.
Right, so you got a string.
And now you want to
Yeah, basically you want to save the
string into a file.
Once you save the string into a file,
then you won't have, you know, though
these uh escapes escapes.
Okay, that's what we going to do, okay?
So
So, the result So, So, this is a string.
Now, the next question is how do you
save a string into a file, okay?
Now, let's look up my Emacs tutorial
again.
Uh Emac Lisp advanced. Let's go to Emac
Practical Emac Lisp. I need to uh modify
the navigation bar. Not satisfied with
this.
You know, it should be
all accessible, you know,
to go to any of these topics without
having to like
click to, you know.
Yeah. Okay, any anyway, so
how do you save a string to a file?
Okay, so let's go to practical e-mac
list
writing a script read file write file.
There it is.
So you have write region.
There it is. So you can use this
function, okay? write region
write region. So point minimum point
max, you know, that's a position. But
but you can also give it a string.
Okay? That will
save that
uh string to a file name. So what is a
file name? File name will be let's say
xx.json.
Okay, xx.json,
okay? Then optional uh optional append,
no. Visit, no. Log name, no. Must Okay,
we don't care.
Okay, so this will
um
Yeah, so this will do it.
Run it.
Oh, wait. Oh, wait.
Okay, so now let's go to the file, okay?
Let's open this file. Fantastic.
Fantastic.
Let's magnify. So this is actually our
hash table.
Can you Can you see? This is actually
our hash table. Fantastic. Um you know,
this is 800 files. Each key
Each key is the
file title.
And each value is the Let's turn off
that. You know, each key
is the file title and each value is the
file path, you know.
We made a mistake, you know, here we
have a toy hash table, but actually it's
a local variable. So we So So the hash
table actually converted was was our
thing.
Okay, so we don't need this file
anymore. So
cut it, delete it,
go back to our code here,
and
let's put the code here.
Paste it here. So require JSON. Okay,
and we don't need our toy hash table
anymore.
Then
then this result is is a JSON file. So
let's just uh
And that's a string. That's right.
So we don't need this. So here is that.
Okay? Simple. Just two lines.
Load the JSON library, then call this
function to turn a hash table into a
JSON string, then call write region to
save it to a file. And the file it's
saved to is this one.
Okay, so God, we I already So we did 80
minutes. We did 80 minutes and now we
haven't begin to write a JavaScript part
yet. The JavaScript part will take 40
minutes or more.
Uh you know, in order to see a search
you know, a search
search engine uh box result.
Okay, so so so okay, so
So right now we have a problem. This
this JSON
file is one single long line, very long.
I don't want that.
I want it to be, you know, with line
breaks.
Because Emacs have difficulties of
handling very long lines. Because when
you have very long lines, you see, it
becomes super slow.
Uh so,
I'm going to
Yeah, let's skip that. Okay, let's don't
worry about this. Let's
uh get on to the next thing.
Okay, it might be helpful to also search
H2 tags. Exactly. Yeah, but later on,
okay, because we need to
Oh, and JSON library is loaded by
default, okay. Great to know.
Uh okay, so
Yeah, the good point. You also need to
It It's good to also search for uh H2
header tags and H3s, you know, but for
now,
let's make the problem as simple as
possible, you know, just to prototype a
search engine.
Uh okay, so now, what's the next So, we
got the JSON file.
We uh we we Okay, we got the JSON file.
It It's going Okay, we got we got the
JSON file and uh
We We have the JSON file, and this JSON
file essentially it'll become a
JavaScript file.
So, we can actually start to work on the
JavaScript now, okay?
Yeah, let's Yeah, let's work on the
JavaScript.
You know, essentially this JSON file is
all we needed. That's all we need Emacs
this for.
To create this
this JSON file, which is the index file
for our search engine.
Um
So, let's move on to uh start to code
the JavaScript front end to write the
search engine.
Okay, so
So, first So, So, okay. So, let's put
the code back into my talk show page.
Today's talk show. So, today So, here's
the code we did today.
Uh this Emacs this
Uh okay. Then, make a backup of this
file just in case.
Then,
So, now we can start to work on the
JavaScript.
Okay. So,
Now,
Now, let's open the JSON file.
What? Not exist. What the
Uh what?
Oh,
Where did we do it?
Uh God.
Uh
This is no good. Okay, so
Where did the JSON file go?
Oh, yeah. So,
yeah. It's in the temp in my temp dir.
I forgot. So,
Yeah, so there it is, the JSON file.
So, open this file.
Now, let's
let's make them into uh individual
lines. So, we're going to do a find and
replace.
Let's magnify so you can see.
Find replace of
of this character.
Wait, not not that.
Yeah.
Find replace this, okay?
Okay. Find replace
double quote, comma, double quote.
Enter.
Replace by
double quote,
comma,
space, double quote.
I mean, return double quote, okay? Do
it. Yes, yes, to the whole, okay? Now,
it's Now, it's much better. Now, it's
not not uh You see? Now, it's much
better.
Okay, here's our JSON file, okay?
So,
magnify so
the key is the file title.
The value is the file path. So, so we
got a JSON file, okay?
So,
cut
cut it out.
Wait, make a backup.
Cut it.
Delete the file.
Now, go back to
go back to my Emacs.
Okay.
Now, let's
new buffer, paste the file,
and save it.
Okay, this is going to be named XX
search
.js.
Okay? So, this is now a JavaScript. Now,
we are coding JavaScript now.
So
So this So JavaScript Okay, JavaScript
now change of tune. JavaScript now
constant.
Index file.
So this index file is a huge JSON
object.
Okay.
Now
You see there are 665
lines.
Too big. You know, we are doing
prototype so let's reduce this just to a
to a few.
Uh
Cut it. Yeah. So let's just reduce this
file
to a thousand lines to to 100 lines so
we can, you know, prototype the search
engine fast.
Okay, so index file
So constant index file.
Uh God, this is Okay, so we are starting
to code JavaScript. This is going to
take an hour.
So what is the basic thing you need to
do? Okay, so let me comment. Let me
write, you know, what What is What are
the steps? What's the things you need to
do? So you need to, first of all
you need to have a user interface.
You know, you need to in HTML page you
have to, you know, create the input text
box.
Then load the JavaScript file.
Then
um
Then I think my wife is back. Then um
Yeah.
Yeah, you need to create it. So let's do
that, okay? So let's just let's do that.
Let's go back to talk show. Let's create
a search box here, okay? And here is a
JavaScript file. Make it load, you know,
uh script tag loaded.
And uh
before we do anything, you need a search
box.
Okay, so actually let's
put the search box at the beginning of
today's talk show for now, okay? Just
for So, here. So, here we need a search
box. So, what does search box need?
So, you need a input text
box.
Okay, that's all you need. So, how do
you do that? Okay, you how do you you
you go to um
you go to my Xadi HTML JavaScript
tutorial DOM scripting tutorial.
DOM scripting tutorial, then you go to
text area.
Not text area, text field. Okay, so
that's how you do
the user interface. How do you create a
For example, I can
test something, you know, you type
something.
You create a
text box, then the JavaScript will pick
it up and print it out here. So, that's
how you do it. So, let's copy the code.
Copy.
Uh okay, so let's paste it here. So, I'm
going to explain, okay? So,
So, this is what you need for the text
box, okay?
Input text, okay? So, let's input text
that
name.
Let's this So, this is search, okay?
Uh search.
And uh
search text text size max length, we
don't care.
Name will be
value will be empty. Name will be
search.
Okay, search string.
Okay, so showing browser.
You see, we got the search box.
And now
Now we need to copy this JavaScript.
Delete it.
We open our JavaScript.
Then
paste it here.
Uh and remove this block.
So, here's our JavaScript code. Uh let
me show you, okay?
JSON EL we don't need. Um
Yeah, so here is the search box.
Then
here's a result box. We don't need a
result box.
Uh we do, because once the JavaScript
got the result, it needs to insert
somewhere. So, it needs to insert here.
Okay, then you load the JavaScript. Now,
in the JavaScript
in the JavaScript, first of all, you
grab the input text. Okay, the element.
Then you
grab the element for the show box, for
the show box.
That's the element where you going to
insert the result.
Then you have a function, you define a
function update the error function.
Oh god, this is going to get complex. Um
Showbox text content in equals to input
text.value, okay?
Then then that then get the event
listener add a event listener to the
input text
element. So, whenever the input element
is changed,
it will call the F update function.
Okay?
So, that's our JavaScript and we can
save it.
And we can show the HTML page in
browser. Now, magnify.
Now, test. You see it works. You see,
whatever you typed, it got inserted
there, okay? That's the structure. We
got the structure down.
Now,
now we need to implement the search,
okay?
So, so we have this JSON file here.
There's lots of entries and too many,
okay? Let's just say 50 of them.
Let's just say 40 of them.
Let's truncate.
Uh yeah, yeah, even 40 is too many. So,
let's just say 10 20, okay?
Uh wait, wait.
Uh let's copy the whole thing
to the top, okay? Move them to the top.
Here.
So, we just have
It's It's It's a lot. Oh god.
Okay, let's just say 15 of them, okay?
So, the that's the index
file. That's a object.
Object. The keys are the title. The
values are the file path, okay?
Then
So,
what we need to write the update
function. So, when update is called
So, here is what we need to write, okay?
Let's make a copy.
So, when update is called
when update function is called
you need to search all the strings in
the object in the hash table
for the title.
And if it's found
I'm getting tired, you know? Let's do
this quickly. I'm going to finish, you
know
So, when when you So, when when the
search function is called, you need to
go through each and every of these
this uh key, the title text.
Search search for it for the string. If
it's found
you display, you know, suppose you found
several of them. Then you display
then you display the result.
You know, you convert the result into
HTML inner text and you inject inject it
into this result element, okay? That's
what we're going to do. So,
So, let's let's uh start to document.
F update
search through
Okay, so if uh they search through index
file
key
and return
a result.
Yeah.
So, we need to write another function.
Um we need to write another function.
arrow function, okay?
Uh yeah.
So, this function will be
called filter results, okay?
Yeah.
It It's just say search, okay?
So,
Let's say filter, okay? F filter, okay?
So, F filter will take a object
and uh a key.
We will take object and
a key is a string.
Return a new object
where
the
the key where the key is
found, okay?
Re- return a new object
whose elements
are the
elements where the key is found,
something like that, okay? That's uh
first draft documentation. We're going
to improve the writing later, okay? Doc-
documentation is important.
So
so this filter will take an object
and a key and search through the all the
keys in the object and return a new
object.
Okay. Uh got a lot to write. Um
So update with So okay, so
So are you guys still with me? Ching
ching, thank you.
Luis.
Oh, there's J- JSON pretty print. Thank
you, that's a good tip. That's good tip
so I can I use it later.
Okay, so uh it may be helpful. Yeah, so
so now JavaScript, so we
are writing
we are writing this function.
Uh did we just up something?
What? I did.
Uh
Yeah, okay. So so we are writing this
function, but this this we don't need,
okay? So delete that. Shrink so you can
see the whole.
Um
Now, let's
call command to prettify the code.
You know, I have I'm using such a
JavaScript mode. If you like my stuff,
you can buy it, okay? JavaScript such a
JavaScript mode is one of my Emacs
packages. So I have a feature that can
format the whole code. You know, F9
F Okay, so let's do it.
So, now it reformatted the code. Now,
it's look Now, it looks pretty. So, you
you see the keys and value key value key
value. That's a object.
Okay, so
um
Now, we are writing the filter function,
okay?
So, the filter function
Okay. So, you got an object. So, first
step is to go through every element in
an object, enumerate the object.
You know, and for each element, you want
to search the key, okay?
And if it's true, then um return. Okay,
so there are many many ways to do it.
Because um JavaScript, you know,
let's go to the JavaScript object.
So, uh so, you know, so right now I want
to look for
ways to enumerate objects properties.
Okay? Now, if I have a search engine, I
can just type it property list
properties, you know?
But now, I don't That's why we are
writing a search engine.
But now, we don't have, then I I have to
know
there is it is properties,
then access property, list properties,
okay? All these are ways to
list all the key value pairs.
Once you have a list of them, then you
can go through.
You can enumerate them.
So,
and uh JavaScript is a bit complex
because you have the enumerable or not
issue. You have the symbol key issue,
and you have also string key issue, and
you have the also inheritance issue.
Because you don't want to go to the
parent objects keys.
Uh
So, there are many ways to do it. So,
one way is to actually
turn this object into a map object.
Now, a map object in JavaScript is
the actual hash
hash table. The proper hash table data
structure.
That's called map object in JavaScript,
okay?
Uh you know, I can show you, for
example, JavaScript tutorial. Um
JavaScript tutorial, then you go down,
you have arrays, you have constructors,
class, you have iterable. Then you have
uh miscellaneous, then you have map
basics.
So, map
So, map object is the
is a data structure, building data
structure in JavaScript, that is
basically your hash table. That's the
real hash table, key-value pairs,
which
the generic JavaScript object is not.
So, one way to do what we want is to
convert the
convert the object into the actual
map object, then it's much easier to
work with.
Uh because
because the map object is uh iterable,
then you can use the four of loop to go
through it. It's gets very complex. I
don't know what you I don't know if you
guys know what I'm talking about.
Uh what?
Yeah.
So, anyway, so
let's not let's not get too fancy, okay?
Let's just do the, you know,
How do we How do we want to do this?
Okay, so anyway, let's go to properties.
I have to think.
So, let's go to list properties, okay?
So, we we have a object. We have a
normal object. We want to go through all
the keys, okay?
And uh there's then there's also
efficiency concerns because this object
is going to eventually have 10,000
entries, more than 10,000 entries.
And uh
you know, so you you don't want to do
too much conversions. You want to use
the most efficient way.
Uh actually, I'm getting tired.
For constant key in object.
Yeah, you know,
I can you know, I can give you a tip
right away because if you use for in
loop, that's no good in JavaScript.
Because when you use for in loop, that
will also include keys of the parent
object and the parent of that parent
object. You know, you you uh So,
yeah, so JavaScript is a bit um
complex, you know, for example, I can
you know, for in loop.
Uh here's a for in loop and uh you
should you know, tip, do not use for in
loop. In fact, you can like
ban it. It actually is good to ban it
for good for good because it will
it will go through parent objects.
Uh
uh so so what you
Okay, so what uh
So, we uh so we
Uh too much talking, so let's get back
to the code, okay? So,
yeah, let let's try to have this have
some tangible form of today's result,
you know? Okay, so let's just code
quickly. So, object keys, okay? So, we
going to wait, what we going to use?
Include symbol? No. Include string? Yes.
Uh enumerable only? Yes. Okay, so we
want
We want to go through the hash table. Uh
we basically we want to search Yeah, go
through the hot hash table.
Um
reflect on keys. Enumerable only? No.
Okay. Uh
Get own property names.
No, we we we want enumerable only.
We want enumerable only.
And also we actually we got a JSON. Now,
is JSON directly also a object? Uh I
don't know.
I mean, the question is, you know, we
got a JSON thing here. I think it's
already a object. But I mean, that you
have to be careful. You have to because
there are
minor details. So, JavaScript reference
um JSON, okay?
You know, JSON is not exactly It's
different from object. I mean, they are
not exactly the same, you know? There's
a little syntactical There it is.
JavaScript syntax versus JSON syntax.
JSON syntax is a more strict than
JavaScript syntax. For example,
uh you need the quotes, okay? And single
single quote doesn't work.
Okay? And undefined it doesn't work,
okay? So, but basically if you have a
JSON it's already a object.
Okay, now once you have a object, you
So, let's see what object entries return
an array of key value pairs.
I am I am going in circles. I'm just
like um
That means I'm tired.
Okay, let's try object arrays. Okay,
let's just uh try to get something to to
show, okay? So, object entries
uh
So, object entries returns a
basically convert the object into array.
Returns array of key value pairs. Okay.
Uh of
that are object string properties and uh
own property and are enumerable. That's
right. That's what we want. So,
object entries
um
Right, so you get array.
Okay, so
then
then you want to go through that array.
So, array you can use for of loop, okay?
Array is a iterable, okay?
So, for each key uh
uh so, actually
for each element in array, so let's look
at for of loop, okay? List properties
and uh
for in loop
uh and the four of loop, okay?
So, four of loop, a variable, you can go
through it, and you can also, yeah, so,
this is a form.
No, so,
Okay, let's do it just the simple way,
okay? It's that way.
For
For pair in key value pair, okay? For a
pair in key value pair.
So, for each pair in key value pair, and
you want to do search.
Something like
if search found,
add it into result array, okay? So,
got
result pairs array, okay? So, right now
it's empty.
Okay, so,
now,
um,
so, now let's search, okay? So, for let
key pair equal equals to, so, this,
uh, I can actually
Okay, key and value pair, so, now we
need to do search. Now,
JavaScript, JavaScript in depth,
reference string,
uh, you need to have, you need to use
string methods to search.
Uh, array, set, date, where is it?
Boolean, string, so, there is string.
Then, you want to search string.
JavaScript is a very lousy language, I
can tell you, okay? So, here is search
um
There, it's easier to read. Um
Then, you So, search string. search
returns the index of the first char of
matched string. If no match, returns
negative one, okay?
Now, um
Now, KK is a string. Now, search.
Okay?
Uh and the regular expression or string.
So,
the
So, the search string is whatever user
typed. So, where do we get the users?
Oh, yeah, the the the filter. Okay, so,
this is the key, X key.
Yeah, so, that So, we search for
So, we search for that key.
Now, if
Now, we need a if statement, okay?
If
this search
is
greater than one
greater than zero
returns the index of first char of
matched string.
Greater than or equals to zero.
Okay? That means it's found.
So, search
if it's found
then
then push to array. So, then
then you need to push your element to
array, okay? So,
so, result pairs array push
um
what you want to push to? You want to
push um
the value.
The
file path.
Okay, value is a file path. So, let's
prettify the code.
Let's hope I'm Okay, prettify the code.
Good.
Um
so,
yeah.
Okay?
So,
so, this filter it seems to be
uh
to be working. I mean, it seems to
be it.
Let's go over.
Okay, so, then after you are done, you
need to return it, remember? So,
you need to return
prettify the code, okay? Return result
pairs array array. So,
um
yeah, so, if if it if it's found, you
search for it, then you um
My wife is back, so, I need I need to
go.
Maybe we could reformat the hash file
like title title URL.
And then iterate through the array. Why?
Well, I anyway, we are getting on to it.
We are working I mean, this is uh
this is working. Hello. Oh, Matthew,
thank you. Spin to win. Fantastic. We
are almost done, maybe 20 more minutes.
Anyway, so this filter function seems to
work, okay?
I mean, seem that that seems to be the
right code. So, let's double-check. You
know, I my coding style is usually one
shot. I don't try any error. Usually, I
know exactly what it is. I code it one
time.
Then it should work. So, let's
double-check. So, this
F filter function takes two arguments.
We define it as a arrow function. It
takes two arguments, a object, a
JavaScript object, generic data object,
and a key. The key is a string.
And what it does is that uh
you know, it will search for all the
keys, the enumerable keys in the object.
If there's a match,
you know, basically return only the
elements in the object that
the key that contains the search string.
Uh okay? So, and it will return the
return
uh thing is a array of pairs. It's not a
object. Returns a array. So, returns a
new array.
Uh
and each element
is
key and the value of the object
where
where the
key
contains X key, the search string, okay?
Okay, that's the documentation for F
filter. So,
so then we go through it. We go through
the
And that's
So, we go through the
We don't need these anymore.
You see
like we talked before in JavaScript, the
semantic unit
there is no
syntactical correspondence between the
semantic unit and syntactical unit.
Because for example, right now I want to
delete this part. I cannot just press a
key. So, I have to actually
go here, that remove that and put it
here.
Okay, so anyway, so
so that seems to be it, okay?
I hope, you know. So, let's move on to
the next one. So, the update
the update function will
call the filter function. Okay, so
So, what does the update function do?
Let's write a documentation.
Calls
and uh
take its result
then insert the result into the show
box. Okay, where is our show box?
There. Show box is a element.
Uh let me show you where.
Show box is a is a um
You see, show is here, this element.
HTML element.
So
So, F update filter takes its result
then insert the result
as inner
inner HTML
into the show box
element, okay?
So,
that's right. So, we going to call
f filter
and uh
the
f filter takes two arguments, remember?
So, the one one of them is the object,
which is the uh index file. And the
second argument is the the word user
typed. So, how do you get the word the
user typed?
Well, it's the
it's the input text.value, okay? So,
input text.value,
okay?
So, here so,
x result, okay? So, constant
x result equals to that, okay? So,
that's a result, and now let's just
let's let's do this so quickly. We going
to just insert this
into the
into the show box, okay?
So, yeah, so,
you know, let's forget about security
and anything else. You know, normally we
need to encode it. Just make sure it you
know, encode it to the proper HTML
syntax and so on.
Uh but now we just directly insert the
result of the filter into the show box
element, which should be here, okay?
Please let it work, okay?
Save it, okay? It's already saved. Now,
prettify the code. Okay, now let's go
back to the talk show page. Now,
close that. So, you are looking at the
talk show page. Now, the
the result result should be injected
here. Okay?
Refresh the page. Now,
now we need to find the search word that
that is in our um
you know, let's say
Stevie, okay? Stevie egg. Okay, that's
one of the title of my page. Okay? So,
let's search for
Oh, I need I need I also need a submit.
Oh, wait. A- As soon as you type, you
will show result. Let's see.
S
T No.
Something is wrong. Okay? Now, time to
debug.
Uh
Con- uh control shift I.
Let's get the JavaScript console.
Let's
JavaScript console.
Uncaught reference error. Result array
result pairs array is not defined. Okay,
simple.
Result
pairs array is not defined. Why is that?
Reference error result pairs array is
not defined in line 41. What?
Oh, yeah. You Oh, yeah. You returned it
outside of it.
Is that right?
What?
Oh, yeah. Oh, oh, oh.
We renamed. Remember, we added a X in
front. So, there. Okay?
Now,
refresh.
Now, let's type. There it is. There is a
result. Fantastic. Did you guys see it?
s t e v There it is.
You know, that's the file path. So,
that's a result.
Now, let's
close this file, so we start afresh.
Fantastic. Now, now close this file.
Show this
Wait.
Oh, so many results. Now, you see, when
you when the search box is empty,
that means the search search string
exists in every every result. So, that's
why you got the whole thing. Now, now
let's type, okay?
s t e
There it is. s t e, you know, then
narrows down, okay? Let's Let's Let's
find something else. Let's see what else
articles.
Okay, BB code, okay? Here, you see BB
code. Let's type that.
B
B There it is. So, essentially, we have
completed you know, the draft prototype
version of a search engine. Search
engine for my website. So, now, you
know, I'm going to work offline for 2
hours or so.
You know, so that I can you know, I'm
going to have a
a search box for all my e max list and e
max tutorial. So, you don't have to know
where things are. You can search like e
max a brief. How do you you know, e max
a brief is one of the most best feature
of e max. But, where is it? Like, is it
in e max tutorial, you know, so many
there's a there's like 800 pages. You
don't know where to find it. So, So can
just There's a search box on every, you
know, corner of the page. You just type
agree, then it shows you where they are,
you know, for Emacs this
and also for my JavaScript tutorial.
Uh what?
Uh
You know, and for my
for my JavaScript tutorial, you can you
know
So I'm going to
have that uh search box. So we completed
a prototype and it took only 2 hours.
Good enough.
Thank you, guys.
Uh thank you, guys. Yeah, that's it.
Yeah, we have a prototype. You know, we
can Yeah, so the it you know, it works.
It works. That's
That's the Unix philosophy. It works.
That's it.
Okay, but we need to refine. There's a
lot to do, you know, you you I need to
refine it. You know, for for example
For For example, the case
letter case sensitivity. For example,
one of the case is Stevie Egg, you know.
You know, like if you type S capital S T
E, you'll find it. But if you use lower
case,
it does not find it. So you need to
change the case, you know. Then also
what happens if user types two words,
you know.
You need to find both of the words in
the title. There's a lot. You know, also
the our result right now
does not show Let's Let's see. Let's
find something else. Yeah, BB code. BB
code, okay. BB code. So
the result should be linked, you know,
not not that we cannot click click. So
actually we need to
Yeah, we need to
There's more code, you know. Um we need
to turn that into a link so people can
click it. Uh I can I can open the file,
okay? So,
you see, it should open this file. You
know, I I wrote a BB code package long
ago.
It should open that file. So, we need to
change the result into a link, and we
also need to format it, you know, not
just one blob of text, you know, you
should like like a table or, you know,
with lines in between, you know.
Um,
uh, so, a lot to do, you know, it's
going to uh, for real, it's going to be
3 more hours. So, but anyway, so,
uh, that's it for today. We showed the
basically how to write a
um, search engine, uh, at, you know, a
very basic elementary search engine.
Uh, and also, we need to right now, so
far, we only search the title, which is
which is already very good, you know,
especially for, uh, programming language
reference website, for JavaScript or
Emacs Lisp. You know, a search box for
title does a lot already. So, but
usually you also want to search
other headings, you know, you know,
regular expression syntax, regular
expression flags, you need to search
so, um,
and you, you know, for other pages, you
also need to search the content, for
example, for essays,
uh, political essays or whatever, you
know, long you know, for example, I'm
talking about
programming culture,
because people remember you say
something, they need to find it, you
know, where that page is.
So, there's a lot to do, but
we did the basics, okay? That's it for
today. Thank you guys for watching.
If you like my stuff, you know, buy my
JavaScript tutorial. That's my That's
the tutorial I'm most proud of, and I
would say it's the best one
the world's top three in English
language, okay?
Uh my JavaScript tutorial, JavaScript in
depth.
And uh also my Emacs tutorial is pretty
good.
Uh because there are not many Emacs
tutorials out there. So, you know,
so if you like my stuff, you know, you
can
you can easily find where to pay me,
where to buy my stuff, you know, I it's
all on my website. Just, you know, check
out my website.
Thank you, guys.
Bye. Finally, we did the search engine.
Bye.