hello good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of Santa show so today
we are going to do wolfam language
coding a very interesting problem okay
uh the wufam language live coding and
I'm going to code a problem where okay
so you read a text file
or files in a directory and you want to
tally word count you want to get a word
frequency list first you know such as
what which word are used the most
frequently you know in English
so you can look up Wikipedia you know
the most frequently used word I you me
how are you where you know things like
that so you want to you know get all
files and entirely count the word
frequency that's one problem the second
problem is that you want to find the
most frequently used in order uh the
most frequently used word pairs like a
phrase a phrase of two words or three
words so for example uh you are that's
probably one of the top frequently used
where are you know that's another
example there are there is what for uh
you know for example when you use your
phone
to uh chat you know phone will usually
make such suggestions so that's the you
know you want to tidy the frequency of
the diagram words okay
so that's the second problem
now that so that's one problem okay the
other problem we we I'm going to do it
uh together today is that you want to
count the letter frequency you know
which letter I must use a frequent
frequently let's see let me let me show
you okay uh shorthand system
okay for example you are looking at my
keyboard I mean this this is a keyboard
layout this is quality you know q w e r
t y you know so the red circle the the
bigger the circle the more frequent uh
that letter appears so for example you
have different
um keyboard layout so you can see in
this world I like uh you know most
frequently used letters uh you know home
row so the problem is to go through a
directory of files entirely you know and
to see which letter are most frequently
used you know get all of them
and percentage you know so
so that is the two problems and also
then after that then you want to do
bigrams okay so let me show you an
example of diagrams uh so you have
little layout a little frequency
so I'm going to do this in Wolfram
language today then perhaps tomorrow you
know the in my next few videos I'm going
to do it in JavaScript in Python in
Golan uh let me show you okay so
actually so you know since I'm doing
video it's better to just
show and tell you know since I'm doing
it so uh some programming language
tutorials I'm going to do it in Wolfram
language today next
week or a few days I'm gonna to do it do
the same problem in emac this in
JavaScript in Powershell in Golan in
Python okay can you can you see that in
Python in Gola and Powershell uh
you know so you know and let's compare
which programming language is the
fastest which programming language is
the shortest source code
you know I already know the answer
that's a wolfam language because it's
you know because I you know all these
functions we need today is building
okay hello Reaper hello immortality hey
immortality are you the triangle guy
server okay so we so let's do it okay
okay so that is the background that
that's what we are going to do I hope 30
minutes 40 minutes okay so I need to
keep my time so okay and and let me show
you again let me talk about the keyboard
so this the keyboard you see I'm using
this is a fantastic one of the best
ergonomic keyboard I recommend is cheap
too 100 150 I recommend it very much so
you go buy it they send me a sample so
and I really love it so okay so I have
like lots of tutorials on my website
about this keyboard okay and uh so you
go check it out and
you know I recommend it uh and you know
next week also I I I'm going to do a
review of this keyboard by itself okay
so this is the expose night okay
uh so okay now buffam language okay now
if you don't know okay so let's go to
structure let's start to do stuff okay
on the pink window is uh over my emacs
commands Okay and uh let's uh so let me
show you wolfam language so if you don't
know you know I did you know 20 or 30
over language tutorials in the past if
you don't know go
I'm gonna I'm not going to repeat the
basic stuff like where do where do you
download uh you know where do you
download how you know when you we you
know I'm not going to repeat them so if
you don't know just search for Sardi
wufam language then you'll find My wufam
Language tutorial and several my you
know those best of my videos I collect
them here so you can start to watch them
hear that one which I've done a few
weeks ago
and several others so watch those okay
if you are new to wufam language so
today yeah so
okay so so that is the background so
let's copy and let's show today's talk
show page and make a record of what we
talked about so uh here's a showing
browser so you can see Xbox Knight
keyboard okay fantastic uh Wolfram
Language tutorial tutorial so you can
people can go to it and here is a
description of the problem we're going
to do
um do one file first then we're gonna do
all files in your directory
okay so the next question let me talk
about why do I need to do it so
uh so the reason I need to do
letter frequency count is because uh let
me show is because you know I have this
project of ergonomic keyboard layout
yeah I mean ergonomic keyboard layout
like letter letter layout so in this
project you know how do I get you know
how do I know that e occurs the most
frequent how do I know the size of the
circles because you need a statistical
data so these are already compiled but
it's incomplete so I need to do a lot
more and for example you also need to do
this for different languages for French
uh French German you know different
languages or Russian you know in the
case of Russian you have Russian
you know you have Russian language
um
uh layout you know you have French
and you have Russian you know you can
see so you need to do this for every
language in tally so this so so I need
the statistics right now I just have
like very simple English so that's why
you need to know the letter frequency
okay and why do I need why do I why do
you need to know the letter Bagram
frequency because
means two letters together you need to
know which two letters happens the most
why do you need to know know that
because when you study the layout
efficiency you know you want to find the
best layout the diagram is significant
uh criteria you know it's a significant
um
thing to consider when you are designing
the best letter layout so for example
where is
um I have talked about that somewhere
here okay
the most efficient layout let's see yeah
there it is so you can see here is a
pre-computed two letter sequence by Gram
count this is from Google actually you
know which is great you know they they
they they they base their copas you know
the source from
10 million uh books you know books but
the the the input source is significant
you know because you don't want when you
want when when you design a data layout
you don't want to paste them on some
academic textbook or formal writing
because when you say when you type you
know to your mom hi Mom what are you
doing today or to your friends you know
you don't type those jargons chemistry
physics academic you know style of
writing form formal formality you know
you should so therefore it is important
when you do this kind of uh frequency
and you know statistics
in the in the in the case of Designing a
keyboard layout layout you want to
consider what type of the input okay for
example when you know today you have
lots of typing websites you know type
race you can compete with your friends
uh the inputs are typically the most
basic commonly used English letters but
if you so let's say you can type 80
words per minute but if you switch it to
a
for example a math textbook you're gonna
significantly significantly slow you
down because the input matters okay so
this is reason why I need to do you know
I'm you know once I have the statistics
I'm going to replace this uh static
image by a JavaScript generated so I can
you know so it allows you to type your
own input and get at least the frequency
of diagrams so that that is why I need
this project
so that is for the letter frequency okay
letter frequency then the other project
I need to do is to uh to get the word
frequency and background words
word phrases why do you need to do that
because I'm creating a shorthand system
for example these are abbreviations okay
you know tentatively named shorthand
okay so let me show you
so you you are looking at my emacs a
brief for example if I want to type the
word reference okay
I can just type r f r okay that becomes
reference so
if I want to type the word question it's
just Q it becomes question okay so this
is a brief system you know in emacs you
know I have like a thousands a thousand
of them
so in order to tally this
you need to know
you know in order to design this
shorthand system for typing not for you
know there are lots of shorthand systems
for writing for manuscripting
you know scripting style cursive style
of writing but this is a shorthand
system for typing so in order to design
this you need to choose you know what
letters to expand to what you need to
know the word frequency and also a
phrase frequency for example I can type
for example
online for example uh very common when
you want to say by the way by the way
okay press enter it becomes by the way
you just type BTW so that's a phrase
that saves you like 10 keystrokes okay
this is a great hand saver so I want to
of course you need time to learn so this
is the reason you need the word
frequency okay of course there are lots
of reasons in crypto graph you know
crypto analysis and so on
So eventually I'm going to write a
JavaScript
interactive JavaScript
page so you can you know paste or type
and you count your words and so on so
that is the reason okay
so now let's start coding movement
language or you know we already spent 10
minutes talking about it okay so
so again watch my old wolfam language
videos okay because I have the
beginnings uh beginner stuff okay so
let's speak in Wolf and language okay
questions comment posted okay
uh no I'm not trying to go with my
username I'm on Discord is CCP email
okay yeah okay I recognize
uh okay let's begin so wufan language
taddy so first of all so let's um uh
let's uh let's go to
okay first of all let's go to Alice in
Wonderland okay
so let's get Alice in Wonderland uh yeah
so vocabulary etymology literature
Classics uh it's for something fancy
okay Arabian Nights the story of the
king
copy it
okay language uh let's see
what
started
okay wait what what the what are those
you know I have sticky keys on so
Wolfram desktop started
is this show meta programming was
created like literally writing a novel
is this how meta programming is created
like literally writing a novel
uh what do you mean I'm not sure what do
you mean so starting with language okay
wolf and documentation that's not what
we need we need to uh wolfam language
okay so there it is now magnify so you
can see so let's put this here and let's
uh
input okay
X input
so here is gonna be a whole whole string
uh well there's a problem because
Okay so
let's the fisherman and the genie okay
let's just say that now is there a now
enter
okay
so we have our text input okay
now actually I know so we need to
first of all we need to count word okay
count Words okay
for each word how many times it appears
that's what we need to do and as it
turns out there's a building function
for it
fantastic saves your time that is the
nature that is the characteristics of
Wolfram language almost you know lots of
things
because otherwise you have to type you
know spend an hour just to call this let
me show you okay uh I don't know where
it is
so what you do is you just go to wufan
documentation search for Wolf and dark
okay wolfam language you know I've been
coding Wolfram language for
15 years mostly in the 1990s so they are
seven seven thousand building functions
everything is built in seven thousand of
it
so you click on uh streaming
manipulation then you click on working
with templates you click on text
manipulation and text analysis that's
right text analysis so over here is you
know the function we need is already
here
World count okay that that will uh total
number of words in a text okay
that's not what we want what we want is
what counts count of words or in grams
okay so that's a function that's
in what frequency okay there are several
okay so it's opioid then you have letter
counts then you have character counts
okay that's so that's all we you know
all the things we need is already
building okay so what count what
frequency letter counts uh character
counts let's see let's do the word first
World counts caves on the association
which means a dictionary or hash table
whose keys are the distinct words
identified in string and whose values
give the number of times those words
appear in string that's what we want
okay then you can also give a number
then that will give you n grams like two
letter two words three so three words
phrase fantastic that's that's fantastic
okay that's what we're gonna do
so World counts so easy so easy
wait counts okay so what counts uh yeah
and what is our variable X inputs okay
do it do it
loading from Wolfram research server oh
my God I don't like it that means it
connects to internet for some reason
this function is not
uh
in a kernel I don't I don't I haven't
spent time to look for y okay so there
it is so and uh and occurs 11 times V
occurs nine times that's just what
that's just this paragraph okay that's
just this
this Arabian Nights Arabian nights I
highly recommend it okay it's uh Arabian
90s uh this is Alan Alan Alan bought the
book fantastic okay you you go you can
buy this book or you could you can read
my annotated Arabian Nights the
fishermen and the genie fantastic
wonderful story
what one of my favorite top top five
favorite literature
okay and it's nothing it's nothing like
what Disney tells you Disney you know
Disney is not Disney's American nights
one thousand and one American nights
okay fish fisherman Genie
so that the World Cup that is just the
first paragraph So let's go back so we
already have the answer here
okay that that's the um
so what we gonna do now so we can start
to read the file
yeah that's what eventually I need to do
uh let me just show you some of the
Let's see we can start to read a file or
we can start to do the letter count
because eventually we need to read the
whole directory
um
and
and by the way the return value that
this return thing that that is a
dictionary or hash table in woven
language it's called Association so if
you don't know already
uh you know you can look into uh let's
close this uh what's this is close
um
pop this back
let's see yeah show show today's talk
show uh
you go to you know you go to My woofam
Language tutorial I have the complete
tutorial telling you what is Association
okay so Association this is here
map array delete element so those are
these position and
Loop function Advanced winds Association
there is a data structure data structure
so Association okay so in other
languages it's called hash table or
dictionary or map
uh okay so that's a that's what it
returns uh let's
okay there's a question about meta
programming so what is the question Jr
is this how meta programming was created
like
detroiting a novel
no I don't want you I don't know what
you mean I just wanted to know how or
what is the intuition to better
understanding meta programming okay uh
meta programming meta programming basic
basically you program your program in
some sense okay uh let's not talk about
that you know we can talk about the next
oh Jesus
a spam
uh we gotta deal with Spam add moderator
hide user put uh
God
okay that's so what we're gonna do next
essentially that's already the answer
what we're gonna do next is uh we want
to okay let's let me just go through
then okay that's word count let's know
what's the other what frequency gives
the frequency of word in text okay let's
try that
gives the frequency of words in text
okay so
in this case you
have to give a word and basically it
divides by the total
that's not very
that's not what we want we already have
the frequency list basically the word
frequency just gives you a percentage
out of the total you can compute it
yourself okay
so that's not what we want
so let's look at letter counts okay
letter counts gives an association a
hash table whose keys are the distinct
letters right and whose values gives the
number of times those letters appear
that's what we want let's do it
okay
uh
so
data account okay
Burnette
okay there it is now let's do bigrams
okay so uh consecutive two letters let's
see the little frequency okay
there it is so fantastic simple so
simple
so essentially we already solve the
problem now let's do a diagram for words
okay
so let's do background for words and
let's see what we get oh my God loading
from Wolf and research
I don't understand why is this function
um
not part of the kernel
okay later count uh wait what
oh it's still
computing
ah I don't like this it's actually it's
you know talking to the internet and do
the Computing but anyway here's the
result okay
so this result is not is
not ideal because you see it includes
the comma
oh wait it doesn't actually include the
comma but the reason it's all one is
because
our input text is too short
so you you don't get things like it is
what is where is you are things like
that you don't get it because you're you
know our input is only one paragraph
yeah here so okay
so essentially we already
have what we want let's see what we're
gonna do
oh there's a question do you prefer
Wolfram over python of course by a
magnitude you know if you haven't seen
my talk show watch uh by a magnitude by
uh watch this video on my website
saudi.info okay
xrd.info home page
then this video
February 6th
you know you jump to 18 minutes you'll
see my
kind of uh give you I give you a
characteristics of different languages
Java closure JavaScript this and Wolfram
language rule Farm language is a
magnitude
uh better than them okay
as far as in terms of
ease of use in terms of you know superb
documentation ease of use and you know
understand the fastest way to do biom
magnitude uh then all of them
each line of wolf and language equals to
10 to 10 000 lines of other languages
including Haskell or lisp
the reason is because you know we are
not even counting
mathematical functions because you can
do integrals solve differential
equations and so on if you count those
then one line of movement language is
ten thousand lines of of all the others
JavaScript go and Java but if you do not
count those if you count things like you
know just simple functions like this one
you know
how many lines does it take to do a word
count well in Python in most other
languages you do a hash table then you
tidy you know like 10 lines
five lines so you know
Okay so
so what we're gonna do next
um let's see
now nltk now I'm not sure you know and
we'll find language language includes
lots of AI stuff like uh
you know what Wolfram Stefan Wolfram
would say is um it has basically all the
algorithms in computer science all the
Practical algorithms you need building
for example you um
stream levithian this you know for
example word counts letter counts you
know that's you need algorithm inside a
building
uh again 7 000 building functions out of
the box you do not need to load the
library like in in Python when you want
a regular expression you need to load a
regular expression Library same thing
with Golan if you want to Traverse
directory you need to load a you know
system OS Library you know that
in Wolfram language is you know you just
call the function right away you don't
need to load Library okay
so what we're gonna do next
um
I'm thinking maybe that's it for today
let's keep this short
um
okay let's see let's see
you know actually what I need to do is
actually I need to Traverse the
directory but
um
okay let's let's try to do that okay so
first of all let me let me let me let me
do um
okay now let's let me do this in the
ufam language mod okay
let me show you what that is so I can so
I have written example language mod in
images that allows you to uh code Wu
from language in iMac Beast so you can
see the uh
you know the web page you just search
for it you'll find it it's on GitHub
okay and there's a video so it's on
GitHub you you know you just go to
download so it allows you to code wufam
language in emacs because that way it's
much faster
okay and uh and uh
yeah and you can download wufan language
there okay
okay so um
so let's start to code that okay so
Wolfram so World count
so completion uh counts okay so impress
so X input equals to
so we want to
do something okay so what counts X input
so for example I can evaluate that okay
so let's do the same thing let's copy
the source code
okay this time let's just copy the whole
thing okay
now open it okay and remove all double
quote
wait do I have double quote there
because in order Okay no Okay copy it
close it
put the whole thing here okay so here is
a giant text input text okay
so now
now let's run this word count do it
there it is wait what okay so it's
repeating the output
so let's go down there it is okay so
here is the result word count
uh it's a long list
see
yeah so V you see V happens V happened
300 376 times and happened 319 times now
you have lots of words now it makes
sense
so these 200 uh that's a Unicode
something that yeah that's a Cody quote
I think
of happened 158 times okay so let's do
this again now let's
um
okay let's run it
uh okay so copy the text new buffer
paste it here now let's make them into
one
each line each word by a line itself so
I'm gonna do some emacs find and replace
okay now it's much easier to see
okay that's the word count okay so close
that don't save now we also need
um
letter counts okay now words counts now
let's do a word counts by Gram and let
her come
Okay so
there it is
okay so word count uh what kind of
diagram okay let's do a comeback diagram
and let's see what happens
you know it's great in when I'm using
Wolfram script it doesn't connect to
internet I don't think so that is great
so here is the result
now let's let's separate into the um
each line
fantastic
so you can see oh wait I don't want that
so I want
um
it's undo
so you want to replace
that
by
wait what do you want to replace you
want to replace
that
by
a new line okay do it
okay there it is so the phrase
what is this 200 character damn
okay that's not good let's uh
so of the happens 100 you know 33 times
2D happens 32 times the fisherman
happens 23 times fantastic
so that's spy gram okay so let's try
trigram what happens if you have a
trigram
I mean three word phrases let's run it
hello
I don't know who are you I don't
so here's a result and now we place
that by a new line replace all
okay so fishermen the fishermen
something
you know I think I think there's a flaw
in Wolfram language here this character
that's you know
it's incorrect
um you know I think it's wrongly read
the curly double quote here
so you can see there are many Unicode
characters
such as you know that
that
uh thing
by the way this is you know I have this
is my work I have annotated this
this work so you can hoover the mouse
and see what we thought means
and uh held you know so they're at
yeah so you can see there's a curly
quote there
uh might and Men that's a poem
you know so this story uh lovely story
okay the Arabian Nights the Fisher man
and the genie and then here comes a poem
oh toilet through the glooms of the
night in Peril and in pain
cytolin stint for Daily Bread comes not
by might and Men
seized thou not the Fisher seek afloat
upon the sea he spread while glimmer
stars of the night are set in Tangled
skin I love this I love it
so go read it okay search for Saudi
Arabian Nights you'll find it okay so
that's the word count that's a
three-letter words count
um you know this
so
so let's find out what exactly what
happened here why is it those where are
those um
funny characters let's see
so let's try to search this line if it
okay such i f r i t by the way if it
means Genie okay in Disney speak in
American speak that's Genie Everett
okay search again
search again search again if it
okay
uh well
let's try this one the if it okay search
the if rate
okay search search search search
okay I don't know which one is that it
happens a lot let's go to the bottom
okay
see something
you know we want to try to find out what
are these
you know what are these slash something
I think it's some problem with Wolfram
language
you know it interpreted the encoding
incorrectly I think
puso shell okay let's try to find whoso
Shell
also
shell
okay that's a single quote
single curly quote apparently
let's try to do it again yeah so who's
the shell who's a shell so single curly
quote becomes
slash two three zero let's let's see if
that's true okay so in emacs what you
can do is this is the power of E Max so
a new buffer
type a single quote magnify and the code
describe chart so it's going to tell you
that
the code point is 44
uh the code point is 44
yeah but that
but in Octo it's 54 in HEX decimal is 2C
that does not explain where it is 230
come from so I think what happens what
happened is that
the Wolfram language has encoding
incorrect I'm guessing
okay I think that's it for today so 40
yeah 40 minutes so
yeah so let's um
so we do we did World count now let's do
letter com okay let's just do little
count
do it run it
okay so letter count is pretty short
copy it new buffer paste it here
replace
comma by comma
new line
okay let's account fantastic that
account is easy okay but now let's see
letter count by five grams okay two
letter
two-letter consecutive letters okay
there it is copy new offer replace
Okay so
uh it's not sorted okay when you do
letter count it doesn't sort it
okay but we can sort it with emacs magic
or we can sort it with Wolfram
I'm not going to do it
um
okay so close uh don't save uh curse
don't save okay so that is the basically
the solution okay
so now pop this back
to a HTML page
showing browser
okay that is today's
um Talk show that's the input
and it's no good it's
um
because the input is so long it's better
if you read it from the text okay let's
do one more thing let's read it from a
file okay so let's get to the path of
the file here
okay that is the file
copy the file path back to emacs and uh
pop this wufam language out here is a
file path and let's remove the whole
text here
so we want to read this file so how do
you read go back to family Language
tutorial
then
here is a read file
read file okay so that's what you do
copy it
okay read and give a directory so the
directory file path is that
okay content Okay so
uh that's that will be just X input
comment that out
there it is now let's do this again
would come do it
uh okay so you need to put a semicolon
so it doesn't show the input do it again
there is a result okay so copy it new
buffer paste it
replace comma by comma
new line go to the top there it is
welcome
fantastic okay
now since we are reading the file and
the source of the file is a HTML file so
you start to get lots of these HTML
um
tax so now let's write another command
to replace those HTML tags so we're
gonna write we're gonna do find replace
any pattern like that we're gonna
replace delete them okay so let's do
find replace so how do you do find
replacing Wolfram language well there is
uh finding stream functions so you need
you go to stream
then you uh
insert into string delete substring
search test pattern matching and string
replace okay so that is what you want
string replace
yeah
so we're gonna
what we're gonna do is that
okay so replace so we're gonna
stream replace input so here is the
input first argument the second argument
is you want to
have a pattern so you know in here you
replace stock by cat but what we want to
do is a pattern here
so
um
so we want let's use a regular
expression
okay regular expression
that and
then here is anything not that okay one
or more okay and replace it by empty
string okay
and it returns a new screen so
so set it back to input okay now now
let's run this again
and put a semicolon here
now run it
now we we will not see those HTML markup
yeah indeed there it is
so new buffer paste it here replace
comma by new line replace or go to the
top there is fantastic that's fantastic
that's it for today that's it so now our
code is fantastic just very short delete
that cling up
put it back to HTML page
syntax color them showing browser
there it is our result this wolfam
language code okay that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
if you pay me okay donate me okay like
my stuff uh you know pay me
so you go to guitar talk show you uh you
know you go to my Saudi website you can
see at the bottom
patreon me Amazon gift card me
okay thank you guys for watching any
other questions
uh
sleeping
emacs uh
emacs
is a YouTube song
okay thank you guys
bye guys
okay so Nick so next coming weeks I'm
going to write the same thing exactly
like today but in
I'm gonna do in you know
in in JavaScript in emac beasts that
should be easy you make this in
JavaScript in Powershell in Golan in
Python
yeah that's that's the language I'm
gonna do exactly the same thing so then
another day we're gonna compare which
one is the fastest which one has the
shortest code
obviously Wolfram language you know it's
two lines done
by
shutting down shutting down in in a
minute okay
so I talked all the things I want to
talk about yeah so
yeah but we didn't do the directory but
that's you know that's easy you just
read the whole
bunch of files in your directory um
uh okay