test so it's like I'm live
so this is live streaming and I'm just
testing up testing it out and what I
want to do is actually actually I want
to stream my screen but it doesn't seems
to be well if somebody there so I want
to stream my screen because recently I
installed the OBS software obvious over
it that's great for streaming but but
you have to hook it hook it up to
YouTube and I've never done streaming
before and so I'm you know I'm
experimenting hey there
so are you here for Emacs are you
following me for Emacs so anyway so yeah
so I can see people talking but what I
want to do is to share my screen so I
can show Emacs stuff so I mean this is
just a test so so on YouTube you know
you have a youtube account you go to it
and you can just click and it will just
start streaming live but I don't see any
option to to make it so that you know
the screens shared
yeah thank you now I'm always happy to
hear that so I want to so on YouTube I
don't see any option to share my screen
however on the OBS software you know I
wish I can show you but you cannot see
it because well I can let's try this you
know just to show you something
interesting so here's my keyboard
he's my workstation my my power station
and it's on the corner of a room you
know my room is very messy it's one of
those where there's no pathway I mean if
you walk into my room you have to like
there's a path you know outside of that
it's all a beach you know I'm not
garbage you know because I keep things
clean but outside of it sawdust and you
know 10 years old males in boxes so so
anyway I want to stream so you cannot
see my screen so this is you know stupid
way to see my screen so this is my you
know Emacs stuff so anyway so I'm just
trying things out this is first you know
if you don't test it you never know so
you know this is just test I think I'm
gonna quit maybe yeah because there's
nothing to do here so anyway so there's
this OBS software you can get up OBS it
stands for open podcasting stream
something like that and you know I
started to use it yesterday and it's
fantastic you know you can go to youtube
and search for OBS tutorial and so it
seems to be a great software because
it's it's available for linux for mac
and windows and it's open source there
are several others you know people
suggest it to me but anyway this this is
this is one of the popular ones and
seems you know works well so yesterday i
recorded the video with OBS and it works
well except that i didn't my setting
output you know have a small screen so
you know so things are very fuzzy but
you know that's just a setting you know
i I tried it later and it works fine you
know he just increased the screen output
size
by the way so behind me that's my bed
you know I've been you know you know you
go to sleep you just you just sleep on
the floor I've been actually sleeping on
the floor for the past twenty years
[Music]
anyway so yeah OBS is great and so so
right now I'm just you know clicking the
YouTube button and do a stream but with
OBS I can you know it's it's easy you
know you can just sit upstream and you
can share your screen but you know again
I'm trying this for the first time so I
just have to start somewhere try
something so random I'm using YouTube
and it's not I cannot share my screen
and so I'm gonna I'm gonna quit and try
the you know OBS streaming from OBS hi
Zen Zen so you are from China are you
from China USA well if you are on
YouTube you know it's likely you are
from USA you know I have lots of Chinese
programmer friends Chinese programmer
friends they follow me for my eMac stuff
someone well I saw someone Angela do me
it was someone I knew a Jaguar why
someone Manuel yeah and south along so
your enjoyment also and yours also
cheats all night in Twitter and P anyway
European arbors don't she someone but
Ottomans so so so anyway so so with OBS
software it you you know you start the
software and you set up you know
streaming there's a performance
preference box and you set up you know
which server you wanted to send the data
to so there's option for YouTube and you
can do that
then it looks like another thing
critical to set up stream into YouTube
is that there's a key you know like a
secret key identification key so you
have you know YouTube will give you that
you just paste that to the OBS software
so you know so you need two things
you know the YouTube server which OBS
already knows YouTube also shows you a
URL and you need a key
so you put that in OBS software and you
can just click start streaming and that
should work so you know I'm going to try
that and you know there's other settings
so obvious is it is like a professional
dedicated software for streaming and
recording so it's much better than
QuickTime you know I was using QuickTime
on a Mac it's free and there's also a
QuickTime professional version but I
haven't used it but anyway so OBS is
looks like much better than QuickTime
because you can you can stream and
meanwhile I also recorded and you can
also have multiple video sources like
one from webcam and you can have even
two webcam and like two webcams or and
one from your screen and you can also
have multiple audio sources and it looks
like it's much easier to control I mean
you have many options whereas if you
just use QuickTime Player to record it's
you know it's just very simple you know
it just there's not much options no
streaming okay so with you know I want
to share the screen because if I have
the screen I can talk much more because
after I'm talking about Emacs in
programming rate related stuff and well
with video I there's no I can show you
my keyboard but email causes I say
remiss fella
you know there there are also people
using them you know I yeah I want to
show you those
you know I well I cannot show you the
website so but anyway there are also
people with using vim and who got severe
ISI and pen you know who is that it's a
famous programmer it's the guy who
started you know that programming
language is kind of gone out of fashion
almost TCL Tico TCL so his name is jeong
jeong host or something like anyway he's
the guy who started TCL he he well he
created invented he Jie and he he got
ice ice severely I mean I mean we're
talking about this period you know
people debilitating you know dis about
the soap so anyway so I'm going to start
let's try let me try just typing a
stress test dedicated to the test and
you see that
okay my stupid camera is keep showing my
bed
you know like ugly [ __ ] you know like I
show you my room okay so you can see how
messy it is it's you know that's a math
book that's set theory and stuff and and
that's junk in junk junk so anyway I'm
going to okay so somebody is saying
using control control square bracket
control left square bracket full escape
no that's the worst you know I'm telling
you because I'm an expert you know
that's what you never want to do that
okay so so if you are using yeah well
okay even both hands you don't you know
I don't need certain it's not a good
method first of all you know this a lot
to talk about key you know keyboarding
the method you know how you type in
stuff so I can go on and on but anyway
I'll give you a few points first of all
the reason for that is I mean first of
all depends on how much you type you
know by that I mean you have to measure
it like you use a keyboard key lock
software so you can know actually how
many keystroke you type a day so among
programmers or casual users and also
professional you know bloggers so typers
there's a huge difference on how much
you actually type so between you know
let's say if you type 50 words per hour
you know so there are people who typed
three hours a day like if you you know
you look at your key log you know it
tells you how many keystrokes so you
know some people are in this category
some people are in this category some
people are you know middle but they
differ a lot like you know over here
it's ten times
small typing than here and over here is
10 times more typing in here so most for
most programmers you actually don't type
that much you're on a low-end so you
know so you know from your experience
you don't see how those other people you
know you know they have to type 10 10
more times 10 times more than what you
do and one day you know possibly maybe
one day you working maybe your startup
or something there's you know some some
project you need to finish a new type
you know you work 50 hours 60 hours a
week then that's when you start to get
pen then you then all your devices you
think that's good but that's not gonna
be no good so okay first of all you need
to know you need to use a key logger to
have some idea you know just exactly how
much you type you know how you know at
what level you know stuff you are
actually typing then the problem with
okay so if you don't if you are an
average programmer you know control
square bracket that works okay you know
maybe work especially if you are younger
but if you are you know if you type much
more than that
you find problem you that may not work
for you okay that's the first thing you
know find out how much you type actually
the second thing is you know if you
really type a lot then control square
bracket is not really good because the
square bracket the left square bracket
key almost no more standard keyboard is
typed by a pinky and also it's like way
out Adam it kind of it's like way on the
top or on the right depending on what
layout you use so that you know you
don't want to do that especially if you
are using vim if you are using vim or
you know if you are using Microsoft like
he's switching mod is one of the most
used command like the most in the number
one basically almost the number one so
you press you have to switch mod every
like every minute so for such a command
you don't want you use pinky and also
the control key is hard to do okay the
other option you know using set caps
lock to us to escape that I think that's
that's reasonable really good okay so so
yeah so if you want to switch to
okay so you are using Evo mod or you
know VIN well all I want to you know
shout out for my for my marks off like
he's you know you can look it up so
these are model model key bunnies
you know you press a key to switch to
command command not so for those so you
need one key that does that and that key
must be the most the most easy to use so
I would suggest also also it depends on
what keyboard you use you know because
most people use a normal you know laptop
keyboard or normal PC keyboard okay so
for those you can put the caps lock to
do escape or you know a set cap swap
caps lock to some other key and that key
basically you want that the caps lock
key on the left pinky position to switch
to the command mod it's not necessarily
escape because any anyway so so yeah do
that you know that's a good option but
if you have other keyboard like you know
my Canisius keyboard or actually okay
let me show you then since I'm talking
so so like this is my Kinesis
so actually I'm using this is a capella
caps lock this is my left side this is
left in my left hand so this is a caps
lock let's see if I can so that's a so
this is a good option which actually I'm
using actually my right hand this key is
also my pinky this keys also switch to
command mode so I have two keys so
I have to because you that's the command
you use you know every minute you know
the most-used command I can show you my
screen now because otherwise I'll do and
I show you my key lock and the key lock
shows the key lock will tell you you
know how many which command you used how
many times it records all your command
so if you want to I would recommend
using that so you just search for Keefe
freak key frequency I mean that the mod
is called key frequency but it's
abbreviated so it's key - f req Daria so
install that and you're allowed your mod
its do that so I'm saying you know if so
if II if you are using a Canisius
keyboard like like mine so the the the
the caps lock over here or over here is
good but also the thumb keys is also
good for switching to command mod you
know there are many choices you know the
depends on thank you I'm always happy to
hear good things yeah so mechanical
keyboard is great MacBook keyboard
MacBook Pro keyboard I'm not sure about
that so anyway so let me so my bed is a
mess I don't want to show that so
actually I should maybe I can show you
some keyboard since a few people are
here let's see how many four people well
four is a crowd so let's see yeah well
why not I'll show you some of my stuff
in
so I got several fancy keyboards here
they are great keyboards they are great
ergonomic keyboards so I can show you
okay so so okay so this here are three
greatest keyboard I recommend anyone of
them
so this Kinesis advantage too and here
you have is see if I move the other way
so this one is Expo keyboard it's also a
great compact keyboard let's see here it
shows so you can see expose keyboard and
and this one is also this is one of the
most wonderful this is this is called
uhk ultimate hacking keyboard it can be
taken apart like that let me show you
see so you can you know put legs up so
it's you know so you can type it anyway
so I you know Mike my camera is pretty
lousy because I haven't done the review
on these because the camera cannot focus
well for example you see it doesn't
focus you know sometimes it right now
it's fuzzy it's you know so it's it's
very frustrating you know I so I cannot
too much keyboard reviews with with that
anyway so so these feet keyboards you
know this one is like $320 or $350
something like that this one is much
cheaper I forgot how much but it's 150 I
think under under 200 okay so this is
cheaper they are all mechanical keys and
this one this is more expensive this is
like 250 something like that okay I
don't you know don't quote me on a price
because it's bad to say how much thing
cost on the video because people say if
you say $200 and people oh you know they
go to the website and that they found
out it's you know 100 or 250 you know
they freak out and also the company is
not going to link to your video because
you know you got the price you know you
got it wrong you know price so anyway so
you'll notice if you actually do video
reviews you know a lot of people online
to video reviews of products they almost
never mention price I mean that's one
thing you learn you know you know you
because price you know how much your
thing cost is like it's fluctuates you
know it's actually you know it depends
on you know market you know they say you
know the supply and demand so it changes
all the time
okay so that I think that's it so how
many people five people well I want to
I'm so I'm going to try to set up the
OBS software so I can you know do stream
with my screen so on the corner you are
see me and I can show you a screen
that's you know I can show programming
that would be much more interesting so
anyway any questions you know since we
are here any questions we can this is
great actually you know I got five
people people it's hard people okay with
you know you know
so I've been observing society well I
because I'm kind of I'm the observer
kind of guy you know I don't want the
camera to show my [ __ ] stupid you
know bad behind it okay
high high up you can just see my face
then so for people so so yeah I was so
yeah I was looking at you know YouTube
you know there are so many people now
making youtube videos you know the web
you know the web started you know in
1990s 1995 and you know beginning around
2000 you know we started to have videos
and YouTube started sometimes around
2000 something early 2000 and you know
through our 2000 you know you know it's
starting from very few videos you know
to today's everyone is making a video
because of the phone in so that so
anyway so you observe the you know
videos phenomenon you know in the
beginning let's say 2005 you know every
time a programmer you know doing a talk
about some programming topics it gets
popular you know several thousand views
or more 10,000 views because at that
time because there's not much videos you
know so the sense is that oh you know
some well-known programmer is doing a
talk about some topic and all the people
start to watch it but over time like
today if you are a famous program well
you know let's say a well-known
programmer that's you know maybe a
professor you know something you do a
video talking about programming nobody
nobody watches you know twenty thousand
that's the most you get you know so
because there's so many so much
information and and so everywhere
my first programming language well that
depends on what you mean by language
wealth so my first one is HP 28s
calculator that's a HP calculator
actually I wrote a blog about it if you
just search my name
sorry HP 28s euro USD my blog so that
was in 1992 and I I didn't learn any
programming until 1999 so I didn't know
what come any I didn't I have no idea of
computer science about anything so but
back then night in early 1990s I'm a
math I'm a very serious math fanatic you
know I like I you know I live in math so
anyway so HP 28s you know that's say
that's one of the that's I think it's
one with the first I don't think it's
the first maybe it's a second it's the
first calculator to let you do prodding
you know graphing calculator also it's a
first calculator that contains symbolic
programming so you can actually solve
you know quadratic equations with it so
I use it my first program is to solve
the 8 Queens problem have you have you
guys heard of the 8 Queens problem so 8
Queens problem is like on a chess board
a you know you want to place 8 Queens on
the chess board so that you want to
position position them so that no green
checks another cream so my so my first
programming is solving that something
that using the HP 28s calculator so
that's my first you know if you can't
add as a language but so in and that's
using stacks you know like every time
you have a value you push it on a stack
and you have let's say you want to do 1
plus 2 so you press 1 put it on a stack
and you press 2
to put it on a stack then you press
press you know press sign and they just
you know they take the arguments from
the previous tax so you get three so the
stack is not just three so that's stack
so one language uses stacks like that is
fourth it's like fourth that's the name
of the language but I actually never I
never looked into fourth but it's one of
those languages you know people talk
about like hackers type you know it's
interesting so anyway so and so my my
real first programming language is
Mathematica you know I've been
programming Mathematica for you know
every day for 14 years in 1990s so I
would say that's the most so Mathematica
is what I would consider is the most
advanced language today I mean even
today it's it's a bit it's slower than
other languages but it's far more
powerful in the advancement Haskell or
whatever whatever you know by far I mean
other languages you know so you have C
low level languages your Python Perl
Ruby PHP that's kind of high level high
level meaning like one line is like 10
lines of C or C plus rest okay
so Python Ruby you know Python Ruby and
JavaScript PHP then then you know you
might consider Haskell to be you know
Haskell cammo to be like kind of like
higher than that because you can because
functional programming you can you can
do more but well yeah so you know you
might consider has got to be on top you
know or some other languages you know
whatever your favorite you know goal and
today's new line closure : and this you
know a lot so there's so many languages
today so anyway so
but mathematica so my second guys over
here I'm not you know I kid you not
because you know Mathematica is say if
you its proprietary language and and
it's um its proprietary so most people
don't look at it because today's world
is open-source you know especially
open-source phonetics you know I'm sure
a lot of you are because that's the
that's the community I live in so open
source would you know most people you
know when they hear proprietary they
they don't even bother looking into it
you know so that's a fact of life so a
lot of people you know you don't know
Mathematica but Mathematica is a it's at
least it's the language is basically a
list you know you I would say list or in
the family of this B it's almost exactly
like every essential characteristic
qualities that define this you know
may-maybe closure scheme comedies for
him agrees essential qualities that
define this is easy easy Mathematica so
it's it's a bit however if you ask the
guy he wouldn't you know he Stefan
Wolfram he's a guy you know he started
Mathematica and Wolfram Alpha you know
he probably would not say because he
sees very people say he's a megalomaniac
so he wouldn't you know you wouldn't
give credit but any into list but anyway
if you look at old literature like
online you will see a lot comparisons of
Mathematica and this so anyway so yeah
Mathematica is actually my first
programming language and that's mostly
scientific programming scientific
programming is totally different from
industrial programming most people like
when we talk about programming that's or
industrial programming very few actually
ever did scientific programming a
scientific programming is very different
so what
other languages of scientific proven so
Mathematica Judea MATLAB ah those are
you know APL those are like scientific
programming languages all the rest like
: Percy prospers c-sharp
he even has MA
okay C C sharp ends Perl Python PHP all
those are like industrial programming
they are in a sense so they are totally
different from scientific programming
the language is totally different that
the concept is very different and also
the programming what actually you do the
problem you solve is also totally
totally different
now there's one simple way kind of like
criteria to tell whether language is
scientific programming language or
industrial programming language that is
you look at you know array index you
know whether the array index started 0
or 1 okay so if the array index started
0 its industrial programming language is
[ __ ] now if there is index started 1
that's that scientific you know I have
articles about that you know I have like
hundred I have like 6,000 HTML pages I'd
written over the past 20 years anyway I
have a written an article about about
array index and also about scientific
programming languages you know if you
search for math oriented languages
anyway so so yeah array array index is
one of the way to tell a language is
scientific programming language or math
math oriented and also you know it's
funny like programmers most programmers
they admire they admire or they you know
they look up to mathematicians because
they think math you know they look up to
math like like they they think math is
above them you know
vast you know most programmers
industrial programmers like
mathematician now over there so and also
industrial programmers they don't know
math much but anyway so I mean so like
I'm a hacker you know like food hackers
I mean like you know hacker news like
people who hacker news all the time will
slash dot before that they think they
look up to mathematicians so when when
it comes to array index you know you
should it start to from zero one you
know they will always be course I mean
the reason you know they always tend to
say oh because it should start at zero
because because mathematics you know
this or that therefore it should be zero
it's so idiotic
you know because if you actually look at
mathematical languages you know math
languages programming languages for
doing in math they all started one and
personally I think one is much better
you know zero is extremely idiotic one
is much better because especially when
you are doing matrices you know matrices
you have so what what what is a matrix
matrix is basically like array nested
array you know you have several level of
deep nesting array so if you have two
two levels you have two-dimensional
matrix you have three level nesting you
have three dimensional matrix but it can
be nested more then you have tensors now
if each each sub list is widths of the
same length so you have two dimension
two dimensional matrix three dimensional
matrix or you have tensors you know but
if if each sub list is maybe different
lengths then you have trees yeah exactly
Julia start at one that's why you know
you know most you know almost all math
oriented languages they started one okay
so the
that's about array so how I make a
living I don't make much you know I'm
actually very poor I'm like okay here's
no more people here is poverty by us
standards and I'm here and the poverty
where poverty so you know III like these
days I make like $1,000 a month that's
right one thousand dollars
so I well I don't make much anyway so
now so what should I talk about that
that's a subject Richard Stallman yeah
and also why do you stick to Mac I don't
stick to Mac you know like people get
the impression you know I'm because
right now I'm on the Mac or something
people think I'm Mac so so Richard well
that's the yeah those are big topics
like I have tens of articles about them
so let's talk about why the the Mac
Linux was so so my I started to use a
computer in 1990 almost exactly 1989 you
know but I started to use computer
everyday for many hours a day in
starting around 1991 so from from 1990
basically through our 1990s my main
computer at home or personal computer is
math and that's okay so that's you know
Mac so I stopped using Mac in 2009 ok
like stopped or totally you know before
you know throughout 1990s I'm a Mac
person them you know you can call it Mac
phonetic you know Mac people are like
they are phonetics they are like kind of
idiotic and phonetic and today's was
it's it's more you know it's luxury its
elite people so anyway so but I started
programming career in 1905
well I worked for wolf on research the
guy who makes
you know the company will mix
Mathematica in 1995 but but my real
industrial programming is in 1998 where
you know the startup boom the bubble in
Silicon Valley's you know so I was
member of a start-up so you know so what
I do is the UNIX Solaris system minion
Dave you know that's all UNIX stuff I
mean like today Linux you think people
think Linux is so advanced but back then
the the UNIX the the Solaris they are
far more complicated you know the in
today's linux and frustrating
yeah the UNIX is [ __ ] but anyway so
so my first then so after math America
so in 1998 and programming Perl pearl
that's that's my primary language you
know person one language I know so well
back then not today you know I forgot
you know he's in 20 years so pro is the
language on but if I want to pick it up
you know in one month I can much you
know same for you whatever programming
language you learned you know even you
forgot but if you at one point you know
it is so well you can learn it you know
after you know for a month and you know
anyway so Perl
so there was Perl Solaris Apache Apache
web server and Linux one on Linux PO
Java oh yeah / Java virus in the Apache
and MySQL my MySQL Oracle we were using
Oracle database so this remember this is
1998 to 2002 and we are I you know so I
walked
we are the you know actually at the
project I walk on it's the eye I would
say you know I cannot prove it but I
would say it's
project with the most lines of code in
Perl so it's a biggest pearl project in
the world let's say biggest top 5
biggest okay this make it that way so I
so anyway back then so anyway what you
know I'm not sure which aspect to talk
to it because I got I got distracted and
we known you know so oh yeah so why do I
stick to a Mac - over Linux so anyway
anyway so yeah I was talking about so so
so I was you know at home I am still
using a Mac but at work we use Windows
NT and Solaris is you know we have
servers you know you know remote servers
and and we have in-house service and we
have staging service you know and back
then well it's not like today today it's
much things are more everything is more
simpler but anyway so those virus boxes
you know they cost $40,000 you know as
Marcos I have pictures on my site
somewhere but anyway so so although I'm
a Mac user but I'm you know my main
programming activity my main programming
expertise is is with Unix
so my the the first Linux I ever used in
install these in 1998 it's called MK
Linux now in big MK Linux you can look
at you know you can search the web
that's the that's the Linux the Apple
started you know because at the time you
know open source just became came into
the scene so Apple and there's a Linux
you know so I have a want to experiment
so m'kay
anyway so m'kay Linux is the first Linux
I installed in and used so but so mostly
so in around 2002 or 2003
the Apple switched to two Mac OS X you
know Mac OS 10
that's Linux that's a UNIX based Mac OS
anyway that's long history so I'm anyway
so I stopped using Maggie in 2009 before
so up to from from 1990 to 2009 Mac is
my main system at home you know for
whatever I do
but then for two years I used Linux I'm
on our Linux Windows was my main system
Windows Vista for two or two or three
years as my main desktop then around
2014 or something like that or 2013 I
switched to Linux
so Linux was my main desktop for like
three or four years and I switched back
to Mac for you know two years ago
because why because a professor gave me
a Mac so I have a Mac like you know I
don't have I don't have money to buy a
Mac so so so if you so so what are no so
which is best you know I can tell you
which this which is the best Mac we Mac
so basically their characteristics
remain the same over the past 20 years
okay
their characteristics remains the same
so if you want the cheapest and you know
workable operating system you go with
Windows you know is it's bundled with
every laptop or computer you buy and it
works reasonably well I mean it's
something you know the user interface is
not as pretty as Mac and the way it
works you know you can plug in you can
buy devices like paint like paint
computing like you know you can plug in
server like I but I bought this here you
know you can and you have Gaming Mouse
and see ways
see game Kimi Mouse so I have actually
quite you know similar the mouse's but
this mouse is great one of the you know
the most important feature about Macedon
second is a spinning is a [ __ ] we all
see it can spin up to like 20 seconds
oops yeah so especially for our Linux
because our Linux you don't have
accelerated wheel scroll on Linux it's
extremely stupid anyway so you know so
for Windows you know everything just
works you can use it for Mac everything
is much more beautiful and much more
intuitive like when you use Maggie it
just works
I mean it's you really seriously it's
true it's true in the 1990s is true in
2000 it's true today on the Mac you know
a things just work however you don't
have as much software like whenever like
Second Life games or some experimental
software or Java you know on a Mac you
don't have it you know Apple you know
you live in Apple's would you know like
Java for example Java on the language
you know since - 20 years ago every Java
version they come out on survivors first
of course when Solaris was a CEO like
then they come out on Windows first for
the Mac version you wait for half a year
or one year and it sucks and fresh for
example fresh mark of media fresh you
know on Windows it works so well on a
Mac it's like two three times slower and
you know you whenever there's a new
version for the Mac II you know it's
like 2 years old you know and also for
chat software like Skype you know
there's a or our chat you know when when
webcam just came became popular you know
on the windows everyone can video can
you know to every other on the Mac you
can't you know Skype doesn't support it
or can't business about it the Mac
version doesn't support it yahoo chat
you know doesn't support it so on a Mac
you have these problems and also on a
Mac everything is twice as expensive you
know that's just the way we you know the
way things are because corporations and
you know the wave corporations are
because that's the way they make money
you know every corporation they do
whatever they can to make money anyway
anyway so Mac yeah so on the Mac things
are much more intuitive much more simple
easier you know they just designed
everything in spirit and but things are
much more expensive and also you
basically you don't play games on the
Mac you know some people made these
disagree I mean I've been in in the Mac
strange
Maxine for 20 years so a lot of people
would say some Mac phonetics I mean
everything everything you say about
Maxim Mac phonetics will counter oh yeah
but but stream is on the Mac or
something you know like oh every game
you can play is is available on Mac my
I'll bet my ass okay it does just
doesn't work and also on the Mac you can
you cannot install a graphics card on
the PC you can you know you spend
hundred dollars you know even a cheap
graphics card it makes a huge difference
on a map you basically cannot you do you
just buy apples preset stuff okay on
Linux Linux is actually the worst you
know I hate to say these I know many of
you are Linux Linux fans you know I am
I'm a hardcore programmer type you know
I don't care for commercialism or stuff
so I really want to Linux to succeed but
Linux Linux is the worst of the worst of
them the Mac or Windows everything like
when you when I use Linux for example
it's almost every week I have to spend
like two hours
first about things installing stuff
things doesn't work find out why it
doesn't work go to stack overflow go to
arc our Kleenex you know a Kleenex has a
great wiki they they talk about how code
details in how things work you know on
Linux so you know I'm I am very
interested in programming and technical
details but however when you use Linux
you just find out you just find yourself
you know like you spend like half an
hour a day to first about user interface
and you know Mouse how to control how to
reprogram it it's a time frame it's a
time train and everything doesn't work I
mean everything everything programming
languages installing things or whatever
especially audio and video I mean don't
even talk about audio or video you know
it doesn't work I mean of course there's
also Linux phonetics you'll say oh it
works you just have to this is this that
but anyway what I'm saying is that even
if you are a hardcore dedicated hardcore
programmer or you know computer
scientists you know you'd you want to
you understand you know you are
professional and and you want to you are
willing and very interested to spend
huge amount of time to just to you know
look at kernel or whatever details even
that Linux is still sucks you know it
just you you know that's my opinion but
however the advantage of Linux is that
it's open source it's not like Apple
tightly control with money you know they
Apple you know everything everything
they do is like they set up a track so
that you know you end up just paying
them you know pay them maybe they are
peripheral peripheral devices that with
the way they advertise their software
the Apple Store that the [ __ ] Apple
Store you know the you know since 10
years ago you started have a trend and
back every software is in Apple Store or
Android store you know
Google store Microsoft store you know
and anyway so so Linux yeah it's free
you know it's open-source but you get
you know you get what you you know pay
for I know some of you are Linux fence
okay let's talk about IMS you know in in
the richest woman in free software
foundation so I was I was a fan I was
you know a fanatic of Richard Stallman
and why it's a long history so I was a
richest woman but over the ten years I
don't think he's a good so so okay so
let me just describe a few details so
this Richard Stallman started the GPL
you know free software foundation then
in around 1995 the open source began the
open source movement that's actually
organization they began because the the
reason they began because they want to
you know they they want to be a
intermediate between the the commercial
world and the free software Richard
Stallman world they want to be like the
because the Richard Stallman world of
software it's like ethic made very
ethical or morality based you know they
because Richard Stallman he wants to he
you know it's like it's basically
essentially it's communism okay
now many many people will especially
open-source fans would say oh no it's
not coming in communism actually it is
that I mean the essential idea of a free
software is communism I mean the idea is
that you know everyone shares you know I
don't know things you know I whatever I
do I you know I make money I share I
share my software you know basically as
essential idea share share everything
you know and that so many open source
movement came along it started by this
this guy yes are Eric
which yes aw Eric Raymond yeah Eric
Seymour Raymond yeah anyway so he's a
he's a questionable guy he said yeah you
know he's more questionable [ __ ] he said
you know anyway so yes I he started open
source so the reason is that because
Richard Stallman is too too much you
know i idealogy so he want to create
something about you know called open
source the idea is that you know so
commercial world can you know it's open
source but it's not morality okay it's
just open source everyone can look at
the source and and there's a war between
the two factions actually they you know
today a lot of people don't know today
but they are at war the richard storm
and the free software camp was a
suburban source
they are like i mean i'm talking about
war not just i don't like them they they
they seriously fight each other to this
state today i mean if you say - I mean
there's a video 10 years ago you know
someone invited Richard Stallman to give
a lecture ends and and the the him the
the the host you know start by saying
you know I want to thank you very much
Richard Stallman for all the work you
did to the open-source community in
stuff and reach the storm and got
offended you know the fact you know if
you say my work is open source you have
you don't understand my work at all you
know this video on YouTube and you know
so Richard Stallman so they are open
source and free software foundation is
at war that's why this acronym F OSS
that was created you know it's supposed
to you know include post reaches you
know open source and free software
foundation you know so they say Faust of
loss software yeah so so anyway so so
anyway anyway so that's reaches women so
I was of
and I was yeah I was a believer of
Richard Stallman and I what I did I also
I despised so I was on a Richard
Stallman's camp I despised open source
because I think you know open source
what I want I want people to share I
mean that's a higher moral higher moral
quality you know you ready software you
shared why not you know that's the
important but then so anyway that's back
then that's 2000 so I have a article you
know I'm you know if you want to find
out my opinions about open source you
can just search my name Saudi and Saudi
free software foundation okay sorry open
source okay sorry you know whatever
topic has cow
pearl Golan Golan is my favorite
language your you'll find lots of
Holocaust so so I was fan of Richard
Stallman but then not today he's I think
he's still reasonable I mean when we
church the people we have to look at all
things like the whole humanity like the
history of humanity
so Richard storm and how do I search him
so okay first of all right so I think he
is he's he's basically what he is doing
is saving ideology and that's the most
harmful you know that's that can get
people killed millions thousands
millions people died because of
communism he is selling ideology and he
have no idea about economics you know
like when you when you talk about you
know the capitalism or communism you
know we get abstract the best thing to
do is actually look at you know
statistics like how things actually are
you know you look at the communist
countries and how they do they do pretty
bad the you know million people died out
of either you know execution or
starvation because things didn't work
out you know you will die
then you know so you look at actually
what happens you know not don't buy into
believe so ideology or what is good you
look at when you implement this policy
when this policy is used what actually
happens to people you know things like
that always scientific it's like
keyboard you know people say oh you
should set keys to this or that or you
should use meme or whatever whatever you
know look at scientific evidence as much
as possible I mean not all things can
have a scientific abut and so you know
there's no research but you actually
start to measure you know use a key lock
software measure how much key you type a
day and use a camera record your your
fingers then you can compare you know
you can see with whether this is good or
that is bad you know peep be scientific
as much as possible in the practical so
anyway so so I was Pro Richard Stallman
but today so I think you know he's
selling ideology it's it's no good and
especially today you know in the past 10
years he he is one of the he's a number
one guy who who did damage to Emax the
biggest greatest damage to Emax I mean I
mean he haven't been coding for like 20
years and he like he's asking what is
magic what is milpa why is people you
know using mapa can you guys tell people
to tell people not to use Mel pie and
you know he max you know he's saying
that things you know you can see on his
you know emails you know so he's a
[ __ ] [ __ ] you know he he's out of
touch with the world I mean okay so
that's first thing I want to say about
him he's sending ideology and he's out
of touch and he is the one person that
who did the most damage to progress of
Emax in the past ten years
okay on the other hand okay okay so we
have to judge a person throughout
history not just you know a narrow view
so I so but compared to
or other person is in a word I think
he's still a good person
he's a reason you know he's a good
person he's good person because although
you know he's kind of an ideologist but
you know they are a lot much worse you
know
priests for example they preach you know
religion they make they make a lot money
the cheating people you know and there's
also anyway politicians and you know
anyway so Richard Stallman and one thing
good about him is that he he's true to
himself I mean he preached what he does
you know so you know he doesn't he
doesn't cheat your money I mean although
he's the head of you know the ideology
so he doesn't have to worry about things
you know people like every you know the
Emax in the past ten years you know who
did the work you know it's not Richard
Stallman it's all the other people but
however all the people just remember one
guy Richard Stallman like you know you
ask me you know people ask me well what
do I think of him it's all the other
people I mean he's the only one taking
the credit basically so anyway so so
yeah so anyway so he the good thing
about him is he's he's a you know honest
and true to himself guy and he you know
and and also free software you know the
idea you know basically it's a good idea
I mean you should have software why not
you share you know if you can you share
you know it's always good to you know do
that right so that's what I but not not
in a degree when it becomes an ideology
like today like when today it's it has
become a massive very bad criminal you
know ideology especially mix with a
social justice you know it becomes so
you start with the mentality of helping
people share in everything and now it
has become the it went to the social
justice becomes that it
becomes a dictatorship and all that but
I would say it's it has roots from open
source as well from the you know sub
free software foundation Hogan sauce the
share mentality and also all the big
corporations the bloodthirsty Google and
Apple you know who helped open source
the most you know ask yourself yourself
who who is the guy who helped open
source it's Google Google and Facebook
to Facebook to you know you know they
say oh we also face open source and also
Apple you know remember back in 2002
when Mac os10 came out apple says oh we
used open source you know the most
industrial stables a system in the UNIX
and you know anyway so so look at what
Google has become you know most of you
probably agree you know Google has
become the most evil empire far more
evil than Microsoft you know it's it's
so sad that you know and it their
software has also become so bad
it's so sad you know like in 2000's like
it's it's us we helped we helped Google
you know because Google is so great you
know it's a company that you know do
know Evo and everything they do is so
great
but now the ads you know they are their
practice their tactics the thing they do
it's so bad you know so it's a anyway so
that's a yeah and OpenGL yeah but that's
another topic OpenGL story so anyway so
I'm gonna end this stream you know I
mean random talking thank you thank you
know for an hour now so it's so it's a
thank you yeah thank you thank you so
yeah I'm gonna try it you know to stream
you know I'm trying I'm going to try to
Hobie a sofa so thanks guys bye
so okay how do you actually exit
hurricane in-stream