Hello guys. Welcome to another episode
of Sound Talk Show.
Today we are going to code JavaScript
live.
So I'm going to
uh
explain, okay? So first of all, let me
show you my keyboards. This is Glove AT
keyboards. Fantastic. I have a video
review just, you know, about three uh
two months ago, two or three.
Check it out. Glove AT. And this is
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard version two. I
also have a video review. Both are
fantastic, okay?
So right So right now I'm using Glove AT
as my main. This is curved keyboard. And
this I'm using it as my keyboard macro.
So all one single key press shortcuts.
Okay, so let's talk about let's do code
JavaScript, okay? So first So
So let me tell you what am I
Are we going to do? Hello guys. Hello
Louis.
And hello uh
Swissbra and uh Muro.
And uh
Magdy.
Okay, so JavaScript. So let's let's
start. So first of all, let me show you
what what what is the job. So we are
going to code JavaScript application
from the ground up. I'm going to teach
you, you know, so you don't you you you
must have some basic familiarity with
programming
uh with JavaScript. Uh and we are going
to code. So let me show you what are we
going to code, okay? So you can see my
screen, yeah.
So let's go to my, you know, just search
for Unicode. You'll find it. And
Unicode, here we have several
applications. So let me show you, okay?
So for example, you can do upside down
text. So you just
type anything here.
Uh let me magnify the screen, okay? So,
Alt T
S
magnify screen 120% okay, so now it's
bigger, it's better.
So, you can
type anything
here and the text will be upside down,
okay? So, then you can copy this and
post it to Twitter or other social
network. So, it's a fun thing. So,
that's one So, this is written in
JavaScript, of course. You can
For example, I can
uh
I can look at the Unicode block. So,
copy the
copy the URL, open it, show in browser,
and here is the source code of that
page, Unicode inverted text.
Uh and and here is the JavaScript, not
that one.
Here.
So, here's a JavaScript code. In fact,
it's TypeScript. So, if we drop into a
directory, you can see TypeScript, then
it compiles to JavaScript.
TypeScript is a superset of JavaScript.
So, every JavaScript is also
TypeScript.
Uh and what TypeScript does it is that
it allows you to add types to variable
values. For example, uh a number or
string. You can So, that it can find
coding errors before you run it.
So, here's a TypeScript code. So, you
can see if we magnify, so you can see
this is a map or table that
converts the text inverted version. So,
each of the inverted version is actually
a Unicode character. For example, this Q
and inverted Q. So, in Emacs, you can do
describe char. So, meta X describe char.
So, you can see in a pink window is all
my command name calls. So, you can see
the
the describe char, that's the command
name. And on the left is the keystroke.
I'm using a Vorak keyboard layout. Okay,
so you can see this Q, and you put the
cursor on this uh let's say P, okay? So,
you put cursor on this thing, and you
meta X
describe char.
Then, it will tell you all information
about that character. So, for example,
this
in this this the the name of this
character inverted P is actually
Cyrillic capital letter Komi D.
Okay, funny. So, and uh you can see you
can find the code point and so on. So,
so let's let's see what is this Q.
So, describe char.
So,
Latin capital letter O with grave, okay?
So, that's actually emulating the
inverted
uh version of the letter Q. But, some of
the character is actually uh
specifically inverted. For example,
let's see what is this one, for inverted
Y.
Okay, turned sans-serif capital Y. So,
you see this character
upside down Y capital Y is actually
specific character for that purpose.
That's available in Unicode.
You know, Unicode is a set of
characters. So, anyway, so that's, you
know, the fun thing to do
to post to your to your social networks.
And then, there are also other
interesting things. Uh let me show you
uh interesting applications.
So, go back to Unicode search, and uh
you see here is the gothic font.
Gothic font.
Gothic style of
typeface
you can use. So, you see
So, then you can copy this, for example,
let's copy it back to Emacs, a new
buffer, paste it.
And let's magnify.
You see, gothic style of typeface.
Uh and you can, for example, put cursor
on this character, describe char, then
it'll tell you this character
displayed as that
is code point 120096
and also hexadecimal.
And then the character name is
mathematical
Franktur small C.
Okay, so close that.
So, all these are Unicode characters.
That's what allows you, fundamentally,
to do this kind of thing. And you can
change it to bold font, bold
uh face font. So, this is actually not
font, you see.
What you are seeing is actually not
font. It's actually characters specified
by
Unicode.
Uh so, hold on a second. So, you can see
close that. You can have it have it
bold, and you can copy that and post it
to your Twitter.
Uh Twitter is amazing, artificial
intelligence is incredible. Uh I mean,
the
stable diffusions and the mid journey, a
bunch of artificial intelligence drawing
that's uh
you know, making a big change to
society. I think that's critical. It's
It's It's you know, it's changing the
land landscape of online internet. So,
whatever you see in the next few years
Uh probably half of it is going to be
generated by AI and you cannot tell
whether it is or not. So anyway, back to
the the this thing. So you can also have
italic and you can also have this
scripted style
uh characters.
Again, they are not font. Okay, they are
actual characters. So if you paste this
you know, let's go to Twitter and let's
create a new and let's let's paste it.
Oh, I pressed the wrong button.
Paste, you see.
Tweet
and send now.
So you can see you have scripted version
of characters. Fantastic.
Okay. So that's a that's a fun use of
this
uh this JavaScript, you know, this this
Unicode application.
So let me show you another one. So So
you have upside down, you have math
text, then you have this this is a fun
one. This is uh
This is
This is Rune
character. Okay, Rune is a alphabet
alphabet used around 1500s.
Yeah, around 150 to 1500s, you know.
Basically, this is a ancestor of uh
of uh
of of of German language or English or
you know, northern Europe language,
Germanic language.
So anyway, but but Latin took over as
alphabet. So anyway, so this is uh fun
to use. Okay, so this can be also used
for secret writing kind of. So and and
you can type some English. For example,
let's So actually, there are several
versions of Rune, so you can change
them. Then you can also switch for For
example, if you copy that, copy it
and you want to know what that means
English. So you click to Latin. Then you
paste it.
So, you know, so that reverse translate
to back to English.
Okay. Okay. So anyway, so and there's
another one. This also This one is also
fun. So you can translate to Braille.
Okay.
So today, what we are going to write one
is uh
full width characters. So full width
Unicode characters. So let me show you
what that is.
Okay. So you go here
uh full width. Okay. So full width
characters, they are basically they are
just um
Am I doing okay? So say hi guys. Okay.
Keep the comments going. So full width
characters are just
like normal English characters and up
and uh punctuations. Except that they
are full width.
Full width means the width of a Chinese
character. So this full width character
exist because in Chinese writing
Let's see. Uh let's go to some Chinese
writing. So
um
Chinese. Okay.
So for example, in Chinese writing,
every every character is a square. And
uh sometimes you have a need to
have English text mixed in the Chinese
writing. For example, a person's name,
uh place name, San Francisco, and so on.
And but if you do that
then the text is not aligned. Because
traditionally, Chinese characters, they
are all squares of the same width. So
they are aligned vertically or
horizontally.
But as soon as you introduce, you know,
English text
your Chin- it screws up your Chinese
character alignment. So that is
how that's that is why you have this
full width
English alphabet and punctuation
characters. They they are used in Asia
in Japan and China. Okay. So, so now you
have Unicode version of it. Before it
was just a font, but now it's actually a
character. So, when you use this
character it's actually full width
anywhere. You don't have to change the
font to, you know, a special one. So, we
are going to what we are going to do is
just write a interactive JavaScript
application to do this.
Good?
Okay. So, actually so, let's do that
now. Okay. So, copy the URL back to
Emacs. Close that. Paste it here. Make a
uh
uh link.
So, and let's start to code. Okay?
Uh JavaScript. Okay. So, we're going to
code JavaScript
and uh
Okay. Pop this out.
So, console log
uh or just print three.
Okay. So, run it.
Three. You can see this is JavaScript.
So, what we want to do okay. So, we want
to do um
Yeah. So, we want to So, yeah. Okay.
There's one more thing I want to show
you for you Emacs users.
Okay. So, Emacs users, I actually have
this written. I have So, let's let's
show it. Okay?
I have this
written as a Emacs command.
For example, copy that text and okay and
meta X
let's show the pink window. MetaX
to Chinese.
Okay, so we uh which one? Wait.
Uh wait, full width. Okay, so you can
see the command name is
xa-convert-full-width-characters,
okay?
Enter.
Okay, so it toggles, so you have to do
it again. Do it again. So, now you can
see
you see now this is full width
character. So, for example, let's put
put put the cursor here and call
describe-character,
MetaX-describe-character,
and you can see this character's name is
full width Latin small letter e. Okay?
So, that's a full width character, and
let's let's say if I make name of
paragraph. By the way, this you see this
uh tiny you see this red underline?
Emacs does that.
Because this character, you see, right
now this character is actually a
uh Chinese space. So, Chinese space is
also full width, so describe-character,
and you can see ideographic space.
Ideographic means, you know, basically
means Chinese. You also use in Japanese.
So, Emacs automatically display a red
red underline uh uh beneath it. Just so
that you can distinguish. So, anyway, so
let's show this in browser.
So, you can see here is the Emacs
command that does that. Now, let's look
at the source code, okay?
So, describe-command,
xa-convert-full-width-characters,
enter. So, here is the documentation.
Let's jump to the source code,
xa-emacs-replace-quotes.
So, here is the code. So, copy it, new
buffer, paste it.
68 lines of code, okay? So,
and let's let's make it Emacs Lisp cuz I
Emacs Lisp mode, so you got coloring.
So, here's the code. And if you want to
use it,
here's the URL. So, open it,
showing browser,
just search for this and you can get a
code. So, it works in Emacs.
Okay, comments and questions, post
comments, okay?
Okay, so now let's write the JavaScript
version, okay? Actually, so we I want to
I do want to have the
the Emacs Lisp code, so we can use this
conversion table. So, you can see here's
the conversion table. Wait, close it, we
open it,
it auto saves
because of Xah Fly keys. And now let's
let's
um
So, here is a conversion table we we we
will need to use in JavaScript. So,
let's make it um let's
let's make it into a single line. I
mean, multiple lines, okay? So, it's
easier to see.
Okay, so you can see
Okay, we will we're going to use that,
okay? Let's go back to JavaScript.
Okay, go back to JavaScript, start
coding. So, first So, in order to do
this, we need
we need a HTML page. So, let's start a
fresh, a new HTML page, okay?
So, let's go back to talk show. Let's
create a page. Uh new page HTML
start a template.
Let's magnify two font.
Uh 1920 let's say 20.
Okay? So,
save this.
Let's say XX HTML, okay?
Okay, XX full width HTML. Now, show in
browser. It's empty, okay? Good. Now, so
first thing you want to do is to add a
uh
graphical user interface where
people can input the character, okay?
So, how do you So, let me show you,
okay?
Uh
you know, you need the boxes like that.
So, let's go to one of these page. Let's
just let's go to the upside down
uh page.
So, you need to create this. So, how do
you do How do you do that? I have a
tutorial. So, you go to
xahlee.info
CSS
No, not CSS, JavaScript tutorial, okay?
So,
JavaScript tutorial, go to any of the
page, JavaScript object reference. You
want to go to the DOM section. DOM is
where you program all these, and you
want to go to the user interface
section. So,
so let me introduce my JavaScript in
depth, okay? This is the best JavaScript
tutorial
in English anywhere on Earth, okay? It's
better than, you know, whatever books
you buy on Amazon by JavaScript experts,
well-known experts, my my my tutorial I
would claim is a better than them. So,
to be more precise, it's the top I would
consider my tutorial to be the top
four
best JavaScript in-depth tutorial
written in English, okay?
Doesn't matter it's a website or book or
or or a printed book, you know, for
example, many of you will say Mozilla,
you know, Mozilla
tutorial. Oh, they are very great. No,
many often they they got things wrong or
you know, particularly in their
Mozilla's tutorial, they
they introduce things misleading and
wrong, okay? So, basically, you you have
to spend a lot of time eventually to get
around to understand. My JavaScript
tutorial is concrete. Everything is a
example. There's no joke. There's no
elaborate telling a story. Oh, I program
in C first. This is like C's this or
like Java something or like Python. Not
nothing like that, okay? It's just pure,
easy to read, easy to understand
uh
explain explanation with examples for
every concept.
Uh
and in-depth, okay? So, if you like it,
you know, pay me, okay? So, you can buy
it, download for fast reference. So,
there's a reference section, too, for
all JavaScript objects. JavaScript
object is extremely complex. First
First of all, it's not in the object,
you know, the meaning the
there's no exact meaning of object. You
know, let let me ramble a little bit,
okay?
You know, in JavaScript, according to
the JavaScript specification,
now every year there's a new
specification because starting around
2015, you know, that's JavaScript 6
harmony.
Uh that's a huge upgrade, huge change to
the JavaScript language making it
modern. So, you have arrow functions,
you have lots of new uh stuff. So, you
you can see
the new stuff is uh you know, there is a
star. So, for example, let is a new in
2015.
And uh
also you can declare constant. You also
you have deconstructive assignment. So,
you know, these are new features, kind
of modern.
Uh but JavaScript, you know, so
according to the JavaScript
specification,
you know, I read
I read them page to page, you know,
cover to cover several version of them.
Uh
you know, according to the JavaScript
specification,
a object a JavaScript object
So, let me show you where, okay? So, a
JavaScript object is just a collection
of pairs. Okay, that's a
that is by the s-
by the spec, okay? Actually, I can show
you the page of the specification. I
have a mirror on my website. Yeah, but
it takes time to to find it. But anyway,
so by spec, so wait, let me show you.
So, actually I explained what is a
object. So, you got object overview,
object basics, you know, basics most of
you are familiar with. You know, you got
you you can define object like that.
This is actually kind of called data
object.
So, okay, so let me get back to the So,
so what is the JavaScript object object
type, okay? So, what is a object, you
know, by spec it's a collection of a
key-value pairs. That's what the
specification says, okay? But actually,
everything in JavaScript is much more
nuanced. It's not, you know, so
for example, a function in JavaScript is
also object, okay? A function is also
object. In fact, all the
all the things you do, array is also
object. Array is a object, function is a
object. Uh then you have the map object
in and you have
So now now we go to the object
reference, okay? JavaScript script
object reference. All these are object.
Regular expression is a object, date is
a object. So you may think, okay, the
spec says the JavaScript object is just
a collection of the key-value pairs.
But a function
is actually a function, right? You need
a function body. That's not That's not a
key-value pair. That's not like a value
named function. I mean a
key named function and a value named
that is the
body of the function. That's not how
function works in JavaScript.
But
but function is a object. So
so the
the JavaScript spec
on what object is is kind of is just
idiotic, okay? Basically.
So what actually happens is that many of
the JavaScript object, yes, first of
all, they must be key-value pairs. They
must support a bunch of, you know, you
can you can arbitrarily add key-value
pairs.
But a a object in JavaScript also have a
special thing depending on the object.
Again, this you can't There's no easy
way to
to to put them into different types,
okay? So they are all just object. So
you have, you know, you have this
you have some of them is a function,
some of them is a regular expression,
some of them is a have a special data is
that is a date, you know? So an object
is a key-value pairs, but actually
for some object, they actually have
certain special things that go with it.
Okay? So
So, that's one just one of the one of
the of the 100 complexity. JavaScript,
okay? So, the typical object, for
example, from JSON, you see, those are
just
what you call
data object. Actually, the naming of
things is also very confusing. So,
according to the JavaScript spec, okay,
let me show you.
Since I'm talking, I'm starting to
ramble over.
Uh
So, for example, let me show you, okay?
So,
a JavaScript object, right? So, a
JavaScript object
Let's see, object overview. Let's see,
object basics. So, typically, you are
familiar with this, you know, name and
age, you know, a list of data, right?
That's a object.
Technically, this this object, that's
not special, but just for data. This
According to the JavaScript
specification,
it's called object object, okay?
You know, if you you know, go check it
go look go go verify it, you know, this
this is actually called object object.
But but, you know, who understand what
the is object object? It's very
confusing, okay? So, that is not a very
popular term. In fact, there's no
there's no common term to describe this,
you know, a
a a a object that is commonly used as
data. There's actually no
no uh
no ad hoc term or common used term. You
know,
the the best way I call it is just data
object, okay?
So, JavaScript is very bad language,
lots of complexities. And also, um yeah,
you know, it's endless, you know, I can
start to talk about this endless. And
also, the most the most insulting so
many
you cannot start to list one of them.
You know, then array JavaScript array is
also object. So, and you don't actually
have array. So, it's
it's
it's array pretending it's actually an
object that pretends to be array.
Because it's a object of key-value pairs
where the keys
are automatically managed like but it
was as integers, you know, 0 1 2 3 4.
And the value is actual arrays
uh
slot values.
So,
you know, it's pretty bad. There's no
true array. And also, then you cannot
compare if two object are identical. You
know,
there's no way. There's no building way.
So, each one each library create their
own equality comparison. You know, in
fact, I have written one and mine is the
best, okay? So, let me let me let me
talk about uh
object, okay? So, show parent chain
clone object method uh
test object equality. So, this is my
code. This code test any two JavaScript
object equality
by by by
by their key-value pairs and uh
recursively deep dive, okay?
You know, every there are quite a few
libraries that does that. Uh I would say
mine is
mine is I would say let's say the top
three, okay? In fact, there are there's
a blogger who compared all the
JavaScript library libraries or
framework
their function on comparing object
equality. And
half of them most of them is just
blatantly wrong, incorrect. Uh
and there are a few good ones, okay? But
the
but ultimately, JavaScript object
comparison is just it's it's it's
you can't even code it correctly. I
mean, because there's so many because
the object, you have certain attributes,
you know, uh
you know, part of JavaScript, I
explained, you know, in my in my
tutorial. Some object has attributes.
So, you have enum enumerable attribute,
then you have two other attribute,
writable, and you also have um
you know, you have few attributes. So,
and these attributes are important
because many of the function that deal
with object depends on whether the
object is the the the value, the
property is enumerable or not.
So, so when you really want to compare
two object equality, there's lots of
things you want to consider. Are you
just Do you really just want to compare
the enumerable
properties? Or and also there's another
complex issue about the key type. You
know, object is key-value pairs, but the
key
can have can be either a string type or
a symbol type. A symbol thing is new in
2015, okay?
Okay, so I started to digress into
JavaScript problems. Uh uh
let's um
maybe I should stop and go back to um
to start to code JavaScript. Uh
actually, this
I guess doesn't matter because whoever
watching this video would be interested
in JavaScript. That's what we are
talking about.
So, what are you guys talking about?
Uh
trolling and post and whatnot. I
don't care about those things, okay? You
4chan people
4chan people, go back to 4chan. I'm not
really interested in those things.
Okay, so JavaScript, let's go let's talk
about the what are we
Yeah, so we were talking about
JavaScript
um
objects attributes, okay? So
So um
So yeah, you know, okay, so check out my
tutorial. So okay, so um
Yeah, so JavaScript object object
overview. So you have
uh
you know, you have Yeah, uh then you
have the is extensible attribute.
Property, you know, actually that's the
Yeah, that's the attribute is part of
the property, okay?
Right, so Right, so so you want to know
you want to know when you compare object
equality, you want to know are you
just want to consider the property
whether they are the enumerable ones,
you know, the property
who has the attribute enumerable true or
do you want to
you know, consider just string keys or
whether do you want to include symbol
key type? And there's also the parent
issue, you know, JavaScript every object
most of them
Okay, so in other words, an object may
have another object linked to it. That's
called the parent of the object or
according the specification call it the
prototype, okay? Basically it just means
a a
So a object may or may not have a
parent.
So, when you have two objects and if you
want to you know, suppose you have A and
B two objects, you want to compare their
equality.
Now, suppose everything about them is
the same, but they have different
parents.
Do you think
they are the same? Do you consider them
to be the same or not? So, there are a
lot issues about this, you know, object
equality equality. So, there's actually
I mean, even if you are the best coder,
you have to
like consider exactly what you want to
mean by equality. So, it's fairly
complex.
So, there's a question. So, let's let me
check the
um
Okay, maybe so we we start to digress
into the JavaScript topic and uh
uh I do want to finish coding. I do want
to
Yeah, so let's you know, so
I'm let's let's talk about JavaScript,
you know, for a while. Doesn't you know,
I'm doing my talk show is just talk.
Then, but let's let's go back to um
after after that, let's get back to the
to do the full width, okay? So,
okay, so hold on a second. Let me get
uh
let me regroup and you know, plan what
we're going to talk about, okay? So,
then we're going to get back to writing
this application in Java in JavaScript,
okay? The full width.
Okay, so Luis have a question. Uh
Luis have a question, TypeScript versus
JavaScript doc. Why TypeScript? Why not
JavaScript, okay?
I would consider so
So, first of all, JavaScript is a very,
very lousy language. Now, you have to
Now, Louis, you know, Louis is a
JavaScript expert. So, Louis already
already know, but let me explain to uh
many of you who may not know so much
about JavaScript, okay?
So, uh okay, so let me actually start to
um
Let me do Let me organize, okay? So, we
we have a organized structure of of the
talk show, okay? So, let me prepare a
little bit.
JavaScript overview. So, JavaScript and
object basics. So, we want to We were
talking about
properties. So, object has properties.
Remember, object is key value pair. So,
you they got properties. And properties
got attributes, you know,
enumerable
and so on. And also, the property key
can be a string or uh
can be a string or a uh
or a symbol type, okay? So,
uh so, let me just show the proper link.
Yeah, here it is. Property attributes.
Value, writable, enumerable,
configurable, okay? It's kind of
idiotic. Very complex, okay?
So, first of all, JavaScript is a
language in 2015, there is a huge
change, okay? So, they they made
JavaScript very modern. So, JavaScript,
you know,
if you compare to Python or Ruby,
JavaScript is not, you know, every every
feature, every fancy functional feature,
whatever, in Python or Ruby,
now you can do in JavaScript since 2015,
okay? So, JavaScript is not inferior to
them.
However, here's the thing. How So So,
JavaScript made a huge change 2015,
okay? And And ever since, every year,
you have a new spec of JavaScript. Every
year, they added about two or three new
features or improvements, okay? So So,
you have JavaScript 2016, 2017, 2018,
and you know, every year. They have a
new new spec coming up.
Okay, so it's great. It's vibrant. It's
one of the most used language, actually
top one or two, depending on how you
count. Top three, okay? JavaScript,
Python,
or C++ basically, or Java. JavaScript,
Python, Java. These three are more or
less the top three most used language on
Earth, okay?
So,
you know, JavaScript is vibrant, but how
and and very powerful today. But
however, JavaScript, you know, they
decided, you know, in 2015, they decided
they are going to maintain backward
compatibility.
The JavaScript before 2015 is very bad
language. Extremely bad. It's one of the
worst language. It's It's one of the
most puny, you know, not expressive, one
of the worst, because it's actually
created, compiled, conceptualized, you
know, it's written in 10 days, compiler
and everything, just 10 days, because
Netscape, they need to push out the push
out the
the the project, you know. It was called
LiveScript, you know, because of Java at
the time is super popular, so they
renamed it. They collaborated with Sun
Microsystems, who created Java, the
language. And Java, they put million
dollars, you know, into marketing, so
JavaScript, they tried to write the
marketing, so they renamed it into
JavaScript. And they tried to change the
syntax, so it looks like Java, but it is
nothing It's nothing like Java.
JavaScript and Java is completely
completely entirely totally different
languages in how they do things in their
structure, in their concepts. It's
entirely different, okay? Not comparable
in any way. It's It's JavaScript and
Java is like the most two opposite
languages. Almost You can say that,
okay?
So,
so JavaScript began as a very bad
language, very lousy. But, in 2015,
they they they they they did a overhaul,
and so it's fantastic. But, however,
they decided to maintain backward
compatibility with with, you know,
JavaScript. Therefore, it
Therefore, all the problems in
JavaScript, all the worst problems,
still it are still there.
Okay? So, what you can do you you know,
you can try to avoid using the old
features or coding a new way, but all
the problems of JavaScript still
remains.
That is the problem of JavaScript. Even
today, it's it's, you know, so many
uh great features, but
fundament- you know, so many old baggage
is still all there. So, to this day,
that for example, we explain object,
there's no
exact precise definition, and the
terminology, you know, is all bad. And
array, there's no true array. There's no
way to compare object. Then, each object
has these, you know, elaborate complex
attributes, you know,
uh so many so many problems, okay? So,
so TypeScript TypeScript is one of the
effort to try to fix JavaScript, okay?
So, TypeScript succeeded because
TypeScript is not a new language.
TypeScript
is
compatible with JavaScript. TypeScript
is just uh simply a
super set. So every line of JavaScript
is also TypeScript. So this this for
this reason
TypeScript becomes the most successful.
Okay, no not any other reason I can tell
you. This is the reason, a social reason
why TypeScript is the is is one of the
most popular today because it tried to
be 100% backward compatible with
JavaScript. So every
JavaScript is TypeScript already.
So basically that means
you don't have to learn anything. That's
that's the issue. You know, most humans
they don't want to learn new things. You
know, they don't want a new language.
They want they want to
be able to know you know, they want to
keep their knowledge available you know,
still useful.
So for this reason
and I would say
this is the most significant reason.
This is the main reason TypeScript
became successful. Okay, and also it's
kind of the reason I use it too. So it's
widely adopted. You know, basically it's
the standard for any corporation doing
JavaScript. Okay. So TypeScript. So what
does TypeScript do? It
just allows you to add types
declare types to JavaScript. So
I have some
example and recently I tried to um
I tried to
uh
write some tutorial for TypeScript but
it's not done yet. So I only have kind
of
it's it's it's a draft. Okay, so here's
my TypeScript tutorial and it's not
it's not fully written. It's just it's
not fully written up. So basically
TypeScript allows you to add for example
for example here is a JavaScript code
but you see this thing
Uh, let's magnify, okay?
So, this is the JavaScript code. And you
see this dot dot dot, that's the that's
called spread operator. That's new in
2015.
So, this constant is also new. So, this
this function, this is we are defining a
function that just returns the length of
a vector.
So, this math.hypot
That's actually also new. That's kind of
weird. That's a new function in
JavaScript 2015.
So, basically it just it just add the
elements of a vector, add them together.
Uh, you
You you square each one, then sum them,
okay? And then you take the square root.
Yeah, that's what it that's what it
does. So, it's very short. It's
extremely, you know, that's the power.
That's what that's the power I'm talking
about the about the new JavaScript since
2015. Extremely terse code. So, this
just add a bunch of numbers, square them
first, then add them together, then do a
square root.
You know, that's what this function
does.
But, however, this part is not
JavaScript. You see that number square
bracket? That is TypeScript. So,
TypeScript
So, this declares the type of type for
this variable, this parameter V. Okay?
So, that's essentially that is
essentially what TypeScript is. That's
all. That's all. You just you can just
add types to variables, to parameters,
to variables, to and also the functions
return value. That's all it
it is, okay? That's that that is all.
That is all
TypeScript is about.
The
benefit of that is that so that when you
compare compile the code
it can find out many errors you made.
For example, you mean something is meant
to be a string and it's actually got the
value of a number.
So, you you will know. The compiler will
tell you.
That that is the benefit of TypeScript,
okay?
Um
So, and TypeScript is widely used. So,
So, it's very useful. So, when you have
lots of code, let's say a few thousand,
you know, once you have
few thousand lines of code, TypeScript
is very valuable because you can find
errors before you run the code.
Now, now let me tell you now so, you
know, let me answer the question fully
about the TypeScript versus JavaScript
doc, okay?
JavaScript doc is no good, okay?
JavaScript, let me let me tell you what
JavaScript doc is.
So, it's called JSDoc. JSDoc is is just
the industry
common practice became
fairly pop-somewhat popular.
Okay? You know, started by I don't know
who who began it, but it's just someone
did it.
So, JavaScript doc doc JSDoc, okay? So,
let's look at
getting started
here. So, that's So, this look at that,
okay? That's what
Basically, this this comment
that's what JSDoc is. That's all
it is. Nothing else, okay?
JSDoc
just allows you to add comments
to your function
so that the comments
are formatted in a standard way, you
know, you follow certain standard, you
know,
symbols. So, in a standard way, so that
it document what the function does. And
it also document kind of, you know, what
type are the parameters and what the
function return. and possibly also what
the type
of the value the function returns. So,
basically it's just a documentation
convention, okay? A kind of industrial
ad hoc standard documentation
convention. This convention of JSDoc
came from Java, okay? So, in Java there
is Javadoc.
That began it. So, it it you know, this
thing started in the Java community. So,
the Java has a tool, I believe.
I I'm not sure it's part of standard
Java. I think it is.
No, I don't I don't think it is
originally. So, it is you know, it's
basically user community developed a
standard way to comment your function so
that it document your function.
And eventually it also document the
types, the parameter type, and so on.
And then eventually it came to
JavaScript. You know, JavaScript they
start they started to adopt this
practice, this convention.
Okay?
And my opinion of it it's not good,
okay? It's crap. It's a
okay? It's It's bad design. It's
It's idiotic, okay? Like lots of things
in by these communities.
Okay?
Because when you think of So,
let's think of about what Let me tell
you why, okay? So, suppose you are going
to design
a system, a standard protocol, a kind of
standard format
to document JavaScript, okay? Or any
other language.
So, there's a question. How do you
design it?
Or
if you design it like the JSDoc, is it
good or not?
Okay, my answer is no, it's it's bad.
It's terrible. First of all, look at
look at first of all, it's using
comments, okay? Now, using comments to
specify specify type
is a hack.
Like the Unix and C people and C++ those
type of people, they love to do that.
Hack. You know, this thing cannot do it,
but they let's just try to make it do
it, you know,
you know, that's do you know, that's
what they do.
Unix, C C++, this type of people, they
created this okay, and Java.
So, this is not good design, okay?
For example, let me first of all, you
are using comment to do it.
It's not really good. You should have,
you know, so type script in this aspect
is a is a better solution.
You actually create a compiler that
properly, you know,
do it, okay? To specify the type. But
anyway,
but now look at the comment. First of
all, using comment to do it is not
it's not the best solution, but okay,
that's you know, what can we do? But
because we have to work with what we
have, you know, in the industry, million
lines of software, you know, you you
can't you if you create something new,
nobody going to use it. So, okay,
comment. Then look at the comment. Look
look look at this.
They specify
you know, you have to use this
asterisk comment, but they the first
line must be two asterisks, okay? Then
each line must have, you know, one
asterisk.
That's that's not good. Why should you
do that? Why you know, so if for
example, if I were to do this, I would
remove the the asterisk for each line.
You shouldn't do that, okay? You you
don't
it requires more typing and requires
more formatting or tools to, you know,
you have to write tools to do the
formatting and it it makes things too
complex, okay? Now, let's look at the
another thing.
You see they use this at sign to specify
a
kind of met- it's it's kind of a meta
syntax to specify the
what the next word
the
the the the the the meaning of the next
word word, okay? For example, this at
param then string title, it means
the next thing
is a string type
and the name of that parameter the next
thing is a parameter and it's of a
string type and the name of the
parameter is a title, then followed by
explanation in English, okay? That's
that's what that is, okay? So, is this
design good? No.
You know, and then then I can go into a
lot reasons about why or about what what
is a better alternative. For example, I
would use
anyway, a lot reasons, okay? So, that's
that's a that would be another, you
know, project hour to to design to
design
a
specification by way of a comment to
specify functions
documentation and uh
parameter types and return type, okay?
That's so, anyway, so, JSDoc is
okay? That's my opinion.
So, therefore
TypeScript versus JSDoc, I would
actually, you know, much more favor
TypeScript.
Okay, I would you know, I would not use
JSDoc. I think it's you You anyone
who use it I I consider idiot, okay?
Most programmers are idiot. They just
follow whatever, you know, they have to.
You know, and it's kind of practical but
it's no good, okay?
Even practically speaking, I would say,
you you know, don't use it. Don't use
JStock, okay?
Uh so, TypeScript
is better, okay?
And TypeScript itself is not perfect
because first of all,
it's 100% compatible with JavaScript.
And JavaScript is 100% compatible with
the old JavaScript, the So,
TypeScript is also you know,
there's nothing you can do. And also,
because TypeScript
they try to be 100% compatible with
JavaScript, therefore they add lots of I
mean, therefore, when you code
TypeScript, so for example, let's show a
TypeScript code.
So, you have I have
for example, let's say
um
Okay, let's let's show all my TypeScript
code, okay?
So, actually
backslash backslash dot TypeScript. So,
here is all my TypeScript code.
So, you have 24-hour clock.
Let me try to find one where I actually
have a lot of
um
you know,
uh type annotations.
So, that would be
Yeah, that would be this one, okay? So,
this this one
uh
actually
So, here you see this is typescript but
not much because you see all the green
characters for example here those are
typescript and annotations. Okay.
Okay, you don't see much typescript
here.
By the way, this code
By the way, if you look at
um
You know, you if you look at my code,
this is the most advanced JavaScript
code. Okay, mostly is JavaScript. It's
not typescript. You know, but so this
way of style is functional programming
in JavaScript. Okay, but but let me show
you the typescript. Okay, so I do have a
um
Uh what what's going on?
Uh
Hold on a second.
I don't know what I did to
Oh, upper directory. I don't want to go
up a directory.
Okay, so
Oh yeah, so I want to show
um
Yeah, so here you see much more
typescript. This is a application that
does
uh SVG drawings. So for example, here's
a function
you know, doing vector, you know, um
find the angle between two vectors
and here's vector addition. You see all
those type annotations. Then here's
vector subtraction. Then so this is kind
of typical TypeScript, okay?
Uh then uh
Okay, so what's uh what are we talking
about? So, TypeScript, yeah, so
what I'm saying is that TypeScript,
because they try to be 100% compatible
with JavaScript, so that when you add
types, your code becomes fairly
unreadable. You know, your code,
especially
Let me show you an example, okay?
Especially when you want to use
de-structure, okay?
So, let me show you.
You know, de-structure assignment, this
is very complex, you know, as you know,
since to the this is added in 2015. So,
you have, you know, these, you know, you
have three dots, then you have optional
rest parameters, you have
you know, de-structure assignment. And
then you also when when you have
objects, they get's more complex, okay?
So,
when you have de-structure assignment,
then when then you want to add types to
to to them, it becomes unreadable. It
becomes very
unreadable. So,
yeah, but what you know, what can you
do?
Okay, that is my question about that.
Um I already talked for 1 hour today. Um
So, what else?
So, uh let's see what we going to do
now. So, do I want to finish coding
that?
You know, um
the reason this TypeScript was versus
js.com up is because recently
you know, recently there's a project
that they decided to
to ditch TypeScript and use JavaScript.
I can I can kind of understand why they
do that because TypeScript is annoying
because because
you know, when you do TypeScript you
can't run the code.
I mean well, you can run in Deno, I
know. By the way, I highly recommend
Deno. Deno is a JavaScript runtime,
okay? It also runs TypeScript. I highly
recommend Deno, okay?
But the one but one of the things with
this middle step compiling is that when
you do
you know, JavaScript dev for the web
anything you do, you have to compile
first. Yeah, there's automation, you
know, that you can do it automatically,
but but
but this extra step in the middle is
kind of very annoying.
And then your source code and the
compiled code are not exactly the same,
of course. So, for example, here's the
same thing.
You know, here's the same thing they
they just, you know, removed all the
type annotations, you know.
Yeah, but the the code are different.
So, it's kind of annoying that extra
step.
Um but there's nothing you can do. So, I
actually I think the best thing to
happen if is that
is that the TypeScript type declaration
declaration actually became part of the
standard JavaScript.
That would be the best thing to happen,
okay? It's not perfect because, you
know, JavaScript is still too lousy. And
you know, but but that I think that
would be a good thing. So,
if this happens then you can have these
type annotations in your JavaScript
code. You don't need to compile it,
okay? The browser will understand it.
That's the best thing to happen.
And I heard that's happening. I don't
know what's the current status, but you
know, JavaScript uh 2022
or 2023 is a proposal of adding
types
annotation to JavaScript in the in in
kind of compatible way with TypeScript.
That's the best thing to happen.
Uh so, the reason this came up because
recently uh I know that there is a
someone I mean, there's a project uh
what project is it? Let's see.
Um
they
they tried to
they they decided they're going to drop
TypeScript and uh
and use JSDoc instead.
What project is it? Louis, I forgot.
Okay, so anyway, so that's about that.
WASM, I don't know much about it. You
know, that's
that's assembly. That's kind of the web
assembly.
Uh I would like to know more. I don't
know much about it.
Um
What?
What good libraries for math formulas
and so on do you know?
Svelte SvelteKit, okay, yeah, Svelte.
Thank you. You know, you know, I you
know, I I'm not familiar. I'm a
old-school guy, so I'm not
In fact, I don't know much about, you
know, the new frameworks. Svelte is the
latest uh and there's, you know,
you know, there there there's, you know,
quite a few
um
React and so on, you know. So, actually,
I don't know
them much to even use them. So, I'm you
know, I'm kind of out of out of out of
touch. Uh so, I heard that Svelte they
dropped
using you know, they stopped using
TypeScript and used JS Doc instead.
Yeah, I don't know what to say about
that.
When React tutorial, you pay me, I'll do
that, okay?
Seriously.
So, you guys, you know, you should pay
me, okay? If you guys have not, so let
me market myself a bit now.
Okay, destructure assignment. Let's copy
that.
Uh
Run code, okay. 24 o'clock, okay. You're
a good guy.
Deno, okay. I highly recommend Deno.
Uh
Okay, so if you don't know, so check out
my JavaScript in depth, okay? Buy it.
Pay me, you get the entire my JavaScript
entire HTML. They are
uh 700 pages or 500 pages including
including HTML tutorial from the ground
up and visual CSS tutorial, okay?
Including this uh
You know, so
uh but the main show is JavaScript in
depth. So, you pay me, you can buy it,
you know, buy JavaScript in depth.
PayPal me, you know, go there,
you know, and uh
you know, pay me if you like my stuff.
Okay, I think maybe that's it. Or should
should we continue to code that? I want
to continue for for for So, for now I'm
going to I'm just going to code it very
fast, okay? I'm going to not going to
care about I'm not
since we digress into the JavaScript
issue.
Uh
So, now let's just uh
let's just code this application without
much uh explanation. I want to code it
because coding this is actually
what's useful for me. Because, you know,
talking to you you know, talking about
this tutorial is not is ephemeral, you
know, after today
uh it doesn't it doesn't I I want, you
know, I I don't have anything permanent.
I want to code this, okay? So, let's
copy that.
Uh actually
So, we want to do the full width, yeah.
So, let's copy that. Copy that.
So, we can actually just copy and paste
code, okay?
Copy this section, close that. And uh go
to my
Okay, so
Okay, so where is my uh the other
HTML file, okay? Here.
HTML full width what?
Okay, here's the file. Close, close,
close.
Um and we want to
paste it here.
Link. Okay, change it to full
width
app, okay?
Open it.
Open it. Rename the title, okay? And
cut, close, back here.
Paste it. Showing browser, okay? So, we
got kind of
thing going. That's a interface, okay?
Then we want to have I want to have
Let's go to the
Let's copy copy the CSS.
Uh talk show today. Yeah, here. Let's
paste the CSS here.
Showing browser. Now, better. That's my
website CSS.
Okay, and the Let's magnify, okay? So,
instead of invert text, we want to
um
Okay, change to full width characters
and uh display this part is where the
result is going to show.
Uh for example, let's put something
here, TT.
Yeah, okay. That's the result uh box and
text area. Okay, so
convert uh so, we
So, we want to copy this JavaScript,
okay? Uh create new, okay.
So, this JavaScript, we want to copy it.
So, we have to do this in a Unicode
directory, okay? So, let's go back to
the Unicode directory.
So, where is this Unicode invert, okay?
So, search for invert.
There. So, here is the JavaScript.
Here's a TypeScript. Make copy of the
TypeScript. Now, let's rename it
uh
to full width.
Okay? So, rename it is our new
file and now
Yeah, open it. So, we're going to So,
let's copyright, okay?
So, here is the code and copy that.
So, here this is the path. Link it.
And remove that, okay? So, we got the
path showing browser. Now, let's
test. Okay, now it doesn't work.
Um
Why is it? Oh, because there's no
JavaScript. Now, we need to compile it.
So, watch the pink window because I have
a Emacs command written.
So, I just call Emacs command. It will
compile the current TypeScript file to
JavaScript. So, I just press
tab C.
Okay? You see
shell command succeeded without output,
okay? So, you can see the command I'm
using is Tsar TypeScript compile file,
okay?
So, you can see now drop to tired. So,
refresh buffer so you can see there is
the JavaScript. Now, go back to the
browser. Refresh. Now, test. Okay, that
doesn't work.
Uh why? Because
Refresh.
Uh
why is my TypeScript not working?
Oh, yeah, because this this this need to
be JavaScript, not TypeScript, okay? So,
JS, okay?
Showing browser. There it is. There it
is.
Fantastic, okay? Now, we just need to
change the JavaScript so that it does
the you know, the
the full-width
uh character instead, okay? So, let's
change it.
So, here is the TypeScript code.
Basically, all we have to do is to
basically, all we have to do is to
change this map, this so-called font
map, okay?
So, that
so that A becomes
full-width A and so on, okay? So, let's
let's let's copy that.
I mean, let's um
delete all of them, so
So, yeah, so you can see
the whole thing is very short.
Uh
Okay, so let let's let's code this. So,
before we have uh remember we have the
map, so let's find it here.
There it is. Here is from Emacs, so we
just
copy this.
Undo
and paste it here, okay? Now, remember
we need to get the
format correct. One is from Emacs, this
here, okay? And
and here is the from JavaScript. So, in
JavaScript, you need a comma between
elements, that's right. So, let's start
to add that.
Change, find replace.
Quote, space, quote, replace replace by
quote,
comma, quote, okay? Do it.
Uh there's a lot full-width characters,
okay? Done.
Okay, so here and uh
okay, then yeah.
Okay, let's clean up this part.
Okay, so 1 2 3 3 sections. Now, this
section we don't need.
Let's just paste it here. Okay.
That's it.
Okay, so now remove these two.
Let's double-check. Okay.
So, we got the digits. We got the
capital letters. We got the lowercase
case letters. Then we got the
punctuation. So, let's put a
Yeah, let's put a separator a new line.
Then
Okay.
Okay, now I want to reformat the whole
file. Right now, this file is
TypeScript. I want to reformat. So,
this, you know, get indented. So, again,
I have a Emacs command that calls the
Deno format command.
So, I just So, watch the pink window.
The command will show there. Okay. So, I
do is just press
tab F.
Okay, we got a error.
Uh yeah, obviously because in JavaScript
you need a comma after each
you know, after each
element in a array. So, let's add that.
Okay.
This is a power of Emacs.
Uh wait. Here do you got a little
problem.
Okay, so
Mhm.
This is another way to do it. You just
added like that. Or you can let's do it
another way. So, find replace, find any
new line character, replace it by comma
new line, okay? So, no yes yes yes,
okay? So, now yes yes yes yes yes yes
yes yes yes, okay?
So, now redundant comma remove.
Good.
Good good. Now, double-check one more
time, okay?
Make sure we got the syntax correct.
Okay, good good good.
Good good good good good. Now, format,
okay?
Tab
F.
Ah.
You got problem. You still got a
problem. What is the problem?
Line 93.
What? Line 93.
Column six, expected
Oh, we missing a comma here.
Okay? Now,
tab F.
Fantastic.
So, you can see the the command the
Emacs command is some JavaScript format
buffer, okay?
Now, you can
find, you know, I don't know if I have
that command available for you online.
Yes, I do, right here. Open it.
There it is, okay? Just copy this and
you you'll have this feature in Emacs.
Auto format your JavaScript or
TypeScript code
in Emacs, okay? Of course, you need to
install Deno.
Okay, so we got this. Now, let's try.
Now, maybe maybe we are done with this,
okay? So, now refresh.
Refresh. Okay, wait. We need to compile
this. Remember? That's a pain with
TypeScript, so
tab C
Compile success.
Back to browser. Refresh. Fantastic.
Fantastic success. That's what we
This is fantastic.
Now, it Oh, there's a There's a problem.
You see, when you do the inverted text,
it actually also inverts reverse the
order.
So, you need You don't want to reverse
order because you can see, for example,
if I say ABC, it becomes CBA.
So, you don't want that to happen. So,
somewhere
uh somewhere the code
Okay, this is annoying. This You see,
I'm using such a JavaScript mod.
So, you see, I'm using such a JavaScript
mod. Everything basically these days
everything in Emacs is written by
myself, almost every mod. So, if you
like my stuff, you can buy it, okay? So,
you can
you know, such a JavaScript mod. You can
you know, just search such a D anything.
You're most likely to find my stuff.
So, pay me if you like it. Pay me, I'll
send it to you.
Okay, but now but we got a problem here.
So, I mean, you know, my actually my
code here there's a syntax coloring
issue because of the quote the double
quote is a very annoying syntax in
programming languages
because they are not matched. Therefore,
um so it's very difficult to parse
correctly. Unlike bracket or
parentheses, there's a match. So, you
know exactly you are missing a right one
or left one. You know, you know exactly
which part is inner text and outer text.
But but with a like double quote
where
the two characters does does not
uh
is the same character. So, you you you
have more problem parsing. Lots of
errors to figure out which one is
inside, which one is outside.
So, anyway
So, it started going wrong about
usually hap- it happens with a slash.
Okay, so let's magnify so you can see
better.
Okay, I think I think it's here. No, uh
here. Okay.
You see?
You see before every string is colored
red.
Okay, but now after
every non-string is red.
Why? Because of this
this because this double quote it
up.
Now, you you know, I can I can do some
change in my Emacs this code to fix
this, but it's you know, it's complex.
So, a work around fix is simply don't
use this line. Okay? So, instead you use
backslash.
There.
So, comment out this line. Now, you see
it's fixed. Now, you see every quote is
red.
Okay?
But
you know, here's a issue about language
syntax design. Very shitty, you know,
the way we the the way traditional
because now if you add a backslash,
now you fix the Emacs coloring problem,
but
but you got this complexity of, you
know, escape. That that's another that's
even a bigger problem, okay? Yeah, but
anyway, but, you know, let's just go
with it.
Let's So, let's focus on the reverse
string, okay? So, here's a function, you
see, one single line function that does
reverse string. So, we don't want to
call it.
Uh where is it called?
Uh I don't find it. It's not called
anywhere.
What?
Why is it not called called?
Oh god.
Uh line 93 still wrong. Space became
comma.
Space became comma.
Uh
really?
Space became
comma.
Uh where was the night light?
I forgot where that was.
Here?
Oh.
Oh, okay. So, it shouldn't happen. Why
So, what's the reason I added that? I
forgot. So, what is this character.
Describe char.
So, this character is ideographic space
and uh describe char.
This is low lie. Oh, okay. So, this part
should be space, right?
It should be space.
So, does this line happen elsewhere? No,
okay. So, thank you.
Thank you that yeah. That's a good
catch.
Deno is really good, but have you heard
of Bun, another JavaScript environment
like Deno? Oh, really? No, I haven't
heard of it.
There's There's so many every
each year there's a several new ones.
No.
But I I like Deno and I you know, in
particular the reason I really like Deno
is because the guy, Ryan Dahl.
He created Javas- He created Node. js,
which is respo- responsible
for making JavaScript ubiquitous, you
know, everywhere because well, also
because the phone, you know, phone. Um
But so, Node.js is a great kind of
innovation, kind of, you know, because
they created you know, it's it's not a
new thing. They created this delayed
How do you call it, you know, the the
Uh what's the name? But they you know,
kind of
Kind uh what's the proper name?
Kind of delayed computing of a function,
so you you can wait for it, pass a
function, then when it's done you call
the function, and meanwhile you do
something else because JavaScript is
single-threaded, which is actually a
good thing. But anyway, Node.js is
great, but it got colluded because of
the guy who took over, who created NPM.
That What What's his name? Um
Isaac. I think he's a scumbag, okay? But
Ryan Dahl is a very great
man I trust. I I I highly respect his
ability. He's He's a mathematician. You
know, he was a PhD graduate,
postgraduate, or something. You know,
studying
some esoteric algebra, you know, thing,
very advanced.
But he But in 2 years he he he started
to code. You know, he created Node.js.
So, that means he mastered C, C++, he's
a just
a genius kind of. Then
so he So, I highly respect the Ryan
Dahl, his coding ability.
And
of course, and also but also he's a
mathematician. He thinks the way the way
he view things, I read, you know, I've
seen his videos, several of them.
He's a great guy, you know, the way he
see things uh
I very much agree with, okay? And he,
you know, the Unix is all you
know, he pretty much says that as well,
you know, the industrial baggage, the
garbage, the C, C++, and Node.js, too.
Anyway, Node.js got corrupted by the NPM
uh Isaac something guy, scum.
So, Ryan Dahl
I respect his coding ability, but also
he's a great person. So, I've you know,
usually I whoever
a person I observe what they did, I look
at their ethical
qualities. More specifically, I look at
into their integrity. Do they lie? Are
they scums? Do they lie Do they do
things to get just to promote to get
themselves ahead? Like, "Oh, I respect
women. Oh, I I think trans should be
something. I think patriarchy. This
scums like the Guido van Rossum,
okay?
You know,
so anyway, so I highly respect the
Node.js, the Ryan Dahl guy, and he
created Node.js to fix the problems he
thought he, you know, he when he created
Node.js.
You know, you know, so
So, yeah. So, I I don't know the new one
fun. Anyway, so today we actually we did
So, yeah, one more last bug to fix is
that where is this
code?
Um
So, let's see what what the code does,
okay? So, so you have a function update.
First of all, the update function gets
the input text.
Uh so, the, you know, here's the input
box. The update function get the input
text.
Then
invert map, which convert it to the, you
know, invert map is this thing. Convert
to the full
full uh width text. Then, okay, so
invert map.
So, let's start to rename variables
because I like to
uh
let's use my new convention, X.
Okay. So, now you got, you know, any
variable starting with X become
highlighted as a local variable. So, the
text array
Oh, so text array. So, here is where you
um let's see. Let's add some lines so
it's more legible.
Uh so, text array. What's text array?
Text array is the you split.
Okay, basically you turn the string into
a array, okay? Now, it's 2023. There's a
better way to do this.
You know, the way I do it
turning a string into a array where each
character is a character is a element.
There's a better way to do it now. Uh
and and the way to do it is you just say
Uh you don't you don't use regular
expression anymore. So, a better way to
do it is just um
that, okay?
Okay, so so so instead so let let's try
it, okay? New file, save it XX
date JavaScript.
Okay? Then, let's
uh let's
Let's the text is let's say ABCD, okay?
Now,
print
XX. Run it.
You see?
Improved code, the mastery of
JavaScript.
Delete that.
Okay, wait. What wait what?
Uh yeah, so here so here's a better way
to do it. Now, let's rename this text
array to to my new convention.
Okay?
So, text array is just array of strings,
okay? Then, you map
So, new array, let's rename it to
Okay, so new array equals to you map a
function for each
for each of X full with map, so
you
if they are the same,
you return the value, otherwise, you
return X.
Okay? Then, oh, reverse.
Okay, here. Here is the reverse thing.
Oh, I see. So, you see this function
this function we wrote, reverse string,
is actually never used. It's redundant
because because we are just using
because we turn the string into a array.
So,
so so for array, there's a reverse. So,
so all we have to do is now remove the
call of reverse. Okay? Now,
watch the pink window.
Okay?
Tap F to format the code, then tap C to
Wait, wait. Wait, something went went
wrong.
Uh
Wait, my
What?
Tap F format,
and it up. Oh,
You know, when you do you know, let's go
back. Another issue. See you see, we are
you see here.
You see, we are using this syntax,
backslash, to represent the
to escape the double quote.
Okay, but if you do
if you call demo demo format,
it will change that to
you know, if
it will revert that to this standardized
syntax without the escape.
Uh so, you got you know, you got screwed
in either way. So, but if you do this,
then then the Emacs coloring got
up. Okay,
we can fix that by just
Uh yeah, just add that's my Emac Emac
JavaScript
mod. Anyway, so here. So, okay. Now, we
tab C to format it. Tab F to format it.
Tab C to compile it.
Command success success without output.
Okay. Now, go back to browser. Refresh.
Fan
tastic. Now, you see it's full width
including
all
caps.
Including
the
exclamation.
Fantastic.
Thank you guys for watching.
If you put the second code in double
quotes instead of single quote, it
should work. Does it?
Okay, I'm going to take your words.
Let's see.
If you put the escape code in double
quotes instead of
Oh, okay.
Now, I think it still changes. Let's
try, okay?
Okay. Now, let's tab F 10. Now, you see?
I know this because I've tried it
before.
Okay. Done. So, 90 minutes today. Thank
you guys for watching. There was great
questions and uh
yeah, great.
Bye, guys.
Ah.