good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
so today we are going to talk about
javascript we are going to live code
javascript and we are going to uh
talk about unicode unicode and emoji uh
and font uh you know some technical
issues about unicode and font so let's
start quickly so i'm using emacs i'm
using sapphire keys
and on the pink window you can see all
my emacs command cores uh such as move
cursor or the keystrokes you can also
see it on the pink window
basically every emax command icon will
show up there and today is 2021
november 19th
yeah
so okay so so let's let's uh let's focus
on what we're gonna do uh
pretty much technical okay so if you
have questions and comments
uh
post it okay
so let me check one more time i'm uh i'm
doing a live um
video check audio check
okay
good to go so this is my keyboard this
is kinesis advantage 2
and this is ultimate hacking keyboard
and this is this is logitech 504 or
something five five zero two
fantastic with a spin wheel i
uh demonstrated many times okay let's
begin so uh
do i have a video problem concurrent
viewers one
it should be more there okay so we so
what we're gonna do so
topic javascript
write javascript to change font symbol
versus emoji font okay explain what's
going on
and explain the technical unicode
solution and explain the practical
solution and create a
um
create a problem from scratch
demonstrate effective font
with css okay so what is the problem so
first of all uh the probably problem the
problem is this okay so
uh hello good morning voldemort
so the problem is is this some unicode
uh okay so so
so okay so you you can see it let me
show you where you can see it easy so
unicode animals insects
uh plants sports uh astrology there okay
so you can see this page
unicode astrology or astronomy symbols
you see all these colored ones are emoji
you know they are shown as emoji but
however some of them are not shown as
emoji for example this one
for example this moon you know some you
know then some of them are not emojis
some of them are for example here
planets you know you got emoji emoji
there but not this one and not the
others so why is that so the reason that
happens is because let's copy that here
and let's paste um to today's talk show
so we have a record what of what we
talked about astrology symbols okay
so what is going on so the
the reason i talked about uh yesterday
is because
so here is the article so um
symbols becomes emoji so around year i
forgot i don't remember what year 19
i mean
2010 or maybe somewhere around there
unicode consortium the organization
behind unicode they decided that they
are going to merge emoji with symbols
so for example
for example arrow okay so
okay let's copy this character okay copy
left right arrow okay uh unicode
hexadecimal 2194 okay left right arrow
let's copy that and let's show that in
emax magnify
so you can see this is the actual symbol
this is not shown as emoji
okay so put a cursor here called
describe char and you can see the full
detail about the character
on on this panel okay so let's make it
larger so
so you can see the code point is 8596
and the
hexadecimal is 2194 okay and the
character name
is here
left right arrow so let me turn on
global highlight mod so you can see
where my cursor is okay so this is a
character but sometimes it's shown as
emoji sometimes as a
symbol so let me let me let me
demonstrate okay
so let's create a new page
create a new page okay
and magnify and let's say
um
html
okay
create a template here
so
title will be
test unicode
okay
uh copy that title and
here we have a character of unicode okay
now let's put a span
okay uh span uh in the style
let's say
okay font
uh family so
i mean i'm gonna demonstrate some of the
issues here so far family so show this
in browser okay save it
test
uh
just a random name okay save the file so
here is a file show in browser you can
see there is that unicode
character okay
um
hold on a second
so
so let's add some
let's add some um
okay so
switch to
css mod
font family okay then
[Music]
okay let's go back to talk show because
i want to grab some
css templates so
so why don't we copy that because that's
what we
need
okay so switch back here so let's add
some
uh css okay so let's see style
let's see not style
class
uh
emoji
okay let's go we are going to show the
same file
i mean the same same character with
different font okay
symbol so one is symbol one is emoji
different class so let's create a css
here
symbol okay
then the other one is emoji
and
and the font family is what we need okay
so font size two
uh
okay so this is what it's going to be
then emoji
so we have
two classes one is simple one is emoji
so emoji we will use the font circle ui
emoji that's a default microsoft emoji
font or apple color emoji or noto color
emoji nota is
google's emoji okay let's say character
size five font size five
font size two
actually
uh let's say body
we want everything from size two okay so
we don't need this font size confusing
confusion
so okay
so body
font size 2 iem
iem means the default font size so twice
as large
then
anything class symbol use the circle ui
symbol or apple symbol emoji i mean the
font
then if it's emoji class use the emoji
font okay now show in browser so you can
see
you can see there
that
the first one
is using
symbol font
the second one is using
emoji font showing browser so see that's
the difference this is very annoying
because
when you write
you know when you write mathematics or
uh you know math or whatever
some of the charac for example some of
the characters all of a sudden become
emoji and you cannot predict which one
it is for example if you write a lot of
mathematics you know uh arrow double
sign or summation and and you know math
formula
some of them will become emoji like
colored you know
uh
dramatic is you know that's not good
you know if you are writing a serious
series
serious documentation for example i'm
writing about keyboards so i'm saying
you know keyboard has these labels you
know these icons to indicate multimedia
keys then next year when i look at my
document again on the web it suddenly
become these you know speaker
pictures you know that's not good so why
does this happen because unicode decided
around i don't know i don't remember
what year around 2010 2012 they decided
to emerge to merge
they decided not too much i mean to have
one single character
to represent
both emoji
situation or the symbol situation they
decided to do that you know just one
single character because
after all it's the same character
you know this for example this uh left
right arrow it's the same character they
decided to kind of condense it just have
one simple representation so unicorn
says you know so and and in practice
this is very bad because it becomes very
complex and very confusing you know
people don't want that
typically when you want to use emoji
you know typically it's used on social
media you know by
often girls you know they like these
kind of picture stuff
uh they you know so that's one
uh situation of using emoji but when you
are you know mathematician or or
programmers you know usually you don't
want the emoji you don't want them mixed
you don't want
unpredictability okay
so this is what happened in unicode
unicode consortium you know made this
decision and it turns out to be a bad
mistake
so that is why
that is why when we uh for example when
we
when we go to uh for example let me show
you okay actually let's go to this page
i'm explaining what's what is the
problem okay so if you look at this page
you scroll down
scroll down
you see
so unicode says so so here's a technique
called detail what uh unicode consortium
actually says
hello cortes thank you
fantastic thank you cortes hello andrew
um i know you are going to talking about
kr
no
uh this is gonna be uh yeah unicode and
uh unicode and javascript today
so
so let me give you the technical detail
of
of what the unicode spec unicorn
consortium says about when should a
character be a symbol or when should be
a emoji
so
so um
so unicode says
unicode says that certain characters
here's what unicode says unicode
consortium they say
some characters they can be both emoji
or symbol okay emoji or text i should
say a symbol here so some characters can
be both emoji or
symbol but however they should default
to emoji
so if you don't have
you know you don't say what you know if
you don't specify what it
should be symbol or emoji then it should
default to emoji for a certain group of
characters they can be both
now for other group of characters
they can be both emoji or symbol but
they default to text okay they default
to symbol symbols okay
actually let me show you the difference
okay so you you see i created this uh
javascript yesterday so let me click on
that you can see you now watch watch
this section okay watch this section
all right click on symbol
now you can see
this is how they look like let's focus
on one of them let's see the
you know the neutral face and the alien
face okay so you see
now i click on emoji
you see they look different now look at
this one snowboarder okay
symbol
it looks like that
snowboarder okay you you can see the
emoji version in the pop-up
okay so the symbol version version
versus versus emoji let's let's magnify
to see the full glory of these
uh symbol versus emoji thing see
so
so this is a problem so unicorn says
some characters can be both
um and uh they you know this group of
characters they should default to emoji
display that is if you just paste the
character in text editors or in twitter
or in
discord you know according to unicode
consortium they say then
this group group of characters they
should by default display this emoji
now this group however they say
they should by default displays
displayed as
symbol okay this group so it's very
confusing how the fact do i know you
know which actually which character is
which
you know very confusing and very complex
but this is what the specification says
okay then there's another group
this group of characters they are always
emoji there's no
symbol representation there's no text
representation they are just always
emoji okay
so that that is what the unicorn says
okay that's a unicorn specification and
so when you have a character
but you do want to show it as let's say
emoji or symbol how do you specify it
according to unicode consortium
you specify it by
by adding
adding a invisible character immediately
after that character and this invisible
character is called unicode variation
selector you know it's it's very complex
so
so there are two you know two of these
in invisible
characters one is uh called variation
selector 15
and the other one is variation selector
16.
so if you use if you have a this
variation selector 15 invisible
character right after
one of these emoji or symbol character
then it means
by the unicode spec
that should
the application should display that
emoji character a symbol okay
and likewise for the variation selector
16 so very complex
so if you want the emoji you know
for example this alien head you know
depending on
let's pick something more um
suitable for writing for example this uh
left pointing magnifying glass you know
it's pretty common you see that in
keyboard
uh you know for example google chrome
google books you'll have you know the
caps lock position usually have that
symbol let me show you
um
so let's start
browsers
sorry.info
hello hello
money hello money
voted more thank you thank you very much
so um
so
so i'm going to go so you go to kusar
keyboard so here is my keyboard page you
have reviews all of all these keyboard
okay and
including the kinesis i'm using and
automatic hacking keyboard there's full
review and video review there so you go
to keyboard section then you go to the
laptop section let me shrink so
you go to the laptop section
and you have this page on chromebook
keyboards so this is my documentation of
chrome
you know google chrome keyboard
so you can see on this caps lock
location typical cap slot location you
can see that
magnifying glass
okay and same thing with the google
pixel uh
book hardware you see magnaflow in glass
and if you are uh suppose you are
writing a documentation you know for
you know for for your cooperation
industry or whatever you know space
aerospace industry or whatever you you
need to document the keyboard you know
suppose you know
and you see this keyboard has many of
these these symbols
so you don't want your documentation to
show them as emoji that's not suitable
you know
so for example that's you know i'm
talking about here you don't want
those symbols to show us emoji
okay
you know you are writing uh
you know for example documentation of
keyboard which i have done a lot let me
show you where
so uh design of computer keyboards
and
then uh
design of computer keyboards computer
keys
you know we here i talked about each key
and uh sometimes also their history
modifier keys control alt windows where
did they come from control key you know
where is it positions on position on the
keyboard the menu key where does it come
from who invented it you know the old
graph key compose key that key what are
they what what do they do
and spacebar why is it so big you know
who who
what which idiot event you know
thought that spacebar should be long and
you know and so on so this page this
collection of articles discuss the
um
keys you know you know their history or
their
optimal placement or their function what
they do and so on
escape key why is it called escape where
does it come from you know which year
so so then you have a section on uh
shortcut note notations for example this
is apple's documentation of keyboard
shortcut keys and the symbol they use
for shortcut keys so so if you are you
know a dark writer at apple
you want these to be symbols you don't
want them you know like some of them
become emoji so that's
so that's
my explanation why this is important
issue okay
about the emoji versus uh symbols
so according to unicode consortium when
you want to
when when you want these symbols to you
know to be actually just symbol and not
emoji you need to add a invisible
character
right after them you know
you know so so very complex this one
up the unicode
unicode consortium in my opinion they
have become corrupted
starting around let's say early 2010s
you know they become
you know they become this
standard
organization basically
revolving around money you know
they become you know not
useful you know 20 30 years ago
unicode is
significant to
technology to human animals technology
because they created a encoding system
they created a system so that
so that we can write in any language any
human language in the past or in
or today you know even including dead
languages
that uh that
that um
you know you can write using a
consistent way so i talked about
uh you know
hieroglyph you know latin greek you know
and chinese and japanese and korean and
so on so for example let me let me show
some of them so
so you have
acrylic for example a russian alphabet
you can write chinese you know with
unicode
then of course japanese
and uh
korean
arabic as well including other languages
such as uh ethiopia if ethiopia you know
the
kind of on the
african continent on the east side of
african continent yeah there's a map
showing you where ethiopia ethiopia is
so you can write all these languages and
hindu you know indian uh languages
with unicode so 30 years ago unicode is
a great invention it is significant um
technology
but today
today's unicode you know since i would
say around 2010 they become
kind of corrupt the organization unicode
consortium so all they do today is
basically mostly okay all they do today
is mostly
talking about emoji like oh we need
another emoji character for
for banana we already have a banana but
today's unicorn is mostly like that
some people may not agree because i've
talked to some of the
i believe you know some of the people
who either works
works at unicode consortium or
uh deeply you know doing work with
unicode for example adobe i know a guy
from adobe he wrote the book
on unicode for example let me show you
uh do i still have his um
picture no i removed the anyway so i
talked to people who work with unicode
um and they you know
they do not
necessarily agree at least some of them
do not agree with with my view they say
they will say oh unicorn is still
important because there are still
uh quite a few languages
that doesn't have unicode representation
like
long-time debt nobody's you know dead
languages that
very you know it's only interest
you know it's only of interest to a
handful of academics linguistics you
know
so they say oh unicorn unicorn
consortium is still important because
they are still these languages that's
not
they don't have a unicorn representation
yet
yeah that's true but you know that's a
very minor small academic you know
community you know 1 000 people you know
so you know but but meanwhile unicode
today is all talking about just uh kind
of emoji and they make it they
make the unicode they corrupt the
unicode they make it worse and worse for
example the issue we are talking about
the emoji suddenly becomes
symbol suddenly becoming emoji that's
the problem they created unicode created
that problem it probably didn't exist
but they
you know around 2010 also they they made
it so that's my criticism of the unicode
consortium i don't think they are a good
organization anymore just like many
just like
most i would claim most of the standard
technical organization bodies they are
they became corrupt for example for
example w3c is another example you know
the web standard organization and before
that then you know then you have the
unix ifc you know that's all
in my opinion uh
not good
so anyway a little bit digression let's
go back to uh so let's go back to uh
what we are talking about the yeah so
the
so this is what unicode consortium you
know say about this issue
okay so so far we covered that's the
technical aspect that's what the unicorn
spec says what should be but in practice
in reality
nothing nobody does this okay
so according to the unicode consortium
if you want a symbol to be represented
as a symbol and not emoji you add a you
know invisible character variation 15
behind after it
and if you want to be displayed as emoji
you add this character behind it you
know invisible character nobody you know
very few people do do that
but however even if you follow the
unicode consortium way it doesn't work
okay let me i can actually show you
right now um
[Music]
yeah it takes some time to show because
i need to i need to actually type this
character this
you know that's how difficult it is okay
so let me first of all show you this
page okay so now let's try to add this
invisible character okay so one of the
invisible character is this one okay let
me see if i can add it here
uh hold on a second show empty space
do it there it is okay so this
so let's uh copy that okay copy that so
paste it here
let's remove the class
okay
so this one is
supposed to
be displayed
as symbol
okay and this one's supposed to be
displayed as emoji
okay and how because
we copy this invisible symbol let's
let's magnify okay so you can actually
see so there is this invisible character
f e
0 e so we
cut it
we
paste it here right after that unicode
you know so it should force this unicode
to be displayed as a symbol okay
now
for the other one
so let's
copy that so for this one
let's put this character let's do it so
i
how did i do it you know i just
converted a
hexadecimal i just converted a
hexadecimal
uh
notation
to the actual unicode how do i do that
how did i do that that's uh from a xl
emacs mod okay so here's the source code
go to the bottom 1000 lines of code and
here is the url you can
go and you can buy it so this is the
emacs package that allows you to display
allows you to type many of the unicode
so you can type a unicode by a shortcut
or you can type a unicode by converting
from decimal or hexadecimal of the
unicode's
id
code point okay so so that is the
emax
input mod okay
so um close that close that let's go to
talk show let's
add add the link so we have a record of
what we talked about
okay now back to uh
back to this okay so
so now we
did that
okay now let's put this here let's make
a list okay now show in browser
so you can see
we followed the unicode consortium spec
so it didn't work you see
this symbol now is still displayed as
emoji i mean it's not displayed as emoji
both of them are displayed as a symbol
it doesn't work
okay same thing if you post this on
twitter or discord it doesn't work no
essentially in practice nobody
respect
this unicorn specification you know it's
because it's one up you know
complexity nobody
follows it so it's a very bad
specification you know you know the
unicode people made a mistake
uh with this um kind of thing
okay so that is about this issue unicode
symbol become emoji so we have covered
that so
and we have
talked about what is the issue and we
also talked about what does unicode
specification say
how it should be
very complex okay
so now let me talk about what what is
actually happening in practice in
practice whether a character is
displayed as a symbol or as a emoji it
just depends on the font which font you
are using and and that's also very
complex for example
we have shown here
you know
let's remove the
the space
display of space okay so for example you
know we have this
you know the symbol class whatever
whenever something is simple class we
use
circle ui symbol or apple symbol as the
font okay then whenever you have emoji
we use you know emoji font
so
that
actually works so that's the most
important you know that's
so if if this is uh
what happens in reality in real world
this is in practice okay so if you are
writing a website a blog
this is what you want to do when you
want a symbol to be displayed as a
symbol you you know use the symbol font
specify a symbol font now that's one
aspect of what happens in practice
so what about on twitter for example on
twitter
um
yeah so let's go to twitter
let's go through some profile what i
posted so on twitter let's say i want to
tweet something something new so
on twitter you don't you know you you
are not allowed to specify what the font
it is you know you just paste it you see
it shows you know it just shows as a
emoji already
so
so if you post it let's see okay so
actually let me um post it
following this my talk show announcement
um
wait not that one that's yesterday so
today
yeah so reply to that paste it here
tweet
okay and click on that open that you see
it shows us emoji
so
so in practice what actually happens
with twitter or facebook or or discord
most of this platform
is that
is that whenever you have a character
okay so let's go to the page
whenever you have one of these character
that
according to the unicode that can be
both symbol or emoji
on twitter they will always just show it
as emoji period you know they
they will just do that but actually not
all of them you know it's like for you
know so this this is why it's the
completely up
it's completely unpredictable
because for some some characters i'm
pretty sure twitter does not show them
as emoji
for example let me let me do this okay
so let's switch to the symbol font
so
for example let's let's paste some of
these okay all these
can be both emoji
and or symbol but according to unicode
by default they should be text
so if we go to twitter reply paste
show
okay
you can see some of them are displayed
as text as not emoji okay
that is a problem
uh so you become complete completely
unpredictable you know it's a
huge mess
but anyway
back to you know if you are writing a
blog
or documentation the best way to control
this
is via font okay just specify your phone
for it okay that that concludes part of
the talk now let's
now let's do some javascript what i want
to do is
to you see this button you know show us
emoji show a symbol what they do is that
they actually change the you know they
modify
the
the javascript modify the class name so
they switch basically switch the font
specification so i want to write that
function to for example here
so let me show you how to do that okay
so let me show you okay so yeah so let's
let's let me show you how to do that
create a new page
save us access
date
emoji okay let's say
html okay
now
insert the template this is html mod on
my website you can pay me to get it for
emacs
so
let's say test emoji okay
now let's just copy one a bunch of these
here
paste it here
so we don't want the you know the
this font become you know this first two
emoji is very interesting because they
are the very first emoji they came from
emoticon we talked about yesterday
any comments questions nobody
okay you um
okay so we so let's do this okay so i
want to
uh so this so i want to write the
application that changes emoji
changes changes the font specification
so
okay so so let's do um
let's let's just say so let's just say
that okay
let's just say that
class
equals to
uh
x
okay what
okay just a class name then here
style
a class
found
it's not say anything okay
so here
i don't even need class let's
let's do nothing okay show in browser
okay so i want to i need to make it
large
css mod
magnify
font size
okay 30 pixels okay cut
paste it here
showing browser fantastic
let's say 40 pixels showing browser
fantastic
now
now i want to we need to add a button
okay
let's say use symbol font okay so this
here is one button
okay and
shrink
and another button
okay
add them showing browser so we got two
buttons use symbol font use emoji font
right now they don't have any action so
now we are going to go into entire
action to them so javascript
so copy the file path you know we are
going to add this javascript create this
javascript file okay so first of all
link it
okay then
press enter
it will ask me your say file doesn't
exist created yes okay so here is the
javascript
now
now let's go back let's
see what is id okay so
document get element by id okay
uh
and that id is that okay constant
let's do this constant that
shrink
okay so that's one
and the other one is
so we got two buttons here okay
so now
elements okay we got the element button
now we need to add event okay so
add event
listener okay add event listener
click
so when people click on that element you
call a function
set
symbol font okay call that function okay
and add another event
so button emoji
is a html element
called the method add event listener so
when that event
when people click on that you want code
a function
okay called this function so now we need
to define the function okay
so
why don't we define the function in
front okay so
constant arrow function
so here we define a constant f6 set
symbol font okay so here we want to set
the font
uh so how do you write the function so
when
when user click it you want okay so here
is the argument which is event
then here is what to do okay so
when people click on that you want to
select
you want to select it's not let's let's
give it this an id okay so let's say id
okay so this id
uh
there okay so that's a syntax for
css for
specifying that this
any element with this id
using the palette sign or say you know
that's a syntax to mean id
so if element has that id then font size
40 so
so that is
so that is that
so now this element this paragraph
element has the id
that okay so now we say
get element by id
okay
so we get that element and we need a
document document get element by id so
once we get that element
we say
okay
uh here's
so constant
element
then
this element dot style
equals true
okay now we need to specify font
family now how do you spell circle ui so
circle ui so let's let's just say that
yeah that's uh that's it
okay here is the javascript now let's
reformat the whole
let's show the pink window
call it
that's it format it okay now we need
another function to
change to emoji font
so what is uh
what what is a
font name for
emoji
there circle ui emoji since i'm on i'm
on microsoft windows i don't need to
worry about apple for now just
demonstrate this
okay
so
so this is the javascript code i think
it should work
so in summary we get the element of the
buttons here these two buttons okay
then we define two functions
when you know it
the function will first of all grab this
element by id
then
basically set the style attribute to the
font family circle ui symbol
similarly for the the other function
and then we add the event to the button
so when the buttons are clicked
these functions will be called okay so
let's
close this
showing browser again refresh now let's
see if it works
use symbol font click
fantastic
use emoji font click fantastic okay
so this is what we set out to do and uh
you know the demonstration that works
fantastic i think that's it for today
nobody is here okay fantastic any
questions any comments i think yeah we i
think uh
yeah let's let's let that just be it
that's it for today
we talked for
47 minutes about 40 45 minutes already
so
any any questions
okay no questions we're gonna shut down
in two minutes
okay we're gonna shut down in two
minutes so today we talked about the
emoji versus symbols issue and a little
bit javascript
so you see a little bit javascript so
you guys if you are learning javascript
let me show you my just search for
javascript tutorial okay
javascript in depth
yeah that that that guy took over my
website so this is my website javascript
in depth
so this is a complete
tutorial and reference on javascript
and also including dom
so if you like my stuff buy it okay
thank you guys
thank you for watching
bye