good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of
star talk show you are watching today is
and today is may 29th and you can see my
date on the upper right corner of the
screen
and today and uh and uh you see this
tax task bar on top that's uh
you know i think that's fantastic you
know
this is about user interface design you
know you're wondering
you're wondering um the taskbar
which position is optimal
as a user interface design issue
you know whether you know normally it's
at the bottom but
you can place it on the right for
example you right click
and go to taskbar
settings then you can choose the
position so normally is
at the bottom and you can choose on the
right
you know on the right or you can choose
on the left
you know i first about this all the time
you know especially on linux um
you know i never came to a decision
which
is better i mean one thing for sure is
that if you have you know as modern
days you know if you have a larger
monitor white monitor
then on the side is not so good because
then you have to
like turn your head all the way uh all
the time
but if you are on a smaller screen
on the side is optimal yeah that i
i'm pretty sure but now i tried um you
know on the top
you know someone square root told me to
try that and i think that's a
pretty good anyway that's uh good
morning
benjamin from australia okay so what
are we going to talk today uh it's going
to be random okay so random i don't know
what i'm talking about
but you know keep talking that's a key
to success
[Laughter]
you don't know what you're talking about
but keep talking okay
okay when you adjust the taskbar it's
screwed
it screwed up your window positions okay
so if you have questions post it okay
and ching
put money in my pocket uh
senza from taiwan good morning censor
and okay so what are we going to do so
i'm thinking the first 10 minutes
i'm let's do some random emacs stuff
uh emac this coding then we are going to
migrate
to keyboards and stuff okay speaking of
keyboard you are looking at
of course you are looking at my hands
with these
fingers i'm going to rule the world
okay that's why i tell you to be a
programmer guys
study programming studying mathematics
well
if you study math there's not actually
traditional mathematicians they don't
give a [ __ ]
about coding okay they think that's
that's inferior but
as you know these days there are a lot
um
mathematicians a different kind of crowd
they you know they do proof systems
programming [ __ ] you know
uh cog uh actually so
uh okay this is wrong [ __ ]
language okay there's a language
uh proof assistant this is uh probably
the most
popular programming language uh
for doing proofs mathematical proofs
you know it used to know these kind of
systems used to be known as um
you know search for automated proof
systems
but uh it turns out after 50 years of
study research
that automated proof proof theory
improvers are kind of a pipe dream
it's not uh possible
uh lots of foundational issues you know
that's uh
that's what's interesting about logic
the deep
you know the deep space of logic
so they they so these days all the tools
are called proof assistant
okay i'm digressing okay so anyway so
you yeah
so code you know learn programming okay
that's a good thing
for today and for the future as well
uh so what are we doing so nothing i
don't know okay so let's look at the
topics
saw talk show topic notes some of the
things i can um
you know some some of the things that's
to do for me uh
okay so oh by the way so you're looking
at my keyboard so let me show you so
this is kinesis keyboard this one
kinesis advantage
2 and this is a silent
red linear switch that's fantastic okay
brown switch and red switch linear
switch versus
tactile switch linear is better if you
have any sort of repetitive strain
injury issues
because linear switch let me tell you
linear switch is
um can we can we put the
camera two more to the right uh let's
see
yeah anyway let's not touch it so linear
switches but
is makes it makes a huge difference okay
because i have been using this keyboard
kinesis advantage too
starting with okay let's show you let's
talk about keyboards okay
keyboards first stop
uh okay uh keyboards are keyboard blog
and lots of stuff so i'm gonna talk
random today so
you see kinesis advantage to keyboard
that's what i have
i've been using this keyboard since
2016.
so i used you know up to now for four
and five years
and i still have prob you know i it
turns out you know
not because of this keyboard but i had
repetitive repetitive strain injury
issues
with my left hand so
and eventually and so anyway so anyway
so
so this one i have from 2016
it was a uh given to me by the company
kinesis
for my review and i loved it but however
that was a brown switch
uh and it turns out the linear switch
the switch type makes a great difference
so this year 2021 this year about three
months ago
i talked about like i bought i bought
this one 350
you know i bought another one so linear
red switches
so i'm going to sell my old one actually
uh for how much
you know so a new one this new one is
going to be 340
okay you go buy it
uh so i guess i'm going to sell my old
one so let me say this
if you are in if you come by
pick it up i'll give it to you for
250 dollars so if you are in mountain
view area you know
talk to me and we can do that um
yeah 250 dollars uh in
perfect con condition okay well i i used
it for four years but it's still
uh perfect that's a brown switch
uh right now i'm on red switch red
switch is
uh critical if you have rsi issues
okay so that's that then then of course
the other keyboard is ultimate hacking
keyboard do i need to show it i showed
you
i showed it many times so yeah you can
see
i have all the reviews on my website
and i've been working on keyboards a lot
a lot of
updates so let's go to let's go to uh
keyboard okay
so any any comments questions why bing
is a good
search engine not no uh because
so why am i using bing uh let's see
something okay why am i using being of
course i don't
want to you know let me tell you the
reason so
we you know most of us use google chrome
google
you know google search engine right so
starting about three years ago
google becomes an evil empire
cannot be trusted so that's why i
switched
to um that's why i switched
to uh go okay so for example i have i
have lots of browsers
so you can see if i turn off my browser
for example search for
for here k-i-n-e-s-i-s
advantage okay you see
the default search engine is stuck to go
now
let's see if they show my my page first
no what the [ __ ] should have
can you say advantage uh
true keyboard okay hold on a second
you know my page should come up first
but
okay but since then lots of these
you know these um commercial entities
they do seo scam kind of thing
okay
uh what
okay so you see look so i i use doctor
go okay
starting about three years ago copy okay
select
all copy now let's search let's try
google okay
new google.com
now on google my page should come up at
least
on the first page i think
so anyway turk the gold
is starting to suck you know it it um
it does not give you the best
results anyway doctor go is a meta
engine it uses it
actually uses google um
you know so for example the
result here for kinesis advantage 2
keyboard is actually
better than dr go i think you know on dr
go you know you have
quite a few amazon
you know pages
okay i'm pissed my webpage is not
showing up on the first page
uh advantage
two
yeah no okay let's see next
not on the second page too neither
what the [ __ ] okay anyway that's uh
so anyway doctor go is not that good
it's
it's okay but it's not that good so
since i i'm using uh microsoft i mean
i'm using the edge browser so why not
just give it a try
that that is all okay so what
what are we going to do so let's go back
to the let's
let's let's go back to let's
let me code i want to do some coding
okay so let's do emac this
first seven people watching okay
um
html youtube linkify
um youtube link if i
add okay add youtube linkify to casa
emacs blog
okay we can do that uh and what is this
to do put to my website at url to talk
show
site gmail local links to full path
okay so those are two functions
and
okay i don't know i don't know what i'm
doing i'm not
um
okay yeah so so let's let's do some emac
first so
let me let me start to read it for for
real okay
so modify html youtube to text
so the url is not tu.b okay
nah i'm not gonna do that now because i
html td tag pair add to web page okay
that we should do um
to the tag pair okay so that one we want
to do
i want to do then create
emacs distro uh okay not today we
did i did a video two weeks ago about
that starting to do that
because html youtube linkify okay add
that too
okay so let's let's put all the
tasks that's about putting emacs
commands
to my website together okay
so this one put to my website add url to
talk show
oh okay so there are two things website
html local links to full paths
html local links to relative path okay
okay so i can do that
delete do that that that that
that that that that that that
that that that
okay what's this one add somewhere rob
pike and richard stolman okay that's a
good story let me
uh so you guys may want to go read it
so this is a story from rob pike rob
pike
is the unix is a unix promoter it's a
he's a unix phonetic he's one of the
pillar of the unix operating system
and he is also the creator of golan
so he wrote you know he this is once one
of his blog
2006 2006
telling the story about an encounter
with richard stowman
so basically you know you you go you go
read it so this is an interesting story
i wanted to put this on my emacs blog
somewhere so this is my notes to do
okay um you know as you know richard
strowman is a
free software foundation fanatic he's
anti-commercialization anti
uh he's a communist basically
so to do ad somewhere why long
options start with two dashes okay this
is another good story
this one i haven't read actually but i
believe it's a good one
so this one is about you know how unix
shell
you know how unique shell okay i'm not
on linux now so
uh how you know how unique shell you
have two dash
glue versions of shell two or smash for
example bastion
uh not bash but well yeah bash to bash
and emax everything
from the gnu project they they created
two
dash syntax for options
so this guy tells the story let's see
uh okay yeah so this guy tells a story
why do long options you know i have my
own stories to tell okay so let me show
you
my article first i have to read this one
though
let's read it so around 1990 richard
stowman
and i were writing the gnu c library
get opt and he wanted to extend it to
support
long multi-character option names for
user friendlies okay
so this is probably a very good account
because he
you know this is from the dragon's mouth
you know
from a person involved with it in
history so he's telling
you the origin i guess
okay so i'm gonna i'm gonna this is
something i want to read but
but you know that's part of the you know
this all
this is a part of the unix philosophy
uh crap unix philosophy crap okay
so let me let me mention that again unix
philosophy
the nature of unix philosophy
uh
okay so unix philosophy the nature of
unix philosophy
you know it's um it's a coat it's a
garbage it's a crap
okay so
uh actually the article is not this one
it's not this one i'm looking for i'm
looking for another article
uh let's find it okay so
that would be let me think okay hold on
a second i think
since i'm not coding now let's put the
camera to my face
maybe
okay hold on a second
so far so good what are you guys
doing
um
okay the unix philosophy so i'm trying
to find the article where i discuss the
uh yeah unix the unix type as functional
language
okay so once i know the topic
you can easily find it hacker code
hacker code and this is part of the
syntax
soup here
and here and let's turn on javascript
turn it on so you can see my past videos
the
screenshot so the unix pipe dot notation
post fixed notation you know the
programming language
syntax is my obsession
unix pipes pipe as functional language i
talked about this many times
so this article discuss the complete
idiocy of the unix uh shell syntax okay
complete idiocy
so okay i'm not going to go over
you can just read the article yourself
okay so it's
extremely inconsistent it's one [ __ ]
[ __ ]
[ __ ] up no design crap uh
but you know but so over the years so
this is about the history or the
evolution
of the unix xiao syntax
okay there's actually certain some
change
not you know there are certain changes
over the past
30 years beginning for example gnu
double dash
syntax 1990s beginning around 1990s gnu
richard stollman he introduced the
double dash
so that you have you know long long
option names
which is a an attempt to fix
the unix crap the unique shell garbage
okay so that's 1990s richard shulman
tried to do that
so you might think you know so i back
then i was very much
for richard stroman i was a free
software fanatic okay because
i talked about many times so
um so double dash
so back then i believe you know so since
we have this double dash
you know unix should let's let's all
you know uh hop on into this new syntax
so it's more
so you have clarity you know when you
read a unix command you don't have a
bunch of garbage
you have clarity you have a full option
names and
there's a complaint by the hacker types
you know oh it's too long to type
well the proper way to solve that is by
abbreviations so you can type something
auto completion okay
like auto completion today everyone is
familiar you guys right
when you install emacs you say oh i need
this autocomplete
company mod you know auto complete yeah
auto complete completion okay
you know open source and unix people
usually
when there's some technology that's good
they refuse
to adopt it until like 5
or 10 or 20 years later that's the case
with the auto completion
because they think you know back then
you know you if you mention
auto completion to the emacs people
they'll laugh
they'll laugh and ridicule your these
emacs
[ __ ] you know because they they
they think they are real programmers you
don't need auto completion you don't
need syntax highlighting
yes that's true you know if you are
young you don't know
back in 1990s when syntax highlighting
was introduced
by you know by the commercial commercial
organizations like the commercial
editors
uh i forgot the name you know pascal and
whatever the e-max refused it
okay the xe max people embraced it but
emacs refused it
until after 10 years 10
until around 2004 15 years
when everyone everyone else has syntax
coloring you know syntax highlighting in
in buffer in you know what i mean right
after 15 years then finally gnu e max
introduced syntax chlorine in terminal
the scum okay and of course you know
this happens on every aspect
of technological improvement for example
unicode
you know microsoft word microsoft word
yes
microsoft word you know the editor the
the the
word processor all the hackers despise
okay microsoft
word supports let me show you okay this
is a big okay i'm starting to get
angry when i start to talk about the
unix linux
[ __ ] now you see this thing
let me magnify you see this
you see this curly quote now that's
unicode okay
in e-max you can you can you can uh call
describe
character and you can see the full name
for this character this thing is called
right double quotation mark okay it's
you know curly quote in short
now that's unicode okay now of course
before unicode
microsoft have had that even before
unicode i believe yes
so microsoft soft microsoft word
supported uh curly quotes back then
you know in 1990s 1990s okay
now when so when did emacs supports this
uh 2010 okay
2010 not even not even even
you know even a few years ago there's a
big controversy
in emacs dev because there is a there
was a [ __ ]
his name is uh
i don't you know i don't remember the
name so the idiot okay
anyway let me get to to the point okay
so basically the emacs people
they refuse they do not like they and
also including the unix people they
don't like the uh unicode okay
they like everything ascii like the unix
philosophy
they want they want ascii they don't
want double byte they don't want
you know they just want ascii
and when you so so what do they what do
they do then when
when they need something that's actually
uh matched quote
they do this okay you see that you will
see that often okay
this is what you see in gnu
uh in e-max this
function docs okay this this kind of the
you know backtick a hack
so anyway let me get to the point okay
let's go to emac let me show you the
article i believe i have article
on that uh
[Music]
let's let's go to emac list so that go
to emacs home page
then you go to emacs miscellaneous
then you have then then let's turn on
javascript so you can see
my beautiful face then you go to
the crimes of richard stoneman okay
here's the collection
of what he's done so now search for
quote there it is okay
emac this stock string curly quote
controversy you know
every every year or two on the emac this
step
there's a huge controversy because
whenever someone mentions some
user interface change then everyone you
know
it's like a big controversy everyone is
like talking
uh hundreds thousands of posts
debating about it so basically the short
story of this
this story is that in 2015
okay someone suggested okay was it 2015
also okay read read my article someone
suggested that
you should finally have the support for
double quotes so
basically like this okay so let me show
you a
so instead of you know if you look up
function um
let's say diode okay so here is the emax
describe function you see the emacs
documentation you see the
you see the curly quote here single
curly quote
okay this is this this is a feature
added about
you know i added about um
uh what hold on a second let me go back
here
added around 2015 okay now now you find
finally have it microsoft
had this feature back in 1990s after
10 years or the arguments debate by
these hackers
oh no we don't want unicode we uh uh
code should not have these kind of
uh characters you cannot have it and so
on blah blah blah it's [ __ ] idiots
so you know in the in in my last
a few videos some people ask why why do
you hate
unix so much you know they don't get it
like all the reasons
i give you concrete actual reasons
why unix sucks so bad and you are living
under a lie
but but then the unix idiots you know
the unix linux
open source phonetics they hear it they
don't get it they don't like it fly by
all they see is that hey why are you
crazy
oh my god why are you well you hate
enoch so much
if someone lied to you and let's say
your parent died because someone lied to
you
are you angry do you say oh
why are you angry just because someone
killed your parents why
why why are you angry oh my god must be
something wrong
that's that's what uh that's what these
linux hackers you know open source
phonetics e-max fanatics they are like
when you tell them you give concrete
reasons so many reasons okay
right now i'm telling you one one very
concrete
reason okay the reason the here the
situation the case
is that you have curly quotes okay you
have unit unicode characters not just
curly quote for example
uh hot okay let's let's say
let's not say hot you know for example
for example red arrow
that's a very useful character that's a
progress unicode is
one of the progress of technology we
need it
in mathematicians you know math
mathematics you need that
okay you need for example
do you need that character uh if you are
a functional programmer if you are
loving haskell yes of course you need it
and you know if you are
email at least code but however
so anyway so back in 1990s okay
microsoft
c because they are commercial entities
they don't have this code issue
all they co they are concerned is money
okay do people need this feature
yes they do okay we need to have that
feature so that we can make more
money people will buy microsoft word and
so on you know
that's how apple microsoft all the
commercial organizations are like that
they go after money they chase money and
money
how do you get money well most mostly
most fundamentally
because when people like your things you
know you you
fulfill a need what customers want
so so that's a curly quote so microsoft
word
supported that you know in the 1990s
uh microsoft operating system and mac os
mac even mac os supported you know even
before the unicode unicode
you know i have so many things to say
you know the unicode unicode consortium
that is a organization that began
unicode back in 1989 also
but it wasn't so popular back then their
vision is that
one encoding for all all humanities uh
writing systems characters but anyway so
my point is that
apple microsoft microsoft word
you know apple operating system
microsoft obviously they all
tried at least you know may not have
implemented it well but they all tried
they you know
to some degree you can have this kind of
thing
uh curly quotes you know curry quotes
and you know uh
so in 1990s they have that and emacs
and including unix people linux okay
they refuse
you know these archetypes they don't
they don't want this they think when
they see this they think oh that's
just for stupid people oh we are real
programmers we don't
you know we don't want this uh fluff we
don't want this uh
icing on the cake this is not important
this [ __ ]
do you get my point if you are a linux
fan unix fan do i have a point
there's a technology feature there's a
technology that
humanity need okay kurdi quote
that are implemented in commercial
software
all over the place but when it comes to
open source kind of thing this hacker
type
they the things they love they don't
support that they don't they don't you
know
they have a kind of uh uh
uh inherent
kind of the you know uh resistance to it
it is idiots that's why i call them
idiots that's why
that's why i despise them so after you
know typically after
ten you should usually ten five ten
fifteen years then they started to that
that
so this is one concrete example why
i you know i despise these hacker types
okay because they believe
they believe something that's not true
you know
oh there are so many so you know if you
watch you know
i i'm sure many of you have watched lots
of my videos okay
this is just one of the examples i have
so many almost every
one of my videos i talked about so many
different
concrete issues okay now if you are a
unix phonetics
tell me where did i which part did i was
i
wrong okay which part is it true that
emacs does not support this
after 15 years it was supported by
microsoft word
is that true is that true that this
incident
you know i wrote about this article this
incident okay
i have so many things to tell so it's
kind of jumbled up
so this occurred in 2015 or so
you know uh someone suggested you know
emacs should support the double quality
quote why
there are good technical reasons too not
just not not just prettiness okay
because when you have double quoted
quote you can actually you have a
matched pair okay just like parentheses
just like this parentheses imagine if
this parenthesis
imagine if you replace all these
parentheses by this [ __ ]
by this ugly hack you know that's what
emacs does
and and and the tech and la tech you
know they use this
uh kind of crap you know the
as a hack to get over
to get over the double curly quote you
know hack
that's what they they are unix and you
know these hacker types
they have no they cannot they their
brain is
incapable to perceive something a good
design
you know they they like hacks that's
what they are
so so in around 2015 someone suggested
uh i forgot who okay i forgot how it
began
okay but anyway you read the article i
have full quotes and you can also i have
quotes and links to the to the dev you
know glue emacs dev
uh article you know
so it became a flame war you know with
how many how many
how many uh messages okay so this guy
author mala baba he's a well-known e-max
uh coder you know he imagines quota he
he said he said he tweeted i just made a
rough count the curly quote issue the
curly quotes issue has generated over
100 000 words on the
emac step list that's three times my
doctoral
thesis one hundred thousand words you
know people these hacker debates
oh we should have curriculum no we
shouldn't you know
and this there is that one of the guy
who was an extreme
idiot from germany i know him because we
have you know he
he he you know let me let me
paul edgard is a great guy okay paul
edgard
he's a great guy he made or he he is the
one
who actually coded the support for curly
quotes okay
guys if you are using emacs go thank him
for
edgard thank him right now he's the old
you know uh
he's the old uh coder imagine
he he's a guy who did he made a change
but however there's another guy
who [ __ ] it up okay but this guy
uh what's his name
because i i you know we we have alan
mccann
mckenzie this idiot alan mckenzie
okay he is a of course he's another emac
this developer he is
he is um he's the cc mod
maintainer okay in imac this cc mod
major mod
maintainer you know he's also imagine
developer for a long time for 10 years
or so
but this guy alan mckenzie he's always
whenever there is some suggestion
to change emacs for the better related
to user interface
he alan mckenzie will shut it down he
will
shut it down he will you know do all
things he can
to to to not have that feature to
to let emax be the way it is in the
1990s this
idiot allen mckenzie
okay so someone started to work on these
you know and
and paul edgar eventually made all the
changes
implementation you know code you know to
support the kurdi quote
then comes the allen mckenzie he says no
we shouldn't have that
okay then that's the that's the
beginning of the flame war
100 000 words okay i don't know how many
messages
how many messages are there hundreds
hundreds okay
uh so
so what what's my point so i want to say
so ella mckenzie
he he's the one who began to turn
everything down because it's already
done
you know the the great guy paul ed uh
paul
paul edgard already made the changes you
know
then pops up ella mckenzie he insists
that
you should not support the way he does
you know he suggests
instead that you should have a markup
the [ __ ] allen [ __ ]
he suggested you should you know emac
this code
you should use this markup then you
should have another mechanism
that turns this markup into the curly
version okay
because his reason is that oh because uh
you know the curly quad is not on
keyboard we cannot have it you know
[ __ ] [ __ ] idiot
so he he basically single-handedly
made emacs worse okay the change is
already done
you know it's already committed
eventually he the paul edgard has to
had to revert his commit okay now but
who makes the final decision okay who
makes the final decision the flame
flame war you know 1000 messages it's a
richard snowman [ __ ] here is a
[ __ ]
crime done by the richard stoneman [ __ ]
it
so richard stollman he is not the
maintainer okay
he is not the leader of the emac emacs
at the time
you know in 2015
you know every few years emacs you know
emacs dev there's a new leader so called
you know they it's known as
maintainer okay the role of the
maintainer officially
according to official you know according
to richard snowman
is should be the person who leads or
who decides or technical decisions of
emacs
you know so right now the current
maintainer is um
uh i forgot you know i'm not good with
names so
who is the current maintainer the steve
uh no um
i i i don't remember now um
who so who is the current maintainer you
guys know okay so
it's very well known okay i i have to
think i don't remember
anyway i'm focused on on my rent right
now
so basically a fee by a according to the
official
the way of uh how emac step works the
maintainer
should be responsible to decide all the
you know technical issues of emacs you
know he lead
he lead the emacs dev team
except when the issue has to do with
political or social uh issues
such as licensing or related to free
software foundation's vision
you know when when when some issue
that's related to social issues or
political issues then
richard stowman has the ultimate say
on what it should be okay
but in this case the curly quote whether
how you how we should support curry coil
has nothing
to do with uh regis roman free software
foundation you know philosophy and you
know nothing
it's a purely technical issue but
however
in the end the [ __ ] [ __ ] richard
stowman comes in and says
please stop inserting curly quotes into
dark strings in imax sources
yeah so richard snowman you know he he
sits in the dev you know he look at you
know he doesn't haven't he haven't been
coding for 20 years he just sit there
and you know and look and sometimes put
post his opinions he doesn't use the
browser he doesn't know what's a
he doesn't know nothing he doesn't you
know he
he use the browser service tools
you know anyway that's a well-known
story i think
i don't need to talk about that so
anyway he he sits there and he watch you
know he
he casually watch the people argue then
he just
say at the end please stop inserting
curly quotes
into dark strings in imax source
and that's the end okay that so that
after that then paul agat you know he
had to he basically reverted or he's
changed that's the end
the guy the boss the god has made his
uh made his opinions no
[ __ ] richard stowman that's a crime okay
he's not he does not have the right
richard stoneman have just do not have
the right
he's not the maintainer at the time not
even
not here he haven't been you know he's
not the maintainer he does not have the
right
to say to give the ultimate decision
what
emac should do when the issue is not uh
political or social issues but he just
they
sit there and he voice opinions oh i
think this way i think that way
so you know so effectively he you know
he's
telling people what to do you know
because he's the you know guru there
he's
you know the creator of the free
software foundation creator of emacs so
people cannot say anything else you know
if he said that then that's
that's just that just like just like on
my in my discord forum
you know i'm the boss i have the final
say
okay that's a that's an issue so and
perhaps that's it for today that's uh
that's a
i haven't talked about this issue before
so you know the so limb but but let me
show you an article okay so
okay
here's the article i wrote this
is about link you know this is about
punctuation so part of in the field of
linguistics
and writing systems linguistics writing
systems
code programming language is actually
part of it you can consider it
as a writing system for communication
with a machine
programming languages okay so this this
article is in the field of linguistics
and writing systems writing system
design
but specifically it's about type type
typography hyphen dash quotation marks
and apostrophe
okay so this one is written in 2007.
and uh you know you can go read it and
but i want to go to
uh to the last part so i showed you for
example
uh some varieties of matching quotes
used by different uh chinese japanese
korean and
also western other western languages
it's it's quite bizarre okay for example
in
in swedish language finnish you you use
matching you know you use the right
curly quotes
to quote and in german german bulgarian
and question and estonian you use this
weird you know way uh
bizarre okay so but anyway
so then you explore the combinatorial
possibilities
so so i you know i discussed several
several related issues okay then comes
the curly quote versus a straight quote
okay
then then it relates to how the
english grammar of the use
of apostrophe okay that's another story
about apostrophe and
and the possessives the possessive form
you know s mary's car james car
you know things like possessive
involving apostrophe is
very uh illogical and bizarre okay but
then comes
uh i have a section about glue
that's why i'm bringing up this article
where is it
there it is okay so there it is
problem of a matching straight quotation
marks okay
so here in particular this style
you know use using the back tick
with a straight single quote
this style is adopted by the free
software foundation in their gnu
project okay although this workaround
solves a syntactical ambiguity problem
i think it is rather unnecessary and
ugly
for a workaround with the constraint of
ascii
for a matching quote i would have
adopted something more symmetric
such as parenthesis and the single
quote okay or
oh uh
curly bracket with a single quote you
know so i i would adopt this instead
if you have you know you know it's
understandable
you know technology is not always
perfect so we evolved you know
unicode was not invented you know 30 or
40 years ago
so we so so when you don't have you know
the
curly quote what can you do if you want
if you need a character that actually is
a matching pair
matching pair is significant in passing
in programming languages in computing
because they it's a simple way to
to know you know which part matches
which part you know so
that's why it's important you know
for example when you have a array for
example array in python
python pearl in ruby in almost every
language in c
array you have a square bracket right
that's a matching pair
that's called match fix operator you
know imagine if you're gonna
use uh you know if imagine if you're
gonna use a hack
such as the gnu you know the backtick
for that that's
you know that's no good right
so so then you know i continue so but
the problem with the glue
is that even today in 2007
where curly quotes have been widely
available in word processes
for over a decade and unicode have
have been practical and widely available
for at least five years
they are still the granular steel using
plain ascii hacks
okay then parent parenthetical comment
in general gnu and the open source
morons
have like a five to ten years lag in
adopting technology
for reasons that are in fact
inadvertently
intentional and or simply incapable
so that's my remark about the hacker
types and you know the
typically the associated with unix linux
and and and these days open source you
know this
and also usually see see programmers
these idiots that concludes today's talk
show i guess you know but imagine you
imagine why these people you know
how does their brain work how can they
not see
you know the something that's better
that how you know
and also in another sense their view is
very limited
you know they are they like ascii you
know like the unix
they ask they like the ascii characters
because it's simple
but you know the word is not just
english speakers okay
you got that you know the word you know
this is is indian chinese russian
okay they don't inc the ascii character
said cannot use cannot be used for
those languages and there's no more more
of them
than english speakers so
you don't you don't you don't you don't
you don't you you want to stick to
asking what what the [ __ ] is your
problem
okay that's my rant against these uh
unix hackers again another day that's
my rant against eunice hackers
i think that's it for today thank you
for watching
54 minutes okay let's read the comments
okay oh my god emily is watching emily
is the most
polite and nice person and i've been
[ __ ] this and [ __ ] that all this
wow hi justin jones
justin jones haskell coda emily
and benjamin
first unicode implementation was for
plan 9.
oh is that true okay i don't know i
didn't know
so benjamin says what are you using to
type unicode how do you make the
text hard okay that's uh i'm using my
packages okay so you can go
you can go to um so for example
you know to type hot i can type that and
press the key then becomes that oh i can
type that
okay it's um for example let me show you
some of my uh
unicode typing systems okay in fact i
have so many articles about that i have
three or four
about on the practical issue of how do
you type unicode in
emacs so let me show you a few okay uh
let me show you a few so copy that paste
it here so
for example each one of these i can
press a key
then this one too press a key and this
one i don't even have to press that key
but i just
i just press a space okay so how how is
that done
so the question is how do you type
unicode characters any emoji
or any math symbols in the most
efficient way that's a key point
what's the most efficient way because
there are many ways what are the
what is the most efficient way so the
most efficient way is
a brief okay so you go to my
brief so i can i can show you so search
for ra search for ra
so you can see here this section okay so
so this is some of my unicode approved
okay
bu okay l a left arrow
oh okay well that's because i mean uh e
max
this okay so let me do it here
so you see bu left arrow ua
up arrow right arrow red error i use all
the time
so this is the most efficient way
to type unicode in emacs okay do it
so you if you don't know how to do it
just go search for
emacs abbrev
okay uh you know just go read it
so actually go go read this one he said
so
you know i have full detailed
explanation on how do you set it up
very easy in two minutes you'll be ready
good to go
now however there is a flaw with this
this way of typing typing unicode
there's a flow
what's the flow that is when you have
one when you have few hundred unicode
characters you need to type
okay if you have few hundred unicode
characters you cannot possibly
remember their abbrev names for example
many of these
i don't use much now because i don't
remember the brief names
so when that is the case you use the
other mod okay so
let me show you the mod okay so uh
okay describe key
so here is the mod some math input
change symbol okay so that is the mod so
you go to here's the code
you go to it
okay so you go to it magnify go to the
top
so you can see some math input dot er so
that's a mod okay you can download it
it's on mailpad
and let's go to the home page so this
so this one is useful when you have a
few hundred
of briefs so
so for 10 also a briefs that unicode
that you
type the most of often that every day a
few times a day
then you want to use a brief but other
otherwise yeah
this um you might use check out math
input mod okay okay that's i think
that's it so thank you guys for watching
um
this is good history lesson i always
wondered why you actually use strange
quotes okay red
firefox theme it's not firefox it's a
it's a microsoft edge
okay so it turns out today is a giant
rambo about the unicode issue okay
that's uh that's
today's topic so and and you know if you
enjoy my stuff
don't forget donate to me okay
uh you know youtube paypal you can buy
my emacs
tutorial or you can paypal me or patreon
me
or amazon gift card okay so you can find
my links
you know on saudi.info
uh what else i think that's it for today
how many people are watching
uh let's let's see 16 concurrent viewers
okay i think six uh 11 okay so that's it
for today anything else anything else
guys
okay so yeah that's it um
let me let me let me see what else i'm
uh i'm gonna
ramble for two more minutes or so
let's see so close then so actually
copy that close that go to talk show
shrink the window show the pink window
and go to talk show today's talk show
and paste it here okay
and make it the text okay
then okay yeah i'm gonna shut down okay
copy that
go back here i'm just gonna type
what we typed today close that
back back math input mod
we already have that because that
a brief okay a brief mod go learn it
if you haven't already
close that and this article the moral
necessities
okay
close that oh and that's that and
e immaculately stock string curly quote
controversy
yeah okay
close that close that close that
close that close that and
unix pipe as functional language okay
that's beginning of our chat
because that syntax soup
hacker code voodoos of software
engineering that's right
[Laughter]
that's another different
uh different different group different
um
you know that that you know the voodoos
of software engine that's those uh
agile people are kind of very different
from the unix
crackpots the nature of unix philosophy
okay that's not
it because that
okay so let me show you uh some of my
unicode page okay unicode
so you go to xr unicode and someone
mentioned
fasting fuzzing says you know a posture
you know actually i can talk about that
you know all these apostrophes and
punctuations for another hour
that's another interesting topic you
know because
that so the topic is about the semantic
of
characters what do they mean for example
let's look at the punctuation okay
so so unicode actually have a dedicated
symbol
for you know the feet
foot sign or minute and seconds
about you know time so by tradition
uh you know unicode has a prime okay so
then then you also have prime
which is used for derivative for example
the single
prime this character single prime is
used for
feet of feet was it feet or foot
and it's also used for derivative
in mathematics okay then it's also you
know
then sometimes it can use uh for
apostrophe
because all these symbols look similar
okay
then you have double prime double prime
is for feet
right yeah uh
so so there's a question you know so
which one you know which one should you
use
normally you know see you see before
computing error before we actually have
computers
then we start to need character set and
encoding before
so before computers we don't have this
notion you don't
you don't really have a notion of
encoding and
you do have a notion of a character set
which is you know for example
english alphabet latin alphabet a to z
and some punctuations but it's different
from the
character set concept in computing
because in computing
a character set is actually must be very
specific
and with and almost always come with an
encoding
that transforms the character to a
two binary digits you know to a number
basically
so anyway before computers all we do is
write you know we write without pain
so when we have a for example apostrophe
or a foot mark or a quote
you know you don't need to first about
which you know which one of these
characters are all you have to do is
just drag it you know just write it
okay that's with the writing okay that's
before
let's say that's before printing you
know you might use some tool
you know to edge on the stone or you may
might use a brush
like the chinese do you know you use a
brush or you might use a creole
you know as the western people queer you
know
all the characters or letters you just
write it so you have really no concern
about
what's the exact difference between a
prime
character versus a you know apostrophe
versus a curly
you know armenian apostrophe or
latin capital letters sartilo
latin small letters subtitle okay so all
these variations
and look at the dash okay there's more
for the dash you know so you have hyphen
minus
you have hyphen you have none breaking
hyphen
you have en dash you have figure dash
you have
em dash then you have horizontal bar
it's [ __ ] all the same it must you
know except some are longer than my
shoulder
so before before computers
before printing error you don't have you
don't have those
you know these distinctions you just
write or
whatever tool you're just writing but
with printing you know the technology of
printing press
it becomes it started to become an issue
because
because you need a specific you know
metal shape to
to print certain characters so there is
a
there became a distinction of which
characters is a prime and which
character is a straight approximate
apostrophe because you have to pick the
different
um uh
you know i what is that called okay so
let me let's go to wikipedia let's look
at some of the
yeah here okay so you can you can see
you need to use this thing
uh this little you know metal things you
you
put them together then you can print
them so it
makes a a difference between of what
characters and also then
then there's a concept of font you know
front face face
and then when it comes to computers you
also have to make a distinction too
because different characters although
they appear they look the same
you know although they looks almost the
same depending on what font or what
monitor
are you using but internally the vapor
the binary representation is different
so that's very interesting and so so so
then comes the question for example when
you are writing
when you are using computers to write
right stuff
what characters should you know which
which one of these characters should
have what meaning
you know so it becomes kind of a
issue anyway okay that's
it
mr 22b
can you suggest a mathematics roadmap i
talked about math in my
in in the past two months so check those
check those um did you did you watch my
videos in the past two months
especially the ones i talked about
mathematica especially the one i talked
about
um algorithmic mathematical art
so you know because there are people i
don't know if it's you or not
there have been people asking me about
how i study math
or what is uh what do i suggest um
you know i talked a little bit about
that unless you have specific questions
like you have to describe
are you like are you 16 are you 25
how old are you have you already
finished high school
or are you currently in college what's
your situation
are you already studying are you a math
major
or maybe you are not maybe you are just
a carpenter
but you are interested in self-study of
math
so different people have different you
know i would have different advices
bye guys donate okay put put money in my
pocket