Hello guys, good evening everyone. Good
evening everyone. Welcome to another
episode of Sound Talk Show. We are going
to code wuang wrame language. Woo frame
language also known as Mathematica.
So we are going to code graphics
programming animation. We are going to
create this animation.
Um if you are here say hi. Love to see
your comments. If you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed.
Okay, so we just going to code that and
let's begin. Wam language.
Cheers. Red wine.
There is wam language. Start a new
notebook. Okay. Three. Shift enter to
evaluate to start the kernel. And
magnify 150. Okay. So, we're going to
draw this animation. So, let me just
show you directly. I have already
written the code like um like about 30
years ago. So, it's just updating
uh
so that I can uh hold on a second show
you.
Okay. So, if you want to know if you
want get the code, you can already do
so. Just search for wraali
my name x ah hl e plank curve generator
package. Okay. So you can search for
wuam language packages and one of them
is wuam plane curve generator package.
So this package you can download it on
GitHub. it will generate about 30
animations
uh animations that illustrates the
definition of plane curves many special
well-known plane curves. So for example,
one of them is this one we're going to
do today asteroid generator and asteroid
can be generated in several ways. One of
the way the definitive way by definition
is you roll a circle inside another
circle. The circle is four times smaller
in radius.
So we can show you so you can see. So uh
so this package so this is another way
to generate asteroid. So asteroid is a
curve that looks like this. Okay. So
this is a animation generated by that
package. one of the way to generate
asteroid
and you can also generate it by rolling
a larger circle. In fact, these two
methods they sync together. Very
interesting. Okay, that's because of of
the mathematical properties. Also, this
curve is also known as a toy called
spyroraph.
If you search for spyroraph, you'll find
uh lots of um
sp i a l sp i r a g r a ph. I think it
was trademarked.
So there's a Wikipedia article and uh
let's go to images. You can see lots of
is this toy. In fact, I happened to have
this toy when I was like 80 years old or
10 in Taiwan. So that was like 40 years
ago.
So yeah, so spyroraph. Fascinating. So
anyway, so the curve the asteroid is one
of the spyroraph. Okay. So anyway, so so
this package generates all these
animations
you can download for free. That's wam
language and uh so another way to
generate uh asteroid is by the ellipses.
So this ellip uh these ellipses they
share the um they are conf focal they
share the focus
um
and they share uh I think the sum of
their circumerence is equal. Was that
right? or something I forgot but you can
look up. So go to asteroid so you can
find my website. This this is called
visual dictionary of spatial plane
curves. This is one of my earliest
project that made my website popular
back in 1997 back to up to 1997.
So you you search for that website
visual dictionary of spatial plane
curves and you just search for asteroid
uh one of them here asteroid. So you can
find this page and then you can find
this animation and then uh properties.
Uh then um
by the way this this mechanism this way
of a bar fixed onto two perpend
perpendicular bars.
You slide the bar around this. This
mechanism is called a treml treml of
Archimedes.
Uh
so anyway so so so yeah so asteroid can
be is a envelope of coaxel ellipses
whose sum of major and minor axis is
constant. I see major and minor axis. I
see. So you
um you know the major and minor axis
which is basically the length of the
ellipse and the width. Use uh sum them
together. Did I define it here?
Major axis is a line segment passing the
fai and intersect with the elisp.
Yeah. So that's basically the width
minor axis is a line segment
perpendicular to the major axis passing
the center of folky and intersect. Yeah.
Anyway, kind of like the width and
height of the ellipse. So if they are
all constant, you know, then you draw
all of them ellipses, then they form
their envelope is the asteroid. So
anyway, that's a asteroid. Okay, lots of
very interesting properties. Okay, now
let's start to code. I want to generate
um the code for that graph. So how so
the code? So today we're going to focus
on coding. Okay. Uh uh so Wuam language
coding. So you want to go to asteroid
and uh
Okay. Let me think about what to do. So
if you are here, say hi. Okay. Love to
see your comments.
Okay, let's get to code. So
what I want to do is I already have the
package. So let's go to get
uh generate. Uh so this plank of
generator package. So here is the source
code. You can see here's the source code
start started in 1995.
Uh 1,500 lines of code. So all these are
wam language code. Okay. Those are
documentation and here's the code. So
you
so okay so let's see what we going to do
asteroid. So there are three functions
to generate asteroid. I think we're
going to do all of them. So let but
let's do them one at a time. So copy
that.
Uh so what we going to do asteroid
generator. So let's create a new file.
Uh so should we save the file here? Why
not? Okay.
Uh
astrogenerator
WL. Okay. So
Okay. So we copied that and uh we
Okay. So why don't we copy one, two,
three asteroid generator one, two,
three.
Okay. So paste it there.
Delete the duplicate.
Okay. Go back. Then you want to actual
find the code. Okay. So we start to have
the code here.
So here starting the code. Okay. Astro
generator.
Okay. and generator two and generator
three. Okay. So, let's copy it, close
it, and paste it here. And
instead of separating them, uh let's put
them together. So,
so let me do this. So, here's options
astro generator and uh so what? So
here's astro generator and there is a
code. Then there's astrogenerator 2
uh okay which is uh just basically based
on oh oh Jesus there's a dependency it
depends on hypotcoid generator you see
so that's not what we want um we want
them to be independent so let me let me
just do some work okay
so
create uh new one. So let's save this
generator to W from language code
and uh delete. Okay.
Okay. And uh
delete that new page. This will be
asteroid generator 3
dot
WL. Okay.
So the generator two three. So three
and uh
three three copy. Okay. Three.
So there. So this is asteroid generator
number three. Uh what does number three
does? It does uh plank of generator. So
this is the number one by treml. Number
two is rolling a circle small circle
four times smaller.
Number three is by uh by this
ellipses
whose
sum of major and minor axis are equal.
Okay.
So
yeah. So it's documented here showing
that it's envelope of coaxial ellipses
whose wh ho e spelling error h o s e wh
h e
okay so I got so let's replace all
wo
e by e s by
Okay, can we like replace all? Okay, it
occurred there. Okay, so anyway,
asteroid generator three is coaxel
ellipses whose sum of major and minor
axis is constant are constant.
Okay. Anyway, special option. So, so
this is generator three. It's
independent code. Um
is that right? Yes.
So astrogenerator 2 is it depends on
it depend on this hypotcoid. Okay.
And astrogenerator one refresh uh
where's astrogenerator one. Okay. So
delete that. So here's the code.
Okay. So actually we can start to run
it. Copy it.
Okay. Select or paste it. Shift enter.
It's defined. Is there any error? No
error. Okay. In fact, we can just uh
shift enter control I mean control shift
N to make it type set. So So you got
fractions there. Okay. It's not not many
parts can be type set anyway.
So that's the code. Then you can read
the asteroid. So this is the
documentation. This is how you define
documentation
inline documentation string in wra
language. Okay. Now there's something I
don't like. Um well you see when you
copy this and paste it to wra they
become uh back slashn.
Uh they auto convert to backslash in.
I'm not sure I like it like uh
shift enter.
Uh okay. Now oh when you press shift
enter
n to type set then it become back slash
n. Okay. Otherwise it's literal
the new line character. Okay. So anyway,
so so here is uh so that's you know so
we can type question mark
that will give you the usage
uh string. So the question mark is
actually
information.
Okay information you can also do it this
way.
Okay, that's equivalent. So the question
mark is actually just a shortcut for the
information function.
Uh well, not exactly.
But um okay, we are digressing. Let's go
back. Let's let let me just code. Let me
just uh show example. Okay, so let's
see.
Oh well you have to do actually you
don't have to um
you don't have to say any parameters
just empty okay Astro generated that
shift enter so now it generates a list
of graphics you see fantastic and
beautiful now if you want animation you
just say list animate so you just Okay,
list animate. Okay, that
that will take a list of graphics and
creates an animation out of it. Shift
enter.
So there we have it.
Cheers.
Okay. What I want to do, so go back to
my website. I want it to replace um
let's see what I want to do. I want to
add the independent code to the page.
Uh so this is asteroid page. So go down,
go down, go down. I want to add
properties.
Okay, I want to add a code right here so
that people don't have to like download
the package when people you know look at
the my visual dictionary of planks. They
can just copy the code right here and
you know and uh and uh you know paste in
Wuam language and they can generate the
animation without having to like
download my uh wam packages find the
link somewhere. So anyway,
so the code is just here. So it's like
you know 50 lines of code actually 20 20
lines but
okay so here's a full code. So actually
for example copy it let's go to this
page. Okay, copy it. Go to talk show. Uh
today's talk show that showing browser
back. Search for asteroid there. Go to
it. Then treml. Okay. So treml here you
can just say
uh start a wam language code. Paste the
code here. Syntax color it.
Uh press press syntax color it. You can
see there was HTML re HTML pre-code
buffer. Okay. Showing browser page down,
page down, page down, page down, page
down, page down, page down, and scroll
down. So you can see here's a tremolo of
Arimedes.
And here's a code, Wam language code. So
people can copy it and you know it'll
run.
So, but okay. So, the is that does that
does that make sense? Is that
Yeah, I can, you know, because I'm
thinking about, you know, so in the
future I'm going to have lots of this
code. You probably want, you know, if if
you are going to add the Woop language
code to the to the web page,
some of them are fairly long, in fact.
Uh, so,
so if you're going to have a lot of
code, you probably want some kind of
compact features. So, you press a button
to hide all the wam language code. Yeah,
that's
that's so this is regarding user
interface design. So, that's probably
something I want to do. I need to do you
see.
So again we are doing you know we are
doing this educational like online book
visual dictionary of spatial plane
curves. Each one each one shows the
properties. Hold on a second.
Hold on a second. My wife is back. So,
uh, I'll be back in 2 minutes.
Okay, I will be back in 2 minutes.
Okay. Hello guys. I'm back. So, turn on
the video. Turn on the camera again.
Check video. Check audio. Check. Am I
back or live? So, my wife is back. So,
I'm going to have dinner soon, but we
can continue.
So you know I'm working on my updating
my visual this project visual dictionary
of spatial plane curves. So you go to
asteroid you need to update all these
graphics but now you included you know
this we have been we did this live
stream like a year ago. So we updated
the um
the video you see
so showing browser. So we updated now we
are trying to include the code so people
can generate the animation themselves
but
okay so what what's the next thing to do
the next thing to do is that first we
there are few things to do okay one
thing is that hello ACP good morning
good evening where you from ACP I forgot
um so we are going to there are few
things we need to do. Okay, we are going
to optimize possibly optimize this code
because this code has been written
like um like like literally 30 years
ago. Okay, so let me let me go to it. So
let me yeah, so this code we going to
possibly optimize it. Okay, we we'll
have to see rewrite don't you know or or
maybe just change the coding style
because after 30 years now I know quite
a lot more about programming you know we
going to we might optimize the code but
but typically my code is pretty
efficient we are just going to optimize
in some possibly but usually my code is
pretty efficient even back then so
that's one thing to do. The other thing
is is to look into uh to look into the
possible formats
for the um animation. You see right
here,
let's search for treml.
Okay, right here. It's actually using a
uh we did this like last year live. It's
using a webp format. You see?
Open it. That's like a webp animation.
So webp is a webp is a image format but
it also
allows animation just like GIF. So it is
actually not a uh you know not a video
format properly but yeah I mean it can
have a video. So
so it's interesting situation. So um you
know so this is all done by wam
languages. So let me show you we need to
show it. Okay this animate. So let's say
xx equals true. Okay.
Okay. Done. Then we say export
uh export uh what is the what is the
syntax? Export file name and uh
expression. Okay. So, file name. Let's
let's do that in um
Okay. So, export
file name xx dot
uh web. What is that file format? Webp
that is a image format from Google about
10 years ago. Google invented it. Okay.
The expression is just XX.
So export to webp format animation.
Okay. XX is uh is this uh is this
animation. Okay.
So it's going to take a while. It's not
done yet. And we also going to do
MP4. Okay,
we going to wait for it. Okay, that is
done. Now let's do the MP4.
It's interesting because the WEBP is a
image format, but it also supports um
animation. Then
done. Okay. Now let's go to documents.
By default, these are saved in document.
So there they are. So you can see
there's a huge file size difference.
Oh, you see
why uh you know why did I do webp?
Because webp is three times larger.
Amazing. So wait,
copy the file path for both of them. Now
go to here and paste it and uh linkify
that and linkify that. You see one is a
video. It became a HTML video tag. The
other one is the uh image tag. Okay. Now
let's check this webp. What size is it?
So wait. So open it. So this is 600
kilobytes. You see one is one is six 600
kilobyte. The other one is like 200
kilobyte. Okay. So the web p is 600
kilobyte. And what about this one? So
let's look at this one is
500 kilobyte. Okay.
Wow. Okay. Now, now you're going to show
in browser show demo.
So let's go look at the so this is about
like file format issue like when you
write a tutorial you have to also
you have to worry about the code
efficiency to generate the animation but
you also have to worry about like which
format should you use and also browser
compatibility like which which version
uh which format video format browser
supports you see. So this is uh MP4.
I like this the best. Okay. I like this
the best because
Okay. Then it it includes that uh this
thing. We
may not want it. You see we may not want
that.
So this uh this is uh webp. You see this
is webp. Let's uh say
that's the name. Okay. Now, actually uh
let's
let's rename them first. Well, move them
into the current directory. Okay. So, I
have a command e emac. Do it. Do it. Do
it. Wait.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Okay. Save it here.
Now
save it in this current directory and uh
the you're going to name them as TMO
webp. Okay. And you're going to rename
them as TMO MP4. Okay. And uh
Okay. So actually let me just do this.
Okay. So
yeah,
so this two we have two webp versions.
So look at this. So this webp is 600
megabytes.
600 kilobytes. Okay. Uh what what about
this webp? This webp is
kilobytes. Okay.
Now um
you see the difference is that they one
of them got this wam language control
things. We don't want that usually.
So we need to fix it. So
So there are several issues. First of
all, which one you going to use? I'm
going to use MP4. I'm pretty sure I want
the MP4 format. I don't want the webp
because it's three times larger the file
size. Now the the other thing is that we
don't want this um
we don't this we don't want this bars on
top. So uh so actually you just all you
have to do is you just
export that. Okay,
there it is.
Okay, mp4. So now let's go to documents
again. XXMPP4
open.
Fantastic. Fantastic and beautiful.
Okay. So copy the file path. Close it.
Now
paste it. Linkify it. Move it to the
current directory and rename it.
Rename it asteroid tremmo. Yeah. Uh just
random character there. Okay. Copy it
and
relink it. Okay. So that we got the
proper figure caption. Okay.
Delete that.
Now open this MP4. Delete it. Delete
that. Open this webp. Delete it. Delete
it. Open this webp. delete the file and
delete that and and now show in browser.
So now page down, page down, page down,
page down, page down, page down, page
down, page down. So we got this
MP4 version. That's what I want.
Now there is one more thing. Um, you see
this video MP4 you need it doesn't show
the you know for example refresh it
doesn't you you want you want a poster
to show
like to show like the middle of the
frame so you can get a overview. So you
want a poster. So in order to do that
you can save this um you want to poster
like that. Okay. So, uh, for example,
let's say
before it finishes,
something like that.
Okay. So, you want a poster. Um, so you
can kind of um, let's say not that one,
almost like this one. That's what you
want. Okay.
So you can like save this uh convert to
canvas. Uh
paste, cut graphics, copy graphics, make
hyperlink, save graphics as okay. Uh not
PDF. We hate PDF. We want PNG. Okay. So
let's just say
oh god
save graphics as uh in fact it would be
better if you just do a screenshot.
So let's do a screenshot.
Okay. So wait,
do a screenshot.
Wait.
Okay. Do a screenshot.
Okay, there it is. And now
move the screenshot here. Open it.
That's one. Okay. Now
rename it that. Okay.
Okay. I don't like that. Uh rename it.
Okay. Now
relink it. So, so that is your that's
the file path you want to say a poster.
Okay. So, you add so shift. So, you need
to do um am I making sense?
Live in South California. Fantastic. The
open video container is web m.
Oh, really? Okay. So, uh, so anyway,
let's let's do this. Um, so we got, uh,
yeah, so we want to tap a.
So, you want to say, wait, uh,
poster. Okay.
Uh, poster
there. Okay. Delete that. Delete that.
Now, go back to the browser. And if you
refresh, it will show a poster like
refresh. You see? Fantastic. Now play.
That's what I want. That's what I want.
And people can like uh do a loop if they
want. And uh there should be a back and
forth uh speed play
loop.
You know I I wish there is a like right
click back and forth. Anyway, so that is
a video. That's what we want. Okay.
Uh so the open video container is webm.
Uh okay. So you are talking about
is that right? The
WebM Wikipedia Webb M is a audiovisisual
media file format. It is primarily
intended to offer a royaltyfree
alternative to use in HTML video and
HTML audio elements.
Um,
it has a sister project for images webp.
Okay. Okay. The web development of the
format is sponsored by Google and blah
blah blah. Um, yeah. Okay. I don't
remember the details, but you know, webp
by now is like pretty old, but to me
it's like still yesterday because why
the Google created a new image
format, you know, and today the better
image format is actually um
XJPEG. Okay, that's called um JPEG
something you know that there's also
JPEG 2000 you know and also another one
is a uh AVIF I think anyway image format
there's a big fight you know big image
format war and we discussed on si
discord but I don't have discord on so
let's not open it
anyway so yeah the image format is like
uh okay let me show you why not AVIF
that's a new uh latest image format AVIF
which I think is very good the other one
is um
uh it's called JPEG um
it's called
XJPEG okay let's just search for XJ
XJ JG. Uh, no.
JPEG XL. Yeah, that's that's one. So,
the so let me tell you guys about this.
Okay, so image format technology they
are apparently still improving. So it's
not like you know you you you thought
you know you learned all the technical
details about JPEG and PNG and how they
diff what's their difference and give
you know you know everything about it
but apparently every few years the
technology changes you know like like
the JavaScript like JavaScript and the
HTML the DOM it changes it just like
keep changing CSS you know you thought
we had everything we needed. You know,
like you mastered the whole programming
language, JavaScript and CSS and HTML,
but actually they keep changing for
reasons.
You know, some of the reason is actually
valid, you know, because society, you
know, because things change, you know,
therefore we need, you know,
corresponding changes to uh progress in
technology, programming languages, you
know, they change, right?
So some of the change are natural and
needed. Okay. But actually but but the
here's the thing. Some of the changes
are not natural and not needed.
They are created because for political
reasons like some some some nasty
organization you know for their they
want some they want money and they have
the power. they they made a change. So
many of the changes in technology
are that nature. Okay, that this is a
interesting thing I'm telling you guys
from my experience. Okay, so anyway,
let's go back to the image format. So
image format they are also changing. So
apparently so the latest two primary
contenders are the AVIF image format and
the JPEG XL.
Both of them are first of all of course
much more efficient than the standard
JPEG that we know of the JPEG or you
know for example JPEG or PNG the image
format that we are used to. The two
major standard are JPEG, PNG and GIF.
GIF is like very Asian, you know, it's
like obsolate, but people still use it.
GIF is like really really bad. Uh very
inefficient. Okay. But it was like 30
from 30 years ago. It's most popular. So
anyway, the the most popular image
format today is JPEG and PNG and
and Google's webp like webp from 10
years ago.
It's like uh it's not so as much as as
popular as JPEG. The the dominant like
90% 99% of the web is JPEG and the other
maybe 1% is PNG. Then the other like 01%
is webp. Okay, that's the situation. In
fact, we can ask uh guac to give you
give us a um
that would be interesting question. Oh,
I don't have the I don't have my Twitter
on.
We can ask what to give us uh my
Twitter. So
tell us the distribution of JPEG
and
um
and PNG and GIF and WEBP
used on websites.
So
let guac give us a sense of how you know
these format are used on web. Let's
magnify the page.
Okay. As of as as of February 2026, the
most reliable and upto-ate source for
the distribution of image formats used
on websites came from W3 text which
tracks usage across millions of sites.
Okay. PNG. Uh what 97%
of website? What?
Wow, I'm surprised by that. PNG 90 77%.
I don't think that's true. What?
JPEG is 72%. I I think JPEG is much more
popular than PNG,
but PNG is 70%. What? What? This is
interesting. This needs more further
research. Okay. And webp is 20% of
websites. Wow, that's amazing. I think
mostly what amazing uh Okay. But very
interesting statistics. Okay.
Anyway, so what I'm telling you guys is
like AVF uh AVIF is the latest in JPEG
XL. Okay.
Anyway, we we digressed a lot. I you
know, let's we should go back to Wuam
language because that's what we are we
are doing today. So, asteroid po uh
yeah, let's go back to wam language.
asteroid uh page. We did this uh okay,
this is what we want. Uh web mp4. That's
what we want. And we got the code. Now
the next thing to let's optimize the
code. Okay, we were going to do the
others. Uh we were going to also do this
one and this one, but let's uh we don't
have time. So let's now uh let's see.
Let's Can we optimize the code? Um,
yeah, why not? So, let's do that. Okay.
Number of frames. Do we have still that
number of frames? Yeah, we do. That's a
option. So, this is how you code option
in Wufam language. Okay. Uh by this is
how you this this section is how you
code option. how you define optional
parameters of a function in wam
language. This is how you define it.
So in in our case we we support the
special option number of frames plus all
the all the options in the graphics. Um
so for example we can we can change our
um
change our code um style coding style
using the S sign. Let's do that. So um
join yeah we can let's make it one line.
Okay.
Uh well
same thing. Okay. So anyway so options.
So let's see the documentation other
options are passed through graphics.
Okay. So
so t means so this is uh
so this is this is another way to call a
function t mean greater than zero. Uh,
can you use like that?
I wonder what uh
I wonder Wam can interpret
this expression using with Unicode.
Let's try.
Oh, wuam can. So, let's do that.
Uh, so yeah.
Wait, that's not what you want. Uh, oh
god,
actually. So wait. Okay, I need to, you
see, I want this to become
the less or equal to symbol of Unicode.
So I have a command to do that which is
this command which is casar math input
change to symbol but right now if you do
it it's not working because it changed
the
it changed the less less than sign to
this pre
symbol. You see this symbol is called
precedes. Okay, it looks like a less
than sign but it's got curves.
Okay, but what I what I what I actually
want is not that uh wait undo undo undo
undo undo undo undo undo undo undo undo
undo. What I want is the you know less
than less than or equal. So let's fix my
emac code. So we are doing multi code
wan language and eacis. So let's go to
uh wait describe function press that key
math input change to symbol. So let's go
there. So this is a package um about
1,00 lines. Uh okay undo. Now let's
search for
search for equal less than. Search for
that symbol not found. Now let's search
for equal greater than. Okay then you
find it. So let's jump there.
Okay. That that's not what we want. So
wait.
Okay.
Wait. Not here. So go back.
Okay, go back. So search for that
symbol. Okay, go to the code these
matching lines. Search for that. So you
got
Okay. So you see
you see.
Oh I see. Um h
what?
So your
so this is bad. Okay. So that should be
uh
if you do that that works. Okay. So but
um
what is that the list function even?
You see this is what I want. Okay. But
why did I type that? Do you guys follow
me? So, Emacs by default doesn't support
AVIF. Is that true? Yeah, probably.
Well, because GNU stuff, you know, open
source, they are always late. You know,
they're going to wait for like two,
three years or five years even.
[laughter]
That's true. You know, if you want AVIF
supporting Emacs, you're going to wait
for like several years. That's always
true for open source stuff.
On the other hand, for commercial stuff
like wine language or like let's say
Google Chrome browser or the Firefox,
well, not much not so much Firefox.
Firefox became like very deep state.
Anyway, anything commercial where you
have to pay, they support it right away.
Of course,
you know, but but then uh you know the
if you want to
you know the open source like free
things to support it, you have to wait.
Anyway, so we are looking into like
esoteric details. Uh you guys probably
don't know what I'm doing. So this this
is the thing I'm looking into. So what
what programming language support this
uh thing? I forgot. Why did I write that
30 years ago? Let's see. Python Python
operators uh we want to look for the
less than equal. So what what was the
Python syntax for
less than equal? So operators assignment
true false boolean operators. Let's see
boolean operators. Uh
okay they they they use words in Python
test equality test order less than okay
so Python it's okay so it's like
less than than equal okay so Python is
using
that okay so this this is
this is what Python use you know I'm
wondering why why did I type that so
let's see
is that wam language no that's not even
wam language so less than equals to
oh yeah so you know in wam language
actually for example three less than
equal you just type less than and equal
it automatically become that
you see you all you have to do is type
less than and type equal it
automatically changes to that you see so
so I don't know how did I get this uh 30
years ago it's a typo probably a typo
so anyway so let's do that that that
that that that that
okay so you are saying that asteroid
generator tmin mean t- max tep can also
be used and the t mean greater than zero
t max less than 2 pi okay so see rose
generator for detail oh my god I don't
want that
so that's about uh you know so that's a
documentation I did this documentation
30 years ago so in general you don't
want
you know you don't want you know look at
look up the other function for detail.
You don't want that. You want just
whatever detail just like repeated here
anyway. So this is about documentation
inline documentation. So what is a rose
generator? So let's look at
um
search for dot uh search for wait.
Okay. Search for rows generator. Okay.
So you got this rows generator.
Okay.
What detail? So see rows generator for
detail. Oh god, there's a lot of them
referring to it.
Okay. So finally here rose generator n
generates uh t mining t-max row
generator also used um
ting and t-max control whether the
animation wheel trace out a complete
rose. Okay.
Uh anyway I I don't want to worry about
this now. So
okay. So, let's see
what
Yeah, you don't you don't want that.
Okay. So, let's just say that.
Okay. actually. Oh god. You know, we
were supposed to optimize this but we
already talked for hours. So
yeah. Okay. So this code, yeah, we we we
really should be working on the code
because that would be
that would be most interesting to me
though to is to optimize the code. But
now we already I think we
already like randomly chatted for so
long.
Um anyway, so
okay, can can we do this? Uh okay. So
let's see.
So we got the code. God.
Okay. So, let's do the code again.
Um,
okay. You need to work on the code.
How long have we been talking?
We've been talking for just one hour.
Okay. So, now what about the code?
Go up. Yeah, here's a code.
Okay, so
God.
Yeah, actually the code is what we
should be focusing on today. But um
okay, so you see the way it works, it's
it's pretty simple. So you know if you
do not give any um
if you do not give any parameters it
basically assumes from 0 to 2 pi I think
it basically calls you see here.
So the first argument will be 0 to 2 pi.
The second argument would be a
optional pattern. What is this?
Basically 41 number of frames 41. So um
so then we start to code number of
frames equals to optional value number
of frames which is 41. Okay. Then we
started to t minep
equals to. So this module part those are
local variables you know I should be
changing them to block because the
module is very slow. Um
so t minep
are three values we set them to be t
mean equals to range t range.
Okay. So if that range is three
what?
Yeah. So, I think there's a lot
I want to change.
Okay, I think
maybe we shut down today because right
now I'm not
uh right now I cannot code
because I had this this 200 ml of red
wine
and uh so they are so we want to
possibly improve the code. That's what
we are doing now. Okay. And in order to
do that, so we are starting to you know
code geometry
uh of this thing.
Geometry is pretty simple. So you move
so you basically at in each frame you
want to change the position of the two
end points of the line. Okay. So that
line segment and and and that would be
just cosine and sign. Okay. You can can
you see?
Yeah. So the end points basically the
coordinate x and y
for the end points of the of this line
segment they are just cosine zero and
sine zero. Okay, that's the point.
That's so so simple.
Okay. So in each frame you want to um
it's so simple. Okay. So but but but
this code there's a lot um yes there
should be a lot to change because for
example the hue.75
we can change to like blue you know the
the symbol blue.
and last frame. Okay.
Yeah, definitely I want to make some
changes to the code. Um
Okay.
Showing browser.
So, by the way, my website has not been
updated for the past 20 days because I'm
having some issue.
of our sync. So I was unable to update
my website for the past 20 days for
technical problems. Uh but I'll be able
to fix that. So what that means is right
now whatever I updated you know what
what I whatever I updated to my website
today you won't be able to see it. When
you visit you know my website you'll see
like the old uh page not whatever I did
today.
So anyway, so so you won't be able to,
in other words, you won't be able to see
this code.
Uh, but anyway, so but you can get the
code of course because the code is from
my plane curb, you know, just search for
it, the package, you you can get the
whole code. Okay. Uh, anyway, but this
should be fixed in a few days, you know.
I'm going to fix it. you you you'll be
fixed eventually. So anyway, what's
what's for today? So let's summarize. So
today
we updated this and we uh created the
code here
and we should have um
yeah the code is not too long.
Um,
and you should have um,
okay, I think that's it for today. So
I think I'm
what am I doing? So I need to also need
the code for this
and code for that.
And we want the web 4 version. We don't
want
we want the MP4 version. We don't want
Web P.
Okay. So, I'm going to do that offline.
And uh
Okay. Okay. I think that's it.
Uh yeah. So, I don't think anyone is
watching.
So, bye, guys.
>> [clears throat]
>> Okay. So, let me think about.
So, we did that. We don't need the
cardioid. We don't need envelope. We
only did asteroid
and uh okay. So close that. We want to
So this is a generator package and uh
shift enter. So
refresh. So we also have search for
asteroid.
So, asteroid 2
generator. So, asteroid 2 depends on the
hypotid.
Jesus,
I don't want that.
Okay. So,
then what about the asteroid three? So,
asteroid three.
A3 is independent, I think.
Let's try it.
Paste. Wait, can you paste it? Shift
enter.
Okay. Then you just need to say
astro generator 3.
Now question mark
to show the
um to show the documentation.
So you don't need any parameters. So
let's run it. Call the function.
Shift enter.
Okay. So it's generated a bunch of
graphics
and but you want animation. So
you you need to say list and
eight.
Okay.
Fantastic.
Now let's generate a um copy that. So
now
export.
Let's export again.
export
that thing.
Shift enter.
Great. So now let's go to
go to the docu documents directory.
Search for xx dot. That's the that
should be that latest. There it is. Open
it.
Uh, okay. Run it. Oh god. Stupid. You
know this VLC player always have this
problem. When you play it after it
finished, it just like um it goes to
this page.
Like you click play again, it goes to
that stupid page.
Okay. So, copy the file path. Close it.
The asteroid generator 3. That's right.
So, close it. Now, you want to go to the
asteroid page. It's asteroid page. So,
that would be the asteroid. Um,
there,
uh, the ellipses.
Okay. So, go back. Search for E Lip.
Okay. So,
this is where you want the code to be.
Paste the code. Uh, wait. Uh, paste
again. Wait,
wait. Uh,
okay. So, that's the animation.
Now this asteroid by ellipse. Uh.
Oh wait. So
So in this example,
what
Permission
denied. Oh Jesus. Because it's open
here.
Uh,
okay. Move to the current directory.
Okay. Then
copy the extract the URL. paste the URL,
make a link and delete the previous one.
Okay. So, so that way we updated the
figure caption.
Okay. So, now refresh. You got this
animation which uh which you don't
really need because this uh
Okay. So we don't want
open it show in browser I mean show
it's 55
gabytes
okay so
question is do you want it I don't think
so because
because as a design princip principle.
When you have some graphics,
you know the the the issue about
animation is that you want to show an
animation only when it is fitting.
You do not want to show everything by an
animation.
So for example in this
illustration to illustrate the property
of this um asteroid which is a
envelope of coaxel ellipses whose sum of
major and min minor axis is constant.
You do not need an animation for this.
if you do with an animation, it's kind
of redundant, you know, it's kind of um
so the the the optimal
design for this page is not to have
animation. Okay, that's what I think.
So,
so okay. So, wait. So, let's delete
that.
So, but there's a question about
So, then but you do need the code
though. You do need the code to show
this illustration. Uh,
wait. So, actually, so you do need a
code. So,
the code is here.
Okay. So you you kind of um
so you can add the code there. Syntax go
ahead showing browser.
Okay. So here is the code for that kind
of overkill
uh because the code is actually trying
to generate an animation
but you can give a parameter so that
number of frames equals to like two so
it doesn't generate the intermediate
frames it generates but anyway the so
but you should um actually you should
modify the code so that
so that um
so that it just generate an image. Well,
maybe not because
because you see this code right now is
generate generates an animation
which
is kind of necessary because when you
want you when you have this kind of
envelope of a set of curves
sometimes you want to show them
progressively.
So in other words,
even though this property can be shown
as one single static graphics,
but sometimes it is necessary.
I mean sometimes it's helpful when you
show this as an animation of progressive
number of curves that forms the envelope
of a new curve.
So therefore that's what this code is
for. This code generates the that
animation.
It can generate the final animation you
know just one frame or two frames
beginning and end or it can generate you
know 10 frames or 100 frames
for refined
animation. So why don't we just show it.
So for example let's call it copy it.
Okay. So let's call it
um so you need to say what is the uh
mean max mean min mean min mean min mean
min mean min mean min mean min mean min
mean min mean min mean min max uh mean
max and step okay so you can say min is
zero max is two
pi and step let's say pi that will be
like three frames I think wait that
didn't Look,
what
what did we uh
generator 3? What?
Wait, I thought uh so there is a
so it doesn't take a step. What?
Wait, that's strange.
Okay. So, there is some
problem.
This is
okay. So that works but as soon as you
give it some value it stop working.
So we need to fix that. Okay. So that is
not correct.
Oh. Oh, you need to uh Yeah, you need to
put them inside brackets. That's why.
Okay. So, you need to put them inside
brackets.
That's right. So zero to 2 pi in
increment of pi there. There it is. So
it generate three frames. Amazing. All
of them doesn't look right.
So in increment of let's say 2 pi and
see what you get. Nothing. That's not.
Let's say in increment of pi divided by
four. Let's say
okay. So this is incorrect code. Oh
Jesus.
This is actually incorrect code. I
didn't realize
formatting notebook content. Okay, I
think.
Okay, so this is incorrect code. So we
discovered a problem.
Anyway, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching.
Bye guys.