good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
and we have turns to talk about tons of
stuff
oh eight people today's busy day
so today is 2021st and uh
june 30 san francisco time
noon noonish and we're gonna talk so
if you have a questions post it okay
post in the chat
and the first stop is going to let's do
some emacs okay
remax for the first uh 10 or 15 minutes
uh and post your questions then i'll
start to talk about
that topic we have tons of topic to talk
about
you know when you are um when you failed
to be a mathematician
you become a programmer when you fail to
be a programmer
you become a comedian on youtube
this is the strategy okay this is your
plan
for life okay so let's show so let's go
to stuff like keys okay
uh my life's work stuff like keys
so go to the directory so you can see
stuff like keys lots of things okay
delete
those backup files okay this is the file
open it
make a backup okay now go to diet
show you see we have a backup so there
is a pool request
from this guy from uh he is
uh by the way he is um six supply keys
police divine dominion okay what a name
he is christian chief
you know and he's the author of the
of the some uh what's the name let's see
if we can find his
um you know he's a
zeta concern something called zed custom
method you know
it's a method for note taking
uh he's the author of some software
about that or something
so anyway he made a pull request on
sapphire keys
actually i'm not certain i'm gonna you
know this
is uh this i should add this
but you know yeah i have to think about
it so but
so i have to look at the code i have to
think about he he is uh
suggesting me to add some uh key
bindings okay
so what i typically do let's just pull
it okay
let's just pull it so flat keys
so delete that okay make sure we have a
backup okay
let's see let's make another backup go
to diet show in browser
i mean show show it you see we have two
backup
now delete starfly keys okay
yeah deleted are you sure yes i'm
certain
wait is it gun yes now go to
uh uh isiah
git pull okay wait before i pull i have
to merge
now if i don't like it i'll just revert
okay because
that's uh that's my methodology of
dealing with pull requests i just
pull in and look at the code and makes
possibly make some changes review it
and in this case he is adding some keys
for indent rigid tree
now i don't use that command but so
possibly i can use you know it should be
in stuff like he's possibly not i have
to think about it
but since i'm doing a live show let's
just pull it okay
because otherwise you're gonna have to
wait for me to
um think about things confirm merge
yes go ahead
okay do we have comments okay confirm
merge
okay he said okay let's see what he said
to be honest i don't know
if this kind of integration with other
packages should be part of some flykeys
or rather part of the users in it
it probably doesn't scale to try to
support arrow keys in stuff like he
command my
map everywhere just close the pull
request if you don't think
it should uh merge okay so anyway
so he so he so i just merged now let's
do pool
okay there it is pulled now let's go to
okay go to diet show okay there here is
a new file
now here is old file let's copy the file
name okay
uh let's
mark them copy it you can see the
command icon on the left
the pink window okay so here are the two
file names
now let's do some powershell magic
thanks
thank you microsoft
[Laughter]
for open source the powershell okay
powershell method so
now magic uh
magic a brief okay uh
diff okay powershell diff that's that's
a syntax for powershell div
if you don't know now let's just so cat
file name one and cad file name two
so this is the command we want to do now
give us powershell paste it okay
can we magnify let's magnify okay
magnify actually
control and scroll the mouse window okay
control scroll up so we have powershell
show me the different differentiation
enter okay so there it is
what there's not many changes only two
okay two something like two lines of
change now by the way
so we are using powershell div okay let
me explain something about powershell
for unix for you unix
idiots so first of all copy that
i don't like you know copy that and
paste it here so we can see better
so what is going on so the
so let's let's see so
so first of all let me show so this is
i'll put a powershell diff let me
explain the powershell diff okay
so that line that line is
uh this is abbreviation powershell has
lots of ideas for abbreviation okay so
div
is actually measure uh
compare object okay let me show you
let's go back to powershell
okay what's the what's the other
powershell window
close it okay so you can see
hey let me show you okay help diff
so you can see the full name is compare
object
okay and we also used cat so what is the
full name of cat
so help cat so you can see get content
okay so that is so instead of saying
if the proper name is compare
object and the cat
is uh what is cat get content
get content
okay so also in powershell uh typically
the
it's case insensitive okay you can have
get content or you know it's not case
sensitive
for variables for the environment
variables for
comparison operators basically it's all
case insensitive in powershell
so here is the full syntax for
powershell
okay so we are using actually the
compare object
comlet okay and by the way
if you want to know if you don't know
nothing about powershell check out my
tutorials okay
the fantastic tutorial and by the way
yesterday
yesterday guys yesterday i spent [ __ ]
five hours and downloaded the vivaldi
the open source phonetics browser
vivaldi
um you know i spent five hours to read
through
all the options and stuff and
so my conclusion
okay so i was using uh i was using
microsoft
edge okay so i i moved
something like 230 tabs into
uh vavaldi you can see on the left panel
you know
vertical tab is a fantastic thing it's a
great feature okay
so i but i spent five hours looking
through all the
you know going through each and every uh
options in vivaldi
uh try you know that's typically what i
do
a lot of time spent so my conclusion is
that you know there's one feature i
really want
that is i want the javascript to be off
by default okay javascript off by
default
but on each side i should be able to
press a button
and have it uh and toggle the javascript
unfortunately that feature is not in
varadi i was hoping it should be there
it wasn't there so
i have to install then i have to install
the
u-block arranger by the way it has a you
know ad blocking building
i have to install u-block or engine and
also i have to install the
uh the close duplicate tab
and it's also not in variety i was
hoping it would be there
but anyway my conclusion is that
compared to
edge you know in fact i think edge is
better
from a user interface user point of view
it appears to me although i only used
uh vavaldi for one day appears to me uh
edge is actually faster it's better in
general
okay um you know i
i had 200 tabs here but i deleted
since i moved to the vavaldi so
user interface wise in general i think
edge is actually
better but however edges from microsoft
as you know you know we don't we don't
like microsoft so
so i you know and i am having problems i
mean
i don't really i cannot trust microsoft
exactly
maybe one day they will open source
their edge browser i'm not sure
uh they open source you know powershot
lots of things but
you know wait wait till they open source
uh edge browser
so vavaldi in theory should be more
trustworthy because it's
is you know kind it's kind it's it it's
from the opera people opera opera is
another idiocy you know long story
you know i've been using browsers since
1995.
my first browser is nc mosaic okay
so i've been using browsers and i have
been you know as a nerd i've been
obsessive about all the browsers over
the past 30 years
30 uh 20 let's see
25 years okay obsessed about every
version you know come and go
lots of them don't exist anymore this is
you know
and and typically since 1999
since 1996 1998
typically i always use like three
browsers or four
uh at the same time like right now i
have you know i have microsoft edge
i have audi i have the of course the
google chrome
who looks into your pants all the time
and then you have uh you know the brave
so i
been nerding about about browsers you
know for the past
25 years and observe their history the
ryzen 4 and
all the nerd [ __ ] idiots talk about
them
and i have like 10 10 10 10 articles
maybe
about different browsers including many
linux ones you know the ice
whistle the whatever [ __ ] you know they
usually go nowhere the idiot the idiocy
of the open source phonetics
uh anyway so browser so user interface
wise
edge seems slightly better just like you
know
same thing okay they are the same but
trustworthiness you know i
i cannot honestly trust microsoft
uh but you know even though it has lots
of settings you know
actually i was surprised it has tons of
settings to
let you trick the browser so i also
spent you know
10 hours or something look into every
one of them
but but it's microsoft you know i cannot
i'm not sure i can trust it
who knows what they do behind the scenes
even with your you know
telemetry or whatever the jargon you
know matrix
turned off but vavaldi suppose but by
the way the valley is not open source
okay that's funny thing i found you know
bavaria
so they basically it's a robot is a
clone
of the google chrome i mean the you know
the chromium the [ __ ] another open
source [ __ ]
chromium google chrome the evil
empire the biggest supporter of open
source you know
so they created chronium chromium but
why don't they just open source the
[ __ ] google chrome
i don't know i don't want no [ __ ]
chromium where i have to
be like to spend 10 years to know about
programming then
then possibly dedicate it on the field
of you know
web technology then possibly again try
to look at the source code
the [ __ ] linux unix idiots
so open source you know google empire
open source so they created chromium
and then uh without these uh
basically is the um you know from
chromium
based on chromium and they added
proprietary code you know
again the open source [ __ ] you know
they are supposed they are supporting
open source but they added proprietary
code
into the body so they you know it's not
fully open source
uh so vivadi in theory
i you know it should probably be more
trustworthy than
uh microsoft edge but these days you
don't know unless
you you you have 10 years experience
working with browser you know javascript
and c and c plus plus
and compilers [ __ ] then possibly then
you
dedicate your every one hour a day to
look at source code then maybe you can
be sure
that you know whether vavaldi is more
trustworthy than
microsoft edge but today as you know
it's not like 10 years ago 10 years ago
you can tell
today between these two in theory
bravadi should be more trustworthy
because that's uh you know the
chanted by the open source phonetics but
but
i'm not too sure so anyway but
so on desktop i think i'm gonna use
bavaria for now
because you know microsoft i'm not sure
but
but there's one uh major feature without
these
lagging okay that is if you are using a
tablet which i do
a microsoft surface tablet okay let me
show you okay
okay microsoft you belong to microsoft
microsoft surface tablet
like that okay when you lie in bed
so just i do you know i die in bed and
die
you know to prevent my ass from rotting
so you have to walk around i take the
tablet and read and walk around
so on tablet one critical feature is
that you want to be able to swipe it
and go back to the previous page as
opposed to
you know supposed to you know aim for
that little back
icon oh you don't have a keyboard right
i mean on the tablet so
i was you know i walk around so you have
to
so you don't want that you want to just
swipe it and go back to the previous
page
so that that feature is critical on
tablet that's supported by google chrome
and by you know by google chrome by
brave uh by uh google chrome brave and
by microsoft edge
but it's not supported uh but uh by
varadi and no
um nor the firefox
thing you know the the firefox the guy
who donated to antifa
who gave you a donation to antifa uh so
okay i hope i am not too repetitive
and that's my summary of my you know the
past
six hour study of about the comparison
to microsoft
edge okay now let's now that's the
that concludes the first digression
now let's go back to the uh
okay powershell yeah powershell and then
we were talking about let's close that
okay so yeah if you don't know
powershell go check out my tutorial okay
fantastic the most
concise easy to understand no nonsense
tutorial about
powershell okay especially if you are
you if you are the linux unix phonetics
you love my page because
i give you exactly what how things are
without
the marketing blurb and without the open
source phoneticism
a powershell okay cross-platform okay
works on windows
let me show you okay works on windows of
course and works on the mac
you can see and works on uh linux
you know because the powershell they is
it's based on the.net open source code
was called.net core but now it's just
called.net
you know it's a complex jargons okay.net
is microsoft's
framework like one system for everything
you know it kind of you know kind of
like java they have a jvm they have a uh
you know the virtual machine so so
one.net
is the foundation.net from framework
microsoft.net okay
then you have a virtual machine then you
have languages c
sharp c sharp f sharp which is a
function of programming
better than pascal
c sharp f sharp for microsoft this is 20
years ago 2002 or so okay so they
compiled to the
uh the the.net virtual machine called
uh common language uh common language
something and
and you know one system one coherent
unlike a
supposed to the uh in contrast to
the linux unix way if nothing is
working together everything is
independent and they fight over
you know the gtk versus what
you know kde and what could not mean
crap
um okay so microsoft
created net framework called microsoft
you know it works on microsoft operating
systems only
but since five years ago microsoft
opened their eyes they think
oh it's time we swallow open source
open source is going to be wiped out now
micro you know
you want to play games you use you have
to buy a pc you have to use windows
and if you happen to be a coder yeah you
use microsoft
then microsoft now supports linux and
microsoft is by the way
statistically speaking if you count
lines of code open source microsoft is
the
number one open source supplier
contributor as far as lines of code is
concerned
microsoft and the google empire you
[ __ ]
open source phonetics [ __ ]
uh you know you you you you guys get us
you know uh give us a worse society
okay any comments okay i'm gonna check
out the comments in a bit
uh so let's digressions let's revert
back to our digestions but first of all
check
the status just make sure i'm not
talking
with my audio off okay which have
happened uh
once or twice okay so
so powershell okay so did i finish the
story about.net
so net five years ago becomes open
source then
okay the jargon okay the net so they
begin in the beginning
the name is dot net core that is the
open source version of the.net okay but
then then they dropped the code
so so so dot net core is the open source
version
and dot net framework or just you know
net framework is the microsoft version
they're actually different
then a few years ago two years ago or so
they dropped even the core so
now it's just.net dot net refers to the
open source
version of microsoft by the way they no
longer develop the
the microsoft only version so net is
like
the open so you know it's the open
source thing now
so and powershell is work is on top of
that it
relies on.net so it's kind of you know
it's it's a designed thing it's a design
it's a systematic
like you know the open source phonetics
the the
cathedral versus the bazaar you know the
esr
idiot so like emacs
like commonly like this emacs and
net they are the cathedral they are with
a one
you know one coherent design a cathedral
it's not like a small piece here like
the unix [ __ ]
unix philosophy [ __ ]
okay so good morning break the loop
good morning but i'm alive and you are
alive
good morning nas okay so what are we
saying
comedian on youtube so christa is a very
nice knowledgeable guy yes he is
uh so you know so let's so we're gonna
go back to stuff like keys okay
so powershell digression so he that's
how you do
diff on powershell but there's one thing
i wanted to mention about
diff in powershell diff in powershot you
know i tell you things
as it is no marketing [ __ ] and no
phoneticism [ __ ]
okay powershell diff is inferior to the
unix
div okay this is all
you know you are looking at the output
of powershell div there's no color
option by the way
on linux there's no color option neither
unless you
you have to install diff color okay so
if you are a linux
you know if you are a young linux guy
you
go check out my xsa linux tutorial
everything you wanted to know about
linux spy command line
okay all the things you wanted to know
about
linux okay so there's stiff so by def
you know unique steve have
a lot of options powershell doesn't have
all you got
all you get is this you don't you know
you cannot
create patch div you cannot have you
know color and
you know that's all this is all you get
despite all the options
so it's inferior okay but anyway on on
unix div you have lots of
options for example ignore um space
ignore line uh you
ignore you know uh line uh things like
that
some of them powershot also have but but
the the major thing is that you have
this kind of
you know plus minus uh thing
and also on linux by the way another a
different tip is that you can actually
not
use stiff but use git act you know use
git as a diff
you know use git as a general purpose
tool
for diff so actually i have that so
you know because i have git installed so
let's see um
git div okay here's the syntax let's see
if we can use that
for for this um purpose okay
so this is one file file one
let's copy okay
okay file one and file two
okay so let's see if that works copy
that
go to powershell okay
then paste it
please oh fantastic it works
fantastic okay so that's a tip
that's a concrete solid tip from star
talk show i hope you
linux fans you can you know find
something useful in my talk show
besides just you know laughing at me
okay so there is the powershell div okay
so actually
uh so what's changed oh okay so wait
uh so plus minus okay so this
is minus and uh
okay so the minus is actually a dish the
addition because i
i reversed the argument so he added
uh sapphire keys and then rigid
the map okay
so but what is the what is the key for
i mean what keys map to indent rigid
tree map okay i don't know
let's look uh so back to emacs
so let's uh shrink
indent okay so
now let's go to soft light keys
okay open it and list matching lines
there it is okay so
it added this one
okay this movement key integration with
building emacs packages
no i'm not sure we should we shouldn't
have that
uh so he created this basically he
created this
whole new section yeah i don't think it
should be
but anyway but which which key is mapped
to that
okay it doesn't even have a key so by
default it this doesn't have a key
so okay so anyway i i probably
gonna add you know accept the audition
but
probably i'm gonna going to make some
changes but
hold on a second i don't have that here
right yeah so in stop light keys you
don't have this command okay
so that is that let's go back to
um let's go back let's clean up
so um okay that's that folks sapphire
keys we merged
divine dominions code thank you okay
let's say thank you okay thank you
commit
okay so fly keys okay more efficient
than
vim you should check out and we should
do another
vim golf to prove it
someday some you know so let's
so now let's let's see uh
what's a comment okay no nobody no
comment what
what's going on with you guys
four people 15 people comments guys
okay let's see let's check
okay next topic so we've done stuff like
keys
okay so hold on a second let me see go
to
star talk show let's write down what
we've talked about
okay okay um
stuff like keys merge
pool request
okay so let's just write it down
so that's one thing we did show in
browser
okay now the let's turn on javascript
so that's today's talk show
what uh what it's not showing up
wait what something is wrong oh
okay i wait oh i wrote i added to the
wrong place
yeah here okay so we talked about that
we talked about powershell
then we talked about vivaldi
showing browser okay
what's the next topic guys
hello hi btx what do you think about the
windows subsystem for unix okay i
haven't installed it
i what you know since i got the pc about
three months ago
i plan to install you know the microsoft
linux
but it turns out powershell is good
enough for me
i don't need i don't need linux anymore
you know all i need so
yeah so so the linux all i need is
basically the you know python
golan or the programming languages and
uh
and uh and some shell tools you know the
bash
bash diff find grip but now with
powershell
i don't need those anymore so i spent a
lot of time studying powershell
so i don't need a windows subsystem for
linux what what do i need it for
you know if i actually but but as a
technologist you know i'm
you know i'm always into you know i mean
linux as well
and observe you know the growth or
changes evolution of
linux so i might as well just buy
another laptop
uh you know it today is cheap you know
200 dollars get you a
laptop then you put on linux it on it so
you don't
mess with the you know this complex
emulation stuff
okay so let's read the comments okay
let's see where we go
here so i want to say
you know what so is something i want to
say
you know i have tons of things okay so
um so
talk show uh programming languages okay
so i have lots of tutorials so
powershell um what
i don't remember okay relax and
let's see what's the next topic okay let
me finish reading the comment
yes microsoft edge microsoft edge is now
also based on chromium uh it's based on
you know the the the engine of the
browser it's called blink
you know it's a long history you know
since i observed the browser
was brother was one in 1999
brother was two okay
you know i can talk 10 hours for this
history of the browsers okay
so so anyway
google chrome began
okay here's here's a short version of
the browser engine okay browser engine
um where do i begin
okay so and and some of the some of the
detail i forgot
anyway so some mozilla so so so uh
netscape okay
netscape the daddy of mozilla okay
netscape
in 1996 you know there's netscape
uh before netscape there's nc as uh you
know the mosaic
okay which i showed before
uh what's what's what's my other
the politics okay my other pages now
there's one thing i haven't
i haven't fixed in opera is that
ah [ __ ] you know i i want the i want the
previous tab key
or next tab key to go to the to go to
the neighbor tabs
not to the previous actually the last
used tab
so let's fix that okay so
opera so alt oats
tea you know one thing i like is that
opera still supports
this menu you know i i mean not opera
the
vivaldi ot uh s
then uh so i want to so tabs okay so
tabs uh tabs upper
operation okay you cannot enlarge okay
that's a flow
on this page you cannot make it larger
or smaller can you
yeah it's that's okay i think i i
consider this a flaw of ui design
you should have not have exceptions so
in
opera they made this settings page
exceptional
you know on the settings page it doesn't
allow you to magnify the font what
why what the [ __ ] okay so anyway
in the tabs i want the i want the tab
you know to
uh
to move to the um let's see where is it
okay i have to read
okay so beginning from the beginning
okay tab display
uh new type position after
okay where is it somewhere
okay tab cycling you see cycle in
recently used order
that's no good cycle in tab order that
is good okay
because if i just have you know if i
cycle in reasons because tab
i cannot switch to new tabs it just
cycle back and forth
so i want cycle in table order this way
you see i can i can go all the way let's
see where is my current tab
you see i can go back back back back
back go to all my tabs
i've been working on these pages by the
way css tutorial
uh and stuff and and this
beautiful gamer thing you guys
in your generation thing okay
so okay so shrink so that's a tab okay
so
so what were we talking about we were
talking about
yeah so we also talked about diff okay
so actually write it down
okay so shrink uh
i what what did i do
okay show in browser so we talked about
uh magnafly magnify we talked about
soft light keys powershell
uh vavaldi browser uh
then we talked about
tabs okay where is it
not tabs but the diff
okay here copy the url
back to emacs paste it here
wait copy wait what the
copy the url back to emax
paste okay there it is make a make a
link
and show in browser okay
we talked about diff unix stiff
uh where were we uh so we were talking
about
tabs okay the body tabs okay
okay so what's the next thing we want to
talk about okay close
this mosaic oh yeah browser history okay
history of browsers okay
let me quickly just talk about that so
you have mosaic first from the
ins you know from from this ncsa
ncsa stands for national center for
super computing applications okay that
is uh
at university of illinois at obama obama
champaign
you know that's a podunk town actually
that's a podunk town
that's actually where wufang research
the creator
of wufam languages and mathematica is is
that by the way
wolfram research you know wolfram stefan
wufem
has a new book okay you go
i recommend it okay so for example let
me show you a new book
combinators the granddaddy of
theoretical
computer science the foundation the
you can consider combinators to be the
foundation
of computer science okay
and together with lambda calculus forget
about tuning machine the [ __ ] [ __ ] the
linux idiots
you know the linux c c plus plus type of
people you guys typically they when they
talk about
you know things related to the
foundation of computer science
they are always they have always you
know
chances at 90 of a time they are say
tuning machine that's all they know
the idiots incredible idiots or
well sometimes lambda calculus okay
which from the mostly from the emacs or
these people they are mentioned i'm not
calculus
but but you know but basically all these
are kind of equivalent
the turing machine is from more of a
hardware perspective
while lambda calculus and combinators is
more from
a pure uh pure abstract
kind of mathematical or symbolic
perspective okay
and this perspective is actually better
so lambda calculus and combinators
combinators is actually more kind of
more
uh better okay but more elegant more
better
better in some sense so anyway stephen
wufam has a new book
printed hot hot you know copy of the
book and but however the content of the
book
is already um it's on his blog okay he
has several blocks so let me show you
this this this vlog is fantastic i tell
you guys okay go
read it go read it after you know after
my talk show
go read it combinators a 100 year
celebration
you know he stephen wolfram
his blogs are always written in a way
that anyone can understand it
okay you don't need four years of
computer science degree or whatever you
don't need a degree you can understand
and also it's not
it's not like you know uh
you know uh watered down you know
teaching kids
hi uh my name is you know my name is joe
blog
i'm gonna i'm going to teach you physics
look look
water look this is water
teaching physics that's what happens on
youtube all over the place
well i'm going to teach you computer
science let me show you what is a
variable you don't see that okay
you go read his blog real
you know if you are a computer scientist
you will learn
if you are already a professor of
computer science
but you never studied studied
combinators you can
read his stuff you'll learn things okay
now
combinators okay real stuff and you know
he
he he has a video three hours and 30
minutes okay
talking about that okay let's we need to
turn on javascript
the complexity [ __ ] of the
of the technology okay he's
got a video but but also he's got two
blocks okay wait
you know he uh two or three okay
uh very low long okay his block is
typical okay
three hours reading you [ __ ]
millennials [ __ ]
you know with your five minutes reading
three hours reading okay go read it
combinators you know i know many of you
you're often asked what do you think of
rust because
what do you think of this technology
what do you think of like linux
new you know this you know rust golem
things like that read this one okay read
combinators that
that's the you know this or whatever
that
you learn things the real thing and
and uh in detail okay in detail that
you know i would even you know he's
known as a maker
maniac you know he brag all the time i
invented you know i'm the only one
but i would actually help him to claim
that
you will not see these kind of writings
you know the
the approach the depth in other computer
scientists okay
i mean there are many computers
respectable
i e you know i respect many other
computer scientists
but i would um i would
highly recommend stefan wolfe and stuff
actually
because you in fact you know other
computer scientists
yeah they also is you know great but
they uh
you know he's you know read stefan wufam
okay
that's that's what i say okay stephen
will frame so that's a digression
um so what were we talking about
uh we were talking about so um so how
did i get into
history of history of browsers okay back
to history
history of process
history of browsers
okay let's write it down so we have a
kind of a topic of what we talked about
so back to history
history of browsers so the first browser
around 1992 1995 is the
mosaic okay from
you know it's from the national
supercomputer center is basically
university of illinois at obama obama
urbana champaign okay that's a place
that's a small
small poden town podong town university
town
where i lived for half a year and that's
also where wu farm research
is at so that's the first browser okay
then
then netscape the granddaddy of firefox
so that's the 1990s then microsoft so
so most mosaic they are academics okay
so they shut down
netscape took over next state netscape
is a commercial entity you know
money is their concern and they're gonna
they're gonna
they're gonna wipe out microsoft by the
way if you are open source phonetic you
don't know you know you did you
you weren't born at that time the at the
time 1990
1998 the the thinking is that
netscape and the web you know that
that's a new thing
we're gonna wipe out microsoft in ten
years there's gonna know
no more microsoft
oh my god the linux linux [ __ ]
phonetics [ __ ]
so the idea is that you know microsoft's
gonna be gone
you know an escape netscape also based
on money
money makes the world around so then
microsoft
saw it microsoft you know
oh my god web is coming up coming so we
need to do something
we need to do something so microsoft but
the code you know according to this i
you know many
you know i read part of the wikipedia
wikipedia
great resource lots of information and
true information because i can verify it
okay so microsoft
uh supposedly bought the mosaic monsega
mosaic
code and they created internet explorer
and by the way okay let me show you my
articles so you can
see the veracity
of the true history i'm talking about
okay
because i have like 10 or 20 articles
about browsers and the back that what
what's happening back then okay so you
just search for
sardi
netscape browser okay so there it is
the the first article okay okay web
browsers to
so so we got one article then we got
another article web browsers
2003 pro and con okay
then lots of other html timelines
some of them is very old and crappy uh
i mean my article and then you have the
white opera browser sucks
okay then you have the bug reporting
attitude
that's the beginning of the open source
this is around 2005 okay
like everyone say every you know no
every
you don't hear it much these days but
everyone is saying oh
there's a problem oh i you know my
brother crashed
[ __ ] up what can i do oh you should go
report help you know report
it you know help the you know that's
open source the beginning of the open
source
phoneticism okay let me let me show you
the articles each one
a little bit okay netscape crap this is
written in 2002
so microsoft created microsoft internet
explorer
you know so i was you know i don't like
microsoft you know i'm not
you know i but you know i'm kind of
neutral
so i observed every version of netscape
and microsoft internet explorer
every version internet explorer is
better in every aspect
okay let me tell you that that is true
internet explorer back in so this you
can look at the year 2002
this article is written for which i got
banned by these [ __ ] these
mac phonetics you can still trace you
know look at you know this is post on
the
uh omni group how many groupies another
browser
omni browser on the mac okay this is a
mac os
mac os x talk you know it's a news group
it's not new scope it's a mailing list
okay eventually i got banned
after two years talking about
my opinions so you can actually you can
try to look at what these people are
doing
back then i was replying to this guy
my rant okay omni
you know omni browser let me show you
okay if you don't know
most of you don't know you don't you
don't remember omni browser okay but you
can
find information from wikipedia
um
okay omni browser what
so so
yeah omni web okay it's called omni web
you know they lasted for like 10 years
you know so anyway so
you know i'm saying this in part because
you know the young people and you guys
you don't know nothing
they they're gonna tell you what do you
think of this browser the new one the
on the linux or the open source whatever
they come and go you know the ice wizard
that long
big ugly history i seen them you know
each one the [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ]
uh anyway so so
so where are we talking about so what um
so let me go back to the uh netscape
okay
so since microsoft internet explo
explorer uh came out
each version every year each version of
internet
explorer is better than netscape in
every aspect
netscape crashes more often landscape is
slower
netscape uses more memory netscape
is less standard compliant you know the
w3c just came up you know
it's an escape supports css less
you know escape is the money grabbing
skunk you know an escape
so that's that is why internet explorer
won the browser wall so by 2002
netscape is basically dead the pipe
dream they're going to wipe out
microsoft dead
so since ie you know ie
wong the microsoft stopped doing
anything to the browser you know they
just let it sit for like 10 years
then around then netscape is struggling
you know this escape is gonna dead
struggling for you know the last breath
you know struggling
so they the open source idea came around
that time
now we're gonna release netscape so that
all the people can
can code you know all the [ __ ] nut
idiots
can code and then then escape
will revive and beat microsoft
so you know so there's a famous jwz
you know i have quite a few articles
about jwz
you know he he he he he's an [ __ ]
okay
anyway i'm kind of rambling over so
netscape
um so netscape died okay but the the
but the unix people the linux the unix
people they lie they keep lying
to them to them they'll say oh microsoft
the evil
[ __ ] they bundle ie with their windows
and blah blah therefore they kill
netscape not because it's better but in
my opinion
netscape died not because microsoft
tried this you know do
uh you know dirty tactics but the the
primary reason
is netscape compared to ie
for every version every aspect netscape
is worse
okay the [ __ ] fuckness escape but the
unix people they lie they we
you you'll not hear that opinion liars
[ __ ] the unix you know linux
at this time is you know getting very
popular but it's not
but you still mostly you still talk
about unix
not linux okay so ie wong
so for the next 10 years ie you know
microsoft they do nothing because
because web is not their business they
they are there
to sell operating systems then firefox
came up okay firefox eventually you know
an escape
you know it's an escape they came up
with an
escape communicator you know bloated
[ __ ] extremely
ugly bloated [ __ ] then eventually
firefox by year 2005 you know firefox is
the new one
mozilla foundation they you know then by
mozilla became what you know took over
basically
they eat you know so you can look up
wikipedia browser history they have you
know charts and all that
they show you when net firefox becomes
the more
um better you know much better browser
than ie because ie
doesn't stop changing because microsoft
you know they
already won't they don't they stop
changing so but
firefox so firefox when it began for the
first 10 years most most of 2000s
they are better in every way then ie
you have features you know you can just
like bavardi today you know
like you guys open source [ __ ] fanatics
you have so many features you can change
things but
firefox they gradually removed every
search feature
just like google just like they turned
become evil
you know firefox mozilla in theory
they are nonprofit yeah they are some
sort of
you know they are not i think they're
i'm not sure they are profit or not i
mean
anyway they are open source you know but
actually they are just
after money so firefox then google
chrome
around i think 2009 you know google
chrome came up
anyway the engine situation is that okay
and also apple okay apple uh in 2003
or something they started to create a
safari their own browser
so when safari was born they borrowed
the open source code from the
kde was it named kde
okay yeah k-k-k-d-yeah
kde uh i don't even remember the names
now okay kde browser they um what's the
name
anyway anyway so it becomes a long
history 20 years ago i don't remember
the names now kd
you know in in fact i had conqueror i
think
conqueror or maybe conqueror is a new
one but anyway
kd has a browser open source okay
so safari apple borrowed their code
in the first three years or so they
contribute back
then after a while they no longer
because you know because working with
open source
you know you have different needs you
have different priorities so
apple then apple then
the kde the browser engine become webkit
called webkit okay
so that's safari then google chrome
around 2008 also borrowed the webkit
okay so webkit is google chrome's
original
the browser engine but about three or
about five years ago google chrome
also split from webkit so they renamed
their engine blink
blink okay
okay so i'm gonna show you some
wikipedia articles so you can see
what i'm talking about so webkit that's
uh
you know you can read about khtml yeah
so the
it was the open source one is called
cage
k html from the kde
you know the phonetics the linux people
then
it becomes you know webkit then
blink okay
then google when google's chrome began
they um
blink okay there it is so google
borrowed from webkit
then then split they named it blink
okay uh microsoft edge when it began
okay so microsoft you know they have
their internet explorer
then around um
five years ago something like that they
saw that you know then google chrome
basically
took over become the most popular then
microsoft is trying to get back to the
you know the web then they
you know they internet explorer they try
to update then
they write a complete new browser engine
by itself
by microsoft itself uh called edge
then what happens is that google you
know google [ __ ] around with it you
know google do devious things
so that edge browser was better than
google chrome
in many ways faster but
google you know google checks you know
google website you know youtube and so
on they check if
it's using blink you know the
microsoft's
browser if they found it is then they do
something to their code so that
microsoft edge becomes slower that's
what google did
so microsoft you know this article and
also i have a
i have a blog you know you just search
the web you'll find you know
you'll find so that's
that's what happened to microsoft
nothing microsoft can do so microsoft
eventually decided okay we're gonna
switch to
whatever the engine google is using
itself link
so microsoft edge switch to the blink
that is why okay so lots of the cloak
and dagger you know the [ __ ]
uh human behavior okay including open
source people
that's what they do okay that's it
that i think that's it for today
i think i rambled in the fast you know
you know okay i
so that's um so we talked over for an
hour now
so that's it for today anything else
so luis says hi luis do you consider
golang a complete replacement for
c or is c still worth learning to create
free and open source for you
luis for i think you are a c fan right
and you also call c
and c plus first right i mean then
why do you ask me that question because
i'm not
fit to answer that question i don't know
c i never called it c
or c plus first but from a language
design point of view
c and c plus first sucks donkey s
that i'm certain for sure i am qualified
to
make that claim you know i i believe
if you ask me okay even though i never
called it c and c plus first but anyway
the question is do you consider golan
a complete complete replacement for c or
c
or c no i don't think so because even
though c
sucks but c has you know uh memory
uh you know manual memory management
which golan doesn't have
doesn't you know goal line is automatic
management memory management
management so for real-time systems you
i
you know you do need a manual
memory management so i don't so golan is
not a replacement for c
but however gold line is designed as a
replacement for c
plus first however in the industry many
c plus first they don't like it you know
they still stick with c
plus plus these idiots because they want
they
they want you know they they want the
in-float [ __ ]
crap they want they want the memory
management
i think it's crap so
anyway gold line is designed to replace
c plus first
but it didn't succeed
much that much but in my opinion
technically speaking
i in my opinion i believe golan can
replace
at least 50 percent of all software
return in
c plus first okay now
listen to this what i say carefully and
precisely okay
i believe that 50
of software that's rated written in c
plus plus
can be replaced by gold land without
suffering any speed
without becoming slower okay and the
code will be
much better simpler less code and
faster okay that's my claim 50
of all software written in c plus plus
not c okay c plus first can be replaced
by
golan without suffering any bad
consequences
that's my claim i believe that
as far as whether you happen it's not
likely to happen because you know
until 20 years later you have to wait 20
years
until the sleepless first programmers
die you know you have to wait
for the young younger generation to take
over that's what happens with other
languages too
[Laughter]
okay that's it for today why did you
switch to
advantage to cherry brown so silent
tourists oh that's
important so so that question is about
about
key binding you know key switches okay
key uh
keyword switches okay let me answer that
basically i'm done i'm done today
um let me answer that let me show you
again so this question about
keyboard um key switches okay this is my
keyboard
this is kinesis kinesis advantage two
okay um uh cherry uh cherry red silent
switches
okay i bought it about three months ago
240 okay this is ultimate hacking
you can find reviews on my website okay
so why do i buy a new one because i had
a previous
one that's a brown switch okay so let me
show you
so you can see again let me show you
again you can see my reviews here okay
i have reviews uh full detail and read
video review
because i'm suffering for uh from isi
okay
i have too many articles to show you
okay so let me copy that
uh so let's go back to talk show and
paste
it here so what we talked about so
keyboard review and let me show you
search for xrd isi okay
let me show you uh isi hand exercise
toys okay i have like tens of articles
about
rsi so you can see each one of them
eyesight hands exercise toys okay so let
me show you
so this is the chinese
the chinese hand exercise ball okay then
juggling balls
uh i should show you some juggling some
other today
so that's one article then uh
that's okay that's the index so i sign
my experiences i want to show you one
that's written recently about
okay so i have to read my typing isi
experience
summary okay so summary you go to
uh 2016 2000 in 2016
2008 here this one okay
okay uh turn on javascript so you can
see the video
i actually talked about it so you can
see your photo
right here it still hurts you know
uh now and then not today
not today but when i type too much it
hurts here
and i realize and so it's a brown key so
it's i'm using a brown key switch switch
you know if if you don't have rsi or if
you don't type that much
it doesn't really matter but if you do
have rsi you type
a lot like me i type a turn okay you
have to measure it that i talked about
in my articles
you have actually you have to actually
get a key lock to actually know
in comparison you know how much you
actually type
because as a programmer you you know
most of you will say oh i type
all day i type a lot therefore this or
that crap
okay actually get a key lock then you
know
then you compare you're typing you know
how much you keystroke you actually push
compared to me you don't type
[Laughter]
okay so i mean i mean this is not i'm
not i'm not bragging
okay so there are different categories
you know
programmers a writer then heavy you know
blogger or gamer you have to measure it
then you know actually where you
fall into then you know then your
opinion
if you are the you know the data entry
clerk that or like me
type that much you know basically two or
three times more than
a typical programmer then
then opinions then then you can see the
significance of penis
because if you don't type much like
typic like most
the vast majority of the you know do it
yourself you know phonetics
uh let me show you okay if you are
vast majority of the hobbyist you know
do it yourself keyboard you know
most of those people you know especially
the plank
you know happy hacking lovers the plank
idiots
uh where's the prank here very popular
okay 40
[ __ ] [ __ ] you 40
you know you do you 40 yeah great if you
type as much like me you get eyes
you're gonna see a doctor you know by
next year
uh you'll be fired for you know you'll
be done for
your programming career is gone you're
[ __ ] you know so most of these people
they don't type that much
you know yeah but they are you know
do-it-yourself fans or whatever
yeah great okay but but when
when it comes to certain opinions you
have to judge you have to know you know
what what is your background
you have to you know there's a there's
science about
keys and rsi okay it's not just you my
opinion oh my opinion i think this way
i think that way okay so so
so my opinion okay this is science okay
is that if you really type you know in
the data entry clerk
category let or writers a lot okay
or you write a lot of blogs or you play
lots of chat games you know where you
have to type in real time
not voice but type you know for several
hours a day
continuously or if you have rsi
then in my opinion the red key switch
you have to you know address you know
the
basically linear light linear key switch
matters significantly okay that's what
happened to me
so i have you know i have i have this a
hand pin
you know like this photo you know i put
this salon pass
you know this is one though this is one
of those painkillers
uh i had this about you know starting
around 2017
i think so anyway
so i eventually you know this beginning
of this year about
uh in march or april i finally spent
you know i bought this new kinesis red
switch that
that solve the problem okay
essentially essentially solve the
problem
but if i type if i still type too much
the problem will come back you know pain
here
so you've seen you've seen my past
videos i used to do this
make you know make this um
is kind of like a massage pain here
right here
i don't have now i don't have it now but
it happens you know
two days ago sometimes you'll come up
when if i type too much
so if you type a lot or if you have rsi
linear red suite light linear red
switches is significant okay don't get
brown switch okay that's the context i
have to give you the context okay not
just random uh you know
do it yourself and you know oh i think
this way or what switch you know
okay that's uh that's that
if you like my stuff okay put money in
my pocket for my talk show okay if you
like
if you like my well yeah if you like my
stuff you find my
talk show useful uh you know donate
paypal patreon or amazon gift card or
whatever okay i have you
you can find links on my website
so let me actually
that's it for me today i'm gonna shut
down in one minute okay
i cannot get to all the questions
so if you have last words post it now
uh
do you know gage gator on clear switch
35 grams okay that's that's pretty good
hello leocado
my loyo loyo fan
uh okay that's it yeah i'm shutting down
in one minute i'm gonna just
read the comments casually you see new
queue from keyboardio yeah keybody okay
they came out
so keyboard io you know let me show you
keyboard io they have
they came out with uh where's
keyboard io where did i put it
oh yeah here so they they have a new
version basically it's the same but they
are making you know another
new one so anyway
i'm i i i'm not
too big a fan you know depends on you
okay
break the loop how are you doing
yes break the loopies right break the
loop knows me
[Laughter]
make the loop uh
yeah k html by kd i use chrome a lot
because you are sleek
uh okay okay okay but c
standard uh okay c should die
that's what she sees the worst [ __ ]
possible
c you know include
you guys what no include means the c
sees the worst [ __ ] sees everything
that's wrong in computer
programming language design scenes c and
unix [ __ ]
you know guys you know include
you know in programming languages you
need libraries right
i mean so so your code you know
around 7 1980s you started to have the
concept
the concept of modular modular
programming
that is instead of like you know line
you know go to line 10 repeat go to line
10 yeah
go to line 120 that's how you
you know your your source code is just a
bunch of lines each line has a number
so if you want to do a loop you have to
say go to line 10 okay
then go to that you know like on line 20
you say go to line 10 then
then you start from there you know
that's that's basic
that's a language basic 1970s or
something
but anyway around 1980s there's a new
concept
modular programming so instead of this
kind of
go-to or loop or you know this kind of
you know monolithic you know
crap you have like you you define
procedures
today it's more known as functions so
you just are functions you know
you write functions this function can be
copied can be moved
in others of two other software you know
functions
you know so 1980s so the idea of modular
programming you know
by the way it's on wikipedia okay if you
don't believe in
um okay modular
uh i don't know you know what's uh
yeah modular programming okay wikipedia
you know i read this
i read these articles like every day
since like 10 years ago
all these articles i read that's what i
do that's what i
uh you know so 1960s even so
you know anyway so that's that back then
it was a new concept
and the programmers especially the
hacker types
they debate no that's no good real men
don't do that
that's the sea [ __ ] like today's
seasick pockets
so much of what i mean back then you
know was a new idea and lots of
programmers resist
it you know no that's not good that's
that's the that's the stupid kids
doing that we are the real programmers
we don't do that
that's that's sad so you started to have
modular programming okay then
then by the time c is around this this
is accepted
you know modular programming accepted
uh so so then then the c pockets you
know they have
like so module so so so you know what
what module means right first of all you
have procedures
procedures then the idea advanced then
you have functions which is independent
of any other variable
you know but in the beginning you have
like procedure for example in
perl a function is still mostly called a
procedure not
you know it's not code function it you
know only starting around year 2010
people started to call you know
procedures
as functions you know you begin to have
like
functions which is you know it doesn't
use global variables you know it's
independent you know
and then okay of course you have another
concept libraries right libraries
which is basically a collection of
functions in a
in a different file then to in order to
do that
in a good way you have name spaces right
you have
like import export but
in c you know c you have include
it just like include something so that
just means
that just means as if the the file
the coding or different files or just
here
no name space the [ __ ] c [ __ ]
you know a lot of reason you might say
you know if you are a c fanatic you
might say oh
well you have to consider 40 years ago
computer is not like as fast
today there's therefore there's some
limitations and restraints
therefore c was like that you know not
okay that's that that is a
valid reason but however that's not my
point okay
c is that way not because
partly because of the constraint
constraints of the computer you know
back then
you know the hardware it's slow no
memory and and so on
but the other part which is the heart of
c
is they are the sloppy facts they don't
think they don't design
they just do whatever it works it works
let's see [ __ ] it
and because of the sea they have damaged
they have made perpetual damage
permanent damage
to the computing industry in particular
the programming language design for
example what's the example for example
today
basically all languages uses the c [ __ ]
head
syntax c test syntax the worst
[ __ ] possible
that concludes our talk show today thank
you for watching
bye
okay go here video
22 hello guys