good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today is June
28th 2019 today we're going to talk
about some JavaScript JavaScript I'm
thinking I'm coding a live coding of
JavaScript meanwhile let me show you
some of the pages so JavaScript and
here's unicode we might talk about that
JavaScript and this is the app I did for
JavaScript
let's see font size big and you can you
can create the text shadows so we might
be working on this because this page
needs to needs more work there are many
features I'd like to add for you can
type stuff here and it will be shown in
real time there and you can change the
font size you see if I change the font
size the whole display you know the the
user interface changes I mean it moves
we don't want that there is a technique
to do that what you have to do is to is
to make this display box this type
element into a layer by itself so it it
does not affect the rest of the page you
know we want the control the user
interface to stay you know not move
around when you when you drag things
around so that's the JavaScript we might
do and also it is this quite a few
things let's see how many people are
watching one people okay so let me let
me know what do you like to see okay so
let's go to our talk show and let's type
out what we're gonna do so JavaScript
and here is my Emacs self like keys
commands so many things so javascript
live coding interactive happen so that's
one thing then JavaScript live coding a
color converter RGB to HSL converter and
explain color models ok let me just type
out the topics so so that is that and
there is also some questions I have to
answer someone asked me a question about
tech so that is key let's see keyboard
blog so keyboard we talked about this
nothing new in keyboard so answer
question about what to use instead of
tech or not take ok so these are the
questions this tandem and other stuff ok
and also maybe live Emacs Lee's coding
ok I'm gonna do that you know depending
on what you know let me know what do you
like to see usually let's see let's go
to back here and post here so people can
see hi guys
so I got three people watching so type
comments here and let's see if I can
paste that that's too long
let's see paste live Emacs list coding
and that would be modify modify this
command log mod so it shows quality keys
which means convert Corti to varrock
okay well rack convert back to Cori you
see on the left panel you can see all my
Emacs commands and this this is this
system by the mod called command log mod
and I'm using a variety board so all the
keys it shows is well rack for example
my home row on the left hand is a EO u
and right hand is HT NS and it does it
show let's see a yo-yo okay it doesn't
so anyway so you know it's showing the
VAR a keyboard but but mostly most
people are using book or T so it would
be nice if I can convert them to Cody I
mean it shows encoding in real time so
I'm gonna work on that if you like to
see that so here are the some of the
topics so the topics here includes let's
type it out the topic includes that and
that and that
so let me know what you like to see but
okay so meanwhile showing browser
meanwhile I'm just going going to start
off by let's answer the question okay so
there is this question so there is this
question
[Music]
come on is shown converting your vorak
output to quote e sounds like headache
it's not much it's it's it's not okay
that's that's a good thing it's not too
much work though I don't think so so so
you are also Emacs users right shown so
yeah I don't think that's that would be
too difficult but let me just answer let
me answer this question first okay so
then we're gonna do I guess that it's to
Emacs then so there is this question I
got asked let's see programming blog so
you know it's on reddit it's another
private questions so people you know
don't ask me quite you know don't don't
don't ask me private I mean don't don't
post it in private forums okay I prefer
much prefer public it may be on Twitter
on YouTube comments or go to reddit you
know such this exact xrn krub go post it
because I answer you know I spent hours
you know for the past decade to answer
questions private questions like I don't
know who you are but those people mostly
these people are you know anonymous they
ask they ask you questions and you
answer them you know two hours a day it
just saps your life and and and they are
anonymous like you know they are you
know you are not most of them have you
know most of them are anonymous you know
you just waste your time so anyway he
asks a question I saw your
2019 March 25th video about talk-show
about tech you know Donald Donald good
news tech so let's Sikhs are we yeah
sucks so I have a article about tech I
talked about this a couple of times
before and you know why tech is
extremely bad so and I did a video of
that and a lot of people asked have the
same question you know basically they
want to know so tech is bad so what are
the alternatives you know so the quit
that the to answer that to answer that
well there are several alternatives I
provide you a list of alternatives at
the bottom here let's see where is it
all the way to the bottom it depends
so alternative depends so if you for
example one alternative is Mathematica
you know you have to pay two hundred
three hundred dollars for a nut for a
amateur you know hobbyist version which
is by the way identical to the
professional version professional
version is like a thousand dollars or
something so math man Mathematica is one
choice oh you never use Emacs
okay so let's not do that then so
Mathematica is one alternative it's egg
it's excellent okay I'm not going to
show you that Mathematica is a great
alternative and there are several others
there there is for example lyx let me
it's open that lyx now some of these
alternatives they are just variations of
tech but they are you know either
variations or GUI you know graphical
user interface wrappers around tech so
you don't actually need to know you know
the tech
syntax and details it provides you GUI
but the underlying engine is still using
the tech technology without a core tech
so some of them are tech variations
you know like rappers and some of them
are variations like this XE tech here
let me show you
so this XE tech blue our tech let's show
you okay loud tech Emacs those are
alternatives and so I was saying so so
so some of them are just variations of a
tech like improved text but but you
still need to know the formula for
example this XE tech yeah it allows you
to use Unicode directly basically that's
what it is for you know so that's one
example alternative and some of the some
other alternative are wrappers around
tech but however some other alternatives
are not based on tech at all
for example this there's this thing
called new tech max now this is not
Emacs know is it tech it's neither
okay it's completely I think it's
completely unrelated to tech I think
wait did I I think it is but anyway this
is completely unrelated to Emacs okay so
this there is this new tech Max and I
have people who told me you know who I
can trust who told me it's pretty good
so you have this you know you can use
this and there are other solutions loud
loud is another solution
but anyway oh these are I don't think I
mean they are different
I don't think they are well I think
Mathematica is the best okay the other
the other thing is that the the the guy
actually and a question that the the
question of this guy is actually about
what is the alternative if you want to
use math formulas on the web now that's
an entirely different question so on the
web basically you don't have any options
it is kind of sad but that is true
because nobody you can use math K what
is called math ml okay I also talked
about here in the bottom math ml but
Google Chrome Google killed it
you know Google's you know unsupported
it about three years ago and you know so
basically there is no good alternatives
of you know to type math on the web
because it's kind of sad you know like
online you know like you have YouTube
and you have you know YouTube videos the
video technology is much more
complicated than creating a typesetting
system for math formulas for the web but
however you know the video technology
just grow and grow because people want
it because that's a major need and also
a major source of money you know money
exchange you know making money that's
what we need you know people want to
watch videos it's video technology is
extremely complicated and you have you
know you have encoding then you have the
you know the GUI system is you know and
the data is huge you know thousands
thousands times of ten math formulas but
but that's what people want and so that
technology just keep going so much and
you know but if you want to type you
know math formulas on the web
it's going nowhere because very few
people wanted not even programmers most
famous you don't need it you know only
mathematicians and you know so basically
you don't have good alternatives to the
40s showing math on the web so he says I
wanted to know your opinion on what is
the best current way of integrating math
in a lightweight static web site blog
yeah this and he wants he wants
lightweight are you kidding there's no
way you know they are they are ways of
course you know for example if you go to
stack overflow or actually you go to
mass overflow math overflow okay or any
you know modern website on math or even
Wikipedia you see lots of math formulas
let's see if I can see let's show some
example yeah okay so let's magnify
magnify so you see these formulas these
formulas this real math formulas you see
all these formulas they are turned by
basically a JavaScript library this
JavaScript library will convert you know
it supports several input syntax and one
of them the most popular is actually
take a lotof so it converts this syntax
into this display and what technology it
uses depends on depends you know it may
use SVG you know the scale scalable
vector graphics or it may use math ml
which is the XML based technology to
display math which Google Chrome no
longer supports or it can support images
you know it just just generate images so
so the input and output you you you have
several varieties of input you know take
formula there's also
skee math formula you know you can use
as a syntax for input you know there are
a few like three or four and the output
format also depends on you know you can
you can hardcore set it to using bitmap
images or SVG or math ml or a
combination of them so that so this
tecnique this thing this this package
this library space is written in
JavaScript of course and it's called
mathjax math j ax and it's it's pretty
big it's huge okay that's let's say a
logo and it sits in its nowhere a
lightweight it's it's a pain yes and it
you know so anyway so if you want to
display math you know so nicely like
that this is almost the only choice the
mathjax you know it's a sad state of the
situation but that that's how things are
so anyway that answers the question this
guy's question about alternatives to
tech let's see go back go back back so
he says I want to have a compatibility
with the maximum amount of browsers
without the client requiring add-ons I
will also like to keep crying inside
JavaScript to a minimum as well as kind
CPU usage yeah well the only choice is
mathjax basically yeah so and which is
by the way it is also what wikipedia
uses you know wikipedia it uses mathjax
but it allows it has several preferences
you know it it you know if it's see if
it sees that your browser for example
you have JavaScript turned off then it
will just generate you know the math
it's still using mathjax it will just
generate bitmap images and display those
images so it depends on you
so easy you know it's you know it's just
basically it's just using mathjax so
that answers that question so I guess
let's do JavaScript in so and see okay
so if you guys you know like pick a
topic otherwise let's do JavaScript
let's see what else I want to talk about
so Jay so what's up shown anything
interesting
let's see JavaScript so there are two
things to do with the JavaScript C
talk-show we're gonna do JavaScript
coding yeah so RGB yeah
so one thing is that we fix this so that
when we change the font size this page
you know the user interface does not
move position so and also on this page
there are more features to add for
example I want to add let me go through
this let me show you so this this
changes color this and this this changes
the offset for example and this changes
the offset and this slider changes the
length you know it basically is changing
the offset parameters x and y but
however by using the length in the
direction you can see you see this way
is more intuitive you know instead of
adjusting X then or just Y so that that
is that then you have blur
then here here is the text box okay then
you can adjust the font size so the the
whole thing movie moving around is no
good we're gonna change that then you
can change the background color let's
see let's say black okay then let's see
random color oh then okay so we also
need another feature that changes the
text color the original text color not
the shadow you know this only changes
the shadows color you know you can you
can you can see the original text there
so we need to change the original text
color and another feature what I want is
that when you design you know I want
these different fonts like this gothic
that's an interesting thing you you have
this Unicode gothic font so let's do
that then okay so let's let's do this oh
yeah so this this is one thing the other
thing I want to talk about let me show
you let's go to Wikipedia HSL color
okay here HS vs. HSV that's not what we
want we want let's see oh yeah here okay
this is what we want you see the color
model is very complicated you know
originally in computing in programming
you have RGB you know RGB is like that
you have the color cube RGB it's based
on you know how you've basically the
addictive color model where you have red
green and blue three colors these are
called primary colors and all the rest
of the colors are a mixture of these
three lights called colored lights this
is roughly based on physics you know
light model so red you know you have
different values for red you know it
forms one axis then you have blue
another axis then you have green another
axis so altogether the color space is
like a cube you know so it's made of
three numbers you know you pick a color
by choosing three different numbers and
this is one of the model of color and
the other model is is called subtractive
subtractive model which is called cmk
why I think cmk why it's that's
abbreviation for seein magenta yellow
and something
let's go there
Oh SIA magenta yellow and key basically
this model is a subtractive model that's
you know when if you are a painter you
know watercolor painter you you paint
and you mix paint you know you mix
yellow and magenta you get red you know
that's how that model works which is you
know which is different from the RGB
model if you in RGB model if you mix
yellow and magenta you don't get do you
get red I'm not sure but anyway did you
know it's different so so anyway let's
go back to the red blue green model so
this is interesting but there's one
problem with this model is that it's not
intuitive because it's not intuitive
because let's go to math notation the
past and future yeah for example let's
see we have a color box here let's
refresh this page get back to default
then let's see a color let's say big
font lots of blue and color let's pick
one color red okay so so we got this
color
let's see RGB so you can see different
color models here RGB sliders red green
and blue you see it's it's not intuitive
let me move that here so you can see
actually can you see it
so you see you have these three sliders
red green and blue you see you
you see the red part it becomes I mean
that the point is if you want a color
yellow like how do you how do you choose
red green blue and it's not intuitive so
in this case if you want yellow blue
must be zero
I guess red and green must be maximum
then you get yellow but now the red part
you can see it becomes you know it it's
not intuitive so that's how that's why
they created a different model h SL
model now let me show you the HSL color
names-- color syntax so this is CSS this
is the HSL model you can see you can
adjust the hue the hue is let's let's
put the saturation to max the saturation
is how much color you want of that
particular color the hue is like a
rainbow
wheel from 0 to 360 let's knit for the
lightness let's put the line is here so
you so you can see the hue is red orange
blue green purple violet it's like a
rainbow then for each color you have
saturation like how much how you know
how much pigment do you want out of that
color then you have lightness it changes
to right to dock so this way this syntax
is more intuitive you got three numbers
you know you can tell just by looking at
the number
what you know what color this will be
like but so so this is called HSL model
hue saturation lightness and and you can
see examples here this is change of you
this is change of saturation and here's
change of the lightness that is one of
the model this this HSA our motto is
invented after the RGB you know the RGB
is based on physics but we you know it
has the problem of not intuitive so
people you know engineers invented this
HSL and by the way there is another
model which is similar to HSI which is
it's called HSV okay HSV is kind of
similar it's used in Mathematica by the
way so on on the left you see this
picture it's a HSA R on the right this
picture is HSB model they are kind of
similar but the the the interesting
question is that how do they you know
like you know color is very you know
it's a huge science color is actually a
huge huge complicated science you know
you can study you know you can get a PhD
degree for it
you know this aspect from physics then
this aspect from engineering you know
from you know from engine then this
aspect from human perception you know
the biology of the eye
which is different from you know just
physical measurements of you know the
light waves you know physically color
are different lengths of waves that's
how we perceive it so in a sense our
eyes our eyes is a machine that can
perceive that can detect wavelength
differences of certain wavelength that's
how we check our perceived color so so
in terms of physics color is just
different wavelengths you know is
something like that but then
human eye the mechanism and our
perception that's entirely different
thing you know it's not just detecting
wavelength because we we only detect
certain wavelengths and for certain you
know it's particular to our brain to our
perception for example we say that dogs
and cats they don't see the same thing
as as we do so there's a human
perception aspect this is important
because if you just model color by
physics
that's what not you see you know you can
only see certain limited things so
everything you know all the colors you
perceive you know that's human
experience it's not you know you can you
might have some colors humans are not
able to see you know like you have
infrared or ultraviolet you know like
you know you have these ultraviolet
lamps you know like black lamps or
something things like that you have to
shine a particular special light in
order to see it so hue you know so the
biology of the eye is actually quite
important you know when you want to
design you know the color model you know
you want to design a system that
specifies color such as you know the CSS
RGB and HSL so there's a physics physics
aspect there's a biology aspect of our
eye and you know that ties to psychology
as well actually you know you see many
illusions where they have to you know
they have a background color then they
have two boxes of the same color but you
see this one is black and you see the
other one was white because but actually
they are the same gray because their
background is one is white you know that
that's you know illusion so it has to do
with you know psychology as well not
just biology of the eye you know it's
tied together so the biology aspect
psychology aspect but there's also
engineering aspect which is very
complex so what do you mean by
engineering aspect for example when you
know your TV or monitors display colors
but however they cannot display
perfectly every other colors because you
know the display system this is created
by you know we have different
technologies you know we have electronic
beans or we have LCD you have you know
let you know lamps behind the screen you
know all kind of different technology
quite a lot you know this you know this
is a lot for projections projectors
different type of displays
so there you know when you say when you
tell them a TV your TV or your monitor
or your phone to say show red color they
you know they actually all show
different different kind of red so
because the technology is different you
know and they have different
capabilities so that is why so this is
the aspect of engineering this is
actually quite extremely complicated so
that's the display system but there's
also the capturing system for example
photography you know you have your
iPhone or camera you take a photo of
something it records you know the
records the lights of the you know the
scene at the time but how does it record
suppose I have a different color of red
here suppose I have a rainbow you take a
photo of a rainbow
you know what what does it store for red
for example you know how it stores the
red color so that's technology and and
it you know it again depends on what you
know the depends on if you are using
old-style
camera you know film that's one way to
record it if you have digital camera
that's another way so you know it's it's
very complicated you know and and also
you cannot do it perfectly you know we
are you know engineering so almost
always you know make too
you know trying to find what's the best
way so you have all these different
complexities you know physics
engineering biomechanics and we are you
know trying to design a color model so
it's it's actually very complex so big
and but but back to our topic now the
question you know the question is you
know so you have this SH SAR model and
you have this RGB model you see RGB
model is basic based on physics like
waves but where does the HSA our model
came from I mean how is it invented like
like when use like for example the hue
you know it's a rainbow color but how do
you actually you know convert it to RGB
that is a question how do you convert
these three numbers to RGB so you know
if you look at this in detail you can
you can see it's it's not intuitive it's
not natural it's it's actually very
complex by the way I did a I wrote a
converter in in second life long long
ago let me show you this interesting
sorry
second life particle system so I wrote
this application this 3d interactive
application in Second Life
okay Parko maker okay here is the one I
spend a month to create this now if you
don't know what Second Life is let me
show you so anyway so this is the
particle maker okay you have to pay for
it you have to buy it it generates code
for your second life stuff I spent one
month more than month to create this and
I sell it for like I think what it was
$20 USD each US dollars so Second Life
is
basically it's like a 3d game it's a
virtual virtual world okay I spent like
four years in it so anyway I created
this particle may good so what is a
particle particle is in gaming
you know 3d graphics technology you have
to use this thing called particle to
create things like rain fireworks
snow smoke or water you know this kind
of thing because this kind of thing they
are not polygons you know for example
here you came up you cannot model them
as polygons so you use this technology
called particles so what exactly is
particles particles is quite funny okay
it's a hack it's a hack basically it's
just images like what you call sprites
in in game in gaming community it's
basically two-dimensional images and you
have thousands of them floating around
your screen your two-dimensional screen
so the ultimate effect is that they
emulate they appear as you know like
rain or fireworks or let me show you
some of the graphics gallery let's see
gallery okay let's open that so here you
have like a huge smoke you know or fog
here is the rain you know here is you
know some kind of artificial particle
you you see stars you know this this is
in real time you know in feet if you go
into Second Life you know just like any
game you know you see them in real time
and here's an artificial ring of stars
and this is kind of kind of like laser
show and this is kind of like volcano
you know volcano dust
and here is another example of some kind
of neon show so but anyway all these are
made of particles and they are
essentially they are just images
you know two-dimensional images like
thousands of them floating around your
screen with the you know - the purpose
is to emulate these kind of things in in
a virtual world in a you know 3d
graphics so in order to create this I
have to write color wheel and I have to
write a function that converts HSL color
model into the RGB when you do this you
when you do this you find this very
interesting thing you know when you
write two algorithm to convert it
because you realize the color models are
extremely complex now if you studied if
you use Photoshop or you know you looked
into arts and you know color you must
have seen this you know you got this
very complicated thing to understand so
you know that's what color are very
complicated thing then so I was saying
so I have to write a converter from HSL
to RGB then you realize okay here is
what it looks like okay this let me show
you so so this is what this algorithm
the result looks like you know it looks
you know basically you see so when you
have HSL where is it
let's see
so let's see how many people I got
watching for okay so when you have the
wizard here yeah here here where is my
application for okay so yeah here's HSL
so when you have the HSA our color you
got these three numbers you want to
convert to RGB you know so it's very
strange because when you increase the
hue you can see the RGB sliders goes
haywire like like when you increase the
hue to a certain point the RGB you know
some sliders goes backwards some goes
forward and the way they move is like
this in this picture here from Wikipedia
it's like this triangle so anyway so
what actually is it doing so how so the
question is how is the HSL created how
is the model of h si our model created
oh it's my pages yeah so the HSL model
they are created by you can you can read
from this Wikipedia article they are
created by like this let me show you
okay so so you have these so you have
this RGB color space which is a cube
okay now you turn the cube you turn the
cube so that so that the verticals are
at the time let me try to find a cube do
I have a cube here I don't I don't think
I have a cube
okay I'm trying to find a cube here
I don't have a cube but let me show you
other things okay interesting things
sabe hyperbola hyperboloid hyperboloid
of one sheet and hyperboloid of two
sheet and hyperboloid architecture these
are all very interesting things so
hyperboloid is a mathematical structure
it looks like this it's a surface it's
what's called a ruled surface and it's
created one way to create it is like
like like this you have a bunch of lines
you know you just put them in your
cylinder you know they just twist they
are basically made of lines you know
line you know inclined position and you
revolve it around a circle you get this
depending how the line is twisted I mean
how how the depending on the angle of
the line you get different shapes of the
hyperboloid and sometimes you can see a
basket made made out of you know it and
this you can do also do at home by you
know if you have pasta you know you put
them into a jar and you shake you know
you wrote you know you rotate that you
know you shake the jar in a circular
fashion then you get this you get this
hyper below it okay so it's a model you
know it's a this is you know a surface
called hyperboloid and by the way this
picture this is in second life so I
created this in second life back in 2009
so so hyperboloid you know it's
interesting you know so this this video
let's watch it it's it's kind of not
intuitive you have this line you know it
can go through this shape this this
curved haw
so anyways so so that's a hyperboloid
okay so what about it so the interesting
thing about it is that if you have a
cube you know like like a dice and you
rotate the cube on the tabletop the
profile of the side is a hyperboloid so
that that's why we are talking about
these so cube I don't have a cube here I
so I cannot show you but if you have a
cube god I need a cube to demonstrate
this anyway if you take a tube and you
you put the corner on top in the bottom
and you rotate the cube you can see if
you have dice somewhere you can see it
from you know it forms spins like that
you see if you spin the dice so so
that's hyperboloid so I think we can go
back to the color thing there are other
things called hyperboloid this one is
called hyperboloid of to sheet and then
we have hyperboloid in architecture you
know these are huge Jimmy's new nuclear
reactor jimmy's or power station jimmy's
by the way they blow up steams those are
not smokes those are not carbon deoxys
the oxidized typically this kind of
jimmy they blow out those are steam is
like water steams coming out but anyway
so so let's go back to the color cubes
so I was saying if you take a cube and
you put the corner
at the top and bottom then you have this
one two three four you have six other
you know a cube has eight corners four
on top and four on bottom eight corners
total so you if you put the cube you
positioned it you know so one of the
cone is at the top and the other corner
is there
at the bottom then you have six other
corners they form a hexagon they form a
hexagon so that is when you see this
picture let's go back here so that's why
you see all these triangles show it's
showing up in okay there's a picture
here so you put a cube then you see you
got a hexagon and so so now what what
why was I going to say okay so this is
this is yeah they got a picture here so
so this is how you transform the RGB
cube into the HSL model so you turn a
cube you know then you got this kind of
hexagon then you just trim it so this is
the HSL model so from this you can now
you can understand how the HSL or HSV
came from and how the numbers actually
work you know like you have a point in
this you know cone shape or hexagonal
cylinder shape you can see how they
correspond to a point moving around in
the cube that is why when you move a
point around this HSA our model you know
the point the parameters of the RGB
changes in a erratic way so anyway that
was that's what I want to mention but I
was going to we are going to do some
coding of JavaScript shall we shall we
still do that
yeah and close the window I got five
people watching so so yeah let's do
let's just let's do a small one let's
create a I don't have my drinks
anymore yeah let's let me get a drink
and let's do the JavaScript coding
so I got a drink of the
the so this is what's called what they
call it band but he's just like energy
drink energy drink cheap energy drink
it's like Red Bull but sugar free then
today I got this
Ruby juice hundred percent juice
you know I I see my name mentioned on
one of these 4chan image boards let me
show that
let's see google.com ok let's go to
Google search so Google search Casali ok
and you see these people talking about
me they do that often tours times what
is this such performance for this query
last 28 28 days see ways to improve this
Google Oh visible only to you this
google scum anyway so it's this go to
past 24 hours so you see this this 4chan
people i got mentioned they quite often
few times a year and they you know
that's a picture of me when I was like
that's that was that picture is from
2002 you know and they they talked
random things you know about you know my
stuff about you know I got this age I
got this web page that becomes extremely
popular it's on reddit or hacker news
every now and then you know why tiling
window manager sucks X monad rat poison
DWM instead and these people this they
talk about it all the time they you know
the these people are kind of nerds and
they are kind of like fringe of society
that is that is the reality they are
kind of the fringe of society
anyway so
so in this article I am talking about
efficiency of operating your computer we
anyway let's go back to let's yeah let's
do the JavaScript let's let's just add a
font let's say I want to create a new
font so let's go to here where do I want
to add it I want to add it before the
font size okay
so search for font size so okay copy
that paste and let's save font so choose
a font okay so we want to let users to
choose a font in order to do that we
have to think about what kind of
interface you you want of obviously it's
not a button it's not a slider so what
is it so let's go to dumb scripting dumb
scripting and let's go to HTML input and
in a case of choosing a font we can
either use a radio button you know which
gives you several choices or you can use
a pop-up menu I prefer radio button
because radio button everything is laid
out you know you don't have to click and
see what are the choices so let's use a
radio button so in order to do that we
just basically just copy the code here
okay font so font we have these choices
and radio button so what choices so
first of all the name will be font let's
say font box
one select okay and the value will be
lets say serif sans serif okay then
mono space showing browser
okay we got font serif sans serif ma no
space that's good it's pretty fired okay
let's add some more space we need some
more space
that's good so we added this user
interface the next thing to do is we
need to modify the JavaScript so there
is some action when people click on that
so copy it so let's open the JavaScript
file open it font select so how do you
use JavaScript to get the radio button
let's go back to look up oh it's just
repeated here and let's go back to look
up the radio button code here let's just
copy it so go to the JavaScript code and
let's go to the top
that's let's paste at the top we want
show box we don't need
so basically the only thing you need is
these these lines let me show you this
this line and this line and this the
name will be the name was fun select let
me show you what it is okay so so first
of all you need to get a you need to
define the element okay we define the
element like here found select okay
and by using the query selector we want
to select our input whose name is found
select and let's forget about that
checked and okay that we don't care so
this this is what we want we just want
to get all the elements of the name
found select okay then we need to add a
event so array from so far select the
query selector actually returns a not
list which is not an array so you need
to turn it into array if you want to use
array method such as for each but
actually today's browsers they have
building they they made it so that for
each you have the for each method
without needing to convert convert
fondly not least into a array you know
they did it by hack because you know
it's it's quite a mess so they
you know this is one of the problem of
the web spec and dumb scripting because
thumb is extremely complicated complex
and there's no logical reason to it you
know over the past 20 years or 30 years
you know they just it shifts you know
the the idea of thinking what it should
be shifts you know Dom originally
originally stands for document object
model today it doesn't stand for that
much anymore
and originally it was designed to be you
know Dom is thought to be like a generic
interface of any hierarchical document
you can you know with Dom you have the
model then you can implement a
programming language to control the
document that was the original thought
but pretty much II was it sees only in
JavaScript mostly you know but anyway
it's very complex so anyway that one of
the extreme stupidity is that when you
use one of the selector like query
select it returns you know depending on
browser and depending on what year it is
sometimes it returns a not list
sometimes it returns a HTML element
collection you can see the problem if
you go to my tongue scripting tutorial
and here get element by ID by tag name
by class by CSS selector and at the
bottom and some of them returns for
example some of them returns a element
objects some of them with and some of
them are live some of them are not live
some of them returns a HTML collection
and some of them returns a not list for
example get elements by name returns
sane not least so it's extremely
confusing and this if you look into the
detail there is no good reason for it
you know it's just history and you
cannot make sense of it so what can you
do you know
in practice you just you know you just
you don't you don't ask why you just
code whatever works so anyway the the
problem with you know both when they
return so if you go near the bottom
there's article about you know what is
HTML collection was a storm list by the
way both of them not are not arrays
which is extremely idiotic you know like
like for every programmers every
programmer when you want to get a
collection of elements the one most
obvious obvious thing you want to do is
to you know apply a map for each you
know a prior array function to it but
they don't they but their type is not
array so you cannot do it
so before JavaScript 2015 you have to do
this extremely convoluted way let me
show you where array like object yes so
anyway so it's very complex
you have to this complexity you know
involves JavaScript as well because
JavaScript arrays is extremely bad so
anyway let's just get back to the so
yeah so anyway I was saying so HTML
elements HTML collection and the not
least they are not array elements so if
you want to call array function such as
for each you have to either convert it
to a ray first like by calling array
form a raid art form which is this
function is is added in 2015 or you can
do it in this complicated way by calling
a radar prototype dot for each star call
that's how you that's how you call a
array method
on any object that is not array you know
and typically you you do this for array
like objects you know the in JavaScript
there's this thing called a weight like
very complex so anyway that's what you
have to do but then in Dom they added
you know because this is a common need
you know everyone when you get some
bunch of you know collection of elements
the first thing everyone needs to do is
to apply a ray method for each you know
to it to it but you cannot so that's a
problem and people has to resort through
these ways you know before 2015 there's
no no proper way to convert array to
array a very like object to array true
array object you have to you know so
it's very extremely complicated and it's
a problem so then they in 2015 they
added a wave form which is you know one
simple way to convert array like object
to array but still that does not solve
the problem because every time you you
co query you know select then you have
to do a conversion to array before you
can actually code for each so so the
browser's began to add the for each
element to the to the not list or let's
see yeah to to this so you know browser
began to add it so in HTML collection
you have for each no you don't have for
each but in not least if it's not least
then you have the for each method and
the way they do it is very complicated
because you know for each is array
method when you have a not least you
have the for each method but actually
it's not from the array method it's
actually just
browsers just added it just you know
just you know just they just do it so if
you have a knowledge you have the for
each method now you don't have to
convert to a ray first but however if
you have HTML collection you do not have
the for each method so the whole thing
is extremely convoluted it is a
there ass you know these this
these programmers these standards this
whatever hackers you know they they scan
you know it's it's one thing that you
know technology always have bugs and
problems that's understandable but but
these elite programmers like they tell
you oh we open-source follow standards
or you know follow it you know what the
group or html5 group or whatever
w3c standards or RFC you know they they
don't understand they don't understand
why it's all up you know so we
just get anyway so we just got this
situation and that's not all because
this HTML collection analyst so in
JavaScript in JavaScript 2015 they added
a new thing called iterable which is
very useful okay so they added a new
iterable thing so now in browsers both
HTML collection and not least are also
iterable objects okay so yeah so anyway
it's it's extremely complicated you know
I could go into the technical detail
they are iterable objects but they they
are not actually iterable interface I
don't think so I'm not sure I haven't
looked but I don't think so so in other
words it's just another extreme hack so
anyway so here let's go back to our
thing we want to add a font select
radio box found and so we we already did
that so we have the radio box to select
font is it here yes so send cereth
cereth and mono space but now we need to
add a interaction to it so we add the
element fan select now we need to add a
event listener so event listener is at
the bottom of this page
the my JavaScript code event is at the
bottom so we add a event let's say here
so you go through the phone select thing
and for each element you add an event
listener yeah
and whenever you know it's changed you
call the function function update F
update that's right so now let's modify
the F update code so that it actually
changes the font you know over here so
in the F update code let's see font font
size font it's
so found select so here
what we want to do is this font family
so we want to change the font family to
to the value of font select that's right
and how do we get the value of a select
it's not dot value because it's a
because it's a radio box so it's not
thought value is rather dot check
checked one of the radio box that is
checked and and you want to get that
items value so how do you do that let's
see so we need to go back to the dumb
radio box so radio button so here is the
code copy it so paste the code here so
selected value equals two here is how
you get the checked that there so then
once you get a value you want to convert
it to string that's right to string okay
at least I don't need so let's put it
here that's right so shadow box shadow
box is the display area for it's over
here so shadow box style dot font-family
equals to equals to the selected value
of the font radio box okay that seems
to be it compile the code this is
typescript okay so some arrows I know
what those arrows are because you know
when you code
typescript for a while you know okay
there's a mistake here curry select font
so you need to add here HTML input
element to cast a type okay then let's
compile the code again let's do it again
property value does not exist okay line
77 now I also know why because this is
one of the problem of using typescript
HTML input element okay that's what you
need to do in it you need to cast the
value let's compile again
okay so we actually should be like that
compile this is this is for some reason
taking a long time to compile normally
it's not like that
oh you need to put a parenthesis compare
again okay we are getting somewhere so
it says that element is is lying 109 now
109 over here
so it says this element is not
assignable to parameter of type array
like why
not assignable to parameter of array
one on my position 22 position 22 so
this is argument of type is not
assignable okay fun select is not a HTML
element it's actually or not least let's
see if we can maybe that works
it's just forget about that those arrows
let's ignore it now because typescript
is a superset of JavaScript so it spits
out these arrows but you know let's see
you know it let's go back to browser
refresh that is working actually it's
increased font size okay let's pick
serif sans serif mono space no it's not
working so let's go back to the HTML
page
sans-serif' needs a
let's go back open update let's go to
the update function so font-family
equals to selected dot value dot two
string okay phone select
let's show the browser console refresh
so what is going on so let's print a
value and see so we want to print the
value let's see
compile it
refresh browser
okay each time we click on that there is
no effect and it's not calling the
update because if it is calling the
update function it should print here so
we know the problem is with events away
from far select selection
so we're trying to solve this problem so
farm select phone select select all
items that's named fun select ok so
which is over here phone select that's
right so you select those items
oh the value here is the problem it's
one of the problem at least so the value
should be cents serif and let's go back
to so let's go through the update
section so checked value the value is
already a string so I don't think you
need to string so font family found
family equals to compile it
okay this let's fix this fun family now
what does this say about style let's say
inspect a font size found so far self
you see font family is actually working
I mean you can see the style here found
family sans-serif
wait but where does that sense serif
came from I think it came from my
browser I mean my stylesheet so so but
anyway why is the event not working so
we selected for each one add
eventlistener input and of F update
let's print font select
it's checked sans-serif' okay yeah you
are right you are probably right
okay anyway I'm a little bit confused
here anyway so let's go back here so
it's printing right yeah I know so right
now we are printing out
we are printing out the element now this
is supposed to be a list of elements but
however we are only printing it looks
like it's only printing one atom one
item you see we are printing the fonts
like here and this font select is
supposed to be you know it came from
here
and this is supposed to be Oh
curvy select got it
I don't know as as I know it's why
because this well because the HTML
selection you go let's go back to Dom
you have two different you have query
selector and query selector selector or
it's very confusing
so over here we need the query selector
or not selector that's right that's why
the typescript is popping up with the
arrows that for each you know not found
or something like that okay okay now it
succeeds without any error so let's
remove the console.log remove the
console.log and hopefully you know
everything will just work
let's go back to yeah so go back here to
refresh browser bigger font serif yay
sans-serif mono space yay so we got that
working actually yeah yeah so we yeah so
that's great so we there's one more
thing sufficient yeah this one more
interesting thing is that I want to show
this this gothic font that's very fun to
have but it's actually not a font
let me show you this this this is called
mathematical font well it's not fun but
it's just unicode characters so you go
here so you have this you know this
gothic or you know like New York Times
logo you know this is this is this
technique technically called Frank
letter font so but anyway these
characters are not actually found for
example if they are just Unicode
characters for example I copy them Oh
Germanic typeface yeah so I you know I
copied them I pasted here and I magnify
you see these are the characters and now
if I called described character you can
see this character is called black
letter capital C you know it's a
character it's not a you know it's not
like a character plus you know font you
know you apply a fan to it but rather
this character represents you know the
the capital C with the found already so
there's you know so that's that's that's
an interesting technique to yes
self-contained unit yes so let's let's
add it here you know to our page so you
know just for fun let's go to the text
area text area okay let's add it here
okay and refresh the page
yeah okay let's see fontsize lodge okay
let's see
blah
and it's turned off though
so yeah that's what that's so what
there's more things I need to fix but
you know I'll just go fly and do it you
know see you see when you increase the
font size
it goes over that's that's no good you
know it also it changes the position of
the you know other sliders that's no
good so what you want to do is you want
to use CSS to make it a different layer
I'm gonna you know if you are wondering
how to do that you can go to the here
layers and layout you want to create a
new layout I mean your layer so that
here
create a layer you know using CSS so
that it actually doesn't interfere with
the rest of the page and we also need to
I also need to add you know another font
choice so that it shows the Gothic
because right now if people type you
know if they type something being the
graphics you know those factor letters
are good so there's no way to get them
back so anyway that's some of the things
I yeah I didn't flow that's also nice to
do there's also a you know a solution so
yeah any any way that's I think that's
it for today I kind of like talked about
random things ahab's
so any more questions so I'm thinking
actually I've been thinking maybe I'll
do another one on Emacs later today but
I'm not sure because so anyway thank you
guys for watching bye bye Sean