Hello, good morning. Welcome to another
episode of Kasan Talk Show. We are going
to code Emac Bisp. Today, Emacs is the
most efficient and powerful and flexible
editor for programmers and writers and F
is the best functional programming
language for the industry
uh for the industry because on the other
hand, Wufam language Mathematica is the
best functional programming language for
scientific programming and engineering
and mathematics.
scientific programming used in uh if you
are an engineer, you research rocket
science, rockets, design car engines,
things like that. design, aerodynamics,
um heat conduction and you know uh
that's real industry not programming
industry but real industry design
bridges buildings dams hydro power
station space station rockets that you
need mathematics engineering and that
you need wam
language am I am I doing good am I doing
good talking checking video check audio
check. So, we're going to codeam uh
we're going to code emac lisp. We're
going to write a major
mod for f. F the programming language.
Okay. Uh if you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed and skip
around because I ramble. If you are
watching
live, hi, welcome. And say hi here.
Okay. Don't be a chicken.
So let's begin. Okay, let's just begin.
We are writing a major mod. Okay, so now
in the past I've done one, two, three,
four, four videos on writing a major mod
from
scratch. So there is for Goland back in
2021. There is one for Python mod
2023 and uh part two then 2023 uh part
three. So, Python mod part one, two,
three. So, and if you want to learn how
to write a major mod, you can watch the
old videos. They are still
good. You know, in modern society, we
have this thing
about we only concern what's you know
the treats the social network post from
today. When it's last week, oh, you
know, it's old, nobody cares. But these
videos are still good, as good as new.
Uh, but today we're going to code a
major mod for F. And
also now if you want to write a major
mod, if you prefer reading, it's all
written out how to write the major mod
tutorial here. Okay, so you got syntax
coloring. Uh, just search for XR EMAC
tutorial. Emac list tutorial.info
info, you will find how to color, how to
do syntax coloring for your programming
language
uh and what does it you know you need to
use font lock mod what it is and how to
use it uh and how do you color comments
and string which is separate from the
font lock and then how do you write a
common command so I can press a key uh
you know so press a key this becomes
common. So okay so let's begin uh F.
So F# for example uh this is F
programming language. Okay, I don't know
how to write F. But you see let um let
this is set the variable and common. You
see how do you do that? And uncommon
common uncommon common. Okay. Un
uncommon and comment at the end of line.
You see that's the command common and
uncommon. How do you do
it? And keyword completion. And uh so
the science of writing a major mod in
Emacs. What is a major mod? Major mod is
a special
um customization in Emacs designed for a
specific programming language
or or even uh or or directory. For
example, this directory you can
manipulate, change file names, move
files.
That's this mod is a major mod. This mod
is called the ad or diode. Okay. So
major mod can you can write chat bots.
You can write uh image you know view
images. So you can view images you know
at the end of code uh you know lots of
images. So this end of code we did this
union union of a bunch of things. That's
woofam language. Okay. So you can view
image. How do you do that in Emacs?
Because that's a major mod designed to
view images. So a major mod is a
uh is you know it's a it's a kind it's a
library in
Emacs designed to do specific
tasks. Uh okay. So let's write that.
That's enough introduction.
Okay. Okay. So, I have already begin.
Um, let's see.
Uh, okay. Let's see. Softly keys. I'm
using softly keys. The most efficient
editing system for Emacs. More efficient
than Vim or VI or Neo Vim. Okay, that's
keys. So, you don't have to press
control or meta or old. So every key I
press is shown on the pink window on the
left along with their command name. Can
you see it?
Yes. Okay, that's enough
introduction. Let's get the ball
rolling, shall we? So um Okay.
Yeah. So keys. Copy that. Close that.
Close that. Okay. So let's just put the
link
here. Okay. But I I need to go there. Go
to my F mod. F. There it is. So I have
already written
uh not much though. So let me should I
start from scratch or should I just
modify this? Okay. I think I'm just
going to modify this because if you want
to start from scratch, you can just
watch my previous talk
show.
Uh you know, if you want to learn
writing a major mod from scratch, but
today we're going to I'm just going to
continue my you know,
quickly this my quickly done mod. Okay.
So this is F mod right now 220 lines. So
first job you know one of the first
thing you need to do is you need to get
all the keywords of the F language. Okay
like if um so so for that to do that uh
let's
see so yesterday we did a F
um find and replace script. This is uh
code suggested from Gro. Yesterday we
did a live stream and it works great.
One shot. So you see so the keywords you
know the so let is colored open should
be color I don't have it for should be
colored in should be colored do should
be you know so on. So the first job is
to find all the
keywords. So how do you do that?
Um well we go to the F language spec.
Okay. Can we can we do that? Uh yeah. So
uh first job find keywords.
Okay. Uh F. Uh where is it? F. I need to
go to my tutorial notes. I'm learning
notes. My learning notes. And here is
the full
documentation. So we need to look into
that.
Turn on JavaScript. Turn on. And uh go
back F
documentation. Uh we need some kind of
specification. F language specification.
Do we have that? Turn on
JavaScript fundamentals. Uh F
documentation tutorials.
F# guide reference. Okay. F language
spec. Open
that. So, okay, hold on a second. So, F
learning notes. Okay. To do
close this is S talk show. Now, put the
my learning notes there. There's a link
and
um learning notes F spec. That's what we
want to find. So there it is. F
specification version uh 4.1 in PDF
in doc x. Now what format is doc doc x?
I don't
know. So let's
[Music]
see. So 4.1. Okay. The latest working
version. Okay. Let's see the dot. Ah,
Oh, that's Microsoft Word. Oh
And so what about a PDF? Let's open the
Wait, why don't they have the F
specification in HTML
idiotic? Let's try this. RFC request for
comment. Okay, this is written in uh
read me the MD uh which is uh stand for
markdown. So cartesian product let's
just see what
the lead pairs okay this is just
partial okay well let's try the PDF
let's see how it
looks you know so our job first job is
to get
First task get all F
keywords. Hello
immortality. Okay, this is PDF. Now you
need to magnify for you guys. So because
otherwise it's you cannot read it.
language spec.
Okay. The F 4.1 language spec. Uh oh,
look, look, there's a there's a
typo. V does not yet incorporate the
RFC's for 4.1, but it says fee. It's
missing an
S. Okay.
So, so let's get a overview. What is
this latest
PDF language spec? Okay. Documentation
is a spec of 4.1 of F released in
2015.
Oh, that is old. That's 10 years
old. Okay. author Don Sim document
update
uh initial
updates. Okay.
What? Okay. So you got
this
introduction lexical analysis, whace
comments, conditionals, conditional
compilation, identifiers and
keywords.
Um there identifiers and
keywords. Okay. Yeah.
Jesus. This is BNF backas no notation.
BN
um backers know um what's the word?
Uh BN usually it's called
BNF backers no form. Okay.
Uh so this is so this is identifiers and
keywords. So those are for numbers,
digit letter characters, connection
connecting characters, uh formatting
characters. Okay, that's for numbers. Uh
yeah. Okay, then the following
identifiers are reserved for future use.
Okay. So then here you have token
identifier keywords. That's what we
want. Okay. So that's what we want. And
the future use. Let's copy it. Okay. So
this is PDF is a pain in the
ass. Never use PDF. Okay. Because they
have, you know, this is complicated.
When you copy, you got lots of crap.
Okay. So, go back to my F mod. So,
there's a F doc lookup. Now, I want to
go to the
keywords.
Functions. Okay. So, okay. F keywords. I
only have
two. So, we need to modify
that. Okay. Let's paste this. Okay.
Comment out. Let's begin to work on
this.
So I don't want that. Okay. Uh first of
all make a backup. I don't want that.
Just say Neo. Okay. Then
set set here so that every time when
this package runs again it resets
because if you put the value here then
you evaluate it it does not work. It
does not work when the variable already
has a value. So that means when you
reload the package, it doesn't reset
things by design and I don't think
that's a good design. So I prefer to
always define it declare the variable
but neo value then you set the value so
that every time when this package f mod
is reloaded it kinds of like reset
everything. Okay, this is also good
especially when you are doing
development of the major mod because you
need to re reload this
constantly. Okay, so now let's uh so so
so the keyword is going to be a list.
Okay, this means don't evaluate the
content of the list. Okay,
so okay and let's show whites space. Did
we copy a bunch of crap? No, because
usually when you copy from PDF, you got
bunch of mysterious
characters. Okay, so make it the line.
So turn off the white space. Then each
one want to be a string. So let's do it.
Uh quotation mark and uh space
uh what other space. Okay, so we got
that. And
uh are they alphabetized? Yes, but we
can do it again to make sure. Sort. You
can see the command on the pink window.
And let's make it one line. And let's
make
it, you know, uh not too long a line.
And
cut.
Paste.
Pretty. Fantastic.
Now we got lots of keywords. Okay. Now
go back here. That's
the Yeah. So we need to So wait. Uh oh.
Actually these are reserved
words. Okay. These are reserved words.
Okay. You need this part.
Keywords.
Copy. Paste. Show white space to see if
there's any No.
Okay. Turn off whace. Make it one line
per word. Now add a quotation mark and
uh uh then no comma. Okay. Then make it
one line, long line. Make it uh make it.
So are they
alphabetized? Yes. But double check to
make sure. Okay. Make it one line. Make
it short. Now this part will be a list.
Okay. Now this cut that
out. Cut this
out. Put it back there. 3Dify the code.
So that's the F
keywords. Okay. So now
next that's the keywords and this is
reserved words. List of
F reserved words.
Okay. Good. Yes.
Set F reserve words. And what do you
want to set them? You want to set them
to
be let's just let's just this thing this
thing. Okay. And
[Music]
uh let's just make it one line. Okay.
Like
that. Fantastic. And beautiful. Is it
beautiful? Yes. Is it fantastic? Yes.
So, we got keywords. Now, search for
keywords. Uh let's double check make
sure we got the quote there. Okay. And
okay. Now search for keywords. Where is
it used here? So now you need to append
s
uh reserved words. Okay. Pedify.
Fantastic. So this is uh all words. Now
search
again. Okay. And then another part you
want to use it is um let's see all
words. Okay, this variable is actually
not
[Music]
used. Yeah. Okay. Let's change that.
Let's change that to Neil and set s F
all words. Then do that.
Okay. Do that kind
of. Okay. So remove
that.
Beautiful. Okay. Now uh now the font
lock keywords. Okay, highlight this
part. Oh, when there's a Oh, okay.
There's also
functions. Okay, that's right now
empty. Uh it's empty list is equals to
Neo. So let's just say Neo and let's say
uh let's say for now for Neo. Okay. So
here's to-do need need uh DOS command
keywords. Okay. That was that's from
PowerShell. So delete that to-do need
color for param that's for
PowerShell. So remove
that. So we got functions. Uh functions
is actually not used. Uh but you got
keywords. Keyword is here. So keyword
should come before functions. Yes. So
put that
there. Okay. So rejects. So this is a
list of words. You make them into one
single regular expression by calling
rejects
opt. Okay. And uh then all these regular
expression of words will be colored
keyword phase.
Fantastic. Okay. So what is this? This
is uh this is dollar sign. Dollar sign
make it
bold. Why are we doing
that? Uh
because so this is
uh what is underscore? What is that
symbol? Okay.
So we don't need this. I don't I forgot
where it came from. From PowerShell
probably. So from PowerShell mod. So you
can you can see
uh lock.
So phone
lock. Yeah. So this is from
powershop fun lock function name
face. Oh beginning. Yeah. So I want to
highlight
every symbol identifier. If it start
with f then I want to make it color it
as a function because in my convention
all functions start with f
uh you know it's not very universal con
convention and I I'm not 100% sticking
to that. So actually I can remove that
but anyway so back to uh F. So we don't
we don't need
that. Okay. So we got
um we got color. So now make a backup.
Go to
directory by compile. Are you sure? Yes.
Is there a error? No. When you typically
when you bite compile uh it'll warn you
or error tell you some error. So there's
no error. Fantastic. Open the bite
compile file. Delete it. Close it. Now
eval the buffer. Now go back to our F
code. Close that. Close that. Close
that. Go to the F code. You see the four
and do are not colored. The try is not
colored. Now we close this reopen. And
this open is not colored. Now we close
this and reopen. It will reload F mod or
I can say
uh F you know. So if I call this again
they will be colored. Okay. Check check
check this open and this for in do try.
Okay do
it.
No
what didn't happen. Okay. Close it.
Reopen it. It didn't color. So what
happened with the do when open? Are they
not the
keywords?
Wait. Such such such such.
So I've got So
actually, so let's
see
keywords. Wait, there's
two. There's open. Uh, wait. So there's
two. Why is it not
colored? There's
two. Okay.
[Music]
Maybe evaluate it again. Now try again.
Sign F
mod.
Okay. Houston, we got a
problem. Now, is there some error
messages? No, there's no error. Okay, go
to the messages buffer. It doesn't say
anything. Close
it. So that means you just double check
somewhere you are not
careful. Am I doing good? Am I
alive?
Respond. Gun Emacs for success says,
"How about you? Here is Luis." Oh,
Louise, a new
name. Uh, just come to greet you. Oh,
hi. Great to see you again,
Luis. And, uh, thanks for the for the
many likes on YouTube, on the
Twitter. So, back to the code. Uh, yeah,
I'm alive. Thank you. Thank you, ACP. So
now we got a problem Houston these
keywords you know we are we failed
failed now why did we fail you know the
great man says well you got to fail
because then you never succeed
something so uh so just rethink okay so
we got a bunch of keywords do we have do
yes wait let's make sure What what
keyword we missing? Okay, we got open
open for in do
try if else. Okay, now go back here. Now
close it. Reopen. It's not highlighting.
Okay, now go back to here. Open do. Do
we have open? You got open do. If okay
so the keywords are
here and
uh search for that keywords and uh
okay color it. Okay so keyword is pink.
So okay I think we up somewhere
here.
Let's see from
here. Okay. So, but let is colored now.
Where does lead come
from? Okay.
So, let's see. Functions. Function is
zero. So, where where the does let
come from? Search
for let.
So let is part of
these keywords right? So what uh so why
is it
um I
think okay now evaluate it maybe we
didn't evaluate is that right close
reopen same
problem okay I'm starting to get
pissed. Go back to the
mod. So, it's opening F
mod. So, let's rename this to be SF.
Okay, let's
just evaluate. Go back here. Go back
here. Watch this mo mode line.
Okay. Close it. Reopen it. Okay, it
means it's loaded new. You see XR F
here, but the coloring is not
happening. And meanwhile, you got the
let colored. What? Why is that?
Okay, let me think about a little
bit. a brief table, syntax table, group
F mod,
uh, fun lock
keywords. Okay, I think I'm going to
rewrite this a little bit. Let's see.
Uh, define
bar. Yeah.
So this you know this is very annoying
part of lisp because you got this back
tick they are design they they are
called reader macros Okay. So that
back tick what essentially what it means
is that when you have back tick parn
that
means don't
evaluate whatever is inside the parent
but
however do evaluate if there is a comma
before it. So that means you do evaluate
this part but do not evaluate you know
that
uh so you evaluate that part. So you
know okay let's see describe variable
what do we have this defined
yes keywords is defined it's this list
now what is the function is it
defined yes but the value is new that's
correct now so why is this fun keyword
face not working
Okay, now let's go to uh this mod. Let's
just do some comparison of things that's
that's
working font lock. Okay, let's go to EAC
this mod to see. So, so here
is you see here is the
keywords syntax coloring for my EMAC.
This mod tried and true. This mod I've
been using for 15 years and I'm using
right now. You see
elisp
now. So you can model
it. So what what what are you doing
here? So
let's so you are
set. You don't need the let you know. So
wait make a copy. So this let is empty
anyway. So
refresh syntax I mean pretty fine. So
you got basically this keywords needs to
be a
list. So that seems right. Seems right
it's a list. And then you got the
keywords looks
right. Okay. This mod seems seems right.
Now go back to the F
mod. This mod F
mod
face rejects up
symbols. Did we up somewhere here?
So F keywords these are a list of
strings. Is that right? Yeah. A list of
strings. I compile. No
error. Okay.
Close this.
Reopen, you know that
I This is
odd because you see this let and print
F, they came
from my old version of the mod that only
color these
two. Uh so they are still coloring these
two but the the
mod already removed it. Let's
see. Make sure we got it
right. So you see if you search for
print it's not even found anywhere.
Uh,
so you know one one thing we can always
do just restart a new Emacs. Let's see
if that
works. Oh, I already So it's here. Yeah.
So actually, let me show
you. Press a key. That will start
Emacs. It started here.
delete. Okay, try again. Press a key.
Yeah, you cannot see it. It started
here. So, here is a new fresh Emacs.
Now, let's go to
um this is my go script. Here is a F
script. Let's open it. Let's see if it
syntax
color. How beautiful. Can you
see? Magnify, magnify, magnify. So, it
actually works.
The reason it does not work over
here is because some residue situation
you know because when you code emac this
usually when you are developing EMAC
list usually you need to restart Emacs
because there is some
residue buffer variables or variables
something so that doesn't refresh proper
proply but so now I have two choices
of behavior. One is to be stubborn
obstinate and find out exactly why is it
not updating in this emacs. you know why
why is wh what exactly what variable is
am I um why is it not refreshing
properly
okay the other choice is just move on
you know close this and you know move on
we you know we what we uh wanted to do
worked most people choose this
way you know just move on get things
done but I usually choose is the
stubborn way because I want that's how I
know so many language details. I want to
know exactly why it's not updating some
you know. So let me try that for a while
for a little bit. Okay. So this mod
close now F mod works we
know. And also we need to fix the print
f is not working because that's not a
language keyword apparently that's a
function. So let's add print f to uh
back.
So so where is it syntax table? So yeah
so keywords the function uh functions
color it. Okay. So you
need print f.
Okay. Okay. So let's now just double
check where what possibly could be
wrong.
Okay. So you got keywords
Okay, reserved words F functions. You
got one print f. Then you got all words,
you know. Then then you got the coloring
keywords and functions. Okay, right now
just color those two. Then you got the
key
bindings. Then you got the syntax table.
Um okay then you got
uh then you got complete symbols
uh you know name completion then you got
you know the template abbreviation for
template. So I can type you know L for
let for example for example uh wait and
do L becomes let
fantastic I type so much I have you know
hand problems these days so I'm going to
get on to use this fantastic
um swab board pretty soon V A L B O A R
D they are magnetic magnetic
Wars of keys, you know, truly fantastic.
So, I'm going to get to use that. You
know, I'm going to become a
because I type too
much despite all the fancy setup. You
know, the, you know, because, you know,
I've been typing for 30 years. And, uh,
anyways, let's go back to the code.
So I I think probably I'm just like
missing update something. Okay. Some
like something miss update.
Uh so let's see. So here's a brief
table. Alpha let CM for comment. CM for
um CM for block
comment. See? Fantastic. And you can
delete with delete it with a single key
press. You can
see. Okay. Undo, delete. Okay. So, back
to this Emacs. By the way, it's a great
thing to have multiple Emacs. Just press
a key and you can launch so many Emacs.
But you know one annoying thing is it
why is it launching in the background?
Usually it's in the front. Okay. So like
let me show you again. Press a key. You
got a new Emacs. So you want to set up
your Emacs so that it doesn't ask you,
you know, oh by the way there's already
a init file. Do you want to like
override or there's already a lock file
or something? You don't want that. You
don't want Emacs. You want to be able to
press a
key always start a new Emacs successful
successfully. So, and don't use the
Emacs server, you know, like because
that gets very
complicated. Press a key, new Emacs. So,
you can when this EMAC is running
something, you can just press a key and
do something something, you know, um on
a new Emacs. So, for now, close that.
Close that. Close that. Okay. Now, let
me get back my uh Okay. So, now we we
focus
on where is our problem. I think I kind
of know. Okay.
So you know the reason it's not working
is because this I'm pretty sure because
you see so this section is where we
actually define the mod define derived
mod scar mod based on fundamental
fundamental is do nothing mod okay in
EMAC there's always a major mod so you
cannot turn it off so in practice
turning off any major mod like you don't
want any features at all means set it to
fundamental mod. Okay. So this section
defines the
mod and
uh and if you look at the documentation
for the define derived mod here's the
documentation describe function to see
it. So you know so you know this is when
you learn how to def write a major mod.
So you can see it's got this bunch of um
keyword argument which is not standard
in Emacs. They are kind of a
hack. So you so this keyword argument
and one of them you know so here you see
keyword ar. So one of them is syntax
table. Okay. Then table. Okay. So what
does that mean? What that means is that
let me go to the code here. You see? So
what that means this line this line is
equivalent to let me show you. Okay.
This line is equivalent to
um
set syntax
table
to that.
Okay, this line is equivalent to that.
So it's some kind of a
shortcut. Okay, so let's remove
it. Remove it. Okay, and use this
instead. I'm pretty sure that will work.
But before we try purify the code now,
before we try, let's make
sure I did use the correct um I did set
the correct um I believe that's that.
But let's look up my documentation for
how to write the mod. Okay, let's go to
today's talk
show. Today's talk show. go to write the
major mod and uh syntax for syntax
coloring the first lesson because syntax
coloring is almost the first thing you
want to
do. So you go to the bottom and you see
uh set font lock defaults. Okay,
wait. So what is that?
No, not not syntax table. Wait, where is
fun lock default? Oh, wait. It's
here. Okay, so we are not
Yeah, I made a mistake. We are, you
know, it's not syntax
table that we are concerned. What we are
concerned is mostly this fun lock
keywords. So we we actually do set it
here. So why is it not
um reset the found
keywords? I don't
know, you know, but this this is kind of
annoying. So let's try
without
God. Maybe that.
Okay. Evaluate the buffer. Now go to the
F code. Now pay attention to this syntax
curing to see if they worked. Close
this. Reopen it. No, it didn't. Okay.
Okay, I give up. I'm going to, you know,
look around
offline. Uh, actually, we got a lot of
other things to do.
Um I'm I'm unsure the SWboard is truly
uh better for ergonomic left and right
finger movement seems straining. Not
really because on normal keyboard when
you want you have upper row and lower
row. So when you want to type upper row
you move up and press. If you want to
press the lower row, you move down and
press. But on
the Okay, let me show
you. Okay, we are digressing. But this
is interesting. So, but on the um on the
Swarboard when you want to type the
upper row, all you have to do is just
like move up. Like you don't even have
to go up so much then press down. When
you want to press the lower row you just
you know press down. And this side are
extra like they they provide you for
like control key and the meta key or
punctuation or whatever extra. So, this
is incredible
ergonomic finger saver and those are
magnetic key switches I talked about
previously. So, but why have I not been
using it after a year? Well, just
because I
just busy coding and you know I just
didn't play with it because once you you
see once once I do this I'm not going to
use all standard keyboard anymore.
That's one thing but it takes time to
learn that's
why. So my I believe that SWboard SV A L
B O A R D is just fantastic. Yeah. So I
I I'll start to get to use to use
it. Okay. So I think I'm going to give
up on why the syntax actually
um why is it
uh function
mod close
reopen? Why why is it
not the font lock is not resetting or
something? Okay.
Uh I don't know why is that comment a
brief. So make a backup. Now load
now by compile. Load the by compile.
Okay. Now go to
F.
Um where is the code? F. So go to
find open it close
open close open and so it's not working.
So So let's
see describe variable font log
um defaults. Let's see what
exactly you see for
keywords its value is found. So, oh, so
this part is not
evaluated. Is that
right? No,
wait. Yeah, it's very
annoying. You see if we go to the new
Emacs instance describe variable let's
magnify. Okay. Uh okay. So you need
to
magnify. Go to up. So now
describe variable font
lock defaults. That is a variable you
need to set. Then the fun lock mod will
just color
everything. So check what is the value
of that variable. Oh, it's actually the
same the same as here.
So so that is not the source of the
error. So what is so is you see this is
getting technical.
Uh, I'm not sure I should continue this
path because this is getting
esoteric, but I can continue to look
into why the coloring doesn't happen.
Should I do that or should I just move
on? Because then I because we move on,
we need to do
um we need to add the templates for lots
of these keywords. You know there's like
do while loop and beast and you know
lots of
others. Oh okay not showing the screen.
Oh that always
happened. So okay let me sum summarize.
So so right now we are trying to find
okay we are trying to find out why the
coloring is not working. But it does
work if you restart Emacs. You see it
works here.
But it's not working
here. Why is that? So, so if we go back
to the F
mod to do with the fun lock keywords not
set. So if we go to
the F file, close it, reopen. Okay. Not
working. Now describe variable fun
defaults.
Okay. So this fun defaults is the
variable you need to set. When you set
that then the the color that's how the
syntax coloring works. So we need to
check what is the value of the fun lock
defaults and it says the value is
this okay local in in this file. That's
correct right. But now if you look at
the
new instance of Emacs where this works
and describe variable fun lock defaults
you can see the value is the
same.
So so I do not
understand
why this doesn't work this no syntax.
Let me turn off on lock mark. Okay. Fun
lock mod. Turn it off. So now there's no
color at all. Now turn it back
on. You see it doesn't work. Uh so there
is some kind of residue. How do you call
it?
Leaked
variable value somewhere like
buff. Could it be buff or local? No.
It's something global.
something global I don't understand. So
this is this is very uh this would be
very interesting for me to look into
because that's when you
learn the deeper technical details about
how things
work. But it's getting technical I mean
very esoteric. I don't so I'm not sure
you guys would be
interested because then everything I
need to explain everything.
Yeah. So or we can move on. So what uh
if we gonna move on then then what we
gonna do is we move on and talk about
how to do Yeah. Let's move on. Okay. So
now let's move on. I want to get I want
to do some templates. Okay. So right now
I have Lcm TQ. So let me show
you. So go to the bottom. L is let CM is
is common block common. Okay. TQ is
what? Oh, TQ is triple
quote. Uh triple quote. Wait,
does F does does F support triple quote?
I don't think so. Wait, I don't know. I
forgot. This might be from PowerShell.
So, DTQ is for what? Okay. So, P is
print line. Okay. So, we got these
comments. So, let's add a few comments.
I mean the the templates. Okay. So, for
that we need to go to
F language guide somewhere.
U language guide. Okay. That's my
favorite tutorial for F official
Microsoft. This is the best. So you need
Okay. So
this
Okay. So you need um Yeah. So you need
to add
some Yeah. Let's do some a brief. Okay.
I mean template. So overview literal.
Literal are numbers and types. We don't
care.
Uh so you got let Okay. So this thing is
so you got triple quote there. Okay.
Copy. Okay. So we can
uh let's move it down. Okay.
So, so this we need this this this we
need
uh wait, how does that
work? Do you need the square brackets? I
think you
do. Okay.
Okay, lit for literal. And what else?
Lit for literal. That's a compiler
directive. So when you have lit for
literal, that means it tells the
compiler to automatically change this
constant into that in the compiled code.
Uh, okay. So, you got literal, then you
got uh match. Okay. So, let's copy this
one.
Match. So, you need some kind of match.
Okay.
Uh
so okay I think that's it you know so I
just need to so pattern
matching in F you know pattern matching
I learned you know I'm I'm a wuam
language expert since
1990s so I've been coding wufam language
for like 20
So I learned in F pattern matching is
much inferior much less like one
magnitude less powerful than wam
language. Um the pattern
matching the reason is because wufam
language is term rewriting system. So
the whole language is designed just
to rewrite you know like you know
replace nested you know because it's
based on lisp the syntax is purely
nested
expression and the term rewriting system
means the engine how it does computing
is just replace part of expression by
other
things okay that's all it does wam
language
mathematica it's called term rewriting
system. Okay. So what all it does for
computation is just replace part of the
expression by other parts. So it heavily
relies on term rewriting on on the
pattern on a pattern matching and
replacement just like regular
expression. Okay. Except it's not text.
I mean it's not
string. So that's term rewriting wam
language.
and uh it's purely based on nested
expression but in in in but in F and
Hascal they are not based on fully
nested expression. Okay.
So, so that means in wam language you
heavily need to have patterns that match
nested
expressions not. So in F you only you
you only match for example you can see
uh pattern matching overview they show
you all the patterns here. Okay.
Constant pattern identifier pattern.
This needs to magnify. Okay.
uh you know you know
so cons pattern like head and tail of a
list
pattern you must specify exact number of
count length of the list same thing for
array and parenthes size pattern is just
um I believe that's just grouping so
anyway that's not
much so but in wolf language you can you
and pattern match with trees like like
uh so it's much more powerful. So
anyway, back to this what we want to do
is we want to write a um template for
the pattern. Okay,
so something like that. Okay, so
whenever you see match, you replace it
by something.
Okay. Uh just
for evaluate it back to the back to the
code. So type match enter.
Fantastic. Then we're going to refine it
later like put put the cruiser here or
something. Okay. That's that's it for
today. Thank you guys for watching. So
it's been an
hour. Yeah, it's Yeah. So I need to do
this. Uh I'm learning PowerShell. I mean
F.
Fantastic. Bye
guys. Anything else? Uh I think that's
it. So literal. Do we have it? Yes.
Fantastic. So literal works liit space
then you got that. Uh so typically when
you type literal you want let after
right I
think.
Yeah by by by by by
Louis. So delete that literal we got let
triple quote then we got uh match. So we
can type match. We got that. Fantastic.
Fantast fantastic. Fantastic.