Hello guys. Hello guys. Welcome to
another episode of Kawar Talk Show.
Episode What episode is this? Episode
698.
Now, if you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed minimum. If you are
watching live, say hi. Love to see your
comments.
Okay. So, here is your chat box. So, we
are going to talk about Emac Bisp.
define var key map and define key map.
So,
uh this is going to be very technical
for those of you Emacs users. For the
rest of you, it's going to be boring,
but I'm going to do a live stream
anyway. It's probably not going to be
many watchers because this is, you know,
when you talk about computer science or
esoteric stuff like not too popular, uh,
the audience shrinks by a magnitude.
Okay, now let's check one last time. Uh,
video check, audio check. I'm using red
light. If you have noticed, red light is
good for your eyes. So, I recommended
uh you know after 9:00 turn on red
light, get some red bulbs. It's good for
your eyes. It's soothing.
Okay. And uh Hello, Tamid. Okay. So,
we're going to talk about let's let's
begin to talk about this. Today's uh
thumbnail is brought to you by the 4chan
people pepe.
This is beautiful. I love it. I love
this artwork. Okay. Okay. So, we going
to start to talk about uh define key.
So, let me introduce you uh what we are
doing what what that is. So, in EMAC
which is a fantastic text editor which
is what I'm using. Okay. It's uh for
programmers and for writers. Amazing.
Cut undo. So, you can you know show in
browser. So, anyway. So in in Emacs,
search for Kasar Emacs tutorial on
kasari.info
you will find it. Okay. So you go to the
key section. So Emacs has thousands of
keyboard shortcuts by default and uh you
can find it. Actually I have an article
1,000 default key binding
you know uh and you got the meta key
from the lisp keyboard uh and so on.
Okay. So, uh, okay. So, let's copy that
showing browser and let's just paste the
link here. So, because we talked about
it, linkify. So, there it is. 1,000
default key bindings. But, let's go
back. So, Emacs keys. This section will
tell you everything you need to know
about defining keys. Okay. So, how do
you do it? So, they define key
introduction page and you can read about
it. Okay. Uh but what I want to do is so
in EMAC 29 they introduced a whole set
of functions to define key which are
superior.
Okay. So define key. So you can read
about it you know it's all detailed here
but let me just jump to the parts that
talks about that. Uh okay. So you click
on define key then you scroll down you
will have the EMAC change keys topic
box. So this link EMAC keys key binding
functions EMAC 29 change. So in EMAC 29
which is rel released in 2023 two years
ago they added a complete new set of
commands for defining keys.
So on the left hand side is the new
commands. On the right hand side is the
old corresponding commands. So for
example the old command is define key
but now the new one is key map set.
Okay. Now another old command global set
key that is let's say if you want to
have F4 to be copy to do control um C
while in actually in EMAC is some other
key it's a meta meta metaww
anyway so in the old command global set
key that lets you set up a keyboard
shortcut in the Windows target. But the
new command is keymap global set. Okay,
so Emacs 29 introduced a set of them. So
they all start with keymap dash
something and they are better because
they
they are better. Okay. So for example,
here is Emacs uh 29. This is a new one
key map global set. then a string that
represents a key in this case control T.
Then the command you want it to be
whitespace mode. Okay. So you when you
press so if you run this control T will
do will turn on white space mode which
means let me show you.
You see they show you see when you have
a lot of white spaces now they show up
as starts. Can you see that?
So now if I turn off whites space mode
press
uh press press press press press press
press press press press press press
press press press press you see normally
you don't see them but in in some cases
like when you code in a programming
language that you know you need to know
the difference between a tab
and the space you know you cannot tell
right now you cannot tell what they are
but if I turn on white space mode uh
which I have the key
uh that that that that so you can see
the tab you you got a triangle for a tab
there.
So that's so anyway back to the key
binding. So when you run this command
then control T will call that. So this
is a new syntax. The old syntax is using
global set key. Then the keyboard
shortcut you need to call the function
key KBD then you know. So it's pretty
similar. It's actually
alike but the new one is much better.
Okay. So that's the EMAC changes. Now
this is EMAC 29 two years ago.
So
you know as time you know the one thing
about software updates you know every
year they update software always update.
So when it's 5 years old they eventually
become obsolete. So this is new just two
years ago you may not want to change
your code yet because if you change it
then many people are not yet on Emacs 29
then they will say oh how come this
doesn't work you know. So, so software
update is gradual, you know, like uh
your Windows, you know, are you using
Windows 7, are you using Windows Vista
or are you using Windows 2000?
Same thing on the Mac, same thing on the
Linux, you know, they update every year.
And uh so they always so the update are
gradual to allow people who have like
five years old computers to be still
functional.
But however it is an inevitability
for the change. Okay. So today you know
you you know so you know in five years
in 10 years this old you know there will
be like not many people using these old
old ones relying usually uh because of
the younger generation. So for me a old
man you know I'm used to the old ones.
So the the old commands for are there
for 30 years, 40 years,
but inevitably inevitably the new ones
will come and replace old. Okay. So I'm
so I'm starting to since I'm a prof
professional, you know, developing Emacs
and uh doing Emacs tutorials for for you
guys. So I need to uh adapt the new one
sooner or later. Okay. So let's turn off
the white space mode off. Press press
press press.
Okay. On the pink window you can see all
my command call names and uh and uh they
are keystroke. For example, you can see
white space mode and keystroke on the
left which is backspace which is this
key on my left hand thumb backspace and
space space. That's Vora keyboard layout
and I'm using keys.
Okay, the most efficient key binding,
more efficient than vim or neo vim. The
most efficient in the universe to do the
same thing. You require less number of
keystrokes and you don't need to hold
control and old stuff. Okay. So you can
watch you know this is my homepage uh
softly keys key binding system and there
are like 20 or 30 videos about it. Okay.
So let's go back to key binding. So
introduction. So close that. Close that.
Copy that. Close that. Close that. Uh s
talk show. Go there. Show in browser.
Emac keys. Close that. So let's just
paste. I want to paste the links of the
things we talked about. So showing
browser
there.
Okay. So,
so the changes. So you see and uh and
there are more changes. Okay. So one one
of the two new commands is define key
map and define var key map. Okay. And uh
so I'm I need to change my command to
use the new command. Okay. So let's go
to my uh packages. So so again this is
something I need to do because I'm a
Emacs dev writing EMAC list code every
day for the past 20 years. So let's go
to uh CSS. Let's see CSS mode. So CSS
mode if you don't know. Okay. So let's
go let's go back here. Showing browser.
Okay. Go to the top. You can see there
is CSS. Open it. This is CSS for.info
my website. So go to the top. You can
see and go to the bottom. There are 800
lines of code. Okay. So press tab and
the help and show all key bindings. So I
got config symbol format buffer. Uh so
you got these commands and these keys to
do them. So let's say I want to do uh
format buffer. Okay. So let me show you
fantastic command. So you see this let's
say this body part. This body part
everyone should understand if you know
CSS.
If you don't know CSS
search for visual CSS or CSS tutorial on
sardi.info info my website so my website
kasari.info info then you scroll down
you'll see visual CSS CSS stand for
cascading style sheet so that controls
color controls the shape controls layout
that's CSS so you are looking at so copy
that go back here talk show
uh and go back here paste the link CSS
there okay go back here and
and go to the top and open the CSS file.
So we are back to the CSS file. Okay. So
you can see the directory here. Okay. So
here is a block of code body, right? So
if I okay I'm not going to demo CSS but
let's say I press a key they become one
line. Okay, still functional valid. Now
if I want to format let's say let's
let's make them all one line. Okay. Now
if I okay save it. Now I want to format
the whole buffer. So I press tab
press F. Fantastic. You see the entire
buffer entire file got pretty printed.
You see the body becames like that. Do
it again. Format it. Fantastic. You see?
So let's tap F. So let's say describe
key tap f that tells me what does this
key do. So tap f will call the command
css format buffer and that command is
defined in this file and has a key tap
f. So you go to the file enter. So
here's a source code and this code
actually you know it's like 30 lines but
it actually requires Deno it call the
deeno JavaScript
okay CSS got spend all the time talking
about that uh okay save it close so
what did I want to do okay so open it
describe key tab F then jump to the
source code of CSS s file. Now go to the
directory. You can see the CSS mode. So
now in this file, this is emac this
package. There is of course key binding
defined. So let me show you
uh key binding. Okay. So you can see
here.
So define var CSS mode map. That's a key
map. That's a set of keys. You know, you
declare a variable. Then then you create
in this block of code you create a new
key map make sparse key map. Then you
define a new
prefix command kasa CSS leader map. Then
for each then you call define key
means you want to define key in this CSS
mode map. Uh god okay. So let me explain
this line. Okay. So you define key for
this key map and with this key space and
what it do is call this command CSS
complete symbol. Okay. So anyway the
point is that this two
um
god okay this block of code is for
defining keyboard shortcuts like we
demonstrated tab F. You see that's the F
and where's the tab? The tab is right
here. You see
you can define a leader key. So you see
if if the leader key exist then use that
otherwise just use tab. So that's my
Kasar EMAC system. You can buy it by the
way
uh for $100 because for 15 years they
are all free but I die of hunger.
Okay. So, so let's Yeah. Okay. So, let
me show you. Okay. Here is the homepage
of Kas CSS mode. You can search it,
you'll find it. Then go one one level
above. Click on that. So, you can see
all my emac be packages.
Okay. So, my point is that so let's go
to the key map. Okay. So, yeah. So what
I'm saying is that
for each one of these EMAC these
packages I have written they have this
uh key map block okay so and this they
are using the old command for example
this define key so let's go back here
let's go back to the you know to the
difference you see the old one is define
key the New one is key map set
and uh and so I want to start to use a
new one. So let's so let's start to
change it. Okay.
So first of all okay so make a backup.
Um
so is this boring enough for you guys?
Sriiety. Okay. So yeah, I want I want to
make a So So first of all,
you got um
so this is just uh this is me start to
do code s talk show. Okay, s talk show
today. Uh you have define key map and
define v. Copy them.
Make a backup. pasted them here so that
I can see and uh okay so
um
so you want to start to define them
first of all define key map define v key
map so instead of this two blocks
you know I can now let's let's purify
them okay instead of this this two block
uh
you know I can do the whole thing with
this new command. Okay, so let's do it.
Oh, I don't have the key. I don't have
the template. Okay, so because this is
so pretty new. So describe function to
look at the documentation first. Okay.
Oh god. So you know, so it's got some
new syntax. So, I need to read them.
God, this is getting boring.
So, do you guys know what I'm doing? You
see,
um,
close that. Close that. Okay. So, this
whole block is going to be replaced by
this
command. And it should be simpler. Okay.
But but how but what how do you do it
though? Uh you see here's the part that
when you need to use your brain to read
the documentation
define v key map variable name
uh then key
what is that key for? I don't
understand. doc full parent suppress
name prefix
key map repeat and the rest okay I don't
I don't know how is this used
okay so so look at define key map first
define key map key full parent suppress
name prefix something something rest
okay so
who's keeping giving me the hearts thank
you
yt space text primary inverse
what does that mean
hello sakuma
okay So you see I'm doing this live
stream because you know this is
something actually I need to do you know
I can either do it offline which I've
been doing you know all the time
uh
but sometimes I do it on you know live
stream so that while I'm doing it for
something I need to do meanwhile I talk
to you guys that's what this is about.
Okay. So this close close.
Okay. So let's just do this. Okay. So
what we do we want to look for example
in you know instead of reading this this
you know this abstract technical
documentation you have to think about
like what what what do you mean what is
this you know let's look at the example.
Okay. So close that. So, so copy define
v key map. Actually, what's the other
one? So, this one is actually simpler.
Okay. So, put that there. Let's let's
put that there. Okay. Define key map.
Copy it. Now, let's look at look up the
documentation for
the ED something in Emacs. Okay. Jump to
the source code.
Here's a directory. Okay. Now in this
directory let's search for define key
map. Okay.
So that um
so let's search it. Search the entire
Emac list this
source code. So it'll show us if any of
this file is using it. If it is then we
can check out how how they are doing it
and copy and paste.
Okay, it's running.
It's running. Wait. Okay, so there there
is a result. So lots of programs are
using it. Okay.
So let's see.
Let's open it.
Okay. So actually lots of
lots of it. So let's see what how many
what files. So all these files not many
are using the new key map commands.
Okay. All these files
uh which is not many because
you know because you know you don't have
to change them. It's not necessary but
it's for forward
you know for the future.
So anyway so let's close that. Let's
look at you know is there you know and
here here is another example but now
it's using macros.
So this is not a good example for us.
Okay let's go to the next one.
This this is about processing images.
Okay. Oh, okay. So, you can see how
simple that is. Okay. So, this seems
very simple. Copy it.
Uh, copy it and go back. Let's go back
to our code.
Autoload. Close. Uh, close.
Yeah. So, let's you know, so here is
kind of a example how they defined it.
Now from this actually I can figure it
out.
Uh let's see map into dark parin image
slice map. Okay so it's using a par
uh and uh what is this? I
define key map.
So,
how many people are used watching eight?
Say something guys. So, okay. So, define
raw key map.
Okay. So let's let's look at the
documentation again. So what is this? Um
so the documentation says you need that
variable name. So let's start to do it.
Okay, let's just start to do it. Okay,
instead of instead of just um so we want
to define a key map that okay variable
name will be that and uh this key I
don't understand what is this key for
oh those are keyword arguments
okay so I think that that key means
keyword arguments like that okay
Uh, is that correct?
Oh god.
See,
define variable name
as a variable with a key map definition.
With a key map definition. Okay. See,
define key map. Oh, let's go there
first. Wait, what's going on? define v.
Oh, actually wait.
So, this part is simpler. Let's let's do
that first. Okay.
Okay. So, define key map. Oh, wait.
Okay. So, key map is just for key map.
You need the var. Okay. So,
Okay.
So you still need the V. So
is it boring? So here's the name.
Then
map put into text properties on images.
What? That doesn't make sense. What?
Okay. But we starting somewhere. Okay.
So it's just so define key map is just
the pairs. Okay.
You see it just pay us. So what we can
do is
okay. So what what we can do is so wait.
So define key map. Let's see the
documentation. Define key map key full
parent suppress name prefix guard. Why
is this so complex?
Oh okay. So this you see this this this
this full parent suppress name prefix
key map those are keyword arguments
documented here. You see full
uh suppress parent key map name those
are keyword arguments. So that's what
this mean this this is a new convention
actually
then
then then
rest.
Okay this is complicated you know.
So another way to look at how to do this
is let's look at the EMAC manual. Okay.
So right now we are looking at the
inline documentation. So
search for the manual for the define key
map. There it is showing browser. So
here is the emac list manual for for all
this. So there it is define key map. So
it looks like pretty simple. Okay.
just like the example we have
but you know but the documentation
I don't understand why is it using conf
confusing things
yeah it it you know it's it's the EMAC
key binding system is quite involved
okay So,
so
uh you need to read them. Okay. Define.
Okay. So,
uh define key map options rest pairs.
So, this key seems like
keyword parameters.
You can create a key map with the
functions described above and then use
key map set for each one to specify key
bindings in that map.
When writing modes, however, you
frequently have to bind a large number
of keys at once. That's true. And uh
using key map set on them or can be
tedious and errorprone. Instead you can
use define key map which is this
function which creates a key map and
binds a number of keys in one shot. Here
is a very basic example that. Okay.
Okay. So let's just go with the like
very basic example here. So you know
exactly just like that. So we need to
convert
you see but there's a complication
because I have two key maps here. One is
that
CSS mode map then the other one is CSS
leader map. The mode map defines a tab
key.
Then then the leader map is whatever
followed by the tap key. So in s CSS
mode you press tap key to begin any key.
Then you know tab space is one thing is
this tab F is format tap R is something
else. Okay.
So,
so let's for now let's just see the wait
this define key map actually doesn't
Oh god. Oh god. This is so confusing.
So where is the name for the key map?
The name for the key map is at the top.
Okay.
Yeah, I'm using the define prefix
command. No
Uh what you Okay, let's let's do this
thing. Let's do brainless. Let's just
No, let's do something brandless. Okay,
let me just show you. Okay, so
so remove all that.
Okay. Then
delete delete delete. Uh delete delete
delete delete. Show the pink window. And
uh yeah. So okay. So actually wait. So
you actually don't want that.
Okay. So you see this block
correspond to this block. This is our
brainless way to do it. Okay, let's just
now remove that. Now,
now this this will be just tab I believe
I think. I'm not too sure. So
and this is this will be the leader map
define V. Okay. Something like that.
And this this this
leader key map. Okay. Parent parent will
be
that. Okay.
So that's one thing.
I'm not sure actually.
Uh oh god. So this means I need to read
more documentation
which is which means
very boring. Okay. most people left.
Okay. So,
yeah, let's keep going.
Define keys. So, a bunch of key um a
bunch of
keyword arguments. Okay. The rest then
definition. Okay. Infer type.
Let's look at the let's see more
examples here. Okay.
Oh okay. So let's see.
So key map image slice map and uh then
in this example.
Okay. So
size images image
um
define a key map doc map put into text
properties on images.
Um
so what is this? Hi.
I don't know.
So define v key map and then define key
map. So it defines a key map.
key map.
I don't understand what is that eye for
dark parent. God is really
Should
be a key map to use as a parent.
Okay. So, maybe I should stop live
stream. What do you guys think?
Um,
so it's been 40 minutes, you know. So,
this this is real life coding.
Very boring.
[Music]
So what what are some other examples?
Let's see
help functions.
Okay. So you are looking at some of the
examples.
What about this one? This one is from
the add define key map.
So define key map is basically
a key map. Okay. With some keys
data hand is so cool. Are you using it?
Uh
okay, close that. Let's go to
So define key map. That's the usage.
Okay. Next
and see.
Okay.
I just watched the video you were
reviewing. Thank you. Yeah. So, I I need
to get on to it. I haven't been using
it. Um
so
so define key map
see
back image speed there another define
key map.
Okay.
Define key map key map. So this this
keyword arguments really confusing.
So let's look at another one. So what uh
Okay.
Okay. I don't know. So
So we have Okay. We have by now looked
at enough examples.
Okay. So here is another example pretty
simple.
Okay.
So here it's defining key sequences.
Yeah.
Okay. So now go back. Let's see what
Okay. then
close. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. So, I think we have looked at
enough examples. Okay. Close.
Now, this is example.
Notice the keyword argument key map.
Okay. Close.
Close.
Now, here is a speed bar.
So, you see they they could have used
define var key map but they didn't.
Instead, you know, they still use the
old define var.
They could have combined these two
together.
Okay. So,
Okay. So this one is got a keyword key
map. Okay, close that. Now uh now this
one is from diff mode diff mode
and uh
okay so it's using let's see
okay so this one is using define v key
map
okay doc and uh escape Then
then this. Okay.
Then here is shared map
define v shared map. Okay. So this one.
Oh, it just have this pairs directly.
Interesting.
You see this is fairly confusing.
You got one of them is define var key
map. Okay. The other one is
define key map. Okay. There.
So you got these two new functions.
Now the way I understand is that define
var is defining a variable. Then
then inside it you can use define key
map. But however
that is not necessarily necessarily
true. You can directly define v key map
and define your keys like here
or you can move this into the define key
map. Okay. So that it's like flexible.
Uh
yeah, but it's but meanwhile it's fairly
confusing.
You see it's confusing for
more than one reason. One of the reason
it's confusing is that it's using this
keyword arguments
which is not
conventional in EMAC. In fact, Emac Lisp
do not have formal documentation for for
the keyword
uh using keyword arguments to define
function parameters keyword parameters.
So,
but this define v key map is using this
or these bunch of keyword arguments.
Okay, that's one aspect it's confusing.
The other aspect it's confusing is
because
you know because of the documentation
you know so so you know this key I have
not seen that document documented
anywhere
if you don't believe me let's go to the
GNU Emacs manual. So here we are looking
at GNU Emacs manual. Okay. So let's go
up. Okay, go up. So here's Emac this
manual. Now if you search for parameter
P P A R A M window parameter search
frame parameters. Okay. Search search.
Okay.
Search search.
Let's search for function. We want
function parameters.
Uh, oh god, there's too many. Let's
search for let's see let's search for
defining a function. Okay, define images
define define symbol define global
variable define define defining function
there.
Okay, so you go there defining a
function. Let's we so we want to know
about the how do you define the
arguments you know rest parameters how
many arguments uh and named
key named parameters also known as
keyword parameters.
So in this section defining functions
section one 13.4
so you got defund
Okay, you know, Emacs documentation
needs a lot improvement. You know, it's
very confusing here.
So, it didn't mention about
the complexity of parameters. So,
okay. So, it's in this section features
of argument lists.
Yes.
Okay.
Then blah blah blah very wordy. Okay. So
it it talks about optional and rest.
Uh meanwhile if you read my tutorial
you'll see simple explanations. Okay
like simply tell you how do you define a
rest parameters and so on or optional
parameters. Okay. But anyway the the the
manual says talks about optional and
rest. So with the emp% optional keyword
I mean in amp% rest but where
we are looking for the key the keyword
parameter represented by emp% key it's
not there you see you see if you go back
here you can see this emp% key
full par suppress and so on that
represent keywords full suppress par you
know so on but the Emacs lisp manual
does not mention anything about emp% key
you see this features of argument list
you know this is you know emac this
manual is not very good because you know
you see they're talking about features
of argument list that's a wording for
this chapter
which is very idiotic Because for most
programming languages, you simply say
how do you define arguments to a
function? How do you define the
functions parameters? You know, you
typically have ordered parameters. Then
you might have optional parameters. Then
you have parameters with default value
which is optional parameters. Then you
might have rest parameters which is
arbitrary number of parameters.
And then you also have some in you know
depending on the language you have
keyword parameters which is you know you
have a name then value but you see this
section does not mention about it. Let's
search for key
you know include a keyword optional. No
that's not
you know there none. Okay. So they they
didn't mention about the ampand key in
the official
GNU Emacs manual for EMAC 30 which is
what I'm using. But however in this
inline documentation for the define key
map it it's you know it's showing that
key.
So let me clarify. So, so this define
key map function
is using keyword arguments
as you can see documented by the inline
documentation here. But however, this
keyword arguments is not defined is not
talked about in the EMAC lisp manual
about defining functions.
So that's what I'm saying. What I'm
saying is that these keyword arguments,
you know, typically start with a uh a
colon. They are kind of semi-standard in
EMAC, you know, they are not exactly
described by the EMAC manual, but they
are like they are like in a limbo
halfass, you know. some some packages
use it some you know but most vast
majority don't
uh and you know there's no documentation
for it
so they are in kind of like you know in
in a in a um
halfexistent situation
so that's why I'm saying this define key
map function is fairly confusing
so you need to so what I need to do is
actually really go through the manual
reading this carefully you know uh for
half an hour
like right now I'm trying to do some
trial and error like right now here so
you can see it it looks kind of right
but that cannot go
I I don't want to run it. So, okay. So,
I think that's it for today. You know,
we start to explore. So, basically the
final form will be something like this.
Okay. So,
in summary before it looks like that but
the new is something like that. In fact,
this is not complete because this is not
complete because um
yeah, I'm pretty sure this is not
complete. So that's why I don't want to
run it. So anyway, that's it for today.
We explored this thing. Okay.
Any questions?
Kasan is back. Nighttime. Yes. I haven't
done a video at night for a long time.
So that's why I'm thinking of doing
here.
Uh
and uh so I'm going to chat for five
minutes and that's it for today. Uh you
know the thing about the timing of a
live stream is that when you do like
normally I do at 12:00 noon San
Francisco time but that means people in
China and in India they will not be able
to see it you know that's uh basically
so 12 12:00 uh midnight I mean 12:00
noon San Francisco time
means
You know sometimes 3:00 in the morning
in China. Let's see. Is that right?
Yeah. It basically means something like
4 a.m. in the morning. So whenever I do
some you know 12:00 noon
Chinese people and Japanese people in
Taiwan, Hong Kong, Indonesia,
uh Singapore, you know the Far East,
they won't be able to watch my watch me
live.
Uh I have sensible people over there
watching me because I'm Chinese blood.
So that's why now I'm doing one I
haven't done one at night for like a
year or half a year. So now the East
Asian, Chinese, Japanese and you know
people they can and Indians they can
watch me live.
uh but
for Americans at this time
not many because most people one of the
interesting fact about population in USA
is that vast majority of people lives on
the east coast why because if you look
at the map it's very interesting
geography
issue okay uh you see
uh let's let's use Google Map. Okay.
So, you go to Google Maps. You go to
Microsoft.
Okay. That's Mountain View. That's where
I live. San Francisco. That's San
Francisco. That's San Jose. This is
California. So, you shrink. You can see
this is California over here. This
block. And you shrink. Then you see the
entire USA.
So you can see by the color on the on
the right side it's green on the left
side it's yellow
means mountain.
So that is why vast majority of people
in USA lives actually lives on the east
coast. Okay. Now let's let's go to
satellite uh satellite and show globe.
Okay. So,
so you can see on the west it's all
mountains, mountains and deserts.
So that's why most people lives on the
east coast. It's all green. New York,
Maryland, West Virginia and Virginia,
East Virginia,
uh Tennessee, you know. So that means at
this time right now it's 11 11 p.m.
California time. That means over there
it's
Uh, it's
2:00 a.m. New York. 2 am. So, most
people are sleeping. So, that's why if I
do live stream
right now,
uh, you know, they are sleeping. So, the
Americans, you know, they are very few
much fewer people are able to watch.
But meanwhile
this is when the China this this entire
you know the most people most people on
earth are in China and India. So there
are like 8 billion people on earth
and 2.5 billion of them are in China and
India each one is 1 billion something
okay so at this time so China is like um
wait do they have sunlight can you get
it to show the sunlight
uh I haven't used uh you know the fancy
feature Can you get it to show tonight?
I don't think so. I forgot.
Okay. But so anyway,
you look so cool. Your website is
amazing. Thank you. Could you tell us
about your self history? Well, I told
that before. So you look for two or
three years ago or just search for my
website like search for you know just
search for bio uh you will find some
information about that. I talked about
that live stream
uh three years ago, four um
ACP says, "Do keyword arcs just allow
for unordered function arcs?" Yes,
unordered and also
uh also with default values.
So
bio let's see what we find bio
YouTube thigh years wants wit thy wits
wants edge and manners that's my
favorite quote
that's from Shakespeare
um okay I I I you know I talk random so
literature classics this is anxi info.
There's like 4,000 pages there. So,
literature classics and uh then you go
to Shakespeare. You go down
uh where is it? Wait. Arabian Knights
Flatland
Time Machine. The tragedy of Titus
Andronicus. This one. Thus wants wit.
thigh wit once manners and edge.
So that's from this my favorite
Shakespeare
uh and LinkedIn I haven't logged in for
like 10 years. So they got my old you
know 10 10 years 15 years old
information there. Um I'm about as good
as dead 2014. So you'll find that and
that's when I'm about as good as dead. I
was dying of hunger. Okay. So there's
ugly some ugly things you'll see
uh you know not ugly but you know not
not not
very pretty stuff.
Um
then
okay profile contact. So you go there
and here is periodic dosage of that's
leaf journal that's like 20 years ago.
So okay and here's Patreon where you can
sponsor me pay me okay if you like my
stuff where is it Patreon. Um,
okay. So, and here is some spam and scam
some some spam and scam site like find
out this guy's phone number, you know,
like there's lots of that site. Find
find out your ex-girlfriend or whatever
wife or where where does someone live,
you know, like something like that.
And here, Python list bank. That's my
That's one of my uh I'm not sure what
that is. That's one of my old email or
something old rent. Okay. So, you can
find you know if if you want to know
about me, you can find a lot of
information and here's my page
profile contact. I'm also on uh Twitter.
And then you can see
um you know many of these social media I
don't use anymore. MSN is dead. Yahoo is
dead. Uh, AOL Instant Message is dead.
QQ
is a China
uh, Twitter, but
uh, I think my account got banned
because I was talking about politics.
Facebook, I haven't logged in for like
over 10 years. Skype is dead officially
like few years ago. or two years ago or
one
uh you know so
yeah and I haven't updated this page you
know for for a long time
uh then you can check out photos of me
then
you know anyway all these are written
like many years ago five 10 years ago
you professional programmer on which
language which you code.
Well, I'm kind of on and off. Okay. So,
I code a lot of languages.
Um, lots of Okay. Uh, you probably new
to me because
programming languages is what I do. You
know, I have a lot of tutorials. So, I
can show you. But that's it for today.
Okay. So you go here god code and you go
to you know lots of programming language
tutorials. Uh there's a index of them
there. Okay.
Uh how can we join discord? Go to kali.
You'll find the discord invite on my
homepage on my kasali.info.
Okay. I think that's it. Bye guys.
Bye guys. We shut down in one minute.
Okay. So this we don't want. So we don't
want this contaminate my
Okay. Cut that. Go to the talk show.
Yeah. Today's talk show. And uh
let's put a code here.
Paste. Pop it out. That's the code. Now
put it back. Syntax for it. Showing
browser.
Okay. Bye guys.