hello guys good morning good evening
welcome to another episode of kar talk
show so today we are going to code emac
L okay so this is a emac session if you
are here say hi and uh if you are a emac
user ask me any emac questions or emac
LEP the best programming language for
the task of text
processing okay emac this and that's
what we're going to do we're going to
talk about function keyword parameters
okay and uh my keyboards glove 0
ultimate hacking
keyboard and uh then there is this
fantastic device this is called swar
board okay now this is actually active
so I don't want to touch it s v a l b o
a r d board so you can search for any of
these on my
YouTube okay and uh let's start coding
okay so if you are watching this offline
skip around because I ramble a lot play
at 1.5 speed okay emac so let's
um adjust this so that you can see the
full of it the pink window shows all my
emac command Calles and key strokes okay
so for example showing browser this is
today's talk show and and go back to emx
suppose so this is the navigation bar
this is that bar you see on top go back
back to emac so if I can press the key
you see that's gun and switch to the
pink window you can see that's a s SM
delete okay and the key stroke is is E
on the vorak keyboard layout which is
what I'm using now press F to undo you
see showing browser now the navigation
bar is back and you can see the pink
window and do F on vak keyboard layout
and I'm using soft like keys so today I
want to talk about so let's go
to search forar emac sis and you'll get
to my tutorial a comprehensive tutorial
on emac bisp and we're going to go to
the function section so emac disp okay
so let's see thisp symbol function
define a function click that's how you
define a function am I am I good check
video check audio check am I
alive hey hey George fantastic oh
congratulations George fantastic
baby you know currently there's a news
about El musk but let's not not talk
about that we're going to talk about
that so on my Twitter go follow me on uh
Discord uh and uh go follow me on my
Twitter so on my Twitter I started to do
talk show so uh so for example um go to
Highlights and uh then uh some of my you
know I post highlight here so you can
see ex talk show number one S Talk on X
episode one this is in January on
personality disorders schizoid
histrionic borderline
schizoo and
schizophrenia that's that's debilitating
so that's talk show number one then
number two number three okay number two
Mass migration of USA Tik Tok users to
red note that's very interesting episode
of online social media and USA versus
China politics that's episode number two
talk on X episode three the Nazi salute
of el musk that's another drama okay so
uh episode four Trump animus Ukraine
Gaza and the Future Okay so episode
number five math history okay and so on
okay so I did um so up to let's see
oh this got disconnected there's
supposed to be let's see click on
that episode seven then there's eight
uh oh okay episode seven so right now
there's eight of them okay so uh you
know go follow me on Twitter I recommend
it because Elam musk which in my
consideration is one of the greatest
American hero judged by what he has stun
you know it's very controversial some
people say oh El musk is this all that
idiots these people are idiots okay I
studied Elam musk uh about two hours a
day in the past about three years so uh
so Adam musk is one of the great
Greatest American Hero and judged by
what by his deeds and the consequences
of what's of his deeds he and and Trump
and of course the Small People Like Us
who voted for Trump they
began uh entire a turning point of USA
history USA Empire okay that's right now
happening okay thanks to Trump and ell
musk no thanks to you bunch of little
Pepe
idiots especially you guys uh forchan
teen teenagers you know like uh babbling
with with your bunch of brainless
idiotic opinions okay back to back to uh
lisp uh I want to call lisp today so
let's back to uh
lisp okay so so now we going to uh
Define a function okay so yeah we're
going to talk about Define function
parameters now so this is a section of
function Let's uh magnify a little bit
let's um
three people watching okay the poverty
of my show so
uh I'm okay so let's uh let's just do
what I have to do okay I need to move
this a bit here and uh the emac this
window needs to I didn't prepare well um
so the emac this window needs to be
broadened a little bit here and in
there hello Jack Jack
Attack what kind of name is that okay so
emac LP okay I'm doing good
okay so EAC l so we're going to do so so
you go to uh emac L tutorial you can see
how you define a function so let's begin
Let's uh let's begin press emac Lis okay
start a start a new code def for defund
expand fantastic we have a function so
let's name this XF okay uh test
function
testing
keyword let's let's uh keyword parameter
okay uh
okay testing keyword parameter
in elisp okay fantastic so here is a
documentation
um okay so let's remove that remove that
we don't need the date but let's put it
anyway okay so so in emac this a
function you there is no keyword
parameter feature so what is a keyword
parameter you know usually normally your
function you have several parameters X y
or directory name or whatever uh or you
can have opt uh um you can have optional
parameters okay so they are the way you
do it is opt okay or and you can have
rest parameters okay
so uh so I need to so this is a syntax
so in this function you have three
required parameters followed by uh
wait is that opt yeah followed by
optional parameters and optionally you
can also have you know the resent
optional is is uh uh okay so followed by
optional parameters you give it you need
to give it a name so let's say 01
O2 okay then followed by rest parameters
which is uh uh rest P okay which is one
single V uh
value so this is this is the parameters
supported in emac list for
functions in other languages you then in
other languages you you can have keyword
parameters you see all these parameters
you know require
are all these parameters are ordered
sequence of parameters so the first
three is required then the next two is
optional so if you pass
you know four four arguments or five
then then the fourth and fifth is going
to be the o1 and O2 and if you pass it
six arguments or more then you know
after that it's all goes to the rest P
you know so that's typically called rest
parameters but in other languages
typically you also have keyword
parameters keyword parameter parameters
is unordered for example in um
let's see let's start Powers shell okay
actually
um yeah let's go to talk show start
poers shell there close that powers
shell move it here
magnify okay and uh let's just prepare
it okay so for example the Okay so
there's a huge amount of things here the
this is a pow shell okay so actually
shrink
it du okay uh shrink it du du okay
that's better so power shell just like
Unix bash you have optional parameters
so for example you can say the path
current then you can give another
optional parameter let's say
filter uh filter uh let's say directory
okay that means only this directories
not files okay so when you have optional
parameters they don't have to be ordered
I mean keyword parameters okay keyword
parameters so the keyword parameter is
in in in this example you have path and
directory and show it so you can see it
shows two directories in this um you
know so
that's keyword parameters you have that
in Python and so on so but IM magist you
don't have that okay so but however
there's a way to do it so go back to
functions Define a function then you go
back here function parameters so that
shows shows you about you know the
optional parameters ordered and then the
rest parameters that comes after that so
and there is no mechanism for default
values okay that's one of the the floor
of emac this and then there is also no
keyword parameters however you can do it
you know you can kind of do it by
convention okay so here's how you do
it am I doing
good so uh so uh George says Ellen has
about 200,000 times more money than me
[Laughter]
okay so he's got so much money
um
uh visent
okay siring
siring siren not
sitting good yeah siren siren is a great
importance to
men because if you don't you die you die
out okay let's go back to this um so we
have so we have you know uh yeah so we
want to do optional parameters okay
let's let's put it here for example so
let's let's say let's change this to X
test okay so we want so X and Y two okay
the X and Y two numbers parameters okay
then we want uh keyword parameters so
how do we do that so here is a
example um let's copy that
okay uh let's let's not that let's make
it like that okay so then okay so let me
show you
okay so actually we don't we don't want
that okay so this is how you
call it okay hold on
second okay so here we
have yeah okay so here we have kind of
we defined the function with a this rest
parameters and we want it to be keyword
so
so what are the
keywords um so right now we named them
ABC so you see this is
not normally support I mean this is not
by default supported by emac thisp so
but we can do it but it's not as
convenient as other languages so the
keyword par the keyword parameters you
simply pass it one one as a rest param
and then the rest Arc will
become uh so we need to change this okay
so change this change this
they in in your function body this rest
AR is a
list of things okay it's a list
then when you call this function so okay
so actually how do you call this
function so the way you call this
function is is so first you got two
numbers let's say three four for the X
and Y and then let's say the keyword
arguments um let document there supports
three key word
ask a b and c okay so that's a name so
here then you just
say uh you just say like that a is let's
say
five b is six let's say that okay if
it's not given it's it'll be used by
default okay so but in the function body
what you have to do is
um in the function body so a if it's in
the list if you found it then use that
if not the default value let's say is
zero okay zero zero okay okay so there
you go ABC so what the function actually
do is just uh uh just print out the
parameter values okay so X and Y so
let's remove
the let's just say x just let's just say
one of them okay so x x is
that parameter value X is that okay
let's put it here x is that a is that b
is that c is that X a BC okay you see
then here the way we now we call it okay
now evalue evaluated now emx knows this
um this function X test now we call it
let's see what they print
okay par values X is three a gets five b
gets six C gets zero fantastic it works
okay that's what I want to show um
the Wier folks message redacted
retracted did you delete it or is it
YouTube did
it okay so so that's what I want to show
but but but but what I so this is how
you implement keyword parameters but
actually what I want to do is to for
example I have a
function um let's go to talk show
showing Brower so this is s talk show
index you can see I have done about 600
videos in the past three uh four
years so let's search I want to search
for all my talk show pages that contains
the word hascar okay so you can look at
the pink window to see the command so
call it I find text let's say hascal
okay in this directory okay HTML files
regular expression
yes okay there you go so you can go down
go down go down go down you see use down
arrow or up Arrow to go jump to the next
occurrence you see all the occurrences
are are highlighted you can just go down
and press enter to jump to the file
showing browser so that's one talk show
that contains the the world has scal you
can
see and you can press a key to show a
list of all files that um
wait uh a list of all files that found
the result you see there's about
um
is there's a line number 34 files
contain in the world has okay so what I
just so so this is output you know close
that what I just called is this function
so you can see s find uh where is
it find find there find text okay so I
can now now let's go to the Bottom now I
can call repeat last complex command
okay you
see you see repeat last repeat complex
command so here it is okay copy it
cancel cancel now go to the talk show go
here paste it okay so this repeat
complex command is extremely useful uh
where did it
go uh there
you see repeat complex command that's
building emac if you want a tutorial of
that just go to SAR emac um you know
just search on my website you'll find uh
detail okay so it you can see it shows
the last command in the lisp syntax so I
call this command I find text pass the
argument of hascal then pass this
argument of the current directory then
the regular expression to filter out
files is.
HTML then you can see
there's two more ordered optional
argument one is NE and one is true T
okay but the problem is you don't know
what they are you see what the [ __ ] is
you know those so you have to look up
the documentation so describe function
there there expand the window so you can
see sine text is a a this closure which
is a jargon for function okay for Pure
function so the syntax is this so you
got search string input directory path
regular expression then optional
arguments then you can see it's the next
argument is fix case search yes or no
then print context yes or no okay P for
pred
so you see
but but how do you know you know so you
got this you know some functions if you
have like 10 arguments
then then you just going to get ne T NE
t or or three four or something you
don't know what they
mean
so in general when a function takes
let's say more than five
arguments then you need to use it's
better to use key keyword arguments
because with keyword arguments this
function will become for example
um let's see let's see the
help uh for example let's copy that
close so if you have keyword argument
this will become like this okay
uh fixed
case okay then uh print
context so now become much more
clear okay so you see what I'm saying
okay I hope so let's put them into a
emac this block
okay now go back here so we did it um
but now there's something else I want to
try Okay um so color the syntax CCT
showing browser so this is what we did
today okay backup now there's something
I want need to test okay so let's try
this
again
um okay Eva Eva go to the message before
okay param values that that's good now
let's do the repeat complex
command uh does it does it um okay
so well now let's do the meta X okay So
Meta
X test function uh doesn't work wrong
number of arguments you can
see uh where's error so anyway when when
you call this function you see we Define
this function but
we but then we meta X then it doesn't
know what are the arguments so you
something we need to fix
here
so so when you call this
interactively uh you need to pass
uh yeah okay so this gets complicated so
the so you need to pass you need to
either pass some value for this ordered
argument or you query the user like a
prompt okay so how do you do that we can
we can prompt
okay so uh so okay so let me so let okay
so
let so in the end you want to return a
list okay so let's say if you call this
function by meta X the first value will
be um okay you need to ask okay
so okay so x x x a x b x c let's say
these are our temporary
arguments
so set XX equals to now you need to
query the user okay so let's see go to
emac this function parameters let's see
okay
so copy that okay go to the talk
show showing browser okay
so put the link here showing browser
okay go there and uh we we want
to keyword parameters okay and we want
to prompt user
about some value okay how do you do that
you go
to em this
section then you go to because this is
related to emac youi to emx when you
prompt user for some question so you
need to go to um
get user input section
so get user
input uh okay ask for a file name ask
directory ask for a
string okay ask for string read string
okay so go back to the code so here read
string okay
uh let's say your name
okay and optional something something we
don't care okay let just okay so this
sets of value what about XA what about
uh the others okay let me just quickly
do it am I talking too slow
okay
comments gz on imminent baby
Goo
weie uh so let's say a
Val for
XA okay let's say that okay repeat
repeat this is just
[Music]
b
c okay then then the result is just
XX uh
uh XA XB x c
okay okay that's it so so this
interactive part is how
emac
feed arguments to your function when you
call this function interactively like
meta X okay
so so uh what what did we do okay so
now the so you ask user for these values
okay so that's good okay let's evaluate
this evaluated and now let's call Meta x
x test your
name enter value for XA let's
say uh let's say three okay three enter
value for XP
let's say four enter value for XC let's
say I just press enter okay
Enter okay
uh so nothing printed let's go to
messages
buffer what what it didn't do anything
oh okay so actually
uh
what so you got three values oh
because wait why is it not doing
anything click close
it
eval meta x x test enter enter enter
enter okay nothing comes
up
now go to messages
[Music]
but it just say X
test okay why is it nothing printed
because we
said oh okay so we need to actually say
messages Okay so
the buffer meta x x test enter enter
enter enter there it is go to the
message buffer parent value X okay it's
empty a is zero B is zero C is
zero uh is that right yeah because I
press enter then it's near so okay
actually so we need to fix
that do you guys understand what I'm
saying I guess not because
this because this is fairly technical
emag this few few of you
guys I don't think you know few of you
guys have even ever wrot a emag list
function except maybe some of you yeah
but we are get getting into more um
fairly Advanced well um okay but
um so what we need to do okay so value
let's put the value inside this bracket
okay because that way you will know it's
empty you know when it's empty you
you'll see this bracket corner brackets
that's used by uh in Chinese okay a
this is this character is called Corner
bracket
okay so when when it's near then you'll
see a corner bracket with nothing inside
but that lets you know there's something
you know but it's empty without this
bracket then you'll just see nothing you
know so sometimes you don't know if it's
uh you know so
anyway so this is how you print
print the arguments and
uh and uh you want to Let's uh let's
make it more elaborate okay so let's
here result okay result okay
so set X result equals
to
format
okay equals to
format format returns a string okay
so okay this returns a string then here
you say
messages X
result and uh you and that will print it
but you want the function to actually
return this string so you can put that
there you know so this allows you
to you know so when you call this
function in emac disp you know like like
that then it will return a string okay
so uh so but we are not done yet
because because uh let's
say let's let's uh
let's shorten this
okay uh let's remove that created
[ __ ] okay so what do you uh so we the
keyw
AR so you want to pass them not like
that you want to
say uh
like that okay because
that's so b c that's how you want to do
it okay and I think that's good so
backup go to the files
directory by compare it yes no error
okay sounds good open it delete it close
it shrink the window okay so now
evaluate this function
now let's say meta x x test enter enter
enter enter okay so now go to the
message sper it says all empty that's
correct let's do it again meta X test
your namea enter value for XA
three value for XB enter enter okay now
see the output your name
uh value for a is three now and B and C
is empty that is incorrect because it
should get a zero because when it's
empty you should get zero
so okay so so when you call this
interactive you press enter what it gets
is a empty string
yeah so it gets empty stram it didn't
get
ne so when this is empty string so you
need to distinguish empty string versus
Neo and so that's you know so this
question is about when you call read
string if the user just press enter
normally the value will be empty string
but you can make it so that the value
returned is Neil I mean the value feed
to your function is
Neil yeah so initial
input okay
then uh initial input history default
value so initial
input okay history NE Okay so you kind
of okay we can fix
that let me just show you how to do that
okay uh am I am I making
sense you can also use case or C def for
more complex argument okay so David says
David minint David minint is a uh emac
this code fantastic but however PKS
that's right
but however I don't want
to I don't want to be associated with
common lisp in any
way because I despise common disp so I
will never use common this you know
defend but the other um the other
suggestion is use P
case uh yes um now PKS PKS is kind of
new new in emac this yeah I could use
that um yeah PK is by now it's like 10
years old so PKS
is kind of new okay so PKS is created by
um by stepan Mania who has been a leader
for emac for for about five or 10
years okay so I respect him he's a great
guy he is
also his profession is a he's a
professor on functional programming
languages okay so he wrote P
case uh which I actually never used and
never actually started to look into so
it says meta language style pattern
matching yeah I've been wanting to uh
use it but I just never got to
so yeah so I should use PKS it's you
know I should you know instead of you
know so P case allows you for pattern
matching so instead of doing this like
manual
hardcoded way and
cumbersome I think PKS will make it
easier so I should look into uh but
meanwhile uh but meanwhile there are
several other issues uh we need to fix
okay so let me see quickly initial
input history default value okay so
initial input Neil history Neil and
default value NE um wait that doesn't
work so they actually so they get the
value so when you call this function
interactively by meta X this will get
the value of Neo so when they are
Neo what you get here so okay so wait
uh wait so delete
that so
XA so this is
Neo so a gets NE then here or
so this returns
near therefore it should return zero but
why is it not returning zero I don't
know so let's so let's
message value
of a
is let's see what we actually get what
okay so and here uh it will
[Music]
be oh actually uh you see that's
why okay
so okay so here we actually print print
the whole
let's see what we
get so
remember this
part is the interactive part is how emac
feed arguments to your function when you
call this function interactively okay so
that's what this part is for if you call
a function in imag this like that then
the interactive part is ignored
okay uh
uh okay
[Music]
so so let's print this actually over
here so so in either case you'll print
them
okay okay so evaluate this make a backup
now Co X test enter enter enter enter
okay go to the message but so you
get so the value of keyword argument is
that okay
so what does that
mean they didn't say Neo you see it just
so this so we we still have the question
of empty string versus Neil
so why is that so let's try message is
just print print a list okay and uh a
symbol AA and Neo and a symbol BB and
three okay let's print run this and see
what we get do
it so this is what we get so Neo okay so
if you actually have a value of NE you
do get Neo so in our case we are
actually getting
empty string
here yeah we are getting empty string
there so that means go up over here we
are getting empty string okay you know
we can fix it but I guess you I hope you
understand what I'm doing so now it's
been an hour maybe that's it for today
um
uh you know I I got actually you
know that's you know we didn't finish my
goal my goal is let me show you this
command
Okay so there is command find replace
regular
expression
um yeah you know you can you can do a
demo it's uh let's
say uh let's open a new
file uh let's go to Alice in
Wonderland down the rabbit
hole Alice was beginning to get very
tired copy it close it paste it here so
we got
this this paragraph
Okay so save it save it XX some
text okay so let's
say I want to replace the word the
phrase right White Rabbit by black
rabbit okay for all files in this
directory okay this is my like temp file
directory okay let's delete those backup
files okay so let's actually delete all
those okay so these are 10 files uh this
one is today's uh this one is our code
close it and uh you know open this one
this is the Alice in Wonderland okay so
we want to all files in this directory
white rabit replaced by black rabbit
okay so so call the
command find regular expression y rabbit
enter replace string
uh black rabbit enter this directory yes
regular expression txt yes write changes
to file yes okay it's done so you can
jump around you can see there's only one
file and uh one two three three
occurrences one two three okay so go to
any one of them press enter to jump to
it so you can see now it's black rabbit
highlighted all black word so now you
can see okay so that command now repeat
complex command let's do it okay copy it
cancel um and go back to uh this file
open it go to the
button make a separator paste it so this
is the command we just called so find
replace replace text regular expression
so you got lots of arguments then you
got
um then you got a sequence of ordered
arguments those are not keyword
arguments so you got but this gets
complex so anyway these are so you can
see these are each one of these are
actually just
ordered arguments but I mean this so fix
search and fixed replace fixed case
search fixed case replace show context
backup those are all buin true or false
but I pass the value of a symbol so when
you have a
symbol it's equivalent to true so this
arguments is actually just true true
true true true okay but I'm actually
passing a symbol so it's so I can tell
what they are instead of TT you
know so this is the problem we are
trying I'm trying to solve you see so
I'm trying to change this function you
know let's go to the source code you
know so there is a source code so you
can see it's just bunch of you know this
whole bunch of old the sequence of
arguments I'm trying to change them so
that they are keyword argument uments so
that is
why we are trying to uh I'm you know
exploring this keyword argument
thing and one of the concern I have is
that if I change this function to use
keyword arguments I want to be able to
call
the replace I mean repeat complex
command this this okay to get a this
syntax of the
call uh with the proper feel of all
these arguments will that work actually
I think it will okay but we just haven't
got to test that yet but the first thing
the issue right now we have is about the
kind of confusion of Neo versus empty
string okay
so so if you actually um let's say
default argument if you actually do that
what will happen Okay ne ne let's see
okay so the default will be just empty
string
okay
now backup evaluate the function now
meta X test your name enter enter enter
enter okay it still return that okay
it's still return that
so that means they are empty string so
that means okay this gets empty string
then over here it's a empty string so
therefore they return empty string okay
so that's why so we need to fix this
okay so if
if if if if it's empty
string yeah so this get you know you
need to
code a lot things uh so it should
be let me show you what should be so a
the value of a is actually let me just
change
it let me change it okay hold on second
okay actually this is better
so so we set them so you know this one
this is much Clear okay so AB
BC okay now it's easier to read so I
don't like I don't like putting the
values in the Le
check am I
good okay
so seven people so um or should I stop
it's already one hour I you guys find it
informative okay let's push on I want to
get you know I want to just know what
happens with the complex command okay if
you don't know um let me show you this
because this you useful to you guys emac
disp search for emac
disp do you find my
website [ __ ] them [ __ ] them no because
you know because I don't do um anyway
so emx okay there it is go there
emx tutorial you need to go to um
actually do a search then search for
complex
uh [ __ ] okay search for let's say
repeat then you'll find repeat last
command okay go
there uh okay then then you'll find a
tutorial about these two very useful
four commands one is just repeat it will
repeat the last command and the other
one is repeat last complex command
repeat complex command
which what this do is that it will
repeat the last command that involves a
prompt so whenever you call a command
for for example find replace it asks you
what what to find what find string
replace string which directory regular
expression to filter the files you know
do you want a backup one bunch of
questions so when you want to call that
command again you have to answer all
those
questions but if you call Rep repeat
complex
command that will call the last command
with whatever the answers to the
questions already
filled and we it will basically give you
a Lis expression like this so that is
why so this is very useful okay this is
useful also for turning a regular
expression into the Lis syntax you know
very
useful so that's why you know so you
guys might read about
this so why am I having a first with all
this because I want to be able to still
use this repeat comp comp Lex command
when if I use the optional arguments
okay okay so let's continue so this a
should be let's rewrite this
okay set a
if string
equal okay God this this gets complex if
that value
is
um if that value is empty
string
then
or okay if it's
empty or
NE okay then return uh let's make this
one line okay then just return zero
else okay so so this this is this is uh
else El repeat that this is this is not
good code
but but you know you get the idea so
this will fix the empty string so we
need to I mean this need to be Rewritten
actually uh but anyway so let's evaluate
it
now col command test enter enter enter
enter enter okay message go to
message there it is you can see there
is a become zero because now we actually
checked for empty
string okay so
um yeah so this gets cumbersome so you
need to do that for B and C but anyway
okay but we got it now let's call the
repeat last command okay do it fantastic
it works
beautiful okay so you can
see copy it
cancel and go here paste so it shows you
the
entire you know the least form of the
last command with all the arguments fied
fantastic
yep it works you see this is exactly
what we gave in the inter interactive
prompt so in summary this is good okay
so this in summary you can use this
um for keyword
parameters okay but the the code to get
the value is a bit cumbersome okay so
the next thing to try is to use the P
case as
suggested okay I think that's it thank
you guys for
watching go back color the syntax color
HTML showing browser so this is what we
have done today I hope you guys enjoyed
it by if you like my stuff just donate
to me okay I'm getting I'm getting you
know go to go to PayPal just go to
PayPal okay PayPal or Amazon
just go to PayPal or Amazon you know
send me
$100 if you work at Google or any
Corporation if you are you know a coder
PayPal or Amazon gift card thank you
guys fantastic ring Tingo fantastic
Winnie uh David say R stream input B Neo
to okay don't use Neo as the argument of
restream um that's true okay third
parameter is default for prompt fifth is
substitute for user Mt string oh
okay uh there's a question why do you
use Windows that's frequently asked
questions for the thousands times okay I
have 10,000 articles on my website and
10,000 YouTube talking about that why
why you know use window okay bye guys
bye guys
bye so this so this is like poers shell
okay Power shell I'm going to make a
screenshot
just you know like 10 years after
today then you'll find this interesting
because then you know oh on 2025
February 16th I did a talk show and
there is this um let's see if I can do
it you know put it here showing browser
there's a record oh power shell back
then there's a thing called poers shell
and looks like that
oh this is what happens when you get old
and you have a history so this is what
at the meaning of History
a record okay so that's what I'm doing
okay
bye shut down shut down which button
which button