hello guys welcome to another episode of
soundtalk show
today is 2000 2000 2021
and today is july july 27th
so july is about to end so voice check
check yes video check we are good to go
so july 27th 2021 in san francisco time
2 o'clock in the afternoon and today we
are going to
do lots of random things you are going
to watch my workflow
uh what i do so uh close that twitter
and so today we are going to code emac
bisp
we are going to code some website uh my
unicode unicode stuff
unicode religious and cultural symbols
unicode
emac based coding and wolfram language
and mathematics i'm gonna do some
mathematics so i'm gonna
show yeah possibly actually we are going
to code one of the
fantastic wolfram language um
graphics uh so uufam language coding
okay
uh mathematics fantastic beautiful
the world of mathematics the depth of
humanity
okay so uh so that's the that's what we
are going to do
and uh let's so let's let me explain
yeah we i think we are we're gonna code
this this is in second life
you know second life is a virtual world
it's just like a game
you know if you haven't seen it uh it's
just like a 3d game but you're going
and you build everything yourself like
like the player builds everything in a
second life
world it's a massive world i lived there
i lived in second life
for like five hours a day for like uh
for like seven years every day uh so you
i build this in
in second life you generate you know you
you write a linden scripting language
which is very interesting which you know
a programming language but different
from
all because this programming language is
inside the second live virtual world you
know
like you know if you don't know second
life you know
you might think of it as a minecraft
okay i think it's similar it's kind of
similar but i've never been to minecraft
but second life you don't have these
idiotic cubes
that's what minecraft is the most
idiotic
uh game in in the world in the last
century
the most idiotic game minecraft because
technology
advances we have better and better
computer graphics
but then this idiot created a minecraft
a 3d game
where everything is made of cubes the
[ __ ] idiots
and also the lego the lego you know the
that i think lego thing is the most
idiotic and
it so happens that the hackers love it
you know all the tech geekers like they
build a
giant lego of a real piano using lego
something using lego most idiotic thing
lego in elegant ugly crap
that's lego and also minecraft okay so
in second life it's
it's kind of like a minecraft but you
you got a real
uh kind of real you know more realistic
okay
so you use linden scripting language in
fact i have a tutorial
uh and i also have so you are looking at
the second life all the diff
all these characters these are you know
the avatars
you can go in and you can build or you
can buy or some of them
are free uh they are advertising and
they are
the the critical thing is that each and
every everything you see in second life
is spilled by
the players it's not like uh other 3d
games where you you know like
quake or whatever you know the vast
majority or
basically all of them 3d games you go in
you you have a world it's already built
you know but in second life
every building every character you see
every hair every every
every texture everything okay
now on this page i'm focusing on avatars
so all these avatars i
are created by players okay the players
they don't you know they are not
computer programmers you know they they
are usually often
oftentimes they are artistic persons
okay so you build all kind of creatures
okay
not not not just avatars but
architectures like like i said
everything you see
in second life like all these all these
all these all these everything at the
way
they moves the way they look the and the
way that you can also have cars and
trains and airplanes and
uh fights uh you know airplanes
so these people they they are into you
know they mimic
they actually build fairly accurate
versions of
world war ii planes okay in second life
yeah there are such people amazing
people wild you know just like
real life you know what incredible
impossible
all kind of people they build
uh planes that that you know
that that that um they build models of
the world war ii era planes and there's
also models of the
uh jet fighters too as well so pam
you know pan pam am is famous company it
uh
it's a big thing it's economics you know
it died out
but back then 10 a.m is everywhere it's
the biggest corporation you know
conglomerate rate uh and it
dies out and also you see and look at
this one okay there are people
who build every model of nasa and other
countries rocket
okay two uh uh measurable to uh scaled
to
to to to reality okay every model of
nasa's
uh space shuttle and rockets and also
russians and
other and and also china imagine that
and also it's you know you might think
oh it's easy it's not
easy you know it's second life build
system you know it's like a 3d system
like
uh something you know you guys would
know about um
uh do we have people no people i'm
talking to myself
okay so wait let me double check if
my i'm uh live and talking
yeah okay so in second life the build
system is crap you know you
you you might be familiar with uh you
know blender
or but in second life the build system
is
a crap also by the way i also have a
tutorial on that okay
so yeah you can see so let me okay let
me talk about
uh random about second life okay so
these are some of the mathematical stuff
people you know a mathematician henry
sagerman
build in second life so you got the dome
geodesic you know this is actually uh
uh how you call
how do you call this in from the math
perspective you know from a normal
person's perspective you call this
geodesic or geodesic dome which is an
idiotic name in created by this
by this fuller minister uh
snake oil sailor you know there's a
famous guy booker fuller minister
something
that's his name bucky you know he
created the buckyball
you know he he created lots of things
and one of the things he's pushing his
geodesic domes
okay why why is he pushing that because
he
you know he he thinks you know he's kind
of this got a vision for the future and
so on
and uh do i have a link to it uh
seashell photo gary i i have i have a
lot of photos of dooms okay
but actually let me show you so let me
talk random sorry
archie texture okay
so you can see functional programming
architecture
no not no we're not talking about
programming language okay so
um geo let's say search for
geodc okay
okay so i have like you know i collect
some photos of geodesic domes and
montreal biosphere i've been actually
two there i lived there
from 1986 to 1989
montreal in canada you know
so these are called the normal
normal terminologies geodesic domes but
that's actually the most idiotic
thing it's not you know geodesic in
mathematics
means the shortest distance on a surface
of a curve
on a manifold okay anyway
it's not appropriate to call these
geodesic
domes okay the more appropriate name
would be um regular polyhedron
you know yeah it would be
more proper to call them as polyhedron
domes okay because they are essentially
almost all of them are essentially uh
regular
based on a regular polyhedron platonic
solids then you project them
onto a sphere you triangulate them and
you form these
domes okay so we talked about geodesic
domes
so let's copy let's go to talk show we
we are starting to talk about
lots of things okay hoo hoo hoo
hoo i see money go test
thank you good afternoon you have
triggered my inner zoomer by dc legos in
minecraft
other than that i look forward to
today's show so yeah so
you know i was random talking about
geodesic domes okay
becca full fullest meanness you know let
me write down some some of the
some of the uh things we are talking
about
booker fuller minister you know guy you
know that guy
do you recognize the name i spelled the
name wrong you know but his name is
something like that
and uh bookkeeper okay so we can
find the name buckyball he's a
in my opinion he's a crackpot okay
so buckyboss i want to go to wikipedia
yeah so bucky ball this ambient
disambiguation okay bucky boy you know
buck means to full ring
this [ __ ] crackpot
let me go to the guy's name you know
he's featured in one
of apple's think different commercial
you know the
uh 15 years ago 20 years ago all
famous think different which is
grammatically incorrect
okay so bucky this this molecule
structure
okay means fuller ring is a type of
fuller ring with a formula c60
it has a cage like it's okay so it's a
type of fuller ring what the [ __ ] is a
fuller ring full of fluorine is a
allotrope of carbon whose molecule
consists of carbon atoms okay blah blah
blah
okay but but okay here's the guy here is
the guy this
this is a major crackpot okay
you know it's um
that may be too harsh okay he's not
exactly
a you know a crack pot in a sense of
cheating people's money but he's one of
those
uh you know you might say crazy guys but
not in a good way i don't i don't like
this guy okay
and he also invented you know he you
know these
crackpots or cult leaders usually they
are found of creating jargons
like the pearl larry war the creator
programming language they are found of
jargons and also
similar to the unix people unix
philosophy
you know lots of things they are found
of jargon's code
and emacs too meta key and so on
scratch buffer meta key and okay so
so this guy richard buckminster fuller
in my opinion he's a kind of crack
potish guy but he's not a
you know he's not a um how do you say a
criminal or
he's not a uh you know someone who just
uh
there to get your money but anyway back
to my point they
this crackpot guys usually are fond of
jargons they
invent jargons they create a lot of
dragons for for example he created
you know look at this look at this
in his writings publishing more than 30
books and coining
coining or popular rise in such terms as
spaceship earth that you know that's a
disney thing that's
that's a disney dome okay spaceship
earth
the maxi dymaxion okay what the [ __ ] is
the [ __ ] that dymaxion dimaxin is a term
coined by architect
and inventor buck minister fuller and
associated with much of his work
permanently his dimaxion house time
anxious
you know what whatever
you know so is you know it's basically
essentially they
okay so it stands for a portmanteau of
dynamic maximum intention this he's into
this
crap that's not mathematics okay if you
don't know you might think oh he's a
mathematician no
he's not the mathematician so he emitted
dymaxion
dymaxium map euphemia realization
eu familiarization is that what i think
is
that is oh god
you okay you know in english we have the
youth you for me you know you for me is
a kind of just a
gentle nice sounding word in to replace
some harsh
award you know like [ __ ] you know the
euphemism for [ __ ]
kind of love well that's not a good
example but you know you know what i
mean
but but this book means a fool okay so
he so in english
there's these euphemisms right and he
created a term
and he take it to mean that is the
ability of technological advancement
to do more and more with less and less
until eventually you can do everything
with nothing
this is you see this is a great example
of this
crackpot you know this this
you know you know crackpot usually have
this concept you know so
so he's saying essentially the
euphemisation
is that something you can do more and
more with less and less
until eventually you can do not
everything with nothing
it's scum okay so so
he you know he and synergetics okay he
also invented the word synergetics
and tense tense 10 seconds 10th
grade kotti okay these are also crackpot
you know they are they are say my math
okay they are kind of like math they
kind of not
you know these you know uh let me show
you okay so
go read we keep wikipedia article okay
synergetics
okay and 10 seconds okay the [ __ ]
idiot [ __ ] the crackpot
you know uh this guy so i despise i
despise this guy
there are several similar guys to him
you know that you know
that's several in in uh historical so
he's uh one of the historical figures
because he uh he act you know he he
influenced the world okay
and you know for a period he he's also
served as the
second world president of mensah
international okay
mensah i was a member of mensah for like
three years
because you have to pay membership every
year and
you know i was a member so in the 1990s
and
mensah is another culty thing okay means
mensah people are
actually not that smart okay mensah is
like
ten percent of the top ten percent of
the population iq
you know and today the word the concept
of
iq and stuff is falling out of fashion
you cannot say it
but iq is the most it's a critical
important
thing in human animals of all aspects
you know you look at all aspects of
human animals in society
their structure and we i talked about
this in
in in recent videos the
the iq of how smart you are is
constitute a
one of the most important you know
aspect of
the shape and form and structure of us
of a human society okay
as iq but today the social justice scan
they are you know they don't want that
because you know because they are just
doing things to gain power
uh so they they don't want any truth you
know if it's true they don't want it
you know that's what the social justice
scan are doing
so anyway this before so we talked about
him and
the reason we mentioned him is because
we were talking about geodesic domes
okay that's a bad name the proper name
should you know geodesic dome is a term
he kind of pushed
the proper name is a uh regular
polyhedron
dome okay regular polyhedron dome that
would be a proper name
because all these are the the the
central theme
of all these storms is that it's based
on the idea of regularity
from you know a regular polyhedron
that's a central
theme that's why i say you know the
proper name would be uh
regular polyhedron domes okay
now there are lots of domes in
architecture you probably
know i've got of course they are you
know especially in church
you know the old architecture in in
in let me show you okay you know in
ch for example the islamic you know they
they also this is also a dome you know
this open dome
uh you know in church you have lots of
domes
uh okay this is grand beautiful western
you know western uh cathedral okay
uh and uh you know you have ox you know
architecture there's a lot of
terminologies but
do i have a good picture of a dome uh
i'm not sure but anyway so yeah
anyway let's get back to the um
so i was talking about geodesic domes
okay so why are we talking about
geodesic domes because
i was talking about the how
let's see where is the i was talking
about
second life okay second life and uh this
mathematician build this
uh not dom it's a
regular polyhedron dome okay not
geodesic [ __ ]
okay so mathematician segment okay you
probably
if you are into math you probably heard
of him he's on active on twitter and
recently
he has created a lots of actual
physical toys you know for example these
dice okay
uh uh very good okay
you know he created a dice of 120 faces
and he also created several you know
a weird you know you don't see them much
you know all these
for example these you've seen a lot but
he also created
for example some of these okay skill
dice
and slant dice okay skew dice and
standardize
you know you might think okay they don't
look regular you know
they are not regular cubes so they must
be biased
but actually not you see so
that's so that's that's why i say that
he's interesting you know many of things
from him
uh henry sagerman is very interesting if
you are
the math or geek or tech you know tech
head you know very interesting and also
of this this also called look at this
one
look at this one funny it's like an ice
cream cone
okay so so let's copy that let's go
let's
so i let's copy that so we have a record
kind of what we talked about
okay i have a lot of pages uh
from you know this guy okay so math
mechanics okay
so he also created this kind of
mechanism mechanism you know
this one is the most simple every you
know you must have seen it but he also
had created the other
so this this kind of thing are called
linkages okay
linkages you can look up wikipedia
there's a lot lots of
information and there's also this is
critically important
especially in the robotic age
you know today we have a lot of robotics
you know
dogs you know from the houston you know
boston dynamics you know the dogs or any
any robotics you know how do they run so
that is based on linkages okay so uh
so there's a there's a branch of math
that's deal with linkages now do i have
a
do i have a uh uh
wikipedia okay let's go to wikipedia
then there's a lot of math this
is a branch of math okay linkages
and i also have you know here linkages
mechanical so
the the most simple one is this one
everyone has seen
this one is called what's the name of
these caesar linkages okay so you have
seen that but there's more complicated
you know
so you have to study curves you know
you know like i talked about my playing
card visual dictionary
or plane curves you know all these are
linkages but do they have
complicated ones
oh yeah and you know the odometer you
know whatever the
speedometer and okay so wikipedia have
quite a few examples
you know linkages is quite amazing
if you like um if you like the
steampunk kind of thing linkages is
critical especially you know for example
the train
the giant iron trend of
100 years ago you know you have the
wheel
you know heavy so you you need the
linkage to
the steam in engine they
they make a piston of a rectilinear
motion
you need to turn a rectilinear motion
into a into a rotation you know that so
that's a train
um linkage okay so
this is critically important in robotics
okay
so let's copy that let's copy that let's
paste that so we have a record of what
we talked about
uh so we were talking about domes and we
were talking about
uh linkages okay so let's copy that that
that that
that that now now let's show the power
of
emax editing
okay so that's today's talk show topics
we talked about
and uh and why are we talking about
linkages because we were talking about
the mathematician
he actually henry sagerman he introduced
me to second life
okay 10 years ago
by now 13 years ago
uh okay so you know he's on twitter okay
so
well what i want to say okay so go back
go back
yeah so second life okay so we were
talking about second life
uh so copy that go back to here
uh paste that okay second life and you
can
and yeah airplane okay
you build thing you know there are
people
very diverse uh crazy people interest
very interesting
usually they are very poor you know one
thing i i learned when i lived in second
life for
seven years including myself i was like
poverty okay poverty below poverty and
there are also programmers you know
these are
kind of the people in second life it's
kind of sad to say they
are they are the dredges kind of they
they are the outskirts of society they
you know weird
weird and a lot of them are and also
many of them significant number of them
they
have they have problems in life okay
they have problems in real life
some of you know some of them are
disabled crippled you know
some of them are it um has cancer
okay i have i know a few who you know
who is my who was my friend who got
cancer
uh terminal illness uh and some of them
are very old old ladies there's a lot a
lot old eight ladies
you know 56 years old but in second life
they are pretty
young 16 slave girls
i kid you not you know because you can
actually not talk to them
know them and they they they go on voice
so i know a few and and
then a lot there's also this girl you
know
she is a i believe uh trans
you know he's a guy okay but anyway in
his second life like me
we dressed as a girl he
so event you know i kind of know so
amazing okay uh amazing because second
life is
you know it's a place where you throw
out
reality the problems in real life and
you know
if you are happy in real life if you
or if you are successful or if you are
busy
usually you got things to do you know
make more money or whatever
you be with your wife or girlfriend you
you know you you got you know you do
your work you know you are happy
but usually if you are unhappy then
then there it is second life it
becomes attraction uh attraction because
then you go in
nobody you know you looks like a dog
nobody know your
all your problems your ugliness you know
and uh
in second life you are beautiful you are
beautiful my friends
so that's you know because you know so
we you know there's no lack of charming
ladies in second life
okay because every girl in second life
is just
amazingly beautiful and the girls they
go shopping
day and night
they go shopping day and night uh
and all these artistic people so these
are kind of weird people
so what kind of group are they they are
you know
he i don't know how you call them today
but they they were like hippies in the
past or they
um you know they got talent but however
most of them they don't they cannot you
know they don't
you know they they are not working for
us you know they are not working
but they have tremendous talent that's
just amazing the
things they create so they just and
you know this so so they just live in
second life to
escape uh real life so everything you
see
is in remember everything you see in
second life is built by people including
these cybernetics okay
so this is an avatar in second life you
can buy
for like two dollars uh usd yeah two or
three maybe sometimes three
dollars usd many of them are free you
can buy
someone made it and then you put on you
know on your avatar then you actually
when you walk you actually you know the
the legs moves like
the way they are you expect them to
so i find this quite amazing you know as
a technology
you know because i'm into technology i'm
into you know cybernetics not
necessarily you know
but i mean those these are topics
interest me and you
so and i also interested in math or in
mechanics so i want to know how this
works and so on and also
then then people have spilled this
cybernetic feed okay this so when you
put that on
your your avatar actually do work like
that
okay so then also there are people who
build the star check you know the
atst machine and it does move like that
so it's amazing because this technology
second life you know
you actually i i don't know how it works
actually
um some of them i do know for example
this machine
i mean i mean by that i mean you how to
actually build it you you know first of
all you build
so have i show you the how to build
second life
you know like blenders thing you can for
example i have a tutorial this tutorial
is
by now 10 years old but i show you how
do you actually build in second life
so you know so unlike
a nike blender or whatever cad
uh systems software you use on your
windows
in second life you build you build
things
house or whatever building cars or
whatever while
you are in second life so second life is
truly kind of like a virtual reality so
you are
inside then you you
well you you interact with your screen
but but inside the world
other people can see just like you are
seeing these
other people can see you are actually
trying to build something
so it's kind of it's amazing okay so
so you can build okay so actually so you
build
um okay so i'm talking about second life
today
so you can build so all these are built
okay
it gets complicated so this you build
but the avatar
the avatars you don't build it like that
you know advertise a different thing
you usually you build you see using
uh 3d software outside of the second
knife then you
import it then you also have to
uh you know create the texture you know
for example in photoshop
and then map it to the avatar to
whatever shape you know so it's
it's very it's not if it's not easy okay
i just believe me i try to learn it
it's not easy in some of these i don't
know how to
i don't know how to build avatars okay
you know for example this thing
this thing scorpion this is actually an
avatar
okay so you go in second half you can
buy it you know three dollars
and you pronounce and you become a you
know this mechanical
uh scorpion quite amazing i was truly
amazing okay
uh yeah and and some of the i don't i
still don't know how they uh
work i mean how to how do you do it uh i
don't know
so but you know but i did learn i did
learn
certain to a certain degree i you know i
learned um for example i
i told you about i you know i i
actually i created a um
yeah okay so you know i i created
actually i sell something
so
how do you say search
taylor dasher okay so i i built a
particle machine
uh okay let me show let me talk let me
tell you about that i built a particle
machine okay
now what what is a particle machine now
uh okay so let me show you
so i built several things you know uh
one of them
also i wrote a linkedin scripting
second life okay so here is a second
life linden scripting language tutorial
so i teach you actually
the linden scripting language a
programming language
to have to allows you to have all sorts
of interactions in second life for
example here you are looking at the
source code
one of the most basic source code
what does this do this do is that when
you
touch it you know instead in second life
when you bump you you run into it
okay so you create this script then you
put this script inside a
object like a box or a pole or or
whatever a physical thing
a physical thing in second life and
whenever people bump into it
you'll say you're like print hello
you know that's what this script do so
it's a linden scripting language it's a
programming language you learn
i you know i actually learned this and i
also wrote
a emac uh emacs mod for it
okay so i can efficiently i can
write a linden scripting language code
in emacs
fantastic okay so actually so let's copy
what we talked about
and uh emacs lssl mod okay
paste it here okay so
so second scripting language so
so you um then i build let me let me
tell you what i
so this is my kind of productions this
is the things i sell okay
so this is this this script
you buy it for linden dollars 500 which
is like
two dollars or something one dollars or
two you buy it you put on your body
then you can pass through walls
and and other things are made okay
and the most complex project i'm
actually proud of is this
very complex casa particle maker okay
so this is a machine you buy for 30
usd okay you you you know
linden scripting dollars but equivalent
to 30 usd dollars you buy it
do we have a comment so
i don't agree with some things you said
but i'm glad you exist
uh we need more people like you who
aren't afraid to have this
uh dissenting opinions okay i forgot
what that was about
but uh exwm
okay i don't like ex-wm so anyway so
this machine
you buy it for 30 usd then you can raise
it in second life so
this is what you see in second life
let's see do i have a picture of myself
with it yeah
so you see this is my avatar purple cat
it's a free avatar so you know
so you raise it then you stand you know
you just stand beside it you know this
it's amazing this this is 3d okay so you
raise this machine
then you can click around you can click
around
and it will generate particles so what
is the particle particle is
particle is a technology it's a
technique
in 3d game in 3d computer graphics
techniques in computer graphics to
create things like water
fire smoke
fireworks beacon or laser light
or hair uh you know smoke
you know those are not polygons you see
those are not made of polygons those are
particles you know those are
you know so water fire uh
or mist or smoke you know so you have to
[Music]
emulate them so the way you do that is
basically essentially
effectively is by having thousands of
little images and these little images
go about on your screen so you have the
actual so
when you see smoke you know smoke ring
or smoke from a chimney
in a game no you know now look at your
game okay whatever game you play
next time you see some smoke or some um
let's see some smoke or some fire
in your game that's particles okay
that's particles
and how how is it done basically it's a
bunch of little images flat
you know parallel to your screen and
they are they move about in certain way
and then
then they disappear and they new ones
appear so this is the technology
particle is a technology technology to
emulate this kind of
uh smoke spring
mist and kind of thing in fireworks or
gun you know gunshot you know
uh you know gun blast you know machine
gun you know there's a you know those
kind of thing
so and what does this machine call
particle maker so this
machine is actually a physical machine
you know a virtual physical machine you
you raise in second life then you can
create the particle effect you want
let's say you want to you know i don't
you know
some you know whatever you are creating
you know a gun of a tank
suppose you want to emulate the smoke of
a
tank's main gun after it fires
i don't know how it looks like but
suppose you want that so you need
particles
but you don't know how to write the code
you know the particle code is fairly
complex i also have a tutorial
somewhere here okay so then you can
buy my machine thirty dollars then you
just click
each you know click color whatever color
you want you know
click the shape you know how they move
you know then
then the particle will show here okay
you know
in real time like when you like this is
like uh
like a station you stand there and you
click about and you
this is a control center okay you stand
there
then the particle will show in real time
when you see that that's the one you
want okay this
is you know uh raining or whatever smoke
this is the exact
effect you want then you just you just
click
press the button on the you know i
explained so this here is the
documentation
this this page is actually a
documentation for this machine so people
buy it can read it
so when you when you see the effect you
want you click
on uh you click on
you click on this button you you stamp
on this
button on the ground okay create script
then
then you will generate the code for you
then you can
just take it you see this
i so i i wrote this about two months
okay
after a lot of learning and stuff you
know i wrote this in two months so you
can so this machine this
is actually a code generator a virtual
physical machine that generates code and
with interactive user interface in three
dimension
uh so i so i'm quite proud of this and
at the
height of the time i was saying like i
was making of
200 a week something like that
okay so that's the particle machine okay
so um
we don't have any people watching five
people no comments okay
okay so now i think we go back
to talk to uh we're gonna talk whatever
we were going
to talk okay so
so this page uh requirements for a
visualization system so what are we
going to talk about
okay i don't know first of all let me
clean up the file
any comments comments
so we talked about a lot of things
mostly about second life
okay so we talked about geodesic domes
math in second life airplanes in second
life
exotic architectures mythological
creatures avatars
in second life and
bill build you know stuff in second life
and uh
ninten scripting language the
programming language in second life
emac second life linden scripting
language mod
and particle maker so we talked about
that we also talked about
a buck minster fuller a kind of a
crackpot guy
and henry henry sedgeman a mathematician
who creates a lot of physical puzzles
and
interesting things
uh why did i stop playing second life
well because i was getting
i was getting really hungry no food no
money
so that's yeah really bad
so that was this this is a time around
2011.
um yeah you know
sad sad time
uh so i stopped
um you know i cannot go on a bit
essentially at that time it's pretty bad
anyway
um so so and they
so let's do unicode okay so there's this
thing i want to do
unicode okay now a change of topic so
let me sip my drink
so so that's that about second life
unless if you have any questions ask me
okay
uh so now we are going to do something
else so let me have a drink
and i talked how long have i been
talking
so i already talked for like
40 minutes okay so i have a drink and
let's do something else
okay unicode so this is this is my
website this is something i want to do
so i have a website a unicode as you
know just search for unicode
arrows you can find it so i have a
script
let's say if i type water wat
and so there is this search box
written in javascript that allows you to
search
dynamically as you type or unicode names
so if i type w.a.t then you see all
these characters of unicode
all these are unicode that contains the
word w-a-t
in their name okay so you get very fun
and then if you want to detail for
example what is this wc
that's water closet that's a united
kingdom's term for bathroom
water classic closet do this do they
still call it that
you know kind of old-fashioned term okay
so then what is this
uh you know this emoji is not apparent
apparent in what it you know look what
it means
so you look at here so it's water polo
okay so this emoji we might say it's not
well designed
when emoji when you look at that and you
don't know what that what the [ __ ] that
is then that means the emoji is not well
designed
so this one is not well designed so
let's see
let's type some random okay h e x
hex okay you got all these hexagonal
things
hexagrams okay uh has a lot to do with
math history and linguistics okay
depending
on where you want to go binary number
system hexagrams
in fact because
talked about it okay uh let's say
h-e-a let's see what we got sometimes
you got lots of
interesting unexpected things okay
h-a-h-e-a
let's say a-e what do you got so a
e is not interesting let's say t-e
okay t
t a h
okay h a
f i i'm trying to find something
interesting
okay if i okay you got lots of chinese
characters
fi r okay then you got
fire and uh fire related things
uh you know let's sometimes you find
interesting things let's
let's try m i n
okay so you have these
uh by the way these are interesting okay
these characters
if you have not seen them kukuni form
okay
very interesting you can go down here
and you can see it
where is it cuny form okay so special
languages languages arabic
korean ethiopic ethiopian
devanagari indian bengali tamiya
tibetan tomato is also interesting
uniform okay there
you know this is this is a language
from the aliens spaceship language
let's see let's see their full glory
magnify magnify okay
cuny form uh now so what i want to do on
this page
what i want to do is that you see you go
down
you see you go down you see uh
that star wait it shows up as a star
on android it does not show up as a star
so what's going on so yeah
okay let's change that you know so
what's going on so let me tell you
what's going on so
i want my page to be pretty right i've
created this website so i want it to be
you know good icons for the ui
so but the uh the one of the complexity
is that when you have unicode on on the
mac
on linux on windows on android or on
iphone
they show different t you know because
on the on here you see i see a star
right
oh it's great that's what i want but on
android
it does not show as a style it shows as
a you know
the it shows up as this character
you know black boring black character so
that's a problem you see each
so you have to think about that for each
and every of the emoji you use
so so i'm on windows so it looks fine
but i just checked on
on you know on the android it doesn't
show up as a star
so why because the the character
i'm currently using is this one okay but
however i believe
on android this character does not show
up as an emoji it just shows up like
that
uh and meanwhile i think this character
might show up as like
is that big so this is a problem of
unicode and
because especially in the past 10 years
emoji is a mistake in unicode it's a
[ __ ] up and
also it became very political
okay i'm not going to talk about that
it became very political and many of the
emoji let me cover a few okay many of
the emojis meaning
changed because certain group of people
you know the
certain group of people they think if
you have a
emoji of a gun that that will create
more violence
okay it's idiotic okay that's idiotic to
the extreme
you know and so so they created emoji
let me show you where okay so let's just
search for gun okay
g-o-n okay so it's not it's a pistol
okay p-i-s-t
okay so you see here is a
pis okay so here is the unicode
the unicode's name is pistol so pistol
is a
gun okay but apple apple began
apple decided oh we don't want to show
an
actual pistol because that creates
violence
okay so apple make it into a
water gun water pistol scumbag apple
so so why
so so what so what is going on and why
am i angry i mean what's
what's a big deal it's you know it's
pretty it's what again is fun
what's the big deal the big deal is that
you are eradicating truth
okay that is the most fundamental
eternal most
important element in human society
you don't want to erase truth okay
more or less okay now you might say okay
yeah but this has nothing to do with
truth this is just the actual
funny picture not really not really you
see
now if you paid attention to pilot
politics in the past let's say five
years
in united states then you know what i'm
talking about
one thing leads to another okay okay i'm
getting into politics but anyway let me
get back
okay so so this so
not just these okay so emoji okay so
this shouldn't be done okay this this
shouldn't be
done like that okay you know who does
that
who which country
forces like force by force
these ideas to you there is such a con
country nazi germany
you know they they ban certain artwork
they bang it you know they they do not
allow it because
they have reasons they saw that good
reasons you know
and we are seeing such an example and
not just this okay this this is just one
of the examples
this quite a lot and i don't want to get
into because
google is going to censor my youtube you
know it's
that's a reality google is uh we are
already into
in in this era
okay so no comments okay so let's uh so
what i want to do with my unicode page
uh let's see
we talked about random on unicode so
let's look at my notes
see today's to-do okay uh
fix the start on the panel unicode stars
um so
let's skip that for today okay so this
is not too much
let's talk about something more
interesting
write a emacs command to sync my
packages from
saw emacs to each of the individual
packages okay let's do that some e-max
stuff
okay so
so as you know let's see
okay so in the past week or two
i created a xr emacs mod okay so
you you know so i created on github you
can see
emacs distro so this is uh you know i i
did this live
online and now it's up is
you know it's in some way usable so you
can go and download
it but now i have a problem so you are
looking at you know you are looking at
this xsa emacs configuration okay so
you clone the git then this is what you
got let's
remove the backup file so you clone the
git
and here is the files you get so
you have a readme you have init file you
have settings okay
then you have packages so you open
packages
let's delete the backup okay you open
the packages then you basically
have several of my packages
now there's a problem you see so these
packages are the actual files
uh inside you know it comes bundled with
sar emacs
but but for example let's say
html mod let's say this file okay
there is a actual git repo
of xa html mod that's not here this
here what happens here is just a copy
okay so let's go to
html repo
so get html so i have it as a bookmark
so you can so you go diet so let me show
you okay so let's hide
the let's hide the details so you can
see
in this directory is the actual
git ripple for html mode
okay so you can see uh this uh so
here is a file here's a file
and over so the problem is that
the problem is that the file you see
you see these two files they are
duplicate
duplicated in two places
and whenever i added one of them
know the normal way the way it's
supposed to
you i supposed to edit them is that i
should edit the one
in the proper repo you know i edit
it i make a commit then i copy
this file over to xr emacs okay
you know because emacs uses lots of
packages
so in the emacs i'll just say okay
updated html to version something
and meanwhile for the html file
whenever i make something i actually say
you know what
what changed you know maybe i added a
new function
i fixed some bug or things like that
so anyway the part the issue is they are
duplicated
so but whenever i edit you know
usually i jump to you know whenever i
start to edit
let's say one of these let's say html
mod
usually i directed it directly edit the
version on xr emacs packages why because
when i press the key it just
automatically go here because this is
this is actually the file i'm using i'm
running so i can make a change
evaluate the code i can see it works or
not
so it's very convenient to work to work
with the version of the package
that's actually running but there's a
problem
if i do that then you know i
updated the one in the packages then
then they they become out of sync
and the but
what i actually need to do is to modify
the one in the repo so that's a problem
so
so so oftentimes what will happen
is that you have one version of file
of these packages in the wrapper one
another version in the
emacs packages so after a while you
don't know which one is the latest
maybe you made some change here maybe
you made some changes there then you
have to do div diff is one of the most
time consuming thing you know you diff
is
really painful so i want a solution for
that so
i'm thinking what i'm gonna do is that
whenever i made a change here
i i'm going to write a command to
automatically copy whatever the file
here to the
repo okay so let's do that okay
let's just do that for html mod okay
yeah let's start to write a command okay
close that close that close that close
that
back to talk show let's write a command
so you are looking at my workflow now
emac this so so start to write a command
defend
okay and magnify and show
the ping window and what i want to do so
sync
emacs packages okay
let me just say that sync emac package
okay
version
sync current package file
to the proper git repo basically just
copy it over
okay so so so what do i do
so okay let's open a new
window
let's see where is the
okay so here is the directory so
html copy the file path
so condition
so we have a condition
equal that
current directory so current file
current file
um how do you get buffer file name
buffer file name
so if the current file i'm working on
is of is
is of this path okay
yeah so
but for file name so let's try that yeah
full file
full path okay so the current if if it's
equal to that
then
so that's the condition that's the first
condition
then then basically copy
copy to the proper git ripple of the xy
html
okay so what is that
uh where is that
so here is the so basically copy it to
here
okay so
okay so we want to copy file
file copy okay
so emax copy file copy file
copy the buffer file name
to the new name
okay optional okay if
already exist uh
no we want to ask so
neo keep time preserved okay
okay so we don't care about these
options
okay so you can see what's going on
pretty find the code so now it's
clear so if the current buffer file name
is that then copy over otherwise
then we have other conditions the other
condition will be
let me show you go to
yeah so the other
you know the other file we need to check
is all these other packages
but you know so we need to write more
code but for now
let's just simplify i mean let's just
give a draft example to
kind of show you what i'm doing so you
can hopefully you are learning some emac
lists
for those of you are watching this for
that
so so condition if it's html then copy
it otherwise do nothing okay okay
otherwise true do nothing so let's just
say that for now okay
evaluate then copy the file
okay delete this file go back to talk
show paste it here
prettify it show in browser
so here we have code casasync emax
package
so let's try it okay let's say
let's try to call it so i'm going to
call it meta xr sync emacs package
do it nothing happens i think
okay i need to change
nothing happens okay
evaluate it to call it again
do it and it prints nothing happens good
now but however if i'm in the html file
okay so let's go to
packages okay let's go to packages
you see um open that
so right now i'm in the site html mod
file
under the packages directory okay
and so this version i just updated this
let's say let's let's update that let's
give it a new number okay
let's say 18 okay 13.18
something okay and now
let's go to the git version of the html
the proper wrapper so you see this is 13
and over here is 13 18 okay
so if i'm i'm on this file i'm gonna
call that command
that command should copy over this file
so let's try it start sync emacs package
do it oh it says nothing happened
what the
okay something wrong let's see
okay i don't know what why is that so
let's
evaluate let's evaluate neo
so what is the buffer file name
why is it neo
so i'm going to you know when i evaluate
this it returns neo
so let me try to see what's the output
of the file name so let's put it here
control u then eval last
six okay then i'm gonna compare
this these are the same thing why is it
so why does it even
so
so why is it so let's try again
eval it says neo what
oh okay so we don't we don't want to use
equal we want to use
because because equal
two strings are never equal okay in e
max when you use eq
so let's try okay emac this so let's say
x okay let's try this
so we are evaluating two strings x and x
evaluate neo you see even they are the
same so
instead what you want to use is either
string equal
um okay so
either you want to use string equal or
you must use um
just equal so for example if let me
let me show you so if we try that
t true you see now if we try that that's
also
t so let's change the code to the string
equal here yeah
okay so we don't need this anymore so
okay now we evaluate this code evaluate
it
and close that okay now we are going to
call it again casa sync emacs package it
should
watch this here it should be 13.18 okay
after i call this command do it
oh then it says fire already exist
okay yeah so i need to overwrite them
okay so so okay back to modify the code
uh copy file uh file already exists
true okay so
uh copy file you know the
okay if already already exist yeah
right over overwrite them okay evaluate
the code
back to the here code again
do it
and what file already exists what
i thought we just told it to
let's see copy file file name
optional okay you've already exist right
we just set true here oh oh
oh wait
oh okay we put it in inside the wrong
bracket
now evaluate it okay
go back to the html
okay now call it do it
do it fantastic you can see
you see it's updated there okay
that's that's something for me this is
great for me you know so this helps me
to keep these
two duplicate files in sync
kind of so i can you know so after a
while
when there's a lot of changes i can
update the
original git repo
so imagine you're talking okay so five
people watching now
okay so so i talked for
70 minutes already so let's let's
continue okay so this you are just
watching me
work okay so i need to so this one is
done
so actually i need to
do others okay so let's let me copy okay
so you can see now i need to go to the
packages fold
what is this adaptive sampling
uh where's the packages okay
[Music]
what confusing okay
now back to my emacs code so okay so
the other file is that
okay
ah wait okay so wait
okay you actually need a lot more
you know at this point we can we can
make the code more elegant because now
it's just
lots of repetitions
entry you need more
okay so clean up the code clean it
okay this is probably unreadable so
let's
up the code okay so like that
and
then we need to clean the second we need
to modify the second part
okay so let's work on like that so now i
need to go to
git
so css mod where is the home page for
css
okay css mod there
there okay then start diet
that's the package home page start diet
okay then e might be smart
okay
then find okay
then supply keys okay
then subject things
then exile insert random id
you know it's unfortunate that each one
of these
their directory name is kind of
inconsistent style the naming of the
directory names
you see for each one of my packages
you know some of them actually the
directory name
ends in el why did i do that because
back then 10 years ago
well you know everyone is having a good
wrap up when git
you know when github just create just
invented
you know everyone is hopping into the
git hub
trend and back then at that time
javascript is most popular
so the question is if i have a emacs
package
let's say let's say this name because i
insert random id
what should the github's directory name
be
so you know back then you know
javascript also at the time is very uh
popular so
the javascript convention is that when
you have a project usually you name it
in dot js so for example
dot js you know that's a project name
not dot js
so the js indicated it's a javascript
project
so i thought oh so maybe so in emacs we
can do the same so
insert random id then dot e-l
e-l just means e-mag this so it's an
e-mail this project so that's why
i have a directory i have you know for
some of this project
their directory name also ends in eel
but i think it's a mistake
it depends depends on what how you think
okay you know for example the
typical tech geekers today
the emacs code you know typically when
they look at my code they'll say oh
is this weird idiot you know he doesn't
know how to name his
he the direct directories those people
are unthinking idiots
the common uh the common people you know
and they they like to tell you what to
do
okay so some random insert mod so i got
that
then saw javascript mod so let's open
copy that javascript mod okay then sign
lookup
okay then here is a you know another
different
name copy that because i look up been
math input you know i actually i can
probably
do a yeah i can work this in a better
way by first of all listing or
emac these files yeah why not
why don't you yeah let's do that why
don't i show you
a fun way to do this so
so you're gonna do the
the recursive okay so actually we're
gonna use powershell okay
so get your item recursive include
uh anything dot e l then
then just say name okay so copy that
shrink
go to git
then paste it actually i don't want to
run that because then you
run uh
let's say exa dot yeah okay so yeah here
they'll be better okay so if i run it
it'll show me all dot er files in my
repo
that includes saw something there it is
uh but actually i want the full name i
don't want the
i don't i want the full path
so i've been talking for 80 minutes
oh wow so what's going on wow
oh those are directories actually okay
fantastic fantastic okay let's copy it
yeah [ __ ] stupid let's copy it
put it here remove the empty lines let's
see what
you got oh then there's a backslash i
need to change backslash to slash
that's a pin oh but i have written a
command
let's look look look at my command okay
so i'm gonna call the command okay
slash slash to backslash
stash to double backslash i want
backslash to slash
okay i don't have it
what
sash to double backslash double
backslash to slash
[ __ ] i have so many versions you know i
you know
you didn't see it but um if i do it
now
you see i have three versions but i'm
missing the version i want i want the
single backslash to slash
idiot okay so let's just do it manually
then
what search string that
wait search stream backslash stash
two slash
backslash backslash backslash backslash
slash what
query replace one backslash
by slash okay just one
replace them all okay i don't know why
is it
okay so
okay so anyway let's go back to modify
the code some math input
yeah okay the problem with powershell is
that doesn't it doesn't print the full
path
yeah and i don't i haven't figured out
how it does that yeah stupid
okay let's go back to git then
so math input
there then find replace
pairs
there then it is utility
right yeah this name i need to change
the name of that
then look up
wait didn't we do this before
yeah we did this before
what's going on what
okay yeah we did that before okay
so here is a code
pretty fine let's see if that
we got a comment
okay i don't i don't really like these
all these
extra lines
why is it not aligned here
okay let's
now let's call query replace rejects to
replace the extra lines
space space
first replace by wait
space space space plus replace by
space do it here here
wait
space space space
plus quote double quote
space double quote
yeah do it okay
so now it looks better
um that was so clean that
okay so that's um
that's that delete that delete that
g that did that go back to
um
go back to talk show
what is this file delete that close
don't save
close that's
typescript
typescript in javascript
go to talk show there
paste it show in browser i mean purify
showing browser there we have it today's
code for that for that thing for um
for this emac this issue
uh wait a minute
okay so let's put the code at the bottom
okay maybe that's it for today neocado
hey neocondo powershell doesn't have
anything of a read link
real path kind of thing
yes of course i mean it does
but i mean the the issue i have now is
that
you see i'm in this direct let me
magnify okay so you can see
you see i'm in this user git directory
and i want to list you know all
directories that has the name xot
as you know something something el.el
okay now if i don't type the name
you know then it's gonna show kind of
funky output with the directory
structure and all
you see it prints like that you know
each one is you know it's not like the
unix it actually prints
kind of like user readable you know
it prints the directory then it prints
the file
with this table format okay
so that's not what we want so what i
want is you know then you pass the
parameter name then it will just give
you
a bunch of names including directory
names
it takes a long time to search
but however you see when it prints a
name it doesn't print the full path
it only prints the path
you know from connected from your your
current path so you have to basically
you have to add the
current path it's not the full path it's
it prints the relative path
to the current path okay
so
so you have to you know so i i think
there's an easy way to get
to print full path so basically you have
to first of all
let's say file only okay
file okay so this way it only print
files not directory
okay and and let's do it
i have lots of crap so it does so it
takes a while to
i have lots of crap in my git directory
i think
so now you see it only prints
files okay and now let's use
the name option okay name option so
it doesn't print this uh table format it
just prints the names
but still they are relative paths
why is it taking a long time this
shouldn't this is uh
you know git directories uh on a flash
drive
okay so it's done you see now
now it didn't print those directory uh
names okay so now you have relative path
so if you actually want the full path
you have to
type it to and you have to remove the
name
then you have to pipe to something full
path something like that
okay i don't know get path
okay get path
okay there's no such
i don't know that you know it's
different from unix
shell so i'm pretty sure it's trivial
you just
maybe i i'm pretty i think i don't think
it's an option it's just you just pipe
it to something
but i'm new to powershell so i don't
know it's
the the main thing is that it's
different from unix
so it's not like oh it cannot do it or
you know
something oh it's painful it's just
different from unix
in the same way that if you are used to
powershell
then you start to use unix then you have
a lot of problems
the unix so in general in my opinion
powershell is far more superior than the
unix
bash or tc far more superior
the name so it is here the name so let's
there is no such thing as the name pwd
okay so let's actually
so let me so maybe i can find the
solution
so there is pwd which prints the current
path
okay so what do you want to
i think actually i know i i can do it
okay
join path so you have you just say join
uh
join string okay join stream pwd
then maybe that okay
why is it taking so long this is taking
too long
it prints nothing
oh okay so pwd is um
anyway i'm now going to do this
uh what's the next thing i want to do oh
well the next thing is that i want to
talk about
wufam language mathematica but
we already talked for 90 minutes
so i think i'm going to stop here today
uh yeah so you know i wanted to talk
about mathematics
language uh because yesterday and the
day before we did a lot
wolfram language and uh you know
it's been 20 years since i've been
coding every day
and it's truly spectacular it was
20 years ago and it is still today
you know essentially it's a magnitude
better than
all existing languages it was true in
1990s and it's just true today
so in 1990s basically the other the most
you know there's not much out there the
highest level language is pearl
and you also have matlab you know uh you
know you have several other math
software as well
but they are not comparable okay
and today after 20 years
you know all you have lots of languages
you have haskell you know haskell exists
in 1990s as well so but anyway today you
have pascal julia erlang
and one bunch of you know so many uh
uh nimrod name uh you know golan you
have uh
rust you have you know these are low
level languages but you also have quite
a lot higher level r
you know ah the language r or python
you know python is getting very popular
with ai and data science since
so-called data science idiot you know
doing a lot of math basically
uh so any anyway ah python matlab
uh you have quite a lot you know the
judea okay judy is the new kind of thing
but still but still you know you i look
at math muhammad language now you know
in the 1990s there are
like 150
functions spilled in in language okay
about 150
i mean a hundred i mean 1500
okay 1 500 or something like that
one 1 200 functions building
in 1990s in language today
you have 7000 you know i showed you
yesterday when i was building the
woofan mod you have 7 000 building
functions you know back in the 90s 1990s
i read the manual you know 1 000 pages
you know throughout three times in
different years so i'm i know i
essentially know all the functions what
they do
but now there are seven thousand
building
functions it's overwhelming i cannot and
i'm getting old
7 000 building functions i can
i don't you know i don't think even for
for if you are young you know you just
start out
to become a mathematician
i don't think you even today any people
can actually
fully you know know all the seven
thousand
wolfram building functions because they
become
this yeah i don't think you know you
might know
what they do but you don't use them
because
they are in different diverse areas okay
and each of these building functions
they are
truly amazing they you know
it's reasonable to say for any like
one single line of wufam language look
at this one okay
it what does it do so so so for example
you know let's
let me show you i mean let me explain my
enthusiasm or the
why do i think wufang language is a
magnitude beyond
all existing languages okay let me start
with language okay
so let's start let's uh three let's say
three okay we magnify then let's paste
the code
uh you see so we got a
we got a this is you know specularity
you see this shiny thing
interactive dynamic uh uh you know
movement you know rotation okay
so look at this thing okay so what does
it take
what does it does it take to build this
you know so first of all you look at
these is existing
existing languages none of them do this
out of the box well maybe the closest
is python matlab
matlab does okay then but
with python you have to know a lot you
have to be a programmer for
a year or two okay in wolfram language
this is
one single [ __ ] line okay
white space insignificant truly white
space insignificant okay
so let me let me show you this okay so i
press the button
you see it you know let me show you some
some some with actual
uh more advanced formatting okay i mean
so what does it take to um
do this in in other languages okay so
years of coding you know one thousand
ten thousand lines
you know this is you can set the
lighting
you can set uh the reflection the
different lighting models you can
you have you can have one or more
several light sources
the lighting can be colored light
sources and
it you can also turn them off and you
also have ambient light
okay ambient light you know for example
let me show you okay the documentation
okay
okay that's too big hold on a second
under 50.
okay so let's magnify okay so the
lighting details
so they show you for example then you
have you can specify
specularity which is um which is kind of
reflection okay
then you have then you have colors on
the surface
you can also change kind of the material
properties of the surface
so they behave differently uh
in reaction to light okay then you can
have lighting direction or whatever
then you have lighting uh point
different
type of light you know then you you also
have ambient light okay lighting
specification
you know just to study and you know
if you are a computer graphics if you
are a programmer
and you you are your field you know you
your research area is computer graphics
yeah you can do this you can do this in
opengl or whatever
opengl or 3d cad modeling
software like blender blender or autocad
or whatever
yeah you can do that but here the thing
is that
in wufam language all you have to do is
just type
this thing you know it condenses
all the complexities and jargons of
computer graphics the science of
computer graphics into
the most essential uh form
okay it tells you when you have a
lighting you have
what what are the issues of lighting
ambient light
light source color of the light bulb
okay
then the reflection properties of the
material surface okay
then you know it's specified the whole
thing but you know you can just say it
and you can
see the differences okay you know that's
tremendous
thing this this is the this is why i
love
wufam language okay you can experiment
you know you know you can play with it
you know for example let's just uh copy
this okay
actually you can just evaluate it right
here
okay so and actually we can
uh magnify any one of them okay now a
sphere is
not to interest okay so so in this case
yeah okay the lighting fix is fixed
fixated to the
to the thing so
so anyway so you see all these different
lighting models okay so
actually this is this postscript or
yeah this is postscript so so you you
see
one what i'm talking about and that's
just lighting okay
lighting is nothing the the the and also
you can have transparency
you know just by this line okay where's
the opacity you see
now let's say opacity two
you see uh let's say opacity
uh zero okay let's see what then you got
wireframe only
amazing okay that's not it you know
so you know so that's incredible you
know
just for this feature alone where you
can you can plot you know
different models of lighting and you can
plot
and dynamic rotation and just for this
feature alone
i would spend 300 you know the student
version to uh
get the wolfram language just for these
just for these
if you know assuming it doesn't do
integration
it cannot do matrix multiplication
matrix equations
differential equations all all that oh
you know and artificial intelligence
things
image recognition only for this feature
alone i would
uh pay for 300 which i did
in 1990s okay so in 1990s i bought it
the student version then i wrote some
code
it was great then i went to work for
ufam research
for half a year as a beginning
as a summer intern then i decided
mistake it's a mistake that i'm going to
go back to
college to get a degree that's that was
a mistake
but anyway things happen in life
so anyway i was going to call this so i
wanted to show you some of the
more complex can we uh for example for
example this one okay
so yeah so this we have this in the
in the youtube screenshot so let's post
that
and let me show you the typography
okay you see this for example look at
this
uh this equation okay x squared plus y
squared minus c
c squared and the square the whole thing
okay
now i press one button make them
you know make them fun looking typeset
okay
fantastic and let's say divided let's
just let's just draw
it now draw it
okay there's an error that's a that's
probably a bug
visualization called contour plot
message not found
okay so anyway so you got this um
amazing thing you know so so this is a
contour plot contour cloud is hard to
implement
so you know how to implement contour
plot
yeah so raspberry pi now about second
hand
okay so so did you try wufa language i i
guess you did
so do you know how to implement contour
plot okay so for a parametric plot
like that this is easy to implement okay
let's change the
opacity back so for parametric plot it's
it's fairly to implement i i've done
that before you know
when when in in 2000s
you can write this in javascript you can
you know you can implement
you know you need a graphics engine so
in the case of javascript
you can use svg so i have used you know
i talked many times i have a svg
tutorial and
just search for size vg tutorial
so for a parametric equation for example
i don't know if you can see it so here's
a three equations
this is one for x one four y one for z
three functions it's easy to
implement uh parametric plot okay
but not but not the lighting and that
all those are more complex
but if you if you just want you know a
bunch of polygons to plot this thing
then it's easy
if you want pretty like black like this
it take you 10 years well
a year or two you know then then you
have to get into yeah the
bitmaps you know anyway but for
a contour plot it's you know this is
this is the equation okay so look at
this thing
so you can see this this is a
one big equation equals to zero okay
uh one big complicated equation in order
to plot this
so what happens here the graphics is
that
all those points on the surface are
you know they are coordinates x y z and
if you plug them into the equation they
this equation becomes true so all these
points are the
solutions of the equation
how do you do this how do you plot this
well the way you do it is that
you basically exam so
so a 3d space you look at every point in
the space
you know you begin you know there are
infinite number of points but you begin
with a
uh you begin you begin with a
uh grid you know a bunch of points on
the grid
then check to see if they you know just
plug
plug them in the the points into this uh
equation to see if that
thick to see if that if it's near zero
or not
if it is then you know that point is
part of the
solution of the equation so
that's the essential idea to implement
uh contour plot or implicit equations
plotting of
implicit equations you know you can
begin by
uh try to do a two dimensional one you
know so you have an equation of two
variables
x and y you want to plot all the
solutions you can
so you can begin to implement this
for a two dimensional equation two
variables
so the essential idea is essentially
trial and error
you you know you you try every point to
see if they are
equals to zero or usually by you know to
see if they are bigger than zero or
smaller
smaller than some number you know within
a uh
region you know to see if them
if they are near zero okay then those
are the points that
are the solution or near the solution
then you refine it then you try more
points closer to
you know then you have some refined
region then you try more points in those
regions
then you refine and you find eventually
your
you know you'll find the numbers that uh
you know make the equation true so
that's how you
uh implement this so it's
so it's spectacular okay so this one
there's no opacity let's try
0.5
so contour plot you know it takes a
while because
it's it's kind of computational
intensive
so okay so this so now you have a
transparency
okay that's i think that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
fantastic beautiful i find this amazing
and how do you know you know let me tell
you let me talk about one more thing
okay
how do you find this equation you know
it would be fun
it would be fun to me okay at least for
me just
just sit here and try different
equations and see what you get
beautiful it's amazing this is a
combination of
mathematics and art
literally yeah so this i find
i do find this amazing and let me show
you also
no computer stuff two things uh woofam
is amazing i mean and
uh i am not any good with mad i don't
know what to do with movement except
copy and paste yeah
that's good that's that's that's the
most scientist
too actually you know that's true most
scientists they are not programmers
so when they use language just like me
right now
you just try you know you plot things
but we haven't get into uh actual
programming of the wolfram language
which i will
i will uh start to show uh in my coming
talk show
so how many people are watching i'm i'm
hungry now
i talked for close to two hours now
uh and how many people are watching
let's see three people five
okay five
okay i think that's it um well
let me show you one more thing so i uh
yeah i want to
show you one more thing like steve jobs
do uh math okay
so playing curves so where do i want to
go
so um
uh you know i'm going to update all
these these are
pretty old most of them 20 years old
graphics
you know so you are looking at you see
this you see
this is a great book by the way you go
by it uh you are looking at you see this
you see this we we we showed this today
you see this this curve is called cross
cap
that's a model of projective plane
fascinating stuff i can explain easily
but
but okay i haven't done so before so
so what's a projective plan okay so
normally you have a plan
and the the plan we imagined intuitively
is that it just goes
infinite you know it's flat it's not
curved
okay it's not curvy anyway it's just the
plane
x and y and goes infinite okay now
what's a projective plane
what what is a projective plane now this
this surface is a model a projected
plane
so what is a projective plane well
basically
it's a concept in projective geometry or
a big branch of math okay so a
projective plane is just like a plane
except that
except that if you if you so this is a
plane right
so if you go in one direction you keep
going
it will come back from the other side
okay so any so in other words any
line there's no line segment okay
any line is just connected to you know
it'll come back from here
but if you go in this direction it will
come back to
over you know here that's not all
okay so that's one thing the other thing
is that
there is a point infinite infinitely far
away you just
imagine it okay there's a point
somewhere outside
that every line will pass it
yeah so you see you if you have a line
here
you'll come back you know over all from
the other side
and also this line will pass
that special not not special but there's
a
point infinite far away it will pass
that
and in fact every line will also pass
that point
now that's a that's a projective plane
or
real projective plane you know a
two-dimensional
real projective plane why is
why real because real numbers okay not
complex because there's also a version
of
a projective complex plane
so that's a idea but why so you might
want to be wondering why do you
why do mathematicians create this
complex idea i mean it doesn't seem
intuitive to you actually it's
quite intuitive you'll get you'll get to
know
why it why this idea occurs when you
study projective geometry it's
very natural and intuitive okay so
anyway so this
this surface is just the model of uh
of that real projective plane it's
topologically uh the same you can see
that
you know every line you you can kind of
see it you see
there are grids on this surface you can
see
every grid they connect to yourself
so that's the idea of lines coming back
to yourself
and
and uh how do i how shall i say it
anyway so
you know so anyway i i i i'm not
so good at projective geometry you know
i started long ago
in the 1990s i studied uh
some of it uh and i need to revisit
okay that's it thank you guys for
watching yeah that's it yeah
there is one more thing i wanted to show
we happen to run into this page
but there's there is a thing i want to
show
about uh i'm getting tired
[Music]
let's see algorithm
okay here so
this thing okay this spectacular let me
show you in wufang language okay
this is another contour plot wait is it
paste it run it
yeah it's take a long time okay but but
i want to show this okay
so magnify
you see this is i call this a borg cube
so i can just sit here all day and try
different
uh equations you see there's certain
structure in this thing
and imagine if you are a game you know
if you write for game engines
create you know it would be i think it's
tremendous fun to create actually create
this thing in 3d game engine
so a person is like very small inside it
so it becomes like a uh
a puzzle a labyrinth or you know
you have all these tunnels and you have
to find out where you are going and
whether
how this thing partitions the space okay
let me
i want to try some some of the
specularity thing here so let's try it
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff donate
okay
paypal patreon the links are my on
my website oh this is beautiful this
is beautiful pink [ __ ]
oh yeah
fantastic
beautiful
i'm gonna leave this for a while so that
youtube will pick this up
as my as my screenshot
bye guys
jonathan here and said takimoti
and thank you cortez