good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show
i'm alive and you are alive hello guys
11 people watching fantastic so today we
are going to do a major task
not really major but we it's probably
going to be one hour this is a emax
workflow so what i'm going to do today
is going to move uh the whole ergo emacs
website from you know that domain to
to kasari.info okay so let me show you
uh so let's turn on let's go to
ergo emacs.org so you can see this is my
emacs website of the domain ergoemax.org
so you have emacs tutorial and you have
imac list tutorial and so on so every
page on this domain is going to be moved
to
saudi.info so you know long story short
i in around 2010 i started to split so
let me show you saudi.org
so this is my main original website this
saudi.org domain began in 2000 year 2000
year 2k
and
and uh
around year 2010 i split them into
several domains cassari.info
for any math or programming technical
stuff
ergoemax.org for any emacs related stuff
worthy english what english dot com for
literature linguistics
writing grammar related things
then
some music
which is all about music songs my
commentaries poetry the lyrics humanity
human animals and their songs you know a
lot of you know because you can you know
there's you know the white people have
the topic of anthropology
or ethology ethnology you know those are
study you know the academic field of
studying human animals or different uh
ethnicity their religion their you know
their culture you know that's why men's
thing
subject matter doesn't really occur in
asia
asia con culture chinese basically so it
doesn't occur there but basically it's a
you know western people
field anthropology study of human
animals
so
when you study human animals there are
many you know you can actually study a
lot about human animals via the songs
via our songs you know national athens
you know the whatever you know so many
songs love songs and and so on and pop
music and rap for example rap
and metal heavy metal they reflect
american culture you know that those
genres
rap music
rap music sp in particular reflect the
the black people in america their
culture how they you know
uh and and heavy metal usually white
people in america then then of course
there's pop there's classical they you
know you can study
uh
a lot about human animals via their
songs and lyrics so i have like
you know i have commentaries about 435
songs
justin scarfi
justin justin scofie the mathematician
from canada the profe professional
mathematician hello justin welcome i'm
gonna read the comments okay keep it
keep them going so songs
to saudi some music dot org uh and
visual arts it's i talked about this
often uh is you can also study a lot
about human animals from artwork
throughout history through our cultures
their artwork
um
so for example i have classic you know
the you know the in asian this this this
piece for example this piece
uh not that one but but but this one for
example this artwork
is
oh this is only fifteen hundreds but
some of them are two thousand years old
okay some of them for example this uh
greek
um
uh wait uh some of them you know some of
them vase you know this uh
this one for example this sculpture this
one
is from
first century ce
okay yeah about 2 000 years old you know
so artwork you know artwork work
reflects
lots of human animals of course
in my
x-arts.org i pick what i like you know
it's not it's a subset it's not the
survey it's not a survey of the entire
human animals artwork but you know part
of it i like and also including modern
ones for example the anime and including
the marlene jen's favorite things memes
well engine's favorite things memes
okay i talked this in my uh in my in my
star talk show often
this is a phenomenon of the last
decade you know you know which which
does reflect you know so you look at the
whole picture the whole picture from the
you know entire history of human animals
so you can see what era what they are
thinking what's their what's you know
what what is it what's in their brain so
this is the past decade in america for
example among the usually typically
young among the youth so
arts
so go back so then there's a second life
exploration of the metaverse the the
metaverse is becoming a thing now due to
the zuckerberg [ __ ] the facebook
[ __ ] a scan of human animals one of
the big greatest scum the
mark zuckerberg
so
you know second life virtual virtual uh
virtual reality kind of thing you it you
know as as we move forward technology
technology catapult us
far into the future really
really neatly you know whether you like
it or not it's pushing us ahead you know
soon you're gonna see your friends with
uh cybernetics you know
and uh you know neuron connections and
and all that so second life you know
where
you know potentially it's going to
replace the web like 10 more years you
know in 10 more years there's no website
anymore this is just virtual life you
you visit website by going into this
gaming interface you know
visit online stores and you know it's no
there's no website anymore browsers
actually just the interface browsers
becomes
a game and game becomes a 3d game engine
you know
possibly in 10 years
so that's my exploration of second life
second life second life dot um
oak but anyway
so i was saying
10 years ago due to i need to need i
need to get ad money i split xari.org
into several domains why because
saudi.org was banned by google
because i was you know bad mouthing
george bush you know george w bush the
iraq war and
so google banned me so i and i'm
desperate so i split them into different
domains so i can put
google ads and that's that
that task of splitting a website into
different domains it's actually
painstaking it took me three months to
do
because then
because you you i don't you know you
split different subject matter into
different domains but you also have to
make sure that for example artwork for
example artwork
long long history you know i probably if
i don't stop now i probably gonna just
talk about this for one hour so
especially artwork for example this one
okay
let's let's let's mention a few the
famous people okay the famous people
that you uh in you know all praise for
for example um
uh you know
i have to be careful because right now
google censorship this millennial
generation and social justice you know
this i show this classic artwork they
open you because
and okay so
i want to mention this one by
michelangelo you know the well respected
greatest one of the greatest western
artists michael
angelo uh leader and the swan okay
so but artwork is
is kind of prone to be censored
especially in america
in the past by christians
today by the malay
by the social justice scan okay so uh
you know many of these um then but in
china
this one is from china okay
you know interesting so
so out of work so so so i'm moving you
know so i was saying you know to move
sip you know i have to be careful it's
not easy you know first of all
technically speaking it's not easy
because
because let me show you so you have um
so essentially you have 1 000 web pages
you know like i have like 30 000
files and among them there's like
7 000 html files so you want to move
certain html files into different
directories okay
first of all
which file should move to what directory
that's
that's one task you have to decide you
have to you know
then then there's a technical aspect of
the moving so
for example in powershell you can just
do
okay let's clear
uh let's see the
clear screen let's start over so and
let's magnify
so you can see the full glory of
powershot for your old bash okay so you
can do the
cd web okay
so you do so so you know the recurse
file uh
include
html and it's going you know it's ten
thousand pages it's go only enough so
so there's the technical aspect of
moving which is not also not easy
especially because once you move the
html from one directory to another then
you got a big problem what's the problem
because every link html link to other
pages now are broke broken
so
for every file you moved you know
five thousands of them for every file
you moved you have to fix the link
and what does that involve that involves
you have to know
what's the original file path what's the
new file path
and what's the file path for each link
that original link
so it's not easy so it's a in general
it's a text processing task so it
involves you know i'm so that's what i'm
going to do today
so i was saying 10 years ago i split
saudi.inf saudi.org into uh six or seven
domains today i'm moving them all back
back
home
back home
so
so actually the word english already
happened so because you can see
the url is now back in saudi.org it was
it was let me show you okay worthy
english
wordyenglish.com you see now it says
page moved
you know page you know wordyenglish.com
page moved so in the past month i've
done some of the movies
so
um
so so so what what
saudi.org
so
in 2010 i split my website into several
domains and now i'm moving them all back
now basically now it's going to be
exactly info which is all about
programming and
math and technical stuff programming
math keyboards
uh you know
those kind of things programming
languages you know tech kind of
technical stuff that's saudi.info
then
then there's kassadi.org which is my
mothership you know
so this saudi.org is going to be just
everything else
arts
writing literature linguistics whatever
so
and today
my task is to move the ergo emacs
website you see logo emacs now i'm going
to move about six about three thousand
pages html back to kassadi
dot info so you are going to see
primarily you are going to see my emacs
workflow what i'm you know so i'm gonna
tell you what what is it technically
what do i have to do
uh and i'm going to do them we are
powershell we are we are
emac these functions i've written
via
uh also pas you know gold line scripts
basically finding replays okay lots of
tons of fine replace fixing fixing the
moving of the links
so that's what i'm going to do so
[ __ ] that
[Laughter]
the preface is already 20 minutes so who
is here
so yeah so let's start okay so let me
let me let's start okay so so i have
already written up
what what are the steps so on the you
know talk show page when i'm done with
the video you you know you'll see this
page you know santa actual page today
uh i already outlined the steps what we
are going to do so i'm going to do them
now
and here you are looking at my emacs of
course uh if you watch my video then you
know the pink window shows all my
keystrokes and the commands command
names i'm using vora keyboard and i'm
and i'm i'm also using soft light keys
so this is advantage to kinesis
advantage to keyboard that my mother
ship my mothership my main drive my
battle station this is the ultimate
hacking keyboard so let's see
can you see it yeah the so ultimate
hacking keyboard so okay
so
so so i'm ready are you ready
12 concurrent viewers 4 likes so let me
read the comments and um let's begin
okay so hello guys hello west hello gog
or funny thumbnail today yeah i'm now
i'm now a star on 4chan
someone someone of 4chan made that
i'm the next i'm the incarnate
reincarnation of terry
god
what is god operating system
you know that's uh terry davis i think
not that yet indeed hello cortez and
thank you cortes thank you very much uh
for the things you um
helped me
uh
so where did uh with this did this diy
where all these dion go i damaged my
finger by the way i talked about
yesterday this finger
bead bead hello justine mathematician
from canada thanks uh
you said one of the few sites that's
actually fun to poke about thank you
justine hayes jones haskell coder and
scala coda
hello justine from canada
uh you know link rick uh
have you tried c plus
c sharp no i haven't tried c sharp
that's not my thing
uh
but i you know since now i'm on windows
i might try f sharp now f sharp is
looking
is looking delicious f sharp you know f
f sharp the functional programming
language in the lineage of camo in the
meta language ml
standard ml sml metal language camo or
camo
then f sharp that's the family tree
haskell is kind of some you know
haskell is
not exactly part of the family but it's
related
hugo no i refuse to use hugo okay
everything i do here is manual and by
emac this like my own code
hugo no
uh
jekyll yeah jaco and if you you go you
know people have been telling me exactly
you should use that no
my way is
i you know i consider it superior but
obvious because well because once you
you know let's say you
let's let's digress okay let's talk
about you know things this is after
that's uh suitable for today's talk show
so for example if you are you know uh if
you
you are a programmer a lot of you are
you know you maybe you master javascript
maybe you master ruby python uh you know
you really master it so when you need a
tool to you know also let's suppose you
also been working with html and css for
20 years you know which which i you know
i grew up with it
so once you master a tool you you don't
need those um you know these those boxed
up tools not you know
you you have a choice because you can
write everything yourself okay so this
is not just me
you know i'm doing it because probably
because i'm old you know i know stuff
you know 30 30 years 30 years watching
html and css screw up
in javascript you know so i know that
i'm i know my ways i don't need those
tools
i
you know so
you know i do i do what i need to do
faster more efficient than whatever
those tools can offer
me uh f sharp yeah f sharp e max is for
the wing haskell
no i haven't studied haskell but it's
you know
so this thumb now is from 4chan okay
just search for xari 4chan you'll find
it
yeah there are so many different ways
you know you can use oakmod plus uh hugo
plus checkout you know that whatever
works for you
so okay let's let's let's do today's
thing so so let me show you okay so
let's start to do today's thing
so first of all i need to go to my emacs
blog and
okay so showing emacs blog i i need
first of all i need to make a
announcement to my rss web feed
subscribers so that they know i'm moving
my site in fact in the next hour i hope
so in next hour i i'm gonna okay i
already spent 30 minutes so in next hour
i'm gonna finish the whole thing and
sync to my website so there's no more
urgo emacs okay so first thing i need to
make announcements so
uh
so moving entire emacs or dot to uh
sorry.info so okay so let's uh global
highlight my line mod okay so press a
key so this is my rss site
so do i need to expand but okay so
anyway so this the rss file is basically
just a
xml atom file so you can see the url so
this is the xml xml file so all i have
to do is now i need to add a new name
entry i need to add this line to that
file so what i do
uh
i already have it um
you know i have a command so if you look
at the pink window you'll see it okay so
i'm gonna call the command
do it
so you can see the command
code is star update r code no the
command code is um
what and hold on a second failed okay so
hold on a second
uh close that
go to
emacs blog by bookmark then they move my
cursor here
uh okay and
do it
okay so i i called the wrong command
that's why uh something failed so
do it yeah so you can see
the command is
atom new entry so basically it just
opened my atom file you can see the
button blog.xml and it added this
this entry
so you can see it just you know it's
just a movie entire email okay so now
that it
okay so now i need to actually delete
because i did it twice so delete the
previous one okay
okay
shrink the white space
close it save it go back here
go back so now if you click on subscribe
feed
you can see
moving entire little emacs to saudi info
so
so actually i need to um sync to the web
server before okay i need to sync to it
web server so let's do it
okay so sync web host so i'm going to
need to type my password
so you guys don't hack me okay
let's hide my keyboard for now
ah [ __ ]
anyway so i have a uh anyway so
so that's done
so now if you go yeah so that's done now
any comments
what fun do you use i'm using the
okay
so if you go to css if you search for
saudi visual css
then go down you can see common web
fonts so this is my tutorial about the
most the best fonts okay the the native
fonts on each operating system so um
so if you are talking about um
basically i'm using ariel so because
that's the most popular
and
the corresponding matrix compatible
fonts basically the same as ariel is
helvetica on the mac and liberation
sense on linux and
remo if you are on google platform such
as google google's
computer what your chromebook
and as for um monospace the native the
best one um if you are microsoft i would
you know i would recommend consoles
and on linux there's a metric compatible
version called inconsolas but
you know you guys are tech nerds you
know you guys probably have your
preferences and by the way on the mac
it's menlo okay on the mac it's menu
it's not shown here because menu is not
a
uh
universal web web font
so that's about what font i'm using
but um so
so let's get back to the movie moving
the web page because we have a lot to do
so first of all we i'm i updated the
atom so
what's the next thing so
let's see
okay first make a blog post
make a blog post about the move put it
into rss to notify the subscribers about
the site move okay i have a spelling
error
blog not block
okay then create the directory emacs in
sally info let's do it
okay so go to saudi info so let's let's
magnify so go to kusali info
hide the unix thing so create a emacs
directory emax okay so there it is so
empty that's good
okay now i'm gonna copy the path create
a new
buffer paste the path okay because we
are going to need it later
copy everything in urban emacs to kasari
info okay so let me show you go back go
back here so ergo emax
so we are going to
copy
[Music]
recurse now this is the powershell
syntax okay
copy because
from this ergo emacs to
soli info emacs okay make it one line
copy
back to powershell
paste it
double check okay copy because
i'll go emacs.org to kasali info emacs
okay
do it
okay that might take one minute because
there are you know
5000 files also
so meanwhile we can actually
you know let's see how many files are
there so cd cd web ergo emax okay
the recurse
magnify
file
okay then
measure
okay
so the request file measure logo emax so
500 files okay
now it's a copying done the copying is
done okay
so
okay so
the copy is the next
in ergo emacs org delete all files
that's not html okay so now
let's go to a help script because i've
done this for my other sites so i have
some uh
helpful notes okay
wait sound talk show let's see let's see
the the files we copied over
yeah there it is oh okay so there's a
kind of error we don't want so i'll go
emax org so we don't want the oval emax
or we we want to move the whole thing up
okay so go up a directory
move the ogre emax there so you can see
there is ergo e-max
and now the e-max is empty
refresh that's correct now delete the
delete the e-max
yes okay now rename this to emacs okay
capital r for rename in diet
okay do it fantastic now it's done
so you see
so again you can see this is in
sally.info right okay
let's go there again
emacs so copy the file path
okay now back to talk show
now
now because i did this before so i have
some help
you know i have some helpful notes let's
go to it
so this file you are looking at is my
my scripts and notes when i move saudi
xr arts.org
so this you know in december in no in
you know last month
so we are going to do it so wait so
first of all
okay hold on a second
so first of all so go to the directory
you can see
i have my past notes are moving
different uh domains to
saudi.org now we are going to create a
new one for moving over emacs
so
let's
open the odds
one
make a backup go back to the directory
okay
go back to directory show the ping
window
refresh so this is a new backup now
rename it
move ergo emax okay
okay so this is a new file
okay done now open the file
now
give it a new date
okay now basically
now
now paste paste our um
yeah so
so now change every word sardi i mean
change every xr arts dot org to
to about emacs okay so i need a path for
orgo emacs so let's do it let's open
this let's do it quickly
so you can see now change every exam
odds to ogo emacs so let's do a find
replace
okay do it do it
okay and now every
xrd.org must be xrd.info so do it
find replace
you know i'll explain what those are for
but yeah you know don't worry about it
no
so um
so roots root
let's rename it
some odd roots let's say alt root
okay old root
and the sari info root let's say let's
call rename that new route
change change okay
uh destination directory e-max
uh
oh
anyway let's not worry about that
okay so now next thing we need to do
okay for
the next thing we need to do for each
html file in ergo emacs change their
content into
to a notice about new url okay
uh is it boring so what is uh
hello no time to see no time no long
long time no c b ticks
okay i'm kind of getting boring so next
what is the next thing we need to do so
relax
let me drink
okay
i want to do the i want to finish this
in in in 30 more minutes so
the next thing we are we need to do is
to
for every html file
let me let me show you okay so
so right now if you go to cassandra
emacs or right let's go to it okay let's
go to it let's let's make this um larger
so we can actually see the whole thing
so this is uh ergo emacs
site
now if you go to one of the emacs side
let's say my emacs blog okay open it
so you can see you know showing browser
you know that's uh emacs blog
so now this whole page will be
the content the whole entire content
will be deleted
so it will say let me show you what
let me show you let me show you okay
so the whole page let's just do it now
so copy the whole
deleted
so what what is the new content let me
show you okay so
so actually so i i
discussed
i showed here so let me show you
here this is the new content
page moved you know uh
html tag
then moved to
um
let me let me show you what what this is
okay let me modify it and put it here so
so this this is a new content so delete
that
okay so it should say
you know first of all it you have the
paragraph tag then
it says page move to this is a new url
so let's try to open that yeah that's a
you see
you see go to diet
go to the top you see this is on saudi
info so
so for every html page on the ergo emax
site you need to
[Music]
change their content into this this uh
line
with the new ui out there so how do you
do it i mean so that's what we are going
to do so
okay so that's what we are going to do
so
um
i'm going to show you how to do that so
this is involves lots of text processing
you know all these files we will need to
change you can see their directory size
here so after the after the change all
the all the file size will be small
so how do you do that okay so let's go
to notes so let's go go back to notes
close that
okay so
so this is a powershell script
um
and basically the script is here
function
write file new url okay for each html
file
you do this process okay new url exactly
dot info okay
so
destination directory name so let's um
hold on a second let's move this away
yeah let's move them away for now so we
don't get confused
okay just
ignore just ignore this because you
don't need to worry about it now
let's just comment them out
and shrink a little bit
so these are just my notes comments um
you know there's a e-max bird bug
you see
right now i'm trying to move my mouse up
you know the scroll wheel but it it
prevents me
doing so you see
this is a e-max bug i don't i'm not sure
why it happened
let's see if i um
can you see my
oh [ __ ] i forgot to show the keyboard
uh you see
i move them up okay now it's you see
this thing happened
i push the scroll bar up it won't let me
expose
yeah i'm not sure what
and it's not
readily reproducible
okay so
anyway
so okay now this is a powershell script
what this shout this um
let me write down what it does okay for
each html file
let's put it here okay
for html file
change its content to
page moved with a new url okay that's
what this
function is supposed to do
now i don't have i don't have
indentation but um
but this is the part okay so
okay
so let me double check okay alt root
check open it correct new root open it
correct
destination file destination the name
that's correct
now xcl oh good what is this join path
new test okay
so this is a new duh
so does that occur somewhere it does
okay so let's
let's um it we don't need that here okay
let's put it here
so
also cut that we don't need that here
okay
then we are going to focus on this um
my body yeah btx you should watch
yesterday
uh you know the previous youtube i think
you might like it
so what are we doing so for each html
file
what what are the steps okay let me yeah
so let me maybe as i you know usually i
write things out for myself and and
since i'm doing video it's also helpful
so
for html
steps
open the
file
delete
the content
insert the new text
to do that
first
find the new url okay
okay basically um
basically that's the steps okay
so
so that's what this function does okay
let's not look into so saudi.info so
this is a new url
uh full path
so
when is this file called i mean when is
this function called basically we are
going to call this function like this
okay let me show you
the
yeah it's easier to do this in
powershell so the
because
file
include
html okay so that is the
copy it
so this is the powershell command we're
gonna call then we're just going to pipe
it to
to the um
check yeah
and just pipe it to this function
uh so what this function
what this function yeah actually you can
see
actually cut that you can see that
actually here
actually you can save file okay
so
everything will be piped to
this function
so
okay so what do you so okay so
open okay so steps let's modify the
steps
first find the new ir new url okay
then open the file delete your content
insert the new text
then
write to file
so what the function need
the function need
the html file path
the new url okay that's all it needs
okay so this is so first of all the
first job is to find the new url where
it mapped to okay so
um
so
so finding the new url is the tricky
part okay let me explain okay so let me
let me explain so for example go to for
example we showed before the block
you know for example
uh okay so let me do that copy
okay
save close close close
so
for example
this
file
the new content is
the tricky part
is to have a function
that
maps old path to new url okay
so you can see this is the file path
over emacs org
emacs blog dot html the new url will be
you know the first part will be
saudi.info slash emacs http then
then the same thing okay so so that so
okay so i hope i'm not
okay let's and okay so now you know the
technical details then then you have to
worry about slash and backslash a pain
in the ass
okay so
let me let me let me um
okay so this full name the powershell
will tell us the full path okay now we
replace backslash by slash
okay
then new uh full path equals to
replace or root by
new url
so replace old route by new url
so new
and new 2 is
new 2 is replace backslash by slash okay
then new content so now we are creating
the new content so
this needs to be today's date
page move to
new to here that's right
okay
that's a new content and out file will
write to file so
so all file
input object
new content okay now file path
that encoding utf8 no new line
width okay so that will write out you
know write to file but
before we do that we want to be sure
this is correct before we actually write
to file so let's comment that out let's
say just echo just print it out first
so we want to print
echo the new content okay
and now we can do it
so make sure everything else is
commented out
okay okay now back to powershell
close this window
now open a new powershell in the same
directory that's good
duh
okay
now we are going to call
move
logo imac yeah i'm going to
now we are going to call this script
okay
so
yeah but before we do
before we press enter let's make sure
because whenever you run
you know shout script you know it's
gonna going to delete your whole drive
uh so check one more time what is uh so
make sure the script is
good okay
so go to the top everything is commented
commented out
um
[Music]
this is a function so
new content echo content
yeah then
then recursively
list all files in the old root directory
uh include you know just html files then
call the function okay let's okay let's
hope it's okay
make sure there's all commented out okay
that's good
do it
fantastic
so for every file you you can see
this is their new content let's check
okay
it's you know let's check
make sure they are uh
okay it moves to xari.info emacs
miscellaneous that's correct
okay
that's correct
you see
okay so we can actually we can we can
start to run the code by now we comment
out the echo part and
[Music]
and and make the right file
there
so before we do that first let's go back
to the old directory
open the file
and uh
let's open you know this uh this blog
index page okay that's what it looks
like you know this is a ergo emacs oh
directory
html file blog archive you know index
now once we run the command
once we run this powershell command
this file content is going to be changed
just you know
let's do it
do it
fantastic done now back to emacs you can
see
the content changed auto refresh you
know
emacs will automatically update buffers
that has been changed so
so so this is new content now let's open
the files to see if it exists
fantastic
open so you see the same file but now
it's on saudi.info you can see the url
fantastic close that back to emacs close
it
close it in fact you can open any file
so you can see
you can see the here is the file size
they are old file size you know first of
all you are we are in the urgo emacs oak
the old directory so the file size
is all the old file size now if i press
u to update
show the pink window if i press u to
update
i mean press g to update g you see every
file is now 137
or 120
kilobytes that means all files has been
changed you see
fantastic
fantastic okay we are almost done
the next step is now
you can see
okay so this step is done move
everything you know
okay next step is to fix these special
files i'll show you what they are so
right now we are in the old ogre emacs
directory so there are some of the
special apache files for example error
files
um
you know what they are well let me show
you what they are so
in order to do so i mean i need to go to
the
uh okay so go to the
move
so go to the new directory
emax
you know so this
this error file is the
um
you know it's kind of the apache thing
so anyway we don't need it in the old
directory anymore deleted
four four arrow four three error deleted
ads
you know google if you use google ads we
will require seo directory to have these
this
you know deleted
e-max the okay
e-max fun index okay
uh e-max manual that's a e-max manual
emacsite.ts
emacs sitemap.ts
do we have a new do we have a copy
okay i think i'm getting boring here i
am am i
so open that delete it and icon favicon
okay five econ also deleted so this is
this is what fabicon okay so you can you
can see it
so that's the favicon
the favicon from 1999.
it's still going
so open favicon deleted five econ
deleted favicon is a microsoft invention
by the way
highlight link javascript deleted
because all these are old dot ht access
okay this is a bunch of rewrite rules
this is apache
apache the ancient you know
[Music]
linux stack you know lamp
lamp
linux apache
mysql
pearl or php
you know this is when you apply for a
job you need to say oh i'm familiar i'm
an expert of lamp stack you know that's
the year 2000s
of course that's
that's uh
seized
you know they
that that lamp become dead
so ht ht
access
deleted
okay refresh
i is for all image files
what is this three prong okay that's
background image uh
css open it delete it
okay site map
deleted
sitemap javascript deleted stat map xml
okay so we have deleted all these kind
of special files in the old directory
now
actually delete them before i just made
a backup so now actually delete them
good
okay so that's the e-max the
so what's the next thing to do let's
look at let's look up
so fix these special files done
now change my bookmark that points to
other emacs site okay so when i use
emacs i have lots of book bookmarks so i
for example i want to go to my emacs
blog okay i just press three key you can
see the pink window it says
open file fast okay then i type just
type eb
emacs blog
okay enter you see this is my old
you know this is the my emac blog emacs
blog in the you know no no there's
nothing in it because we just made a
change so so now i need to change my
book emacs bookmark to pointing to the
new
positions okay so
so open it
okay let's open my emacs bookmark
bookmark so that's that's my emacs
bookmark okay
search for ergo
so there's a ogo emacs blog
there's a emac list
page emacs tutorial
dddd okay
delete them in bookmark and search ergo
emacs this uh
software keys
delete
okay do it
close
so now this is my
new emacs file path okay now i need to
bookmark this page so press three keys
watch look at the pink window okay
do
do okay
so
bookmark
bookmark set
so
how do i want to name this eb
so let's say eb emacs
blog
okay now i have set my emacs bookmark
so close this close this
now i can
open the bookmark again
press
x open file fast then just type eb
okay then i'm back on you know showing
browser i'm you know now i have
bookmarked the new file path for my
emacs
blog okay close it let's just do okay
now let's continue next
next
okay now the next thing is actually the
bulk of the
task you know
so let me explain this okay so what uh
so it's probably very boring for you
guys now let's see
three concurrent viewers
uh
oh [ __ ]
okay it's already one hour so the next
thing is actually
the heavy duty task of
find and replace so let me explain
what's going on so
so okay so i i now moved a few thousand
files from one directory to another now
every file the links in them
is now changed so i need to fix the
links
so for example let's go to um
actually this step is optional let me
explain okay so let's go to um let's go
to kasadi.info okay so the new directory
emacs
so let's for example open
emacs and let's open
blog so now if you scroll down so let's
see
and search for
search for href okay so that shows you
all my links
let's show the pink window okay so do it
again search for ief so you can see link
to discord first of all show in browser
showing browser so yes you see there's a
link to patreon to amazon to paypal to
to
atom web feed to discord
and and you know then lots of local
links
so but now here's an interesting part
you see
it says here's my wolfram language
tutorial so it links to sally.info
so if you look at the status bar you can
see the actual
link in browser but you know it's too
small let me show you here
so search for wolfram
okay so you can see there it is so here
you see this link
so this link now is the fully qualified
url
uh you see it links to http xli.info but
now
you see now they are actually in the
same directory because right now i'm in
the directory consoli.info
so i
don't need the fully qualified domain
actually
i just need a relative
file path for example let me open the
file open it copy the file path close it
put the file path here
you see and
make a link okay so
now this page will find
language syntax and operators
you know these two links are not exactly
the same except one usefully qualified
domain name which i don't want
why
because when you have a fully qualified
domain name
then all your html files
cease to be useful when you are using
them locally like right now like if i
click this it's going to go to
sally.info which requires internet
okay so for example if i sell you my
emacs tutorial
that won't work because every time you
click you're just going to go to my
website anyway so you want you so i want
the local links when they are in the
same directory or you know when they are
in the same domain you want the local
links so now the task is
for every occurrence
of fully qualified domain name link to
anywhere in sally.info you want to
change it to a
related file path okay
uh this is not easy okay so um
so if you know yeah am i going to do it
so how are you going you how how are you
guys doing nobody is watching now i
guess three people
uh
so either i can stop
today or
continue okay so i'm still going so
let's see
uh what's going on so yeah so i need to
change every link fully qualified domain
name link to
relative okay that's
that's only part of the links i need to
change there are also other things for
example
for example
right now we are showing a example where
in the emacs directory
it has a link to casada
info but however
it works the other way too
for example i have some page on sally
dot info for example study.info then go
to comp
go to
blog so this is a showing browser this
is my programming blog
okay actually let's go to keyboard blog
so
close
that search for keyboard so you can see
keyboard
search for blog
open it showing browser so this is my
keyboard blog
so you can see there's a link to emacs
blog
so if we go back to
the emacs search for href
you see that's a line
so again it's using a fully qualified
domain name
but now
that this emax block is in the same
domain so we don't need the fully
qualified domain name so in other words
in summary for every link that contains
fully qualified domain name
to urban emacs or to sally.info they all
need to be changed
so that's a task okay so
okay that's a task
um
close that okay so what are we doing
close that
so i explained the task let's see
close that close that this back to my
notes okay
okay that's that's when this okay let's
show this okay so
that's when this is useful okay let me
show you
so this is a okay so this is emacs so
okay so let's let's make a new file
instead go to directory
rename this
to dot el
so we are we just created a new file dot
er which indicate emac this copy or
deleted the whole thing okay back to
that file
then
select let's select select select select
uncomment
now
delete okay
now go back to the emac list file paste
it so now this is now in proper emac
list
i'll explain what they does they do okay
now close this
now back to powershell
okay now open the emac this file okay
first of all put the date today state
here
magnify
so exactly find replace so what do you
need to find
so those are the first two are dealing
with images let's move them down so
let's focus on
href
link so
first of all change every
so this says change every
everyxsaats.org
to xardi.org
in this directory
okay so
okay hold on a second first of all let's
do this
so change every logo e max
change every
ah this is a very tedious because you
have to make sure
this is actually so i'm actually let's
stop i'm thinking
let's stop it
okay whatever you are feeling is best
thing to do okay that's a that's a
fantastic advice
okay so now what we gonna do
this okay so this
so now the changing link actually yeah
it's this is very tedious and uh one
must be very careful because if you make
a mistake then you made a change to a
thousand files
that's that's going to be hell to fix
you know that's going to be hell to fix
so you want to make sure you know that
the relative link is actually a pain yes
the relative link
so what
so um
but i'm you know i need to do this for
sure
for sure but actually it is not
absolutely necessary but right
yeah so it's actually not absolutely
necessary because for example let's go
to my emacs let's go to my
emacs blog
you see although it uses fully qualified
domain name it still works you know it's
not necessary to use
relative link
okay let's skip this for now because
there are other things to do easier so
let's let me explain what what what the
other things to do
so now
in the old directory
i need to remove
all jpeg files for example let's go to
okay let's let's go to um
let's go to the old emacs directory so
go to
go to a new
powershell this ergo emacs
the
recurse
file
include
jpeg
okay there's tons of jpeg i want to
remove them
in the old emac logo emagster do it okay
then you also have png
so lots of png files
now you want to be very careful because
if you are if i'm in the wrong directory
then that's disaster
okay removal png files now what what
else are there so now let's do
exclude
html so
show me all files
that is not html okay
do it
okay so you got text files you got
javascript files okay let's write it
down
so that's when this part is useful
because you know
uh that's when this part is useful jpeg
png gif svg you know movie files yeah
let's do that
so in fact actually um
let's just um
you know we are in we don't have to
worry about
copy that
okay so we actually need to include text
txt
and dot el
okay copy that
paste
make sure the directory is correct i'll
go emax yes
yeah that's the old directory requests
include jpeg remove png gif and so on
do it
wait did you
okay done
now let's try to show all files that's
not html see if there's still okay
there's gz
gz
okay so let's uh let's do it okay so
there's more
okay
and ts of course
when you have js you must have ts
typescript copy
and pdf okay let's do it
do it
okay
now show all
non html files do it
okay there's tgz org
htmpdf okay this is some more
tgz
org
htm
pdf
do it again
xml yeah then you need to delete xml
okay
just one single file actually
fantastic now
now show
exclude
so now ergo emacs directory has
no other files than html it's only html
files fantastic
what's the next step
the next step is to close that
cross set
cursor
process
let's just upload okay let's just
upload
okay sync my website this is going to
actually so you can actually see the see
the changes
so but before we do that i need to hide
my keyboard so you don't see me typing
passwords
okay is that right yeah
so
oh okay so
here
are sync
there it is
i'm done i'm done for today
i think any questions any comments
massive massive change
so let's show keyboard again
so any comments any comments
cortes
tiago cisco
yeah so there's a lot of file you know
one more minute should do so now
let's look let's can we you know we can
go now we can go to um
ergo emacs now you see this is a google
emacs website now if i refresh
the whole thing's uh you know the page
will be gone let's try it
now it's still uploading some of it
uh you know sorry the info i think it's
already gone
keyboard reflection in your glasses oh
jesus
yeah it doesn't matter
you know it is nothing on my website
it's you know it's public information
anyway
uh
so it's still uploading lots of image
files so few thousand image files but
you know refresh
gun
you see ergo emacs now is officially
gone
ending closing a chapter 10 years
a decade a chapter of my life so now it
says 2021
november 13th page move to here okay
click it there it is now you can see
it's on salida info okay
so yeah that's it for today thank you
guys for watching let's have some tea
[Music]
tea
now offline
offline then i'm going to do the task
carefully about changing all the
fully qualified domain name
links
then you know
then i'm going to start to uh add https
you know a lot of you have requested oh
so why don't you you know how come you
are not using https you know i talked
about that
i haven't talked about that online much
but
i mean i haven't talked about that in my
video but
i've discussed that in my discussion you
know if you haven't
yet joined
on discord uh the reason
why that is because um
google
is no good okay
okay bye guys bye i'm done too bye bye
strips
you know
you know i developed i got a back pain
since yesterday you know getting old for
no reason
and it's still
no i cannot stand straight
but that's it for today guys that's
no no i'm i'm walking
awkwardly because
okay i'm shutting down bye
oh well if you like my stuff buy it okay
emacs tutorial and my patreon
and stuff
bye