Hello guys. I'm alive. Good morning.
Good evening. Good afternoon.
Welcome to another episode of South Talk
Show.
We are going to code JavaScript
somewhat.
Okay, another South Talk Show.
And we are just going to code
JavaScript. Before we do
let's get drunk.
Okay, so today we are having Erguotou.
So this is Chinese vodka.
If you don't know, it's also known as
baijiu.
Uh
means well, basically means Chinese
vodka. Okay.
Now 50% alcohol
uh something. 56 degrees something.
Now they call it proof or something. I
don't I don't know. I don't understand.
But 56
% alcohol by volume.
Uh which in chemistry terms it's called
ethanol. Fascinating.
South Talk Show. You are watching and
here's my keyboard, Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard.
80 UHKAT. Okay, fantastic.
You can find my reviews on YouTube.
And my written reviews on my website.
Which I'm going to show you. By the way,
this and this trackball, fantastic. This
is called Nulea trackball, n u l e a.
Okay, let's switch to my screen so you
can see my screen. Can you see
Can you see my screen? Yes, showing
browser.
So I'm coder. I've been a coder for 30
years.
I'm a old coder. Okay.
So today uh not Wolfram language. Today
we just going to do uh some JavaScript.
I'm I'm going to show you. Okay, you
want to go blog.
Uh can you see my screen? Yeah. Can you
see this show file name? You see?
Uh let's have the drink first.
I already had one shot, by the way. So
this is second shot for the day.
Uh if you are here, say hi. Love to see
your comments.
Otherwise, play at 1.5 speed. Okay.
Um
Yeah, so I'm going to like do some
drunk coding, something like that.
Slightly drunk.
You know, when you when you get drunk,
you cannot code, but it because it um
it
degrades your
thinking abilities actually. Your
logical analysis abilities when you
drink.
Yeah, I don't I don't enjoy drinking
that much actually.
So anyway, so so I'm you know, but it
makes you like it makes you stupid
basically. That is the um
specific intention. I mean that that
what what is the word?
>> [snorts]
>> That is what the alcohol does. It makes
you stupid. And it makes you relaxed
your
radar systems, your nervous, you know,
your sense you know, your senses become
dull. Hello India. Hello hive mind.
Hello to India.
So India, what time is it India? Let's
see um
it India is like um
14 14.5
hours faster, something 15.5 I think.
Wait, uh or was it 14? But anyway, so
let's see.
Let me see. India is around 8:00 um
Let's see. June
8:00 in the morning. 8:00 in the
morning. Am I correct? Close, 7:15.
Fantastic.
Okay, so we going to do this we going to
code this uh JavaScript. JavaScript and
the browser object model called DOM.
Okay. But first of all, let me show you
what what what
it is. Okay, but before that, let's have
a drink.
So again, this is Erguotou. It's Chinese
drink. It's um somewhat known as Chinese
vodka.
Now vodka, every everyone understand
it's Russian thing. It's a pure
distilled spirit.
Uh by the way, you can read about it
today. You can ask AI what is vodka? How
is it made? You know, it's fascinating.
It's actually the history of alcohol.
And the science of alcohol and the
biology and the
um
nutritional science of alcohol.
Fascinating. Okay, because when you talk
about alcohol, you know, like what what
is it chemically?
You know, you can study.
Like we can well, I can start to digress
and we going to ask AI, you know, what
is alcohol ethanol, you know, chemistry.
Then you got um your history of alcohol,
which is very rich history of human
animals, you know, in different regions.
You got vodka, you got gin, you got
spirits. What what does it mean? You got
beer, of course. You got wine, red wine
red wine
white wine of grapes usually, but other
fruits. You got fermentation
fermentation
um which is a chemical process and what
does it mean? You know, you got
distillation
uh which is a way to make concentrated
alcohol called spirits. Okay. Because
how do I know? Because I read
I read up a little bit. I asked AI.
Fascinating.
So you got you you know, you see you got
the chemistry aspect of alcohol.
Chemistry, like what what molecules
are are they?
Uh you got the um
human history of making alcohol. And
then you got the um effect of alcohol on
animals. Okay. How it interact with your
nervous system. Why does it work? You
know. Why does it Why you get drunk?
What is the effect exactly? It makes you
stupid and
and and happy basically.
Okay.
That's what I'm doing. It numbs your
brain. It incapacitates
your
uh ability to analyze and your ability
to feel pain.
It is also
one one of the effect. Okay.
Listening to you while making breakfast.
Oh. What does Indians eat breakfast?
You know, I I know I learned, you know,
India is a big country, huge.
And India is interesting in the sense
that for for example, um in the past few
years in USA India became
or Indians became very popular in poli-
politics.
So what what are you cooking in uh
breakfast in India?
And also what what what region of India
are you in? Like north or south?
Because I learned in the past few years
you know, there's some quite quite big
differences.
Um
I'll just coffee and toast. Okay.
So India in the past few years became
very politically
um
popular in USA.
For several reasons. One is because the
H1B visa, you know, the Indian
immigration. Because the USA got [ __ ]
up severely for and also Europe by
immigration by
kind of like
racial issue. Okay, like anyway, I'm
drunk so I don't want
>> [laughter]
>> So I cannot talk logically.
Anyway, so so there's immigration, huge
issue. Like and then Indian
they imported Indians, you know, by the
H1B visa or whatever
for technology, you know,
because
well, apparently
it is true
that hiring Indians is very cheap. You
know, let me let me tell you why. Okay.
So anyway, wait
actually we we we are supposed to code
this, but let me tell you
Let me tell you the story anyway since
we got Indian watchers.
Yes, there are many Indian.
You see? So India So uh southern India
from Bengaluru. Oh, that's the center of
technology of India because I just
looked up recently.
You know, I was wondering what city
in India
uh that has the most more most people
who knows programming, you know, which
city in India has the most coders? And
that is
Bengaluru
uh
Bengaluru. Okay. It is also known as
Bangalore, I think.
Bengaluru. So that is actually the city
with the most programmers in India.
Which is
in USA the most the city with the most
programmers is basically so-called
Silicon Silicon Valley, which is
basically
South San Francisco Bay Area, which is
where I am.
Where I am, you know, where Google,
Apple,
um
PayPal all originated here, HP,
Hewlett-Packard,
and bunch of others, you know, like the
whole internet, eBay,
uh Yahoo is also here, you know, like
almost almost all the
uh web the the the biggest web
corporations, okay?
So, anyway, so so I was saying, yeah, so
India so India became very politically
um
discussed topic in USA in the past 4
years
because of the massive immigration
illegal in immigration the Biden
the USA president former USA president
president imported like I I I believe
was 10 million.
Okay, so they just imported illegally
and a lot of them are actual criminals,
okay? Like
who are
who like murdered people or wanted you
know or thieves, you know, from other
countries, you know.
Usually, you know, not white people
typically.
But that Indian is kind of they are like
but Indian apart from, you know, massive
immigration of these illegal people and
also from
Arab countries, you know, in into
Europe. So, what they say is that Europe
got invaded So, the white man
what the white man
says is that they got [ __ ] you know,
by themselves
by the white [ __ ] themselves by the
white people such as Biden.
And there's another sub class let's not
mention it now, okay? Anyway, so this
this massive immigration
is a big issue in USA
in the past 4 years, but also in
in the past 10 years in Europe,
especially
United Kingdom,
France and Germany.
Okay, especially these countries massive
immigration of non-white people imported
into their countries by the white man
[ __ ] themselves.
Okay, by their leaders such as Biden or
in in in France and Germany or UK by
their
respect respective, you know, white
typical like like almost all the time
white people, okay?
So, the white people are [ __ ]
themselves up. The white scums, okay?
So, that's one thing, big immigration.
Now, what about Indians? So, the Indian
you know, Indian is um
in as far as USA is concerned, they are,
you know, Indian they got
you know, by by by chance, you know,
Indian is [ __ ] by you by the Brit Brit
British people by the Brits.
The white [ __ ] the British people.
Indian by [ __ ] in the ass by the
Brits, okay? For like in the past um
100 years.
So,
I'm mentioning that because that that is
why India today speaks English.
English is their official language
for the Indians. They are about 1
billion of them.
So, the most popular
the most
the country with the most people today
or the most bloodline are Chinese and
India, okay? Each each has about
1.something billion people.
Okay, so we got the most people.
So, India happens to speak English. It's
that's their official language. Why?
Because the Brits
you know, conquered them runs them, you
know, India Indians are the slaves of
the British white [ __ ]
So, India Indians been [ __ ] by the
Brit very much, okay?
Now, it is official, you know, it is
official language, but I
yeah, okay, you get my point, but I
it's, you know, we can we can look up
Wikipedia. It is I believe, you know,
I'm pretty sure actually I could be
wrong, but because you are Indian, you
probably know better, but I'm like 100%
sure it because I looked up. It is one
of the
Okay, so maybe it's not official
language, but it
like it's in practice it is like the
you know, English is the language for
India for anyone who is educated, okay?
So, so it's kind of odd. So, in So, in
India you have, you know, they speak
English and and okay, so then then they
um
So, India So, what I'm trying to say,
you know, let me get to the point. So,
India happens to So, there's a lot
programmers.
You know, so USA started to hire a lot
Indian. Why? Because they are cheap.
Instead of the white man.
Because when you hire Indian
programmers, you know, maybe JavaScript,
Python. Indian programmers,
you know, from my experience actually I
worked with them since like year 2000.
Like
like half
most of my co-workers are from India. At
that time I don't know anything about
politics, okay?
So, anyway, so so Indian programmers
they be they they they there's a lot
huge amount of Indian programmers in
USA, especially here in Silicon Valley.
And also Indian
they became the head of Google
and Microsoft
and
Adobe and quite a lot and then
was it also IBM? I forgot, but Indian
became,
you know, the the corporate corporation
leaders of the major the biggest big
tech in USA including
um
uh including
yeah, Google, Microsoft that's big
enough that's a biggest empire in whole
human history like Google and Microsoft
and and lots of others, okay? So, Indian
they they they became
the CEO of the biggest
USA corporations. But anyway, let me let
me
get back to what I was going to say. So,
Indian
programmers they became there's a lot
Indian programmers and they are cheap.
Why these corporations as also Elon
Musk, you know, Elon Musk running X and
SpaceX and Tesla, you know, why do they
hire Indians? Because Indians are cheap.
You know, it's like you pay
half the half of the pay or even less
more
you know, much actually less than half
instead of the white people. Because if
you hire a white man, oh my god, Jesus.
The white guy is going to complain. It's
going to demand vacation. He's going to
demand rights this and right this and
that because white man, you know, the
white [ __ ]
they are like superior. They you know,
they have rights, you know, they have
lots of rights. They have lots of power.
Okay? So, [snorts] they want this that,
you know, human rights or female women's
rights, feminism and so on and on. And
vacation. If you do something wrong,
they're going to sue you.
The white [ __ ] okay? In USA.
But Indians don't they don't do that.
Obviously, because they, you know, if
they can come to USA to work, you know,
as a programmers or whatever, they are
very lucky. They they [ __ ] crave
you know, they they they can't hope
anything more. You know, it's like
heaven.
Because in USA they get paid
10 times more than what you can get paid
for in India.
Okay? So, whoever Indian when they come
to USA to go to to work in a corporation
in coding or whatever,
they are very happy. They are quiet.
They don't complain.
You know, you got to do some something
to do, they just do it, you know, they
don't complain. They just work.
And that is also my experience of of the
Indians I know.
Cheers.
So, that is why these corporations,
Google, Microsoft or whatever others,
and Oracle Oracle, my god, Jesus. Oracle
I I realized that's another very evil
corporation.
Anyway, they hire Indians because
Indians are cheap and obedient. That's
the thing. That's another
uh observation I want to make, okay?
>> [snorts]
>> Because Indians are
turns out Indian people they are
obedient to
they obey
the white, you know, the
evil [ __ ]
That is why they climb they climb the
ladder. They became the head of
Microsoft CEO, the head of Google.
They are all Indian and other
corporations, okay? This is my personal
opinion.
Do they, you know, it's like it's very
rare and almost you never see seeing it
that Indian programmers they make like
they make up some noise or revolution or
they demand they create a new theory or
they say, you know, we going to start a
new methodology or whatever. You almost
never hear that.
Okay, Indian
programmers
even the head of Google, you know, they
they are almost like oh just quiet. They
just
go along with whatever
the white fox have set up, you know,
created. They just go along.
They never start to create a their own
theory and you know, say saying that oh
we need to do this from now on. They
never do that. They obey.
So that's what
that is my personal
observation, okay?
Uh I don't know if you I hope you guys
are not offended, okay? I'm just telling
you my opinions, my observations. So so
the Indians they
you know
you know, they they they they they get
promoted promoted, you know, in USA so
they became the head, you know, CEO of
Google Microsoft and elsewhere.
Cheers.
So even today so that, you know, because
of the immigration and white men got
[ __ ] in the ass so bad. Uh it's fairly
complex, okay? We are talking about
politics in the past 5 years.
Okay, you disagree. Okay, you have to
tell me what's your opinion, you know,
you you got to say because I don't know
what is your opinion.
Uh you know, try to
you know, type up what's what's your
opinion.
But you see so so in the so because of
the immigration because of white white
people they got [ __ ] in the past 10
years
by white people themselves and by
another people also known as white
people but they are actually
they don't I you know, I they identify
as something else which is today doing
the war in Iran, okay?
So they you know, there's quite they
they got quite [ __ ] okay?
So the white people because, you know,
the white people they
the Christianity they got stamped on.
They got, you know,
and they also got [ __ ] by the
Black Lives Matters, okay?
>> [laughter]
>> But basically the white men got [ __ ]
by themselves by white people, okay?
And and and the other
group.
So um
So I feel some sympathy, you know,
especially doing the social justice
warrior eras which is from 2016
to about um
to about 2000
24. What like about 10 years social
justice warrior era. That's when the
white people got trashed
but most importantly by white people
themselves such as Biden
Hillary Clinton
and lots of others and and the certain
group
which today are doing the Iran war,
okay? I
you know, I don't want to mention the
group's name.
So the so the so you know, so
uh
Yeah, anyway so, you know, so huge
amount of immigration and uh
Okay, I'm I think I'm drunk. Um
maybe I talked too much
>> [laughter]
>> about random things.
Okay.
Uh
This is now officially a politics
stream. Yeah, okay. So
um
So kebab donor
I'm not a says I'm not offended but my
counter argument is illegal to talk
about in most country states on the on
this platform.
Where is Oracle headquarters?
Head
Okay, um
Oracle is headquartered right here,
Silicon Valley. Uh
San Francisco Bay Area, okay? So you if
you don't know Oracle for example, you
can search for it. Every time you go to
San Francisco
for example, I drive to San Francisco.
Okay.
You guys don't know but let me show you
the map, okay? Oracle head work Okay, so
let me show you the map. Should we go to
Google? Okay.
Google Earth. Let's go to Google Earth.
Uh let me show you guys the map. Let's
do just random chat, okay? So today's
topic is like Indian and politics, okay?
So you need to turn on
JavaScript so Google knows where you
are.
[ __ ] Google.
Okay, there's
a bit more to go.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> Okay, so what whatever that Google Plus
So there we have it. Google Earth
file and manage find and manage all your
project in Google Earth. Dismiss the
[ __ ] Jesus, another tip dismiss the
[ __ ]
So we are looking at Earth
which may be uh
going away.
Okay, so you want to So yeah, let's go
to USA, United States of America. So
that's, you know, that's here.
So let's magnify. So get rid of the
clouds and there you see. So there
is USA. And I'm am in California
here, okay?
And I'm in the San Francisco Bay Area.
So let me let's magnify. So magnify So
by the way, this is this part is called
West Coast.
On the other hand, New York and stuff
that's called East
Coast.
So, you know,
New York Washington that's East Coast,
okay? And California
that's West Coast, okay? And Oregon.
Okay? And above above USA is Canada.
The most populous countries are Montreal
here which is mostly [snorts] Quebecois.
Half of them speaks French, okay? I
lived there for half for 3 years during
the about 1986.
I lived there when I was a teen
in Montreal.
Okay, then you you got Toronto which is
very populous uh
city, lots of Chinese there and also in
Montreal. But anyway, you got Chinese in
lots of places.
Then you got Vancouver which is another
uh
big city, lots of people, okay? So
anyway, Canada Canada is very cold,
okay?
Anyway, so that's Canada, okay? Above
USA. Then let's go to San Francisco
area. So you magnify that's part of
California.
Magnify magnify magnify magnify magnify
so you can see kind of this this
uh
half island, okay?
That's called San Francisco South Bay,
okay? You can see this area.
San Francisco South Bay. This is This is
called Bay Area, San Francisco South Bay
Area, okay?
Then Okay, so what is Silicon Valley?
Silicon Valley is basically this area,
San Francisco South Bay.
And the center is more like here, okay?
So you got Mountain View, Palo Alto, San
Jose. This Mountain View is basically
the center
so-called Silicon Valley.
Okay.
So if you guys don't know Silicon
Valley, let me spell it out. Silicon
Valley. Silicon Valley, okay? Not TV but
the location. So you go there.
So Silicon Valley is um So that's This
is where I live, okay? You got you got
Apple computers, you got Stanford
University, you got downtown San Jose,
you got HP
uh computers Hewlett-Packard, you got
Google Googleplex.
Okay, anyway.
So it says Silicon Valley is a region in
North California. That's correct. That
is a global center for high technology
and innovation.
Located in the South part part of San
Francisco Bay Area. It corresponds
roughly to the geographical
area of the Santa Clara Valley, okay?
The cities Sunnyvale, Mountain View,
Palo Alto and Menlo Menlo Park are
frequently cited as the birthplace of
Silicon Valley, okay?
That's Wikipedia description.
Now, let's go back, okay?
So that's what I'm telling you guys,
okay? San Francisco, uh
you see San Francisco, okay? So, let's
go back so you can see this
USA on the west side, California
state and San Francisco.
Now, Los Angeles is in the at the
bottom, okay? So, you will see Los
Angeles is there.
Okay. But, we are talking about San
Francisco.
San Francisco
and then you magnify, you can see this
kind of
this kind of like hook or bay. That's
called Bay Area, South Bay Area, okay?
Then you magnify, then you start to see
Mountain View,
Palo Alto,
San Jose, a big city. So, this and
Redwood City. So, this area here
is Silicon Valley.
That is basically the center.
Historically, it is the center of
innovation of all computer the biggest
computing technology, okay?
Computers, uh Cray computing, you know,
anyway, that's So,
Google is right here. So, Google is like
where I live. Google Google
for example, we can go to Google. Google
Uh Google is right here, okay? This is
Google. This is You see Google visitor.
Google visitor experience, okay? This
This This place is called Googleplex. Uh
where is that?
Anyway, this area is Google, not I mean,
Google is so huge. In fact, you know,
Google's got buildings all over the
place, so it's not just this.
Like Google is just I mean, this is like
officially the Google
headquarters. Actually, the is here.
Okay, it's called Googleplex.
Googleplex.
Uh do they actually say
um
So, are you guys with me?
Is this
talk interesting?
Oh, okay. So, please teach us some
JavaScript. Okay, so maybe we should go
back to coding.
Uh well, okay, but well, but uh
Okay, so but Okay.
I'm not sure what to do. Okay, so
you know, I actually So, today we are
supposed to code this
um
Yeah, I wanted to code
actually I we I I haven't actually
started to tell you what guys
>> [laughter]
>> I'm half drunk, okay?
I have not
begin to tell you guys what is the
coding problem. You you see
um
But, I can do that. Anyway, so we were
talking about India and stuff.
By show, uh what is that? What do you
mean by show?
By show, okay. So, maybe you mean by
show the
the white lefties, okay?
Um
Anyway, so
it's
uh maybe let's uh kind of
for continuity's sake, let's just finish
what I was talking about, okay? So,
[snorts] here's Google.
Um
I mean, they should show the Googleplex.
I mean, there there should be a like
a name popping up. This is Googleplex,
okay? I believe that's there.
Anyway, that's the Google headquarters,
okay? Google headquarters is here.
Um I don't know why they don't they
don't have a like a title. And any
anyway, this Computer History Museum
that was uh
that was the building for SGI. But, SGI
got
uh bankrupt
10 years ago, SGI, okay?
Uh okay, so you guys don't know.
Uh let's go to study
the info.
SGI is Silicon Graphics computer is one
of the most popular
computer
like 20 years ago, Silicon Graphics,
okay? This is their logo. I went there,
this is you know, this is like So, this
photo is taken in 2005.
And this location is
10 minutes
it's uh
30 minutes if I walk there, walk by
walk. 30 minutes, so that would be like
2 km
from where I live, okay? So, this
computer is Silicon Graphics is the most
popular like
you know, the one of the most
influential
computer corporation for 20 years, okay?
But, it's dead
beginning in 2005, okay?
Anyway,
uh so anyway, so what are we talking
about? So, we started to like um
Yeah, oh okay. So, we were talking about
this um
Computer History Museum.
So, if you came from another country
to California
to Silicon
Valley, you might
have
heard of this Computer History Museum.
This building
was Silicon Graphics, SGI.
Then after Silicon Graphics died, you
know, bankrupt, then it they changed the
building became Computer History Museum.
So, you see lots of history of
you know, computers.
Uh so anyway, so So, anyway, so this
area is Silicon Valley, okay? For
example, Apple
Apple is right here, okay? So, can you
actually see it? Cupertino there it is.
De Anza College I went there I went
there like 30 years ago. Cupertino, uh
Anyway, so
Apple computer is right here, okay? So,
you can see the there, you see? This UFO
building, you see?
That's Apple computer.
Um
You got a title somewhere, Apple Park,
you can see.
Anyway, this is Apple's
building.
This building was
uh
was kind of the what what is what Steve
Jobs created. But, before that, Apple
computer is like uh above a little bit
below, okay? Apple The original Apple
computer building
is a bit below this UFO
center. It's above It's uh it's like
somewhere down here, okay? So,
Anyway, I don't know if this uh is
interesting to you guys, but anyway, so
you are looking at
This is Silicon Valley, okay? Google,
PayPal,
you know, all the like
uh Yahoo, all the big companies is here.
Okay.
So, anyway, so let's see what else. Uh
okay, so nobody is here. Um
Do I stop this
uh live stream or do I uh start to code?
Let's see.
So, in this live stream, what I want to
do is that you got this Unicode.
Okay, I think I'm drunk.
Uh
So, we got
Okay, so I think I'm drunk. So, you got
um
You see So, okay, so let me let me let
me show you guys what I'm I want to do,
okay? So, you got this Unicode page.
You know, this page allows you to see
all Unicode you possibly ever want to
know, okay?
Let me show you a few hands
and gestures,
okay? Gestures,
hands, Unicode hands, and
this This gesture is the most popular by
girls.
>> [laughter]
>> A heart symbol, you know, [ __ ] idiots
are girls.
And you got food, you got food, you got
pizza, you got hamburgers, you got hot
dog, hamburgers, toast,
uh flat bread, Indian Indian, you know,
Indians got this
pita. Do they call it pita? I believe
so.
Then you got also, you know,
you know, bread, you got
French baguette,
croissant, French you bagels. Bagels I
believe Jewish.
Uh well,
you know, anyway, so pizza is like
Italian or something.
Hot dog, American. This is like
represents USA and french fries.
Even though it's like named French, but
it's actually kind of American thing.
And hamburgers, of course. Then
anyway, so
Unicode love symbols. Oh my god, hot
as
tits and ass as in [ __ ] and penis.
Okay.
Okay, so
So this is Unicode my page, okay?
solid.info Unicode.
So what I want to do is that, you know,
you go to So there's lots of emojis, but
besides emojis, you got
uh you got the words or right all the
words writing systems, okay? So on this
page, you can click show name. So click
on that this user interface JavaScript.
Show name.
So each character So let me let me try
again, okay? So you can see let me close
it. So show name
toggle no name Now show name. No name.
Show name. No name. You see? So you can
see
you can
make the page show all the characters
name.
For example, this character heavy large
circle.
Now this circle is
Asian in Basically, it's Chinese symbol
that means good.
That means good or perfect or pass.
Okay, for example, you can see this
cross and circle symbol
on your
Sony PlayStation
controller or Nintendo, you know, the
you know, the Japanese
uh game
controllers. You can see these symbols.
And Japanese use symbol use this
symbols, especially the cross, the
circle
for anything meaning like good
or pass
instead of fail, okay? It's the opposite
of fail.
Circle means perfect, good, or pass.
Okay.
So Japanese use this circle, which came
from Chinese
because Chinese that's what, you know,
that's what the circle means in Chinese,
okay?
Kind of cultural meaning.
But but in the West, you don't use
circle, of course. In the West, usually
it's cross or like a check mark. In
Asia, you don't use check mark. There's
no check mark
in Far East, okay?
So anyway, so so so you got this
interface that shows the name. So you
can So then you can, you know, you for
each Unicode character, you can see
the full name of the character, which is
critical. Okay.
So you got hyphen, you got hyphen minus,
you got hyphen, you got nonbreaking
hyphen, which is that character. Then
you got um
en dash en
dash Then you got figure dash.
Then you got em
dash. Then you got horizontal bar. You
see?
Kind of tricky, you see? Then you got
low line. That's You see
So that's when you need So because in
Unicode, lots of characters, they look
similar.
But they are actually different
uh [snorts] for different purposes, you
see?
Hyphen minus.
Hyphen.
Nonbreaking hyphen.
en
dash
en as nanny.
Figure dash. Then em dash m as mommy or
mountain.
Then you got horizontal bar, which is
even longer.
Then you got a wavy low line, and you
got low line. Then you got tilde. Then
you got wave dash. Then you got
Okay, horizontal ellipsis
and middle dot, you know? So you got
lots of these
Unicode characters.
Okay, so you can show name.
And you can change, you know, you can
click this to show symbols only or like
symbol versus emoji. Can you see that?
Emoji font. So now they are shown as
emoji or you can make it shown as
symbols, okay? Because Unicode
for certain characters in Unicode, they
have both a emoji version and a symbol
version, okay?
Then Okay, once you do that, then you
also have a choices of using Google's
font. So let me go here.
Where So if you go to the emoji faces,
then you can see
the differences of using Google font
or Microsoft font. Can you see that? Can
you see?
Let me remove that. Google font
for emoji faces.
Microsoft font.
Or you can pick Apple font, but Apple
font doesn't work because on Windows
machine
you don't have Apple, you know, Apple's
font is not available.
Okay? So anyway, so you can see Let's
check. Google's font
for emoji faces or
Microsoft's font
for emoji faces, okay?
So what I'm doing here is showing you
this user interface bar that has this
kind of features, okay? So for example,
you can
show them as emoji or show them as as
symbols
using symbols characters. So many
characters become like so-called
symbols, okay?
Now
this apply to applies to lots of emojis.
For example, you know, like Unicode's
got
10,000 characters or something.
So you can show lots of these symbols.
They are available as emoji, but also as
symbols. You see?
You see?
And also, by the way, they are different
symbol fonts. There's symbol font from
Apple and there's symbol font from
Microsoft
for Windows and there's also symbols
font for um
from Google.
Okay, so if depending on what font you
are using, they will look different,
okay?
So anyway, so that's
my introduction of this this this user
interface bar, okay?
Um and you can see it here. So copy it.
So go to the code. So
open it.
So can you see the user interface bar?
Where is it?
There it is. That's this line, okay? So
this line div class that class and then
pick font this
So this this is called
you know, this this user interface bar,
I name it pick font, okay?
Then
there is the JavaScript. Here's the
JavaScript code. So if you open the
JavaScript, open it.
It's
you know, I
I wrote it as TypeScript, which compiles
to JavaScript, okay? So open the
TypeScript. So you can see here's the
code. So this TypeScript, which is about
100 lines only.
This TypeScript will generate It
actually generates this HTML bar, okay?
So now you can see it by inspect.
Right click and inspect
uh in a browser. So you can see
um
So you can see this this this is
actually generated code, okay? This
entire
uh
div
uh actually actually here. So from, you
know, this this part is all generated.
Basically, it generates this this line.
Okay, then you can like
you know, you can do all these changes,
okay?
Does that make sense?
Am I like going too slow? Does that make
sense?
Diego
em What are you saying? I don't know
what you saying.
Okay, so I maybe I should stop now. Um
So what I want to do is that, you see
uh
Okay, let me tell you what I want to do.
So shift control I to show this. Then
you want to show this You want to show
this page
in a mobile phone
way. So you can see
So this is how you
debug or develop on your mobile phone.
So in a browser, I'm right now on
desktop, but you can however show
what the page looks like on a mobile
phone. For example, iPhone or
Galaxy Note
uh from or iPad from let's see let's say
iPhone SE, you know, anyway, so you can
show
how the page looks like on iPhone, okay?
So, my issue my problem is that you see
on this page on a phone, you know, you
scroll down scroll down and then
but suppose you want to show them, you
know, you want to show them a symbols.
But the the user interface bar is
already, you know, you have to go to the
top first, then you click, you know,
that
then you go back to see, you know, for
example, you want to see what this
battery
uh power symbol low battery looks like
when it's symbols font or when it's
using Apple's font or using Microsoft
font.
You can't click here, you know, you have
to go to the all the way to the top.
Then you okay, then
dismiss that then you have have to say,
okay, I want to see emoji, then go back
to check.
Okay, it's looks like that and that
change, you see.
Then go back to the top of the page and
see symbols again, then go down
and you can see the symbols, so you see
that
battery page changed.
So, it's tedious, okay? Because this UI
interface is not available. You have to
scroll.
So, what I want to do is to make this
make it make it float, so you can have a
button that says
something like float, you know,
like or when you auto when you scroll,
it automatically become a little icon on
the side. So, when you click on that
icon, it expands. So, you don't have to
like scroll all the way up and to see,
you know, changes.
Do I make sense? Okay.
I don't think anyone is watching this.
Um
you know, my uh yeah, okay, so let me um
So, that's the easy the code. That's
That is what what we want to do. Um and
uh we can start to code that, but I
think
I'm going to quit, okay?
Close that.
Showing browser. Okay, so he's
um so I become web dev. Becoming web
dev, what you talking about? I'm a web
dev since like
since like 25 years ago. I'm a
professional web dev since
1998.
1997 actually. That is actually my
besides Wolfram language
which is scientific programming,
mathematical scientific programming.
My first job actually my first
professional job is web dev since 1998.
We do, you know, we we were the in the
um
we I write
uh I I write e-commerce software like
Amazon, you know, Amazon which is a huge
e-commerce
server, that's what I wrote.
Uh anyway
So, anyway, so I was going to, you know,
we going to write this little code, but
I think I already talked on random [ __ ]
for 1 hour, so
uh and plus my web is back, so maybe
stop
or
I take a break and actually work on
this.
Uh what do you guys say?
You know, I've I've have been so
unfocused in the past weeks that
I would say philosopher and
mathematician. Yeah.
I'm a philosopher sure for sure, but
philosopher is cheap.
Because philosopher being a philosopher
is not really a good thing because, you
know,
because philosophy the topic is like
anyone can claim to be a philosopher.
Like it's like
So, what I'm saying is that the
qualification
the value I mean the the the critical
judge of
truly good philosopher
is
not very clear. It's not very precise.
Okay, that's what I'm saying. You see
the value of mathematician is very crisp
crisp and precise
almost throughout humanity.
You know, if you are a mathematician
and if you are widely
considered, you know, accepted as a
mathematician you know that that you do
have value. You have significant and
value to society to human animal
society.
Your value to society is highly
recognized.
You know, if you are a mathematician.
Okay.
Similarly, if you are a let's say
but less, but you know, if you are a
physicist or chemist or in general a
scientist like a hardcore scientist or
even engineer or programmer
you know, if you are, you know, truly a
programmer or engineer or scientist,
your value to society is
is certain, okay? It's it's fairly like
certain.
Now, but but but if you if you
you know, if you claim to be a
philosopher
then
then you you kind of then then your
value to society is kind of
questionable.
Why? Because first of all a lot of
people can claim to be philosopher,
especially like today when the society
is very corrupted like USA.
You know, you you you you you can have
random Joe who is like deep state [ __ ]
face, you know, they are just like
trying to brainwash you. They don't
actually know anything solid.
You know, they they can claim
Oh, by the way, I'm a philosopher, you
know, I'm a 21st century, you know, I'm
a postmodernist.
Like lots of like these scammers
exist today.
In USA in academia, they are promoted by
the deep state king and queens, you
know, they they they want to do wars and
stuff, okay? So, this this this people
or or feminist or a transgender
philosopher, you know, we have lots of
that in past 10 years.
You know, they tell you, you know, I'm a
philosopher. I study, you know, I I I
I'm a expert of gender issues on of
human history. You know, they they're
going to tell you, oh, gender is a
construct, you know. So, so what I'm
saying is that there's
lots of these like actually they they
are not really philosophers. They are
just like
In other words, what I'm saying is that
philosophy the the topic of philosophy
can be
can be made up, okay?
And you can't be sure because this is
this is philosophy is different from
computer science or any hardcore
sciences or engineering or mathematics.
You cannot
you know, you cannot just make [ __ ]
If you make up [ __ ]
it's useless.
But
philosophy is very different.
In philosophy, you can actually create
like [ __ ] totally useless or even
destructive
such as such kind of like capitalism,
communism and related, okay? Or
anarchist or whatever.
You you can kind of you can kind of make
up [ __ ] or Hegel and whatever Hegel
[ __ ]
Or pass, you know, there's there's
there's a lot, you know, I can go into
it in detail. Phenomenon phenomenology
you know, or uh Bible stuff, you know,
theology.
You know, so in philosophy in the realm
of philosophy, you can easily almost
trivially
or Scientology, by the way, there's also
Scientology. You can almost trivially
create a
useless even destructive [ __ ]
and became popular and, you know, so
it's it's kind of like a scam or sham,
okay?
That's philosophy.
So, in the realm of of philosophy, you
you know, it's not um
something that
whose value is
readily acknowledged by society.
Uh
So
So, what I was saying, so philosopher
and mathematician, yeah, so
So, me
I'm a philosopher, kind of.
Uh but I actually mostly I'm mostly a
programmer, you could say.
Of my life's work, I'm mostly
you know, it's it's it's um
you would consider me a programmer.
That is more solid because I have like
thousands of programming tutorial pages
and
code
I have produced.
Meanwhile, as a philosopher, well,
that's kind of a true of me.
Um
but it's not, you know, I I haven't like
published, you know, particularly in
philosophy and stuff.
Even though I consider myself kind of
like a philosopher.
Okay, and and as a mathematician title
for me,
uh that
Well, I mostly amateur mathematician,
you could say that.
Uh due to my publication on math
education.
Okay.
Educational
math materials.
Uh as you know, I've talked about that a
lot.
My website is most famous for
mathematics for
15 years. The most like the most the top
100 most popular websites on mathematics
for about from 1997 to 2010
or 2015.
Okay. So, for 15 years, my my uh
websites, especially this one, Visual
Dictionary of Special Plane Curves, and
uh and this especially this one,
Discontinuous Groups of Rotation and
Translation in the Plane, that's most
cited, okay, in in
in publications, in academic journals,
okay,
and on websites.
So,
as far as calling me a mathematician,
that kind of works, but I'm mostly
amateur. Okay.
So,
uh so, I structured yet chaotic, that is
kind of true.
Okay, so, maybe last question. Do you
think beauty will be the solution?
Beauty can be a religious experience
where beauty is grounded in math, fabric
of our surroundings. Yes.
Uh without diving into detail, yes,
beauty is absolutely
the uh
uh kind of one of the answer for
humanity, beauty. So, let me talk about
that. Okay, so, actually I agree with
that. Beauty is a So, you were saying,
can beauty be a religious experience?
Okay.
Uh I don't know about religious
experience. Yes, I think so, but
actually, the way I think of beauty, I
think the beauty is actually the
kind of the kind of beauty is the
goal
of human animals.
Why are we here?
We are here
you know, the question of why are we
here,
there are lots of answers you can find.
You know, different philosophers or
different historical figures, such as
politicians, such as Chiang Kai-shek or
other, you know, big politicians, they
will tell you, you know, they have
different stories to tell.
They will tell you different answers
about
what is the purpose of
human animals.
But
what I would tell you is that the
purpose of
human animals is basically
for the beauty of it. Okay.
>> [snorts]
>> Uh and beauty, so, what is beauty? Uh
beauty is one of the major branch of
philosophy.
So, there's no one single answer.
But beauty is the um
um
Beauty is basically
in my view is the
procreation, okay? In other words,
beauty is mostly
the fundamental basis of beauty is
procreation. That means you [ __ ] and you
make children.
You replicate
or multiply
ourselves.
That is the basis of beauty.
And which in turn, beauty means
beauty spur from girls, okay? Female
young girls. That is kind of the
foundation of
uh beauty, but but
but
but not in all aspects because
um because, for example, you have
mathematical beauty. Now, mathemat-
mathematical beauty, the you know, the
beauty of mathe- mathematical theories,
they are
I think it's very difficult to tie it to
girls and sex.
Um
yeah, I haven't thought about that, but
it's it's it's hard I think it's hard to
tie
mathematical beauty, the abstract
beauty, to
girls.
But what I'm think what you know, what I
have been thinking is that beauty is
essentially
about procreation, okay? About
replicating or multiplication of
ourselves.
I think that is the
basis of beauty. Okay, anyway, so, that
relates to your topic.
So, I think the human, you know, what
what is the purpose
of us here on Earth, I you know, so, the
answer is beauty to
create
and uh perpetuate
what we see as beauty.
That is the
purpose of humanity, okay? It's kind of,
you know, my take.
Okay, I think that's it.
Uh
Yeah, so, we talked today for
an hour and 14 minutes.
Okay. Bye, guys. Bye, guys.