test Tesla hello guys welcome to another
show of s talk show today we are going
to do random so you direct the topic say
what you want to ask me questions and
I'll talk about it okay uh and uh
otherwise if nobody say anything I'm
just going to start to do my things
covering my latest blogs I have like 10
blogs Wan language emac this coding or
programming languages in general or uh
web you know web CSS web coding web dev
or politics so you got to say what you
want to ask me questions okay if you are
watching this offline skip around and
play at
1.5 speed and donate okay you pay me pay
to get what you want pay to direct the
society you want okay we got some
questions so
um so let's see timer is from Los Ang
anges hello uh ta wants to talk about
keyboards uh tatim says I'm thinking of
getting a new keyboard I have digma defi
love it but there is a new keyboard NAA
it looks good with attachments okay so I
can give you some opinions about that uh
I don't know digma so so my opinion is
not very good okay uh Diego kasas says
seems like a Spanish name can you talk
about your web browser extension setup
okay so let me just talk about those two
questions but meanwhile today is Sunday
let's have a drink okay now I'm not a
drinker but I got this from somewhere
from a from a friend I guess or some I
don't know where but what is this
whiskey so let's try Canadian whiskey
Crown Royale Crown Royale Canadian
whiskey so let's try that and I got a
Coke from some recommendation from
online so let's P let's
see so I I don't drink usually I don't I
don't even drink every day but now I can
afford some drinks so someone
recommended this so you gotta get this D
Julio you know whatever whatever uh
Reposado tequila so so I ask him and he
says I need a picture because I don't
know which which is brand which is the
type whatever so he showed me this so we
got it 30 something dollars so this will
last for me you last four
month or even half a year okay but my
wife says you got some already so let's
have this whiskey
now you see the fine details the you
know you know that that when you drink
whiskey you're supposed to use the
whiskey
glass he says um the guy says the D Draw
Something rep rep rep or something you
need to use uh mix with Dr
Pepper but I I didn't see Dr Pepper in
Costco so so just
cook interesting t t
taste so let's talk about keyboards then
let's talk about my web browser
extension so while I'm drunk you can ask
me questions you can poke me actually I
don't get you
know I um I I'll get slightly you know
um Euphoria that's what drinking does
Euphoria make you stupid uh but I'm not
a heavy drinker so about keyboards so
he's saying uh question about digma okay
so let's go back
to hello Louis l long time no see L
from Switzerland I believe now I hope
this time I got it right love to see you
enjoy life yeah yeah and now I can enjoy
some
life so questions okay you need to post
questions so you um digma okay so let's
go to keyboard keyboard fantastic all
the keyboard you ever want to know
keyboard ago keyboard and this guy is
asking TAA is asking about digma
keyboard which I don't have but
Luis if I'm not mistaken Luis got it
let's
see uh no okay that's another guy uh
zet uh this guy is from Germany he got
it he got the moonlander okay well
actually Mander is not from digma okay
so this is Mander I don't have so but um
so what is the digma so do I have
it uh I don't think D
ym
dyg oh there is okay so I have a photo
of digma Ray Louis yeah so Louis got the
digma ray but he cannot get used to it
so he sold
it but this to me would be great okay so
but but I don't actually have it so I
don't have experience so but you are
saying so you want my opinions on new
models I guess digma defy and uh Na okay
let's what
what let's copy
that so close keyboard okay showing
browser there is uh digma okay
so uh
okay so let's
see so there is stigma defy you have and
uh then there is digma NAA okay so let's
look
up digma D5 okay let's open it
actually open it and also image search
Dy GM uh a okay so it's actually
supposed to be Dy
GMA okay so do I have the JavaScript on
turn it
on so digma D5 which is what you have so
digma defy got oh lots of thumb Keys 1
two 3 four five six seven eight eight
thumb keys for each hand okay so that
looks pretty good okay and it's
orthogonal linear layout so I like it
and uh can I do Ting I
suppose Ting means te your keyboard of
what yeah so there is a
picture uh so you don't have to flat
flat is no good okay so there is stigma
D5 so but you are uh you want uh check
out the new model
dimaa so
uh let's see some
photos so my analysis s my defi is
pretty good and uh then you got
digma what is
digma so
digma uh God mod that's one of the thing
one of the phrase the white men loves
obsessed with something something God
mod something something God Particle
something something
God you know you have to understand from
Asian like when you first hear it what
what's with this God God this this that
that you know Asians we don't do that we
have you know we have like our mythology
but we don't say God this or
that um you know so the god M signifies
like the ultimate you know like the
ultimate uh things so digma defy digma
raise two and uh why why choose
digma uh you are you you are us and what
so what is this
stigma
stigma is it a
picture no there's not much did you
spell it
correctly but uh it looks good with
attachment Okay so
so so maybe it's not na maybe it's not
digma let's search for
na NAA
keyboard oh okay so yeah so it's not
from digma so the N keyboard let's have
a
look okay so it looks like this uh so it
looks like one of those do it
yourself once uh
okay so my impression of this
thing is not I think
digma is better
okay let's see digma defy and uh and uh
dig digma defy yeah I think digma Defy
is
[Music]
actually better okay so so the
difference with the digma D5 is that you
got you know the thumb keys are thin
profile so the thumb Keys
uh get a better picture the the thumb
keys are low profile but the other keys
are like traditional like very thick
very uh a lot
height so that means you have to press
it down all the way so this is stigma
def5 and then the
N
[Music]
um the NAA keyboard I suppose it is a
kind of do it
yourself so here's how you tend it
interesting design novel new
design okay in fact it's quite radical
because you can see the position of
thumb Keys when you tend it the position
of thumb key is
actually so so you don't press down you
go
Inward and then you got these two huge
knobs uh and there's uh quite a few
novelty here you see this this
Thum
um can you get a bigger picture uh open
imageing a new
tab okay can you you can see
this this n
or or B you know the quity B you see
they made it into a just one key let's
see you put your hand there yeah so you
don't you no longer have the inner word
like traditionally B on a quy and n on a
quy you no longer have those keys can
you see me so so it's like this key
okay so you you know longer have the
inner keys they merg it into one um so
this is kind of more radical design uh
what is it called Nia okay NAA more
rical design and thumb Keys then you got
inward which I'm not sure you know I
don't know if that's
good and also elimination of many of the
you know the inside two column ke keys
in fact four column keys they removed it
yeah so I'm not sure about this one I'm
not sure the two big knobs knobs are
good I suppose these are
multi-functional knobs so for example
you can just rotate the wheel it'll
function as Arrow key left right arrow
or page up down I
suppose
um yeah but overall
you know if you just give me a keyboard
force me to use the keyboard I would
probably go
with with the yeah with what you have
the
digma digma D5 okay that is my
opinion okay next I guess
next cheers
no more questions okay if no more
questions I go to I'm going to do Wam
language keyboards uh okay so let me
just double
check views
19 what does this mean current viewers
jackpot okay no no questions okay so
that means I go to wolam language okay
so this's some keyboard
news uh I want to double check double
check okay so there's some keyboard news
so this famous guy uh
he he did a video review of this fancy
ergonomic keyboard so this one is
from uh what year is is
it uh it's from I forgot so let's go to
keyboard
history 1980 okay around 1980 this is
actually a Proto prototype it's actually
never mass produced so this keyboard is
TA
ergonomics ta ergonomy study that's what
it's called ta stand for Triumph Adela
okay Triumph
adeler 1041 ero study Oro economy study
okay so actually you need to get the
proper name there so anyway this guy uh
this gu guy quos quos run 22 he's a
great video uh keyboard reviewer so he
got a YouTube reviewing this keyboard
this keyboard is never mass produced
but anyway so that's uh that's kind of
news on keyboard and the other news
about keyboard is I have you know I have
over 1,000 articles on keyboards so I
kind of started to reorganize a little
bit so you can have all the groups on
touch typing so what is touch typing
touch typing typing means there's a lot
this this question can you touch
type of course if you tou touch type the
normal way yes but then there's a lot of
people who don't touch type the normal
way they use like three fingers on each
hand or something they jump over and
they will say yeah I touch type too but
not in a standard
way but actually if you can put a cover
on top of your keyboard so you you
actually don't see the keyboard and you
can walk like that for for five minutes
then whatever method you use then you
can touch type if you cannot do this
then you don't touch type okay that's a
fact uh this is kind of the fact okay
anyway touch typing there's a lot issues
you know with you know then some people
will claim uh so here is how to touch
type you know the the key to touch type
is
that is that just for each key there's a
specific finger to use for that key
that's it if you follow this method then
you touch type always you know always
use the the specific finger for specific
key now if you do not follow this then
then then whether you touch type depends
on whether you actually can work four
five minutes or longer with the cover on
the keyboard you know like most people
they claim they can touch type they
cannot actually they cannot actually do
this they have to like like every few
minutes they have to look down you know
so that's the thing about touch typing
and there's a lot Mysteries like like
myth about touch typing too some people
will claim if you learn the standard
touch type you'll get hand pen that's
also
false so there's article uh so like
thees touch typing cause repetitive
strain injury this article you know the
best way to avoid injury is not to go
pro you know that that pokes what these
people are thinking because a these
non-touch typing people they will they
will say they will claim uh touch type
is no good uh uh because if you touch
type all the all my friends who touch
type they got hand pain problems you
know which is actually true a lot of
people who has you know hand repetitive
strin injury including me has hand pain
you
know but that is like saying the best
way to avoid injury is not to go pro
because you know what happens to your
body the the the people who go goes to
hospital who has leg leg injury ankle
sprin hand injury spine injury head
injury those are professional athletes
okay if you don't want those injuries
don't do professional athlets like like
you know you don't know how to do
nothing you stay home you then you'll be
fine you see that's that's that's like
what these non-touch typers are
saying if you don't touch type then you
cannot type fast you can type like 40
minutes 40 minutes tops 50 50 words per
minute stops okay and which also implies
you don't write documentation like you
avoid it you avoid writing you know full
sentence you avoid it that's that's a
difference okay if you actually touch
type in the standard way you will find
yourself typing a lot starting you will
start to Natural type a lot chat or
whatever writing blogs or write full
documentation for programming languages
naturally and naturally when you
increase your
load you'll also be prone to injury okay
so the best way to avoid uh injury is
not to go pro don't learn touch typing
so that you naturally don't type a lot
of things you don't because you don't
you know you are too slow you know you
just like you know
two two finger method three finger
method so that's one of the myth okay
about touch
type
um and then uh there study so anyway so
I have lots of Articles okay uh I think
that that's you know I want to go back
to uh no comments okay uh I go back to
doing
mathematics okay have a drink first
so those of you watching 10 people you
got to say okay comment comment on
whatever you want me to talk
about so Nia is not digma so what type
what type of keyboard is this you
looking at my
keyboard are you looking at my keyboard
uh so you are new here in every of my
video by now I have 300 more than 300
videos so every of my video I introduce
my keyboard so this is gl80 I have a
video
reviews on YouTube this is automate
hacking keyboard I have a video review
on YouTube this is new trackable I have
a video review uh ultimate hacking
keyboard then there is this um this
fancy device this fantastic input device
okay this novel um this is
mag wrong okay this is
no this is magnetic
um uh switch okay I also have a kind of
a small introduction
review are you a hacker yes I guess you
guys are new here okay so I talk about
programming stuff okay I'm uh you know
hacker uh that depends on the meaning of
the word hacker oh there's another
question Diego says can you talk about
your web browser extension
okay uh okay so I talked about this
before uh in the past 30 years beginning
in two uh
1992 1992 is is when I started to use uh
computer every day okay just about every
day every day many hours so I've been a
nerd I'm a programmer I am into
mathematics so since about 19 95 or so I
use I always have used uh three browsers
two or three browsers sometimes four
some for some years it's full so on the
Mac you have um back then you have the
uh you know in the beginning Netscape
net Netscape browser there's Mosaic
browser that's the first in 1992 Mosaic
browser that's this is even before
internet become a thing okay then
Netscape browser a lot of you know
Netscape browser eventually became
Firefox so today you know it as Firefox
from Mozilla so before that it was
Netscape browser okay so I use Netscape
browser I also use um Internet Explorer
which began in 1997
also and this Opera browser also 1998
also was one of the best so anyway why
do I use several browsers because I'm a
pro programmer and also I'm a web Deb
professional at least back then 1998 I'm
a webdb professional so when you do web
tab you need to know the differences you
know sometimes the page works on this
browser sometimes doesn't on that
browser but today I talked about this
before in my live stream I use several
today because so for example on Firefox
which is what you see here right now
there are 12200 tabs you can see 1,200
tabs they are all of my website okay so
all these are my website uh you know my
website here is today's talk show uh
math blog uh and this is s talk show uh
to do there is mathematics uh you know
so so there are
1,200 tabs open and uh then for example
this is a uh this is about Graphics
image manipulation
where uh typically this girl this girl
is a Playboy model okay so she is one of
the most used picture in image
processing computer science articles
talking about image processing okay
because we like pretty girls um so her
name is
Lena uh of course now she's
old you know it's what What a Wonder
that's life you know how a girl when
she's young so so beautiful but you get
old every girl does so does men you know
I'm getting I'm becoming
ugly so anyway so 12,000 you know all
these Tabs are my uh website you can see
you know and you know so Firefox I used
just for web dev all these are local
files you know so for example this one
is Javascript object uh introduction to
JavaScript object so I go here emx paste
a link so you can see magnify you can
see that's a link and uh paste it again
now press a key now this becomes the sad
the.info now this is the now it becomes
the um the actual URL here is just my
local version
so all the things you you see here are
local
um you know I got tons tons tons of
stuffff which so Firefox I use for
development of my website which is
mostly
static okay and bra browser which is
fantastic which is what you see here I
used it on x.com Twitter and uh be it
requires cookies it has a um it has a
add blocker build in build into the
browser so you don't have to install ad
blocker so I
use Bray browser uh pretty much just for
x.com okay for Twitter then there is
Google Chrome I still use but I hope to
get away uh Google Chrome Chrome browser
I use for anything to do with Google for
example YouTube I need to login so what
is advantage of sver browsers because
well you can separate them because
usually you have like hundreds of tabs
right so depends on you so for me I'm a
web dev again web dev then you also you
do need several browsers you need
sometimes CSS work in one browser in one
way but not the other so you need to uh
cross check and so on and also
JavaScript okay that is why I use
several browsers
Ching thank you Tima so let me finish
the question first so
uh what about extensions okay so on
Firefox I can show you my extensions
okay uh so where do you go to show exp
uh extensions
so basically I try to avoid avoid
extensions I only use
um uh let's go to
settings uh let's
magnify uh where is the EXT extension
you know they they changed this setup
all the time
so more for Moa [ __ ] idiotic so let's
you know I use
this uh manage extension okay there so U
block or engine that's add block that's
the best you know there's a lot
confusing names like add blocker or add
block plus u block plus a lot of them
are scams so you have to be very very
careful now this one is trusted U block
or engine
okay uh so that's one I that's uh one
extension I use and I avoid like so I
have another extension I use uh there
click on
that okay Brave search okay I recommend
uh you know duplicate tabs closer I use
especially use for if you have if you
work if you dab on your um local files
because if I open again you'll close
duplicate automatically okay so let's go
back
to tabs
here okay so it automatically close
duplicate tabs very useful when you work
in emac and you know show things in
browser uh but that's about it ecosia
now I need to delete it EOS yeah is a
search engine I used to use so
remove H
what remove okay so back to extension
Brave search duplicate tab tabs
closer uh all R redirect yeah I can you
I still use side Berry or side Barry is
this uh vertical tabs I use uh very
useful uh that's it and you blocker
engine okay I try not to use use many
extensions for each one the browser
extensions I use I'm very picky they
must be open source because browser
extensions they are critical they can
they can get information whatever
website you you go to they will know
okay they will know and they'll phone
home they'll send it to you know
whatever so you need to be very very
careful about browser extensions
basically don't don't install
any but the older ones I actually
install I know they are open I actually
spend some time to look at the you know
their git uh to make sure it's safe okay
so if you go
to Windows actually I have a list of
browser extensions okay so this is
Windows Microsoft Windows tip search for
sard you'll find it then
uh okay poell fire sharing how to
keyboard shorts Cuts how to Windows
Microsoft Windows tips uh kind of
esoteric tips then there is a good
browser extensions okay so there's you
block or engine this a collection of
great uh extensions so next time I'm a
new new machine
uh I can just follow my own list you
know so you can search for good browsers
extensions. info okay U block or engine
duplicate tab browser GitHub you see I
link to GitHub so in fact I have the
GitHub cloned you know uh you can also
learn about JavaScript how to uh write a
browser extension so there is uh GitHub
old Reddit red cor why that because uh
redit like many other websites you know
they become scam like you go there kind
of like Twitter Twitter is much better
under anim musk today but for example
let me show you an example so if you
um so if I go to uh let's go to what
what what is the
um uh what is this ly okay
lady lady is a controversial guy but she
cont controversial girl but she's very
hot okay oh white girl and she's with a
who is this date night with bzang oh
Korean that's
interesting that's interesting because
the ly character she's like proide
ethnos State something like that not she
is daating a Asian
funny uh but what I want to show you is
that okay so here is a political figure
kind of political Pro Trump
influencer Insurrection Barbie That's
the name she goes by and her Twitter
name is the uh defiantly free okay she I
looked up she is one of the gener
related to G
six person I think she has been you know
put to jail for a month or
something uh so what I want to say uh
what I want to show you is that
um you know like basically when you go
to a website or this social website they
they'll show you a lot irrelevant things
you know for example you want to you
want to go to see uh for example her
then you see there it is okay so you you
know I'm following her because I'm
interested in her opinions and stuff
right oh [ __ ] you guys didn't see the
um my
uh [ __ ] how long have I been talking
without showing the
screen so yeah so I guess I guess [ __ ]
it went [ __ ] wasted 10 minutes or
something so what I want to say so
anyway so let
me
[ __ ] so anyway here is my tabs
um yeah I got I talked about a bunch of
things without showing me my
screen
so so that ecosia is a web search engine
okay I don't use anymore I use Brave so
if you want um you know search for
window
tips sad. info and then there's a page
on browser
extensions there okay so here are the
browser extensions you block or engine
duplicate tabs closer each one's got a
GitHub you can go to these are the ones
I recommend
okay uh and and uh uh GitHub old redit
redirect okay can you guys see it yeah
so so what happens is that when you go
to many of these social uh networking
website social media website for example
I follow her Insurrection Bobby okay
she's a political rightwing
figure then you you know I want to see
her what she say then then you go down
then then then boom it gives you this
irrelevant [ __ ] who to
follow why are they doing that because
they want you to follow more you know
they want you to constantly you know
post or whatever do with the platform
you know they that's what they want but
but this is not what I want I'm just
here I want I want I you know I want to
follow this person I don't want to see
irrelevant things you know who to
follow so lots of the this website reded
almost any of them okay since like 10 or
15 years ago they started to do this
[ __ ] so that's that's that's that
happened with Reddit you go to Reddit
then then like 80% of the things are
irrelevant you want to you know read
about some keyboard thing you know they
they show you irrelevant oh by the way
also check out this oh by the way also
we have this you know hot girls group
[ __ ]
them so that's why you got this old
reded redirect you know because reded
redesigned so that it gives you a bunch
of crap this automatically redirect to
the old version uh you know like that
anyway so let me finish the comments and
let's
see okay I kind
of timer $10 thank you I noticed that
you like using your pain Mouse yes what
is the reason you prefer to use the pen
Mouse is it more efficient keep the
drinks going okay good question
so so I got a review so you can see
this P Mouse is like
um so let's show you don't forget to
turn it back so you can see this is hang
H IO n okay this one of the China Cheapo
fantastic this one is $40 I bought five
years
ago uh I bought it or did they send it
to me I think I I think I bought
it uh I don't remember but I have a
review on my website yet like um so why
do I use it not because
well the the the the real reason I
sometimes use this is because I sitting
in front of computer too long every day
like um today you know at least for 10
years I sit in front of the computer for
like 10 hours a day so I would say I'm
on record as the most the
person who spend the most time sitting
in front of a desktop computer per day
on average for a span of 10 years okay
if you can suppose you are God and you
can have the old statistics you are
omnicient so God and God God God who is
the person who sits in the front of a
computer the most for
for a period of 10 times and the God
will say it's it's a guy known as K okay
actually I would say I would rank among
the top
10,000 in USA that's
how that's how how how how how big a
deal how serious I am so I see the the
compu in front of computers typing and
using the mouse so
so when you have hand pan because you
you if you use one device for 10 hours a
day doesn't matter how fancy how
ergonomic is device you're going to have
problems okay you're going to have
repetitive strain injury so then I
started to use the right left hand Mouse
then okay switch to track ball you know
then you know then okay then I have to
every three month I switch to something
else you know so constant problem for 10
years and then one of the solution is
the pen which is very fantastic because
then so let me show you so I can go back
here I can scroll uh but it's not it's
not a pure it's not a great pure
replacement for a mouse
because because for example I can for
example uh let me show you why okay for
example right now there's a issue
happening you see let me explain
okay so normally I use a track boo you
can see all Mouse right I have a Hoover
two click setup that means every time I
move my mouse to some window it it
automatically bring that window up to
front you see so it's supremely
convenient this is a great hand saver
saves you hand pain because pressing the
mouse button is one of the
most uh the most strenuous okay if you I
mean most for most people you sit in
front of the computer for just 1 hour a
day no problem but if you do that for um
for 10 years 5 hours day you're going to
have problem so Hoover click Hoover auto
click I have articles you can set up on
Mac on Windows on on on Linux
okay but now suppose I switch to the pen
okay you see now I Hoover to the Firefox
it doesn't come up you see now I hover
to the OBS it does come up I hover to uh
to
Chrome it doesn't come up now it does
okay you see so you got this so I back
to Firefox it doesn't come up but if I
switch to the mouse Firefox comes up you
see so this there there are issues with
the
um with the the pain input so it's not
total replacement but it's great to
change your hand habit so whenever I
have a chance I go to the pen or go to
the mouse or you know or the um track B
okay so that that is why and also one
important thing about pen is that
whenever you need to draw for example I
do mathematics so for example I can show
you so I need to explain about
mathematics then you need a pen it's
like absolutely necessary okay so let's
go back to my uh YouTube studio
so yeah so can you see it yeah so you
can see this is x axis this is the Y AIS
and we have a parabola this is uh yals
to
x² or we can have a circle uh you know
you it's required and signature
okay and you can you can write Chinese
okay okay so that's about the
pen so I think that's it uh why do you
hack why do you hack innocent people
it's hackers like you that makes
Community look back what what kind of
question is that you a
idiot uh I'm not interested in trolling
okay so if you guys are new here you
know I'm not your typical forchan idiots
doesn't that doesn't excite
me hacking has there many meanings I
talked about this so many times in the
past
have I ever created a website for a
company yes of
course that's another kind of question I
you know by just by that question I I
know you don't follow me like you are
not a TP you know this is probably your
first time seeing me live stream and you
have these dramatic questions have you
ever done you know that's that's well
that's that's kind of life okay that's
kind of the situation that that's a
problem with America with social network
and with a Zuma crowd right now because
you got all this uh brainless you know
brandless grips what what you know you
got those anyway so let me let me
explain so actually
recently someone asked me that question
this is kind of common like like s just
what have you ever done you know what
are you known for you know people want
to know know that so here is a list of
the projects I'm more most proud of okay
uh I won't go into details but uh but
you can kind of see so one of them is
credit card system and hash table back
in year 2000 I work for web order we are
the first to create a uh Web Store like
Amazon okay so it's a web store system
we sell it to Amazon or some big company
then then they can have Merchants sign
up to create a store so you got 1
million one billion merchants and each
Merchants can have inventory and you
know sell pen or mouse or whatever
clothing you know so so then they the
Amazon website then the consumers can go
there and buy things you know I I want
to shop for keyboard or Mouse whatever
okay so but the at the back is the
commercial e-commerce so-called
e-commerce
system we are the first one to write
write that okay one of the first I
suppose the
grham the guy who created you know the
Yahoo store he is first the the Paul
grham okay so that's one of the thing I
did working for a company then 1999 I
wrote a report system or in one single
file in Pearl Pearl connecting to my
SQL I write it all by myself one single
file of pearl 4,000 lines of code I I
think I still have the code somewhere if
I want to find it so that's and and
that's a BG database report like
trackers you know people can go there
file a bug you know what happens is it
in state of the BG is it closed new you
know whatever things like one fix and
things like that and math geometry
titting packages and and others and also
did I ever create a website of myself
well if youon bug report or Hoover
Institute 2005 okay I created the entire
website for this Hoover Institute of
Stanford they are associated with
Stanford University okay and I get I get
you
know this is one of the reasons sad you
know I get paid peanuts I get kind of
scammed by white people you
see you see normally when you do
contract you know you get like $100 per
hour 200 $200 per hour or more okay but
me I you know I don't know I'm not good
at talking to people negotiate but what
happens is is that the Hoover Institute
they get they get white women okay a
white woman who doesn't know any coding
but she is like then she go to online to
to pick coders for her and she pay them
like peanuts $20 an hour something I
think that that's what I get 20 maybe
27 an hour
205 okay and she told me you know when
when when this is happening this woman
by the way she passed away I learned
that she passed away she told me you
know when we started this Hoover
Institute is a big Institute okay that's
a big so-called um Think Tank okay
that's like you know when they if you
want the project of website it's going
to cost you like typically they you know
as far as I know like $100,000 you know
$100,000 for the
website but I get I get get you know
maybe
5,000 so I created the entire website
for them entire you know the that's on
Linux Apache web server mySQL database
uh and the pro code okay so I created
the entire thing according to their spec
you know they they have complicated like
they you know when a user login you need
to go through these steps each step you
have to put a check mark when it's done
you know some kind of educ ational
system for their um training education
educator training training Educators
okay 2005 I created website for Hoover
Institute and uh then you know so when
this project begin they this white woman
tells me you know you're going to go to
this interview meet basically meet up
with another
guy which is happens to be a woman a
young
woman to
to you know she is from I don't know
what exactly is her role you see I don't
know it's because they try to hide it
from me and she tells me the the the
woman who pays me she tells me you know
go there and when they ask you uh when
they ask you how much is the project and
don't say you know don't tell them since
something like that okay basically she
tells me to lie and I just lied for them
uh it's kind of sad okay it's kind of
sad because I didn't know better I
didn't know you know how to this
negotiation with other people or you
have friends you know another thing with
this situation is that usually these
people you know they get hired or
whatever or in the government they have
friends you know someone you know
someone knows someone so you get hired
for
free so I got scammed by these uh people
and uh you know I know the names I still
have the names but you know but it's you
know there's no need to go into
that anyway and uh and several other
things okay so what am I doing
okay am I
good so there's a question about
blocking JavaScript yes so in like I
said in in
[Music]
inar like actually all my all my
browsers has JavaScript off except maybe
uh
Chrome s.
info uh
s. info so this is my website uh can you
see B basically JavaScript you turn it
off because when because all the viruses
in scam the one thing most important to
them is
Javascript okay that's the most
important thing to them if you have
JavaScript off then they basically can
do nothing basically okay now nothing
they can do so JavaScript is the most
important thing if you have JavaScript
on they can do lots of things they can
know how many second you stayed in this
scroll you know during what period you
scrolled up one line they can know all
that they can know which website you
visit after another they they know all
that okay so if you really want to be
careful turn JavaScript off okay so I
have it off by default via this uh this
U block or engine okay so only when I
want it on for example when I want you
know the digma
website I think it you know I can trust
them then I go there and turn JavaScript
on okay then maybe you know many bad
website many website when you have
JavaScript off they they show they they
they become bad you know the things
doesn't show right so you can say that
the digma website is well done you know
uh because I have JavaScript off but
their website is still shows everything
perfect in you know in the right
position so that's why JavaScript off
okay because I uh am a very extreme nerd
I you know I I control things not the
other way and similarly in Brave I also
have off by default so I can go to any
website for
example uh let's go to S
doino go there and
brave
uh I by default I have it off but I
think for s i turn it back on okay oh
yeah it's off block script yes you see
so you don't have JavaScript so when you
go to search it won't
work nothing shows okay so now you need
to turn JavaScript
on now if you type
keyboard you have
results
okay okay that's it my uh drink is done
I think that's it for today
uh anything
else 609 so anything else uh I think
that's it uh so let me prepare to close
down
okay bye guys