Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Tsar Talk Show.
Today's topic is no topic, random. So,
you ask questions and I answer.
Okay? So, ask question now.
Okay. So, no topic. So, I'm just going
to start to do random and uh
uh Oh, yeah.
100 ml
of red wine
to soothe my soul.
Sooth my brain.
Today is 2023
October 11th.
And we are currently in the
troublesome world. There's a big
killing going on. You know, the
politics.
Huge killings. Hello, Chinese people.
Some some some What what the What the
[ __ ] is your name?
You know, that idiotic Chinese
characters. Some people love to use that
idiotic, you know, super complex Chinese
characters. Actually, I can explain
that.
Uh you know, immortality. Good morning.
Oh, good afternoon. Good good afternoon
or good midnight or good evening.
Uh Intex 080.
Uh Daniel, good night and God's son. Oh,
God's son. Cheers. Cheers.
So, no topic. So, ask a topic, okay? Ask
a topic and I'll talk about it. Uh and
uh so, here is my keyboard Glove 80.
Search xahlee.info.
I have a video review. Fantastic.
This one is ultimate hacking keyboard
version 2.
Also fantastic, okay?
Okay, let's go Let's switch to my
desktop so you can see what we going to
talk about, random stuff.
Okay, Andrew. Good morning, Andrew, from
Midwest.
What do you mean by super complex
Chinese characters? Okay? You see the
person above you, Andrew, in the
comment. Uh let me copy his um
So, you can see. Let me copy his name.
Copy. Okay, now back to Emacs. Now, you
can see open a new window, okay? There
it is. Now, magnify.
Okay? So, oh Oh, this is Justin. Hello,
Justin, the mathematician from Canada,
the professor from Canada. Is that you?
I think so.
Long time no see.
Justin love this kind of [ __ ]
Uh well, I got a I have more to say, but
maybe I shouldn't. But anyway, Justin.
Long time no see. How are you? So,
what do you mean by complex Chinese
charac- Chinese characters? So, like
this, okay? So, these are Chinese
characters. I mean, they are rarely
used. Only you They are never used. You
know, like in English, sometimes you see
for fun, you know,
uh you know, people wants to find what's
the longest word in English, okay? So,
let's let's let's let me show you, okay?
So, it's similar in Chinese. Uh
analogous. So,
what's the longest English word, okay?
Now, the power of my Emacs to do do do
search for that.
You see, what is the longest word in
English? So,
here are a few huge monsters. Let's see.
Okay?
So, God, this [ __ ] idiotic [ __ ]
pathetique site.
However, anyway, let's see the longest
word. Uh okay, blah blah blah blah blah.
Okay, okay, so
new new mono
trans trans
trans
Oh, okay. New
new mono ultra microscopicsilicovolcano
covol
covolcan
can
covolcanoconiosis.
Okay, that's supposed to be the longest
word. It used to be some kind of
communism stuff, okay? 15 longest word
in English. The [ __ ] idiotic
irrelevant pictures. You see this this
scam commercial websites.
Okay, God's question. God's sons got
question. Alex said a random question. I
was curious about theoretically
speaking, could you build a C language
in Lisp? No.
Uh as in write C inside of Lisp.
Mm, yes.
I know a weird question, but was
curious. Okay.
So,
what kind of question is that? So, you
want to So, could you build a C language
in Lisp as in write C inside of Lisp?
Yeah, of course, you can.
Uh that is actually I don't think that's
too difficult. All you have to do is
just make
Yeah, you I mean, to do that, you
basically are writing another language
because Lisp does not support,
you know, syntax like C. Lisp has reader
macros, which facilitate facilitate for
you creating
uh
different kind of syntax, but still Lisp
is still lots of nested parentheses. So,
Lisp by the fundam- fundamental nature
of Lisp, it does not do,
you know, the C syntax. Of course, you
can add it. But if you add it, it's no
longer Lisp. You are just doing your
thing, you know, you are just creating a
new language with
part of it Lisp, part of C language,
okay?
So,
you know, so that's uh Okay, so we I
mean, I'm jumping around. I shouldn't
jump around. Let's go back to this.
Let's finish one topic at a time. This
Chinese character and what's the longest
word, okay? So, the longest English word
I know,
it used to be like 10 years ago involves
uh
some kind of communism concept. For
example, anti-disestablishmentarianism.
Okay? That was the longest
word I know and uh
Yeah.
So, in Chinese, you have kind of a
similar thing, you know, Chinese words
are made of characters. So, you have
this character This like never used.
Just like the longest English word. It's
never used. You You don't even know what
it means. So, this word is made out made
of three characters of the word for
thunder, okay? So, let me type the word
thunder for you.
Okay. Uh
in Emacs, we can do it in Emacs or we
can do it in Windows. Let's Let's do it
in Windows first. Okay, so Windows
notepad. Yeah, okay, notepad. But
notepad is going to be
Okay. So,
you Now, you need to switch to Chinese.
Now, I'm going to type the word thunder.
Oh, in Chinese.
Uh
Okay? This character. Uh
l e i, okay?
Uh l e i number three. Yeah. Okay, and
they magnify, okay? This is the Chinese
character for thunder.
You know, thunder. Okay? Then in So, you
can see this character, which this Mr.
Young, professor mathematician from
Canada, he put he put in his name. This
character is made of three thunders.
Okay, what does it mean? Yeah, I don't
even I'm not sure It's like
something related, okay? So, let's look
up what it did what does that mean?
Three thunder character in one.
You know, it's just for shits laughs.
Nobody uses this word.
Uh okay, so let's see. Wiki- Wiktionary.
Let's magnify.
Okay? Blah blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah Chinese source blah blah
Asian Chinese big dictionary Kangxi
Zidian Da Han He Zidian Hanyu Da Zidian
page number one
381 something and 16th character, okay?
So, but what does it mean? Like show me
where is it Where is the meaning of
this?
Uh jing yong yu lei lei. Okay, so this
character, the only Okay, so this
character is pronounced bing.
Okay, it's like Microsoft Bing. So, this
character, three thunder characters,
is pronounced bing in Chinese in
Mandarin, okay? And the only use of this
word is in the combination bing bing.
Okay? So, let's see what that What is
the bing bing?
Okay, you you It's pronounced um bong
bong here.
b yong bong bong
Okay, so I suppose it just means
thunder, like bam bam.
So, where's the meaning? Yeah, okay. So,
the sound of thunder.
So, the Justin profession Professor
Professor Young, Professor Young poo,
you are an idiot.
He used you know, he loves that.
Uh this thing. So, and the second
character is made of three characters
for dragon, okay?
So, let's type the dragon.
Uh in Chinese, it's long, okay? L O N G,
okay? So, the first one is simplified
character for long use in China. But,
then let's get the
uh the traditional character for long.
Okay? The this one. Uh [ __ ]
Let's try again.
Uh second page, number four, okay?
So, these two characters are the same.
The first one is simplified.
Long, okay? The second second one is a
traditional. It means dragon.
Uh the dragon the concept of dragon is
different from
Oh, bing bing, okay? So, anyway, the
concept of dragon is in China is
different from
uh
western dragons, okay? Western dragons
is typically evil. It's looks like a
dinosaur. It got bat wings and it can
breath fire. You know, that's a western
uh dragon. But, let me show you a
Chinese dragon, okay?
Uh
you probably have seen it in in um
Chinese New Year festivals and stuff.
But, the Chinese dragon is typically
uh
good omen. So, Chinese dragon is kind of
like snake but with eagle claws and it's
got this you know, so that anyway,
that's Chinese dragon, okay?
Okay, let's switch back to English,
okay? Chinese dragon.
Okay, so you got now you got this, you
know, many pictures of Chinese dragon.
So, Chinese dragon is not evil.
Typically like evil thing. Uh and it's
also typically it's good thing. It
represents the
the king, the emperor, usually.
You know, good omens, typically.
So,
So, here you have a Chinese character
made out of three dragons, okay? Now,
let's look up Wikipedia, what the [ __ ]
that is.
Okay, so this is Wikipedia.
Uh so, it says let's see.
Da, so it's pronounced da.
Uh
so, what does it mean?
So,
uh da da da da da so so okay, so it's
mean it means flying dragon.
Okay.
I mean, it means the the it describes
when dragon is flying. So, you have
three dragons. And also, there's another
character that's made out of two
dragons, which means exactly the same.
So, anyway, that's so that's a funny
thing.
Hello George, traditional looks better.
Yeah, it does, but that's debatable,
okay? So, in fact, I have article on
that.
Uh
so, you go to let's let me show you,
okay?
xandl.org
So, this is my website. And you go to
wordy English, okay?
Uh
And uh I have a Chinese blog.
So, you go to Chinese blog. Oh, speaking
of dragon, I have a article on dragon
this this this quote.
The nature of a dragon. This Well, if
you don't speak Chinese, then I cannot
explain. It's you know,
it's
very interesting, okay? But, anyway, so
we talking about um
the
We are talking about the simplified
characters. So, let's go to that part.
Sa sa Zhongwen Biji
Okay, Young poo Justin says second tone.
So, what does this um
So, this word is pronounced
da da, okay? Da, I guess second tone. Da
da da da
No, according to Wikipedia,
da
da or So, they have two pronunciations,
or
da
da to idiotic big five. Anyway, so the
you know, so that's the thing about
that. So, anyway, about simplified and
Chinese simplified characters, so you
can go to my for example, I have a list
here
a list of simplified and traditional
Chinese characters. So, this is actually
a complete list, okay? The blue one is
simplified. The
the black one is traditional.
And uh the red squared means
means they are simplified from
um
from ancient characters. So, for
example, we we were talking about the
character thunder.
And here is a character for
for light lightning, okay? So,
the traditional character is like that,
okay? It's very similar to thunder,
okay?
But, however, the simplified is like
that.
So, the simplified is actually from
ancient. So, so
a thousand 2,000 years ago,
the character lightning is written in
the simpler simplified form.
Okay? So, in that sense, the simplified
is actually
better. Uh but, actually a lot of
the simplification they got screwed up.
Anyway,
and then I have actually I have an
article
um
I have an article about which one good
or bad Chinese simplifi- uh characters.
So, here I
It's my notes about which characters
simplification
is better or worse.
For example, all these
all these are good simplification.
By the way, my Chinese name is Li Sa.
Sa ren de sa, okay? Means kill. Sa Li.
Sa means kill, okay? So, in traditional
form, that character is written this
way.
But, you see,
but the simplified form goes back to the
ancient, the way it was written a
thousand or 2,000 years ago. So, you can
see this character kill is like
off with your head, okay? So, this
character makes it simpler, make it
you can easily see, okay? So, that's why
I say, you know, for example, this word,
the simplified form is much better.
Uh and
you can see this character means air or
or chi, you know, air or kind of spirit.
So, it's also simpler.
Because it's you know, it's like
cloud it's air, you know?
And this character means the cloud,
okay? So, this one is also simpler. It
makes more sense, cloud.
You know, and this this word is
tears, okay? Your tears.
So, this one is also simpler because on
the left side you have water. On the
right side you have eye.
So, water in the eye, tears.
And the traditional form got [ __ ] up,
you know, it got a dog inside a house.
You know, so if you want to judge about
simplified versus traditional, you can
you know, it's lots of study and
useless, basically.
But, there's a lot to go through, you
know, thousands of thousands of
characters.
Okay, that's about that. So, let's go
back to some English topic, so all the
English people non-Chinese can
appreciate.
Uh
so, I talked for 20 minutes. Any other
questions we have?
Act- uh yeah, so let me read the
questions. So,
Why did you start wearing a Maoist hat?
Well, because
it's not it's not that I really, you
know, decided to have this hat. It's
just by chance
I got this hat.
And this hat, you see?
Now, I cut my hair. My wife cut it for
me.
So, I think I look better with the hat
now. Let's see which way you which way
do I go? Oh, I can go here.
Here.
Okay?
Mm.
Now I'm a red guard.
I defend justice.
God send hex out. So the this question I
kind of answered.
Uh
you have to kind of study compilers and
to really know that.
Mary Poppins
int 80 says int x080.
What does that mean? So let's look up.
So this guy, our friend, his name is int
0x80.
Now typically the 0x something is the C
language's idiocy to represent a number
by hexadecimal.
The C extreme idiotic [ __ ]
Okay, C language.
Okay, so what but what is the
hexadecimal 80? I don't know.
So let's see.
Can we find out? Yeah.
Let's see. Let's Let's use multiple
technology to find out what is the hex
hexadecimal 80. Okay? Let's do
Emacs Lisp.
Okay, so let's do
Emacs Lisp
What?
Okay, let's do Emacs Lisp. Let's do
JavaScript. Let's demo the power of my
language knowledge. Let's demo Wolfram
language. So we want to know what is the
hexadecimal 80. So in other words,
convert hexadecimal to decimal. Okay?
Well, so in Emacs you represent
in Emacs Lisp you represent
Yeah, if you want to input a
hexadecimal, all you have to do is
um
this with this syntax.
x 80. Okay?
So that's that's that. So do it. So see,
it's 128. Oh, 128. That's the
you know, that's the that's the powers
of two.
Oh, that's So that's eight bits.
Wait, that's seven bits.
Wait, where do you use int 80? Where do
you want seven bits? Seven-bit ASCII.
Anyway, so this is how this is Emacs
Lisp. Okay?
How can you convert a hexadecimal to
decimal? Now JavaScript
JavaScript JavaScript idiocy.
Uh got JavaScript. Okay, JavaScript is
parseInt.
Okay, let's go to
JavaScript mode. Now let's show me let's
show some my pink window so you can see
JavaScript mode and parseInt.
Yeah, parseInt. So number and base.
In fact, JavaScript Does JavaScript
support input of hexadecimals?
Um
Okay, red wine gun.
JavaScript input of hexadecimals. Does
it?
Maybe maybe so. I don't remember. But
let's use the in
um
int. Okay, so 80
parseInt. So base 16.
So console.log that.
Run it.
Buffer is not a file. Save it first.
Okay, let's run it in your browser. So
control I
shift control I. So we get the
JavaScript console.log
and paste it there.
So can we magnify here? Yes, kind of.
Enter. 128. You can see.
Fantastic.
Now does JavaScript support like
um
0x80?
The C dot notation. It does.
The [ __ ] idiotic C [ __ ] It's a
you know, C is a virus. You know, it's a
cancer. So this idiotic idiosyncratic
notation spread and spread to every
language. The C [ __ ] and Unix.
Okay, let me tell you.
So okay, so let's let's copy that.
Let's copy that. So JavaScript is that.
Okay?
And or
Wait, or
or it's just that. Okay? Now Wolfram
language. Now let me show you Wolfram
language why it is super powerful.
Now in typically in the C industrial
programming idiots, you know, C, Java,
Python, Ruby
Bash
C++
Rust these idiots.
In their head because all because of C.
Because C began and it spread and and it
brainwashed all of them.
You know, in these idiot idiots' brain,
they don't have a concept when when they
see, you know, binary or hexadecimal or
sometimes octal octal notation.
They don't have the concept of let's say
base nine.
You know, if you tell them, oh, you
know, if you ask them can you show me
Okay, wait. Start Mathematica. Okay,
start a Wolfram language. We're going to
show later. Okay?
First of all, let's say enter three.
Okay, three
plus plus
three
Okay?
So in these people, they they only know
binary
octal sometimes octal is like forgotten
these days and hexadecimal, right? But
if you ask them, can you show me a
number base Let's let's say what's 100
in num in base nine?
And they'll go, what? What?
[ __ ] C idiots and Unix [ __ ]
So the number base is a general idea,
you know? But if you came from
mathematics
if you are came from mathematics, a
mathematician, then you understand the
concept of number base. Not just binary
two
eight, 16. [ __ ] binary [ __ ]
You understand number number base in a
general sense. So
So
for example
Do we have number base? Okay, so let let
me let's see what is the function in
Wolfram language for
uh
What is this?
Oh, that's
So we want
Yeah, we want We don't want those are
chapters. This is
section heading. Okay, this is some kind
of section heading. Like org-mode, you
know, org-mode, you know. So you have
for example, if you press alt
one
This is you got the title. alt two
uh
alt two, you got section.
Then you can have alt three, subsection,
you know, so on. That's why Yes, that's
why you are seeing this bullet thing. So
anyway, what I want to type is actually
asterisk. Type it in wrong.
So shift eight.
Why is shift eight become that?
Okay, shift eight.
What's What's going on?
Did I Is my keyboard screwed?
What?
Okay, now you got uh
So I want
asterisk. Oh, yeah, I want base.
So I want to see what functions are
available for
for base for the number base. Okay?
Base decode, base encode, base form.
Okay, let's see what is base form.
Okay, so there it is, base form. Base
form
Okay? And you can you can So let's say
then what what what base? 16. Okay?
Wait.
Base form expression and prints the
number in expression given in base n.
So why is this What?
Uh
So, let's look up the documentation. So,
Yeah, so why is this
Oh, yeah, so that's right.
Oh, yeah, so that's right. So, so what
do you actually you want to do is you
want
base
in base 16. That's 80, okay? But, we
want to do the reverse. We want to know
what is 128 in base 16
in decimal, okay? So, so
base form, what's the other function?
Actually, Wolfram language also does the
I think I'm pretty
sure it also does the
Does it?
No, it doesn't.
So,
number form, okay? Number form is the
thing you want.
Okay, number form expression and prints
with approximate real number of
expression given to end digit precision.
Okay,
uh and uh with
Wait, that's number form is not it.
Um
Ah, okay. You have a special notation
here, okay? So, you want to say 80
that that 16.
Failed. What?
You can enter number in any arbitrary
base using Oh, okay, so that's
So, instead of you base 16 80.
Okay? So, that's how you do it.
To go the trouble.
Uh Wolfram language is like that, okay?
So, there it is. So, what is the other
questions?
Let's see. Oliver $5. Thank you.
Oh, god.
All this talk got wasted. [ __ ]
Uh
So, okay, so
Yeah, wasted wasted 10 minutes, okay?
So, anyway, in Emacs this is it's just
that, okay? In JavaScript it supports
the
C Okay.
That's The reason is because I have
one too many drinks, maybe.
So, in JavaScript is that, okay? The you
know, you can do it direct input, you
know, base hexadecimal or you can
convert, you know, from a string
hexadecimal base 16. In Wolfram language
is is just this notation, okay? So, by
the way, so this notation, so why
Wolfram language has this notation?
Because this notation allows you to
uh give it in any base. So, for example,
let's say base two.
Digit at position 1280 is too large.
What?
Oh, yeah, so there's no 80 in base two.
So, okay, so let's say base eight.
Ah, base eight you have zero to seven.
You don't have You don't have eight. So,
okay, so anyway, base three, okay? Wait,
you got to have some Let's say base
nine. So, the number the base nine
notation of A0 in base nine.
That is decimal 92.
So, the point about the Wolfram language
notation, this, you know, with the base
and correct correct and the number
allows you to
input any number in any base, okay?
Get that?
Any number in any base.
So, let's say 800, 8,000 or whatever.
Let's say base 17. Let's say base 17,
okay? What is that in decimal? And
Okay? In decimal, that's 11358856,
okay? That's
This is how in Wolfram language you
input a number in any base, okay? So,
previously I was talking about
you know, previously I was talking about
how C language, this C
this C language a virus syntax spread to
all the
languages, you know, this zero X.
So, why why does it suck, you know? So,
let me describe why I hate C. This is a
typical This is a prototypical example
of the C idiocy to the extreme. C and
Unix [ __ ] okay? This is a cream of the
example of C.
I don't hate C because Oh, because it's
low level, because it's assembly,
because it's not mathematics. No, that's
not the reason.
I despise C and C++ and the whole pack
of industrial programmers with their
binary operators [ __ ]
Because they don't have a brain They
They designed their language in a way
it's all hack, okay? This This This This
input This
This is called literal um
uh literal expression for number, okay?
Technically.
So, this number input is one of the best
example. You see? So, you want people to
be able to input a number in in in base
in any base, okay? So, the C people came
up with this. So, you start with a zero,
then you start with X.
Why X? No Well, no particular reason. It
just, you know, it's just convenient.
So, what does What if you have zero A
zero A
80. What does that mean? Well, it
doesn't mean anything. So, when you have
X, that's special. It's a special syntax
special, okay? It's exception. So, you
have to Everything in C you have to
remember this is for this This is, you
know, this little thing [ __ ] C.
Then so So, X Oh, yeah, why X? X stands
for hexadecimal.
So, you can have zero X. So, this is,
you know, the input form for
hexadecimal. So, if you want octal,
then it's zero O. I I I think I forgot,
you know. But, if you want binary, it's
Is that right? So,
I don't remember it's right or not. So,
can we
Can we do that? Let's say 1100, okay?
Let's see JavaScript
browser, okay? So, this is we were using
the browser browser console before.
Yeah, it does. So, this is a C
invention. So, you have like
B for binary. What about O? So,
I think that also works. Okay, no. Octal
is not that that. But, anyway,
you start with zero and B that's stand
for binary number input. Zero X is
hexadecimal, okay? That's C
language kind of created this whole
thing and it spread to every language
and it brainwashed the industrial
programmers. So, why do I despise this?
Because, you see, they they use X
special, you know, it's just special.
It's like
it's just irregularity full of filled
with irregularity
X and B.
Okay, so what what What about if I want
a number in base nine? Oh, you cannot do
it. What What if I want a
number in base three? You cannot do it.
And what does it mean if you have, you
know, zero A or zero C? Oh, that doesn't
mean anything. It's just that special
case, you know, this [ __ ] C and Unix.
This is the reason I despise C and Unix.
And when you talk to the C people, you
know, they don't understand, you know,
this.
We have a few of our forum, you know,
basically the whole industrial
programmers. They They don't get it.
They don't They don't understand. Then
they'll say, "Oh, why do you need Why do
you need base three? Oh, you don't need
it." You know? So, anyway, the the
characteristics of this problem is that
it's just a hack. That's what C and Unix
do. It's just hack. It It works. It
works.
Everything syntax Everything Everything
about every decision in the programming
language is like that.
Uh
Why do you Okay, so let me answer the
question. Why do you need base nine?
You see, the number base is a general
concept in in numbers, okay? It's It's
about It's It's It's about the notion of
number um
representation. So, it's a general
concept. So,
so what is the um
So, it's a general concept. So, if you
design a language, you should be able to
why you know, why should you should be
able to represent
all these bases. And why is it useful?
Because
you know, different number bases have uh
many different uses in mathematics just
in general. Now, the binary happens to
be very super extremely useful because
that's one of the
end of a spectrum, you know. You have
base two starting with two. You cannot
have base one, you know. So, two
So, that's the the simp kind of the
simplest.
And it it happens to be extremely useful
for computers.
Uh and then So, why is why is
hexadecimal base useful? Well, because
it's it's it's a factor of the binary.
You know, it's power of binary, so you
can
condense the representation of a number.
That's why hexadecimal is frequently
used. For example, in CSS, you know, the
in in in in the [ __ ] CSS color, which
also began by Unix, which [ __ ] up the
entire industry. You represent the color
by
Uh okay, so let me show you. So, let's
see if I can find it. So, we want to
find a Let's see if we can
Yeah, there there there there there it
is. You see?
FF 0000.
That represents red, you know. It's a
very cryptic [ __ ]
And it becomes standard everywhere.
That's not the way, you know, in Wolfram
language, you know, if you want to
represent red,
you know, you can actually just say red,
okay? The but if you want the general uh
spec, you can see uh you can say
uh
the edge
Uh
[ __ ]
So, I want
this
Now, this is this is wrong. Shift
star gives you that. That's not good.
Yeah, we I don't know why is Wolfram is
doing this.
But anyway, so I want uh color, okay?
So, you want you know, it's supposed CY
CMYK color and uh
lots of color representations, okay? So,
Okay, I'm kind of going nowhere here.
Uh yeah, so the color is represented by
the keyword hue, okay?
Yeah, I remember. So, hue
Mm.
So, you can hue uh zero is red, okay?
What uh what about
So, you can give more options. Let's say
0.5 is the saturation.
Okay? So,
but what is hue exactly? You can let's
look up the documentation.
Okay? So, here is the documentation for
hue.
So, hue is HSB model, okay? Me means
hue, saturation, brightness, okay? And
Wolfram also supports uh
several other, you know, you can specify
RGB color. So, let me let me show the
design issue, okay? So, for example, RGB
like the Unix [ __ ] okay? The Unix which
it's a virus, you know, the Unix and C
design is a virus. It spread and spread
and spread to all so that the typical,
for example, average programmer or CSS
designer today,
they when they when you ask them what's
a color representation, they'll just say
this, okay? This
They'll they'll they'll just say this,
nothing else. Why?
W- why do we represent, you know, with
this cryptic FF whatever be, you know,
[ __ ]
Uh because C and Unix idiots.
Okay? So, that's why computer language
today computer when you code web or
whatever, it becomes extremely complex,
you know, filled with bad baggage
because these people don't know anything
about design.
All they know is that back then back in
40 50 years ago,
this is the simplest. It just works.
Useless memory,
you know, that's these idiots.
So, anyway, so this color short syntax
is RGB, so
Of course, I have 1,000 articles on
that. So, you if you just search for CSS
tutorial, you can see
uh visual CSS, okay? So, here is various
ways to represent color.
Traditionally, it's represented by three
two digit
three hexadecimals. Each one is two
digits, okay? So, you can choose color
wheel.
Uh you know, you see?
And then you can represent by So, here
is the basic colors by this, you know,
hexadecimal [ __ ]
Then you can represent then CSS
Then then CSS stupid CSS, they created a
shortcuts.
But anyway, then in 10 years ago, they
created uh
more different syntax, so you can
Now, so instead of hexadecimal
incomprehensible [ __ ]
now they
finally after 10 years, they created
this RGB.
But however, they also got it wrong, you
know, it's from 0 to 255. The [ __ ]
idiocy. This is an You see, I'm
concerned about it because it's a bad
design. It's brainless design. Why 255?
Why Why is the maximum 255?
Who the [ __ ] told you that? C and Unix
idiots.
Okay, so
So, anyway, so it's
So, let me show you Wolfram, okay? So,
RGB uh okay, RGB color.
Uh Yeah, you okay, you can also actually
choose, you know, you
You know, so here is Wolfram language.
So, this syntax RGB color
is
is analogous to the CSS
this syntax, okay? Now, the difference
is that in the CSS syntax, you have to
use a number from 0 to 255.
That's the range. In Wolfram,
it's 0 to 1, okay? This is the best the
most beautiful
design.
Because 0 to 1, that's a real number.
That's a you know, a range of real
number. You can have infinite precision.
Whenever technology improves 10 years
after today, 100 years after today, it
still works and still best design.
But the 255
is a [ __ ] idiocy.
You know, it's just it was just a
special thing. You got the magic number
255. That's a Unix and you know, and
also they start with zero. The most
idiotic [ __ ] from the C and Unix
brainless. You know, it should start
with one. 1 to 256,
okay? 1 to to the 2 to the eighth power,
2566,
not starting with zero. The starting
with zero got lots of problems.
Okay, that's lots of rant. That's it for
today, maybe.
Okay, so I talked for 15 minutes.
Uh
Why would you want base nine, okay? So,
oh yeah, so I haven't Did I answer the
question? Well,
let me give you a some some let me give
some credit to the C design, okay? So,
you see?
So, base nine So, in in programming, the
most used useful and practical number
base is two
and eight and 16, okay? It happens to be
useful. Well, because base two is the
most is what computers use because
electricity on and off represented by
binary 0 1, okay? Then you have octal or
hexadecimal.
That's only because they condense the
base two notation. So, you don't have
You don't need so many digits. It's
mostly used to for programmers to read.
Okay? So,
Okay? So, that's why octal and
hexadecimal are used.
No basically no other reason. Just
because The only reason is that they are
short representation of binary digits,
okay? And binary is needed because
computer are binary, okay?
So, but So, why is base nine or other
useful? Well, that's just general
mathematics, okay?
Uh
So, in computers, they are not that much
used, actually. So, we could So, there
is, you know, I've been I have been
dramatic, you know, we
I was
you know, this in C. So, I mean, in
practice, you only need base two in
computing at least. You just need base
two
base 16. So, that's why the C [ __ ]
created this idiosyncrasy.
Uh and so, why don't we, you know, why
why didn't they, you know, go with the
Wolfram design so that you can have any
base? Well, because they don't, you
know, back 40 40 50 years ago
if you go with a Wolfram design then you
have to write a general generalized
algorithm to take, you know, any base to
convert any base.
But, you don't need it most of the time.
So, they just go with the the shortest
speedy, you know, the hack possible.
That's C. That's the life of C. That's
the story of C and Unix design.
And it's practical practical, you know.
So, one of the why is uh why is C
everywhere? Well, that's because they
are the most practical. They are
brainless, but they just go for the
the most common needed thing.
You know, so that's why.
Well,
uh yeah, uh George has that argument.
Starting with zero makes sense for RGB.
Well,
yeah, in some case, but not in general.
I mean, that gets us into the discussion
of array indexing and all that.
Uh
Well, I mean, well, so for color, so you
are saying starting with zero makes
sense. Not really. You know, you see
I don't, you know, no, that's
false. Okay, so let me explain why.
Uh God, what's this special character?
So,
you see, when you So, let me show you.
So, okay, so
So, let's let's talk about the color
representation. For example, this
Wolfram syntax. So, let's say we are
using the RGB model, red, green, blue,
okay? There are many other models, hue,
brightness, saturation, you know, and so
on.
But, RGB is one of the popular model,
okay? So, in this model, you need three
numbers, right? So, in the Wolfram
language, in a Wolfram function, you
each number has a range of zero to one.
Zero represent the minimum amount. One
is the maximum, okay? Zero to one. The
best design.
Okay? So, but in typical Unix and C and
you know, then then in CSS, it's zero to
255,
okay? Why 255 in particular? Well,
that's because
basically, you have 256 values. Two to
the eighth power. Binary. Again,
involving binary. Why why 256? Well,
that's because
you have eight bits, you know,
represent, you know, the physical device
eight bits. So, anyway,
two 256 possible
increments, okay? From zero to 256.
Not uh uh supposed to the Wolfram
language, infinite. Zero to one,
infinite. You know, in if you study real
numbers, you know, that's infinite
amount of
precision, okay? But, anyway,
in in in C in in
you know, in in CSS and C
we have 256.
But, however, they start with zero.
So, instead of one to 256, you have zero
to 255.
Okay? So, which one is better?
Uh
So, in this case, I s-
in this case,
you could argue
I I I mean, in this case, I don't think
there's a clear decision which one is
better. You could argue starting from
zero is better because
um because zero represent none, right?
But, then the disadvantage is that you
got this odd thing, 255, this magic
number.
Right? You got this magic number. On the
other hand, if you have
one to 256,
that makes sense.
Because why? Because you have a total of
256 values. Why 256? That's because you
have eight bits, two to the eighth
power. So, it's kind of makes sense.
But, however, when you use one, it's
not, you know, it just means the
minimum. It doesn't means no
representation. So, anyway, that's a you
know, that's debatable debatable.
So, anyway, that's it for today, I
guess. I
I'm not exactly drunk. Uh but
Okay, today is just random chat. Who
else is watching? Three people. Oh,
actually, I got 10 people.
So, am I making sense? We talked about
number representation. We talked about
mostly why C sucks. The hack mentality.
You know, that's what it's You know, the
the thing about C is that let me talk
about C, okay? You see, C language and
Unix.
So,
I recognize we have talked about, right?
They are practical, which is very it's
essential essential, okay? It's
essential 40 years ago, 50 years ago.
You know, you just need binary. You just
need hexo. You are not going to like,
oh, let's be general and create a number
base notation number nine. Any base can
work.
That's not practical. You do that, your
product go nowhere because
you know, remember 40 50 years ago,
nobody, you know, you have lived very
limited number of memory, you know, you
are not going to like
That's why Lisp long ago is very slow
and Emacs known for um
you know, Emacs is known for
8 megabytes and constantly swapping. So,
I got a poem here.
You know,
8 megabytes and constantly swapping. If
you look it up, that's like a phrase
describing Emacs 40 years ago. Like,
what the [ __ ] No, you know,
if you use Emacs, your computer becomes
super slow. Yeah, but today is like 8
gigabytes, you know.
A million times more memory. You know,
it doesn't matter anymore.
So, but 40 years ago, so you are
constrained by memory. So, that's So,
there is some point there is some at
least some point the way C is designed
that way, okay?
But, the thing but but it the
the thing with C is that it brainwashes
people like even today. Like like what
this I described before. You ask people
you ask people about the general idea
about number base or this Wolfram
design, for example.
Uh wait, where is it?
You know, this num- for example, this is
the number
in a base 17 17 notation. This is a
number in base nine notation. You can
have any base, any, okay?
You you you talk when you talk about
these peop- these things to the general
industrial programmers, they're going to
flame you, okay? This C brainwashed
[ __ ] They would just going to say,
oh, you don't need you never need it.
They they they they are going to go into
a denial all the way.
That is what C has done.
Okay? 40 years ago, it made sense to
have just hexadecimal or whatever.
But, not today, right? You know, so but
but C has made has brainwashed people,
the industrial programmers, to such a
massive degree. This is just one
example, you know, this is just one of
the example of number notation, you
know, there's so many other, you know,
issues.
Okay, that's it.
Todd Fisher says, "Well, Kasai has
inspired me to add generic bases for
numbers literals in my toy programming
language." Okay, fantastic.
Uh okay, so
kind of understand your argument about
one versus zero. Okay.
Uh
Okay, so that's it. I guess that's it
for today. I believe that the Icon
language support general bases. Icon is
a successor of Snowball, okay? Yeah, I
don't know
uh about the Icon language and Snowball.
Like, 20 years ago, in the '90s, it was
somewhat known, Icon.
Uh but, I guess it just died.
Uh okay, so what uh why is this
[ __ ] you cannot click it.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Seven
people. What? 12 people. Okay, no more
people. Okay, pay me. You like my stuff?
Pay me.
Uh
okay.
Uh my drink is gone. Should I get more?
I think so. Why not? It's already 1
hour. So, any more questions?
Today is random. Any more questions? I
was going to
I was going to show you some of the um
what we're going to talk about.
I was going to talk about
So, we talked about
the Emacs poem, 8 megabytes and
constantly swapping.
We talked about
the syntax for color, you know, the
three hexadecimal two digits.
Hack. You know, it offends me.
Offensive.
You know, this because you know, like
today you you you program, you know, if
you are a programmer, right? It's
complexity everywhere.
And when you see things like like every
every thing, why is it that way? Why is
it that way? Well, that's because his
history. One bag of history, [ __ ]
You know, so this this Unix
this Unix, you know, the C this
hexadecimal, that's one of the thing
that's
I'm
I despise since like 20 years ago. Why?
Because why do I know? How come I knows
I know this? Well, because I came from
Wolfram language in 1990s.
Before I touched any C or Perl or
industrial programming or networking or
whatever Unix.
I came from mathematics. So, when I
you know, for the first 10 years when
I'm programming first five,
you know, I'm seeing this this kind of
design, you know, the let's see, let's
go to color, okay? So, for example, I'm
seeing this, okay?
Make sense. Make sense.
Then I started to get into Unix, right?
Then I started to learn Oh, oh,
hexadecimal.
Then you have then then zero x means
But you cannot represent in base nine,
but only base 16. Then you have the
another [ __ ]
That that's how I felt, okay?
So, if you grew up if you grew up like
people say,
if you grew up with a religion, that
religion is how you see the world. So,
if you grew up with the industrial
programmers, C, Python, JavaScript, this
is natural to you. This is natural. And
when I see when I show you this, you
say, "What?" Oh, that's that's neat.
But tomorrow by tomorrow you forgot all
about it. You you are back to this this
this [ __ ]
They brainwash they brainwash your
brain. This this C C, I hate C, okay?
That's today's topic. Why I hate C. Not
because it's low level, okay? Because
because many of the design is just
brainless.
Do you customize layers for your
keyboard or do you use the
uh
the uh what is the
Do you use other about Of course I
re-customize. I always have you know,
whenever you have like and let's go to
keyboard.
Okay. So, if you have a programmable
keyboard,
uh especially non-standard, you know,
like weird design,
you typically always customize it.
For example, I did uh Glove80. So, wait,
can you see it my screen? Yeah, okay.
You can see my screen.
Yeah, of course. So, you can actually
see my customization. So, let's go back
to
uh go here, connection,
Glove80 keyboard layout. There it is.
So, I show you save the standard layout.
Then you have
Yeah, then you have how do you customize
layout?
Uh a little bit complex. That's one of
the disadvantage of Glove80 you when you
want to change layout. Slightly complex.
Then you have soft flat key layout.
That's my my personal layout for
Glove80, okay? So, just lots of articles
on my website you can search.
Uh
So, there's a question. Is there a
low-level language you like instead of
C?
Uh
I don't really know, okay? So, I like Go
lang
very much. Go lang. Go lang is like in
my opinion the replacements of C.
A little bit because the C type of
people, C and C++ and Rust, you know,
they insist that you must have control
with the memory. Like you you must deal
with the you know, the whatever memory I
don't you know.
So, but to me, you shouldn't have to to
do that. So, Go lang is my
is a language I like very much.
Extremely simple. Simpler. Go lang is
simpler than Python,
than JavaScript, okay? And simpler to
learn. Very highly documented. You know,
I have a Go lang tutorial, of course.
And I have an article why I love Go
lang. You know, you can read that. So,
very simple and very good.
Uh but however, you see, I'm not a
low-level programmer. So,
it just so happens and I don't you know,
I'm
pretty old. Um
I don't have time to study it. You know,
I like to study more math and logic and
proof theory. Those kind of thing and
machine learning. I'm not really
interested in low-level stuff. So, I
don't really know
any you know, tech I never studied
assembly language or machine machine
language.
So, in those areas, I don't know much
about them.
Uh but so the the question is so, I
can't really can I cannot really have
experience. I don't have experience to
know if I
is there a low-level language I love.
So, yeah, there's Rust, Zig, Nim, yeah,
so.
Some of the people on our forum
uh like them.
Okay.
I don't know I don't know about Rust.
All I know is that there's a lot of you
know, no nothing fandoms for Rust.
But I suppose Rust is better than C
simply because it's just like 30 years
new language. Typically, newer languages
are better.
But I don't like the Rust fad, of
course.
Okay, that's it for today, I guess.
Should I Is there anything else or
should I quit?
Or should I get more some more drink?
I think I'm going to quit, okay?
Uh let's quit in in 3 minutes. Let me
get a drink.
Okay, can you see what are you seeing?
Let me get a drink and uh
In three in 5 minutes we stop.
This shirt is not so good because it
makes my tummy pop out.
But so, I have to
10 people are watching. So, what what
else?
Red wine.
George, you missed red wine. 100 ml red
wine.
Okay, so there's an interesting comment.
Amph
Amphithese
says,
"In assembly language, they only load in
memory as bytes.
So, RGB is three bytes only. One red,
one green, one blue." Yeah, that makes
sense. You see but you see but C uh
that's the thing about C, you know.
When you talk to the C programmers,
that's what they say.
You know, when you for example, what we
talked about today about the idiocy of
the RGB, you know, the representation,
the hexadecimal and so that. The C
fanatics, especially the smart one,
those who have written compilers, you
know, they all say, "Fuck size. The
[ __ ] idiot. He doesn't know that you
know, each each of these character is
represented as a byte. As a byte, you
know, that's what they say." But these
people are the extreme idiots, okay?
There's a difference between there's a
difference between implementation and
design of the language. Just like just
like HTML, you know? This is HTML. This
is what you write.
And this is what you see.
And the and so, notation, there's a
difference in notation then then there's
a difference in implementation. There's
a difference in what machine your
language is designed for. And and also
what machine what kind of task your
programming language is designed for.
Okay, so there are these issues.
Right? So, the fact that the fact that
um
a specific type of
computer
that is digital electronic computer
made by integrated chips
you know, CPU, you know
in this sis in this hardware
you happens to have these bytes and
electronics, you know.
Anyway, so that's the that's kind of the
implementation issue.
Why? Because for example
we talked about before, you know, this
RGB color with the range from zero to
one.
If you design your language this way
does that mean does that mean if you say
0.74 it's going to beep error? Oh, 0.74
is not is not a byte. Does that mean
that? No, of course not. That's your job
to implement this to translate this on
the current machine, the current
hardware, the state of the art, how many
digit how many bytes represent the
number, you know, how many how large you
know, that's the thing.
So, your language does not change.
You know, like the C, you know, for
example, one of the idiocy this C cost
is that you have int, okay? So, you have
the type int.
Then you have the type double. Then you
have the type long. You know, after 10
year after 20 years you have to change
your type to double or long. That
[ __ ] suck. Java, C, you know, C++,
those kind of thing.
Okay, that's it. Thank you, guys.
So, there's a question about
Advantage 360. That's the last question
I answer and that's it for today. Pay
me, guys, okay? If you like my stuff
you can go to my, you know, studycode
study.info.
So, you can PayPal me
PayPal me and Amazon gift card me
or you can
Patreon me.
Oh, you cannot see it. [ __ ] Okay, so
back to study.info. You can Patreon me.
Amazon gift card, PayPal me or you can
go buy my, you know
buy my Emacs tutorial.
Okay, fantastic, comprehensive, the best
tutorial on the web.
Or you can buy my
JavaScript tutorial.
You know, in the past days I did a lot
JavaScript. Kind of update my JavaScript
website, so
anyway, so you have all these functions
the best the most efficient possible
written by me, the most correct,
efficient and clean code, okay? Than any
of those, you know, the [ __ ] famous
JavaScript coders with their library on
NPM, okay? I'm telling you.
Okay, so one of the best is um
test object equality, okay? There's
quite a few libraries out there that
does this, but my code is best.
Okay, that's it and shut down, okay? So,
let me go to the something, you know
I want to say about today. Let's see.
Uh okay, so let's see.
Yeah, so Stephen Wolfram is going to to
is going to be in San Francisco.
Stephen Wolfram is going to be in San
Francisco.
Uh attend giving a talk at Ted AI
October 17th and 18th. So, he's going to
be there.
I'm probably going to go and meet him.
Okay? So, he's going to give he's giving
a talk at
So, that's one of the event and that's
on my Twitter, by the way.
Did I miss any questions? So, let's see.
Interesting things.
Octal number starting with zero and hexa
is 06 is not consistent, okay?
Thank you, Oliver Winspear.
Okay, so
there's a lot things going on today in
politics, of course.
Huge, that's very sad. Huge.
We are witnessing
you know, I don't want to say the word,
but we are witnessing
lots of killing, lots of killings.
It the American empire is like
Okay, bye, guys.