good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
Show today is 2020 January 10th
Friday 3 o'clock 2 o'clock 20 minutes in
the afternoon San Francisco time and
today's main topic is keyboards anything
about keyboards or input systems and if
you have any questions about keyboards
this is the right time to ask me ok
anything about keyboard keyboards Do It
Yourself keyboards which keyboard is the
best keyboard which one is the cheapest
to buy which one is the most ergonomic
which is your favorite
what about flat keyboards which one is
the best which one do you think which
one do I think which one does she thinks
good morning Emily
in the morning testing and in keyboard
design keyboard design stuff keycaps
key switch systems and keyboard firmware
the interfaces the varieties of
interfaces what are the different ways
keyboard labeling technology you see
everything about keyboard and typing and
typing related stuff such as for example
the finger length the finger length in
survey and all that stuff so that's a
main topic for today but I'm going to go
random a little bit I'm going to go
random and show you a sundry of
fantastic things in the world we live in
the fantastic things and especially
computing programming stuff so just in
scarf I mathematician in Canada if you
want to buy a keyboard you can go to my
keyboard blog and you know you can read
my blogs so they are like hundreds of
keyboards and mouse in different stuff
in typing stuff you can buy and for
example let's say if you want to buy
this mouse then you just click on my
Amazon link now this link goes to the US
am Amazon but I know you have Amazon in
Canada so I need to I need to Amazon to
connect my account so I get money but
anyway so if you find a keyboard you
like you can buy it and which one
keyboard to get depends on what you want
depends on you so in the case of you you
are kind of sitting a wheelchair right
so you so I'm not sure what's your need
for keyboard you know if you can tell me
maybe I can give you some suggestions so
great Emily's here and great Kathy is
here good morning guys have you guys
went to the Emax meetup yet
okay so let's so we have many
interesting things going on you know so
let me show you this one okay let's
digress this this this is Conway's Game
of Life only torus only actually only
not the not I you know so so one of the
interesting things with this game of
life on a try for you or not is that I
wonder about whether it's topologically
equivalent to a torus or not because you
have to think about because there's a
twisting issue so I don't know if this
is completely equivalent to a you know
the game of life on a trifle you're not
versus on a torus
I'm not sure I have to you know this is
a question you you have to think about
now do you guys know what I'm talking
about
like you know what I'm saying Emily do
you know do you know what I'm saying
like whether the game of life is the
topology equivalent on a Taurus vs
trifle or not or not so one way to think
about that is to trace you know
basically we want to you know we don't
want so you know what I'm talking about
so are they equivalent do you think they
are equivalent you don't want you know
there's an issue of twisting so you know
unlike only Taurus there's no twisting
so a twisting would be for example if
you have a Taurus and you cut it then
you trace it hunt you know 360 degrees
then you reconnect so that would be that
would have a twisting so in math
magicians terms you call it orientation
so there is a weather there's the
different differencing orientation okay
now I got it now thinking about that now
I know the answer so the the answer I
the answer I'm pretty sure is that it's
independent you know whether you want
the twist or not is independent of
whether the thing is on a torus or
trifle or not because if you want to
trace you just trace it if you don't
want to twist you just you just don't
twist it so you know it's different it's
a separate question
so Emily say certainly without twisting
it is the same as tourists okay yeah so
I got confused for a women but okay but
however we still have the question that
is the question is on this particular
rendering on this particular you know
rendering do they have a tryst or not
and we can find out by just tracing the
to say to see if they come back to the
you know we trace the lines around the
Taurus and when we come back here to see
if they connect right here or or connect
somewhere else I don't know if that
implementation on screen yeah so yeah
yeah so you are right so this and okay
so now we know the answer to that
question about a twisting or not now the
next question interesting would be what
is the effect of having a tryst on the
game of life
now do you know do you guys know the
game of life Emily have you played it
the game of life this this is fantastic
you know during the 1990s I spent
basically a few years in this game and
you know this okay so so we are
digressing and this is we gonna talk
about this and this is gonna be one hour
the game of life and in general the the
science of cellular automata which is a
fantastic fantastic subject the science
of cellular automata and so do you know
do you know about have you played it
have you actually like traded the game
of life Emily and Kathy and Justin have
you have you so by the way this creep
pick over he is a mathematician I don't
like the guy okay I don't like a lot of
things I don't like this click cliff
pick over a guy I mean he's a good guy
okay but he wrote he wrote tons of books
on mathematics that belongs to a
category of math popularization okay so
if you go to Amazon for example grief
pick over so emily has played it a lot
fantastic so you know if
pick over what a strange name cliff pick
over let's see if I'm doing okay with my
video okay so I'm put I need to put up
the the Jedi hood and so on now I look
better let's see what are these Jesus
sex drugs Einstein and elves what the
not Jesus this guy that's why I
despise this guy this cliff pick
over this Montand is this lowlife
okay you see why is that because math to
me is the God's creation okay in what
means words it's a god of creation it's
etched in stone let me show you okay
it's not to be trifled with but this guy
cliff pick over right a ton of this math
popularization books with this with this
egregious this this how do you say
what's the word egregious not that
egregious this this pop this oh my god I
forgot the words this let's look at
let's look at anyway let's look at the
cover you see he says six strokes
Einstein and elves sushi psychedelics
parallel universe in the quest for
transcendence what the he's you
know trifling mathematics this guy so I
don't I don't like his stuff at all
Clifford Clifford pick over okay so
that's his name and and he's on Twitter
and every day he's you know he's on
Twitter he's posting drama everyday
drama mathematical drama you know this
the
the word just came to me these this
class how shall you say the crass
you know appeal to your senses you see
this most idiotic this this math
illustration this factor this type is
the most idiotic thing he he loves to do
it and this is actually the what the
population loves the masses you know
that they love they love it for just
what is kind of what's the word I'm
trying to find what is this crap you see
this you see mathematics to me is not
just it's written in h in stone it's and
it's beautiful it's austere and code but
he this creek fold peak of a guy he
makes it like he made he prostitutes he
prostitute mathematics to become this
crap thing that's what he's doing you
know Clifford peacock and by the way he
has treated one of my websites walk two
years ago a year ago two years ago he
has treated one of my plane curves walk
yeah okay but I don't like you know I
don't like he's the way he to things his
style and stuff you know and and what is
this new book you know he so he's
publishing tons of books what is this
they led live way the la mort and they L
tell her something okay
this erection Quantic Jesus you know
he's trying to peddle this guy is what
what what he's doing is peddling
mathematics like peddling pedo it you
know this you read you read is this it's
that's what I'm trying to address with
the word I'm looking for
read and sensing sensational that's what
he's doing like you know the naked
pictures of girls in the UK United
Kingdom United Kingdom they have this
newspaper that's publishing focus on
sensational stuff
what is the name page six page six
am I correct Emily and Kathy like United
Kingdom I you know I read stuff on hippy
dia so they have this newspaper they
have a page six publishing sensational
stuff like what movie star in what
bikini and an online they have this
male-female thing god that that do read
sensational thing and look and look at
this click for takeover guide this DC
this is abusing mathematics this
disguise abuse mathematics offensive
this is offensive to my eyes you know
and and now now look spirograph you know
this is very popular spirograph thing
okay we are digressing a lot comments
guys what so what do you guys think what
do you guys say check status live okay
good so cliff Ford pick over you know
he's doing two in this period mathematic
thing you read sensationalism you know
you know then this guy kiss Jesus then
you know every nerd it like to post
about this guy every nerd Raggedy they
don't know nothing about history they
don't know nothing about it nothing then
everybody every nerd every day is like
Nicolas causa Tesla Nicolas Tessa this
though that Nicolas Tessa with this you
know this lighting like collect electric
stuff
Jesus so I despise these things you read
you know sensationalism and and the best
example the epitome of this style of
these crass crassness is is by this
cliff pick over guy and you can see you
know in his title sex drugs in Einstein
and elves what the you know he sees
abusing mathematics and you look at his
books you know he's been publishing
books since 1990s
you know because back then when I was
studying mathematics you know that's
that's how you attract people not the
right way though so I know this guy you
know one of his earliest book is chaos
let me show you you know he he published
you know he write tons of garbage like
you know so yes like how many books 1 2
3 4 5 6 7 8 7 8 9 10 8 9 10 11 12 13 14
15 16 you know he oh he also published
okay
history of mathematics this is not by
him this is a real math book I have that
book I have showed a few times this now
over here
that's real math not not this one not
this one he's mad you know you see this
book are history mathematics by this
mathematician historian copy boy oh this
is a good book then you go over heat to
Clifford then you go over to the
Clifford pick over guy then you see his
crap you know the medical book what the
is the medical book this one
mathematics devotional devotional now
it's getting into the code that like
like medicine and stuff and the
mathematics devotional
so anyway one of his earliest book is
chaos you know that is when chaos theory
is becoming very popular you know this
this guy publishes tons of books thirty
books forty books and with this most
offensive cover okay can you guys do you
see um do you see what I'm saying do you
see do you get a sense my sensibilities
does my sensibilities make any sense to
you guys my sensibilities and okay that
that's about this guy you know so let's
actually find his earliest book chaos
okay actually this page there's more
pages is that right so Kathy says gosh I
don't know getting away from doing
gossip helps retain my sanity getting
away from Lewin gossip helps with Amos
energy okay if you are pissed why are
you still browsing his website well I am
explaining I'm explaining my point of
view you know I have to do it properly
you know so one of his book that's chaos
which is very popular studying in 1990s
look Jesus this book chaos in Wonderland
now he now he wants to drag in
wonderland chaos in Wonderland okay so I
my recommendation is don't buy this
guy's book okay if you want to study
math there are a lot great books that is
also entertaining a appealing and
beautiful but they are via mathematics
not not this guy okay not this
click-click Ford pick over and today he
sound
the posting or this garbage everyday
like few times every few hours you know
and that usually sells just like naked
girls you know the with bikinis so
people retreat him you know he's in he's
this type of guy anyway so that's him
Cree Ford pick over okay so let's see
okay so let me copy things to my Emacs
so we have a record of what we talked
about digressions today's main topic is
supposed to be keyboards and actually I
have a lot to do okay so actually okay
so actually let's get my Amazon link so
I can make some money
oh there is no JavaScript I need to turn
on JavaScript
oh I'm not following that guy no I'm not
following that guy but but this guy
Clifford pick over or whoever does this
sensational things they are usually
retreated by your friends you know for
example I'm into math in computer and
you know in Linux right so you know so
but I don't like this Clifford pick over
but because he's really sensational
stuff so other my followers or some some
people I follow mathematicians they will
sometimes retreat his stuff so there's
nothing I can do you know this so
Twitter you know Twitter is encouraging
critter loves it because you know more
traffic traffic the better for them so
that's why it's it's very nasty annoying
you know condition we are in there's
nothing you can do
if so that's this guy Clifford let me
spell it correctly so we have a lot of
topics to talk about about cellular
automata game of life actually I never
talked about game of life hop game of
life properly so we can do that
or we can talk about cellular automata
in some little technical detail although
I did talk about that a few times
cellular automata so let me show you
this book again
I read twice at least a new kind of
science so this book by Stefan Wolfe I'm
and this you know I have actually
annotated kind of annotated the books
content a new kind of science that's
cellular automata very interesting stuff
okay so what what else we gonna talk
about so it's click close that fonts oh
my god fonts the Nerds interest fonts so
we can talk about fonts close across the
kree Ford pick over so you see
so this mathematician this this is a
great guy Dave Richardson okay he's a
mathematician and he you know you see
he's reposting his retreat retreating
the Clifford pick over stuff I am
following this guy Dave Richardson and
he has also written a book the tales of
impossibility which is about try section
try setting the angle and square the
circle and doubling the cube
so you do you guys know this these
problems these are classic antique Greek
problems very famous problems that have
changed the course of mathematics in you
know in a significant way it's a you
know it's one giant chapter of
mathematics do you guys know about that
so so he you know he he wrote this book
this Dave Richardson let me let me let
me just post it okay Dave rich said okay
so I'm going random so if you guys have
a like me to talk about specific things
then we win then we do that otherwise
I'm kind of right you know just talking
about whatever I'm seeing welcome good
morning welcome so we are going in
random about mathematics
so retake day so Dave Richardson so
let's go to Amazon okay let's go to
Amazon again let's look at his book okay
so so he published this book tales of
impossibility the to hunt the 2000 year
quest to solve the mathematical problems
of antiquity so back in Greek times
2,000 years ago there are three problems
in math everyone trying to solve and
these problems turns out to be
impossible but we do not know it's
impossible you know all the mathematics
mathematicians they they all try to
solve it but they do not know actually
it's impossible we know we started to
know it's impossible around I think you
have 1500 so the three famous problems
are you know I can talk about this for
hours
so because they are a lot to say and
actually I have personal experience so
this is a this is a
wouldn't subject because they are there
are there are a lot of crackpots or
people who are trying to solve these
problems and they think they have a
solution like in in the Department of
Mathematics if you are professor you
will receive mails you know these days
emails or postal mails from people who
you know they think they solve the
problem and they send their proof so you
have to receive through this garbage so
there are tons of these you know people
who think they solve this 2,000 years
old problems they and actually I have
encountered personally encountered one
of such guy you know one day this is
around 2000 through 2003 also and
typically these are old retired guys
typically they are engineers or
programmers but they are not
mathematicians you see that's the thing
you know when you know math you know
math you know do math you know what is
going on but if you are engineer or
programmers like a lot programmers you
know they don't know math but they think
they think they kind of they know so
these people typically retired engineers
you know accomplished some of them are
accomplished you know
so this engineers old you know
programmers so they they they saw this
problem about they heard about this
problem
Asian problem about try try setting the
angle or squaring the circle or doubling
the cube
I'll explain what they are if you guys
don't know what they are already so they
they think they have the solution you
know they work hard you know they trying
to you know they work hard so they think
they solve this 2,000 years old problem
so they try to publish it or st. since
and some of them actually they have
books published by them you know which
is force and they try to send these to
mathematicians but if you are a
mathematician
you know Rio mathematician or professor
you know it's already proven impossible
like three three hundred years ago but
that doesn't stop these crackpots
because these crackpots you know that it
doesn't stop them before reasons hard to
explain
just like religion you know you can't
stop people from believing or religion
you can't stop them it doesn't matter
how logical you try to explain it it
doesn't stop them so personally I
encountered that guy whose name I shall
not mention but I have actually I have
some blogs so he contacted me he is
trying to tell me you know he thought he
have a solution I mean also when you
look into these people this so-called
crackpots they are not actually
crackpots they are sincere I mean they
are truly sincere you know they are oh
typically 60 years old or 70 but they
are truly sincere they true truly
believe that is soft no a 2,000 years
old problem so I made this guy you know
he sent me you know first by email then
he started to send me his proofs he knew
me because I have you know I have
published math stuff on the website you
know he started to send me proofs and he
has also apparently as I found out later
with contact with other mathematicians
so I so I have actually a large story to
tell you about this problem so I need to
write them down actually because
otherwise I forgot what I want to say so
show my blog about this guy who tried to
trisect
the angle okay so that's I want to show
my blog about that and I want to show
David Richardson's book on Amazon okay
so that's one thing and I also want to
I also want to show the other book by by
David Wood something about trisection
problem okay so there is this guy a
mathematician I've corresponded with he
has published a book just like Dave
Richardson on this try section problem
and Underwood okay so his name is
Underwood I think this guy is totally
Underwood the UD why I might spell it
wrong so Dudley Dudley Underwood has
published a book on triceps trisection
and in his book he collects all the
crackpots who tried to who published you
know they're proof you know their
solution to to solve these three Asian
problems so I actually I have that book
I don't know if I can find it maybe see
my bookshelf I haven't seen it for a
while I don't remember but okay so but
one thing at a time so let's go to Dave
Richardson's book on Amazon so guys what
do you think say something okay let me
know how am i doing and the you know
opinions questions stuff so what's a
books name so let's do one thing at a
time tales of impossibility okay tales
of impossibility
it's going young there it is okay
David s Ritchson this mathematician on
Twitter we are sort of acquaintances a
little bit ok so that that is his book
so you guys go by this book I actually I
haven't read it I don't actually I
didn't even know he published well I
know since I see you so this is his new
book David which since hotels of
impossibility so so let's see what what
this book what is he doing with this
book what this book is about tell us of
impossibility recounts the intriguing
story of the so called
problems of antiquity four of the most
famous studied questions in the history
of mathematics first posed by the
ancient Greeks these compacts compass'
and straight these compass and
straightedge problems squaring the
circle transecting the on angle doubling
the cube and inscribe in regular
polygons in a circle have served as
ever-present muses for mathematicians
for more than two millennia David
Richardson follows the trail of these
problems to show that odometry their
proofs demonstrating the impossibility
of solving them using only a compass and
straightedge depended upon and resulted
in the growth of mathematics okay so so
in this book he is talking about the
history of these problems and how this
history propelled draw of mathematics ok
so like I mentioned like I mentioned
before these these three problems most
famous of them are three three of them
these three problems are
huge chapter in mathematics so in fact
they are a fuel to to tremendous you
know many branches of mathematics for
example they prepared the they prepared
algebra they prepared geometry they
prepared non-euclidean geometry and you
know and you know they are fundamental
they they are a huge chapter so this
book according to the blurb it seems
like you know it's going to talk about
the history of these problems and their
relation to the how they drove you know
math development so you go by this book
now I'm going to show you a few other
books I've read you know the other books
I've read there are quite a few books on
this but there is another one I read let
me show you ok it's not here
so you guys still here Vokoun say
something I need to check so so let me
check my status six people watching am I
still alive yes yes
okay so tales of impossibility so let's
sorry
try section under wood so here is
another book that talks about this
problem okay so thank you where did we
go wait
pain curve books
and let me show you some of the my math
pages playing cups a fascinating subject
so here is my reference I mean this is
my collection of references related to
playing curves and one of the guy this
book I'm talking about the Tri sectors
by underwood dudley underwood dudley is
a mathematician at what university i
forgot but he so his book is about this
is published in 1994 this book is about
he collects all the people who try to
solve this problem
who tried you know these crackpots who
thought they solved the problem so this
is an Underwood so this is easy to read
you know very very interesting book
amusing you know you can read it you
don't require you know you don't have to
have a degree in a same way this tells
of an impossibility book you can also
read I don't think you need a degree so
they are like they are like real math
Popular's raise popularization books
meanwhile they are real mathematics not
you know not like the creeks Ford pick
over book so actually let me let me let
me tell you okay so so this book okay so
that's about this book now let's go back
here so
okay and now let's go to shell that's
it's let's go to do some max let's saw
interactive a brief and sync to my
server and then I copy the file path and
and that is today's link so you guys can
go there and quick stuff ok so then I'm
going to tell you about so in this book
third would Underwood dot V so he is a
it's a collection of stories of this
crackpot crackpot try sectors who try to
solve the problem so so he collect these
accounts so you know he tells us what
they do you know the you know he
actually go and visit interview each one
of these people you know in real life
they he interview them he get there you
know he let them talk about why they
think they solve the problem what's the
motive a motivation what's their
background their family background
what's their profession no he tells us
about these people who think they solved
the the problem so so once I read this
book and I found one of the chapter you
know I forgot what how many chapters are
there how many sections but one of the
chapter is talking about this guy I know
this guy who contacted me too
you know he want me to help him to
publish his solution to the tri-sector
problem so this is around 2004-2005 so
this guy six years 60 years old engineer
okay
white guy he actually come and
eventually you know starting with email
so he actually come to meet me he you
know he meet me in a coffee shop and he
pays everything very nice very nice guy
you know very nice gentleman
you know he so he wants to tell me he he
solved this problem and you know but I
know this is already proven impossible
so I you know so I you know he has
printouts you know or his proofs and he
yes he has also printouts of my websites
you know so he's a very sincere and
honest gentleman you know so he is
telling me you know he print out
oh my you know some of my websites on
trisection you know for example let me
show you my this this website so I you
know I have this website my website is
very popular back then since 1997 so you
know he you know he's very kind email
saying that you know I admire your work
and you know stuff and he's you know
sincere about it not not just
but he also want me to help him to
publish his proofs so so I'm in a
situation you know I'm trying to say you
know this is already proven impossible
you know you are just doing what you
your work is actually just you
know but you so you have this situation
is hard to say that but I do try you
know so he showed me he has his proofs I
can you know I can point out okay here
is where you went wrong you know you
made a wrong assumption and things like
that but it's just impossible it's just
impossible in so many it's hard to
explain it just seems impossible it's
it's kind of like when you are trying to
tell some God believers that God doesn't
exist you know gee is it just doesn't
work so I end up helping him to to draw
to you know to draw and organize his
proofs and he actually paid me for it
you know he repaid me our defeat
something like $20 or $30 an hour
so that's that's that's about that so he
we met about three times you know over
like two years period and each time he
treat me too you know he paid for the
lunch and all that so that's about that
my story of this one of the trice try
sectors so okay no comments I guess
that's boring so that's it's this switch
topic then six people watching soap link
of books try sectors okay close that and
post it here okay I already posted
Cosette Cosette and go try section you
know let me so what what is a problem
you know you can actually so today you
can read it on Wikipedia you know you
know it will tell them in detail the
problem is you are given an angle on the
paper on a piece of paper so you you are
given an angle like three points then
you want to draw a line that is
one-third of the angle so in essence you
want to find a point and draw a line so
that you know this this angle is
one-third of the given angle so that is
the that is a problem the general
problem now you you might think so
that's so easy what's the problem you
just use a protractor where protractor
is not allowed what what is allowed is
that you have to use a straight straight
edge like like a ruler but without
marking on it so you know like a ruler
you call that straight edge you know so
you can connect any point you any two
points you want you know if you have two
points you can connect it by a line and
you can also have a compass that is
given a point and another point you know
two points you can draw a circle
centered on one of a point so these two
things is are the only things you are
allowed to do so using these two root
two tools your task is to trisect the
angle so that is the problem transecting
the angle and this is the most popular
among these three problems this is one
of the problem okay they are two other
the other two is the other one is doubly
no Q okay let me click on that and
square the circle but but anyway once
you know the trisect trisection angle
trisection you kind of get the flavor
what it is about so you can actually
just try it you know you go ahead and
try it it's very fun you know this this
is a very tempting problem very
appealing appealing to laymen you know
without any math training because any
any person can understand the problem
any child child can understand the
problem in and you can immediately start
to work on it you know just draw lines
draw circles try you out you know your
goal is trying to find you know trisect
the angle and the other problem problem
is doubling the cube that is you have a
cube a cube has certain volumes right
you know you you you take the length of
the side and you multiply the length by
itself three times what you get is the
volume of the cube your problem is to
create a new length such that the new
cube volume is double the then original
so essentially the problem is given the
length you know like a number you want
to find a another lump number such that
that number square that number cubed is
equals through the original number cube
and the only tool allowed you allowed
for the
is same thing with a compass and
straightedge same thing with a try
setting the angle so that's that's a
doubling the cube problem and the last
problem is square the circle okay so I'm
not going to go into it you can you can
read it on hippy dia so that's about
these problems
good morning but now let's talk about
something else okay
let's talk about something else close
trader close trader okay some problem
with a go Emacs mod he cannot find a
cheat sheet but so what's up part so I'm
going to start to go random topics and
so here is a cheat sheet what what do
you mean he cannot find it anyway
so no comments no comments then I'm
going to start to do some eMac stuff
maybe well today is supposed to be
focused on keyboard so anything about
keyboard spot in guys let me close the
window because the the Jesus let me show
you okay because my neighbors they are
moaning the law the the long you know
they are blowing you can you cannot see
but happens happens every every Friday
or something very loud super annoying
okay am I so good
how long have I been talking
I'm supposed to talk about keyboards
today so but Tsubasa is keyboard switch
hi yo've oh now we got people the stuff
like his work with space max there are
people doing that but I have personally
never tried they are actually if you go
to space max there is a github issue
that suggest them to provide an option
of using sawfly keys as part of the
space max but I didn't have time to look
into so I you know it's it's that that
issue has been there for like three
years now but I think yes you can you
can use stuff like this with space max
I'm pretty sure you can yeah you you I
never tried it so I don't know what to
tell you because you know it's a
technical issue you know I have to
actually try space max then you know try
to get you know try to install flights
sophocles turn off the Evo mod because
space max by default they use evil mod
so you have to turn off that I know
people I think I'm yeah I know people
who are using space max with sapphire
keys but I've never done it so I don't
know I've never used space max so I
cannot tell you how to how what what
what to do to get them to work
I suppose it's pretty simple you just
install space max let me show you okay
space max if you guys don't know so
space max came about five years ago
maybe now it's six years ago or
something space max is a Emacs
distribution meaning it's gluey max
bundled with a bunch of packages so in
other words it's like
it's a whole thing set up for you so you
don't have to did ring with the config
files and stuff you just download the
whole thing everything just walks now
this is very convenient and it's also
very popular
you know usually this kind of
distribution they become very popular
because anyone you don't have to know
much about Emacs config or although all
the details about learning Emacs you
just don't know this you can use it you
know out of the box
oh the fancy you know UI or or enhanced
packages and stuff that's all bundled so
you don't have to you know go to the web
as people what's the best one for Python
what's the best one for : how you know
what's a bit then then how to configured
you know very complex you're gonna spend
hours so that's space max they came
around around six six years ago you
called Emacs distribution okay so
everything package is bundled by by this
sky I know this guy a little bit you
know so he you know I know this this guy
okay Brenner
pen pen okay you know these tiny Jesus I
know this guy okay space max okay so his
name is Sylvain Pina okay
Sylvain Pina let's copy his website he
okay
space max
by okay so that's space max and by the
way I also did a Emacs distro called a
go Emacs
that is why my don't domain name you can
see is over Emacs start oak it's a go
Emacs because from about 2008 to 2012
something like that for 5 years I have a
ogle Emacs distribution called a go
Emacs we're just like space max you just
downloaded everything is bundled I have
selected you know and convict the best
packages for Python for PHP you know
JavaScript everything you need so I
stopped you know I stopped doing that so
today there is no ago Emacs distro no
more and the main thing about ogle Emacs
distro is that you have the ogle Emacs
key binding system which is still
available so if you go to my website you
go to Emacs home page and you can see
the ogle Emacs
so this limiter so right now it's
maintained by this guide by this guide
by this guy was his name I forgot now
Matthew Matthew Fiedler he took he took
over about about seven years ago around
2012 or so wait this this doesn't look
good what's going on so you need
JavaScript okay now that's how it's
supposed to look so ergo Emacs mod so
the this package is a efficient key
binding for Emacs and you know I I began
around 2007 also so the this is the
major dish in Ocoee Mac's distribution
so back then I have this package
this is the main thing then I have the
Ocoee max tea straw where the key
binding is using a bow eMac smart plus
you have packages for everything else
bundle but the ogre Emacs distro is no
longer available you know it is because
you when you do that everyone is just
asking you questions you know you don't
you get paid you even there's no pay
every day is four hours something you
you know you work on your on it that's
that's that's what I did for five years
open-source you know so anyway so oh boy
Emacs mod is still available and and in
fact right now it's part of glue Emacs
you have to sign papers to assign the
copyright to give the copyright to new
to to reach a storm and free software
foundation so now this is actually a go
Emacs is now part of the GNU Emacs so
it's you know it's also in the ALPA GNU
Emacs free software foundations
repository called
ALPA and but however the the version
there it's kind of dilapidated you know
you'd rather you want to if you want a
go Emacs mod you wanted you want to use
the version of Melba memoir is not part
of Emacs but anyway ergo Emacs since
around 2013 2012 is now led by Matthew
Matt Fiedler Matthew Feder a great guy I
have not met him but you know so he in
fact he has made major changes he has
basically rewrote the engine so that's
okay Emacs the change of hand happened
because I started to work on stuff like
ease which is which is modal and also
because you know for historical for
reasons it's not like one day I decided
oh I don't want a go
Emacs mod anymore it's not like that
rather
because I was using another keyboard and
I got Kinesis and I then I still have
hand pain so I started to work on modal
you know like like vim like evil mod
modo
and because moto moto the way of the
Moto is actually more efficient it's
just more efficient you save like 10 10
to 20% keystrokes so I started to work
on so you know then it then that
eventually become soft like he's you
know before he was like oh go Emacs VI
mod so I was thinking oh it's part of
the oh go Emacs mod but you have the VI
mod so so you can go moto but eventually
you know the matte fiddler he took over
over Emacs mod and then I just focus on
Sava keys I renamed it stuff like he so
we went we went to separate ways just
like you know majority of open-source
project you know so my relation you know
so ok Emacs mod it's not modo ok though
at one time he also started to
experiment with moto but that became a
bit rod a bit rot you know so the model
feature in yoga Emacs mod is is not
there it's not robust something like
that so anyway if you so yoga Emacs mode
is not moto it's based on using your
thumb on old key it's great you know but
so if you if you don't like moto I can
you know I can recommend ago your Emacs
much you know but however the philosophy
kind of deferred you know so the matte
fitra
I want things to be extremely simple
including a code I don't want
complexities in code I want anyone who
don't know anything about Emacs who
don't know anything about the jargons of
Emacs such as key binding you know the
per first
then the maitake I don't want none of
that I want people back then originally
people who don't know nothing about
Emacs they just know Microsoft Notepad
okay they can download or go Emacs
oh go Emacs mod and use it right away
your walk you know pace is control V you
know copies control C and all that isn't
you know it's things like that you just
walk so that's what I want you know
that's kind of my style if you will you
know my philosophy would my package is
my projects that's the way I want to go
but you know we so so mad took over we
you know we you know he's a friend of
course so we in a beginning few years we
beginning five you know we work together
for like five years so you know we work
together but eventually I focus on stuff
like he's and also he made changes so
that the code becomes more and more
complex
so today the the code in yoga Emacs is
extremely complex you know some people
use your code bloated why sad because I
mean there's a good reason the Ocoee Mac
smart because it tries to you know when
you would so if you install over Emacs
the core by the mat is that it works in
every major mod you know it just works
okay that's his Co but it's not simple I
was like so you have you know it's also
starts slow you know it starts slow
because it it actually has to you know
the way ergo Emacs works right now as
far as I understand is that he actually
reads every other major mod and minor
mods keys you have installed in Emacs
and we mapped them so that's that's a
giant non-trivial complex task and he's
doing that you know he he you know
that's to his credit he rewrote the
entire engine so that the core the final
goal is that when you have a go Emacs
um it just works eeny doesn't matter
what other major model Magnum art you
have you have you know because in order
to make this work it's not trivial at
all it's very complex because Emacs does
not have a way to to provide you know
key binding set priority you know it's
very complex so the way it works is
actually it reads or your other major
multi-man manimals their keys then try
to remap them so you know like you have
a rapper or something like that so it's
it's so that's what he is trying to do
and to some degree I you know it's
successful but the price you have to pay
is that the code becomes you know 10,000
lines 20,000 lines you know it's
impossible to understand anymore because
then you have Marco's you know the you
know Marco's and you know it's very big
code and this the startup time is so so
very slow so that's the price you have
to pay you know and that's the way he
goes so you know he so you know that so
I just you know so he just took over I
don't want that though you know that's
not what I want I proof I want just to
be simple now the problem with being
simple code is simple in fast code is
that if you have some other mods for
example magic that magic is a big Sam
example because match it has lots of its
own keys you know so the problem with
simple code is that when you have some
other mods minor motto major mods such
as magic that will overwrite some of
your keys so some keys will start to not
work that is a problem there is no
solution to you know to fix everything
perfectly you either go with complex
code or you have simple code that you
know some keys doesn't doesn't work if
you have some mods you know that's
that's just a situation so in stuff like
easy
the code is extremely simple that's the
way I want right now it's like 10,000
lines for example let's see let's go to
sapphire keys and so four thousand four
thousand lines and but however the code
is extremely simple every and anyone can
understand it and you can modify it to
the way you like on the other hand for a
go Emacs mod you cannot modify it the
way you want but actually they provide a
go Emacs mod the code line by mad
fiddler he actually provide a system
where you can override keys so for
example in stuff like keys if you want
to override something you don't like you
just dive into the code you type into
the source code you just create a copy
of it modify it right away
you you can understand the code you can
know you know where to look for you can
just create your own version on the
other hand you cannot do that with a go
Emacs mod but however the Ergo Emacs mod
provides kind of a system where you
follow the instruction you know it's
like space max it creates a separate
layer where in this layer you can add
code to modify keys you know overwrite
keys things like that so that's the way
you know that goes so so space mac is
kind of similar they created a system
like a layer on top of Emacs so you no
longer to config directly to Emacs
rather you write convict that's for
space max this make space max translate
those codes to Emacs so I don't like
that okay so that's about space racks
so what's your question keyboard switch
oh okay my knee space max it's not
Richard Stallman's free software
foundation yeah well he's been kicked
out so another question Erik Carson have
you looked at Terry Davis in his temple
OS that is a frequently asked question
because every nerd comes to my live show
always ask me that why I know why
because Terry Davis and his temple or a
state Terry Davis is known well known
because he's a nut job you know he's a
fringe of society because he's got this
psychological this severe psychological
problem this see schizophrenia which is
a it's not just a personality disorder
but rather it's a physical mental
illness it's a because you see illusions
you see illusions you hear and you know
see things that's not there you see the
different reality so he's got that
problem and he you know he sadly he he
he is dead he's run over by a train and
you know two years ago two or three
years ago we don't know it's a suicide
or not so he's you know he's very kind
of popular among you know online ammo
nuts you know and that's kind of a pub
you know and you know so people kind of
associate me with him too because I'm
also kind of the fringe you know with
the strange ideas you know I but what I
want to say is that I think it's a sad
situation you know he becomes famous not
because people actually want to help him
you know some people can help him but
but half of the reason he's famous
people talk about him all the time is
because he's drama
he's a showcase you know he's like
enric you go you know when there's a
train wreck you go and watch it
well what happened Oh dramatic you know
oh the train killed people look look
train wreck you know so people talk
about him all the time
like on the full Chan on the Chan on
Hacker News you know some people among
these you know these spectators you know
like there are 10% who actually do good
to him you know reach out or donate him
monies things like that you know do good
hit for him the rest 10% are just
spectators you know and spread you know
he's you know this Dave Terry Davis guy
so why does this happen so I mean you
cannot blame these people these
spectators like everyone you go when
there's accident you know the car runs
someone down you could watch it you know
and you you tell people that's normal
humanity you know and this is with us
for you know for thousands of years but
this one thing I want to say is that the
modern society you know like 100 years
ago 100 years ago when there is a drama
you know they don't spread like the
internet you know there's no internet so
when did when there's a drama use you
spread by visually like you use actually
see your car accident then you tell your
friends your town your neighbors so this
actually in real life that is when
there's a drama it happens in real life
awesome murder happens you know murder
or rape you know things like that that's
in real life so the trauma are kind of
spread more slowly but but still is in
real life but now since the internet and
especially be deep bye-bye because of
these Facebook and Twitter this
commercial you know scumbags you begin
to spread drama just for the drama you
know the like far removed from any real
life or CV
considerations you just spread you know
it's just like Oh Oh Terry Davis you
know look at this crazy guy oh god this
is you know you can post it you know it
is present spread so that's that that
made the problem kind of was that made
the problem was so that's what I have to
say about Terry Davis in tempo OS you
know he's kind of he's very he's sort of
genius in some way you know he I've seen
tempo s so it's you know it takes great
mind to create that it's not trivial you
know not you know he's so he's a fairly
above average programmer that's how I
say that's all I can say so that's about
that so space Mac is moto2 you only have
single key command like yeah that's
space mod is a space max is Evo mod it's
using emo marquee binding so looks like
you guys don't know the things okay so
you you might so let me tell you about
stuff like this
sapphire kisses model so why don't I
just use Evo mod because evil mod or vim
they are key binding is historic oh it's
not efficient okay it's not from the
ground up efficient so soft like ease is
much more efficient that's what I claim
yeah you know I can actually tell you
it's actually a fact
scoff like ease is much more efficient
than vim or evil mod because every key
binding every key choice you know where
the what key what command you put - what
key is based on statistics so that's my
that's a ficus
good morning Reaper so I'm going to
actually close down I've been talking
for too long so and today's
topic is supposed to be oh my god
supposed to be keyboard and and we
already talked for 14 minutes after an
hour already
so bar says about process about process
about key switches well four key
switches you know but as far as you are
concerned you know so I think you
already know most of it so you go to my
keyboard blog and go to design of
computer keyboards which is on the Left
pen panel over here then you click key
switch so this page tells you all about
key switches I guess most of you already
know this so buddy's just asking so what
what is do you have a specific questions
or something about key switches so
actually that's about it for me today so
key switches you guys can read about it
let's see what and I then yeah so like
so that's it I think so thank you guys
for watching so go through my keyboard
blog buy my stuff Oh Pedro me patreon
patreon me oil stuff my my tutorials
okay that's it for today and sohbat
okay so Bart says what's your favorite
one so my favorite keybinding I mean my
favorite my mechanical key switch is
probably read ok Cherry MX read I want
it to be light so I actually I can show
you okay so actually but I I need to go
to a bathroom
so let's do five more minutes I'm gonna
talk more about keyboard stuff okay
let's why not
so I mean I'm going to show you my
Kinesis this is using a brown switch
actually so let's see if I can press it
okay so this is Kinesis brown switches
Brown let's see if you can hear it no
you cannot put weight huh hold on a
second
okay that's Kinesis brow meanwhile I
have this ultimate hacking keyboard it's
on my website you can find and this is
red switch okay let's see if I can do
this properly okay here okay so let's
switch is much more smoother now this
one is not cherry MX red cherry MX red
but it's a this one is actually from
China from company made by China which
is I think better okay so this is cherry
MX red actually so I can put them apart
and you can see - so here is my key
switch tester if you guys don't know and
this is my key pool so actually so I
have a hard time holding a camera but
you can see you know you can buy these
switch testers on Amazon like $10 or $15
and this is the key for you pull it off
so that's blue
you pull it off that's brown oops
you pull this off so that's red that's
black black is black is like red strong
strong resistance but smooth so this is
red very smooth black is smooth but
stronger resistance this is Brown
Brown's got a prick stupid camera stupid
logitech camera there Brown is quickly
there's a slight quick and blue is some
of the most quickly stupid camera blue
is the most quickly it may actually make
us makes a noise and so my favorite is
red because I wanted once you type a lot
I mean really a lot a lot you I think
you prefer we read but for most
programmers you guys you probably don't
type that much so brown and blue is good
for you I think but I think if you
really type a lot like if you measure
lock your keystrokes then you'll find
[Music]
maybe you are like red better
yeah Oh rings so orience can make it
quieter and so actually that's about it
today
I mean keyboard switch so here is a
picture of the mechanism you know Browns
got this click you see that over there
that is the click that's that's what I'd
make that's what made it quick and blue
Scott a quick to but more quickly okay I
don't know what I'm doing so this is a
linear switch linear switch I think it's
fantastic I mean I mean this is an
optical switch optical switch is
fantastic okay so and you can buy you
can buy optical switch by so there's
woman G switch yeah we should talk about
this but it's kind of latest data I
gotta go I'm gonna go to the bathroom
mister so this guy this this guy Chris
hiya son twenty-two very
he's a keyboard switch expert he's a key
switch expert so he has reviewed the
Roman G okay so this is Logitech Roman G
switch and there okay here is optical
switch here is optical switch an optical
switch I think it's great and you can
buy them too this keyboard is also very
cheap like forty dollars of them
something so I recommend it so if you
just want a plain flat keyboard
I actually recommend this optical switch
keyboard
okay okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching bye guys
what's going on with this