check good morning everyone I'm sorry
I'm late and welcome to another cloud
talk show and today is August 17th 2019
so good morning Tech ways good morning
noon Bernie and you guys can hear me now
good morning weebo so what what is
today's topic type in the chat please
pick a topic and let's begin
so guys pick a topic and let's let's
begin let's see what is is okay so
Santosh Oh Kuno Bernie Sanders 2028
elite gnu emacs user that's long travel
ganda name z tron crazy random chat okay
let's do random chat okay so it looks
like people like that and which is
actually easier to do then you know for
example doing a JavaScript tutorial or
something you know focus that is
actually harder so random chat okay so
but let's talk about let me show you
okay Emacs completion actually I don't
know much about I mean I probably don't
have much to show you about that let's
let me begin the saw start command log
mod so in this window you can see all my
Emacs commands such as forward backward
up arrow previous line next line and so
on and okay Emacs completion you know so
so what package do you use for Emacs
completion okay so let me talk about
Emacs coefficient it and then let's talk
about some random stuff and if you have
any questions any suggestions opinions
just post it you know then we can talk
about that
Emacs completion so good know Bernie so
let me know let us know like what
package do you use I can explain to you
what is my situation with completion
basically I do not use any of the
confusion packages so let's let's write
down let's write out today's topics
Emacs completion okay then
there are two very popular Emacs
completion packages and those are two
most popular P or P you AR AR ones okay
one is called autocomplete and the other
one is anyone know what's the other one
so one is autocomplete the other one is
called well I don't remember so let's so
what we do is we're gonna we're gonna
let go to mapa these packages so called
list packages the command these packages
okay yeah company you are right thank
you so the other very popular completion
packages company which is silly name it
stand for like complete complete any you
know but it names so it's company so
anyway so there are two completion very
popular completion packages these are
you know these are at least ten years or
something like that both of them now the
autocomplete is is their first it's
written by a Japanese guy you know in
Japan but then people start to
contribute and it seems like people
noticed a problem is that it's hard to
extend therefore this guy created a fork
I think you know originally was a folk
so he created the company mod which is I
think more popular today a good morning
g-good morning green deck good morning
battle of MU great to see you guys so
they are too so we gonna talk about
random topic but first thing we're gonna
talk a little bit about Emacs completion
so so know Bernie if you have specific
questions like type it okay because
because I don't yeah I don't know if you
have specific questions or like what
programming language are you coding are
you needing completion
for particular language or you are just
interested in my general view like what
do what do i do you know you know the
more information the better you know I
can talk about things you know gets more
interesting so right now I'm just you
know talking generally about my
completions in Emacs so you have auto
complete bio Japanese which is the first
thing you have company mod which is I
think or engine or your folk then
company mod you know I don't you I don't
use them because well I guess you can
say it for two reasons one reason the
first reason is that they are they are
kind of a hack let's install company
Mart okay let's see you see because I
don't use any I I use very few packages
so let's go to my Emacs directory dot
Emacs start be ALPA go into the
directory so Co MP so I don't have you
know I don't have it installed at this
is all the packages I use I don't use a
sink I don't use stash I despise this
this wrapper to emag list - and they
write they become popular because they
kind of they provide a wrapper to Lisp
functions so that for any beginner you
know or not very experienced these
programmers you can just use these -
there's a bunch of others F - and you
know you know they are basically
wrappers to the Emacs Lisp language such
that you know for example - is for
dealing with all lists I think list data
type let's see so - by this guy okay -
well this you know good guy and - is for
yeah list API so you see emag list we
say old language and and I'm gonna
answer answer
okay so you Maggie's is 800 language and
the dev you know the Emacs Lisp step
team has problems as lots of issues the
communication the mentality the codes
problem so they don't they don't change
they don't fix things quickly you know
it's almost impossible to do so and
every time you contribute you have to
sign papers you know it's very
controversial so it's like sluggish it
doesn't move then mail power came alone
so everyone just you know push to mail
path so mail piles like tens of
thousands packages and one of the issue
with emag list visa it doesn't grow you
know and it's very hard to get anything
to talk to the developers because
there's political fight there's
different personalities there's simply
some some of the old Dave have strong
attitude you know they don't you know
it's rather a problem compared to you
know open source stuff in general so
eMac this has been stagnating for like
you know twenty thirty years you know
very you know once a while every five
years you have maybe one change so so
email is you know when you want to
manipulate list for example in Python
you have a race you know JavaScript
array so list you have a bunch of
functions right and and and and for Opie
languages such as Ruby or Python you
have a hash table or dictionary then you
have all the methods that manipulate the
the hash table you know like you know
the dot notation you just you have a
hash table or array then you thought
then whatever you know you have a set of
all functions that can work on the list
not so with Emacs I mean the point I'm
saying is that all the functions that
work on list you can see them you know
it's all there you know it's easy to see
also in documentation but Emacs is more
of a functional language
but still you should be able to have all
the list of functions that work on lists
and they should all have consistent
interface for example the first argument
should be you know the list you want to
change the second argument you know like
the items to move removable things like
that but however emag based the
functions that works on lists are not
consistent that's one problem but also
they are scattered all over the emag
list documentation you know it's like
some you know like docked eMac this
documentation is also a old you know is
you know thirty years old the structure
I haven't been changed
you have the structure organization of
eMac beasts manual has not been changed
for for like thirty years something like
that you know here's the Emax list of
documentation so if you for example if
you lease program eMac beast you want to
walk you know you you need from
functions that work on least this is
there is no way to find you know one
page that lists all the list functions
instead instead they are scattered in
okay here you have least you know
consoles this related predicate sleaze
you know it's not just here they are
also its list so much functions in other
pages you have to you have to go you
know so so there's no coherent you know
so to begin at least email its
programmers it's it's a problem it's
hard
therefore these people created this for
example this guy created this - you know
there are so many things I don't like it
about it you know so many aspect and
mentality first of all notice the name -
you know it it's a pig a pig named it
doesn't indicate anything anything about
Beast you know it doesn't say this
manipulation function so you know at
least you have to anyway that that's
that's naming that that's one thing okay
- you know like it's like
popular fashionable you know the - and
okay so what does this package to you
know basically it's a it's basically
like rapper so if it's like a API so it
provides a consistent you know you have
all these functions that work on lists
and they have all unified kind of
consistent interface you know like which
argument goes where and and they they
are basically wrappers to the Emax these
list functions you know so so this is
you know for beginner programmers is
this is actually fantastic as opposed
it's very practical you know because so
there are many issues you see because
well yeah it's practical but you know
notice you know first of all you should
be what really should happen is you
should we should get list eMac this for
the language to go to you know if
there's a problem fix it they're not
adding a wrapper you know then then
there are also other issues you see
another issue is for example this is an
example where how the Emacs new dev you
know they have problems they did they
don't you know they don't admit like
every time you talk to Emacs people
phonetics they they say oh you are a
troll you know they don't agree well I
think I think eMac beast you know dev is
great it's the most wonderful
polite helpful place you know people say
that you go to Reddit you hear people
say that all the time you know and when
you say something they disagree they
they you know you get banned oh you get
you know vote it down nobody see your
messages or you know things like that
this this is the you know it happens in
every almost every programming language
you know they are anyway so you first of
all you should actually it indicates
several problems one is that Elise is
not going you know it's it's very bad
this means Elise is very bad but when
you talk to the Emacs phonetics they do
say they say Oh Elise eMac miss miss the
greatest language you know
you know this package the existence and
popularity this is one of the most
popular land package on ALPA the top top
five top five okay and with tens of
thousands or hundred thousand downloads
and lots of packages require these - ok
this - package so this you know we can
see that this indicates several problems
one is at least language email is for
list manipulation is manipulation is
pretty lousy there's a problem you need
we need to fix that it also indicates
that the new dev Scott problems they got
you know as a organization that work on
a Mac Emacs you know they've got
problems because otherwise this guy can
simply hey say hey you know I got this
package you know can we you know you
don't need this package because you can
dedicate your effort to just you know we
just we will have the much improved eMac
Lisp you know language and also this
indicates the Emacs manual problem you
know Emacs menu when you talk to people
they say oh this this is the greatest
writing and so on crap it's got lots of
problems so that's you know so that
problem you know eMac this problem in
Emacs menu problem and also political
problem because this is notice this is
on alpha arm alpha which is which is
entirely outside of the new you know
organization free software foundation
it's entirely different organization and
so why is my Appa so popular
meanwhile the GU news ALPA you know they
also have a repository freeze from free
software foundation why is our pod you
know alpha has you know maybe five
thousand packages but a male power a
hundred thousand packages why is that
because in order to contribute to to
have your package to on the new alpha
server you need to sign a agreement
basically says you know from from this
day on the copyright belongs to you you
know that's you have to do that and
and you know a few years ago you have
its needs to be done in written form
like mail but today you can do it
digitally but I had you know I have
signed ago Emacs I have went through the
process it's very unpleasant and so lots
of problems ok and and also you know as
many programmers we programmers
especially these programmers you know we
have a kind of thing for elegance of the
programming language you know that that
is why a lot of lots of us you know like
Lisp but this also indicates a problem
with the well should I say that I don't
I don't know I I forgot what's the point
I'm trying to say so anyways so there is
this - ok let's go to male pilots show
something well I got 14 people watching
me episode - is one of them oh yeah
grapple ok I remember what I want to say
you know you see so this is actually a
rapper you know it you know it does you
know it adds some functionalities but
mostly you know like 80% it's a rapper
to the Emacs Lisp you know functions you
know so it's it's inefficient you know
it's inefficient you know you you you
when you program a language you don't
work over through a rapper you know like
it's like JavaScript you code typescript
which is a wrapper to JavaScript because
it provides types then you compare
JavaScript that's not a good thing you
know you rather work directly you know
so there are these aspects I don't like
it and also it's this is not this this
package is not following the gloom emag
lisp programming convention for example
you have you have look at these names
okay this function names start with a -
okay let me let me show the list
matching line sniffing okay so use okay
I know why you know why it's called -
because every function M
- that that I don't like either because
let's say you know it's a it's a tactic
it's it's kind of the low you know
devious means to capture popularity
you know because by using a - so you
know so it's extremely easy to notice
and you know to use this package because
everything just that start you know but
however to the whole wider community of
Lisp this is no good because you you are
making something standing out for
yourself then tomorrow I'm gonna start a
package that you know every function
name start with the dot you know it's
even easier than your - you see but if I
do that's not good
you know because then everyone you know
every Joe start I'm going to make create
a package so I become famous you know
and I'm gonna going to use the tactic so
my all my function name start with the
dot you know everyone start to do their
things that's no good you know and gluey
max list convention you know they have
you know if you read the Emacs menu
there's a section about Commission you
know you don't do this you can this is
not allowed I mean you are not supposed
to you know you supposed to start
functioning with the - that is just your
tactic you know your kind of method to
get your package you know for yourself
so but but when you then you look at the
Emacs community you know every day they
are like oh helping each other and so
good they call me a troll because I
criticize all the time but that you
never hear you never hear people
criticize anything about the - you know
it's like it's like you know it's a it's
all of a phony you know these people you
know what so what do you you know the
you know people are like that you know
but what you have to do you know you so
this guy I haven't seen him done but you
know he's a great guy I think he's also
the the guy who started Emacs rocks
which is great
very funny very well done Emacs tutorial
Emacs rocks and very well prepared
you know each video is only like five
minutes but it's it's tense with
information and also funny and and you
can useful let's let's see
Emacs rocks so I'm digressing a lot but
anyway but today we are like random
topic right so there it is Emacs rocks
so you have to where's this video okay
there there is a video so this is very
popular and very good so I do recommend
it but I think it is him right let's
does anyone know is that same right yeah
I'm free show Mac now swing from from
Northern Europe's Scandinavia I think
right so all these problems you know
that's you know so therefore I don't
like it and now like every package you
install almost all require - you know
this is ok no good this is like you know
usually just you learn this we just use
the core functions you have you know you
you so anyway so yeah so anyway so
that's about - so ok I was saying I
don't use much packages - was required
you know these are sync - git commit
they are all required by magic magic is
the one I use so much magic requires all
that and I use commodity which is for go
language then key frequency is great
because let's see let me show you key
frequency show now this records this is
a log of all your other commands I
coding Emacs I mean this must be several
months old so you can see I've code the
previous line you know to two hundred
thousand times you know
you know so this is good for when you
want to find out what which keybinding
use you use most often then you can you
know create a easier key binding or if
you are designing key binding like I am
folk stuff like ease you know so this is
good to use you know so this is key
frequency mod so that's that and okay
and smacks smacks is great this is a
replacement for MX like meta X I can
transmit IX you have very nice
completions and you also have it
remembers you know which command you
call the most so when you type for
example if I type key it will list all
the commands that contains the word tea
but ordered in the way that the you know
the one I used most often will come on
top so that's snakes which is a
replacement for meta X and that's it
that's so I use snakes match it key
frequency go mod that's the only four
packages else outside other people's
packages I use or the all the rest there
you see are the kind of requirements
depend dependencies I don't really like
when you install a package I don't like
those that install dependencies you know
you know like in a Java Lent in a job in
a JavaScript land npm when you install a
package install 100 others literally
like you you need a package you install
it it has like ten different
dependencies
each one has came or dependencies so I
did I've seen you know this this is true
when you install one package littered
you know you might end up with 100 just
for that one package then you need other
packages you know my god javascript so
Emacs is you know eMac this piece kind
you know I wouldn't say but
maybe he's going in that direction I
don't you know that's no good because
then well part of the reason is you know
a society you know we advanced
technology and more programmers people
has less time you you have less and less
you know really programmers you know who
knows a lot so a lot of programmers you
just you know you just pull libraries so
is so it's kind of like a bloat you know
you you don't know what you're doing you
just know okay this website tells me to
do this then I can do you know I can
have I can do what I want so to do this
you just you just type this download
this library that library download ten
hundred others that's you know that's
what happens today so that's about the
packages I use now I was going to I was
going to install company Mart and let me
explain so why I don't like it well I
think it's good package okay I mean when
I talk about things like many of these
are just my own opinions like you don't
have to follow I'm just giving you my
opinions but these are good packages you
know - I'm pretty sure it's very well
written and good you know so I'm going
to install company company model so
lease packages okay I call these
packages then search for conp a company
mod CEO MPA in okay there it is
okay company mod module module detects
confusion framework okay let's see what
it is okay and let's install it install
okay what bad request what the all
right you see that new again because
this is from guna you know this they
always have problems you should install
from the mail pod
you know what's the arrow says like
network problem something
huh
so okay here's company ma let's try it
again installed it's just in storage
okay so it's installed by the way it
says company is an available obsolete
package you know lots of mail for
packages says that does anyone know why
what does it mean like is a available
obsolete package does anyone know let's
search for it
oh jeez an available absolute package
yeah what what you know what
it's mean did you know I've seen this
for years I I don't know what it does
anyone know so okay so we I just
installed company ma close it close it
close it close it
okay that's let's start a new buffer and
switch to Sai Emacs Li smart then let's
say D fun okay let's say D fun oh do I
have to turn comedy Madan
anyway I use my own confusion like you
know for example I press for example I
press I want to defund hype recipe you
know I press ENTER this defend and I
press into a space again there it is
there it is I don't use you know company
convey mod you know say the variables I
type s space set Q that's what I want
space I got the thing you know and same
thing with JavaScript you know switch to
a JavaScript mod and you know so
JavaScript let's say C is for constant
you see C space okay that's good that's
what I want and L space you know I have
let and array prototype
array.prototype has something okay
for each okay okay there it is
you see that's what that's that's the
completion based on a brief and based on
based based on a brief basically so you
know I this is okay so let me show you
so this is some JavaScript mod okay I'm
gonna talk about this stuff okay so and
I have saw Emacs lease mod then I have
Sarge TM l mod and then I have saw CSS
Mart okay let me demo CSS Mart for a bit
okay so let's for example let's go split
a window go to the top there is a CSS
file open it so you can see it's in my
CSS mod go to the top go to the top and
enter what something is wrong there I
need to find out anyway so I want to say
let's say dive ok dive and that and I
let's say display I press the space this
way that's what I want space okay then
you know I mean I'm break okay oh I can
say table and stuff let's say n space
marching okay C space color space red
okay that's what I want you know so this
is my kind of my home cooked a brief
abbreviation conviction system okay now
but oh these are my own mods but if you
don't want to use them you know yeah you
you know you you know because you
already have some other solutions that's
better for you so if you don't use them
you
also easily trivially create your own a
brief system just like just like you
know the example I have demonstrated you
can do a trivial trivially let's go to
my Emacs blog so if you just go through
my Emacs website practical Emacs then
you go to buffer topics Emacs fine
replace copy/paste topic and do topic
Unicode topic font white space rectangle
shell
there's sorry there's a editing topic
just search for a brief abbr ok so no
wait abb ok Emacs efficiency topic at
the bottom so a brief mod so in this
page I show you it's easy very easy ok
in 5 minutes you can set up any or brief
just like item what I demonstrated you
know I just like that wait ok so yeah so
just like you know for example s space
space you see M for messages space your
message that's a function right that's
that's to print something space you know
then you have that and the letter the
brief letter is based on how frequent
that function is used so the most
frequent you know completion function
name has one one single letter such as
message like when you Cody this you want
to print all the time you know to see
what's going on and D define function t4
defines also you know very popular so if
you know let me show you the code ok so
here is the code it's such for a brief
ok let me go to the brief section
yeah so let's go there there it is so
you see this or this list let's go to
the top of the list
okay so there you see define a brief
table it's you know see for contact
let's try and see space see cat
space you see you know conquer extreme
TiVoed if an f4 format iPhone insert you
know so here is my brief you know you
you you know I explained in this file
how to do that you can do it without
needing to create a new mod you know you
just copy this putting your init file
and I'll be it and also several months
ago I have a video tutorial on Emacs a
brief so so you can try that so second
so let me I'm going to read the comments
on second imma get rid of this image so
that is about a brief that is about my
own completion system and for example I
code goal and so new buffer switch to
Golan oh I don't have my own goal and
mod so I call me ty x go mod okay so
this is some someone else's smart okay
but now I want abbreviation you know I
need to start to code : I need
abbreviation so what I do I I type g 3o
k space oh okay wait g space okay let's
know geo space there it is you see i
have a go templates now let's save it xx
star geo okay let's run it okay
now the answer is 33 which is correct
you see so I stuck I can start to code :
now now suppose I need to define a
function so function is F space I got a
function template you see but this is
not not my Ahmad so how did I do
a brief let's go bookmark to Maya
breathe fire okay so a brief so here is
my a brief file so you know 600 lines
and you can see : parties here you see
and the advantage here is that at any
time like like right now I'm coding :
I can type a for return that's right
okay so I can pee for print you see P
space is for print now suppose there is
something I need let's say min okay
let's say I need this I need a shortcut
for men I don't have it you know and it
so happens I find I need it often so I
can define it right away in for example
let me show you so I want a brief that
expand to this okay I want em to become
this so I just I just go open my a brief
file through big bookmark then I just
type okay here paste oh wait I copy that
duplicate em and this part will be
whatever is the brief I want
so the brief I want is let's say that
okay so I paste it here you see that
line okay it's now it's good now load
you eval buffer the whole file it's done
I go back here M enter you see is it's
so convenient M internal you see it's
super powerful okay not indeed the file
I don't need that
Avada buffer close it and Emacs Lisp
close it don't say close it okay so
there's another JavaScript one okay so
so okay that's about abbreviation and so
that's this is okay so this is what I do
for completion and abbreviation
I basically just rely on abbreviation
whenever I need something completion I
just add it right away
like you know today add it right away
you know after a while I look at my OB
file a lot of them I don't use anymore I
remove them now now let's see let's try
company mod ok meta ex wait hold on
let's go to open a new buffer meta X
Emacs this mod ok now this is in Emacs
be smart let's let's do different ok TEF
tab okay so I need let's turn on company
mod meta x c om PA and y dash mod ok
it says enabled now TAF let's try again
te f oh there it is you know you don't
even have to press any key
okay so d fu well
DF u NT Y doesn't have a div what
doesn't have the fun that's my
complaints whenever I DF u Y doesn't
have different what's the problem
okay so but before I explain the problem
I mean I don't know what is a problem
what is the problem so and I mean about
the know the company mod so TF okay let
me talk about some of the issues with
company mod let's see okay so de f you
see so now it pops up this this thing
you know this this widget did in the
pop-up window you know how that is
implemented that is a hack that is one
of the biggest hack you know you know
why this happened
you know you know why DF okay because
Emacs does not have a framework or API
that does you know this widget textual
widget pops up there is no such
framework instead so how they do this
they do it by Emacs has this I'm pretty
sure about this okay but don't take my
word for it so I be the I'm pretty sure
you know this is implemented by let me
show you how how it is it's a hack it's
a giant huge hack okay
and this is why in the other days with
the autocomplete mod sometimes it
crashes Emacs like you know when you
have this probably crap crash Emacs so
what so how is that done you if you go
to practical eMac please wait go through
write major mod and go to the bottom
okay good here's how to write a major
mod then look at overlay highlighting
this is how it is done it is using the
mechanism of overlay
okay I'm not in a position to explain
the details like because I have to look
at I don't know I haven't looked into
but it that's I believe I looked at it
just a little bit you know several years
ago and I you know and I kind of got
confirmation you know it's a hack
because Emacs does not have you Magnus
does not have a framework or API or a
system to do these pop-ups so instead so
basically this is done by you know you
just you just go to a position and this
ray or textile you know so you do it
each one of these you got you go to a
position disappear text and you know and
you you write rappers you know functions
that eventually becomes higher higher
level but it's very is it's not you know
as far as I know okay it's not the
proper system but also what you know
what is a proper system let me show you
what is a proper system control control
meta I you see that mini buffer this is
the proper system for Emacs completion
okay now if the company mod is actually
done with this then I like okay I accept
I approve this is the proper way to for
completion to walk you know you might
say oh but it's not convenient because
it is at the bottom that is true so if
you want to fix that you know top to the
GUI Mac step get them to fix this
framework you know that is the proper
this is a proper mechanism proper
framework for completion you know you
know you know but but this you know
although it's convenient it's a hack
it's I know because you know I you know
I look underneath you know but to most
people you just look at things you don't
think about you know what's actually
working how it works in underneath okay
with I said you know I I you know
company mod
I guess it works you know it's
convenient yeah for for me I don't use
it because I don't like this idea this
hack and I don't like this
this tiny you know window I rather
prefer you know let me tell you why I
prefer this this full completion okay
you see that now that is the traditional
Emacs way everything is text and you
have power let me explain so I want I
want all the commands starting with
death now I can switch with a switch to
completion you know you see there's a
buffer that then you can see you see now
I got the whole thing I can copy it I
can open up new buffer paste it I can
start to manipulate it for example let
me let me show you this command
metarex space to new line okay okay
that's not what you want but anyway okay
in any way sure white space so what are
these okay these are tabs so replace
replace tab by return new line okay
replace all that's what I like you know
I you know I you know I have at least
you know I like I can manipulate it I
can reorder it again okay let's do this
select all sort oh wait oh no and press
the wrong key sort you see I got them
sorted then then remove that crap you
know then you know I can do lots of
things you know this is the power of
Emacs the traditional way it's the same
reason many people like Oakmont
because everything is text square you
can manipulate instead of you know video
input boxes you know you have to mouse
click to this to focus on this input box
or that you know things like that so
also another thing important to mention
is the Y snippet mod that's also no good
okay just use a brief a brief can do
anything everything
why is no good why snippet mod is ten
years is like ten years old you know it
began in 2008 also and I in the
beginning I liked it very much because
you don't have to know lease you know
you can define your brief you know
templates by you know writing a file and
you know so that is a huge that's very
powerful you know you don't require
people to know lists to create templates
and you know why snip it but since I
learned a brief you know since I started
to actually learn the Emacs lists you
know default you know a phone call a
brief system I don't need you know I
don't even you know I don't need my
snakes watch my snippet which is very
very complicated you know you look at
their code you know the X 10,000 20,000
lines you know very just just like just
like that company you know with that pop
up that's very complicated underneath
you know it's like let me show you this
okay let me show you let me show you
this okay not keyboards language Aman
Linux I'm gonna show you this okay
compliant for being hacker code there's
a thing I want to show you okay it is
this one coding while learning at
college is like that coding for a
project in real job it's like that but
there's one more thing let me show you
this this okay you see that then you
magnify okay so anyway so you see what I
deal with what I what I deal with as a
web dev on a daily basis portrayed as a
house so kind can you fix this bug for
me you know
it shows a beautiful house and no
problem let me take a look at the code
and then they inside the house it's like
garbage you know the house of a garbage
that is what it is like you know for
that company mod and why I snippet you
know underneath is like crap so I don't
like hack I don't need you know this
little pop-up you know special pop-up
and also with my snippet you have this
places like like let me show you an
example okay y snippet so new buffer
Syed is smart - enter enter okay t enter
enter then you get that okay so when you
have a function usually you have X Y Z
right okay in this view D you don't need
a coma so you know you have many
arguments to a function when you when
you use Y snippet it
for example format okay format is one of
the command that has several options you
know when you use Y snippet it has these
so-called stops like you press tab you
first tab to to put you know then the
CUSO is face here and meanwhile you
cannot do anything you cannot move coos
afridi you cannot you know move by word
you cannot do anything
you are thick you know at for a period
of time the only key you can press this
tab you press the tab again you your
cursor moves to the next position that
it's like a straitjacket you know you
cannot move you can only do this thing
at one time you know that's that's why
that's why I sniff it so I don't like
that I prefer you know just type the
whole thing you know I can you know I
have powerful you know kusa movement I
can go to anywhere I want you know I
don't want you to limit me to these
positions so that's about that's about
the y snippet so let's see what we wear
my so let's go back to the
[Music]
so this is okay so that was my curse
that close that close that no save okay
so let's back so why a snip pit let's
mention that I'm gonna abso after this
then I'm gonna be the comments don't
like autocomplete because the pop-up is
a hack it is based on is it's it is
based on the overlay overlay is a
mechanism to to place a text anything
anywhere in the buffer yeah so that is
what so if you read this page you'll
find yeah let me post a link if you read
page this that page you can easily you
know understand what overlay is about
okay so the purpose of overlays allows
you to place you know it's like a it's
like a sticker you know like yeah you
know like stick notes you know is it's
almost like a stick it notes you know
you can you know you can stick it any
any you can place it anywhere it's kind
of like that so that is how that you
know that company mod is done
wait so if it uses the mini buffer then
I would like it much better okay that's
about the company mod now why a snippet
I don't think it is necessary
once you learn about a brief okay once
you know about Emacs default Abbey
mechanism and I don't like why snippet
because it almost always has these stops
you know that limits three whose
movements you know and you know like
when I press something I want to see the
whole template so I can think about you
know what I want to write you know I
don't want to only see part of it in you
know so that's but by the way you know
many of these can be configured but the
thing is you have to spend time there
you have to configure and configure
wires snippet you know but in fact you
don't need it you know this Emacs a
brief which is the fastest you know he
makes a brief the actual mechanism how
it works for example right now I type
you space it's you why are you so you
are spaces while you are you know I have
lots of briefs so this mechanism it's
actually returning in C so you know like
you cannot remove it you know so it's
this a brief mechanism is actually very
core fundamental you know to Emacs least
so so it's very fast and you can
thousands you know I have thousands of
briefs okay so so that is about
completion
that's my opinions about completions in
Emacs
okay so let's let me take a drink and
and let's read the comments
well okay so there are many ways to stop
a brief if you want to if you do not
want it to complete for example you well
I mean actually you know actually you
should read my tutorial okay I have like
a huge let me show you let me show you
okay so practical Emacs ABB ie a brief
mod so let me post the link yeah so I
would recommend just read my tutorial
big because and because okay so Emacs
has actually over ten commands dealing
with a brief so you can have you have a
command to add a brief interactivity you
don't like the way I do it is actually I
open my a brief file
this is Lisp code and actually I just
add you know modify this code like for
example you you okay you are I was here
you know I if I don't want it at deleted
eval and it's gone now if I type you
well nothing happens so this is this is
my personal way to edit or manipulate a
brief but this is not the normal you
know this is just my way now by Emacs
tradition you have like over ten
commands to deal with a prefix I assure
it here okay so I explained here you go
to this page you know if you follow this
page then this is the Emacs supposedly
traditional way to deal with a brief you
can't so you have like ten commands
actually it's two it's rather confusing
and many of these commands you don't
need so it's confusing to me and I don't
find it you know as good so I don't do
it that way so but anyway the point is
you have like over ten commands you know
if you don't want to complete you can
call the command first then type you
know something like you know like that
and you actually it's less efficient
that way you know if you'd for example
if I don't want the Uwharrie to expand I
just type T you know
then something mentally dirty actually
that's faster you know you might think
oh that's that's complicated but it's
actually faster I mean the alternative
is you al so you co command let's see
breathe you know they aren't like you
see there are so many of green commands
you there's one of them that that kind
of tower to stop or since something Oh
another way you can just press ctrl Q
okay now control Q okay now I type
something it doesn't you see it doesn't
expand you see okay wait wait let's see
you you are space okay you okay now you
are control q space you see that's how
so you can press ctrl Q that's one of
the way control Q is a general mechanism
to to make whatever character you type
next literal you know anyway that's so
that's that's about a brief okay yeah so
close my a brief IO so let's make that
that and
okay so so anyway so let me read the
comments saying so many dude your
bookshelf is standing tired my bookshelf
in the background it's very old
that's to Jack Ella Graham how are you
so let me read the comments okay so
let's see hi I'm pretty okay iris iris
are you still there and so okay
iris in hi Justin hi Justin
so iris says sorry answer this question
I actually select all copy shrink and
it's actually easier if I just read them
here so iris says please answer the
question I use sapphire keys and I love
it but when I switched windows or frame
it is hard to see if I mean in solo
camera mode
why when you switch windows of Fame's
are you see oh they're Irish Irish Irish
okay so okay so I I talked a lot and so
is Irish says when you switch windows of
frame it's hard to see if I mean some
white why because for weeks for example
for me when I'm in command MA
the cursor is always a square like right
now when I'm inside mother kusa is a
ping Iping so even if I switch window
you know you know I can just look at the
cursor right now it's rectangle so it's
a command mod switch cruiser it doesn't
change unless I switch to insert ma so I
don't see why that happens
you check check okay so okay questions
type it okay so I resize I mean change
color and shape every time there is a
frame a window and switch it shouldn't I
don't you know you should tell me what's
the problem I doesn't seems to happen
Matthew salsa greetings hi hey from a
posse Oh Matthew for spazio great
bathroom you hey bottom you are you
other people responsible for Lisp quite
elite right ISM well you know it's hard
to you know I don't want to say I don't
want to call them Eli Thyssen because
that has many meanings
you know like depending on what what do
you think what faction you are you know
to some people that thinks one thing you
know other people I don't you know it's
not I wouldn't it's it's not the elitism
that I'm I don't like rather it's just
it's just not working okay it's it's not
that it's most mostly code I would say
if you ask my opinion its code part of
the problem is the the free software
foundation you know the the ideology so
yeah and it's you know that let's not
get into that you know it so anyway so
that reminds me of the equally named
cryptocurrency which is absolute trash
oh okay so Bernie Sanders Wow the coupon
eases the aliefs starter manual is a
slow and repetitive to read exactly it's
like if you print it out it's 900 pages
okay and it's repetitive so it's like
you do oh my god it's you know it's and
the thing that the reason it's like that
is because it's written in the 1980s
okay you know like today you don't even
have the word
you anymore people like don't save
manual you know phone you know any
device you they don't come with a manual
anymore 1980s
everything has a manual you know use the
user's manual you know and it tends to
be elaborate you know chapter the
introduction you know chapter chapter
one chapter two you know manual you know
even TV has users upper you know
so-called operators manual let's let me
show you okay some of the history of
keyboards you know all these terminals
and stuff they have user's manuals or
operators manuals and or you know and
you you also have maintenance manuals
you know and Microsoft Word has manuals
Microsoft you know what manuals two
volumes you know back in 1990s beginning
in 2000 you know early 2000 2003 okay
manual stops they don't first of all
they don't print it anymore
it's just digital you know online then
even even online manual stops stops
oftentimes you don't have a manual just
like when you get the iPhone just use it
you don't know you you know so Emacs
menu is from I'd 1980s you see you got
you got this elaborate you know it's so
bad okay
oh by the way let's not confuse there
are two things there is the Emacs manual
and there is the Emacs Lisp manual okay
I was talking about Emacs Lisp manual it
act if you want to call this it is
necessary that you have to read it okay
English case English case inescapable
there is no alternative if you really
want to be expert of emag disp for
beginners you can try my tutorial okay I
mean you know yeah so so you know my
tutorial is pretty good for intro as I
say you know of course so if you you you
know you know you know too
get you begin with it's pretty good it's
and rather complete you will find
nowhere else you know online or printed
that's you know I am like 10 times more
complete yeah so so it's good but if you
you know beyond beyond my introduction
you you know you started to code writing
a mod readying a major mod writing some
you know thing you actually have to read
email is manual okay now that's about
email is menu 900 pages Emacs the Emacs
menu is also huge you know eight eight
hundred pages let me show you actually I
have it here go to my directory up up
the directory oops
I don't want to go it's here okay Emacs
menu this here is the V's manual open it
go down 945 about 945 pages HTML pages
940 the Emacs manual code to you know
740 pages okay Emacs menu is worse than
the e list menu because the Elysee menu
actually they contain technical details
you know you actually need to know on
the other hand the Emacs manual the
Emacs people they you know copy and
paste
they spent you know pages to tell you
what is the concept of copy the concept
of copying text the concept of pasting
text and so on so forth for text
replacement anything and you see why do
i you know to swear them because these
Emacs fanatics you know when you talk to
them
this Emacs dev or what you know many of
them up good people okay of course but
when you talk to you like they it's just
you know they nobody like nobody
criticized it if you dare to say a
little bit you know a rough about you
know criticize they nobody like you they
bang you
they'd vote you down down with it for
example that the fact these people it is
this kind of situation that brings the
technology the community that destroys
it okay oh my god Emacs Manuel you know
the shall we shall we actually try to
like read a few page you know actually I
have a HTML last version oh this is
peeled in in the Emacs editor like you
can read here's a Emacs manual you know
but I have I have like preet of
prettified you know HTML version I you
know I did
so look at this one random okay seven
chapter seven point five files okay text
that you inserting an eMac spoofer lasts
only as long as that's the Emacs session
to keep any text permanently you must
put it in a file go yourself
this this is the result of Emacs
fanatism they they telling you what the
file is and every time on reddit every
day every month okay every month people
will say oh please reads me the
menu please read the manual they tell
you to read menu but when you read menu
when you spend your time like it's been
chapters telling you about copy and what
is the concept of copy what is the
concept of file do you think that's
that's that's that's a good thing in X Y
X okay okay so let's go back to read the
comments okay so Emacs manual let's
close it close it close it close it you
know I always close my buffers like on
like most people who tends to leave
everything like often it's a case it's
very common where you will have you know
hundreds of buffers if you go to the you
know list buffers I don't do that I
don't like that I always scream you know
everything is like functional
then gun you know so what so I have one
key to close but you see I press one key
closed buffer okay we open s coast
yeah I want to close that one key you
see on the other hand if you a max you
you call the command Q buffer it asks
you do you want to do you actually
really want to say we want to keep a
buffer
even though it's already saved okay do
you really want to please say yes on
that okay let me tell you that is why
the reason people have a lot buffers
open is actually induced by the Emacs
command key Oh papa which actually
prompt you redundantly you know because
it's not annoying when you cure before
it and then you know like control XK
okay let's see if if I still remember
that correctly control XK oh yeah yeah I
can show XK or you know control X K ki
over then do you do you really want to
cure this well yes or no that's you know
be done done typing this is the Y you
know when you use a tool the way the two
is filled you know the two is designed
in every detail it actually induces it
it induce a certain workflow so it is my
opinion okay I had you know this is one
I had this opinion for long ten years
ago the reason you know sometimes you go
to a Mac you know Emacs community what
they we are brag you know like like oh
look I have three 300 buffers open you
know like wow you know like like the the
Linux you know the up time you know like
look you know three thousand hundred
files open that is actually induced by
the queue buffer is it's cumbersome
keystroke and redundant prompting for
confirmation so because of that then you
stop to using queue buffer
yeah you know you use the crit instead
there's a berry buffer
I think these very buffer yeah let's see
what's a key oh that don't that doesn't
have a key but usually in many mods you
can type Q which just buried like hide
it so so when you do this you know then
you accumulate buffers like some buffers
you open like month you know last month
it's still there you don't need it
anymore but it's yours
open open Romeo you could you you
contributed a fire great good for you so
what did you which one is it
okay so guys don't use the swear words
okay I tried to avoid it because Google
when you google see that they don't they
don't like it
Google you know Google these days are
been panning accounts and due to comment
see you know they don't care if it's you
or your followers you know making a
comments so so I'll try to avoid that so
Bernie says no so did I miss anything so
good new Bernie says free software
foundation gets arrogant with his
criticism yeah you know as yeah you know
I I don't want to criticize but every
time this I do it often so often that I
guess it's it's it's useless to me for
me to shy away anymore because every
other episode I I criticize about open
source you know Richard Stallman he's
got problems like 10 years ago I you
know like I just criticized the Emacs
menu
ten years ago I I you know I wrote to
him private mail you know I I you know I
think you know these Scott problems you
know I politely everything is very nice
and politely and and positive you know
so-called constructive
you know I said you know so maybe I can
I can help a create a rewrite a manual
you know so that so that you can reduce
the size you know by even have you know
because people people don't know what is
you know people don't know what many of
these basic things you know there are
many Emacs specific things you know like
Mark MX Mini buffer you see all note to
that but yeah but there's a lot
redundancy you can actually reduce
velocity by half at least
so I write to him and he's he you know
what he said you say yeah great great
idea you know why don't you email your
changes to me you know to then we'll go
from there you know that's that's very
typical of his
that's what he tells people you know so
what so you know I spent my life you
know I'm going to spend a month to make
improve the improve you know to walk
basically walk this thing out
send it to him for his approval if he
doesn't like it you know what what can
you do with it then my one you month
everybody's good that's that's that's a
good move that's that's what happens you
know anyway so battle muse is one of the
most important achievements from a
marketing managers perspective is to
make your product recognizable so Emacs
- it is from from their perspective a
good move yeah but that's what I'm
saying it's it's not that's a selfish
tactic that's kind of a selfish you know
not you know not not critical but it's
it's kind of like that and when you have
so many you know behavior so things like
that you know it's just no good you can
see it's no good just in says it should
be like - theater not pewter okay let me
by the way yeah - yeah that would be
better name let me mention okay okay
here's another thing about the mail pod
you see so once you see - becomes very
popular okay then the glue Emacs people
the dead okay they began you know they
started to fix the Emacs Lisp function
problem so today you do have some kind
of coherent list of functions okay this
is one of the very interesting and
critical social phenomenon because you
know this is a social phenomenon I mean
the Phenom phenomenon is this okay so
suppose you have a product Emacs or
whatever okay so I saw the product and I
make suggestions okay you don't and what
are the suggestions I make
you know you that you you don't care you
don't you may not care you know who
cares yours your suggestion anyone has
suggestions but once once you take the
effort to create your own version that
becomes competitive to to to them and
successful then they pay attention this
is like um this is similar to you know
every country they they say war and
stuff I mean they say peace you know we
want is peace no you don't get that the
only way you get the only way you win
respect is when you have nuclear weapon
okay that that is like the fundamental
truth and in the same thing in society
the deal you know the only way you know
do you get respect you see when you are
when you are powerful in which you
know everything is like you can be a
philosopher you can talk all the great
philosophy nobody you know practically
speaking very few people it you know
it's not very impactful it becomes super
you know every everyone pays attention
when you actually become a power that
that is the thing so similarly situation
happened here you see when you say if
you suggest to Emax people oh you know I
think you you know at least functions
needs you know this one you missing that
one they don't care they you know I you
know my book I have reported like tens
of bugs to Emax new Emacs they sit there
for 10 years after ten years I got a
reply after 10 years then he says you
know thank you you know a form if I and
something something you know
them you know after 10 years and not
just one well not this this is just just
not one time only it happens several
time in fact two weeks ago right now you
know it's in my email I don't want to
show it one of my Emacs bug report
that's 10 years old came up again you
know then people are discussing you know
why does it came up I know because I
started to do
videos you know talking about Emacs
these some people start to watch it you
know and then I know this because I can
I can see you know some you know people
start to link to my website you know
some articles ends so anyway so I got an
email my ten years old you know good
news report bug report then people
started to talk about it and you know it
makes you know how do you feel it feels
like testing that could you know leaking
a coin didn't like they don't they don't
give a about you actually you know
anyway so so yeah okay I wanted to show
you the the the today's emag list
functions emag these functions that work
some list today
now you have kind of comprehensive one
created by canoe dev you know this guy I
don't remember his name of him but it's
because he created that because because
the - it is because the - you know the -
becomes so popular and then the goon who
started to create this now they were
they have it - let me show you where
okay so it's down list these data
structures okay then you have let's see
okay sequence
please data structures let's look at
least okay now he is a basic tutorial
about list then sequence functions there
let's go back should be here their
sequence functions okay now let me show
you the part you see this list you see
this list this list 40 items this list
began about four years ago it's written
by I don't have the name handy but
he's on Twitter he's very active and
he's a devout Free Software Foundation
believer okay he he probably doesn't
like me okay
but anyway he created this this these 40
list functions kind of being a coherent
user interface
you know this came out because of the -
you know they wouldn't you know nobody
would say it like you you know you know
but you know I actually you know you can
see some of their discussions on the new
Emacs dev beast
so anyway so that's that okay so I guess
in my own right SNT I really you know
hate them the yeah so the the gaim Magna
also make X SNT you know those names
those names are like insult to my eye to
my brain you know you know so when I
criticize people you know you know I
want to say you know I guess he's a nice
guy in in always you know there's no you
know I'm I don't see I don't think he's
a bad person I think he's great you know
he's doing great things but it's just
this this this this kind of little
things I'm not sure how to put it any
any way
so JavaScript okay so let me let me
finish the comments quickly I think I
think mal pais bleeding edge and there
is a very separate stable repo okay well
my many one of the many things I school
at company is not allowed company is not
showing us absolute for me oh why is
that so
well my name you know there's an
interesting story about that my name in
Chinese is this okay that's Chinese
that's that's pronounced si sir and that
that means kill
okay so Li this is my first name Lee
okay B son and the name sir okay which
is saw and that is actually constructed
it's made up and it is my legal name but
okay so that name was created because of
my fascination with symmetry in math
there okay you can you guys can read the
article okay so that's the arrangement
kind of my name because of the symmetry
the symmetry of the letters XH and it is
my legal name just means a visual studio
called Sumi so with the large libraries
like see prospers company shows the
arguments for the functions oh okay
yeah so I I guess I you know I I should
be you know company is actually probably
useful you know I don't think a brief
can may not totally be place it may or
may not I don't know but you know I I
just use a breed myself because it's
it's faster it's simple you don't have
to install packages you know and you can
you can create your own set of
completions anytime and more efficient
because you can you can choose you know
one letter to add two letters
okay sometimes I use collab notebook for
Python okay I Python shrimp ow
so she about Ella Graham where you from
oh this this one is going or ninety
minutes
okay so let's finish it
snippet can be combined with company you
know you know cuz I have the snotty
amount for huge stars in Chinese
community what no that's think that your
description your disk how do you say
that description is incorrect your your
retail you your description is incorrect
that it's supposed to be the supposed to
be mochi as that how do you say that
[Music]
yeah
Eva that so the for dark stars something
like that anyway so
you know some like one time try some
Chinese Chinese blog they just made of
this they call me and it was and three
other people one of the one of the like
one of the kings in the dark side in
programming community but actually what
it means is that each of these four
people just have a weird that that is
actually the force I mean that is why
this face got created because these
people III knows this other three people
I've chatted with them like we are weird
that's that's why you know and you know
in a weird means dramatic you know
online usually we are guys you know if
you are dramatic you get becomes more
popular your fame so let's see what else
I think message is wink
we think so anything else comments oh oh
oh oh sham bow you are from China so in
China right now it's it's four o'clock
in the morning with what city shrimp I
love Ella Graham what city in China so I
mean if you know okay so I guess that's
it for today if you have any more
questions just type it I think that's it
if if I missed your questions just say
it and
I will be back be back tomorrow yes of
course I set out a schedule dinner and I
10 o clock for the next four or five
days
you saw my blog right path alone ooh so
thank you guys for coming and I had a
great great time if you like my stuff
okay by my tutorial by my tutorial
patreon me PayPal me you know you know
you know if you want to do that you know
how to find the links okay do that so
that you know I can have a happy life
and you know create more more
interesting things thank you guys bye