good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh today is 2020
January 19th Sunday and today's a hard
time so I have not been doing video in
the past few days I got things to do but
I haven't been doing them so but I'm
itchy to do one right now so this is
unprepared I mean yeah well kind of
unprepared so hello guys
Freddie and Emily so this is a new time
for my live stream videos I haven't been
doing video at this time for like four
for four months or five months something
like that
so Emily Emily is about to shower but
I'll join the fun when I get out okay
how long are you going to take the
shower for me usually it's like 20
minutes to 30 minutes and so I don't
know about you but today I think we are
only going to do like 30 minutes or
something so a Freddie Freeman course Oh
Freddie Freeman what's up Freddie
so we have this code so what am I going
to do Richard Stallman okay so my micro
vac checked check the new link okay so
I've been actually doing check the new
link so I have been doing a lot of Emax
and periodic dosage for one okay okay
fixing George
okay I'm live now let me go to the M
live on YouTube showing
so what am I going to say okay so I was
doing eMac stuff but let me fix that
link so let me so today is random topics
I'm just going to do some things random
and you can see my screen and whatever
I'm going to commit there are a few
things I want to do
so let's write a topic okay so let's
write a topic list and I'm also changing
my work flow kind of I'm not sure it's
going to work out because usually I have
my main window on the right side but I'm
trying to get into the hard habit of
putting the main window on the left side
but that's because well because the left
side seems to be the primary side for
most things for example when you do a
video in screen usually it shows on the
lower right you know that's kind of
convention so so I think it's it works
better if you have your main screen on
the left side long hot shower so
actually so I have quite a few things to
do so first of all let's start a exalt
mark can you guys see me so okay so
santockki Oh okay let's type a show
today's date and call XP X our new page
that creates a new HTML make a link and
copy that copy that and go here you see
I have my food and stuff okay so not
actual index this is a few days ago food
and today we have a new topic and also
another thing the fisherman and the
genie
oh fish okay let's put that there
okay so okay so today we don't have a
topic it's kind of random and just so if
you have a questions for me ask it today
okay so let me copy so because other
I'm going just to talk random and show
you basically how I work in Emacs so if
you go to the browser again refresh you
can see I moved those thing into the
link here and also let me move the
picture the food picture into the link
okay and I need to know what what is my
photo so actually so would it be okay if
I put the photo to the right let's see
over there would that work if I put it
the my head over there I guess your walk
right so let's try that you know for a
change you know that that's experiment
to enrich your life you know you have to
try things like the youtubers the
[ __ ] youtubers like this they are
conditioned to make money for themselves
and whatever you know anyways is stupid
you know it you have to try things like
this you know this yuppies you know
modern date people they they their life
is too good so they have they got into
this habit or this kind of thinking
about oh let's try to do some new thing
you never done before for months
so so a lot of the programmers and also
youtubers and girls and you know
whatever they you know they have this
thing about doing new things for a month
it's kind of idiotic you know they're
like you have to think about why why do
human animals have this thing you know
you know in the past thing you're
studying about past ten years why do
human animals have this thing about oh
let's we need to do something new like
try something new for for for for a
month or something you know normally
human animals you know that's not a
natural thing of how you know human
animals to do because basically a human
animal you you know you do walk
you go hunt or whatever you get food and
that's that's you know for most history
of human animals that's your life you
know you're just busy you get food you
go kill Tigers or whatever you get food
and and that's that's it for you know
that you don't you think you get tired
then you sleep but in modern days
suppose you know we are or we don't need
to do that anymore
so we are mostly we we drive to
Starbucks and to whatever and and chat
about iPhone about latest iPhone or
what's going on then but if you are
happy then you are happy you find some
hobby right you find some hobby or you
go dancing you go to crap you watch
movie so you go [ __ ] or you do whatever
you know you play video games right so
that's also good I guess you know that's
also that's kind of natural you know
when you don't need to worry about walk
then you have free time then you do
whatever you think you you know you do
philosophy or you go dancing you watch
movies or play video games Oh women you
go out shopping you know you do whatever
or dancing but then this you see in the
past 10 years or 20 years you started to
have this this thing about oh we need to
you know try something new for 30 days
it's idiotic so okay so let's see censor
censor good morning great to see you hi
to China and the Whoopie homey what up
homie Pisa Betty Pisa baby were you from
it's a pity
emily is Syrian shower and Freddie good
morning to Germany oh it's so nice to
enjoy a long hot shower usually for me
it's only five minutes oh five minutes
moaning moaning woken come on in welcome
to United Kingdom
what do I think about crime a crime
'change movements I kind of talked about
that climate change yeah also so I
talked about that in past videos you
know one thing beats to another so it
ends up by talking about that for for 30
minutes but basically about climate
change you know that's a very very
complex topic even if you are a
scientist on climatology
you know the study environment even if
you are a scientist specialize in that
it is my belief that you wouldn't know
what's really really happening so it's a
you know it's a complex question and we
don't really know exactly what's going
on although I'm inclined to say and also
I mean trying to believe even though
even if I don't know but I mean crying
to you know believe in let's do
something about it you know let's clean
up in the environment it's not you know
destroy it trees or whatever actually
you know they are actually more trees
than in the 1990s because I have an
article on that this is a report from
NASA we have actually more trees
actually significantly more trees than
in 1990s and this is a article from from
NASA
but anyway but let me get back to good
morning George let me good money to
Australia let me get back to climate
change a summary of my view so my view
is that I don't really know Kesari NASA
more trees okay my in summary about
climate change is that I don't really
know what's going on I and all right but
I mean trying to believe it in fact I
believed Green I'm for green you know
for much of 1990s and 2000s banty oh you
know 2016 when the social justice scan
rose up you know about safe space about
women about trans about this or that you
know suddenly over sudden 2016 and Trump
so it is until 2000
I was so surprised what I saw this this
you know this strange jargons means
waiting means spreading you know a safe
space you know this kind of thing so I
started to read you know you know then I
think I discovered I just started I
discovered lots of things we've have
been lied to that I believed you know I
did me in California for the past thirty
years most of you know since 21 so I'm
50 to about 52 now so I lived in
California and I believed in a green
things you know the you know solar power
actually I have a lot videos to humming
a lot Holocaust to show you anyway
so since around 2016 I discovered many
of these things we've been lied to by
the progressives so so these days so
about climate change what should I say I
mean what do I say hold on a second let
me find the Arco NASA not none okay NASA
Moultrie how compilers work and so on
okay so we need periodic passage
periodic passage NASA Moultrie actually
I wrote an article somewhere but because
I don't it's not finding it so anyway
but let me find it in actually preferred
it to the right you prefer it to the
right what do you mean in general you
prefer your main window to be on the
right so climate change are you still
interested in about that topic NASA it's
such for NASA okay so this is in sardis
org and sorry there it is small trees no
trees so nASA says the world is greener
it's showing browser so here is the
article on sorry dog periodic dosage and
so NASA this this is an article from
NASA
so NASA actually tell us that we have
more trees than in the 1990s and also so
in general about crime in check climate
change I'm you know I'm a nerd like many
of you guys most of you guys and I'm
very much concerned about efficiency you
know I love efficiency I want everything
to be efficient like do more and spend
less energy if possible like efficient
keybinding and so for that and as far so
as far as you know cause you know I love
you know I love Sol solar panels I
actually I talked about this many times
let me show you some hearts okay so odds
so you go to my website saw heart start
org so you can see I've collected
I have spent tremendous time I talked
about these few days ago I don't
remember when I I spent tremendous time
collecting these fantastic photos about
solar
solar power you know all these different
technologies of solar power and I think
they are you know to me they are
beautiful because it's like when you see
Star Trek or Star Wars Star Wars you
know you have this giant giant spaceship
you know it's technology so this kind of
fascinates me and I love them you know
the solar tower you have different types
you have this this one giant mirror this
this building is like 15 stories high
something like that so I love these
things and you know and I really
believed I like to believe you know the
where is it here I like these things you
know I you know these are
self-sustaining technology I mean the
beauty is that you know stop thinking
about climate change for a moment just
think about technology the beauty that
the reason I love them is because they
are efficient and self-sustaining that
is the beauty you know the beauty of the
technology is like amazing so I love
these same things but then you know and
also these geo domes and also biosphere
2 in taxes which is a major failure and
this one is in United Kingdom broken oh
you prefer my cam on the right okay
great great to know so so right now my
cam is on the right I think okay so
actually today is we cannot do a short
one so I'm gonna stop in 20 more minutes
I think so anyway so this this atom the
atom project this one this is in United
Kingdom you guys know a poke and you
know and Emily so you know you might
visit when you feel like it it's on the
southern tip of united kingdom come well
Conway or UK so yeah I love this
technology so in general so let me come
back to crime
so in general I love these green
technologies and I also believed for you
know 1990s and 2000 I much relieved I
believe that we need to say save whales
save Turtles cleaning up the sea you
know I'm very much relieved that but
beginning in 2016 because the social
justice [ __ ] the [ __ ] it's with a their
you know their their their theories and
all that so I started to look you know
like what's going on yeah and I started
to look at and in the day I discovered
lots of things are not what I believed
okay so you know done you know the wrong
done by the Democratic Party in USA the
[ __ ] Democratic Party they are
scumbags so too you know I discovered
that to my to my dismay you know I mean
California which is very progressive
state but anyway about about climate
change about the planet I still don't
know what's you know no but I think
nobody really knows I tend to believe it
nobody really knows so we need to I
think it's it would be good that we try
to fix it
but the problem is you see the problem
is you see the leftist party you know
the regressive party the Democratic
Party or elsewhere in other countries in
UK in Australia in you know the white
countries typically Canada this [ __ ]
leftist bleeding-heart [ __ ]
you know they so they want to push for
you know green you know which is good
but you know but but the thing is that
they are doing it meaning they are just
doing it for their own benefits you know
they are not really good they are not
really truly concerned about humanity or
whatever they are doing you know they
are they are [ __ ] around
you know they they they prop up this
girl you know the greater something
great earthen book something they prop
up this this you know girl you know this
climate change is such a important issue
you cannot have like [ __ ] some high
school girl to talk about this
so these [ __ ] heads are doing it so what
can you do so so anyway let me get back
to the important point so what I want to
say is that I think okay we don't really
I think nobody truly knows but however I
do think that this is important issue
that it it's a we open you know it would
be good that we we try to fix it however
we cannot do we cannot start to fix it
because the leftist party that they are
[ __ ] around when you know this thing
requires all the nations to work
together you know it's not just you know
we need to work together and find out
you know to to you know reduce costs
things like that not not by you know
politicians just pushing things around
so so it's a problem so to me you know
who knows what will happen this is a
problem you know I so let me summarize
again if it's not clear you know I I
just like to give you my opinions so I
think it's kind of our problem and I
agree we should really work on it to
reduce you know carbon deoxys deoxys D
dioxide is thing other things like that
oh yeah we should do something about it
but given the situation today especially
by the leftist you know the social
justice [ __ ] ads or those people who who
think they are vegans they they want us
to stop eating meat you know this crazy
extremists these [ __ ] they are doing
these things and when they are doing
these things this problem cannot be
fixed because because you know we're
going into a war that's what happens you
know this
these toothache in order to fix this we
need the whole all of us you know work
together to fix it you cannot just have
you know part of us you know [ __ ]
they are pushing you know you cannot for
example if I'm trying to convince you of
something I believe I cannot just punch
you and say you know just do it that we
would not walk you're gonna punch punch
back you know that's what I'm saying so
we have these leftist [ __ ] they are
doing that so that's gonna be a problem
for us you know so that's my opinion
about climate change okay so so Eden has
been - so Vokoun has been - Adam project
great beautiful face I think there's a
was it James found gem James Bond movie
or some some other movie has me be made
in this face you know movies they
especially sci-fi movies they love these
kind of races so Freddie says on that
note have you heard about Earth ships
before home made from recycled parts
with a lot of self-sufficiency build in
usually like automated watering for
plants Earth ships what do you mean I
mean do you mean spaceships or do you
mean just self-contained environment if
you mean self-contained environment yeah
this you know this there's a biosphere
you know this is kind of it I don't know
I forgot what's a co of Eden Project I
mean but it's on Wikipedia you can look
but there is another project called bio
biosphere ok biosphere 2 like and it's
it's you know there's a lot failure like
corruption you know it ends up with you
know failure but any anyway this
biosphere project is you know it's
beautiful it's meant to be it's trying
to study
humans living in a you know in a
self-contained environment to be
self-sustainable so they don't you know
you don't you don't keep food you know
you don't import anything from outside
so it's like this place is entirely
entirely sealed off from the outside so
originally they tried to they plan to do
this for yo too but anyway they [ __ ]
up you know they tried it twice they
[ __ ] up so it turns out people are
smuggling food or whatever inside to it
or smuggling computers or whatever so
this is biosphere and I think they
stopped the project they trying to sell
it to some businessman and someone is
trying to turn it into a museum or
amusement park or something like that
this one is in Arizona it's in USA so
earthships some very cool project exist
off grid so Earth ships you know home
made from recycled parts I don't really
you know also the recycled thing that's
a big lie you know we like especially me
you know I'm very very very much into
recycling you know it's like I know most
of you are nerds too and most of you
probably have similar interest but I can
tell you I have I have more obsession
about recycle I like that I need to know
you know I need to recycle everything
but anyway so recycle is like one of the
big lie anyway I talked about this in
another video in another video let me
actually I want to update my website so
let me run a command key shout what is
this let me show or NASA okay so now
sorry is going trees so they go let's go
to e shout and call and update my
website
the other thing I want to talk about is
that so in the past two days I've been
working a lot on my Emacs to do again so
let me show you so we have like we
actually have fire on our farm
well hoops we have Lena's toe votes
anyway that's so we have Carrie Carrie
Davis so have people kept asking me
asking me what do you think about Harry
Davis because he's crazy you know like
me somewhat I mean yeah well I mean he's
got problems he's got severe you know he
see things he has delusions so anyway so
so I have a so actually I blogged about
it when I watched his video in the tempo
OS it's amazing so actually let's go
back to this code and tell I don't want
to watch videos okay so so what else
what's up you guys I think we're gonna
close down in ten minutes actually so
good morning Alan got an example of some
interesting recycling reusing in your
trainings no no I know I don't I don't
have I mean basically I think the only
the recycling I talked about recycling
like in one of my videos I think if you
just search for recycle your you will
see it let's talk about something else
some very cool projects is off-grid
passive solar shelter made of natural
and an upcycled materials addressing
energy garbage management sue each other
okay my roommate is back actually I
think I should go I need to go let me
talk for a while so recycle things you
know that okay so let me tell you what
to do so recycle the only thing you want
to recycle is King Helu
and Kenz you know like that that you go
recycle well and in the newspaper you
know newspaper and but almost pretty
much that's it because a lot of it just
goes to the dumpster landfill oh oh the
other thing about energy is that what we
really want is nuclear energy other
things are not good you know these are
this beautiful wind turbines they don't
do much okay you need you want nuclear
power okay so what else okay yeah I
wanted to say I've been working on my
Emacs tutorial in the past today so so
what's a change the change is that the
change is that so now on every page for
example you go through my practical
Emacs tutorial you can see so we I have
this navigation box you see this big
navigation box now before you know this
navigation box is very long right now
but before it was is suppose it was
little boxes like this this is one box
and this one is one box but now it's
like consolidated into basically this
this navigation box is a table of
contents you know it's freedom so and
the thing is every page you click let's
say you go to let's say you go to list
buffers okay then you page down page
down page down then you will see the
exact same navigation box again table of
contents so so you can see the green one
is the one we are currently on so this
repeats throughout every page so that
means it's now more coherent I mean you
can tell which
you are reading and more coherent and
more easier to find things you want so
but again but see oh I have quite a few
table of contents for example this page
is practical Emacs tutorial then you
have this giant table of contents for
Emacs customization you know like 30
pages then you have this then you have
this page then you have the giant table
of contents navigation boxes for all
things related to keys in Emacs
then you have you know some commands
okay this is you know I need to make
them into a navigation box I don't know
if I already did yeah so anyway that's
the point so I made a lot of things in
to consolidate it not navigation box so
okay so if you like my Emacs tutorial
you go here and buy it okay you buy it
and for those of you who bought it in
the past three years I'm going to send
out a new version to you in email okay
if you did not receive it and after a
few days just email me okay you guys you
guys go buy it
okay so what else I wanted to say I was
going to walk on good morning Alan and
Fisher and you know this there's a lot
interesting things you know so I was
eating fish yesterday and when you eat
fish you need to you need to read this
the fisherman and the genie so have you
guys read it yet read it yet read it
read it
so fisherman is genie and this is part
of the Arabian Nights when I talked
about this several times in my video so
when you read the 1001 nights you must
read this version by Sir Richard Burton
okay so there is this story of our
fishermen and genie
okay so you guys need to go read that
the fisherman and Cheney and let me read
you a poem you know this book is filled
with poems you know I realized that like
I realized that in old literature like
you know five hundred years old
you know 1000 years old literature they
tends to have lots of poems like
interspersed throughout so for example
in the story the fisherman and the genie
there is a poem by the way this is this
these are my annotations okay like you
can wait it's my one where's my drama
script what oh wait right I want to they
filtered out my that's okay let's go to
Chrome
so I spent a year or two to annotate
this work 1001 night so you can see
these are annotations and I have
JavaScript I wrote it
I heard the JavaScript to to have them
so these are my annotations but let me
read the poem ok so the poem so it's
kind of small
so all toilers through the groom's of
the night Oh toilet through the groom's
of the night in pero and in pen sight
oil instant for daily bread comes not by
might and men ok and this you know this
writing is actually not easy to
understand because this guy this guy
Richard saw a button he intentionally
righted in a archaic way that's what I
heard from English experts anyway so
that's about that and also yeah so
actually I wanted to tell you something
else ok so there is one thing
cincin okay we have among us
arrghh girl ok a girl but but she is a
guy it's complicated so she gave a talk
about Cobo ok so this I'm gonna shut
down in three minutes ok so anyway so
she so she gave a live tutorial about
Cobo the for me language cobalt by
season so season is you know it's is in
our group you know I told her to like
you know you guys you guys have every
one of you every one every last
[ __ ] one of you ok you guys you
guys need to do a tutorial like did
start learning teacher something ok each
one of you know something other people
don't know so I talked to Susan to give
a tutorial so she did yesterday
live live and with with with with a
videos you know doing video and she did
in in she did it in discord and nobody
came so I'm the only one watching but
afterwards she put it on YouTube so I
wasn't sure what to expect because I've
never heard talked to her before on
voice so but it turns out it turned out
it turned out fantastic so I actually I
enjoyed it very much so this video is
one hour
but I learned Cobo now I know Kobo at
least the basics you know what all the
strange things in Kobo so I learned you
know and you know this so go watch it
one hour so you can find it you can find
it if you go to the programming on this
code and it's pinned is one of the
pinned there so one hour you can watch
that and this one hour it's kind of long
one hour but but it beats reading
Wikipedia you know if you spend one hour
reading Wikipedia watching this video is
more much more it's better it's more
efficient especially because COBOL I
learned you know you demonstrated you
know actually you have this column thing
oh my god the columns that came from
punch cards so you don't see these
things you know the way Kobo is you
don't see them there is no analogous
things in other programming languages it
only happens in Cabo because this is
like 60 years old programming language
okay I think that's it for today
anything else any questions you guys
have or yeah I you know once I start to
do a video I tend to talk non-stop
because there's always lots of things
but I think that's it I and also I need
to go my roommate is back
and they are going to watch you know
Chinese melodrama on their computer and
they hate they are gonna occupy the
Internet okay so that's it okay so
that's it so see you guys the Lord okay
Lord so here is a poem from the
fisherman and the genie when you eat
fish you have to read this poem Lord to
the Lord who gives to this - that denies
his wishes and doom one to toil and
catch the prey and other eat the fishes
it's kind of so is that pitch
it's pitching about unfairness you know
like today in modern society in our
society we have this we have lots of you
know fat and rich and [ __ ] they are
ruling the town oh do okay that's it
thank you guys for watching see you see
you on this code