good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today September
19th 2019 Thursday 4 o'clock p.m. San
Francisco time and today we're going to
talk about the bunch of things so what
is the topic morning Jeremy have not
seen you for a while have you ever been
on my talk show of Jeremy I know you for
like two three years right three years
on master Dan for almost I think four
years from the atom what's what's his
name Adams radio show what's his name
Jeremy you know that that guy like typed
in John Adams and something
vorak watching using Adam Curry
yes no agenda show so let me let me tell
you guys about that show so actually so
I don't listen to radio shows at all I
mean that's just not my lifestyle so
I've never listened to radio shows and
you know I don't you know some like I
some people tell me you just play in the
background but that doesn't work for me
because usually if I play some radio
shows in a background I don't you know I
don't listen like like it doesn't you
know when I want to listen something I
have to like just just listen to it so
playing in the background usually
doesn't work for me because sometimes
they people talk about interesting
things then then I have to stop what I'm
doing then I just have to concentrate
listen so anyway so there is this show
Adam Curry and John vorak now Adam Curry
is a guy who basically invented podcast
you know the one of the idiotic joggins
from the tech nerds okay podcast you
know why is it called podcast because
iPad iPod you know Apple invented this
little mp3 device
iPod so in the beginning you know you
have brought I mean you have broadcast
so they have the iPod the apples product
mp3 player and people bring anyway so
podcast just means just means audio
recording kind of yeah a show audio
recorded and and you can play it you
know anytime you want so but this stays
I don't think I heard the term podcast
much anymore
he's I am I correct oh and Jeremy says
podcasting came from aquaculture to cast
seeds oh that's interesting okay that's
interesting okay so anyway so Adam curry
invented podcast kind of I guess you
know back in 2000 was it 2002 something
like that 2005 and okay and John Warwick
I kind of know I did I didn't know Adam
curry until four years ago but John
boric he is the sky I never liked him
you know this there's a story to it I
never liked John Warrick because he he
he is the tech columnist for like 30
years or even 40 years at least 30 years
so he write tech columns I like about
programming about Auburn systems like
back then I know that back I mean he's
he began even in 1980s but I got into
computing in 1990s but even in 1990s
you know he he write for PC Magazine
sometimes for mag magazine anyway all
these tech magazines you know Mac
Wardens so you know I know I know
you know so in the 90s I know from
reading history I know he has written
pieces articles that criticized UNIX
that's right on our topic genre Barack
and his style I mean he is this
commercient
kind of type of
you know even back in 90s like his style
is always sarcastic and criticizing
things you know and usually so I you
know back then in the 1990s I was a Mac
fan and usually when I read he stuff it
doesn't you know I don't you know I
don't believe him I don't it's not
convincing to me I think he's he's in
today's jargons today's lingo today's
you know you just call him a troll and a
lot of people call him a chaw a guest
but however around 2000 around 2014
maybe you know when Google+ is you know
over over the place 2013 or 2014 also
Google Google Plus is all over the face
and John Barak well I I saw him you know
life when he joined one over the show
twit what what is it show called Jeremy
do you know the run by another guy trait
I think the show is just called twit so
he don't John Moraga is a guest on the
show so I actually saw him and I and I
like that guy from that day I liked that
guy so he's this kind of he's kind of
this humor guy and always sarcastic it
kind of a gadfly he always poke poke
poke fun of you of your things and yeah
he's a funny guy but anyway the the No
Agenda show I haven't listened to much
because you know I don't listen to radio
shows I tried it like two times doesn't
work out for me so okay so let me so
today what is today's topic guys like go
into the you know description and find a
topic and let's talk about it let me
read the comments okay so that's about
No Agenda show and let's go to Chris our
talk show page and today's topic
so magnify so let's go to today's topic
we need to lock down what we talked
about today so Kassar talk show date a
new page ok and make it aid Li cut it
paste it here and go to the page so we
talked about Adam Curry father-daddy of
podcast and Zhang Borak what'swhat's a
fun way to put it easy kamuran munch and
i how do you spell c'mon c'mon
DG or and now that's strong let's see
Komachi are not found so ok so you need
to go to web search there it is
curmudgeon stupid English what what is
the a Tamala G of a commercial actually
that's interesting so let's let's do
that etymology so anyway a commercial
and the no agenda show now no agenda
show as far as I know it's kind of it's
not mainstream ok for you know it's not
mainstream so so many of you guys you
know might like it you know just search
for knowledge in that show I'm pretty
sure you'll find it it's a podcast so
commercial let's look at the etymology
of commercial so eat etymology linka fie
ok it's showing browser let's look at
commercial so commercial means cherish
cherish miserly fellow mean men from
1570s of a non engine Oh a normal
range of the suggestion based on a
misreading of a car boat note from John
and that is from French over merchants
evil heart something something anyway
arranger unknown that's interesting or
engine unknown guys so we got something
that's orange and know like UFO so
what's okay that's geometry that's the
interesting stuff so let's see what what
you know I need to read the comments so
I get feedback what's going on so Jeremy
Weibo good morning Weibo Weibo champloo
Weibo champloo we are boo
Champa where are you from from what
island you came from so let's see
Thomas walk morning Thomas Thomas where
you from
so do you recommend pearl as a general
purpose for me language for a lamp web
developer for a you know lamp stack lamp
stand for Linux Apache MySQL and P stand
for PHP so do I recommend Perl is a
general-purpose language not really you
know you know so in my opinion power is
dead today so yeah it really practically
but practically speaking it's kind
instead so I would not recommend it you
know you rather actually go with just
you know if if you are on the lamp stack
just go with PHP PHP is actually very
good today okay now you know PHP and
JavaScript these two languages are the
languages every in hacker hates you know
this UNIX people idiots okay let's see
my opinion every hacker hates PHP and
JavaScript
however they become the most popular
like PHP through our 2000 is a number
one most popular language and JavaScript
today you could say it's a number one
most popular language okay you know why
because because all the good languages
they have a code like Lisp has cow you
know I talked about this
many times in my video you know in
hacker community you know this elite
programmers they have a they have you
know they have sometimes they have some
kind of code okay and usually the
languages they promote don't fare well
don't fare well okay because why because
it's a code it's a code and this delete
hackers sucks they tell you what to do
they tell you oh you need to use the
Monad like they don't solve practical
problems like every time you have a
question you go ask and if it's Haskell
people are gonna say oh did you try them
on at monad you should try mana
oh this issue you know you should use
Korean you know mainly in this scheme
group they will say oh you should use
tail recursion and it they talk then you
know they they talk in their Fantasyland
tail recursion scheme where scheme today
is geek scheme is Terry cursing in
omar's okay okay that's scheme then this
you know come and listen and they gonna
tell you Oh Marcus Marcus Marcus these
idiots
so meanwhile meanwhile the PHP language
in JavaScript you know they they are
kind of this language like like they are
you know they are not elite they are of
the low you know low ground and but so
but anyway when you have a question
people are actually answer you know oh
you need to do this way I mean I mean
they give you you know just the answer
answer to your question
and so they are and I mean so they don't
have a code in fact you know JavaScript
and PHP that's two languages everyone
hates so much even even today you still
have that you know you can see it
everywhere hacker news on you know or
the social media Twitter but how I have
a PHP and JavaScript they they are so
they you know because they don't have
this code affiliation so they grow and
grow and they you know they focus on
they are truly just focus on
practicality and and today in my opinion
PHP is very good okay I will say PHP is
a very good language and JavaScript
I wouldn't say it's very good I mean
Jeff because JavaScript has huge amount
of baggage
well something same thing with PHP but
but javascript is the syntax is is
pretty bad anyway so that's my opinion
about PHP and JavaScript so yeah so Adam
and Jung the Adam Korean John crack John
John boric is no they market themselves
as crackpot and buzzkill yeah buzz buzz
Keo is John go back I can I can see that
now Adam I don't know much about Adam I
was I'm following ad among on Twitter
but but they are kind of old though they
are like 60 something right or even 70
yeah so so Weber says if you were
learning a natural language with Emacs
do you have any pieces of advice within
oak mod if you are learning a natural
language with Emacs do you have any
piece of advice within oak mark like
what do you mean like so you mean like
if you were if I'm learning French and
I'm a Emacs user and I'm also you I'm
using oak mark so what what is any tips
like what I mean I can see what so we
bought type type your question okay I
don't quite get what Jeremy says no
agenda takes the format of an
old-fashioned wacky morning DJ show okay
complete with soundboard but does
there's very serious media analysis it's
very very good stuff okay I can't I
can't trust you on that compete with
soundboard not what does sound bored me
yeah I don't soundboard is like I know
what's a storyboard you know storyboard
is like when you
make a movie a film you draw like like
kind of like comics you know you have
one cell and next sale sale and you
illustrate the stories so that's
storyboard I don't know what is a
soundboard somewhere is sets of samples
that are played for effect oh okay okay
etymology of weebo okay what okay what
what is the entomology of weebo we a we
need to look at that earth I don't even
know what is we but what does we bought
me so
etymology Minkoff I show in browser
let's check it out
and Weibo is not a word I don't think
it's a it's maybe a slant it's not a
proper English word right Weibo urban
dictionary okay not sure why I want to
read that okay it says a person who
retains an unhealthy obsession with
Japan and Japanese culture okay I got it
typically ignoring or even stunning
their own ratio and cultural identity
okay Weibo that's about Weibo that's a
lot of the you know current youngster
young people culture yeah you know like
Japanese culture in America is kind of
this exotic thing it's it's it's
interesting in several ways okay first
of all first of all Japanese is you know
it's in orient you know Far East and so
it's exotic for sure it's exactly to
American because it's Eastern Eastern
culture in Korean Chinese so it's a you
know it's it's far into American culture
so and Japan ended but also Japanese
aside being part of the ischium largely
influenced by China but Japanese has
their own they they have kind of for
example anime okay animes you know but
they also own sexuality they have you
know they have their
particular lots of weird things in Japan
okay
and meanwhile in contrast American
people you know you which is if I may
say it's the background is Puritan
Christianity you know you don't you know
you don't you don't you don't allow gay
or you know or sex or you know oh you
know I there are some words I don't want
to mention because Google is starting
going too bad so anyway Puritan it's
very very they don't you know they don't
want sex stuff so so Japanese stuff to
America is very you know it's like just
out there you know and but also
meanwhile they're Japanese anime is so
cute it's a well done you know so that's
one thing but but I think there's
another aspect ok is so the the Japanese
culture becomes very popular in America
you know one reason is because Japanese
is very exotic okay
their culture is very exotic in American
eyes not you know not too much to
Chinese because we are kind of you know
we are kind of the same we share the
same culture but to Americanize to the
white people sites okay that's one thing
but however there's another thing the
other thing I would say the reason
Japanese become so kind of I mean it's
not just popular okay here's the thing
you see Japanese culture in America for
example anime it's not just pop popular
these rather is kind of being a weird
state because for example on social
networks on Twitter everywhere on
Twitter young master then you will see
your turn of people American white
people okay who don't speak Japanese but
however you'll see their profile photo
you know as a Japanese anime girl you
know some cute girl oh and their profile
text will be some Japanese text okay and
you see that's the thing you see this is
not just a normal popularity you know is
it's
not just no more being popular like like
many movie stars are popular right movie
singers in America or you know a popular
in USA but the Japanese think culture
anime stuff they are not just simply
being popular they are kind they have
kind of maybe the proper word is
subculture in America so you see all
these profiles you know American people
with Japanese profile photos and things
and some some even go to the extreme
where everyday a post is almost like
which in Japanese okay that's so yeah
that's a phenomenon and the for example
another guy for example let me mention
another guy jwz very famous you know
he's a famous for having Emacs
you know he's famous for ex Emacs he's
famous for having written the UNIX
version of netscape browser you know
he's he's you know on the TV shows
Silicon Valley stuff so jwz guy he you
know on his blog he's posting about
Japanese stuff all day like like for the
past 20 years yeah 20 years he's you
know every every week he is posting
Japanese stuff and his style and
attitude is like he is half making fun
of Japanese stuff and you know anyway
he's a he's kind of a weird guy so
that's about Japanese culture America oh
let me mention another reason okay
another reason is Japanese Japan are
somewhat friend
politically friends with USA oh in
American the way American says you know
we say we say we say they are friends
you know we say they are our friends
this is interesting because for example
United Kingdom and the USA Americans
they are friends okay they are friends
they are but they are of the same or
ancient basically German or you know is
a Western Europe okay
in America you know as today's social
justice a they are white people they
have the same origin they share many
things beliefs in culture but
politically so they are friends mostly
politically you know but Japanese are
not exactly like that friends with USA
but however Japanese are friends you you
know rather Ally with us a bit why
because you want you want to friend with
Japan to fight the China the communist
China's so that's not that's part of the
reason I think that that also that is a
part of the reason there is this kind of
a weird Japanese popularity in American
culture on the other hand for example in
contrast you don't see this with Chinese
you know many of the Japanese things
they are Chinese or engine but you don't
see USA you know you don't see Chinese I
mean even today Chinese she has become
so powerful you know shooting rockets
and stuff you don't see much news in USA
media every time you hear about China is
like oh they are so evil you know we
need to free them yeah so so that's in
contrast you know you don't see much
Chinese culture you know in you know as
pop culture in USA but you do see that
in in check as you know Japanese culture
so that's about that
etymology so la cacica
la cacica way from that looks like a
Spanish name la cascada javascript is a
language of the people
okay of the of the new generation though
at least Jeremiah says people just love
to hate on things
Thanks tomas war says thanks oh okay
about that
Emacs about about the Linux Linux Apache
MySQL PHP stuff okay
so Jeremy says okay so
Adam Curry was formerly a VJ NTV okay
VJ stand for video jockey oh okay so he
was a VJ on MTV what does video jockey
do I guess I guess you just edit videos
in real time or one so Weibo says we
about we about says I suppose school
Oakmont note-taking methods asides from
the obvious hierarchical structure in
autumn automate automatic tables
creation yeah so we both say it's about
learning a new language in oak mud I
don't know about any tips about that
what do you so what you know I mean who
Oakmont note-taking methods that's
that's one thing interesting but when it
comes to learning learning a new
language I don't see oak Mart has
anything to do with it I mean anything
particular so I don't know and also I
mentioned this few times you know if you
look at my old videos they are a few you
know people always want me to talk about
oak mud or compare you know why are you
using HTML we are not using oak mud so
it's a frequently asked question I
talked about it a few times if you
search my youtube video so I'm not a
Oakmont user sorry I don't know any much
tips about that so in fact two days ago
or three days ago
there's 10 minutes or 20 minutes talking
about Oakmont so you know maybe you are
you would be interested I explain why I
don't use oak mud I explain why I use
HTML and I give a short outline of
Oakmont features and you know and my
experiences yeah
the title is so for example the title of
that talk is go through talk show such
oak mud okay here it is
2019 September 12th man Durham and
abroad said entrepreneurship
my experience of akhmad why isn't your
mom using Linux okay that's that's that
that one so check out that one
catchphrase like drums a catchphrase
from actors or politicians introduction
host of so VJ video jockey is
introduction introduces and hosts
thematic programs presenting music
videos so any any else anything else any
other topics otherwise we just go random
I guess so I've been talking for 30
minutes I we can do maybe another 30
minutes
your mom is using Linux if she has a
fire act or an Android fire or fire fire
Android that's not Linux okay
I know Jeremy Jeremiah okay he said
pronounce correctly Jeremiah I mean you
you are a Linux fan and you are
open-source fan right or maybe a free
software foundation fan but I don't
think you are correct in saying you know
she used Linux if she has a file Android
that's not that's not true you those
Android users they are using Google they
have nothing to do whatsoever with Linux
Google is using Linux because it's free
it benefits them they are like the thief
you know they just scrap it they do
whatever they do you know they are the
extreme Evo's you know you know you
agree with me on that so then you know
when we talk about you know who is using
enix I mean you are saying you are
saying you know oh yeah but but but look
all the Android users are using Linux so
they are for big Linux is so great right
that's that's the you know that's that's
why you are saying that but that in my
view in my point of view that's not the
case at all nobody is using Linux
because the internet sucks so bad
yeah there we go again Linux is a kernel
but most of us don't use it unless we
are just forever does yeah so you know
to you
to the Linux fan people then you know
they change their definition with Linux
when Apple is using Linux you know they
say oh look even Apple adopted Linux or
UNIX you know because Linux is so great
then when there's a criticism is it oh
that's not your next eyes on you UNIX
shell is not a battery it's not Unix you
just you just you need to switch your
shell okay
Oh excellent it's not you next is dead
you know so what is Linux Linux kernel
you know this is like you you know
that's a that's piyah so okay everyone
has spires so you my opinion that's
that's the typical Linux users you know
one of the example now anyway so I think
we should switch to some different topic
because I talk I I rant about open
source all day day and night you know it
almost every every week you know
sometimes going on hours so so anything
else
so I guess no any other topic then
another topic so so anything else you
know guys just type it Emacs questions
or anything so otherwise I'm just going
to talk about some random stuff yeah
so today I obviously today we are not
talking about technical stuff because
usually my concern is that when we talk
about technical stuff we just focus on
technical but we already talked have for
30 minutes random stuff so this is
today's juice
today's juice is tomato juice this is
from $1 dollar tree store you know in
USA you have these stores called Dollar
Tree as everything is $1 so that's one
dollar a bottle then you have this cheap
energy drink nameless you know what they
did rip it
ok energy drink sugar free of course I
always drink sugar free and let me show
you you know a few days ago that's hold
on a second let me try this video
okay that didn't work few days ago my
roommate gave me this moon cake moon
cake you know a few days ago is Chinese
awesome
festival okay you cannot see it but moon
cake have you had moon cake Jeremiah and
Jeremiah is in where are you Jeremiah in
in mid USA or eastern USA I forgot so
Jeremiah says lists Lisp in browser
implementation that often closure
Wisconsin Oh Wisconsin with Wisconsin is
the house state of cars am I correct
but a lot of cheese right that's what I
know of Wisconsin so let's see what I
can get out of this moon cake now I have
this very lousy camera
this is moon cake could cut into a
quarter piece you know
the land of the Spotted Cow oh okay
the Spotted Cow so smarted cows oh so
they are cause that's not spotted I
guess yeah
I haven't even heard of that phrase
spotted cow okay
okay I'm eating I'm getting one then
I'll talk okay
Oh Chinese man is old man software now
look are you on your phone
Jeremiah so when I make it to the
Chinese bakery I rarely make it past the
red bean paste buns yeah those are good
so you're on desktop okay so you tell
you about closure well I so so are you
doing closure I know
Jeremiah is a big Lisp fan and you've
been coding this like since 20 years ago
something like that you know I'm also a
list fan but as you know we you know I
criticize this all the time you know
yeah I don't like the common list
phonetics okay yeah and I know you're a
big fan of of Lisp I think I think you
coded list since long ago right and do
you see your code list so are you
learning closure or are you I talked
about closure a few times in my video so
I'm not sure so for example there is
this yeah recently so 2009 2019
September 15th there is this video
rotate 13 bash Perl Ruby closure Lynn
agon Linux Mac Windows key binding and
Emacs efficiency so that's September
15th video we talked about that so
Jeremiah says Lisp but more skin yeah
scheme I usually say Lisp to me in the
larger family okay okay so I will look
for past videos so don't waste anyone's
time yes well I mean my videos
you know we I'm just random talk okay my
videos they don't get much views you
know one 100 if you typically each video
is 100 and I kind of know why because
I'm not like aiming to make it popular
because because you know the way I'm
doing is like random talk like random
chat sometimes for 90 minutes unfocused
so that's not typically what people want
so the way I'm doing just like my blogs
you know typically my followers will
become this niche no mainstream group
you know also kind of intellectual and
also not very in the mainstream you know
we got people okay so that so that
becomes my follower and that and there
are not many that you know such person
but if you want to become popular for
example I would you know have a Emacs
channel every day is just like let's say
20 minutes no more 20 minutes you know I
you know not know late
no live chat you know just focus 20
minutes Emacs everything about Emacs and
eMac beast then but then the channel on
JavaScript for example every day is
about JavaScript you know just technical
tutorial that will make me more popular
but but that's that's just that's that's
you know that that's the thing that's
just not my thing you know a society we
become everyone becomes that's actually
a selfish move we like this smoke saw
okay yeah well that's because you become
my follow up because you see life is
almost like where you take it to be
because I'm like this so so now all my
followers are like you know you guys
okay yeah and and some people will tell
me no no the moment you change you know
you become than weird we we start
following you that's that's correct yeah
and I like it you know I like you guys
but however I mean but but however you
we are kind of in this very niche group
you know because I know for sure you
know I know if I if one day I started to
do no focus then
get 10 10 times more followers and they
they all like that you know they they
want that they don't want your weird
personality or talk about philosophy or
you know things like that
we about but we about what country are
you from like if you don't mind sir
nobody know who you are like say what
country or city you from did you say
that no I don't think so so and another
thing about video is that you tend to
repeat many question many topics a lot
and I mentioned this before it's like
almost unavoidable because like I
observe you know I am observer of things
I'm much of a thinker and philosopher
not much of anything else
so I observe like you look at the pop
star singers okay Britney Spears Michael
Jackson Prince Oh Orly you know today
singers whatever you know some of them
like the same song they have to sing for
20 years like like sometimes you hear so
on stage use you think that's not the
way you sing it because they changed you
know they change the to and stuff
because you imagine they have to sing
the same song for 20 years you really
get tired tired of it however
most people vast majority people going
to your concert they want they because
they are so familiar with your you know
song a you know your particular song
they just want to listen that you know
so that's a situation you have to you
just have to repeat like you go onstage
you to or you repeat the same thing and
that's what people want to know that's
that's unavoidable and the same thing
happens with scholars and lecturer
lecturers for example Jordan Pederson
and Camille Paglia
you know you you watch the YouTube
videos right once you are after 10 or 20
of them you see a lot of repetitions
right that's the same thing
I think it's the same thing with me
because then every day you know often
the UNIX thing which language is the
best can you you know crochet or Lisp
things they kind of turn up and up again
and woof on language superfine research
you know wolfram mathematica stuff so
that's so this is I mean so this is just
I think it's just the life situation
there is nothing it's just the way life
is you know you have to you know that's
just the way it is hanging out with us
living room thanks for the tip on so
Jeremiah is in Wisconsin Wisconsin
Wisconsin gets cold in the winter so
let's go to Google Maps and Wisconsin
has a accent this particular accent
because I remember in 1992 I have this
kind of my boss she's not really my boss
but she's you know I was working as a
sacred secretary and she's one of the
salespeople she came from Wisconsin and
whenever she says copy
you know like can you make a copy of
this you know like she's you know
because I was secretary I typed for them
you know I do things for them in office
you know so I make sometimes I make a
copy for them and your copy of documents
and she always say make a copy make wait
how do you how does she say and make a
copy yeah that's what she say
make a copy let's see where's with with
Wisconsin is this middle let's remove
the auto Craig yeah with Wisconsin there
gets cold I lived in Illinois is for a
while I went to Kansas for a few days
because there's
Bini back in 2000 2001 also I went to
Kansas for a few days I lived in
Illinois Champaign Illinois for half a
year in 1995 because I was working for
Wolfram research champagne there it is
Champaign Illinois
you know my impression is that every day
in morning you wake up you spell done
you you smell done you wake up to the
done of cows Champaign you don't know it
and so Champaign Illinois I lived there
for have you then I D other place I
lived is Marilyn I lived there in 2006 I
think 2006 for half a year
Marilyn where is it
Marilyn is somewhere here as Marilyn
Marilyn is very small state they don't
even show the state
let's see West Virginia Virginia
Maryland okay here Maryland so East
chimeric Maryland you know the
impression I got is all the highways or
roads you have potholes you know the
roads are not very good and yeah it's
it's kind of poor I think it's kind of
poor state so let's see post yet bust
here says thanks for the tip I'm not
finding caps lock on control on this
stuff yeah that's that's my one of my
gripe of the popular you know the
popular theme hackers tell the people to
do to change you know to swap caps lock
to control I don't think he's a good
thing the however if you are on a laptop
then that's a good thing
so what's a good thing to do a good
thing to do on a normal you know if you
are not using a laptop keyboard if you
are using a full-size keyboard the best
thing to do is to the best thing to do
is actually to use a model mod like Evo
mod works off like this that's the best
thing to do and if you are using Evo mod
or supply keys then you mix the caps
lock to mode or switch okay and when you
press the caps lock don't do not press
it like oops my sun is shining into my
face do not press it like do not move
your pinky like that do not do that
rather you you move your hair oh and
it's like you do you do it like that
okay so wherever you want to press press
the caps lock you just do like that do
not like move the pinky okay so first
thing to do is to use a model ma ma da
model is much better you have to spend
one month to learn yet okay though in in
this one month you have a lot
frustration but but it's it's a better
long run okay and once you are using a
modem odd then cups caps lock for models
which is a good choice so that's one
thing now if you are not using a model
mod the the second best thing if you are
using a normal PC keyboard is try to use
a try to make the old key as control
okay make the old Chios control so I
have lots of articles about that
sorry caps lock I have like several
articles about that let me just write it
down so so Microsoft Windows swap caps
lock control okay that's how to that's
how to how to swap our Microsoft Windows
so Linux swap caps lock escape keys okay
that's another how-to and here's how to
make half sake to do home key that's
another hug too and this one is for
Emacs and I'm opening new tabs so we can
visit them later and this article Emacs
why you should not swaps what you should
not swap swap caps lock and control okay
and another article use your palm to
press the control key in Emacs no
actually this is someone else's blog but
I have my own blog about that
I guess he linked to me but anyway
there's already a lot articles so let me
just copy so there is one let's just
suppose to talk show so that that so
Microsoft Windows this is how to how to
swap caps lock with oat or swap it with
control okay that's when article now
this is swap caps lock to escape key on
Linux okay that's another article you
also have a Linux article on swapping
caps lock to home and to of course to
control as well somewhere somewhere okay
I have too many articles are you know so
let me just pace it okay how to swap to
come home key okay then then this
article okay so this arco is about how
to press the control key economic way to
press the control key normally now if
you are not swapping control okay then
then one way if you are not using a
laptop keyboard and if you are not using
you if you are not swapping control then
a good technique to press control is
just use your palm okay I cannot
demonstrate that because right now I'm
using a Borak I mean using a Kinesis
keyboard as you can see it's not a
normal keyboard so I cannot demonstrate
you the techniques but however okay so
maybe I should cross the window blind
ah now say
so this is annoying this this is a cheap
apartment I got this window blind and
the Sun four o'clock yeah five o clock
sunset sunset around sunset it shines
into my face anyway if you are using a
normal PC keyboard okay then this is a
great technique to press the ctrl key
just use your palm you use your palm
like that use your palm like over here
this area to press the ctrl key or you
can also cut it into a semi face and and
hit the ctrl key that's what I do
ok oh you can use the pinkies knuckle
like like pinkies knuckle like that you
that's another way to hit control to
never never ever just like never ever
like just extend your pinky to hit
control that's no good ok so that's one
way I mean this picture this photo is
not me ok I I recommended this technique
and some some people you know some
people follow it and they have shown
they have taken pictures and posted to
Stack Overflow and elsewhere so this one
he came from Stack Overflow I think ends
and also Chinese weblog ok this is a
Chinese weblog anyway so so that's one
way to do it another way
ok so here's another way this is another
guy super user you know one of the Stack
Overflow and I have a demo here kind of
this a video you can play and also
actually there's more what I have a
photo of a great technique let me find
that okay so that's the article so let
me
so this is someone else's blog use your
palms to press the ctrl key in Emacs oh
this blog actually I have not seen so he
says I'm not saying anything pretend you
have to discover I'm just confirming and
trying to convince other Emacs zealots
or newbies like that Cod is 10 years old
advice to palm press the ctrl key ok
yeah so so let's see I haven't seen this
block so here is him doing that so this
is a good thing to do so let me actually
I haven't seen his blog usually and I
know the I've seen blogs that links to
my website ok so that they are but ok so
but there is another very interesting
thing
ok this article you know when I say this
in the Emacs Emacs is a coat
ok Emacs is this heavy coat they every
time I say this you know people all the
Emacs users they will flame me they will
say oxides the idiot and if no I don't
have comments on my blog I used to have
because the discuss comment system they
start to charge you
otherwise they put you know this this
this ads they pastor ads low-quality ads
over over like this like try this way
away
we are ways to lose weight ok they post
you know women pictures you know send
scanty card women or you know or some
plants that looks like a you know
or try try this weird you know food to
some things to something to live longer
you know let's discuss forum they they
started to do that you know they force
ads and you don't make money with ads
they only they make money you know they
force that ads or otherwise you have to
pay like $10 a month so therefore I
removed my
discuss forum comment system but I used
to have comment system you know that's
been running for 10 years since also and
you'll see these people though Emacs
phonetics you know they come and they
will say no literally on this page you
know I should actually I'm able to show
the comments yet if I reinsert discussed
comment and I can do that but I need to
find the discuss code anyway so people
will say that and and and read on this
page they all say disks are idiot you
know they they honest you know this is
important they honestly believe that you
know what they say so they all say this
is the most II you know one of the
comments for example I don't let me pair
off paraphrase but I don't I don't
remember exactly how they say but I
paraphrase it you know like code very
closely they all say something like this
this is the most idiotic thing I ever
heard
they say that literally because they
truly believe it you know this like they
say this is the most idiotic thing I'd
never ever ever heard not just one
person I mean this came from different
people and okay so that's that's the
comment on my blog okay then you will
see it on reddit and stack overflow and
hacker news this elite you know
the UNIX philosophy idiots okay type
type of people but you'll see it they
say it you know the most idiotic thing
ever heard but you know on the other
hand you see these people just you see
this sky for example this sky then you
see this this guy another guy then
another guy that plug you just sing you
know that another guy they all like it
you know and that's just not just them
I've seen a lot I've seen a lot you know
who who who recommended you know who say
oh yeah this is a good advice you know
let's let's do this using a pump you
know did now it becomes somewhat popular
okay now you are see actually you'll see
them already down sag overflow you know
it
so you see so this so that my problem
with these eunuchs is that you
see they they honestly believe they're
what they say and they honestly say you
know I'm a troll that I had you know
this is this does not work you know so
it's it to me it's like they are saying
1 plus 1 equals 2 3 okay so they are
these people I say 1 plus 1 equals 2 2 2
2 okay
but now but but you have this in this
code Emacs code community least code
community UNIX philosophy code community
they say no no I is the most idiotic 1+1
is actually 3 how could anyone believe 1
plus 1 equals 2 2 now this is my this is
my reaction ok this is how I think this
is how my might feel these
people I mean how can they possibly have
these people they don't they don't look
outside they don't look they don't look
outside you know they never thought
about things
oh yeah the other thing so I have about
10 articles about this caps lock and
control switch issues like 10 articles
like it gets on my nerves hang over 15
years by now
15 years I've been ranting about this
then but but you have this army a coat
army like every time you say like even
today I'm pretty sure if I post on
Twitter you know if I go to Twitter for
example I say oh try to switch try not
to switch caps lock with control I'm
pretty sure then immediately even even
among my followers
you're got cattle army people oh no I
don't agree
no no no the switch caps lock with
control is the best thing okay why does
this happen because it's a code they
live in this well you know for for for
30 years like because how can use reddit
all these forums every day they have
this any thought that's contrary up and
you know just like they banned me you
know like this kind of things like you
know you using palm to hit control
no they don't BAM okay but ten years ago
they pen it they this
Emacs phonetics did the UNIX philosophy
and in Linux people okay I'm
sorry
I know ever I started to talk about some
of these issues you know the detail I
get angry you know and I direct you can
see it you know reflected in my
expression and all the words come
out because I because how can you
believe Bosnia because I here is a real
example showing how this little innit
did you know this UNIX is this you know
community code like people they you know
how they are factually incorrect but
they insist their way that's the thing
you know if you don't you know if you do
your own way you think that way is
better I think this way is better okay
we have different opinions we try to see
which is better or or we can ignore each
other
okay using your sons I see my sons but
that's not a case in this whenever I say
the Linux people the Emacs
and the the Common Lisp you
okay whenever I say that that's because
they do not allow any of my opinion like
when this issue happens when I say
something they panned me factor these
and open source phonetics they
did they Pat me because they want to
tell you what to do like programming
idioms you know for example in Python
you have this happens in many
communities Perl this you know
especially comedies and Python okay okay
at least these three okay for example
and also Emacs Emacs okay any Mac B's
they have a specific sub code like coats
like community every they filter out
anything they disagree with okay so you
need so they have this code like
community so what was I going to mention
you know so so that's that's why I get
angry so they they you know they did not
just disagree with
opinion they then they call you a troll
they start to you know so-called
character assassination okay
they do everything bad to you they don't
want they don't want your opinion to
spread you know they they say you know
like even today you can see oak Sally he
doesn't call Emacs I mean he doesn't
know lease you know he doesn't he never
coded you did this you know I mentioned
this one time yesterday two days ago
also you know they are P there are a few
people a handful people less today okay
used to be more because today there's
another power rising up the social
justice you know so today you cannot
criticize any people anymore for for
other reasons okay anyway so there are a
lot of people I mean even today so they
don't you know they anyway so that
that's that's that's my rant again about
again about that thing cool for school
says what do you think about space max
it has both evil mod in emacs keybinding
I never use it I think it's a great idea
I think it's great so you know if you
like it I think it's great yeah so it's
a you know you space market sorry max
distribution so-called MX distribution
that means it's a Emacs but bundled with
a bunch of packages or prepared for you
like so so you don't have to worry about
oh how do i config or what package to
install you know it's a bundle
everything together nicely packages
space Max and by default they use evil
mod you know key binding which is like
like like VIMS
okay and in many packages so it's nice I
I wanted to try to try it but I just
never did I think what happens now is
I'm kind of getting old so actually that
is true you know in fact past five years
you know Emacs grow and grow
today you have like thousands of
packages just like JavaScript library
MPA you know you have like thousands of
packages and
and if I look at reddit you know many of
the questions I don't know because they
are all talking about packages so it's
different from let's say ten years ago
the Emacs community so you know I I
wanted to look into it I don't I just
don't have time and also because it
doesn't do me any good
I mean what's what's my point of looking
into space max now as far as for my own
benefit no because I have my entire
system I'm pretty sure even I never used
it I never tried space max but I'm
pretty sure my system is more efficient
than space banks you know I have soft
like ease in my own packages let's just
smile because because I'm a illest coder
so I create my own system but so so
looking into space max does not benefit
me you know I could write a tutorial and
I've been you know I have my Emacs
tutorial for over 15 years now it
doesn't you know people you know doesn't
you spend huge amount I'm only it you
don't get benefits okay no money you die
of hunger and most of the Emacs
community they don't like me okay
because so they don't so like for
example another example okay so for
example every now and then every half a
year or year on Emacs reddit for example
Emacs written on Emacs you will see you
know recommendation of Emacs books okay
all Emacs tutorial like some new newbie
or say Oh what's a good I'm trying to
maybe I'm thinking starting to get into
eMac Lisp what's some good resources
you guys don't recommend okay you will
see a bunch of recommendations but
almost never they they will never
mention my website same thing with the
Emacs tutorial or things like that they
are not mentioned my website but on the
other hand my website if you look at my
website on the internet okay my Emacs
tutorial and my Emacs list this tutorial
they are the most comprehensive the most
by number of topics by number of
articles by number of words by the depth
they cover they are they are a magnitude
more than anything you find on a web or
even published okay I can at least
that's the case for eMac this tutorial
okay Elise for example if you go to my
eMac please tutorial so I got so you
have practical Emacs you have practical
eMac B's and you have bunch of you know
you you have like a few hundred articles
okay - oh you're focused you know not
not counting the rent you know I have a
bunch of other you know rants about
which is stolen about this language
criticism and so on it not counting
those anyway so I have this tutor but
you see nobody mention it why I know why
because I I say things I criticize Emacs
I say you know people don't like me so
you know you don't you know they they
don't they don't link to your site and
also because I mean even I have friends
okay I have there are some people
meaning okay in the Emacs community this
they they like me and they somewhat
support me but however you being kind of
this weird guy it's not like you are not
mainstream okay whenever you know they
have a hard time you know they need to
conform you know they cannot just point
out you you have pressure you know you
know like if you mentioned for example
today in our pilot political situation
you have to be careful I mean even you
don't support mainstream right but but
you don't you you have the concern you
don't dare you don't dare to say things
you know because then all the pervs PR
the people your friends see oh that guy
is you know trying to associate with you
you know this this extreme right-wing
group you know then you know that's a
problem so that's you know you being
ostracized you know that's the word
so I think maybe that's it for today
I've been talking you know we've been
talking for over one hour so if you have
any questions for me posted any other
other comments
maybe we can do five five minutes or
yeah so my minutes also yeah so on a
keyboard key binding capsule our topic
actually I'm done yet I'm not done yet
because I want to show for example let
me show you this okay
this is another biased opinion of these
people who want to believe you know with
like when you are in a community I mean
this happens to everyone including me
okay now if you ask me to name something
I'm biased it would be hard because I
mean that's true for yourself as well
because yourself you don't see it even
if you try I mean you could try I could
try and I could think of something
unbiased but in what general is just
hard because you know and in fact there
is a scientific basis on that because
your brain our brain our brain is not
you know throughout through viral
evolution our brain is not here to think
rationally or logically but rather a lot
of a lot of it the way we perceive
things this has to do with how so we can
survive so we can have more children
it's a it's not about you know so so how
you become a more just person or more
favored person that's not you know those
true just person favor person they get
eliminated you don't get children you
die off rather we are we are you know
evolution your brain the way you
perceive things is more you perceive
things to benefit yourself that's that's
that's how all these spires lot most of
it a lot of it came from that so anyways
so in the you know Emax community for
example for those people who insist that
you should swap swap caps lock with
control you know this is one of the
kote mantra they say you know they did
tell everyone
oh you should swap caps-lock with
control so so when these people they
will say you know one of their thought
is that oh all the old computers they
all have caps lock at the right position
okay that's what they think they think
okay like this one okay like this one
this one is tech meaty 1100 okay they
think all the old computers have caps
lock at you know at the right position
this is original wait wait not a spot
wait they think the caps lock should be
way yeah here okay here look at this
Apple keyboard you see control is a
control is to the left of a caps lock as
is at the corner okay so all these
people
Emacs phonetics they think all the
keyboard used to have the control
besides a you know that's what they
think they do you know they they want to
believe they want to believe they want
to believe UNIX is the best operating
system they want to believe Emacs is the
best editor they want to believe this is
Common Lisp is the greatest language
they want to believe you know people
want to believe Perl is the best so on
Python people want to believe computer
science we are computer science I
thought so you know you want to believe
in Apple phonetics this fops Apple you
know they have money they buy every
Apple stuff gadget every whatever Apple
came out they buy Apple phonetics they
have their there one day they want to
believe whatever Apple to say so anyway
so this so but if you actually look
history of the Keela the caps lock
position that's so what they believe is
force
it's just force okay so I I did a survey
of all the keyboards you know so what
happens is that it's kind of like heaven
half
some some have caps locks to the left of
a some have caps locks to the to the
corner you know on but control to the
left of a okay but anyway these people
believed it is yeah they typically they
are also Microsoft haters so they
believe it is Microsoft they blame a
Microsoft Microsoft created keyboard
that that made the caps lock to the left
of a popular that's not true the fact
actually the one that made it popular is
IBM IBM PC keyboard that keyboard and
seat series of IBM PC keyboard made made
the caps lock to the left of a popular
Universal kind of okay so here's a
survey of all keyboards you know and
also by the way this never had control
to the left obey this miss kind of this
machine keyboards is kind of out you
know it's weird to compare to all the
others so so I've actually I have a
collection of list machine keyboards
actually a few months ago I have a video
I talked about this list machine
keyboards topic for one hour so you have
and you know they relate to Lisp III
that's very interesting topic by itself
so okay so that's I think that's about
it for today so so let me check the
comments
so yeah that's it for today and so bossy
it basquiat says why is control H in
emacs is for help but in bash it is
backspace default yeah there is a
history to that now the impacts in patch
control H is backspace that is because
because in historically the terminal I
think it's I know the reason for that
but I forgot if I have a blog about that
I might have but I know someone else has
written blogs about that I think you if
you search the web you'll find it but
let me show you
chapo history if you go to Casa keyboard
blog then go to keyboard history I think
that control edge for backspace that
came from terminal for example because
on terminal they actually have a key
okay not not this one I think it's the
same with the e VI this one had a DM 3a
yeah I I think it may came from this for
example this uch that's a vis backspace
you have the arrow printed on it this is
an interesting to talk about this is
about VI key binding history and also we
can top out about Emacs key binding
history but it's too late today so let's
talk about that next time so anyway so I
think that came from terminal now in
Emacs it's different control HP is
something else because because Emacs
yeah most of Emacs key binding came from
this
machine keyboards and the father of
lease machine keyboards is this one this
this one is called cell keyboard
Stanfill cell keyboard sales and stand
for Stanford AI lab okay and we recently
today three days ago Richard Stallman he
got kicked out kick you know he quit as
a free software foundation president and
he also got kicked out as a visiting
professor from C cell C self central
anyway it's you know it's something AI a
I lab okay anyway so so so Emacs
keybinding mostly came from list
machines as to why is it edge I don't
know the details but I think it's based
on edge for help you know in lisp
machine typically you have an entire
system likely max you know today a lot
of people say Emacs is a lisp operating
system Emacs is basically as close as
you get to list machine but in the back
you know in those days 20 years ago 30
years ago so so in list machines you and
this OS you have like entire system it's
kind of like Emacs almost like like I
you know Emacs okay so you have a system
you have help system you have you know
like key binding system you have you can
customize everything you have describe
key you have describe key describe
function for example describe hold on a
second describe key control edge edge
okay for example I can Co describe key
weight
okay so describe key control H F
describe function okay here's a here's a
inline documentation for the command
describe function anyway so it's you got
a whole bunch of systems and typically
in this culture okay okay in this list
culture everything is it's it's is in
sharp contrast to the UNIX culture now
let me let me talk about UNIX cultures
because then you get the easy idea so
units culture you have tons of
abbreviations like incomprehensible
command file command names like cat yes
you know CD you know you got you know
and less more you know and you get fancy
kids you know Katie's mother money and
anyway that's a that's a UNIX culture
everything is abbreviation short you
know things I got in in the Lisp culture
everything is spelled out like Lisp is
kind of like the whole Cathedral it's a
system so when it comes to you know you
so it doesn't use all this creep cryptic
abbreviations so you have help and
things like that
so when it comes to key binding its H
for help I think so that that's that's
my that's what I think ok so I think I
think that's that's it for today so let
me just read the comments to we close
now in two minutes
okay so like this smokes acid so United
States cause what do you think of
Wolfram Alpha if I'm offered the few
times I try it doesn't really work well
I actually said Oh Jeremy so actually
last week I did a entire video on a new
kind of science Wolfram Alpha okay new
so let's go to San tanco new kind so
this is actually a good one you know
some of my videos like once
once in a month there's one or two
that's the best for a month something
like that so this this you know if you
are interested maybe you watch this one
so this is September I mean this is
August 28 math languages scientific
programming a new kind of science what
is random and cellular automata yes
actually wait that one and
scientific programming a new kind of
science yeah so that one is about no so
that one but there's another one to mean
let's say automata silly automata Turing
machine okay oh yeah okay I think it's
that one wait yeah anyway yeah yeah I
think a new kind of science I think it's
the one
ya know because let me try to find it
okay syntax
yeah yeah that one just check that one
so I guess I probably lost all watches
let's see how many people are watching
all the people are getting so anyway
that's that's it for today
thank you Thank You gerald Jeremiah and
bust here Basquiat says I was in your
Twitter discussion if you want to look
at my discussion on castle culture what
is your Twitter handle post it okay if
it's not too out there okay don't pose
anything else to out there if your
Twitter account is like you know all the
chance to have don't post it
oh yeah oh yeah that's right so Jeremiah
is correct on that that's right yes
that's a that's a that's a correct
answer I think so Jeremiah says because
control H control H is the standard
character for delete in a stream UNIX
convention yes but also I think it came
from ASCII I I think I'm pretty sure now
I remember
it came from ASCII and by the way that
UNIX terminal that VI UNIX terminal the
reason they have arrow keys on you know
H hjkl
is also because ASCII they are they are
kind of tied to tied together so they're
yeah control H so ASCII code number 8's
Kiko number 8 you have that's control H
back for meaning backspace yeah so thank
you guys for watching and thank ya so
bye if you likes my stuff you know put
my put money in my pocket okay bye