Good morning, guys. Welcome to another
episode of South Talk Show.
Today is 2019 October 25th.
USA Friday
12:00 noon
San Francisco time.
Welcome all.
Good morning, Bot. Good morning, Freddy.
I think Freddy is here. Freddy Freeman.
And a good morning
Odd Harold.
My friend.
So, we are going to talk about uh
keyboards.
Let's see.
Keyboards, welcome to the chat and uh
type questions you have or comments.
Okay.
So, uh
Good morning, Freddy, and uh
and uh who is it asking uh
Odd Harold.
Ask a question about Kinesis versus
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard.
Oh, Kinesis discuss how comfy the
Kinesis is. Okay. So, let me show you
the Kinesis.
I showed this a thousand times. Let's
see if I have this video. Okay, I have
it.
So, I showed a thousand times. Now,
remember I switched to this keyboard.
This This is the Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard. And now, look how I changed my
name. It's now XXX.
This is
X-rated keyboard.
Uh and this is the Kinesis. And uh
so,
Harold Odd Harold ask how comfy the
Kinesis keyboard is. How comfy?
Uh well,
let's see if I can
have these
like put it on my shoulder
and uh
and maybe I can type. How comfy it is.
Okay, this is a tricky
tricky maneuver. It's like a military
maneuver.
This doesn't
doesn't look too good. So, it's it's
very good. I love it better than the
better than the ultimate hacking
keyboard.
Uh this is not going to work.
Okay, and uh what the [ __ ] is this?
Oh, this is
this is the microphone.
Okay, how do I
how do I do this? On the right shoulder
or on the left shoulder? On the right
shoulder. Okay, now it's better.
Now you can see. Now I have to actually
do this this way.
So, how comfy
comfy? Okay, hold on. Magnify, magnify,
magnify.
How comfy is the Kinesis Advantage
2 keyboard?
It is supremacy.
Okay.
Um
So, it's very good. I like it very much.
You see it's got all these curves as you
know.
Uh it it curves down so that your your
wrist
your wrist do not bend up like a typical
keyboard. You the your wrist is straight
and uh your fingers dip in to the keys.
And you can see the keys they have
different height. You see this D
this D is uh hold on a second. It It's
You see this D?
Well, I'm using a Vor ax so you see that
that's E.
That is O.
So, so anyway, you see the the D is
lower down because your index finger is
higher, much higher. And so they are
they are adjusted for your finger
length.
And so it is fantastic and you use these
um
thumb keys for
for space, for frequently used keys such
as
Okay, such as
enter. You see this is enter, this is
space.
And on the left hand you have backspace,
backspace, backspace. And you have
forward delete. Okay, forward delete.
Something like this, move to the
beginning and forward delete. Okay, I
need to
forward delete.
Oh, I
It doesn't It does not work here because
I'm using Emacs with special key
binding, but you can see it here.
Stupid Mac that it prevents you from
holding
uh
Wait.
This is
prevent
you from holding
uh
I'm using You see, I'm used to Emacs, so
So anyway, holding a key down. So you
can use You can move to the top,
move here,
and uh you see forward delete. So
anyway,
the thumb keys are great.
So how comfortable? It is extremely
comfortable. It's my
keyboard of choice. Okay, actually
uh all this typing is when wasted
because you didn't see it because
all this typing
all this typing went
went wasted because you did not because
because
because I forgot to switch my video
setup.
Okay, now back to Emacs.
Back to Emacs. This is fun.
fantastic
Okay, so space
enter
backspace
and forward delete
Okay.
So anthem keys are great and yeah, it's
so it's great everything.
That's Kinesis Advantage keyboard and
you go buy it now.
I have I I have a video review
um
keyboard, okay.
So you go to my Kinesis keyboard blog
and go to ErgoDox keyboard and you go
here and you buy it.
It has I have a video review, more
detailed video review and text review
everything.
So actually, so let me open a new
buffer, paste it here
make a link
copy it and go back.
So those of you in USA, buy it.
Now
uh
Now let's see.
Yes, I'm here. Now am I still talking?
Okay, so
Now, let's get this fixed.
Okay.
So, it's fantastic. Now,
Now, my only complaint is that the thumb
keys are a bit far because I'm a Asian,
as you know, I'm a Asian.
My hands are not big. My hand are in
general smaller than white men's hands,
smaller than black men's hands.
Um
you know,
how smaller? Well, not too small, but I
mean like half a centimeter. That
matters. That makes a difference. And
women's hands are even smaller. So, this
this is
So, this keyboard, if you look at thumb
keys, this is my natural thumb position.
So, I have to stretch quite a bit to
press the enter.
So, you have to be careful because once
you buy this keyboard or ErgoDox
keyboard,
if you buy this keyboard or ErgoDox,
anything with the thumb, you have to
watch out. You don't want to make this
movement too much. You don't want to do
that, okay? You don't want like just go
there, put press enter. Rather, what you
want is you move the whole hand over.
That's what I do. So, I don't like
stretch to press these keys. I don't do
that. When I want to do that, in fact,
actually, when I want to press this key,
typically, I actually use this finger.
You want to move the hand your whole
whole hand. Don't stretch. Okay, that's
important.
That's important because when you have
any type of repetitive strain injury
or
when you feel uncomfort,
but again, depends on how much you type,
you know, if you are young, you you you
are a programmer, you never
actually type that much. You think you
do, but compare compare to others, you
don't.
So, you don't have a problem. So, you
think, "Oh, Kinesis advice are
bullshit." Well, that's because you
don't type that much actually. You a lot
other people do.
So, like I mentioned many times before,
you have to get a sense of how exactly
how much you type.
Okay, so the the key the thumb keys are
a bit too
Well, so depends on your hand. For me,
you know, it's a bit too
too too inward.
So, that's one keyboard. Good morning,
Alan.
And so So, yeah, I recommend it.
So, I have so many, you know, ergonomic
keyboards reviews here. You can any one
of them is good. Okay, all these are
pretty good. Which one to choose really
depends on you. Depend on your
situation, depend depends on your
preference because they For example,
their price varies greatly. For example,
these Microsoft ones, this is pretty
good. It's only $60.
On the other hand, if you want Kinesis,
it's $340
or $320, something $300. Okay.
And
if you
you know, if you don't really
want, you know, this extreme, you you go
with the
uh Ultimate Hacking Keyboard. This is
great.
And this is what I have here.
So,
I had this for like over a year now, but
mostly I'm using these because, you
know, because it's curved. But But
yesterday, last week I switched to this
for a while for a change, and now I
switched back
because I I prefer these, you know,
because
but if if I'm on a go,
then this is better because that is kind
of big.
So, it really depends a a lot on you.
And also,
you know, they have very different
features and qualifications.
Uh
very different. For example, this
this
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard is a got the
greatest programmability. Let me show
you.
Uh
Karabiner Event Viewer, Karabiner
Elements, okay? Uh wait, that's not what
we want. Close that.
We want to open the UHK Agent.
UHK stands for
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard. UHK Ultimate
Hacking.
It's got the greatest programmability of
them all, I would say. E- even, you
know, I know some of you are Ergodox
fans. Like every day you are
um
talking about, "Oh, Ergodox, we need
Ergodox. Ergodox, what do you think of
Ergodox?"
This one. This is the Ergodox, okay? The
Ergodox keyboard got the worst problem
with the thumb keys.
Now, remember I said the Kinesis thumb
keys are a bit too
Uh wait, can you see the my screen?
Okay, yes. Okay. Remember I said the the
Kinesis the thumb keys are too much. I
have to move
my fingers inward to press these keys.
The Ergodox is actually worse.
Um I talked about this uh uh
before in my video.
So, in fact, you go down, there is a guy
uh
Ergodox
thumb keys.
Okay, bad point. ErgoDox thumb key pain.
This guy is a fanatic of ErgoDox
keyboard.
This guy uh
he's he's somewhat well-known in the
keyboard community, but and he loved
ErgoDox. He got several ErgoDox. He
built them.
And he's a evangelist for ErgoDox.
But one day he felt the pain you know in
his thumb. He don't know what's the
problem. He thought it's a thumb pain,
so he adjusted the thumb pain.
Then the pain went away, but it came
back after 3 days. So he's in a trouble.
He's in trouble.
Like me several you know in the past 15
years, you know you you started to have
pain and you don't know what's going on.
You don't know why. You know usually
this happens. You don't know why.
But until you really try to find out why
and he found out it's because of thumb
keys because he's moving the thumb keys
too much.
The thumb not not the yeah, he's moving
the thumb too much. So
so he ditched them all. He sold all his
ErgoDox and he went back to
he went back to this keyboard, okay.
PC keyboard. He went back to this
another very famous popular
high quality keyboard. This one. He went
back to the Leopold FC 660C.
Remember
it is this model that's critical because
they have two models. The other model
looks similar, but it's not the same.
This one.
FC660M
is similar, but it's actually entirely
different. The key switches stuff are
different. So he went back to this one.
Which is
idiotic, but you know E each person it's
different.
So, you have to watch out for the thumb
keys, okay? Don't I mean even on
ErgoDox,
you know,
don't try not just move your thumb like
that. Move your whole finger, you know.
Uh this is actually
this is a good advice applies to every
keyboard. You you don't want to do any
kind of kind of stretch like pressing
the uh control key with your pinky like
stretch or something like that. Don't do
that. Move your whole hand, okay?
So, that is about that.
Uh Meow Cat, watch your language.
Please.
Good morning, Cathy.
Uh okay, let's see what's the other
comments. So, Odd Harold, are you still
here? So, Odd Harold is swapping between
keyboard necessary. Uh
swapping between keyboards. It's not
necessary, but for me I sometimes I
change keyboard because they it
it's not necessary, but you know,
for me it probably it's fun because I
love keyboards, so I want to switch
around. And also partly because if you
have RSI, repetitive strain injury, it's
good because it changes your muscle
memory, you know, for a change.
Uh so,
so if you want curved, so this is great.
Of course, there's a also Maltron, but
Maltron is $500, okay? Kinesis is 300
something, but Maltron is I think it's
better actually, but it's $500.
So, it's up to you, like.
And then you have
these do-it-yourself keyboards. For
example, this one.
This is fantastic, okay? Now, this one
the thumb keys are closer. For so, if
you have smaller hand size or if you are
a woman
or Asian, this is better thumb keys.
So I tried it. This is really I really
love this one. Elegant, but
you have to
you know, build it yourself. But
actually
so I went I went in a keyboard meet up
in San Francisco about 2 years ago, 2000
18 or was it 2016?
Uh
so I tried it. It's fan- fantastic. So
that's Kinesis Advantage 2.
Uh actually that's Advantage 1. But
anyway, so
so Dactyl is great.
And you can see many people has build
it.
And but today you can actually buy it
pre-built for sale for I think was it
$340.
Yeah, you can buy it. You have variety
of configurations.
You just go to this page, okay? I have
JavaScript off, so you don't see the
variations. But anyway, you can buy it.
So that's pretty good.
And you see this keyboard has much less
keys than Kinesis.
Uh okay, so that I'm not going to um
You see Kinesis, you got these function
keys on top.
You don't have that. So so the solution
is
a solution for that is again to get a
programmable keypad, okay? Like the one
I have in the middle. You get, you know,
for for example, I can
um
uh anyways.
Okay, I'm back. Let's see what uh
What comments do we have?
Made me mad. Made me sad. Oh, that's
because Webpack.
So, I spent 3 hours studying Webpack
JavaScript yesterday looking at the
source code.
So, and what do you think of uh the
vernal laptop keyboards before chiclet
style? Okay, uh we can we can talk about
that. So, Bart says
Bart says he is
going to build
this keyboard.
Nyquist Nyquist
Now, this is a very simple design.
So, this is also do-it-yourself. You buy
the kit and you assemble it yourself.
You also have to solder the electronics.
Uh you know, you might spend a day doing
that. So, I think this is pretty good,
you know, pretty simple.
And good luck to you, Bart.
So, uh next question. The others are too
wavy, okay? Yeah, uh I like it just
square. Square, okay.
Yes, I'm here. And yes, so Freddy says
and yes, since you are talking about uh
JavaScript frameworks, I wondered how do
you do unit tests in JavaScript? If you
do, what framework do you use? Okay.
Now, you may
I talked about this many times.
I am a JavaScript expert, okay?
But, however, I do not know the modern
frameworks, the modern JavaScript
frameworks, actually. I need to show my
stuff.
So, you go to my JavaScript website.
This is JavaScript in depth. This is the
most in-depth
This is the best JavaScript in-depth
book
in English language on Earth, okay? It
is the best.
That is my assertion. That is my claim.
Now, you can anytime, if you know a
JavaScript book, type it right now. I
can give you my comment why mine is
better. Like any any book, printed or
otherwise, printed or Mozilla or
Microsoft or from whatever or JavaScript
the JavaScript you don't know
JavaScript, there's that book, okay? Any
JavaScript book in English language,
type it. Uh make a criticism. I'll tell
you why mine is best, okay? And you can
go buy my tutorial.
You know, go there, buy it.
Make a comment commitment and help me,
support me.
So, I have a JavaScript in depth and uh
simple DOM tutorial, you know? So,
JavaScript in depth includes JavaScript
object references. And also, in this
tutorial, you have a basic practical
DOM tutorial. These are the DOM from
ground from the ground up. You do not
need This is This tutorial is is not
about React JS, no using jQuery, no
using nothing, no library whatsoever,
plain vanilla
JavaScript. So, if you master
my tutorial, you can you can write a
framework such as React JS or
View or Angular or, you know, a bunch of
them.
Uh but, however,
I'm a dinosaur. I'm old-fashioned. I
have, you know, I and I'm getting old,
so I do not know
actually, so I do not know the modern
JavaScript development workflow. Like
you NPM, you know, NPM in it get get a
structure of you know, so I was just
looking at Webpack.
You know, I was looking at the Webpack
source code for 3 hours yesterday.
You know, I'm trying to
in my usual exploration,
you know, Tsar exploration fashion, look
at all things, you know, what whatever I
find interesting in the source code.
Anyway, modern JavaScript, you have, for
example, you have this
package.json, you know, NPM in it
package.json, then you got this
1,000 dependencies, okay? Like
literally, some of them not 1,000, but
for example, in Webpack, you have 21
dependencies.
That means those are libraries you have
to install before, you know, if you are
working on Webpack, I mean, developing
the Webpack library, you need these 20
21 dependencies, and I was looking at
them each one, like what they are, what
they do.
Um
and then you have 41
dev dependencies. Now, dev dependencies
means
means it's not the final product of your
project. So, if you are working on
Webpack, you know, if you are the
creator of Webpack,
you your final project is the Webpack
library.
But, however, when when you are working
on it, you need what's so-called dev
dependencies that makes your development
easier, you know, you have bunch of
tools. So, you this webpack, for
example, require 40
one
dev dependencies
and 21
actual dependencies. You know, it's a
headache. And each one of them
dependencies, the library, may also
require 10 or 20 dependencies.
So, that's today's JavaScript situation.
You know, NPM and webpack, by the way,
webpack is a tool. It's called bundler.
So, if you don't code JavaScript, it's
you know, it will take some time to
explain, but basically bundler takes a
bunch of JavaScript source code and
output one JavaScript source code all of
all things together.
Meanwhile, eliminating the code or
function you don't use.
Why why do you have that? Because
JavaScript originally do not have a
library system.
So, over the past
30 years now, it's a bunch of
you know,
uh non-standard solutions, then standard
solution comes up, then you have to
worry about compatibility because you
can't just throw away all the entire
industrial code that's using one system
of library system, you know, library
mechanism.
So, you have lots of tools that deal
with this problem. So, you have the
concept of bundler.
Which is, by the way, different from
compiler, although it seems like you
know, it's like a compiler. It takes a
bunch of source code output one single
source code, JavaScript code.
But,
that's bun- bundler, but it's not
actually compiler. Then, you have
you have loaders, you have transformers.
So, modern JavaScript is very complex,
okay?
Then, you have Node.js. Then, you look
you know, look at this
uh package package.json. You have You
have what not engines. You have engines.
You have
uh okay, homepage. Then you have script
section. Script section is bunch of like
auto automation test testing unit
testing and and
a bunch of crap, linting and and and
stuff, okay.
So,
so that's modern JavaScript development
and uh I'm not familiar with it. I don't
know how,
you know, I don't have experience. I
don't know exactly, you know, I'm not
familiar with it.
But I'm learning it, so that's why I'm
looking into it. So, as to your
question, what do I recommend about, you
know, what unit testing package, you
what unit testing library I use, things
like that, I don't know.
Okay?
So, that answers that question.
Uh
So, comments comments, guys, comments.
Let me read the comments. Next next
question.
Nightmare is a great choice. Yes, and uh
Fitman says, okay, hold on a second. Let
me check.
Check my status.
Am I alive? Yes, 13 people watching.
I'm lucky. Friday. Okay, if today is
Friday Friday and we we got 13 people
and now 14, okay.
Next question.
Uh
So, Freddy says, currently using Mocha
in TypeScript. Okay.
Mocha.
Uh
I don't know what that is. Is that a
template system?
Let's see. Mocha TypeScript.
It's interesting. So, yesterday So,
Mocha TypeScript. Okay, let's see what
that is.
Uh Mocha TypeScript writing Mocha test
with style OOP style. Oh, okay. So, it's
a test framework, I suppose.
Import blah blah blah from Mocha
TypeScript. Okay, that is
uh
JavaScript 2015.
And sweet class hello something
whatever.
Okay, it's a test framework. I don't
like testing. Okay, I don't like unit
testing. I did a video talking about
that.
Uh you don't do unit testing.
Well, you you it's useful, but uh
but not the way today's
average programmers perceives unit
testing because
average programmers, just like average
people, they are brainless. They don't
think. They live in modern society like
your pet. You know, modern society, you
got pets, dogs, cats
who
when they were children
they live in your house for their entire
life.
You know, you open the door, they don't
they won't go out because they don't
know what to do. They they are afraid.
So, they are just happy. Pet. You pet
them. Pet. So, modern human animals are
kind of like that.
You watch TV or you go to Twitter, you
watch your smartphone every day. You are
happy. Okay. When someone talks about
political stuff, controversy, oh,
someone got killed. Oh, you know,
oh, you don't want to talk about that
because
you are fine, you know, as long as just,
you know, you you go to work, you make
money, you can go to Starbucks and have
a cup of coffee, enjoy your life. You
are okay. Okay, you don't worry about
You don't You don't I don't want to make
trouble. Okay, you want to be good.
So
So when the politician, the powerful,
you know, the
Epstein
or whatever, you know, the powerful
Google Google's head, Facebook,
Zuckerberg they do things. They do
things. Okay, but you
you are normal people. Okay, you are
law-abiding citizen. You don't want to
talk about that.
So that's that that is what modern
society has become.
Uh
Why is that Why is that all
uh or what can you do?
Well, it's part of nature. Okay, it's
actually natural. It's It is natural
when you have this tremendous technology
and when your society becomes
complicated.
That's kind of the
how things go in a natural way. It
is in a sense that it's a natural. Okay.
Um
Okay, so So what why So why why am I
saying that? So that's modern society.
Okay, it's not because
um
Well, what My point is that it's it's
actually the way things are. It's It's
It's just a modern society. So my point
is that similarly for average
programmers, they are also normal. Okay.
Uh because they watch TV, they watch
their smartphone, not Well,
for programmers, well, what do you
watch? Not TV, but you watch You go to
You read Hacker News. You read Reddit.
You go to Google. You go there work
every day. All you hear All you see
every day is the same old typical
opinions about programming. What is
good? What is bad? Oh, you should format
your code this way. You should not do
that way. Okay, this is the best
technology. If you do that way, you are
evil or you are stupid, things like
that. Modern average programmers are
brainless, including Well, so who who
are the leaders? Who create these bad
things? Typically, the programmer
celebrities, like for example, some pe-
some of the few I don't like.
Larry Wall, who created Perl.
Python, the guy to Van Rossum who
created Python. He got a bag of
opinions, okay? I mean, these are good
people, okay? But I don't like their
opinion. And typically, they create a
cult-like structure. They For example,
Python community, Perl community. And
they tell you what to do.
Not directly, not not like a
dictatorship, you know, that's typically
what Americans think. Is it dict-
dictatorship? No. Okay, then it's good.
Okay, that's the typical American.
Think think, okay? They don't think.
But anyway, Guido van Rossum,
uh Larry Wall, for example, and uh the
guy who created Rail, Ruby on Rails.
That's he's an [ __ ] He goes by the
name DH, you know, DHH or HDD or
something.
He is an [ __ ]
And he is also one of the guy who tell
you what to do. Like his opinion is the
best opinion. He
Unlike me, okay? I tell you my opinion.
I think it's the best opinion, but it's
up to you. You can see, you know, I give
you the perspective. You can you can
judge.
Uh think about my reasons. And if you
don't believe, you don't you know, if
you don't agree with me, that's fine.
Because different people, different
background, different needs. You know,
you go you do your ways.
But some people like the DHH guy, you
know, the the guy who created Ruby on
Rails, He's a
scum, in my opinion, okay? Because he
tell you what to do, and if you do, you
know, he he force his opinions onto you.
And also because he's rich, he's one of
the rich and powerful. He's uh like
that.
Okay, so lots of questions. Let me get
to them, okay? So, I I was digressing. I
was saying, so modern programmers,
average programmers, they don't think.
They
the thinking ability is removed from
them, just like uh uh uh
average people, and just like your pets
in your house, your, you know, your dogs
or your cats.
Uh happy is the keyword, you know? You
you you want to keep them happy, just
like your government keep you happy. And
uh these open-source things, you know,
these Python, these uh Ruby on Rails
guy, you know, they keep you happy, you
know?
Well, open source.
It make you happy, open source.
Everything is free, free, my friend.
And uh you should support it because
it makes you happy.
Okay, so
so what is What am I talking about? What
uh I'm talking about modern JavaScript
uh development.
Uh
and uh what
I forgot. What is the point? Why am I
talking about that?
Free us in herpes, open source, Linux.
Okay, so
so unit testing
So, I guess I was talking about unit
testing, and uh that, you know, So, I
was saying, you know, unit testing is
good idea, but not the way typical Yeah,
so not the way
what most people are thinking, you know,
because it has become unit testing along
with
unit testing came from Agile. Agile came
from
extreme programming, okay? That's when
that's the concept of pair programming
originates. And why?
Why did pair programming originate?
Because that's a way for
non-coding managers to manage you
programmers.
To make you watch each other. To make
you fight with each other. So they can
fire you at any time. So you as a
programmer is just a pawn in you know
under the big corporations like Google.
They can you know fire you, do anything
they want.
And they are the purveyor of open
source. Without Google, without
Facebook, without Microsoft, open source
will be dead
long ago.
It is open It It is Google, Facebook,
Apple, Microsoft, these people with
1,000 million patent lawyers. They
They
you know, put
put uh meat in your mouth in in this uh
you know, pets. Just just as you feed
your pets every day.
So more come uh so so I was saying yeah,
so so test, you know, the the test, you
know, test testing software testing has
become a industry, you know, billion I
don't know million hundred million
billion dollar industry.
You know, big corporations you have like
unit testing. So anyway,
yeah, unit testing is good, but not the
way
you think, okay? It's It has, you know,
because
what average programmers thinking about
these things are just uh commercialized
brain box, you know, they just hand it
to you. You You should think of that
way, you know, you should do unit
testing every code every you know, for
example, if you are you know, if you are
bought out if you are you know, into the
agile thing
there are some programmers are
if you are bought out by the agile thing
then you your thinking will be oh
every line of code must have a unit test
first, you know, like you have to write
unit test first before you get anything
you know,
there's a you know, there's a train of
thought over there.
That is extreme case.
But anyway, unit testing is and and also
you see it it is somewhat it's kind of a
loop, you know, it's a feedback bit
feedback loop.
Unit testing has become pervasive and
critical all important in in in
software.
Why? Because software becomes
more and more and more complex, you
know, browsers you you know, anyone can
[ __ ] up anytime you it's common, you
know, even I if I even I do.
Because for example, if I you know, I'm
looking at webpack, you know, the mod
one of the modern JavaScript
library
and I look at the code first you know,
first of all, you know, like it loads 20
dependencies and 40 dependencies dev
dependencies. What the [ __ ]
It's not the case before like before
before the modern you know, JavaScript
era.
Let's say in 1900 or 2000s.
When you have a library that's just a
library
typically or you know, that that library
is just by itself.
It may use other libraries but like one
or two three five at tops, okay?
You know, so you you you you can use
that library or you can study that
library and use you know how it works.
Not the case with today's JavaScript
thing.
For example, I look at Webpack, you
know, suppose I you know, I'm a hotshot,
you know, I know programming, I know
JavaScript well. So, I want to
understand it. I look at Webpack.
First thing First thing is this 20
dependencies.
Each one of them, you know, it's you
have to read study each one of them, you
know, it it it it may take a few hours
more than few hours, okay? It will take
days or weeks to understand each one of
them.
And then you have the 41 dependencies
and also each of these dependencies,
they they they may load, you know, 100
other dependencies.
And anyway, and so
So, okay, back to the so
in 1990s, every other language, Pearl,
you know, when you have a library
that just does one thing.
I mean, yeah, of course it does one
thing, but it
usually does not load 100 other
libraries.
This is, I think, unique in JavaScript.
I do not think it is the case in other
languages, not not in PHP, not in Pearl,
not in Python, not in
Ruby. I'm not sure about Ruby, but I
don't think that, you know,
and not in For example, the language I
know, you know, you don't use you don't
call like 40 or you know,
other dependencies. It's kind of unique
in JavaScript.
And I don't think it happens in Golang,
neither. So, why does JavaScript Well,
part of it is because JavaScript is
truly lousy, so you have
25 years of baggage, you know,
tremendous baggage of it.
So, back to unit testing. So, I was
saying, you know, so why why did it
become
popular? For two reasons. One
is the corporations
commercialization because money.
You know, once you have unit testing
you have thousands of corporations. They
sell unit testing framework. They sell
unit state unit testing services. Like
they can help your company, you know,
tell you what to do, tell you what's the
best way. You know, there's a lot
consultancy
corporations like that. They help other
medium to small companies, you know, do
unit testing, things like that. They
They Then you have frameworks, you you
have entire software, not open source,
you know, often some some of them open
source, some of them not.
They sell their, you know, library of
framework for unit testing and you go
their website, they'll see, "Oh, we we
do we our clients, Google, Facebook, you
know, Microsoft, government, you know,
it's all good things. Open, you know,
unit testing."
So why is it popular?
One is that because it's money, because
money. They want to, you know, these
corporation exist not because unit
testing is truly great. It truly helps
software industry. Not necessarily so.
But more because they are company, they
want to make money. Or you
happens to write a unit testing
framework. You want to promote it, of
course. You then you start to tell
everyone, "Unit testing is the most
important thing." You evangelize. You
become one of the programmer
celebrities, where every fart you say
becomes on Hacker News. Then 100,000
programmers talk about it. "You know,
unit testing. Oh, he says this, this,
that, that. Oh, I agree. Oh, I don't
agree."
You know, [ __ ] heads.
These idiots.
So one reason unit testing become
popular is because like Agile, you know,
because commercialization, because
money. Money. Not because it's good,
because, you know, money. They make
money.
So, that's one reason. What's the other
reason unit testing becomes so pervasive
and critical? Because
software itself becomes more and more
complex. Why?
Part of the reason is because the
programmers becomes more and more
brainless. Because you started to have
agile, you started have to have pair
programming, you focus on all these
garbage, okay?
You don't focus on math. Math, for
example. Practice. Know your programming
language well. You don't focus on those
things anymore. Because it's like losing
fat, okay? It's like women losing fat or
guys.
You know, you want to lose fat. Oh, but
you have this something something diet.
And next year you have something
something SlimFast next year. The next
is year you have something incredible
new diet that you you lose weight. Well,
if you want to lose weight, stop eating.
That's it, okay? People who are poor,
they don't gain weight, okay? It's not
You you have so much money, you're so
comfortable.
But you cannot help yourself. You then
you have to then you have a need to look
at this
one weird way one weird trick to lose 2
lb in a week, okay?
This all garbage. And they make money,
you know? They they are trying to sell
their SlimFast or whatever. They all
trying to make money.
And all some strange exercise or yoga
or, you know, you know, some you know,
they especially when it comes to diet in
America, you know, it's crazy. Paleo
Paleolithic diet or whatever. Sugar,
you know, what whatever meat diet or
carb-free diet, juice diet, whatever
diet that is that that [ __ ]
So, that's a similar situation in
programming. Back to unit testing, okay?
So, today's programmer because the
corporation, commercialization, and the
hacker news all all they are all trying
to make money. Money is that drives, you
know, all this crap.
Then, you get programmers who are who
become like idiots.
Okay? Well,
fact more more precisely, you you you
get programmers who are who know less
than let's say 90 let's let's say in the
1990s.
You know, who don't study, you know,
much. You just use a bunch of like, you
know, like webpack, you know.
You just load libraries. Each one is
like five lines. You should know how to
write it. You don't need it, but
you don't know what you're doing. You
got software blow You got, you know, So,
you got [ __ ] because you are no good.
Then, you got lots of other [ __ ] Then,
browsers, you know, each browser Google
Chrome they they are they become
criminals. They do whatever, you know,
they fight they On one hand, they say,
"Oh, we respect standard." On the other
hand, they do devious things, [ __ ] up
everything.
That's browser. So, it become the
browser today becomes is probably one of
the most complex software, okay? More
far more 10 times more complex than
Emacs to write a browser.
It's not just about about a spec, you
see? Because they have a lot of hacks
to be so so that they are fast, you
know, to be competitive, you know?
That's another story. So, anyway,
one back to my original what I'm trying
to say. One reason
uh unit test becomes ubiquitous because
money, commercialization by this corp
by, you know, lots of corporations. The
other reason it becomes necessary almost
because
software becomes too complex. Not not
necessarily so,
but rather one drives the other.
Because, you see, software, a browser,
for example,
may not need to be, you know, Unix
browser, you know, it it actually may
not be that complex. The complexities
are man-made. Human animals made them.
Okay, so they become more and more more
complex. Why do they become more
complex? Because this framework, these
corporations, they, you know, put
garbage in it. So it become more
complex. When it's more complex, you
need more unit testing. So it's a
feedback feedback loop. You see, that's
why I'm saying.
You see, it becomes so complex, this
webpack, this [ __ ] two 20
dependencies and 40 dependencies.
So when you write this webpack, you need
to then you need you need unit testing.
Then you have
one 1,000 unit testing frameworks. You
see? You see what I'm saying?
Now, in my biased opinion, this
Where does this come from? From the Unix
philosophy. [ __ ] The Unix people.
Those people who promote Unix and Linux.
You know, Unix is the first one. Unix
and C language is the the granddaddy who
created this kind of thing, this kind of
mentality, you know, and then thinking,
oh, you know, for example, Unix begin
with jargons. Unix philosophy, that's
first thing. Unix philosophy, which is
unscientific, you know, crap, you know,
it's a just code mantra.
Unix philosophy.
Then, you know, that's that in my
opinion, it's this is rather biased
opinion, but it's a
That's my view of things.
So have you done any rants about
software dependency bloat in general?
Uh no, but that's what I'm doing now.
Is that not enough?
So, uh
So, let's go back to the question. So, I
was talking so unit test, yeah, I don't
know unit test, okay, I don't know too
too well. Actually, I talked about unit
test for like half an hour in previous
videos. You might find it. Let's see.
Go to Tsar Talk Show, search test.
And okay, so it's it's not in the title.
Now, search the content. Unit testing,
okay, unit test. Let's see if we can
find it.
No, I should have it. I talked about it
sometimes.
Last month, also.
So, let's keep Let me keep reading the
comments.
Actually, I do have some
um
some more keyboard stuff I want to talk
about.
Evolution of laptop keyboards, yeah, I
you can talk about that.
Uh and other things.
Uh so, let's read the comments.
I have to go to the shop now before it
closes. Be right back, okay, Freddy.
Uh
Kathy,
uh
Kathy, I'm almost on board now. So,
Kathy, you need to buy a keyboard.
Uh is that right? Is that what you're
saying?
Have to go to the shop. Can you see this
is cool. So, Alan says another thing
which Tsar would not have to worry about
is that some key codes are hard on the
Kinesis.
Yes.
Uh that is true. Yeah, Kinesis. So, if
you get Kinesis,
you have the issue of
of key codes.
For example, if you want to press Alt
Tab, you know, Alt Tab is very common on
Windows. So, you have to press this key
with your left thumb.
Okay, let me show you then. And the tab
on the left corner. So,
which is actually a problem.
Uh let's see if I can show that.
So, you see how do you press Alt Tab?
So, for me, this is my natural position,
okay?
So, I have as I have stretch here and
stretch the my pinky, you know.
And but if you have bigger hand, that's
I guess that's okay.
Uh
Yeah, but so Alt Tab is one of them.
Then, sometimes you have Alt Shift Tab.
Then, sometimes Control Tab. Sometimes
you have to press Alt Control something.
So, that's a problem. That's um
But, you know, as I one of my
uh one of my recommendation about
keyboarding is that you should avoid any
key code. So, you should remap any
you know, Alt Tab Alt Tab something,
Control Tab something.
Try avoid them as much as possible.
Use single key press. For example, if I
want to Alt Tab.
Yeah, let me show you.
So, if I want to Alt Tab, you know,
switch to the last uh
application. I don't I don't I don't do
code, okay? I just do press this key,
okay?
You see?
And but you I know you might be asking,
"Yeah, but alt-tab can switch to other
windows."
I don't do that because when you do
alt-tab, okay, let me show you
uh
Okay, so alt-tab, let me show you.
Alt-tab.
Wait.
Uh
Is it con- Wait.
Oh, I'm a Mac. Um uh
I'm a Mac on a Mac, so my key is
actually
uh command.
Okay. Actually, I set my tab to be here,
so this is will be weird
for you to look at. I never press this
command-tab, okay? So, you can see this
is typical, you know, when people talk
about alt-tab or uh
command-tab. So, actually, let's switch
to Google Chrome.
I don't do this. I think this is the
worst thing because it requires a brain
cycle. Because when you press alt-tab,
you are your brain start to engage
because you need to see which program
you are currently, you know, you want to
switch to.
Okay, this is getting more detailed.
Basically,
when it comes to user interface, you
want to avoid any user interface that
requires brain cycle. So, you want to
avoid any any thinking at all.
You know, you want you want your user
interface to be as much as
uh based on muscle memory as possible.
Like without having to look or without
even, you know, having to think.
The need, the requirement to look and
think is the worst, such as the uh such
as the old tab.
Uh let's see where we are. So, for
example, right now I want to switch to
uh OBS. Okay, so this one. You see, it
takes some thinking to do.
So, requires thinking and requires
seeing is a worst. You don't want that.
So, if you can remove the thinking part,
just seeing part, okay?
The best is remove them all. You know,
for example, I
when I want to switch to my last app, I
don't need to look. I can close my eyes.
I I know I know my finger positions. I
can press a key. You know, I can you
know, I know I don't have to look.
So, when you are working, you know, you
just press a key even your eyes is on
the screen, but you you are not actually
having to pay attention to anything. You
just press a key. It's a muscle memory.
You can that's that's that's the thing.
It's it's a it's a muscle memory.
So, but what if you want to switch to
the app before that, okay?
In that case, I use the mouse, okay? I
have auto click, like I mentioned. I'm I
Hold on a second. Let me stop this
talking.
So, I move my mouse to whichever window
I want. I don't have to click. I'm not
clicking.
I've showed that before in my videos,
okay? So,
So, you can see my mouse.
I'm not holding any buttons, you know, I
just I just nudge it and uh
when the mouse cursor stops moving, it
does a click.
Okay.
So, that's that's my way and I that's uh
uh
that's better, okay? That's I think
that's superior
user interface.
Human-computer interaction,
human-computer interface.
And uh yeah, and also I recommend to
avoid any key codes. So that's what I
do, you know, I don't I don't
I avoid any possible keyboard re- rebind
them if possible, you know, you buy a
programmable keyboard. The Kinesis and
the
Ultimate Hacking are both programmable.
So you can program it. That's what I
did. So avoid any of the
code keys. So on a Kinesis, the code
keys may be a problem because why?
Again, history. You know, because we
have a momentum of bad design. So why do
you have these, you know, old shift
tab things like that? That's because for
mass vast majority of history, keyboards
are based on this shape.
You know, for
because history, because typewriters,
okay? Keyboard are this shape in
general. So so old tab, you know, that's
kind of close, you know, they don't you
know, it's it's just there. Then you
have old shift tab. So all the keyboard
shortcuts came from when they are
designed,
they came from this shape of keyboard.
So that's why you have them.
But now Kinesis, since it's more
ergonomic, but then you have then, you
know, the shortcuts is no longer uh
you know, all together in one place,
things like that.
So this is a natural
way, you know, evolution of things. Uh
you cannot blame on anyone. You cannot
say, "Oh, because oh, these people are
stupid, you know." This is actually
natural because you invented mechanical
keyboards, then people invented computer
keyboards, which is based on mechanical
keyboard. Why? Because habit. If you
create Kinesis, you know,
nobody will use it even today because
habit.
And that's also important, you know. So,
what I'm saying is that don't you know,
I'm what I'm trying to say is that try
not to follow
some sort of
um
uh controversy, not controversy, uh
conspiracy theory. You know, so you
know, you might you know, I know some
people some people
might will say, "Oh, this is all
garbage, you know. Why Why are not
everyone using using Vorark? Why
everyone should be forced to use
Kinesis?" Things like that, okay.
Yeah, that's good idea, but
but however, remember vast majority of
people
they don't need to type that much. So,
when they see this keyboard, they are
happy with it. When they see Kinesis,
they think it's weird. Weird, expensive,
unnecessary, and impractical.
That's most people, vast majority
actually, people's opinion on Kinesis.
Why? Because actually to them that's
true. You know, they don't really you
know, they type 10 minutes a day. They
don't need this
uh big, you know, thing and they have to
learn. You know, they have to spend 1
hour, you know, 1 month to learn to use
it. All the keys are new positions, you
know, they
that's not good for them. Your mom, your
dad, you know, for example, your you
know, whoever doesn't use a computer
often.
So, for vast majority of people
uh you know, they they are happy with,
you know, this normal shaped
uh keyboards.
However, it is still true this are no
good, you know, if you really
concerned about, you know,
uh human computer interaction
ergonomics, things like that, this are
you know, it should be phased out. It is
true that
So, uh okay.
So, Leo Cardo says, "What are some basic
changes you would like to see for the
standard keyboard?" I think making the
modifiers uh 1.25
unit to 1.2
uh space are some Yeah, I think that's
true. So, yeah, make the space bar
smaller
is one of the great improvement. You
know, when you look at the standard PC
keyboard,
uh there's quite a lot things you need
to fix, you know.
You uh lot quite a lot, okay. The caps
lock key is a relic. You should remove
it. The space bar is too long. You don't
need that big, okay. Split it. Split it
into two or three or four even.
Uh and uh you know, there's lots of
problem and uh the slanted Okay, so I
have an article here. You go to keyboard
design. You go to here.
I document many
stupid things of the traditional
keyboard.
And I discuss how those designs came
from.
Uh so, you can you know, you can read
about it. So, the keys, you know,
arrangement are like in this
They say staggered staggered layout, you
know, they are not in a strange way.
They Why Why is it staggered? Because
you see the bars underneath the key,
they need to keep these bars
evenly distributed. That is why the key
becomes this
this kind of sloped
uh arrangement, you know, because in
because originally when you have
mechanical typewriters, you need
it's necessary
that way because you need the bars
underneath to be evenly
distributed.
So that
the mechanism is simpler so that you can
actually have a typewriter. Otherwise,
you wouldn't have typewriter, you know,
you you know, design engineering so back
in the days. But today we don't have you
we
our keyboard is not mechanical but still
we have these all these bad designs
inherited from tradition.
The major force of that is habit because
people don't want to change habit. It's
good enough, it's good enough. People
want don't want to and for example
So you know, let me give you a simple
example. You
people can understand. You are a
programmer, right? What's the language
you program in daily, you know, maybe
it's a Python, maybe it's a
uh
Java, maybe it's C, okay.
And
I'm sure you've heard
there are some other
programming language phonetics. They're
going to tell you, oh, you should learn
Haskell, you really should, you know,
there's no reason to not learn Haskell,
okay.
And then then you also hear people about
other languages. You get that you get
idea. Lisp, you know, this Haskell and
others.
Or Rust.
Yeah, but the thing is, you know,
yeah, Haskell but it's going to take you
a month or more to learn, you know.
You don't need to Do you need to? Like
if you are already working a job, you
know,
it's it's actually wasted of time
because there's no need for you to
unless you work in a new project, you
know, they require Haskell, right? You
already have a job. You do you you code
Haskell you you code Java.
You know, you make good money, you're
happy. In fact, you do not want Haskell
to be popular because once Haskell is
popular, it threatens your, you know,
your favorite language. You know, that's
the case.
You know, so it's this all these are
natural reasons, you know.
So, in the same way, keyboard, most
people are happy uh with the just
traditional bad designed, in many ways
bad
uh keyboard design. They don't change.
Uh the change is coming slowly, but you
know, it's usually it So, today, for
example, we know a lot people love, you
know, like us, you know, we love
we appreciate ergonomic keyboards. We
and many of the, you know,
do-it-yourself among keyboard
uh fan communities, you know, they they
create keyboards like that.
So, so PC keyboard,
there are lots of things that needs to
be to change.
But, if the question is what do I if I
can just pick one simple thing,
I would say that is I would say
split the space bar into two.
Okay.
Split the space bar into two.
In fact, Microsoft tried to do that
actually. Microsoft did that, okay. Let
me tell you. For example, we have some
we are beginning to have, you know,
keyboards with split space bars, but
but for average people, they don't like
it actually. So, it's kind of sad.
Again, why? Because habit, you know,
people don't want to change habit.
You know, because people are used to,
you know, then you For example, you
bought your
mom a new keyboard, you bought your dad
a new keyboard. It's got a space split
space bar.
Now, your dad is not a keyboard nerd,
okay? So, to him, oh, this is new
because you tell him you told him this
is truly good because it's got new
design because it fixed all the
problems. But to your dad,
you know, he's thinking, oh, this is
great. This is, you know, my son told me
this is new design. But
when he actually type it, you know, he
only types 10 minutes a day.
He got annoyed, you know, because
the because he
he has to adapt to this new thing. You
know, maybe by default the left space
bar do backspace or something else.
He got annoyed because he used to press
space bar with both left or right hand
or whatever, you know, just hit it with
the palm. But now he cannot do that
anymore and
he won't tell you but he always
think, you know,
this is annoying. God, this is annoying.
Who invented this?
Who invented this straight space bar,
you know?
But he doesn't know because he only type
10 minutes a day, you know, if he types,
you know,
2 hours a day, he start to have hand
pains. He will start to like, you know,
he will start to look for solutions. How
how did I get the hand pain, you know,
how how did it happen? He will need to
see doctors, you know, it's going to be
a problem.
So, he will he begin to read about
keyboards. He then he begin to try
actually try this, you know, space bar
and he begin to actually believe and he,
you know, find it actually better.
That's the thing.
So, people, actually Microsoft, for
example, they have designed Let me tell
you the story about the split
split space bar.
So, we go to keyboard. Okay, so actually
go to the ergonomic keyboard.
And and go down.
And Microsoft
Okay, actually
Let me Let me tell you this one. Okay,
history of
ergonomic keyboard history.
Okay, it's not here.
Um
Okay, I have it somewhere here. But
anyway,
my what I want what what I was trying to
say
is that Microsoft had a
uh semi-ergo ergonomic keyboard.
Not this one, because this is kind of
full ergonomic. But Microsoft made a
semi-ergonomic keyboard.
So, it looks like um I I have a page
somewhere, but where is it?
Let's see if I can find it.
Uh this one.
Okay, so this one. So, Microsoft I think
this I'm I think this is maybe it's no
longer made.
Let's uh see Amazon.
There it is. Okay, so it's still
Yeah, it's no longer made. It's, you
know, it's defunct.
So, go back. Close. So, Microsoft
created this keyboard back in 2013.
You know, it's a little bit ergonomic
because you can see it's a bit curved.
So, it So, you So, you don't have to
you know, you don't have to do that.
It's more more natural a little bit. And
they created split space bar.
And by default, I think by default or
maybe optional, the left space is
backspace.
Now, this is a great innovation because,
you know,
backspace is one of the key you press
the most often most often. You don't
have to move your hand, you know, you
have you have this wrist moving problem.
It becomes painful. So, now you just
press your left thumb to for the
backspace.
It's a great
innovation.
But, you know what?
I go I go as usual, you know, in my
research. I go read all the Amazon
reviews.
I go read all the Amazon reviews, you
know, and look at what people say. A lot
of people they get annoyed. They say
this is the most stupid you know, s-
uh split space bar with a backspace.
They don't want that. You see?
So,
so here is a
the problem. You see, we are seeing a
problem how
people, you know, they do not want to
change. Even it's something better. They
they, you know, habit is the thing.
Habit.
This applies to programming languages,
you know, it applies a lot to
programming languages, too. You you are
used to see syntax or whatever Java, you
know, the way. You don't you don't
change until until you die. Your
generation died out.
You know, so programming languages
change
basically every 10 years kind of every
10 years is slowly changes every 10
years because
you have to wait for the whole
generation to die. They get They are
retired. They no longer program. The new
generation takes over. Like today's
JavaScript people.
Maybe.
So, I have I'm outdated.
These JavaScript millennial [ __ ] heads,
they are doing these things and maybe
it's better, okay?
They're waiting for me to die.
So, anyway,
yeah, people people, you know, like to
stick to with their habit. And you see,
the most the the interesting thing is
that they don't realize that.
I mean, so for example, when people
criticize, you know, this split space
bar,
they truly believe, you know, this is
idiotic. They truly believe that one
giant space bar is just good, okay? They
truly That's
you know, because habit, you know? And
also because they don't have a need, you
know, they don't have to need to They
don't have hand pain. They don't have a
need to change. So, they don't see a
what's the problem. Why you you need to
split the space bar. They don't see it.
In the same way, you know,
this working in the same way in
programming languages and also Emacs.
For example, a lot of Emacs users, a lot
of my followers, you know, you follow
you use the Emacs default key for maybe
5 or 10 years. You don't want to change,
you know?
As long as you don't have hand problems,
you don't want to change. It It just
works, you know, because changing
means
you have to spend 1 month to or 2 months
very painful because every time you type
something it's wrong, you know?
Something happened. You don't know what
went You have to Oh, what did I press?
Oh, because it's a new key binding. Oh,
you know, it's it's painful for 1 month
to adopt uh new things. People don't
want to change.
Um
okay, so how long have I been talking?
1 hour 14 minutes. So, maybe 2 minutes
and we shut down. Uh and let's see if I
missed any questions.
So, Leonardo's question. Yeah, I think
there are so many things we can change
with a traditional PC keyboard. And I
think the if I can just pick one,
I would probably
you know, split space space bar is one
of the easy thing to do, you know, just
just split it.
And make the left one backspace. That's
a good choice by default. There are so
many choices but you know,
make it backspace is is a good choice.
And there are many also you can you you
could, you know, you probably want to
split the whole keyboard as well, you
know, that's one thing you can do. Uh
you know, but
you know, then it becomes more and more
changes. Then you have tenting, you
know, that's all that.
Okay, so that's about that. So, let's
see next question addressed to me. Okay,
no more questions I guess.
Uh
Asian plus girl.
Yeah, so Kinesis keyboard is kind of
large if you are Asian female.
Uh so, in that case I would recommend
um
Kinesis Freestyle is
pretty good. Actually, you know, I
recommend almost all of these all of
these. Okay, so I recommend
Kinesis Freestyle.
I recommend this very much because it's
got programmable keys, it's split, you
can tent it, Yeah, and it's got extra
keys, fantastic. And And those are the
the programmability of this keyboard is
fantastic. It's the the programmability
of this keyboard is the same as the
Kinesis Advantage 2.
Uh so, you can and also they got on the
fly programming. That means you don't
have to launch some kind of software to
program the keys. You can if you want
to.
Because that way you can have a visual.
You know, you can have a visual overview
of what keys are where.
But you don't have to. You can just
press keys to remap keys, you know,
that's called on the fly programmability
or driverless programmability. So, this
is fantastic.
And Ultimate Hacking is also fantastic.
And also, you know, depends on how much
you want to spend. For example, Kinesis
Freestyle is 150, 150 or 100
or maybe 200, something like that.
Don't quote me on the price, okay,
because okay, $200, 100
uh 200 $200 with the
uh
backlighting.
And but if you want go with Ultimate
Hacking, it's 240 or something.
Uh but you have much less keys.
My personal preference, I would prefer
the Kinesis Freestyle.
Uh even if they are the same price.
Because this is, you know, more keys and
stuff.
Ultimate Hacking, they have, you know,
it has its own advantages.
Uh first of all, because the
programmability beats them all.
As far as I know, yes, it it has more
programmable features. For example,
I can program a key to be dual function.
That is, for example, you can make the
Caps Lock, for example, if you want to
I didn't do that, but if you want to
uh you can make a key, for example, this
key
to be
con- to be to be Caps Lock, for example.
But, if you held it down and press
another key, then it functions a
control.
It's up to you. So, you you can have
actually
hardware-based
dual-function keys. So, that's
fantastic.
Uh and I don't think you can do this on
the Kinesis, you know, Kinesis.
So you know, so each one has different
uh and also Happy the ultimate hacking
is
very compact, so it's portable. You can
bring it to work if you are uh uh you
know, contractor, if you need to travel
a lot
this is better.
Because the Kinesis kinds is is kind of
bulky. You know, you
these the the palm rest you can remove,
but you know, but not the top and you
know, on the side and the side keys.
So, you have several choices and ErgoDox
is pretty good, except it's not tented.
You cannot you know, you cannot uh do it
like that.
But, you know, if you don't have hand
pain or you know, this is great. It's
also programmable.
Uh and it's cheaper than neither one of
those, I think.
So, anyway, you have lots of these
choices. Um
so, for small hand, actually, I have a
article for that.
Best ergonomic keyboards for small
hands. So, all these are great, okay?
Um
But, however, this one
this one is from Japan
and this one cost $500.
So.
You know, $500, that's a bit too much.
You You For example, you rather you can
just buy this ultimate hacking
and buy another keypad,
you know,
instead of this
uh $500
from Japan.
But this one is interesting because they
actually
because it's designed by Japanese, they
actually have like two
or three sizes.
Like uh two or three size, let's see.
Two sizes, okay, standard and small.
Wait. Yeah, standard and medium. So,
standard is like typical standard.
And medium
they call it medium, but it's it's more
for Japanese hands, so it's
you know, it's actually if you truly
want, you know, your hand to fit, then
this one, 500 something.
And yeah, so you can you have several
choices about that.
So, we are about we are we are ending.
So,
let's see what I drink and uh
and that's it for today. I get a drink
and that's it for today.
So, today's drink, first of all,
the power juice.
Power juice, which is condensed coffee.
And raspberry and uh cranberry and
apple.
Most of it is apple juice, you know,
although they don't print it there,
but juice is like that, most of it is
apple. Because apple juice is cheaper.
And raspberry and cranberry, those are
very expensive things. Those are very
expensive fruits.
Yes, I mix them with fruit juice. I've
done that in so many videos. You haven't
seen it before.
Yeah, so I
And And by the way, they are all
sugar-free. I never drink sugar sugar
water. I never put sugar to anything.
Uh and that's good for you. Don't
Okay, don't ever drink sugared
thing. Because I used to, you know, I
used to drink this another brand called
uh this, you know, this energy drink.
I used to drink This is sugar-free, by
the way. All my drink are sugar-free. I
never drink sugared water like Coke,
Pepsi, never in my life. Now, maybe once
once a year, okay, something like that.
But basically, I never drink sugared
things. I don't don't put sugar in your
teas. I've seen American, you know, they
Actually, my girlfriend, okay, that I
had
a girlfriend back then, she put sugar in
the tea. What the [ __ ] You know, in in
China, you never ever put sugar in the
tea.
You know, sugar or milk, you never ever
put milk in the tea. Tea is just tea.
You drink tea for tea, not sugar and
milk.
That's Western. I suppose that's England
tradition. You put milk and sugar. Who
Who does that?
Uh you know, so
don't drink sugared Okay, so for for
like for 3 years, I've been drinking
those energy drink, sugared ones. They
do things to your body, you know,
because I I you know, after 3 years I
noticed
you know, like you have what's called
cellulite on your skin. I noticed I have
that. I never had that, okay? But
uh sugared water sugar does that to you.
So, I don't you know, I stopped doing
that.
Okay, did you just mix Spam with fruit
juice? Yes.
Uh
cranberry. Okay, that's it for today.
Thank you guys for coming.
Bye. My keyboards, okay. Ortholinear.
Yes, I love I like ortholinear
keyboards, okay?
So, why don't I
Why don't I show you some guys some more
video footage of my things, okay? This
is my drink. That's milk, okay? That's
why you see the
residue on the side.
Milk in the morning, milk and coffee
powder.
So, you see this Ultimate Hacking I was
using it
for a few days for a change.
But yesterday yesterday I switched back
because this is you know, it's got more
keys.
But on this one then you have to hold
down this and press that.
I mean even it's great, but I don't want
to hold down this because it's got not
enough keys. You have to like
uh did you know, do that.
So, but this
one of the flaw you see it's it's not
ortholinear.
So, this
on the other hand this is all straight.
It's a
uh square grid, okay? You can call it
square grid or
you call it a matrix.
A matrix layout.
Or you call it a rec- rectangular
layout. or you call it a also
orthogonal.
Also linear layout, you know, these are
jargons.
Um
you know, for example, this one is also
a
not that one, but but this one, you see
this it's a
also linear.
A grid layout. I just I I like I prefer
the term grid because it's simple.
People understand what it means. Grid.
Okay. When you say grid
the full name will be square grid, you
know, like a grid paper to uh
to plot math.
Grid. But people, you know, you don't
need to say square grid. You know, grid,
people understand it's a grid. Grid
chessboard. Grid, okay. You don't need
to say the jargon ortholinear also also
ortholinear. By the way, why
ortholinear? Because because also is
short for orthogonal.
And if you ask people, you know,
orthogonal, where it came from? It's
orthogonal, that word is used in math
most most often, okay.
Now, I don't know what's the etymology.
It would be interesting to look into.
Uh Kasa's Talk Show
go to Kasa's Talk Show
uh and uh
Okay, magnify.
Okay.
o r t h o g o n a l orthogonal, okay.
Now, let's call the command etymology.
Okay.
And show in browser. Let's see the
etymology of orthogonal.
So, it says pertaining to or depending
upon the use of right angles, okay.
1570.
From French orthogonal from orthagon
from Latin late Latin orthagonius
from Greek Orthogonios
right angles right angled. Okay. From
Ortho straight.
Okay, so so Greek right angles angled
and from Ortho straight.
And gonia angle corner.
Okay, so
then it's from PIE root
knee angle.
Okay, so orthogonal basically came from
originally from
Greek meaning straight angled straight
angle, you know, straight angle 90°
angle right angle.
So that's that term is used in math
most of the time orthogonal.
And then you have a math jargon also
normal. Okay, also normal is actually
you know, orthogonal is a basic
geometry, you know, you you say
orthogonal lines, but also normal also
normal is more advanced in in in
differential geometry. For example, you
have also normal vectors.
Anyway, orthogonal.
So when it comes to keyboard, okay,
let's go back to keyboard, you know, I
so I
when it comes to jargons, you know, I
I look at things
I study from all perspectives, you know,
that catches my fancy. So you have to
pay attention to the
term used to describe the
the key layout. So this one typically
people say it's staggered.
Staggered layout the traditional way.
And often you just you hear people say
also staggered or
um
I I I would I would just call it
slanted. That's the term I usually say
slanted.
Because it it's slanted.
Uh
but but normally you know the keyboard
nerds say staggered the English people.
So I suppose that's
I I prefer slanted.
Uh but anyway
So notice some of these are still using
the you know slanted layout staggered
layout.
Even though they are supposedly um
ergonomic keyboards you know split. You
know why? Because I know why. Because
if you create a keyboard like you know
suppose you are a creator of this
keyboard and you want to sell it.
Now you need to sell because if nobody
buys your company dies.
Your product doesn't exist. None. Gone.
Okay. So gone. So you want to be able to
make people buy it.
Now when it comes to design you see
everything every design is of choice
almost of a choice. You have you know so
when you are if you think of yourself as
a creator of a keyboard
then you have to think about you know
whether you want you know the grid
layout or slanted layout. You have to
make a decision.
Uh
you know for example this ultimate
ultimate hacking is supposed to be
ultimate but however they choose the you
know slanted layout. Why? I know why
because
if you create a keyboard with you know
the uh also normal you know orthogonal
grid layout
the chances of people buying it will be
reduced by tenfold. Yeah that much.
Because vast majority of people they are
not used to this. They don't it's
foreign like we mentioned before habit.
They don't they see it they find it
strange they are not going to eat buy
it. Okay. They on the other hand, if you
have a keyboard like that,
they see, "Oh, this is great, split now,
you know, I'm going to try to uh I have
hand pain, and I'm going to try to adopt
ergonomic." And this they see this one,
they will buy it.
But if you have the grid layout, then
then they try to type it, it's a mistake
all the time. They don't They don't buy
it. So, basically, when you have a
staggered layout, the chances of the
keyboard sale is 10 times more, okay?
So, that is why, like I said, it's slow
for this, you know, even these all these
ergonomic ones to change is to change.
If it's slow, slow process.
Because I've I've asked I've talked to
the
uh ultimate hacking uh guys, you know,
like one day I made a Twitter comment,
you know, I don't You know, I tell them
this is not good, you know, you should
have grid.
This is also the reason
This is also the reason, you know, I
rather not use this. I rather prefer
this much, you know, because
the curves in the keys, but also because
it's grid, also because it's got more
keys, more keys than these, about five
or 10. If you don't count these small
keys,
this one has got five or
like five or 10 more keys than these.
You know, and one of the reason is
because because of the slanted layout,
you know, the left hand, you make
mistakes when I switch between them.
Yeah, but but, you know, but they need
to survive, that's the thing. They They
as a keyboard maker, they need to sell
it. If you make it grid,
your your sale will be reduced like 10
times, that that much, truly, you know?
So, this really So, I mean, so what Why
am I saying this? I'm talking to of
those of you keyboard nerds, you know,
like maybe you you believe oh, it's a
conspiracy, you know, why they or
something like that, you know, everyone
should follow the grid. That's true, but
the fact, you know, you have to consider
the
reality, you know, the reality is that
you if you make it grid
then
then you will have 10 less people buy
it, then your company close down, then
you are done for. That's even worse if
your company shut down, nobody buys it.
So, that is why they pick that, you
know, and uh and same way with another
uh keyboard, new new one.
Okay, that's it for today, I think. Um
1 hour and 34 minutes.
Bye, guys.
Go to my Patreon, go to go to my PayPal
if you like my stuff.
Thumb up
thumb up keys, share my videos.
Bye, guys.