everyone to another episode of sound
talk show we are going to code emag list
today we are going to write a command to
uh look up YouTube a command to search
YouTube and another YouTube command
another emac L command to embed YouTube
video in a HTML Page Plus the thumbnail
you know grab the thumbnail so we're
going to do that and uh the thumb now
you are seeing is generated by gr it's
I'm trying to generate a image of a girl
with a wild beast horns the goo you know
the G
horns so and uh about a month or two ago
we talked about artificial intelligence
image generation that's very interesting
so let's just begin coding uh and if you
are watching this offline play at 1.5
speed and Skip around uh if you are
watching live say hi okay let's code it
so look up YouTube so I'm going to just
start to code it uh emac
L uh wait start emac lisp okay paste so
that's what we're going to write so
Define Define function by the way for
those of you who bought my Kar packages
SAR emac this packages I just saw an
email I'll reply today okay uh my email
is
all uh you know like full of emails I
haven't read so usually I read after a
few days so here's a Define function
look up uh look up
YouTube of the
word under cursor okay that search
YouTube basically so
we are writing this I have written so if
you look at
um uh let's go to S emac blog so search
for emx tutorial you'll see my emx
tutorial ons.info
and there is a section on SAR emac
packages so here is a list of my
packages and here is my list of commands
so lots of commands those are you know
you have the source code you can so you
can copy so there are like tens of them
30 40 of them so we go to Kar emx
packages and you'll see a package Kar
looks up so you can look up Google the
web or Google or using Google search
engine specifically or using Yandex
which is from Russia or using BYU which
is a if you want to search Chinese you
want to know what's going on what's the
mainstream View
the mainstream opinion of in China uh
especially you know when you have
Chinese
characters uh so bu is similar to Google
it's kind of the
mainstream uh often corrupt point of
view so Google is for USA so that's why
you sometimes you don't want Google like
anytime you search something that's
slightly related to politics or even if
you search girls you know actresses or
whatever you want to for example if you
go to Yandex you'll get much better
results you know like like like uh yeah
usually so Yandex just remember Yandex
is for uh is uh in Russia so uh yeah and
you can also search
Wikipedia or you can search internet
archive internet archive
recently uh just last week or you know
in the past month they have a
controversy it appears supposedly they
got hacked uh the the and the reason all
this mainstream media says the reason
internet archive got hacked is because
there's some propellent activist
hackers uh I mean the reason so they say
the reason is that because the Israel
Gaza War so they want to destroy destroy
internet archive which you know the
reason G given is very silly internet
archive is almost have nothing to do
with you know this war you know those
ATT trous you know very bad but I'm not
going to talk about
that um but you know if the prop
Palestinians hackers if they want to do
something they got like 10,000 more
important websites to hack not the inter
internet archive so the internet archive
the
incident happened you know this month
actually went back to few months ago uh
you can find the more detail I showed
the video by the L deck guy about last
week you can find on my Twitter x.com
ens X but anyway so internet archive
they got sealed in USA by Publishers
because internet archive was trying to
during the it they have some excuse to
make these copyrighted books online
supposedly because people cannot visit
libraries so they temporarily trying to
make them online lots of bad fishy
corruption going on you know and of
course usually these kind of in
incidents in the past 30 years you the
earliest one I remember is with the
math uh
Eric Smith Trove happened in
1990s okay that's like a like a this is
before Wikipedia you have this math
Trove you know that like Encyclopedia of
mathematics written by this era guy but
the area guy and published by CC press
so it's online free but it also come
with a CD so remember this is
1990s okay published by AR guy but then
the area guy joined wolam
research so the website becomes wolam
research uh
and and um what's the exact detail I
forgot but then C C press is not happy
because we agreed oh yeah I think when
when they when he published by via CC
press the website
becomes partially available not fully
available you know commercial because
you have to you know when you sell
that's agreement you
know if you do it free nobody pays you
like the open source you know you you
you you die nobody give a [ __ ] they just
jump to other open source open open
source is a extreme harm so anyway the
the the the math
um I forgot what's the name so in fact I
have a Blog about it but um yeah anyway
we are dig in but anyway there is this
math encycl CC Encyclopedia of math okay
let's show
it this incident I'm personally involved
okay so there it
is see there it is exactly this one
okay so
this Eric W
wiin he is a I believe he's a
astronomist
okay he he got a degree in astronomy so
in 1990s he created he he he has a habit
our personality are similar we are nerds
we write a lot we document what we
learned so he he you know he accumulated
you know lots of his notes about
mathematics and eventually it got
published in 1999 by CC press as the CC
consise in encyclopedia mathematics
and I believe I don't remember the
detail but I believe since it got
published by CC the website became only
partially Avail available like today
this article is available but not
tomorrow tomorrow some other article is
available you know partially available
then Eric wiin joined joined wolam
research and wolfan research in 2000 uh
you know it became it got rebranded as
wolfan research is math word
okay uh math word
okay
uh and so okay so there um and uh then
then it became a available online fully
so of course then CRC press is not happy
so they sued a
Weinstein and uh then then it became
this this event during about year 2000
okay year 2001 okay it became a big
internet thing you know internet drama
this is early days of Internet year 2000
okay then it you know the popular
opinion of course the popular this is
when open source is like on the scene
with Apache and Linux so popular opinion
is like CRC what the evil [ __ ] is the
CRC press you know we're going to B PO
is SC CC press why why people do that
you know lots of the masses okay why did
they do that because they want things
for free you know you got this n you
know nice in you know encyclopedia math
it's free but
now the CC press going to sue you
because of copyright and so
they um so you know they they they they
push you know they defended by by going
to the population the masses so the
masses or the you know a lot of like me
students not me exactly I'll tell you
why uh but other students you know or
professors they they they demand you
know they they they they'll say you know
let boys got CRC press because they are
evil law they just want money they want
copyright copyright should be banned
everything should be free you know like
the open source
[ __ ] why you know so I mean that's
all they want they want things to be
free don't they don't have to pay and
they you know their ethical EXC excuse
behind it is that this is good for
Humanity you know information should be
free like like the p they they stealing
copyright movies of Hollywood you
know and many of the hackers many of you
guys like saying you know we should you
know we we uh we should have everything
should be free uh you know the best
thing in life is
free you know one bunch of Lies what
they really want is just get things for
they don't have to pay the benefits
these people the the the the average
people they don't care they care only
when this is their own thing when it
happen to them for example if you are
running a company then then suddenly you
don't like this you know this this
masses making making you know making
making a scene of things you know they
they will call you you know they will
they will say you are evil you are the
evil Lord and and all you know you know
the
mob
so the so we are uh back to the internet
archive you know so this this you know
incident hacking incident so uh we don't
know what's going on because the
internet archive is doing things they
they are you know they are promoting oh
books should be free uh and
stuff you know that's an interesting
idea why why shouldn't it be free
information all the source code wouldn't
be great you know the like the wonderful
we live in a world where all the
information is free whatever I do is
free for you and whatever you do is free
for me like the free software Foundation
Richard soulman yeah that's uh ideal
ideally yeah but in
reality whenever something you are
making money you I'm talking about you
personal each person
okay when you are making money and
suddenly people demand demand that you
should it should be free so you don't
make money anymore then then you you
won't you you don't buy this ideology
anymore you see you you can project this
ideology to everyone should be free but
when it comes to your personal profits
or whatever
benefits when they demand this you lose
it you don't have you know you don't get
money anymore then suddenly you are not
happy you see when you run a company
when you anything you do the only people
who are always promoting these three is
they are the free writers typically the
students in school they get paid you
know they their parents they live in
their parents house you know they don't
have to worry about food they demand we
should you know things should be free
open source you know they don't say free
you know they don't say actually we
don't demand free beer actually we want
just the freedom you know that's a lie
you know that's a fundamental lie but
actually if if emac just you know just
cost $10 to download emac will die right
away and Linux too
if if Linux cost just $10 to download
steel open source you'll die right away
you
disappear you know so this so
essentially the idea is communism you
know you cannot basically one form of
you know this open source basically uh
communism it's a great fantastic
ideology imagine the world without
religions without War yeah it's a good
imagination but
but when but it will happen only if you
each one of you sing this
song actually you know you give up
everything you own then that will happen
but you will not do that you
see so anyway internet archive is is
very question questionable thing so
anyway let's get back to talking about
Let's uh back to emac this coding
okay communism so you see you see it's
funny when you look at the open source a
lot of people they will say it's not
communism it's not
communism including for China let me
mention China
because you know they like they some
Chinese people in China I know
programmers you know they they don't
like the CCP you know like like but then
they are into open source U but it's not
it's not you know open source is not
communism it's very different because
this this
this actually it's just communism okay
communism means the ideology the
wonderful ideology where everything is
shared you know you don't ow owe nothing
you don't have the right whatever
whatever [ __ ] that is to own a house a
car your car belongs to me your house
belong to me well I mean that's the you
see because you are we are so prosperous
we don't need to have like ownership you
see you know this patent this copyright
we don't need it we we just share share
you know today's technology is so great
we just share you see commun communism
you know so great no no religion you
don't need it you no no rank you know
ranking you know no hierarchy we are all
equal you know it's fantastic
except when it comes to your food you
know you're eating you know you can get
two pizza or three but now you don't
have it then you you get
angry so um yeah yeah
so so you see today the Richard stowman
he's the only one you know like you know
he get all the donations he become the
scent the you know the scent of G he's
got you know he he don't have to worry I
mean he's not a greedy guy but however
you know he seen the song you know he
don't have to pay because all the
donations like like like some of the
Indian gurus selling you
things so he he he's good you know but
me been coding emac this for 15 20 years
all my packages my entire the most
popular emac tutorial was free for 10
years even a zip file for you to
download nobody give a [ __ ] I die of
hunger
almost almost um killed myself that is
in
2011 for 10 years very very bad you
cannot you know if you are American or
if you are in any of the SoCal developed
country you cannot possibly imagine you
know my situation
the you know that's a poty you don't
understand you I mean I cannot even try
to express um but
anyway so let's go back to to the to
yeah to the code okay so let's see uh
emac block close yeah so we were going
to code
um yeah okay let's code this okay so I
want to show you so I already have this
package so you can you know if you like
my stuff you can pay me and get it so
you can look up you know also look up
Google Maps look up word definition or a
specific dictionary several victionary
or dictionary. org that's open source uh
website which is very
lousy uh you can look up synonyms look
up all synonyms look up atmology of word
okay so let's
[Music]
see look up okay press three keys and
you are looking up the synonyms okay so
look up is you know kind of equivalent
to pursue seek search looking look for
Sharp for Chase hunt you know
like so that's synonym Let's uh so let's
go to atmology okay press a few Keys
then you got
atmology magnify let's see
look up looka okay wait so you got
looker you got viewer you got Overlook
uh okay so but you don't have um so
let's try
look so let's well let's just read what
is a looka okay looker this is a looker
oh English Lo one engage in
looking uh one who watches over from
1300 sense of one who has a certain
appearance that's that's what we say
looker today she's a looker is late
1500s slate
1400s slam meaning attractive woman
attested from
18 93 oh
1893 a
looka okay so that's some demo of the
look up my package but let's look at the
source
code okay so here's a documentation CU I
look up atmology jump to the source code
open it and here is the source code you
know just few just five lines but
actually it Calla this function
okay it
Calla this function which take care of a
lot of things uh this is extremely
trivial to write by the way
so I have written a tutorial on how to
write this look up so let me show you
okay but for now let's just
um uh let's just modify this to be um
okay so we just modify it based on the
lookup atmology but let me show you how
to write this okay uh you know full
tutorial so you just search
for emac
tutorial look up so emac Dictionary
lookup emac lookup function
documentation command to lookup
doc lookup web so let's open them
uh oh yeah so here emac this command to
look up documentation write your own
lookup command so here is a code very
simple doesn't require any
Library uh doesn't require any external
packages you just require browse Das URL
which is part of emac okay so you just
um you know very simple you just grab
the current word and just call browse
URL and uh with a URL the URL will
attach you know a pen the word to
it depending on the website they have
different formats so that's how you do
it but for now let's go back here I want
to look up YouTube okay so in order to
know to write this you need to know the
format for YouTube lookup so let's
check YouTube search you need to know
what exactly the format uh okay so let's
search
for uh let's say search for
format let's search for formation let's
see what that
is okay uh s s Beyonce SS okay now copy
the
URL copy back here
and and paste it here okay so here is
the format that YouTube use so you just
so this is a keyword CQ I mean that's
the placeholder so cut it and put it in
here okay so
that's it so let's check so interactive
that means you can call this command by
pressing meta
X then you call the command look up
internet and the first argument is the
word the word is a argument you pass to
it so if it's NE then this command will
automatic automatically use a current
word okay then the URL would be this one
and this curly keyword is a placeholders
you it'll be reformat I mean it'll be
replaced with by that word so let's go
to
it so you you know for example you are
searching cly Q on YouTube interesting
you know YouTube has billions and
billions of videos You'll see all sort
of things like typically we we became
num you know each one of us have our
lifestyle and so we only
see a window of the whole world you know
we are accustom accustomed to see only
part of the YouTube but what when you
want to see other things you just like
search for a random World almost you can
try it then you'll see all sort of
things you've never seen
before so this one is a starburst CQ
locket interesting cute women like those
things and here's orami instructions
single strip Square curly Cube okay so
this is of interest to me because this
is mathematics and
geometry and this one cly cly girl
method something something hair girls
things okay so and yeah interesting
so anyway so that's it so then so then
you got uh Association list you want
this to be
YouTube so Association list you want to
get this key so this this line is about
which browser you want to use for this
command because the this you know look
up what on internet is designed so that
for each website you can specify a
particular browser for it for example
Firefox uh Brave browser which is the
best and Google Chrome or you can
specify the emac
browser so if you want to do that just
say it here instead of using the Le get
so anyway let's run it okay so actually
let's
yeah okay let's run it okay let's look
up on YouTube so let's try some word um
let's say emac this okay select that
meta
X look up YouTube okay do
it fantastic it works learning emac this
fundamentals system Crafters okay he's a
good
resource uh oh oh There Is Mine
live then this one emac this by CK okay
I don't
know I don't know who is this guy CK
then iMac this by Tony
Alden uh I don't remember who that is
this is me uh learning EAC this in 30
minutes Gavin
freeor he's also a good guy good
resource uh you know it's too bad
usually they don't show my videos
because my videos mostly is is live
stream and I don't you know so there it
is okay I actually found it emac this
for beginner two years ago it's
live uh and here's one system Crafters
yeah he's a good resource you can you
guys can watch
it uh and this one is Zuma fu zumas SC
you see lisp in 100 seconds you see very
popular half a million views these kind
of scums zumas you know the reason they
post to YouTube is so is is so that they
can amass the most stum up so they can
make money they can become
influencer but what the [ __ ] is this
being 100 seconds who actually can learn
a programming language for in 100
seconds nobody you see and you
cannot so what is this this is a meme
this Zuma [ __ ] they you know they
do this this is a memes this is
entertainment this me 100 seconds and
this guy I I I found this video before
by the way he also have like python in
100 seconds something you know like
scumbags this these these people are
scums and look at his name fire ship you
know typically they are aown they don't
use their real name this stop that [ __ ]
this [ __ ] you see you
know you know this this mean [ __ ] you
know why is he this guy here because
he's there trying to make money these
are grifters these are the Zuma
class Fire Ship high intensity code
tutorials and T F news to help you ship
your app faster [ __ ]
scun you know this year you see all the
social media he's like promoting himself
you know he's like this is Norm this is
normal in you know all the Zuma
generation like almost all the
population young young people they have
no idea what's going on this is like
normal this is this is what they aspire
to do
what [ __ ] scum this a you know so
what is a consequence of this of
this you know why are they doing it of
course money it's because and behind
them they are just pawns actually behind
them is it is Google YouTube they are
making these things you know like uh you
know like Google ads they can pay
you uh 40% I think Google Google takes
like 60% almost half something like
that and then they ban if you talk about
politics that's not what government want
you to say you get banned things like
that and then Google try to create the
shorts to emulate the Tik Tock T Tik Tok
is the combination of
brainlessness you know each video now
instead of you know instead of manually
trying to say you know learn something
in 10 seconds in 100 seconds the Tik Tok
is just everything is just exactly just
20 seconds or something so you don't
even you cannot even make a video that's
like half an hour to learn something but
you just it's like it's just
brainlessness
Purity look at these
[ __ ] look at this big go explain
with a deck of cards these
[ __ ] you know these faces the face
of
scums of the face of grifting scums and
then the women women and
men
okay so we got the command yes is it
correct yes is it final yeah I think
so okay so let's just put it in
into my uh local package so let's um
describe key press press press okay jump
to the source code okay uh it's 400 500
lines of code so you got all these look
up commands then search for def list
matching lines so let's consider where
do I want to put it look up
YouTube so that would be uh uh let's
say map okay now put it behind the
street map okay
[Music]
so so paste it there and put this Auto
load this autoload thing in emac this is
a convention it's very it's nasty okay
because this is a hack I despise this
autoload let me explain so you see first
of all it's a comment you know this is
this is a
comment so comment in a programming
language means that the compiler ignore
it it means you know it the common is
just for human consumption but not so
but actually actually sum of common has
meaning you see this this thing for
example this thing then you have to
follow it by three pound sign then then
you you know the word autoload is like
like the the the hack directive that
tells the compiler that tells emac that
you should set set up this function to
be autol loaded meaning that technically
it means you know grab this function
name put it into memory and also pair it
with the location of the file where this
function is defined which is this file I
look up e you see
so that when when use a meta X you will
have this command even though the file
is not loaded yet okay but we you will
have this command so when you run this
command it will you know associate you
know you'll get the pair the location of
the file then load it okay so that's
what this
autoload hack is doing you can do it
yourself so you know so if you don't
want this hack you have to say
autoload okay so for example
autoload function name that then file
name okay file name would be that the
the whole file path okay so in emac you
can Abri that to be just that okay so
let's Okay so autoload function name
symbol file path then optional doc
string okay doc string is optional you
know it's like this this part is
temporary dark string because emac
haven't loaded the file for this
function yet so it doesn't know it
doesn't have access for the dark string
but however when you do describe
function you know I mean
uh when you do describe
function you know this autoload command
will show this do string you know just
temporarily so anyway so delete that
delete that you don't need it so so this
this autoload comment hack is just that
okay so if I am you know the leader of
emac I would ban this autoload because
it's a hack it's a what the [ __ ] it's a
commment it's not supposed to you know
you just manually manual yes do it
manually specify this
autoload that that is my opinion so
because when the what is the consequence
when you have these
hacks that's that's when you get you
know the complexities in programming
today you know like when you have 1,000
options 1,000 parameters this option
affect that that and this you know you
don't know what that what it is doing oh
because there's a convention like this
you know like for example this is a
comment yeah but it's it's actually not
a comment you know it actually do
something then how do you find out what
does this do exactly oh but it's not a
function name so you cannot just like
describe function it's actually you know
you got to like try to find you know
maybe common convention or something
hack you see see emac this because I'm
familiar I've been coding it for 20
years so I kind of know but to you you
may not know and worse is when you are
you know coding python JavaScript Ruby c
c C++ Java or web Technologies know Dome
you know whatever CSS complexity
exponential like you have no idea what
the fu [ __ ] is going on because they a
lot of them is just hack this is
convenient why don't we do this saves
typing the C
C++ industrial programmers fuckets
okay you see when you talk to a typical
emac lisper for example you know all
this uh good
people uh let's go back uh wait hold on
a
second let's
uh you see what I'm saying is that when
you talk to this when you watch this um
let me do a screenshot of this scum
bag so we have a record that we talked
about it
so you know a screenshot so I can put
into
my uh you know today's talk
show okay so now go back you see these
people uh let's also do this this ones
what a what a
scun okay so but anyway so but we do
have good people doing emac this
tutorial
you know we talked about system crafters
and some of that um okay so let's do a
screen
screenshot and uh I want to give a shout
out to this guy to Gavin because I think
he's doing good
um and I don't know who are the other
people but anyway so what I want to say
now is that although these people are
great you know I think they are doing
you know good emac tutorials emac this
tutorials but usually they don't talk
they
don't they don't address you know they
don't talk the kind of topics I talk for
example this [ __ ] autoload [ __ ] this
[ __ ] scum hacks okay typically they
they don't see it you know they you know
they they'll just tell you how this
works you know you know it saves you
code that's that's
it okay hey Crystal CH Ching thank you
thank you Crystal ching ching hey
Crystal we miss you in Discord so come
back you know maybe you should um you
know come back we miss you
uh so happens more and uh uh Mo and uh
and Dion
left uh and then we started to have a
fresh
new Direction so s Discord now is more
more to be uh we are trying to be more
professional so we don't you know we we
try you know so people who join all of
you guys are welcome but don't just join
in and start posting [ __ ] [ __ ] talk you
know like like brainless [ __ ] talking
you know like you know so we we try to
get back to more professional like when
you actually have some content it can be
anything it can be politics too it can
be racial issues religion can be
programming issues you know web dev or
Windows
frustrations but don't [ __ ] post like if
you don't have useless you know just
like you know try to post something
useful like you know that would be uh
that's the direction so come back
Crystal so crystal says what do
mainstream emac users think of your uro
key binding hatred of combo
Keys oh typically you know I'm half of
the time I'm known as a troll you know
since like year 2000s because the way I
talk like today I just talk I just you
know said these [ __ ] with their
autoload and C C++ idiots you know
that's usually not acceptable to the
typical liberal educated white
men why do I say white men why don't I
say black men because white men in
America here they they are they they
they run the country you you know uh
typically so this so This liberal
educated white people the way they grew
up you know not necessarily something
wrong but it just they are culture you
know they don't they their culture do
not
accept when you uh criticize or you know
attack things in
society uh
so so anyway so so I'm kind of known as
a troll half of the time but there are
also people who really appreciate my
point point of view now of course I'm
being a dram dramatic you know sometimes
not all like you know C or C+ plus
coders I mean they are not bad people
also you know some of them are great
programmers you know they very technical
C especially when you code
cc++ yeah so what I'm saying so so so
yeah
so so a lot of people they do appreciate
my emac tutorial and my keyboard
tutorial okay so they do appreciate uh
my emac and keyboard stuff but they will
also often say k is crazy so you know
take his opinion gra of thought you know
but anyway they they usually they like
my especially my keyboard opinions a lot
we say k is Crazy K is like don't know
nothing he's just shallow but however
his keyboard stuff is correct you'll see
a lot of
that so what do they think of your ego
key binding and hatred of combo
Keys yeah I mean some yeah I would say
most a lot of it a lot of people like it
you know I would say yeah in general
they they they you
know okay I think that's it for today
elixir of Life today's drink is just
coffee coffee
so let's see the comments Noob Noob are
we done with aent of code no not yet yes
yesterday I spent three
hours uh we started to talk about it you
know watch yesterday it's a wild ride I
started to you know continue to code the
function to find the
py of a nesting
sequence then I started to mention how
in wolam language you can have the
inline inline string documentation like
like the emac this here you see inline
inline string documentation hold on a
second let me copy that
um okay so let's remove that okay now
wait make a backup go to
diet buy it compile it yes successful
why do I buy compil it because when you
do it usually it'll tell you little
errors like you have unused variables so
it's a good idea to buy compile but
usually after I buy compile this is the
result okay buite compiled file usually
usually I delete it
because B compile technically is faster
but however it makes no detectable
difference you know like today it
doesn't make a difference for me unless
it's huge package of 5,000 lines but
even for few 5,000 lines for example my
HTML uh package that's
like you know that's like that's about
6,000 lines you don't you know you
compar doesn't
make like the difference the speed
difference is almost undetectable by
human so anyway we done with this lookup
let me talk about uh what was that I
want to talk about I want to U oh yeah
so yesterday um yeah so I started to
mention about how the wolam
language Syntax
for um
where is today's talk show okay so we we
need to go to today's talk show there so
you go to the talk show index page then
yesterday episode
593 we I started to talk about the wolam
languages unine documentation and I
started to mention
how that feature in programming language
for inline documentation begin in lisp
okay thisp programming language it begin
in thisp then it spread to others like
python uh Pearl two par first then
python then R then Ruby like almost
every programming language you can have
inline documentation now you cannot have
that before remember like 30 40 years
ago it's expensive who the hell you know
add this useless uh wait you know string
into memory you
know but it is so it begin with lisp
programming language then I started to
mention how also the garbage collection
uh garbage collection the automatic
memory management feature also came from
this then then I started to talk about
the jargon garbage collection then it's
a wild ride on all sort of jargons we go
when we over all jargons poly field
Lambda
um you know then Eric s Raymond giant
topic and then we talk about uh
philosophy of mathematics the three
major schools of philosophy of
mathematics okay I think that's it for
today okay bye
guys have uh Halloween's coming I we
bought a Halloween pumpkin so some kid
will come by some you know like uh the
like maybe 10 20 so hope you guys have a
good
Halloween uh and I think that's it for
today so we shutting down in 3
minutes so lookup is done so we got this
new command look up YouTube fantastic go
to the top change the version date let
me show you how I do
it there it is and since we got a new
command so bump up the minor version
okay then delete that save it close it
show in browser back to emx close it
close it close it showing browser
today's talk
show and delete this list of
things okay and oh there's another thing
one more thing actually um let me do
this okay so now it's red oh I forgot to
increase the website font so we did this
look up YouTube there's another thing
we'll do it another
day yep then we went over so yeah we
need to copy the lookup function how to
do
it uh not there yeah command to look up
do that's that's a page you want to read
if you want to learn how to write this
okay close
then then uh emac Dictionary look up
that's not what we want then emac
search okay bye
guys CH please explain grandfather clock
versus
Space didn't I explain that before I
thought I
did yeah we did I mean we kind of went
like long run about that so grandfather
clock is is just um
you know so like okay here's the thing
okay let me let me go on that five
minutes
probably uh for that for this occasion
we need to go toar
Arts so in design in the
design of things in architecture
interior design or whatever you have
usually you have this style of Baro
uh
baress and uh usually I associate it
with grandfather clock
okay uh okay let me let me show you some
interesting on my side it's not search
so uh
well well I mean so anyway in design
usually you have this style as uh for
example you can look up Wikipedia media
uh the Baro style Baro or uh it's fairly
complicated the history uh you know yeah
so actually so
let's Okay search Baro style uh then
there it is so in art in architecture
too so yes and usually they are very
elaborate and guilded like for example
golden color for example Trump you know
you might have seen
Trump's you know inside his home is you
know he kind of like that that Baro
elaborate you know like and little
decoration like but this style is not
is is roughly the opposite of functional
style for example this these pillars you
know does it why should that you know
little pillars you know in that shape is
that necessary so no and uh do you
actually need like a bunch of stone
pillars under this window no you know so
this is not functional it's it's it's
not functional it's a it's a matter of
style uh but especially this style it's
like like so elaborate like almost you
know very little of it is functional so
on the other hand so you can go on the
other hand to the Other
Extreme
of of uh by the way so for example you
can look at all these I mean but you
know so all this this old church
beautiful you
know
uh uh uh you know very beautiful uh
stuff okay
especially the grand churches so and
there are many different styles so you
have to study history of art okay so
this Milan Cathedral in
Italy which is engion of Rome beautiful
yeah I mean you know like usually I
don't associate I don't think this this
is not called Baro so they have
different jargons
okay they have different jargons I like
this though I mean even though this is
not purely functional but anyway so but
barog is kind of the combination of
elaboration just for useless elaboration
just for the sake of it and also I don't
like the Baro style because usually it's
gold golden you know I don't I don't
like I don't like the you know golden
color gilded you
know so and here's another style and
also very beautiful you see
um uh then uh you know then this this is
City thing um you see this is beautiful
I mean it's also historical you know
like you have this but so this these are
called bires they are used they have
this kind of structure so that they can
uphold the weight of this giant huge uh
wall so something like that so you got
these pesses and you know and each of
these thing you know there's terminology
for all these parts so I I think this is
deepo something is it necessary no
but I mean the pillar is necessary but
then but then you you know but it's
beautiful okay so but the opposite of
this barok so we got also uh you know
the art deco which which is I like it
very much very beautiful uh artco is
basically the style of in Batman Okay o
Deco beautiful so this this one is in
India okay so this uh New India
Assurance building arle okay this one is
in USA United States of America
beautiful and uh this one also in United
States of America beautiful extremely
beautiful
see our Deco uh and this one is uh okay
this is also our Deco yeah so but you
know so but here we are starting to get
into more like functional design you
see I mean I mean all these are still
decorative but I mean it's more
functional design clean okay
geometry
um so so this is Baro I I hate this one
you know I hate the Baro style so what
I'm saying is that so you can apply that
to keyboard to your house decoration to
sofa for
example the psychology fudi and sofa
okay that
is let's see if we can find some
pictures you know like usually when we
think of psychology we think of this
this sofa okay
uh you know the the the client just lies
on this sofa so although you know I like
this one
especially you know so I don't like
these nonfunctional I hate them I hate
those Styles so that is what I mean I so
I just call them grandfather especially
grandfather clock like wooden heavy and
elaborate you know I much prefer
functional and space like like the most
concrete practical functional Space Age
and light for example for example
plastic plastic is just amazing
invention
plastic
imagine you know a material that's light
and durable you can drop on the ground
it won't Break Meanwhile this Asian
earthware you drop on a floor it breaks
so functionally the plastic cup is just
superior but today we got the plastic
micro plastic going into your
balls that's a different
story so plastic you know but people
like usually they associate with
cheapness you know for example pen like
today A lot of people are into pens you
know the qu pens or or or uh whatever
you know they like they have you know
you can go to Amazon you can shop for
pens some of them cost few hundred
dollar you know
like who who the [ __ ] use those you know
usually those people like you know they
like Baro like Trump sh suits and ties
and golden
pen you know and caps you have to take
it off and and then right so I don't
like those I like scientific okay uh
which does not necessarily mean the
scientific one should be bad I mean
there's so many aspects okay uh for
example one of the bad thing about Let
Me Explain okay
so let's search for modern geometric
Furniture
okay turn
script okay you don't get much uh
let's use Google
then okay you need to have JavaScript on
otherwise the image won't
show you see modern geometric fun
Furniture typically these are [ __ ] these
are the worst [ __ ] possible they are
uncomfortable you know many of the
modern like in modern museum you go to
San Francisco like modern mum Museum you
know they they building is all glasses
you know in a geometric shape you know a
triangle or B you know uh and typically
these these these are just good for
looks you know like this uncom you know
so so even though it's simple it's
opposite of Baro but this this is
actually [ __ ] but because usually these
kind of things you know you know it's
kind of nice geometry I love I love
geometry but this these things are
usually just actually not functional
they are just
crap okay so so it's you know there's
some details there are many aspects you
have to dive into okay I think that's
it okay bye
guys bye guys so let me make some
screenshot we shut down in one minute
okay so this reverse lines okay so you
need to select or
reverse
region fantastic cut it close
it ODS block block open it back
close it here yes and paste it these
three things we talked about and then
let me show you some of the command to
you see this is my screenshot
directory now I'm just call some command
do
it do it do it do it it automatically
move all these screenshots to my current
buffer okay one more you see it's open
it automatically moved to this directory
showing
browser go down so these are the things
we talked about
today fantastic see you guys