Good morning everyone. Good morning
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
Sound Talk Show. We are going to code
wam language today and doing plane
curves, special plane curves. We are
going to recreate this image. This image
is done like 30 years ago. Uh so we're
going to recreate it. So it's going to
be wam language coding also known as
Mathematica. If you are watching
offline, play at 1.5 speed because I
ramble. If you are watching live, say
hi. Love to see your
comments. Okay, so Wuam language also
known as Mathematica. So play at 1.5
speed. Okay, so let's begin. So my
keyboard, let me show you. Gett
fantastic glove 80 keyboard. Nia track
ball Logitech 405 with uh the best thing
502 G502. The best thing is the spin
wheel infinite spin uh and the ultimate
hacking keyboard and
also also let me show you this delay and
delay. This is farboard the most
fantastic advanced ergonomic keyboard
device. Okay, so I will get to it
eventually. Uh you can watch videos of
all these. I have video reviews on
YouTube. So this is again SV A L B O A R
D S board magnetic switches. So
fantastic. Okay, I'll show I'll be using
it sometimes. So, so let's start to uh
code wam language. Say hi if you are
here. Let's stop that. So, can you see
my screen? Yes. Okay. So, wuam language
talk show today. So, let's go to kasar
talk show today. So, we going to code.
So, wuam language you know uh go to
kasali.info info my website and or
search for sawufam language tutorial you
can see where to download it's free uh
and uh I have the complete tutorial for
this language uh the most advanced
programming language by far better than
Haskell Python Ruby uh
lisp or rust you know by far so but
mostly it's used for by mathematicians
scientists,
engineers, okay, but you use it just
like Python, okay? It can do artificial
intelligence, machine learning, neuronet
networks, like 7,000 functions building.
Okay, so Wuang language tutorial,
download it, go read it. And today we
going to do so, so here is my uh planker
packages. Today we're gonna do um Okay,
let me let me get on to
the Today we going to do the
hypotcoid hypocyclloid and
hypotloy. Okay.
So, okay. So, let's begin. So, um hello
dosey. So, what we going to do? So,
first of all, let me explain what are
these. Okay. Um am I ready? Uh let's
see.
So explain what they are. Okay. So let's
do that. Okay. So hypo truck and it's
easier. It's the best way if you just
watch your animation. Okay. So let me
show you
animation. So you go here. Let's uh
enlarge this window. So
that close that. So go back here,
enlarge the window and uh not not dev.
So this hypotcoid they are also known as
um spyroraph. So you can see there's a
Wikipedia article about
it. Uh I got I have this toy back in
1980s when I was 10 years old. So it's
like great fun. So you generate these
curves and one thing I learned from
Wikipedia is that
they you know why they have these
because one of the reason is that when
they print money you can see US dollar
they have these uh kind of curves. So
why do they put that there? Because
these curves it is given given one of
them because there are millions you know
infinite variations. So given one of the
drawings it is
almost impossible to find exactly what
are the parameters to create these
drawings. So they put it they print it
on the dollar bill so it prevents
counter
counterfeit. Of course today you have
much more technology like hologram or
whatever transparency. So anyway so back
then that's one of the reason they this
um they create created this
curve. So basically that's that's how it
works. So you roll a circle around
another circle
then then you put a point fixed on the
rolling circle then it will trace out a
curve. So it will trace out all these
varieties depending on the distance you
know the size of the two circles or the
or or the distance you know where is the
fixed point on the uh rolling circle. So
the rolling circle can be inside the
larger circle or it can be outside. Do
they have an animation of that? They
don't have.
Okay. So anyway, this is known as
spyroraph because you know some toy
company created marketed as and
trademark
spyroraph. Okay. So but their technical
name is called hypocycllo
hypocyclloid epicyclloid. Okay. So there
it
is.
Hypocyclloid.
Epicyclloid. That's a blue one.
Hypocyclloid. That's a red one. Then you
have
um
epitrocids. Then you have hypotroids. So
all these are spyroraph. That's a
technical name for them. The mathemat
mathematicians you know for
mathematicians. And there are many
special cases. For example, this all
these are called rows curves. Ross is
the most um the most common is are
these. You can see can you see my
screen? Am I doing good? Say hi. Hello
fellow. Hello blue
three. Blue three. Hello fellow Python
scriptors. So you see these are called
rose curves and uh you know these are
well known. You learn them when you do
calculus when you take uh class in
calculus. Um and they are special case
of of um of the rolling circles. So I
have an animation. So let me show you
animation. Okay. So anyway, so all these
are special cases. So here is an
example. This this specific one is
called asteroid. Okay. Lots of
interesting properties and and very
interestingly it has a properties of
such that you can generate the exact
same curve in both ways. So rolling a
circle inside a circle uh that is 1/4 of
the radius. So you generate a asteroid.
But you can also generate exactly the
same curve by rolling a circle that is
um
3/4 the radius of the larger circle.
Exact the same curve. And you can have
linkages and mechanism that connects
these two together. So they they they
trace out the exact the same point. Do I
have that somewhere? Um yeah. So it's a
lots of lots of mathematics. You can
actually see it here. So this is a
gege. Um let's see if I can
magnify. Okay. So using Gbra can you see
this? Let's see. Let's magnify that. So
let's drag this point. So you can see
the blue curve inside is the asteroid.
And all these lines you see all these
lines are mechanism you know ways to
show you how how can you actually trace
the curve create the curve in fact
without rolling any circles. So, so
there are so many properties you know
you can trace the curve by rolling a
circle or or you can trace the curve
by by all these uh geometric
constructions. You can you can see and
and by the way the the the red curve
outside of it that is another asteroid
another cyclloid uh uh
hypocyclloid and it
can and another property is that it is
actually the
um the radial curve uh was it the
um the radial curve the blue ones. So
any anyway so so this interactive
geometry um application it's called G
algebra okay so you know I have like
hundreds of them showing this
interesting properties you can it's free
it was open source like 15 years ago
then they became very popular and they
made it closed source so that is
extremely
nasty so anyway so so let's see the rose
cub so I'm going to talk random a little
bit. Okay. So, so for example, here's a
rose curve and let's see uh what does
this one do? You
can Oh, yeah. You can animate it. You
see, I mean, so this is like rose curve
of different
parameters. Now, let's let's go back to
a a easy easy one. So, you can see at
some point they become just like that.
Okay.
So this curve is created by rolling a
circle
um around another circle. Okay. But if
you change the circle size and the
tracing point then you got all these
variations you see. So this this family
of curve curves is called rose curve.
Okay. And they are just a special case
of the spiralaph special case of the you
know so there are so many infinite
varieties of these um kind
of so ge algebra interesting you can you
know try you can you know use it and you
can check out my website and you know
and get all these uh inter interactive
um applications. It's amazing. So if you
are learning math this is uh tremendous
fun and this this one is particularly
very interesting because
this you know what is this showing is
the is called
costics that is you shine a light ray so
in the center you have this blue curve
of three like shaped like a triangle
it's so it's one of the it's called
deltoid which is a special case of hypo
cyclloid meaning you roll a circle
inside the larger one. Okay. So you can
create this delto del uh this this
triangle shaped curve inside. Okay. But
then you um then you put a point. Let's
see where is it.
Basically
you for any point you know you you pick
a point on the on the plane and you
shine light
rays towards the curve and then it
reflects off or refract off then you
then it will form you can see it forms
this shape. Okay, it forms this diamond
shape and that diamond shape is the
asteroid which is a which is a looks
like a diamond which is a special case
of hypocyclloid. So again the diamond
shape can also be created by rolling a
circle inside another circle. So you see
so the inside you got this triangle
shape deltoid which is a special case of
cylo uh
hypocyclloid but on the outside you know
if you shine a light on the on the
triangle shape and it reflect off then
you got this so-called envelope this
diamond shape then that is a asteroid
which is another uh hypocyclloid. So
this amazing and fascinating properties
you can see. So I'm I'm moving this
point P around. That is the uh that's
that is the light source. So so this
demonstrates doesn't matter where is the
light
source there uh costics which means the
re reflection and
refraction will create the the asteroid.
Okay. So in other words, the costics of
a
deltoid
is a
asteroid regardless where is the uh
origin of the light source. So that's
what this
uh this application demonstrates. Okay.
So that's about ge algebra. So let's go
back to um so this is asteroid you know.
So
remember so let's look at um okay so
let's look at deltoids so can we see so
asteroid can also generate this way so
amazing properties so let's look at so
here it shows where the
deltoids costics which is the light ray
refraction creates generates the
asteroid so there's a connection between
them
um and here's the deltoid. Okay. So
fascinating. So actually I I don't know
what's the proof you know. Um so I did
this like 30 years ago uh starting in
uh you know I write I write programs in
Mathematica language to generate them
and today I'm just updating them.
Fascinating. Okay. So let's go back. So
so is it interesting. Did God write the
universe in lisp or wufam
language? Well, wam language is a is a
family, you know, it's a particular case
of lisp. If you don't know yet, let me
quickly show that
um uh digression. Okay, let me quickly
quickly show that the equivalence of
lisp and wam language if you don't know
that yet. Uh so wam language tutorials
by video. So I have lots of like
hundreds of videos talking about wam
language in the past. These are the best
ones I collected
here. And uh wam language mod uh
packages. Okay. So so these are all
packages. Most of them are for plank
curves like for example this one. This
one specialized in generating
animations. Okay. So it's all free on
GitHub.
So download wam language and get them
and some are for pl um for tilings f
another fascinating subject. Okay so
these are for trocoid that's the topic
we are talking about today you can
generate all
these and this package is not for you
know if you want to show the rolling
circles then you want this one. Okay. Um
yeah the animation it create animation
rolling circles and other animations to
generate all sorts of
curves and uh but if you want you know
if you want given a curve you want to
change their parameters. For example the
circle size of two rolling circles a
circle rolling around
another but if the circle size are
different they they they trace out
different curves.
And you want to show not the circles
rolling but you want to show how the how
the change of circle size create
different images. That's this one.
That's what this one is for charcoal
plot. Okay. So you can see uh and and
you can also generate animation of it
like
that. So you can see you change one of
the parameter they become smaller and
different shape to different ones.
Fascinating. Beautiful. Uh and also this
one is interesting because this one
shows that a line
segment can actually be generated by
rolling a circle like that. Okay. So
um so let's go back. So that those are
woof packages. Uh I'm gonna um so
download that and I'm gonna show you how
rolling a line I mean a line segment can
be generated as a uh by rolling circles.
Okay. So here's some animations. Let me
get back to the lisp and wolfam language
thing.
Um, okay. So, you got this
um animations. Okay. And where is the
single line? Okay. That would be
hypotcoid. Mhm.
You see this shows a line segment can be
actually generated by rolling a circle
inside another of half radius of the
larger
circle and elis elisps can also be
generated that
way. And here we see the deltoid, we see
the asteroid, and we see other fancy
one. Rose, this is Rose. Okay, that's
about that. Um, yeah. So, uh, so uh, so
let me show you about
the how Wam language is a um, lisp
programming language.
Okay. Uh, so wam language history there
you go. UFM language version history of
notebook user interface you know today
it's very popular you have this Julia
uh Jupiter notebook where does it came
from it came from wuam
language 40 years ago starting in 1998
the notebook interface came from wuam
language okay let's start wuam
language so I highly, you know, it's my
favorite programming
language. It's my first programming
language, but it turns out also my
favorite after, you know, after all
these
years. So, hold on a second.
So, so Wufam
language shift enter to start to uh
launch it to start the kernel and
magnify.
Okay. Okay. So that's about notebook
interface. Then we want to go wam
language history. So wam language is
basic basically based on
lisp and APL. Okay. So you know here's
old documentation uh like 30 years ago
and
APL. Okay. So, so for detail wam
language versus lisp you can see wuam
language got every you know lisp
language why is it special because you
can list about five things about lisp
that is different from all other
languages. So one of them is everything
are symbols check. Same thing with wuam
language everything are symbols
everything is a expression check. uh a
expression is either atomic expression
such as numbers or string or a list
check also true in wolfam language
purely nested syntax true you know in in
list you got
paren so you know you got all these
parenthesis so you know you know like
this is lisp code wen language is
exactly the same purely necessary syntax
but you use the square bracket instead
and you put the head of the expression
outside. So and predominantly functional
programming check both in both case
reader macros. Exactly. So this you got
this you know square bracket for vector
you got this uh apostrophe for quote you
got back tick for quote but evaluate
parts of it. You got comma to indicate
which part you want to evaluate and you
got the uh the pound
sign you know and you know these are
kind you know in this they are called
reader markers and in wam language you
have a more elaborate version. So you
got you got so in wam language actually
you can you can have infix infix
notation but they are equivalent to the
nested version. So here is a complete
uh list of them in you know this you
know called reader macros in lisp but in
wuam language they are just called
syntactic forms.
Okay. So you got that then you got list
macros. So in list you got list macros
but in Wuam language you got like a
glorified list macros which is pattern
matching symbolic pattern
matching or also known as
um term rewriting system in computer
science. So if you take the computer
science perspective it's called term
rewriting system in in fact that's how
wam language works the entire language.
So imagine if you are a list coder wam
language is is such that every function
you write is a list macro okay that's
basically all you
do
so okay that's the lisp in wam language
then the other thing is APL APL
programming language is like you know so
so the main thing about APL language is
two things they use short unic code
symbols for function names
That's one thing which is um not too
important because it just renamed
functions. But the other thing about APL
that's um an innovation back then is
that they treat every function every
every every argument as a matrix or
array. So list array or nested. So you
got matrices or of of any dimension.
So whenever function takes an argument
whenever that argument is a list or
array or matrix it automatically apply
the function to the whole elements. So
it's like map. So in Python in
JavaScript in you know in Java we have
the map function from basically from
APL. Okay map. But the thing about APL
is that it it does it the map
automatically. So you don't have to
manually say maps a function to
something whenever the argument is a
list it automatically map. Okay. So that
is APL that is the the s the the the the
core characteristics the the the
innovation of APL APL stand for a
programming language. Okay. So so that's
a case in wam language. Okay. Okay. So
wam language got the list
characteristics APR characteristics and
every function in APR is in Wufam
language. APR is small like you got 30
functions that's
it. But then so besides these two wam
language does mathematics. So uh you
know symbolic solving equations
integrals derivatives and so on. So
these
three parts you know the you know the
this characteristics APL
and solve equations uh or integral and
you know differential equations or
vectors or solve matrices you know that
makes up that basically makes up the
wraim language what's known as
Mathematica. Okay. So then you can see
the details. So for every every part you
know like almost like everything about
this in wolf language there's a
counterpart okay and exactly basically
exactly the same thing except you know
the syntax differ a little bit but
exactly the same concept. So for syntax
for example for comments uh for for
grouping expressions for arithmetics
uh for
booleans uh then for variables
assignment
uh flow control if else which switch
condition and you know and loop while
map uh map C do times you know and data
structure. So in in data structure in
list basically everything is a
list then you have a hash table
basically list and hash table and well
you have vector okay so in this in wam
language language exactly the same so
this list this and association so every
every data structure is just those
mostly just list
okay so for example wam language does
not have hash table and until until
about 10 years ago. For the first 20
years ago, for the first 20 or so years
of wolf language, there's no hash table.
Everything is just a list. So what if
you want a hash table or dictionary?
Well, you just have a list of pairs just
like this called association list, you
know.
So, and you know, so so you can check
out that. Okay. So let's go back to um
so is that
interesting? Keep your comments coming.
Okay. So let's go back to start to code
some
uh some more fam language on the
mathematics on the
u on these
things. D
says you have influenced me to look into
more I didn't know it was a lisp. Why is
wam not used more often in some of the
places list use? It's simple. The answer
is simple. Wam language is not free. In
fact, if you want to buy it, it's like,
you know, like if you want to use in a
corporation like professional
organization, it's like $2,000,
$1,000 back in 1990s. They have student
version which is $250. So, it's very
commercial entity.
Okay? And most coders, you know, they
don't like it, you know, like the C and
Unix people, they don't want things
that's not free. they want
free you know so basic then the open
source became very popular since year
2000 everyone demand open
source so then basically that killed all
the commercial uh compilers and you know
so everything is like open source and
free but wuam language remained
commercial so today you can you can
download the um you know you can
download it free starting about um let's
about five years
ago. Okay. So, you can download it free.
Uh but it's still commercial. It's not
open source. Okay. The free version
provide everything. It's it's not a
crippled. So, it's like exactly the same
as if you buy if if you pay it, you
know, if you pay it. There's a student
version, there's a hobbyist version like
three
$300 something like that. Okay. check
their
website.
Um, you know,
so yeah, it's commercial. I mean, yeah,
you know, so the open source, you know,
people want free things, but now you got
you you you got the free um
version. Okay, so that's about war
language. So, uh, hello Hank.
Okay, let's code some let's start to
code. Okay, so close uh that show. So
let's start to code. I want to code um
what are we coding? So I want to
regenerate this graph. Let's try that
today.
Okay. So open that. So go to the top MB.
You can see there's a wuam language
notebook. You know these are 30 years
old. So open it. Make a backup. Open
it. Okay. So let's move it here. And you
can see it says, you know, Asian
notebook. Do you want to update the
appearance? Yes. Okay. Then uh magnify.
Okay.
So, so these are all my old um you know
like this is
1995 many of these are obsolete but I
have a updated version on my website and
on
GitHub. So description uh okay
so how we going to do this?
So you can see this is ancient
um okay so this is the graph we want to
recreate
okay now this is 30 years old now
remember
so okay okay so we need to do that okay
so let's let's start with something
simple okay so let's put here let's save
it
um untitled
uh spiral
graph.
Okay. So it's calling power plot and
calling that that is my
um that is my
um my packages. Okay. So okay. So let's
see. So you can get
those. Okay, let me let me let me start
to do this.
Um, so what do you need? So this package
is uh so this one is for uh plank code
formulas. Okay. So yeah, so let's focus
on getting this done hyper. So okay, so
go to curve formulas. Let me just get
it. Okay, so we are doing what is this
one? This one is uh
hypotcoid. Okay, so hypo this one is
hypocyclloid. Okay, let me just grab the
formula. Okay, so hold on a second. So
go to talk
show go to today's talk show and start
start a coding
block language. Okay, paste the code
there and uh Okay, then search
search
hypotid search
search. Okay, where is the definition?
So the definition is here that is the
formula. Okay. Copy that. Close that.
Okay. Now show in browser. So there's a
wam language. Let's uh pop it out. Paste
it here. So this is the formula. So we
want to
uh so let's copy
this. Okay. So we need to make this code
work. This code right now won't work
because it's coding a package. I can
load the package but I don't want to do
that. I want to show you how to do this
um without you know without like a
special
package. Okay. So you define this
function hypocyclloid and which is has
three parameters there.
uh let's let's uh
show okay three
parameters. So hypocyclloid is a special
case of
hypotloid. So it becomes um yeah so it
becomes one and one over n one / n and
what is hypo
hypotcoid which is uh this
one and it is a function of t. So here's
the formula. A and B, A and B are
the the radius of the circles. So circle
A, circle B, radius H is
the the distance from the center of the
rolling circle. That's the tracing
point. Okay. So anyway, that's the
formula. So then you want to Okay. So
let let me just quickly show you
something.
Okay. So, parametric plot takes two
functions. One is the
um um Okay. So, let's not do
that. So, parametric plot takes two
argument. One is a function. Um the
second part is a parameter t from zero
to let's say 30. uh let's say 10 pi.
Okay. So you need to define a and b.
Okay.
Clear. A b. Okay.
Then then you assign a =
5 a =
1 b = to let's say 1 over 3.
Okay. So we can now plot
this. Okay. No go. Okay. Something is
wrong. So why is it wrong? Because H is
not defined. Yeah. So we need to define
H.
Uh AB
H. Okay. So h
is 1.1 over3. Okay, copy
that. Now if you are wondering what is
h, let me there. There it is.
Okay. Okay. So what is edge? Uh h is the
um so let me show you an animation. Uh
do we have an
animation? Yeah. You see this? You see
this bar extending far out from the
yellow
circles. So the distance from the leng
so h is the length of that bar.
Okay. So if the length is different, you
have different
curves. So here the formula a and b. A
is the larger
circle radius. B is the radius of the
smaller circle. And H is that length of
that bar. Okay. So, so you got
that. Okay. So, and and what's the other
thing? So, if you change it to 3
over7, so if you change this to 3 over
7, then you get that seven star thing. 3
over 7 shift enter fantastic okay so you
don't need any packages you can just in
fact you can go to wuam research like
you can go to the wuam alpha and it
will I I'm pretty sure okay so wuam
alpha
website they have somewhere that allows
you to uh evaluate wuam language code
online
like okay so let's see
uh yeah
uh okay I missed some part of
it so let's copy again turn on
JavaScript
yes mafa doesn't understand your query
okay so
Yeah, you need to go to somewhere. Wait,
try the following. Okay, wam, you know.
Wow, it it types set the thing.
Fantastic. So, in Wuam language, you can
type set the thing just by
pressing control shift N. Okay, it's
beautiful. That's the beauty of uh you
know wam language. You don't have to
learn lat or tech complicated you know
just control shift n we'll do
it. Okay so we got that. So let's move
on. So what but what um okay so okay got
so now we need to get we need to work on
this
code.
Yeah. Okay. So this code will generate
this
graphics. Okay. So this is 30 years old
graphics.
Um so so let's make a break point there.
So we need to get this code to work.
Okay. So why so I'm doing this you know
this particular graphics is to show
uh let me go back here okay so so this
particular graphic is to show it it lets
you get a general idea of what the
parameters what the curves look like for
a certain
parameter because there are so many of
them you know so so I've choose
This is carefully chosen
values. So it is intended intended to
show you that so at a glance you can
know what kind of parameters will
generate what kind of curve. Okay. So
for example if you see these uh six
curves you can see the number six there.
You see -1 / 6 or -5 over 6. So for
these five curves you can see the number
five -1 over five or -4 over
five for this one is four you know for
this one is
seven. Okay so you know so and this one
is four. So you know you can like get a
sense of what it looks like. Okay. So
let's uh let's try to update this. Okay.
So let's see. Uh oh my god my my this so
this is kind of advanced code I wrote
like 20 years ago 30 years
ago they uh okay parametric plot uh
hypotcoid okay so I need to define
that oh it's
epitrocoid okay I got hypotcoid but I
don't have a trunk. AP trunk is
basically just a change of
sign.
So get uh let's see curve formulas. So
what what we need? We need the epi
epitroid formula. Search for it. There
it
is. Copy back here.
So
let's put it there. Okay. So this part
we
remove and where is the formula? Okay.
So search for the
formula. There it is.
Okay. Copy.
Close and paste it here. And this this
is the inline documentation. Okay. Move
it up.
Okay. So we got
hypocyclloid
epicloid. So hypocyclloid is defined in
terms of
hypotrocoid. Epicid is defined in terms
of epitrocoid.
Okay.
Um okay. So Okay. So we need some kind
of clear um because that makes
it so that you
can so when you re-eva re-evaluate they
will clear clear out all the rules and
stuff.
Um
hypotcoid. Okay. So that then then you
need
the MP cycl. Okay. Yeah. So clear
them then inline documentation then um
then the actual definition here. Okay.
Then then
you Okay. So,
so okay. So, you got
this. Okay. You got
this. Actually, it will just
work. All you have to do it will just
work. I'm pretty sure. So, go back here.
Select
all. Uh, wait a minute. Shift enter. Let
me make a screenshot of
this. Okay. Select or paste. Uh, no, not
that. Copy or select or paste. Okay. So
we got a code
here.
Now shift
controlN to make
it type
set. Okay. So now we can evaluate it and
hopefully it will create
this after 30 years. Okay. Let's see.
Yeah. Shift enter. Okay. Do it.
Okay. No, wrong. Yeah, graphics array is
obsolete. Okay.
So, yeah. So, it's obsolete. You need to
use graphics grid. But, however, it
still
works. Now, you see, you need to change
the thickness. Yeah, I kind of like this
new
thickness. New default thickness.
Okay. So it it works. Um this minor
detail graph graphics array is obsolate.
You need to use graphics grid which is
um trivial to change. It doesn't matter
much. Okay. So graphics array is a
function that just take a takes a list
of graphics. Then they will try to
arrange them in a in a like grid. So
that you know so they they they replace
with a new function graphics
grid. So anyway so that's it. We did
what we wanted. Fantastic. So let me
copy this. So
um uh cut graphics. Let's see. Uh
export copy graphics. Uh, save graphics
as
uh I don't want PDF, I want
JPEG. So, you got PDF, HTML,
BMP, JPEG, PNG. That's what we want.
Okay. Then, uh, this Windows
interface
XX. Okay. Now go to
desktop
refresh. There is a graphics now open in
a in the dedicated
graphics.
Fantastic. Fantastic. Okay. So, copy the
file path. Close
it.
Show metadata. Okay. There's a lot of
metadata. We make a backup. Now remove
meta data. Okay. Show metadata again.
Now it's meta data is removed. Okay. Now
copy the file path. Close. Close. Go to
talk
show. Today's talk show in browser. Go
to the
um hypocyclloid page. Open it there
and search for PNG. So this is the old
image. Now let's put a new image here.
Linkfi show. There it is. Fantastic.
This is update after 30 years. Yeah,
it's much
better. And then move the image to the
current directory. Wait.
Uh move it to the current directory and
just say there. and uh rename
it. Uh rename
it. Uh okay, this is my old
um naming convention. Let's make
it epicyclloid
hypocyclloid gallery. Okay, let's just
say
okay, redo the figure tag. There you
have it. Okay, that's it for today.
Fantastic. I hope you like
it. Anything else? I think Yeah, that's
it for today. Uh I'm going to I need to
code. So, you know, I need to code a lot
more. I need to um you see this package?
I need
to and there's a lot of animations and
stuff I need to
redo. Okay. Bye guys. I think that's it.
So, so this old image let's see this is
36 kilobytes.
Okay, let's look at the new
image.
566. Okay, you need to uh optimize it.
Make a backup
first.
Optimize.
Okay, refresh. Now it's
242 kilobytes. So it's
like Yeah.
Uh, if you like my stuff, okay, support
me. Go to
my.info. Pay me, okay? Go
to.info. You can
then.info. Then all the way down.
Patreon me, Amazon gift card, PayPal. I
prefer those. Okay. send me $100 or you
can get my entire website of all the
programming tutorials. It's about $6,000
pages, three gigabytes of information
written in the past 30 years. You can
pay me $300
PayPal or Amazon gift card and uh I'll
send you a zip version. Okay? Or you can
buy my Emacs tutorial and JavaScript
tutorial. you you know go there if you
are interested you'll find the you know
the link to pay me and get the zip
file. Thank you guys for watching and
bye guys like it very much. Thank you.
First time I see Wu in action.
Fantastic. Hey
10.
Bye. Okay. So close down.